<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0611" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shakers, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">6</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">11</biblScope><date value="18761101" TEIform="date">November 1876</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">81-88</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="6" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="81" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="11" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">THE SHAKER. Official Monthly.—Published by the United Societies. "WHA.T IS TRUTH P" "THE
                        ETBB1STAL RELINQXTISHMEHNTT OW Vol .VL| G. A. LOMAS, EDITOR. N. A. BRIGGS, PUBLISHES. No. 11.</p><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Light enough" TEIform="index"/>LIGHT ENOUGH</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leggett, E. T." TEIform="persName"/>E. T. LEGGETT</byline><p TEIform="p">What thousands, blinking like the birds of night, Dazed by the brilliance of o'erpowering
                            light, With slumbering eyelids, grope the green earth o'er, And in full floods of light
                            still sigh for more : Not light they need ; could all the suns that glow, In jne
                            concentered, brighten all below, They'd still complain ; for all is dark within ; No ray
                            illumes their citadel of sin. Not light is wanting; light is everywhere; Each tree's a
                            sermon and each flower a prayer: Earth, seas, and skies, the seasons as they roll, Teach
                            man's whole duty to each reasoning soul. The light, that at its dawn, ere man was free, Led
                            saints of old from death to victory. From heaven to earth, from God to man to-day, Still
                            dazzling shines upon the better way. No light has dimmed, no fountain ceased to flow; No
                            truth 's involved that man has need to know; No law has changed, rewarding good or ill; All
                            ill is Hell,— all good is Heaven still: No chord is missing from earth's glad refrain; No
                            link is broken in earth's golden chain; Still, as the sunbeams, angels come and go, With
                            smiles to cheer and balm for every woe. That soul, of all is happiest and best. Who,
                            blessing others, is in others blest: In every sphere where men or angels are, True happiness
                            is true religion there: He who conforms in body, mind and soul To all God's laws imposed for
                            his control, Or prince, or peasant, be his station given, W'herever he may be, to him is
                            heaven. 'Tis folly to resist, where man is wrong; Man is too weak for treason — God too
                            strong; Omnipotence is His with all the spheres; To Him eternity's unending years; Let's
                            then be wise before it's all too late, Acknowledge God and keep the laws of Fate; With heart
                            and hand join with the hosts above, Who less know God is great, than God is love. Union
                            Village, Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Make room for truth" TEIform="index"/>MAKE ROOM FOR TRUTH</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>GILES B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p">[The following excerpts are from a private letter, made without permission of the writer. But
                            they contain so much truth, and the evidences of the "passing away of old heavens," together
                            with the needed rebuke to stereotyped religionists, that we make bold to use them, as the
                            property of God and his people everywhere.—Ed.] s ¦» * * Why, we know of many people who
                            believe enough gospel truth to save them from sin. and in their obedience are saved from
                            sin, who nevertheless are very limited in their knowledge of fundamental principles of
                            truth, which other souls would have to be convinced of before they could take one step in
                            the way of God. And these fundamentals are of such vast importance, that a want of their
                            recognition has riveted the handcuffs, whet the guillotines and spiked the torture casks of
                            nations of inquisitors, who, for what they call heresy, have tortured until death, millions
                            of human beings, and retarded the advent of Christ's second appearing for hundreds of years!
                            The probability is, that nine-tenths of those who have enough truth to save them from sin do
                            not see the least impropriety of having as a requisite for eligibility to office in the
                            United States' government that a man should believe in God — no matter if it was the God of
                            the Presbyterians or Trinitarians, claiming that some are elected to heaven from all
                            eternity, let them sin as much as they choose, while others, never so righteous, would be
                            damned, by the decrees of God, to all eternity! They cannot see the point that this
                            requisite of eligibility to civil office would create a State standard of religious belief,
                            and terminate in the adoption of capital punishment or the inquisition for what said
                            officials might denominate heresy. They cannot see that such requisite would fix upon a
                            specific Ood-idea or OodcJiaracter as the God to be believed, to the exclusion of every
                            other, and that thus liberty of conscience would be at once abridged, aye, annihilated! * *
                            * Now, if we should be so conservative as to render nothing which this class of minds would
                            object to, what possible avenue would be open for the continuous revelation of truth, which
                            is what our Shaker gospel claims as a foundation principle of Shaker faith? We confess we
                            cannot see said avenue. Many cannot see why the least objection should be raised to the
                            authority exercised in closing the world's exhibition on some particular denomination's
                            Sabbath, while to carry out in justice such a system of freedom of conscience as Shaker
                            religion claims as Christianity, the exhibition at Philadelphia should either be opened
                            every day of the week, or dosed every day ! But some ask : " What has Shakerism to do with
                            it ? " Why, the domain of Shaker testimony and duty covers every moral and religious phase
                            of human error— sin, and it cannot do less than this, to be a gospel of full salvation from
                            all sin. It has been said: " He cannot live rightly, whose faith is wrong." Abstractly
                            considered, this is true, yet relatively it is erroneous. A good degree of righteousness may
                            be attained unto by a living obedience to principles, which originates a faith which those
                            so living do not sufficiently understand either to believe or disbelieve. Hence we have,
                            relatively speaking, righteous life without faith; however paradoxical, it is true. * * * *
                            Jesus was a heretic, judged by the religious law of the Jews. Ann Lee was a heretic,
                            according to the theology of the Church of England. Father James Whittaker was a heretic by
                            the standard that justified Abijah Wooster and others in their old heavens religion when
                            Father said: "Abijah, go and bury your Christ, for he stinks!" This was the Christ of a
                            religion which justified any in living only a Pauline quality of Christianity. Jesus
                            anticipated the proclivity in human nature to create gods, and the tendency to worship him
                            as God, hence called himself the " Son of Man." Ann Lee did the same, and often rebuked the
                            tendency to worship her by saying : " Don't kneel to me, but kneel to God; I am but your
                            fellow-servant." * * * Shakerism i3 a recognition— 1. Of one God, dual in principle, spirit
                            in esse. 2. Revelation of God through human and angelic media. 3. This revelation has been
                            in progress from time unknown. ' 4. It is manifested to our age through Jesus Christ's
                            example and teachings. 5. Additionally manifested through Mother Ann Lee. 6. Continued in
                            manifestation through their faithful followers. 7. The evidences of these manifestations
                            being of God, and Christian, will be in harmony with, and in support of, principles of truth
                            revealed by preceding media, which have been tested as savory by life experiences. 8.
                            Shakerism is a theology which conserves all preceding revelations of truth, while it
                            continues to reveal truth as fast as humanity (individually or collectively) can be
                            developed to comprehend the wisdom of God. * * *</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes by the way, no. 4: trifles" TEIform="index"/>NOTES BY THE WAY -NO. 4 TRIFLES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/>H. C. BLINN</byline><p TEIform="p">On my desk, by the hand of some kind friend, I find " Trifles," and the last verse says : "
                            It is the little sins Lead to great wickedness; In little deeds that bless The highest good
                            begins." Trifles! Well, in the common acceptation of the term it may be perfectly correct,
                            but they ultimate in a magnitude as extended as the whole world. From these trifles spring
                            all the thorns that so seriously afflict poor fallen man on his journey through life. No
                            better sermon could be preached for the redemption of the world than is contained in these
                            four simple lines. Avoid the little sins, the lovely sins, the darling sins — those nearest
                            to our own hearts, and so near that we almost fail to recognize but that they are a part of
                            our being, and we shall never have cause to mourn over those of " great wickedness." Sin,
                            like every thing else, grows by cultivation. It may be petted and flattered in the days of
                            infancy, but as it develops on the right hand and on the left, it often frightens SHAKERS,
                            1Y, NOVEMBER. 1876, SHAKER VILLAGE, 11 <pb n="82" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. us long before the
                            age of maturity ; and unless it can be arrested, it becomes in advanced years a frightful
                            monster, and, " to be hated, needs only to be seen " in that state. He who wrote in the good
                            book that " man is born unto trouble, as the sparks fly upward," illustrates with much
                            accuracy our present condition in life. In this latter day it seems to be inherent in the
                            very germ of our being. If, however, it could be arrested in infancy, there might be more of
                            an encouraging hope of the promised millennium. But while there is so much to encourage not
                            only " little sins," but sins of magnitude, it needs an army of peace-makers to speak peace
                            and to proclaim the gospel of "good news." The crude and even vulgar manner in which many of
                            the revolting1 crimes are heralded through the land is no doubt often the active stimulus of
                            other deeds of darkness. Shaker villages are by no means so far removed from these
                            messengers of wrong living and wrong-doing but that they are obliged to share, to some
                            extent, in the malaria. Editors and others may perhaps be warranted in saying that they
                            publish what the people wish to read ; but it must be a sad and morbid state of the mind
                            that can dwell with satisfaction over the rehearsal of crime. The warning voice of the
                            testimony of our gospel work is in its every breath against it, as well as against the
                            fascinating sensational literature that is sweeping like a deluge over the land. There may
                            be those who, for the "little" or the large sins that they may meet in this line, would feel
                            no condemnation for either the writing or reading — indeed, no more than' they would for
                            bearing false witness, or for coveting their neighbor's goods; but as we would not wish to
                            be judged by this standard of mind, we peril our souls and the prosperity of our Christian
                            cause in proportion as we cherish the sins of the world. The relief, yea, the sunshine to
                            this unpleasant picture, comes from the " little deeds that bless." In this the peace-maker
                            rinds all that his willing heart is able to do, sowing seeds of kindness — deeds of love. It
                            is a development of the spirit of Christ in the soul which reads: Do unto others as ye would
                            that others should do unto you. While there is such an extended field of usefulness spread
                            out before us, it would seem unfortunate that he who has the least light from God should
                            either hide or squander it through the influence of a less worthy cause. Better would it be
                            in the consecration of our lives to the spirit of good, that whatever we do, it may be as a
                            protest against the little as well as large sins of the world, and ever for the exaltation
                            of our high calling.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Change the sabbath day" TEIform="index"/>CHANGE THE SABBATH DAY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p">I PROPOSE that the American government change the Sabbath to any day of the week, except the
                            Jewish or the Mahometan Sabbath day. The pagan Sun-day is of all others the most improper.
                            As Shakers, I and my people observe it as a day of rest with as much fidelity as any people.
                            As an American citizen, proclaiming liberty of conscience to all mankind, I protest against
                            the sectarian, superstitious closing of the world's exhibition on Sun-day. It is not the
                            true scriptural Sabbath. The government did right in blowing up Hell Gate on the Sabbath.
                            Let the Christian clergy blow up the gates of hell — religious controversy; let the world's
                            exposition be open, free of expense, to the world's poor on the remaining Sabbath days, and
                            henceforth keep hands off the only government constitutionally free from sectarian theology.
                            Then they may keep any day, and as many Sabbath days as they please, unmolested. And we —
                            Jews, Quakers, Catholics, materialists, atheists, Protestants — will all unite and keep any
                            day the American government may appoint as a day of rest to man, beast and cook.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Choice of treasures" TEIform="index"/>CHOICE OF TREASURES "Lay not up for yourselves
                            treasures of earth."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Neal, Emma J." TEIform="persName"/>EMMA J. NEAL</byline><p TEIform="p">That heart which builds for self alone, The miser's portion gains ; But when its wealth is
                            needed most, There's nought of worth remains. When death shall still the throbbing pulse,
                            And silence action here, The clink of gold will not appear In the immortal sphere. The
                            boatman, from that sylvan shore, May hear the miser's call, But cannot bear his pauper heart
                            Where love o'ershadows all. No counterfeit wears virtue's mien, When heartfelt joys unfold ;
                            Eternal gains, with bogus coin, Cannot, be bought nor sold. Where bloom the fruits of
                            paradise, True worth e'er gains its prize ; While worldly titles, fame — all liesThrive only
                            in disguise. Those who so fully are absorbed Amassing earthly ore. Of well-filled vaults,
                            they here may boast, But none of heavenly store. By giving much the soul grows rich,
                            Where'er its hands may toil To build for others homes of health, Or cultivate their soil.
                            The philanthropic soul ne'er wants The miser's golden store ; 'Tis blest by blessing others
                            here, And on the eternal shore. Then let me choose the " better part," The riches God has
                            given — For Jesus taught, the pure in heart Should find their wealth in heaven. Mt. Lebanon,
                            N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="John Ruskin" TEIform="index"/>JOHN RUSKIN</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL, FRASER</byline><p TEIform="p">Op the many distinguished living Englishmen, there are few who equal John Ruskin as an
                            artist, in literature, as a hater of shams, in honesty of thought and purpose, and in a true
                            appreciation of a want of righteousness in modern civilization. In his sixty-seventh letter
                            (July, 1876), to the people of England, he dashes off the following outlines : " A civilized
                            nation consists, in broad terms, first, of a mass of half-taught, discontented, and mostly
                            penniless populace, calling itself the people. Second, of a thing it calls a government, an
                            apparatus for collecting and spending money. Third, of cap italists, many of them rogues,
                            and stupid persons. Fourth, of a certain quantity of literary men, saying any thing they can
                            be paid to say — of clergymen, saying any thing they have been taught to say--of
                            philosophers, saying any thing that comes in their heads. Broadly, the civilized nation
                            consists of mobs, money-collecting machines, and capitalists. The capitalist lends the
                            civilized mob money, to buy gunpowder, infernal machines, or any thing else it has set its
                            idiotic mind on, and appoints its money collecting machines to collect a daily tax
                            thenceforward forever—A National debt." John Ruskin and his " Companions " have, instead of
                            a debt, begun to collect a National Store. They hold, " That a heap of cannon balls, or a
                            cellar full of gunpowder is not a store, though a heap of potatoes and a cellar full of
                            coals is." Again, " Now, the men who have the teaching of the people in their hands at
                            present tell them that it is not practicable for the goverment, or money-collecting machine,
                            to buy potatoes, etc., but must buy iron plates two feet thick, gunpowder, and red tape." "
                            The first condition of companionship is Honesty. The second, to earn our own living, and not
                            allow other people to work for us. First, as necessary to our health and honor; but much
                            more, as striking home at the universal crime of modern society — stealing the laborer's
                            bread, and teaching him pious catechisms, that we may keep him our quiet slave." " In
                            carrying out the designs of the Society, the person charged with it should be implicitly
                            trusted, and accurately obeyed by the companions. He cannot lose his time in persua. sion or
                            contention ; he must act undisturbedly^ or his mind will not suffice for its toil.
                            Hesitation and opposition might waste and pervert the power of the Society. His authority
                            over them must correspond precisely to that of a Roman Dictator in a war against external
                            enemies. It is not the command of private will, but the dictation of necessary law, which
                            the companion obeys—only, the obedience must be absolute, and without question; faithful to
                            the uttermost." " The practice of faith and obedience to some of our fellow-creatures is the
                            alphabet by which we learn the higher obedience of heaven ; and it is not only needful to
                            the prosperity of all noble, united action, but essential to the happiness of all noble,
                            living spirits. The moral scale is raised according to the degree and motive of obedience.
                            To be disobe dient through temptation, is human sin. To be disobedient for the sake of
                            disobedience, is fiendish sin. To be obedient for the sake of obedience, is angelic virtue.
                            Enforcement (of this) must be in the very teeth of the maddog's creed of modernism : ' I
                            will not be dictated to,' which contains the essence of all diabolical error." He suggests,
                            " That the mercenary professions— preaching, law-giving and fighting, be entirely
                            abolished." We, as a people, cannot but bless every good effort. When the designs of these "
                            companions" are realized, they will but approximate to the work we are in. We have no cannon
                            balls, but heaps of good things; and paid preachers, etc., with us, are as scarce as cannon
                            balls. The time seems to be drawing near when such men as Friend Ruskin may seek to know the
                            secret of our lives ; and we may have to tell them. First, ignoring the action of our
                            sensual — lower self. Second, manifesting to all the higher attributes of our being. Third,
                            loving and blessing those having the charge of affairs, who yield their services without 82
                                <pb n="83" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKBE 83 money and without price. To such, we can afford to
                            yield child-like, implicit, angelic obedience. Allow me to congralutate you, my gospel
                            relations, one and all, that with us is the Order of Heaven; and that we see before us, the
                            fulfillment of prophecy; that Saviours have come up upon Mount Zion, and do judge the Mount
                            of Esau. And while we bless the Saviours of to-day, by strengthening their hands and hearts,
                            may those of the past be remembered in love and reverence; and emphatically He, who opened
                            the way — "trod the wine-press alone, while of the people, there were none to help." And
                            whose sweet word was, " Except ye be converted, and become as little children, ye shall not
                            enter into the kingdom of heaven." The human spirit who stands in the rectitude and purity
                            of the work we are in, is a " covert from the storm, and as the shadow of a great rock in a
                            weary land " of wrong and pollution. Shirley, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Materialism—spiritualism, no. 1" TEIform="index"/>MATERIALISM-SPIRITUALISM. NO. 1</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, W. H." TEIform="persName"/>W. H. RUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p">These terms, as commonly understood, are used to express ideas the direct opposites of each
                            other. Yet, taking them in their original signification, there is no sufficient reason why
                            they should be made to represent ideas so different. The materialist is one who asserts that
                            there are certain elements in nature, possessing in themselves, separately, neither
                            intellect, will, affection nor passion; yet when, by some mysterious or fortuitous
                            occurrence, they combine to form the human organization, they produce all the phenomena
                            exhibited by the human soul, but disunited, these phenomena, in each individual case, cease
                            forever. This, of course, is mere assumption on his part. The elements of nature, by
                            combination, pro duce numerous forms — the stately oak and elm, the graceful palm, the
                            slender reed, the plant with its vast variety of flowers, charming by reason of their beauty
                            and splendor of color and delightful fragrance, and the numerous forms of beauty in the
                            mineral and animal kingdoms. The intelligent materialist does not maintain that these
                            formations possess any elements or forces which were not in existence before they assumed
                            their several forms; nor, when dissolved that their elements cease to exist. They may go on
                            combining and shaping themselves into forms of beauty forever. The chemist combines various
                            elements in nature, and produces results which are not effected by them separately. But
                            behind these are the purpose, judgment and skill of the chemist; and these compounds, in
                            many instances, continue in combination until the same skill is employed to separate them.
                            But when separated, they each retain their natural force. That is never lost, neither in the
                            combination of the elements, nor when they resume their original status. It is just as true
                            that the forces of reason, will, memory, love and affection, and the like, are never lost.
                            The contrary of this the materialist has no means of proving, though his theory requires him
                            to assert that there cannot be thought as we see it displayed in man, unless certain
                            elements which he calls material are combined. The human organization contains certain
                            substances which all agree to call material because they are perceived to be identical with
                            similar ones existing elsewhere. But the materialist is unable to prove that there do not
                            exist in the human organization, elements, or primary substances, which have, as yet,
                            escaped the scrutiny of the keenest-eyed chemist. What does he mean by the forces of the
                            elements ? For aught he knows, may they not be distinct substances combined with what he is
                            pleased to call material elements ? When combined, do they add any thing which they did not
                            possess separately ? If so, then something is produced where nothing was. So with the forces
                            of the human soul, intellectual, affectional or passional. It cannot be shown that they are
                            not eternal substances, very refined, no doubt, in their nature, which combine with other
                            elements, forming, ultimately, the intelligent, rational, active being that we call man. Nor
                            can it be shown that these forces once combined will not always continue thus, though they
                            may be separated from what are called the material portions. Just here the materialist and
                            spiritualist diverge. The materialist makes assertions, and it is evident enough that he can
                            do nothing more ; for, if there is no existence of the human being when the earthly form is
                            dissolved, it is impossible to know it; but if there is such, then there is a possibility of
                            knowing it; and this knowledge some claim to possess and undertake to make it clear to
                            others. Like all attempts at demonstration, however, this is not equally satisfactory to all
                            persons. What is absolute proof to one is not so to another. The demonstrations of science
                            are such only to those who investigate the facts for themselves ; and even to some who
                            attempt to investigate, they furnish no satisfactory proof, because there is not
                            intellectual development sufficient to comprehend them. Many rely upon the statements of
                            those who have proved the truth for themselves ; nevertheless, the most satisfactory proof
                            of science, whether physical, intellectual or moral, is that which one acquires for himself
                            and possesses within himself. " Add to your faith knowledge," is advice applicable to every
                            human being. For this the virtues of candor, patience and steady perseverance are necessary.
                            Possessing these, whatever may be his present lack, one may constantly " grow in grace," and
                            in all those things which lead to the knowledge of immortality.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fruitfulness in the divine life" TEIform="index"/>FRUITFULNESS IN THE DIVINE LIFE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webster, Elizabeth H." TEIform="persName"/>ELIZABETH H. WEBSTER</byline><p TEIform="p">¦ "I will that ye bear much fruit." To the citizen of the world nothing is more cheering than
                            to witness the evidence of growth around him; if in the city, the improvement and stability
                            of building; the good order, industry and intelligence of community. If a dweller in the
                            open land, his interest is different, but none the less hearty, in the improvement of his
                            surroundings. The oak tree, which his own hands planted in boyhood, has grown to be a shade
                            and a solace from the mid-day heat, and the vine which, long years after, he guarded and
                            trained, rewards him yearly with its ripened treasures of fruit. Nature has few inactive
                            seasons; but one winter for a whole series of blossoming, fruitage and harvest. What then of
                            that most wonderful of all the creations of God ? Are his periods of growth from infancy and
                            on through adolescence to old age the ultimatum ? or do they comprehend the whole glory and
                            majesty of humanity ? Verily we believe not. There is a germ of infinite possibilities in
                            each mortal tenement, which may grow and develop into an angel, or dwarf and become debased
                            into the opposite; a germ which may grow into a creation of beauty and healing, or sink into
                            a dependency and a curse. As that soul-germ is tended, protected and nurtured, so will be
                            its growth; till, taking on the conditions of maturity, these words of Jesus speak with
                            power to its consciousness — " I will that ye bear much fruit." But what is the fruit that
                            such as are called of God can bear? The same as the natural man, whose enjoyments and
                            pursuits are all "of the earth, earthy?" The same as the natural instincts of man,
                            unilluminated by the self-denying gospel of Christ bring forth, in those who live in the
                            element of worldliness ? Most truly we believe not. A wiser than the generality of mankind
                            has said that the offspring of the spiritually called, are the holy and elevated thoughts,
                            words and deeds which they produce, transmit, and which bless the world with their elevating
                            tendencies. Jesus said," those who are accounted worthy to attain the spiritual condition
                            live as the angels " (here on earth). How, then, do the angels live? He has told us how they
                            do not live, when he said : " They neither marry nor are given in marriage." Is it mine and
                            thine with them? or have they gained that blissful height for which Jesus and his disciples
                            toiled when on earth ? the oneness in love, which came from each loving his neighbor as
                            himself and providing and caring for no selfish love nor interest ? Curb the tide of natural
                            impulse and desires, and the current, instead of producing natural fruit or limitless waste,
                            will in time yield the peaceable fruits of righteousness. This is the fruit that will yield,
                            instead of uncertainty, blight and mildew, positive results of goodness, and all the
                            Christian graces. The fruit may be slower in developing than that of any natural crop ; but,
                            Oh! so sure; for is it not said " The sower to the flesh shall of that reap corruption, but
                            he that soweth to the Spirit shall of the Spirit reap life everlasting? " The results will
                            be a progressive elevation into every thing that is just and pure and lovely in the one
                            case, while the slave of his passions will be sinking lower and lower in subjection to them,
                            until " the evil days will come when he will have no pleasure," and no earthly offspring, or
                            riches, or honor, will be able to cheer the soul entering on the untried spirit condition,
                            for which the other has become so well fitted. The fruits of the Spirit are love, joy,
                            peace, etc., and though the cross which Jesus bore, arouses in us conditions opposed to
                            those graces, and feels at times heavy, and the yoke burdensome, still will come the time,
                            when the blest fruition will be obtained and the victory complete. The battle must be fought
                            by each one for him or herself ; in one sense single-handed and alone, each soul to its
                            maker; and in another, as in the company of the just and redeemed of all ages ; an
                            innumerable company <pb n="84" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> THE 8HAKEK of the just made perfect. A sympathy
                            which is not of God only weakens and enervates the struggling soul which needs the tonic,
                            bracing air of truth and honest dealing. Watered by the prayers and tears of the faithful
                            and the spirit of contrition and godly sorrow ; strengthened by the rays of truth and love
                            from the Sun of righteousness ; dug about and enriched by the faithful labors of the many
                            consecrated; toughened by the biting winds of adversity and kindly criticism, how sweetly
                            comes echoing down the many years from the great Husbandman : " Trees of my own planting I
                            will that ye bear much fruit." Fruits of love and consecration ; the lovely fruits of peace
                            and meekness, which will make you beautiful in the eyes of angels and the good ; and which
                            will enable you to become trees of healing and life for the sin-sick souls of earth — "
                            Life-giving nourishment for souls an-hungered." Those who are on the plane of the natural
                            and earthly may perpetuate the earthly image, according to nature's laws, but who are called
                            to a spiritual resurrection, to newness of life and obedience, die to the earthly that the
                            spiritual may live, even as the grain is ground and its vitality destroyed, ere it becomes
                            lifegiving bread to the hungry. " I will that ye bear much fruit:11 Tor the barren and
                            leafless, we know Give grief to the husbandman's heart. Then hasten, in spirit to grow. The
                            dew and the sunlight receive, The false and the hollow shake off; And true to thy uses
                            perceive — Christ's kingdom is not afar off. If we would grow, we must be faithful in
                            obeying our convictions ; faithful in our temporal avocations and in all the duties of life
                            ; consecrated in all our faculties to the good of the body of Christ, in all its uses and
                            adornings ; withholding no gift which has been intrusted to our care, to be used as by
                            faithful stewards for the interest, enjoyment and edification of the church. Forgetfulness
                            of self, animated with pure benevolence, will make us willing servants of the spheres, in
                            all that is elevating and refining ; will make us more like him who knew no will but the
                            will of the Infinite, and who went about doing good. We shall learn to pass and repass each
                            other as the angels', and would as soon harm ourselves as injure, by thought, word or deed,
                            the feelings of- another. Knowing that love and union and joy and peace are heaven, we shall
                            not thoughtlessly mar that heaven by anything unfeeling or unkind, but shall speak and act
                            so kindly and lovingly, that never a saddened heart or tear-filled eye shall witness against
                            us. In this condition of harmony and love, the angels who are sent to minister to the heirs
                            of salvation could reach us, and by their help and influence we can be . so swallowed up in
                            heavenly joy and illumination, that the sorrows and trials of life would disappear, and
                            fancied joys be no temptation. The sphere of love, blessing and peace would be so strong and
                            sustaining, that " great would become the peace of Jerusalem," and lookers on would be
                            constrained to exclaim: " Behold how these brethren do love one another!" and thus would be
                            spread our Zion's fair fame. The Prophet said that Saviours should appear on Mt. Zion, and
                            to fulfill the type will there not be those who have walked humbly in the footsteps of Him
                            who was pre-eminently a Saviour from sin ? With the authority of the leader and Elder
                            Brother in our redemption, his voice kindly yet earnestly speaks to each of us, his
                            professed followers : " / will that ye bear much fruit." " The true heirs of heaven are all
                            interwoven Like fruit bearing vines in the vineyard of God, Their spirits are living, with
                            beauty they're blooming, While watered and fed by the hand of the Lord. They love one
                            another as sister and brother — Uniting with angels in heavenly mirth, They are the redeemed
                            — The servants who're sealed — The glory of heaven, the light of the earth." Harvard,
                        Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Heavenly aspirations" TEIform="index"/>HEAVENLY ASPIRATIONS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Mantle, Henry" TEIform="persName"/>HENRY MANTLE</byline><p TEIform="p">Heavenly treasures we are seeking, For this earth is not our home; From its shades we are
                            retreating, Hoping for the good to come. Praised be our God in heaven, Praised be His saints
                            below. With the saints above we leaven, And their sympathy we know. Oft our trials seem
                            oppressive — Hard and harsh the storms we bear"— Mercy then makes more impressive. That of
                            heaven we may share.. Whether high or low our station, Let us labor to fulfill Every
                            righteous obligation — Bowing to God's righteous will. Life, we seek, life everlasting — May
                            our souls immortal live ; And of heavenly fruits be tasting, Such as gold nor earth can
                            givePass away ye fading treasures — Pass, ye vanities of time — Let us have immortal
                            pleasures — Pure, substantial, and divine. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="music" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Music, no. 11" TEIform="index"/>MUSIC-NO. 11</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, James G." TEIform="persName"/>JAS. G. EUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p">Musical instruments. — A two-fold meaning is often applied to this familiar term, one of
                            which has reference to the human voice, while the other has reference to mechanical
                            structure, the latter of which is to become the topic for this article. Musical instruments,
                            as mechanical means for disclosing musical tones, have been brought to almost inestimable
                            perfection, yet nevertheless are quite foreign from the cherished claims of some, whose
                            limited knowledge of their superior worth stands yet at very low ebb. Eealizing the
                            prominent reasons for such a woeful disdain of musical instruments, the arguments in their
                            favor could not be otherwise than considerate and candid. To elicit points more clearly, the
                            subject of musical instruments will be considered under four heads, to be treated upon
                            respectively in their proper time and place. First, their use in schools.—Every
                            singingteacher doubtless finds, from personal experience, various degrees of talent
                            displayed in his pupils. Some are capable of accomplishing quite readily almost any and
                            every point presented for their attainment, while others are much more deficient, scarcely
                            able to discern even the ordinary intonations of the gamut, much less to perform them,
                            without a long and tedious taxation upon the teacher, especially if there is not a ready
                            instrument to lighten the weary work, and determine the falling away, if there is any, from
                            the pitch or key — a fault remarkably prevalent where no instrument is used, and equally
                            ruinous to musical effect. Even one faulty singer upon this point is liable to draw a whole
                            choir from the key. Second, their abuse in schools.— Instruments, as a general rule, should
                            never become the moving power in school, but only a "backer "— an aid to the singers,
                            enabling them to sustain the key. When singers collapse into an indifferent condition,
                            leaving instruments to perform their share of the work for them, they cease to be the mere
                            aids for which they were intended ; hence their use becomes abuse. Third, their use in
                            church.—As preliminary to this point, it may be asserted that, were the mere harmony and
                            beauty of music the only point for consideration, it might with propriety be claimed that
                            congregational singing should be wholly excluded from church. But the writer, with no
                            disrespect to the God-given laws of harmony, takes the position that in the worship of God
                            the greatest good to souls should be paramount to all other considerations ; hence, to
                            restrain or debar from musical praises, because talents are not par excellence, any who
                            should feel moved to join in the song, would be an encroachment upon the devotional feelings
                            of the worshipper that no systematized course of music culture should ever be allowed to
                            justify. (But more of this in our next number.) Musical instruments, wherever used in
                            church, should subserve the two-fold purpose of aids to the singers in sustaining the key,
                            and helps, to swell the strains of music to far greater power and perfection than voices
                            alone would be capable of doing. Fourth, their abuse in church.— Similar, and quite equal to
                            faults shown up in school abuses, may be discernable by those in church, and quite as
                            difficult to remove, attributable not altogether to the use of instruments, but in some
                            measure, at least, to a lack of true de votional feelings, as the writer fails to recognize
                            a single instance of a singer's exhibiting a marked degree of apathy when singing with
                            instruments, that showed less sign of the same malady when singing witliout them. If the
                            use, then, of instruments serves to warrant such lamentable departure from religious
                            devotion, the fault should be attributed to right causes, that instruments which in
                            themselves are designed to be not only harmless, but of great worth to devoted singers, be
                            not made the objects of bitter, condemnatory imprecations, when the real fault is with the
                            singers, some of whom, through their passive, disinterested and irreligious condition of
                            mind, would render the use of instruments a positive abuse.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Interesting calculation" TEIform="index"/>INTERESTING CALCULATION</head><p TEIform="p">The following from the Christian Observer is commended to the reader who chews tobacco: Allow
                            that a young man, who is a confirmed tobacco chewer, may live twenty-five years. In each day
                            there will issue from his mouth half a pint of fluid too nauseously disgusting to describe.
                            In twenty-five years this will amount to five hundred and fifty gallons or more than four
                            hogsheads of this detestable mess. In the same time, allowing him only two ounces a day, he
                            will roll, as a sweet morsel under his tongue, half a ton of the hateful weed, which will
                            sicken a dog or kill a horse, forming a heap the size of a haystack. Then his rejected quids
                            would form a still larger pile. Now if such a young man could see ten half hogsheads full of
                            abominable filth, destined to pass through his mouth, a wagon load of tobacco and ten
                            wheelbarrows heaped up with quids, designed for an equally intimate association with his
                            lips, how would the prospect affect him ?</p></div2><pb n="85" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hyde Park, Massachusetts, September 19, 1876" TEIform="index"/>Hyde Park, Mass., Sept.
                                19,1876</head><p TEIform="p">Mr. F. W. Evans—Dear sir • Two years ago, while in the cars, traveling in New Hampshire,
                                I bought several small books of a Shakeress. They were explanatory of certain things,
                                but I did not get the particular information I was seeking. When entirely convenient for
                                you, I would be pleased to receive answer to the following questions: 1st. Did Ann Lee
                                profess to be inspired by the Spirit of the Living God like the Prophets, whose writings
                                are received in the bible? 2d. Did she profess to be the woman foretold in the twelfth
                                chapter of Revelations ? 3d. Did she ever say she was authorized, or permitted, by the
                                Lord, to claim the promise made in the beginning —that her seed should bruise the
                                serpent's head? 4th. Do the writings of Ann Lee, or any other Shaker or Shakeress,
                                resemble, in any respect, those of Joanna -Southcott, of England ? As you may be aware,
                                Mrs. Southoott published many books, claiming the above. Yours truly,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Richardson, George L." TEIform="persName"/>Geo. L. Richardson</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mount Lebanon, October 10, 1876" TEIform="index"/>Mount Lebanon, Oct. 10,1876</head><p TEIform="p">Geo. L. Richardson —Respected friend: In answer to the questions in your letter, I
                                inclose a little tract that will help you about Prophets. A Prophet is a Man, or Woman,
                                inspired by the Christ Spirit — not Jesus —from the Christ sphere. Ann Lee was a
                                Prophetess, and more than a Prophetess. She was the Character of whom the Prophets wrote
                                in the forty-fifth Psalm and other portions of sacred writ. She was not the Woman named
                                in the twelfth chapter of Revelations. That was the Holy Mother Spirit in Deity. In the
                                twelfth verse we have the Church, after being in the wilderness 43 months —1,260 days —
                                when Ann Lee becomes the Church symbolized, or personified. Her history exactly
                                corresponds with the Revelations. The Church and State Governments persecuted her. She
                                fled, on Eagle's Wings —the American Ensign — to the wilderness of America. The "flood"
                                of lies and slanders came. The Earth — Infidel Government of America— helped Ann Lee by
                                swallowing the flood — separating Church and State. Her seed bruised Lust — the Head sin
                                of man's sensual nature. Joanna Southcot I know all about—have her books. She came up
                                under the same elements that Ann Lee did. When Jesus came up, some thirty Jesuses came
                                up too. The elements that produced Napoleon or Washington would have produced thirty, if
                                one after another had failed. The wellbeing of the race does not depend upon One person.
                                Had Ann Lee failed, another would have been raised up in her place. Christ is distinct
                                from any human being. It is the baptizing spirit of the New Creation. Shakerism is pure,
                                primitive Christianity. It is like a " city set upon a hill that cannot be hid."
                                Community of Goods, Celibacy, Peace, Plainness in dress and speech, Yea and Nay, are
                                distinguishing marks, not easily mistaken or counterfeited. Respectfully</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Great truth" TEIform="index"/>A GREAT TRUTH</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hacker, J." TEIform="persName"/>J. HACKER</byline><p TEIform="p">Man is of the earth, earthly. All things earthly are subject to corrosion and rust. Weeping,
                            like acid poured into a rusty machine, softens and loosens the rust, and laughing, like pure
                            water, washes out the rust. Hence, the wise man said there is a time to weep and a time to
                            laugh. Hence, weeping and laughing should be indulged in, in the proper times. Berlin, N.
                            Y., September 4, 1876.</p></div2><div2 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="An extensive fruit grower of South America..." TEIform="index"/>An extensive fruit grower of South America...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">An extensive fruit grower of South America has discovered that the vines of the Tomato, put
                            beneath plum and peach trees, as a mulch, is death to the curculio and borer. THE SHAKER.
                            Monthly —60 cents per annum. A DUAL ADVOCATE OF CHRIST PRINCIPLES.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Decline of spiritualism" TEIform="index"/>DECLINE OF SPIRITUALISM</head><p TEIform="p">There is nothing strange, to us, in the fact admitted by leading Spiritualists, " that a
                            partial eclipse has gradually crept over the heaven illumined face of Spiritualism." Having
                            been led out from worse than Egyptian bondage—theological enthrallment—to the banks of a New
                            Jerusalem, where progress might be eternal without impediment, they have chosen to " tarry
                            by the shore," and play thus long with the waves and instruments of their liberation, taking
                            no other advantages of their liberation from the house of captivity. The very simple
                            illustration of the return of " one from the dead" has been, and is verily sufficient to
                            make Babylon of all the pet schemes and man-made creeds of the ages. Though seventy-five per
                            cent of the manifestations claiming to be spiritual phenomena were only frauds, what of it?
                            If twenty-five in one hundred are true, and even much less than these, what will become of
                            the theological pets, physical resurrection, vicarious atonement, election and reprobation,
                            heaven, hell and the devil ? The emancipation from these errors has been experienced, more
                            or less, by spiritualists for twenty-five years ; and millions are the converts from such
                            bondage. The Shaker Church was thus enlightened one hundred years ago; and a continued,
                            unbroken manifestation of communication between the two worlds has ever since been its
                            boast. Had it remained stationary, dallying with the manifold physical phenomena common to
                            it, and which have become so positively disgusting in modern spiritualism, where,
                            spiritually speaking, would said Church long since have been? Eclipsed; blotted out;
                            forgotten. And whatever of eclipse the Shaker Church has experienced, we frankly confess, it
                            has been caused by our failure to progress ; by our " tarrying by the way "— striving to be
                            satisfied with past phenomena, moonshine — reflected light— rather than pressing forward to
                            the vivifying brilliance and warmth of the sunlit revelations of to-day. Inasmuch as we have
                            progressed from the merely phenomenal to progressive spiritual duty, spiritualism has not
                            only relieved us of dead and deadening theologies, but it has given us new and living
                            convictions. These convictions have led us away from our old lives, even as far as they have
                            removed us from old theologies. They have taught us that the generative, reproductive,
                            earthly principle is not spiritual, however righteous as an earthly elementary, and we have
                            left it for something more progressive. What have Spiritualists done? Spiritualism 'lias
                            instructed us that Communism is more, very much more, spiritual than the narrow circle of
                            the conjugal relation; hence, to be much more spiritual we have embraced Communism.
                            Spiritualists, do you see that we move? "In heaven above, where all is love," there is no
                            such narrowness as is exhibited in private families; why should there be in our heaven
                            below? Spiritualism has taken, or is taking away the elements that would make us quarrel and
                            fight for the constituents of the old life ; does it work so with you, eclipsed brethren and
                            sisters ? God grant that it may! Spiritualism teaches us that progress means, "from the
                            world, from the flesh, far away ;" have Spiritualists arrived there yet ? And so we might
                            continue. We would lash, with whips of large-corded criticism, the converts to Spiritualism
                            for their laxity in accepting the terms of spiritual progress, and accept their lashing
                            criticism, inasmuch as they have transcended us. We hope, and believe a little, in the
                            efficacy of the " New Movement." But unless it shall cause their " righteousness to exceed
                            the righteousness" of their surroundings, and their former, fleshly lives, we will continue
                            in the opinion that they not only accept the eclipse, but desire the old flesh-pots of
                            Egypt, rather than any advance that costs so much self-denial to be genuine Spiritualists.
                            We had greater hopes of " Spiritualists " than we have realized. Why ? -fe</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Brotherhood" TEIform="index"/>BROTHERHOOD</head><p TEIform="p">One of the transcendent qualities, and best evidences of Christianity, is the manifestation
                            of brotherly love, like unto Jesus' and apostolic times. Perhaps there is no quality more
                            wanting among professed Christians, to make them genuine holders of the title, than an
                            equitable distribution of all their wealth, possessions, time, talents, accumulations. It is
                            apparent to every one that such a distribution is simply an impossibility outside of radical
                            Christianity, and other Christianity is very weak salvation. The natural, unchristian
                            practitioner must have wife or husband; consequently, children should be born; shelter,
                            food, education, etc., are the necessaries following. It is not in human nature, unbaptized
                            by the Christ, to care as well for a neighbor's as for its own. The laws of the Jews
                            recognized and condemned this very selfish principle ; hence, set apart Sabbaths, whereon
                            equal distribution of accumulations and power was again and again enforced — even the land,
                            the foundation of all earthly wealth, was returned to its original owners at intervals of at
                            least half a life time. But the giving-up-all principle, either for God or humanity, is more
                            foreign to the myriads of professional Christians than to any persuasion which they dub
                            heathen. If a man gives up his wife to the Lord, or a woman does the same with her husband,
                            it is with especial understanding that the Lord will permit the continuance of all the
                            selfish, unchristlike behavior of the past. The same of their children, houses, lands, and
                            all personal possessions. Are these not facts ? When Jesus gave up his wife, or her who
                            would have been such to him, he renounced even the further intention of engaging in marital
                            relationship. With its renunciation his life was cut off from the earthly ; and " who shall
                            declare his generations?" Where are his descendants ? All men and women became his brethren,
                            who, after his pattern, did the examples he set them. All of his wealth was theirs ; all the
                            children conceived and born prior to the Christian conversion of their parents were equally
                            his. The apostles " left their nets and followed" his examples ; and thus a little community
                            was inaugurated where " none possessed ought that he called his own." Thus, Christian purity
                            was not <pb n="86" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 86 THE merely construed to be virginity of life, but was such
                            in very deed — is as really such today. The practice of virginity opened the way for the
                            equally ncessary, if not superior distinction of life, common property. Professedly
                            Christian friends, " let us reason together ;" realize the impropriety of bearing a title so
                            commonly misrepresented in our lives. Let us renounce the title, or accustom ourselves to
                            what it was in Jesus and disciples. The renunciation of the name Christian is not nearly as
                            terrible as is the shame of wearing a title that is disgraced by unchristian lives. Let us
                            accept the criticism, that only as our lives comport with Jesus' principles of life, are we
                            his disciples, or worthy to bear the Christian title. Then will shame rest on nearly every
                            church in our world, professing Christ,; aye, every church will want to hide its head with
                            more or less shame. Selfishness predominates almost universally, while the wealthy in power,
                            in talents, in money, secretly, if not openly, oppress and defraud their neighbors ! Why are
                            there rich and pool' in any church calling itself Christian ? Inasmuch as there exists
                            inequalities there is no Christ; no matter where the profession is made, nor who makes it.
                            The voice of The Christ sounds as full of rebuke against selfishness, and in favor of "
                            brotherly love, today as ever, and do we will to hear it ? And the voice sounds
                            significantly distinct to those making the greater boasts of their profession. Let us all
                            awake to greater righteousness in Christian equality; until before God in our secret lives,
                            and before men in our open professions, the name and the life are synonyms of Christianity.
                            And let the churches shame themselves for their lack, and do better. And let the " peculiar
                            people," who, having taken the initiative step in Christ-life—a thoroughly virgin practice
                            —" deal justly, walk humbly," in the most unselfish and equal manner; being " zealous in the
                            good works " comprehended by ana denning Brotherhood.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Any idols for sale?" TEIform="index"/>ANY IDOLS FOR SALE?</head><p TEIform="p">The Christian Register says: <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The Christian Recorder (Philadelphia), organ of the African Methodists, advises
                                    the pastors of poor churches, pressed by debt, not to go out begging. " The better
                                    plan by far would be to rally your own people, and get them to give to God the money
                                    they spend for naught, in the shape of tobacco, etc." Most of the " white folksey "
                                    will be quite prompt to applaud this advice ; but will it occur to them that the
                                    same principle applies all round? When the Unitarians, for instance, shall care
                                    enough for their own religious privileges and principles to practice some
                                    self-denial,and retrench some useless expenses for the sake of getting and doing
                                    higher good, there will be a great deal less begging by the weak churches, and a
                                    good deal more given by the strong ones. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Christian recorder (Philadelphia, Pennsylvania)" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit></p><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">So say we of New Churchmen, or of any kind of churchmen. We should like to rake
                                    the contract of running the church, Holy Catholic and otherwise, of all the names
                                    and kinds, for the sum which it costs our nation for tobacco. We would agree to
                                    build all the churches, pay all the ministers, defray all the incidental expenses,
                                    double the amount of contributions to all missions and benevolent objects, and
                                    support all the theological seminaries. If we could get such a contract for ten
                                    years we should be the richest men in America, if not in world. If men, good men,
                                    Christian men, would make as large sacrifices to the Lord as they do for satan,
                                    there would be no lack of means to do any work which is given to the Church to do.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New Jerusalem messenger" TEIform="index"/>New Jerusalem Messenger</bibl></cit></p><p TEIform="p">Come now, good, strong Shakers, let us all join in and say and act " Amen !" to such active,
                            judicious, and Godly conversion of means. When the period conies that we cannot, then we
                            will wish we had done just so; now that we can, let it not be said that we love any habit
                            better than we do the Lord, or those to whom we ought to be the means of conversion unto all
                            Godliness. How much true gospel would our useless, unchristian habits spread if these should
                            be sold? See if the grumblers of The Shaker's tax, or the same for any evangelical work, are
                            not those who are deeply interested in some selfish, worldly habit. " Sell all " (useless,
                            ungodly habits), " and buy" for ourselves and others true gospel principles and the power of
                            salvation,</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Best uses of money" TEIform="index"/>BEST USES OF MONEY</head><p TEIform="p">This greed for riches sets every man in business against his fellow. It piles up riches with
                            the few at the expense of the many. It assumes a thousand forms of benevolence. It assures
                            much upon the receipt of little, beginning in deceit, and generally ending in fraud and
                            disappointment. * * * Men, for popularity's sake, give their money to old church
                            institutions that have no need of it, and receive curses instead of blessings as a reward.
                            Men are asked to aid the Church, or to increase their annual pittance, and plead poverty,
                            and hard times, and dull business, but enter into some wild scheme to add to their already
                            large accumulations, and within a week, or a month, or a year, the fire, or the thief, or
                            fraud, or business reverses takes away ten times the amount they were asked to contribute to
                            the Church. There is a large truth in the above sentence of the N J. Messenger, and worthy
                            of heed by many readers of The Shaker. A few years hence and time and money will be among
                            the things of the past. The highest and best uses of money and talents will then appear the
                            very reverse of what we fear, even some of the most economical trustees hold them to be now.
                            The main body and heart of the people, called Shakers, are liberal, patriotic, anxious, and
                            confident that truth will prevail. And the heart of the people beats in unison with God. May
                            there be no selfish impediments in the way of spreading true Shaker principles, for they are
                            " the salt of the earth." ^</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>EDITORIAL NOTES</head><p TEIform="p">" The New Movement," by Spiritualists, is gaining approbation where it has heretofore been
                            ridiculed. We hailed the same as desirable ; yet wherein does a spiritualist differ from the
                            multitudes, excepting theologically ? And where is the theology, which, of itself, would
                            keep a church mouse from starving ? Spiritnal (?) friends, " except your righteousness of
                            life exceed " the lives of your brethren, orthodox, (?) your secession and " new movements"
                            are useless addenda. Nil nisi cruce, will meet your real needs. Can we not raise sufficient
                            enthusiasm for the Cause op The Shaker, to double our December issue ? Five cents each, from
                            our thousands of readers, would treble, and circulate the usual edition ! How many are
                            anxious, and willing to preach the gospel in this way— silently, saliently and successfully
                            ? The missionary box is now open. Who bids most ? Believing in our principles — living under
                            their excellent conditions — enjoying the good fruits of the gospel very measurably, we are
                            anxious everybody should know of them, and, according as they can afford, test them. We
                            believe the true spirit of inquiry is on its travels; and where sufficient zeal is aroused
                            anywhere, to demand an oral exposition of Shaker principles, such inquirers may
                            unhesitatingly address our valued " Corresponding Agents," or this office, for the desired
                            assistance. " A half a loaf is better than no bread;" and some self-denial is far better
                            salt — salvation — than despairing, unlimited indulgences. A GOOD Shaker in every household
                            would be a living, active reminder to the people of how Jesus lived when on earth. If this
                            cannot be, the next best movement is to place a copy of The Shaker there. "Let every one
                            preach "— and they can in this way. If we were a millionaire, two millions of households
                            should harbor a copy of The Shaker during 1877 ; and we promise to send a copy somewhere,
                            whenever its cost is received by us. " Millions for tribute !" Who will interest themselves?
                            The Christ life is the true Resurrection. Who would be " Children of the Resurrection " — "I
                            am the Resurrection," said Christ—may and can begin that resurrection in this life, with a
                            great deal of spiritual advancement and future gain. The fact that " the children of the
                            resurrection neither marry," etc., is not an argument against marriage, so much as it is an
                            invitation to be something higher, better, purer, more spiritual and resurrected than " the
                            children of the world." Those who are " miserable sinners " have no right to the title of
                            Christians, be they who they may. Christians are those who, naming themselves after Christ,
                            have departed from all iniquity. If Christ associated with publicans and sinners, it was to
                            reform them so they could justly wear his title; and when they would not part from their
                            sins, he tarried with them no longer. From the many exceptions which the clergy of this
                            country take to Prof. Huxley's theories, we presume there must be much true theology in his
                            ideas of science. We have learned that Doctors of Divinity, (?) Theological Students, and
                            Theological Seminaries dislike nothing more thau scientific truth, as illustrated in the
                            life of Jesus, the Christ, or the same, revealed to those who are infidels to the means
                            used, to the end that men may inter pret what scripture does not mean. And thus millions of
                            dollars are worse than wasted on such institutions and men.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>BOOK TABLE</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Family herald and weekly star" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Country gentleman" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">If any one doubts Canadian enterprise, let him secure a copy of 27(6 Family Herald and
                                Weekly Star, Montreal, Canada, the subscription of which is only $1.25, post-paid. We
                                used to think the Weekly Tribune New Fork, enterprising, but it is not equal for "common
                                humanity's" use to the Weekly Star. Send for a copy. The Country Gentleman, Albany, N.
                                Y., keeps ahead of any Agricultural, Horticultural or Stock publication in the world.
                                All the premiums which others offer, it uses in improving its usefulness; and this is
                                premium enough. It is a most valuable paper for farmers, gardeners, etc. Dr. B. M.
                                "Wade, of Watervliet Centre, N. Y., recommends, rather than deplores, the extensive
                                adulteration of coffee with chicory (cichorium intybun). Those who have been conscience
                                stricken by the fraud, may be relieved, and realize that the root is more valuable to
                                the human family than the berry which they have attempted to counterfeit.</p></div3></div2><pb n="87" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>SOCIETY RECORD</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="North Union, Ohio" TEIform="index"/>North Union, O. </head><p TEIform="p">North Union, Ohio. Anticipated development of stone quarry at this place looks like a
                                steady source of income to Society. Grist mill, built in 1843, has failed for years to
                                be more than a convenience, and sometimes only an expense, is now running by steam, and
                                likely to be appreciated as one of the best in the country. Nearly 1,000 bushels of oats
                                threshed. Early potatoes were a good crop ; late ones not so good — bugs, etc. Roots and
                                garden products coming in well. This Society has 1,350 acres of land. A dairy herd at
                                the centre family — forty cows — are unequaled in the State. For reasons, see cover, of
                                what Ohio Farmer says. </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watervliet, New York" TEIform="index"/>Watervliet, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Watervliet, N. Y. This Society closed its public services on October 1. On Sunday,
                                September 24, Geo. B. Amery, of White Water Village, Ohio, delivered, by invitation, a
                                stirring address to the people. We were sorry that the usual thousand of auditors was
                                not there. </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. Much has been said of Shaker speaking and singing at the Salt Point,
                                N. Y., Peace meeting, and there is no doubt much good was done by the attendance and
                                efforts of Elder F. W. Evans &amp; Co. The music, "Pray, ope the gates," being a New
                                Hampshire production, and highly complimented, we may as well consider that Enfield had
                                a representative spirit there. While Philadelphia was a failure, Salt Point was a grand
                                success ! Why? Worldly ambition was entirely obliterated in one of these places! Any
                                Societies, dedicated to human improvement, will do well to urge Mt. Lebanon to
                                participate. </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, Conn.</head><p TEIform="p">Enfield, Conn., sent a company of relations^to Mt. Lebanon and Watervliet, during
                                September, on a visit. This is the only company of our visitors that has met with us
                                during the year, and it numbered some very beautiful souls. One of these loved The
                                Shaker so well that she invariably "reads every word in it, advertisements on cover and
                                all!" Some of The Shaker's best friends are at Enfield, Conn. </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="White Water Village, Ohio" TEIform="index"/>White Water, O.</head><p TEIform="p">White Water Village, Ohio This Society is making a determined push to introduce their
                                seeds and other products into eastern markets, and to keep as shy of middle men as
                                possible —as grangers ! Who can blame them ? </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Canterbury, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Canterbury, N. H. (Shaker Village P. O.), beats the entire world in Washing Machines.
                                While we k»iew they were very good, we are joyful that they are ne plus ultra in their
                                line. We will welcome better, but advise all in need of laundry apparatus to address N
                                A. Briggs, as above. </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Groveland, New York" TEIform="index"/>Groveland, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Groveland, N. Y. (Sonyea, P. O.), has been blest in basket and in store, and we hope they
                                will have storage room to pack their crops, and health and help to secure all. The
                                people are worthy, and needy of much kindly sympathy in lifting a heavy load, unearned
                                by present residents. God helps them. Let the opulent imitate God. </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Philadelphia, Pennsylvania" TEIform="index"/>Philadelphia, Pennsylvania
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Philadelphia, Penn. This Society has been the recipient of very numerous visits from many
                                other Societies — Maine, New Hampshire, New York, Ohio, and yet continues to live.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spirit of the farm" TEIform="index"/>SPIRIT OF THE FARM</head><p TEIform="p">The Farm Implements. — Now that the crops are laid by, what about the farm implements? We are
                            not going to worry over them — why should we? The editor of this paper has plenty of friends
                            who make or sell agricultural implements, and why should he continue to run against their
                            interests, as he has long been doing, by urging the farmers to take care of their tools?
                            These people must all live, that is if they are not "middlemen," you know; and if a
                            neighboring religious editor tells the truth the signs of the times now promise very well
                            for their getting along — the implement makers and dealers, you understand. That editor says
                            he saw in a ride of ninety miles which he took through an average agricultural district the
                            following unhoused implements, namely: Forty-four ploughs, twenty-three harrows, seven
                            mowers, one reaper with beater and platforms as last used, wagons too numerous to count, and
                            in one instance a set of harness hanging on a fence. The ploughs were mostly standing in the
                            furrow where they had been last used. Such a sight as that gladdens the heart of the
                            itinerant manufacturer, and is an example which ought to be followed by every tiller of the
                            soil who wants a new set of implements. And now, dear farmers, such of you as are tired of
                            the old tools, let us give you a bit of advice. If you don't take it any better than advice
                            we have given you on former occasions, all right — it will be no great loss to us; so here
                            it is: Do not rub linseed oil on your fork and shovel and rake handles; do not paint your
                            ploughs and mowers; do not use any rust preventive on the iron and steel parts, and above
                            all, leave every thing out of doors. You really have no idea how quickly you will possess a
                            new set of tools, provided you have a balance at the bank. Only seven mowers and one reaper
                            out in the air in a stretch of ninety miles! And only one set of harness! Well, we will hope
                            for a better report from that section the next time our contemporary goes that way. Jour, of
                            Progress.</p></div2><div2 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Treatment of an unmanageable horse" TEIform="index"/>TREATMENT OF AN UNMANAGEABLE HORSE</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A beautiful and high-spirited horse would never allow a shoe to be put on his
                                    feet, or any person to handle his feet. In an attempt to shoe such a horse recently,
                                    he resisted all efforts, kicked aside everything but an anvil, and came nearly
                                    killing himself against that,and finally was brought back to the stable unshod. This
                                    defect was just on tlie eve of consigning him to the plough, where he might work
                                    barefoot, when an officer in our service, lately returned from Mexico, took a cord,
                                    about the size of a common bed-cord, put it in the mouth of the horse like a bit,
                                    and tied it tightly on the animal's head, passing his left ear under the string, not
                                    painfully tight, but tight enough to keep the ear down and the cord in its place.
                                    This done, he patted the horse gently on the side of the head and commanded him to
                                    follow ; and instantly the horse obeyed, perfectly subdued and as gentle and
                                    obedient as a well-trained dog, suffering his feet to be lifted with impunity,
                                    acting in all respects like an old stager. The gentleman who thus furnished this
                                    exceedingly simple means of subduing a very dangerous propensity, intimated that it
                                    is practiced in Mexico and South America in the management of wild horses. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New York commercial advertiser" TEIform="index"/>N. Y. Commercial Advertiser</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Land measure" TEIform="index"/>Land measure
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Land Measure.—We give the following table, under the impression that some of our friends on
                            the farm may find it useful, should they desire a simple method of arriving at the exact
                            size of fields or patches under cultivation. 5 yards wide by 968 long, contain 1 acre. 10 "
                            " 484 " " " 20 " " 242 " " " 40 " " 121 80 " " 60^ " " " 70 " " 69^ " 60 feet " 726 " " "
                            110 " " 369 120 " " 363 " " " 220 " " 198 " " " 240 " " 181J^ " " " 440 " " 99 " " " Ibid.
                            "Latin and Greek are all right," said a Delaware farmer, but give me a man who can plow
                            round an apple tree without touching the roots." The following, from The Prairie Farmer, is
                            worthy of a place among the writings of Franklin. The sayings of "Poor Richard," who " paid
                            too much for his whistle," are equaled by the writer of —</p></div2><div2 type="story" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Boy who had a patch on both knees, and gloves on" TEIform="index"/>THE BOY WHO HAD A PATCH ON
                            BOTH KNEES, AND GLOVES ON</head><p TEIform="p">When I was a boy it was my fortune to breathe, for a long time, what some writers call the
                            "bracing air of poverty." My mother — light lie the turf upon the gentle form which once
                            enclosed her strong and gentle spirit—was what is commonly called an ambitious woman; for
                            that quality which overturns thrones and supplants dynasties, finds a legitimate sphere in
                            the humblest abode that the shadow of poverty ever darkened. The struggle between the wish
                            to keep up appearances, and the pinching gripe of necessity, produced endless shifts and
                            contrivances at which, were they told, some would smile, and some to whom they would recall
                            their own experiences, would sigh. But let me not disturb that veil of oblivion which
                            shrouds from profane eyes the hallowed mysteries of poverty. On one occasion it was
                            necessary to send me upon an errand to a neighbor in better circumstances than ourselves,
                            and to whom it was necessary that I Should be presented in the best possible aspect. Great
                            pains were accordingly taken to give a smart appearance to my patched and dilapidated
                            wardrobe, and to conceal the rents and chasms which the envious tooth of time had made in
                            them, and by way of throwing over my equipment a certain savor and sprinkling of gentility,
                            my red and toil-hardened hands were inclosed in the unfamiliar casing of a pair of gloves,
                            which had belonged to my mother in. days when her years were fewer and her heart lighter. I
                            sallied forth on my errand, and on my way encountered a much older and bigger boy, who
                            evidently belonged to a family which had all their own dragging poverty, and none of our
                            uprising wealth of spirit. His rags fairly fluttered in the breeze; his hat was constructed
                            on the most approved principle of ventilation, and his shoes, from their venerable
                            antiquity, might have been deemed a pair of fossil shoes — the very ones in which Shem
                            shuffled into the ark. He was an impudent varlet, with a daredevil swagger in his gait, an
                            "I'm as good as you" leer in his eye — the very whelp to throw a stone at a well-dressed
                            horseman because he was well-dressed; to tear a boy's ruffles because he was clean. As soon
                            as he saw me, his eyes detected the practical inconsistencies which characterized my
                            costume, and taking me by the shoulders, turning me round with no gentle hand and surveying
                            me from head to foot, he exclaimed, with a scornful laugh of derision, "A patch on both
                            knees, and gloves on! " I still recall the sting of wounded feeling which shot through me at
                            these words. To parody a celebrated line of the immortal Tuscan — "That day I wore my gloves
                            no more." But the lesson thus rudely enforced, sank deep into my mind, and, in after life, I
                            have had frequent occasion to make a practical application of the words of my ragged friend,
                            when I have observed the practical inconsistencies which so often mark the conduct of
                            mankind. When, for instance, I see parents carefully providing for the ornamental education
                            of their children, furnishing them with teachers in music, dancing and drawing, but giving
                            no thought to that moral and religious training from which the true dignity and permanent
                            happiness of life alone can come; never teaching them habits of self-sacrifice, and
                            self-discipline, and control, but rather by example instructing them in evil speaking; in
                            uncharitableness; in envy, and in falsehood, I think with a sigh of the patch on both knees,
                            and gloves on. When I see a family in a cold, selfish solitude, not habitually warming their
                            house with the glow of happy faces, but lavishing that which should furnish ¦ the
                            hospitality of a whole year upon the profusion of a single night, I think of the patch on
                            both knees, and gloves on. When I see a house profusely furnished with sumptuous furniture,
                            rich curtains, and luxurious carpets, but with no books, or none but a few tawdry annuals, I
                            am reminded of the patch on both knees, and gloves on. When I see the public men cultivating
                            exclusively those qualities which win a way to office, and neglecting those which will
                            qualify them to fill honorably the posts to which they aspire, I recall the patch on both
                            knees and gloves on. When I see men sacrificing peace of mind and health of body to the
                            insane pursuit of wealth, living in ignorance of the character of their children who are
                            growing up around them, cutting themselves off from the highest and purest pleasures of
                            their natures, and so preverting their humanity that that which was sought as a means
                            insensibly conies to be followed as an end, I say to myself, a patch on both knees, and
                            gloves on. When I see thousands squandered for selfishness and ostentation, and nothing
                            bestowed for charity; when I see fine ladies bestained and bejeweled, cheapening the toils
                            of dressmakers, and with harsh words embittering the bitter bread of dependence; when I see
                            the poor turned away from proud houses, where the crumbs of tables would be to them a feast,
                            I think of the patch on both knees, with gloves on.</p></div2><pb n="88" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Glory be to God" TEIform="index"/>GLORY BE TO GOD</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Randlett, Timothy" TEIform="persName"/>Elder TIMOTHY RANDLETT</byline><p TEIform="p">Enfield, N. H. Oh Glory be to God Most High, For in Thy majesty Thou dost reign triumphant in
                            heaven, and o'er the earth. Glory be to Thy name evermore, Thou hast caused Thy light, in
                            splendor bright, to shine on earth, — as in heaven, so on earth, so on earth.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beautiful things" TEIform="index"/>BEAUTIFUL THINGS</head><p TEIform="p">Beautiful faces are those that wear— It matters little if dark or fairWhole-souled honesty
                            printed there. Beautiful eyes are those that show, Like crystal panes where hearth-fires
                            glow, Beautiful thoughts that burn below. Beautiful lips are those whose words Leap from the
                            heart like songs of birds, Yet whose utterance prudence girds. Beautiful hands are those
                            that do Work that is earnest and brave and true, Moment by moment the long day through.
                            Beautiful feet are those that go On kindly ministries to and froDown lowliest ways, if God
                            wills it so. Beautiful shoulders are those that bear Ceaseless burdens of homely care With
                            patient grace and daily prayer. Beautiful lives are those that bless— Silent rivers of
                            happiness, Whose hidden fountains but few may guess. Beautiful twilight, at set of sun,
                            Beautiful goal, with race well won, Beautiful rest, with work well done. Beautiful graves,
                            where grasses creep, Where brown leaves fall, where drifts lie deep, Over worn out hands —
                            Oh, beautiful sleep !</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allerton, Ellen P." TEIform="persName"/>Ellen P. Allerton</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The superstitious see horrid spectres and hideous phantoms in their sleep..." TEIform="index"/>The superstitious see horrid spectres and hideous phantoms in their sleep...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The superstitious see horrid spectres and hideous phantoms in their sleep; their bewildered
                            imagination creates tortures by which they are crushed and torn; they fancy they hear
                            commands as dreadful as they are whimsical, and which they are constrained to obey. A
                            superstitious person dreads his fancied God, and yet fancies that he finds refuge in his
                            bosom. The fears derived from superstition are more causeless and stupid than those derived
                            from any other source.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Plutarch" TEIform="persName"/>Plutarch</byline></div2><div2 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sensible notice" TEIform="index"/>A SENSIBLE NOTICE</head><p TEIform="p">Le Derby, a French Journal, gives the following as a pr;nted notice which the Minister of
                            Agriculture has caused to be posted in all the crossways of the forestal domains: MINISTRY
                            OF AGRICULTURE. This placard is placed under the protection of good sense and public
                            decency. HEDGEHOG. Lives on mice, small rodents, slugs and grubs (vers blanch, animals
                            hurtful to agriculture. Don't kill the hedgehog. TOAD. Farm assistant: destroys from twenty
                            to thirty insects an hour. Don't kill the toad. MOLE. Is continually destroying grubs (vers
                            hlancs), larvae, palmer worms, and insects injurious to agriculture. No trace of vegetation
                            is ever found in its stomach. Does more good than harm. Don't hill the mole. MAY BUG AND ITS
                            LARVA OR GRUB. Mortal enemy of agriculture ; lays from seventy to eighty eggs. Kill the May
                            hug. BIRDS. Each department loses several millions annually through insects. Birds are the
                            only enemies able to contend against them victoriously. They are great caterpillar killers
                            and agricultural assistants. Children, don't disturb their nests.</p></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="North Union, Ohio" TEIform="index"/>North Union, Ohio
                        </head><p TEIform="p">North Union, O. High credit is given of Elder G. B. Avery's public address at this place on
                            Aug. 13. The assemblies on Sunday have very materially increased numerically since. The
                            Shakers met with the "Men of the Forests," on 30th August, in Burgess Grove; did several
                            handsome sentiments and sung some delightful songs among others " Glorious Day." Mutual
                            Criticism : We incline to a dread of criticism upon our conduct, either from a knowledge of
                            our defects or from a suspicion of others'injustice. That the inclination is, to say the
                            least, an ignoble one, no noble-minded person will dispute. W-herever there is the power of
                            persons or organizations to bear mutual criticism, holding strictly to the rule of " neither
                            giving nor taking offense," an exceeding greatness of blessing must derive. Let
                            organizations try it on such principle. Let families try it. Whoever keeps in good temper
                            most strictly is the better Christian; and who does not " will learn something to his
                            advantage." The above is a work of interest, published Socialist, Wallingford, Conn. Price
                            25 cents.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>EVERGREEN SHORES</head><p TEIform="p">Notice is given, with some very affectionate comments indeed, of some of the dear, departed
                            aged. Among the very bright stars that have set in this world, to rise on the " evergreen
                            shores " of " the better land," few have surpassed in virtue and value, some we mention in
                            this issue. To say that we love them—their life and Christ-like demeanor—but faintly
                            impresses the general reader. Did we not, as gospel relation — having no bloodties to speak
                            of — have_ such immovable faith in fact of their removal to brighter, happier spheres, we
                            should very much mourn their departure. Our farewells are kind, yet they are realized by the
                            pure in heart beyond our expression.</p><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rubush, George" TEIform="index"/>George Rubush
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At White Water Village, O., <persName reg="Rubush, George" TEIform="persName">George Rubush</persName>. June
                                9, 1876, aged 76 years. [Should have been reported earlier.]</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Williams, Anna" TEIform="index"/>Anna Williams
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Mount Lebanon, N. Y., <persName reg="Williams, Anna" TEIform="persName">Anna Williams</persName>,
                                September 7,1876, aged 93 years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Collins, Lucenia" TEIform="index"/>Lucenia Collins
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Hancock, Mass., September 23,1876, <persName reg="Collins, Lucenia" TEIform="persName">Lucenia
                                Collins</persName>, aged 82 years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Smith, Max" TEIform="index"/>Max Smith
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At North Union, O., September 16, 1876, <persName reg="Smith, Max" TEIform="persName">Max Smith</persName>,
                                aged 48 years.</p></div3></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>