<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2605" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">20</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">East Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">26</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">5</biblScope><date value="18960501" TEIform="date">May 1896</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">73-88</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="26" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="5" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
THE
MANIFESTO
   1896.
A CONCISE HISTORY OF THE
SHAKERS.
Just Published.     The book is printed
with large type  and on excellent paper.
It contains  130 pages and has
ILLUSTRATIONS
of the Shakers and their
A Visit to the
of EAST CANTERBURY,   N. H.
BY
LLOYD H. CHANDLER. U. S. N
Liberally Illustrated with half tone
pictures of persons and places.
The Village of EAST CANTERBURY
is situated in one of the lovliest spots of
New Hampshire, and is high enough to
overlook the surrounding country.
Price,  15 cts.
AUTHORIZED RULES
OF
THE   SHAKER   COMMUNITY.
The religiousJbasis of the  Order must
be a foundation resting on the principle of
righteousness, which principle is God.
"United   Society    of   Believers"     This should rule the life of the individ
It treats of the Rise and Progress of the ual for the Protection of his own soul, for
Society, together with the   general   Prin- the peace of the family and as an evidence
ciples of the Faith and Testimony.            of his upright standing before the world.
Price 50 cts.                                              Price> 10 ctsThe  work  gives  quite an extended account of the  Several SOCIETIES, their
organization and general management.
Price,  50 cts.
Address   H. C. Blinn,
East Canterbury, N. H.
A SUMMARY VIEW
OF  THE
 CHURCH,
OR
MAY
MILLENNIAL
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
Ex-President Harrison's next article in
his series in The Ladies' Home Journal will tell
what it means to be President of the United'
States. He will outline the President'spow er
his duties and how he discharges them; the
trials and annoyances to which he is put, and
show what the central idea of the President
is and how he tries to carry it out. General
Harrison also explains what relation each
Cabinet officer holds to the President, ami
tells of his own relations with his Cabinet
when he was President.
With the exception of the book-buying residents of large cities, comparatively few people know how to obtain a book that they may
wish to purchase. Every newspaper office
knows how frequently letters come asking
"How can I get a copy of such and sush a
book, published by so and so?" As an accom.
modation to its large constituency of readers,
The Sunday School Times has just announced that it will supply them, at the publishers'
advertised prices, postage free, with any
proper books, religious or secular, that are in
the market. This should free the readers of
that paper, at least, from further trouble in
book-baying.
JOHN D. WATTLES & CO.
1031 Walnut St., Philadelphia, Pa.
The old saying that "One man's meat is
another man's poison," is aptly illustrated in
a true story entitled, "All a Matter of Taste,"
in the April number of "Chatterbox." Both
little and big folks will find instruction and
amusement in the doings of an African king,
who liked to eat ants. "The Treasures of San
Antonio," an illustrated story of adventure in
search of buried treasures, by F. Hussell, will
prove of absorbing interest to the youths of
the family, while the little ones are sure to
find delight in "The Young Wanderers," the
story of a brother and sister who got lost, and
instruction in a sketch about "A Bird's Cradle," that tells all about the nests of different
birds. "Old Customs of St. Valentine's Day,"
with illustrations, will interest every member of the family from grandma to the toddlers, and "The Story of Nelson," and a bit of
natural history, entitled "The Games of Swallows," will catch the fancy of the boys. Another touch of history is about "The Lily of
the Valley," and with its charming illustrations, is evidently aimed to please not only
the little miss who is still absorbed in her
dolls but also her big sisters.
Little boys and big bojs, and the girls as
well, will be touched by the story of "The
Faithful Dogs" and how they saved a little
girl from a poisonous snake. In addition to
all this there are poems, illustrations, a story
of African adventure, fables, puzzles, a
frontispiece in ten colors and in fact a feast of
good things of a variety to tickle the intellectual palate of every member of the family
from the tot in pantalettes to the "Totterer"
on crutches. Jn its April number "Chatterbox" more than substantiates its claim to the
foremost rank among periodicals for young
and old. ("Chatterbox," 50 cents a year or
3 months for 10 cents; Estes & Lauriat, Publishers, Boston, Mass.)
The Outlook Company has arranged with
Mr. Justin McCarthy, the famous historian,
novelist, and political leader, to write for publication in THK OUTLOOK, a popular Life of
RIGHT Hon. WILLIAM E. GLADSTONE. Mr.
McCarthy has had an intimate personal and
political acquaintance with Mr. Gladstone
for many years, and is peculiarly fitted to undertake this work. The personal and social
sides of Mr. Gladstone's life will be thrown
into strong relief. Mr. McCarthy's skill in
graphic narrative and in imparting to history
the attractive qualities that many readers
look for in fiction only, are well illustrated
in his book, "The.History of Our Own Times.'
Few books of our generation have had a
wider reading on either side of the Atlantic.
The Outlook's Life of Gladstone will be profusely illustrated with portraits, reproductions of drawings, and other pictorial material gathered from many sources. It will form
a principal feature of The Outlook's Illustrated Magazine Numbers during 1897.
The "Lee of Virginia" series of illustrated
articles is continued in the April number of
Frank Leslie's Popular Monthly. The present chapter, the third of the series, is devoted to the early life of Robert E. Leehis boyhood, his West Point training, his marriage
with Mary Randolph Custis, residence at Arlington, and over thirty years' service in the
United States Army, including the brilliant
campaign in Mexico, where he won rapid promotion and the cordial admiration of his
great commander, General Winfield Scott.
The illustrations and portraits accompanying
"Lee of Virginia" are especially interesting
this month. A charming personal description
of Mile. Emma Calve, the queen of the opera
season, is given, together with some of her
Paris portraits, never before published, and
numerous "snap shot" glimpses of her "farm"
life at Cabrieres, in the south of France.
Other illustrated articles are "Feasts of Labor," "Touraine and its Castles," "Man and
the Animals," "Birds of Paradise," "The Lakedwellers of Venezuela" and "Air Ships."
The new serial novel of New York society, by
Margaret Lee, opens brightly in this number.
Amongst the short stories is a delightful one
entitled "The Bride," by Mrs. Launt Thompson. The poems are by Ella Higginson, Alfred Austin, Clinton Scollard and Henry
Tyrrell.
The Journal ov Hygeio Therapy. March.
Contents. The Science of Life; The Massage
Treatment; Nerve Harmony; Anti-Vaccination; Our Work goes on; An Important Decision; Disease; Harmonial Philosophy; Eating
in Relation to Sleeping;   etc., etc.
Dr. T. V. Gifford & Co., Kokomo, Ind.--><pb n="73" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Autobiography of Chas. D. Hampton of Union Village, Ohio, no. 4" TEIform="index"/>AUTOBIOGRAPHY OF CHAS. D. HAMPTON OF UNION VILLAGE, O. NO. 4.</head><p TEIform="p">I CAN well remember when the idea of the spiritual world and change from time to eternity was
                            of all ideas the most gloomy. Dreary, cold and helpless, death looked to me as the crowning
                            horror of existence, a fatal plunge into the unknown abyss,the untried yawning gulf of
                            hopeless uncertainty. Such was the influence of early and improper education and I shall
                            ever feel thankful to that kind Providence which threw in my pathway a rational idea of God
                            and the spirit world. By this means I have been ever since entirely released from all fear
                            of death or the consequences of death, and looked upon God as a kind, benevolent Father, and
                            the Spirit world as a sweet, tranquil home. This view of the subject smoothes the asperity
                            of feeling when called to meet the loss of friends. Let us therefore take a kind farewell of
                            our parent, our brother or our sister for the present, confidently resting in the assurance
                            that they are in active usefulness in a sphere precisely adapted to their condition of mind
                            or mental development. Not dead or sleeping, but alive and in the full enjoyment of all
                            their powers. My circumstances in early life cast me on ground that compelled me to feel
                            keenly, on a certain occasion, the frailty of human nature, as it exhibited itself in the
                            actions of a Quaker preacher. I was constrained to look deeper into religion than I had
                            intended, and was brought into a condition to examine the foundation on which my religious
                            faith was grounded. This examinMAY, <pb n="74" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 74 THE MANIFESTO. ation conducted
                            sincerely, brought to my mind other views than those in which I was educated, and produced a
                            general change in all my religions sentiments. In order to give an idea of the revolutionary
                            movement of mind, I must relate a little occurrence which took place soon after my removal
                            to Ohio. I will set down "naught in malice" as I have long since outlived all its
                            consequences so far as regards the temporal loss sustained by it, and 1 look upou the one
                            who injured me, as my brother man, altho lost to honor and integrity. When I concluded to
                            move to Ohio, I sold my carriage ami bought another of smaller size, in its stead. A few
                            weeks after we reached Ohio, I was invited to attend a Quaker meeting. A quaint, simple,
                            guileless looking man was also in attendance. He was a preacher and to all appearance a man
                            of honesty and integrity. Indeed, I felt moved by his pathetic appeal, and on returning home
                            after the meeting was surpi'ised at the arrival of this preacher accompanied by a friend.
                            After some general conversation I found that the object of their visit was to purchase my
                            carriage. I did not like to dispose of it, but as "Poverty's cold wind and pinching rain
                            Beat keen and heavy on our tender years." after some mild persuasion I consented to sell it.
                            The preacher took the carriage and passed me the sum agreed upon and went his way. A few
                            days later on attempting to purchase another carriage, I found to my astonishment that the
                            money I had received from tlu preacher was almost worthless, being notes on a bank which had
                            failed a few days before this date. Being thus introduced to Quaker diplomacy in money
                            matters, I tried to force him to remunerate, but he had the advantage of me, and I could do
                            nothing with him. "I was a stranger and he took me." My confidence failed and my dependence
                            on man went out forever. I was without friends in a strange country and the possibility of
                            want of bread staring me in the face. I became wreckless to everything serious and devoted
                            my time and talents to making money. I pursued this course for two or three years until the
                            writings of Swedenborg forcibly arrested my attention. My mind was held and caused to
                            reflect seriously. My downward career was sensibly checked. His clear and beautiful
                            expositions of Scripture, his moving "memorable relations" with his luminous and consistent
                            idea of God, and the vivid and living view of the spiritual world, all struck me as true and
                            reliable, and from this spiritual shock I have never recovered. All taste for my former life
                            vanished and became in my estimation as dross and mental folly, to say the least. I became
                            comparatively thoughtful and a marked change came over me. I examined the doctrines of every
                            religious sect within the compass of my <pb n="75" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 75 knowledge,
                            and sought dilligently for the truth. In the progress of this search a measure of light
                            broke upon my understanding and enabled me in some degree to comprehend the standing of the
                            professing world. In seeking Lo he instructed by their priests and enlightened by their
                            preachers, a similar fate awaited me as came to the lot of Rasselas when he inquired for
                            knowledge of the insane philosopher, for I found to my sorrow, the more I listened to their
                            inconsistent notions the less I knevy. Their irrational dogmas cast no light on a spiritual
                            existence, afforded no rational explanation of man's final destiny. Their ideas of a future
                            state were vague and inconclusive and finally they offered me no ground for establishing in
                            my soul a rational faith in Christianity according to their views. Few possessed a full and
                            unwavering confidence in the hope of immortality, Instead of a sound faith in regard to
                            Christianity, the most important of all subjects, I found a stupid kind of traditional
                            hope,to-day strong, tomorrow doubtful. The popular religion of the day was a genteel,
                            dressed up thing, which it was unfashionable not to possess or in which not to have an
                            interest. The heavens of this popular religion were dark 'and gloomy. Creeds and confessions
                            of faith are the mouldy and withered monuments of an age of bigotry and ignorance. Man in
                            his original standing is a noble and dignified being, but he is now found the willing slave
                            of sensuality, as his passions are leading, him into all manner of folly. Under the
                            influence of these imperious masters he thinks feebly and acts as though paralyzed. He
                            trembles at the thought of death, and his dying hope is to escape the vengeance of an angry
                            God. This is a true outline of the fact, as it commonly exists under the character of
                            religion, among the mass of mankind and such it must continue to be until the light of
                            eternal truth enables them to perceive purer ideas of God and his providence. When the time
                            comes for them to be enlightened, they will be led to the fountains of living waters where
                            the soul may drink and be filled, and made to rest in quietness and assurance forever. Made
                            to know that it belongs to the family of Christ and has entered through the gate into the
                            city, and is no longer a stranger but a fellow citizen of the household of God. We know that
                            our friends who are gone from among us are still existing in a beautiful spirit world of
                            which this earthly home is but a faint representative. Existing not in intangible and
                            floating vapors, but in real, substantial human forms to be seen and conversed with in
                            freedom and ease. Possessing every faculty for thought and reflection which they ever did,
                            and greatly improved in all that can render human society pleasing. These ideas in our minds
                            are indeed fixed facts, established and indubitably proven to our full and perfect
                            satisfaction. Our acquaintance with that world of beauty, and our just apprehension of the
                            true relation existing between our world and that, constitutes in no small degree, the joy
                            and happi- <pb n="76" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 76 THE MANIFESTO. ness of our present probationary state and
                            opens a wide field of rational delight to animate and enliven us on our checkered journey
                            through the wilderness of Time. This view of the subject, with a contrite spirit and a
                            conduct consistent with all the requirements of known duty, disarms death of its sting and
                            robs the grave of its victory. It opens to the soul the bright gleamings of the brilliant
                            light of its future home, and the tranquil peace and increasing joys which must flow from
                            congenial associations and harmonious social organizations. Think for a moment how the pain
                            of separation must be modified with a view of facts as above stated, before the mind; how
                            the rough edges of existence and the cruel asperity of disappointment sink into comparative
                            trifles when calmly contemplated from this point of view. When we consider our faith in all
                            its immense variety of bearing, we are lost in thankfulness to a kind, benevolent Father,
                            solicitous for our good and can only give the most willing obedience to the requisitions of
                            duty, and in a humble reception of the many proofs of his kindness and mercy. From the
                            clouds of gloom and darkness we are now free, and forever free, and our mental horizon is
                            bounded only by the unlimited sphere of boundless good, and our spirits invigorated by the
                            open, bright and exhaustless fields of infinite progression. An everlasting approximation
                            toward this divine fountain of good, which finds full exercise in the duties of active
                            benevolence and the virtues which ennoble the human soul. (To be continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Belief v.s. intelligent faith" TEIform="index"/>BELIEF V.s. INTELLIGENT FAITH.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo G." TEIform="persName"/>By Alonzo G. Hollister.</byline><p TEIform="p">REV. JOHN CUMMIN GS, in his "Last Warning Cry," p. 219, says "For six thousand years the hope
                            of perfect happiness has burned in human hearts, like a lamp in a gloomy sepulchre, only to
                            be extinguished, to be relighted and to be extinguished again. I look for no perfect
                            happiness in this world. If any man thinks he sees it in the distance, he may depend it is
                            but the mirage in the desert, which deceives. * * * I have no hope of perfect holiness in
                            this life. * * * I believe in it as a future attainment. To strive for it is our duty. Be ye
                            holy for I am holy! The expectation that you will ever attain to it upon earth in this
                            economy, is to expect that you will be as gods, and that you will cease to be men." "To the
                            very last pulse in your being, or beat of your heart, you will be constrained to feel '0
                            wretched man that I am. There is a law in my members warring against the law of my spirit,
                            so that the good I would do, I do not, and the evil I would not do, that I do!' Ascetics
                            have fasted, monks have worn sackcloth, nuns have surrounded their bodies with spikes and
                            needles and pins and thorns, and all have tried by mortifying the flesh to <pb n="77" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 11 mortify what is a very different thing, its lusts and
                            passions ; and they have found that th' punishment of nerve and flesh and blood, is not, and
                            from the necessity of the case never can be, the extirpation of evil passions and a carnal
                            nature. Perfect holiness has never been actualized on earth except in the Son of God." That
                            the foregoing medley of truth and error exhibits the real state of worldly professors of the
                            Christian name, there can be no reasonable doubt. The soul-chilling, antichristian doctrine
                            of the churches, that no one in this life, not even a Christian can do the good he wishes to
                            do, nor abstain from the evil he wishes not to do, or in other words that it is impossible
                            to live on earth a sinless life, bears a lie on the face of it, and is indefinitely
                            prolonging disappointment to all who believe such deceptive teaching. To keep the law of
                            God, perfectly, requires the whole strength of soul, mind and body, and no sane person can
                            put forth all his power to accomplish that which he believes to be an impossibility. Said
                            doctrine, by destroying all faith in the possibility even with supernatural aid, to overcome
                            opposing evils, so paralyzes the will that its receiver fails to perform the good within his
                            power, and is therefore hindered from establishing by well-doing, the only conditions upon
                            which the desired happiness can be secured. This is not the state of Christ's true
                            followers, for it was said of him "He shall save his people from their sins." People who are
                            saved from sin, are not sinners. If they have been sinners, they must confess and repent,
                            and thenceforth abstain from every evil work, as an indispensable condition of discipleship.
                            Jesus the truth-teller says, "He that sins is the servant of sin" which is self-evident, and
                            as "No man can serve two masters," it is also evident that a servant of sin, can not be at
                            the same time, a servant of perfect holiness, the only ground on which perfect happiness is
                            predicable. The Apostle tells us "He that sinneth is of the devil,"and hath not seen Christ,
                            nor known him." Hence the term ''Christian sinners" is as contradictory, as to say "honest
                            hypocrites." Those who try to serve two masters by professing to follow Christ while
                            continuing in the corrupt life of the world, make sad work of religion. The hope of perfect
                            happiness burns in their "hearts like a lamp in a gloomy sepulchre, only to be extinguished,
                            as of course should be expected, so long as affects resemble their cause, or so long as God
                            and his Christ are just, and their word is relied upon as true, so long as the eternal life
                            of the heavens, differs from the carnal life of the world. What just cause have those who
                            reject the life of the spirit, practiced and taught by its true exemplars, Jesus Christ and
                            his chosen Apostles, to expect the perfect happiness of children of God, or children of the
                            spirit. What right to the perfect reward have those who [profess inability to live the
                            perfect lifeinability to keep the commands of the Teacher they profess to follow, who said
                            "Be ye perfect, even as your Father in heaven is perfect." <pb n="78" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 78 THE
                            MANIFESTO. People who neither enter into the great Exemplar's teachings themselves, nor
                            suffer others to enter. And why unable? Because they do not truly believe in him tiny
                            profess to follow, as their practice, which is the only test of belief, proves. They do not
                            truly believe in him who says "AH things are possible to him that believeth." "All things"
                            here does not mean miracles and prodigies which involve a suspension of law, and the
                            established relation between cause and effect, but all things right and necessary to the
                            truest welfare of the believer. Although spoken with immediate reference to the spiritual
                            power which heals the body, it has equal application to that Divine power which liberates
                            and heals the soul. Hence it includes the possibility of obeying all the commandments of God
                            to him individuallythe possibility of doing ever the good one is commanded, or that he would
                            or ought to do, and abstaining from the evil, which he ought not to do. If this was
                            impossible, it would be wrong to require it, nor could there be just condemnation for not
                            attaining thereto. When Jesus said "Whosoever he be of you that forsaketh not all that he
                            hath, he can not be my disciple," he spoke either the truth or falsehood. If he spoke truth,
                            how can those who steadily reject the terms, reasonably hope for the reward promised? It is
                            true that self torture inflicted on nerves of flesh and blood, or any abuse of the body, can
                            not mortify the depraved nature of the flesh. But "the cross of Christ," which is
                            self-denial in the mind, faithfully and continuously borne, will mortify all lusts and
                            sinful passions, which degrade and tyrannize over the soul. True Christian self-denial in
                            obedience to the spiritual light nowr coming into the world, will accomplish what the
                            unaided ingenuity of man never could, that is, the eradication of all carnal and sinful
                            desires from the soul and thereby effect the destruction while still on earth, of that "body
                            of death," of which sin and sinful desires are the sole cause. Jesus said "Whosoever will
                            come after me, let him deny himself, and take up his cross and follow me. For whosoever will
                            save his life (by disobeying his Teacher,) shall lose it, but whosoever shall lose his life
                            for my sake and the gospel, the same shall save it." Whoso then will follow Jesus Christ,
                            must go in the way of self-denial, keep his commandments, and "Walk in his steps." If the
                            perfect life, and its resulting happiness can not be realized in this economy, how and when
                            will it be realized, or what cause to expect it hereafter ? Jesus tells us "Every one that
                            is perfect shall be as his master," or Teacher. This, and the command "Be ye perfect," shows
                            that Jesus not only deemed perfection possible for his disciples, but that he required and
                            expected it. To suppose that he did not, is, as the Apostle says, to make him a liar, and
                            his sayings, idle words. Hence it is a reasonable inference that if Jesus actualized perfect
                            holiness <pb n="79" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 79 on earth, his true disciples are empowered
                            to do the same. After having been purified and made perfectly holy in body and spirit, by
                            the washing of regeneration and the daily cross, they have perfect peace, signified in the
                            promise, "In me ye shall have peace," and a happiness that the world can neither give,
                            enjoy, nor take from them. If to expect these results from fulfilling the prescribed
                            conditions, is to expect that we shall be as gods, such expectations being founded not on
                            mystery nor miracle, but upon the ascertained relations of cause and effect, should be
                            deemed neither extravagant nor improbable. But as only he who lives the life of a doctrine,
                            or system, can by any possibility so understand it as to become a true teacher thereof, it
                            appears both extravagant and presumptuous for people reputed intelligent to teach in
                            Christ's name, who never lived nor truly believed in the life that he taught. Every kind,
                            degree, and quality of life, must produce fruit of a corresponding kind and quality, and we
                            have no rational evidence that putting off the mortal body, will change the life, or the
                            fruit of its tenant. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes referring to the early history of the shakers in the United States" TEIform="index"/>Notes Referring to the Early History of the Shakers in the United States.</head><p TEIform="p">WHILE in vision, Mother Ann had seen the people at Harvard Mass., and while living at
                            Watervliet she sent Daniel Wood as a missionary to the people who were under the charge of
                            Shadrach Ireland. His mission began in an awakened spirit and with light from God, but
                            unfortunately ended in the flesh. Some of his followers, however, were still looking for
                            advanced light, and were not, as yet, wholly swallowed up in the world. In this company of
                            interested souls was Abel Jewett, Zacheus Stevens and Beulah Bert. Daniel was a faithful
                            minister to this people, but as they had been deceived by Ireland, they were very cautious
                            in moving unless they could see a pretty sure foundation. Beulah's parents were followers of
                            Ireland and as she was born under the sanction of a spiritual marriage, she was one of the
                            holy children. She seemed to have inherited a religious quality of mind and was very plain
                            in her attire. When Mother Ann came to Harvard, several of these disciples accepted her
                            spiritual gift, consecrated their lives to God, and followed hei in the regeneration.
                            Elizabeth Jewett says she was at the Square House in Harvard when a furious mob surrounded
                            it. Some of them acted more like brute beasts than ike men. One coarse fellow kicked her
                            most inhumanly and broke several <pb n="80" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 80 THE MANIFESTO. of her ribs while
                            she was on her knees in prayer. Many were kneeling around the Elders through the hope of
                            protecting them from violence. Eunice Wilds was the daughter of Elijah Wilds and was one of
                            the company that Mother Ann addressed in reference to the little idols or foolish toys that
                            they had in possession. Mother said that such things would shut out the gift of God. Eunice
                            had a severe cross to sacrifice these things but her great love for Mother Aun induced her
                            to do it. This enabled her to bear persecution from her younger companions, who were not
                            believers, and still continued to wear their jewelry. Father James called revivals the
                            prolonging of God's mercy, "They are the operation of the spirit of God; they are sent to
                            keep the people from sinking into total forgetfulness of the things of God. Where Christ is,
                            there is power to put away sin, and where there is no power to put away sin, there is no
                            Christ. No souls can be saved unless they confess and forsake all sin." "See how the mercy
                            of God has come to you, and shown you the way of life and salvation. If you repent and obey
                            the gospel it will make you thankful, joyful and sorrowful. The sound of repentance will yet
                            be the most joyful sound ever heard by mortals. AVhen we have a gift of God, then we know
                            that we can do the will of God. ' Sarah and Nathan Kendall make a journey to Watervliet from
                            Harvard. I often made this journey on horseback, a distance of two hundred miles. Much of
                            the road was through dense woods. This being new the stamps of large trees and underbrush
                            were often left directly in the path. In the winter we could go with a sleigh, but even this
                            was very dangerous, as the roads were often so drifted with snow that it was difficult to
                            proceed. I frequently was obliged to get out and walk as the horse plunged into places of
                            deep snow and water. Sometimes my brother Nathan would take a side-saddle, which we could
                            use if the snow left us, before we were ready to return. On one of these trips I was obliged
                            to return on horseback while Nathan traveled on foot. It was in the month of March and the
                            horse often plunged into the snow and water, and made the journey very dangerous.
                            Occasionally we changed places and I found it very tiresome to walk through the snow. On
                            reaching North Hampton we found the river full of floating ice, and so dangerous that the
                            ferry-boats would not take any passengers across. This obliged us to stop over night and
                            filled us with great tribulation in regard to our journey toward home. (To be
                        continued.)</p></div2><pb n="81" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Jesus" TEIform="index"/>JESUS.</head><p TEIform="p">JESUS was a Jew, so says the historian, and his early education must have been received from
                            the Jewish traditions and literature. While some of these historians have attempted to write
                            the life of Jesus and exclude from it all that has been termed miraculous, and account for
                            all those singular manifestations that are accredited to him, as the results of natural law
                            ; another writer remarks, if they were or were not miracles, the greatest miracle of all is
                            -'that a Judean peasant has revolutionized the religious world, and that this peasant is now
                            receiving divine honors in the most enlightened countries of the world." There is no harm in
                            knowing this provided it is a fact. That the mission of Jesus will eventually revolutionize
                            the world and make of it what the Revelator foretold is certainly the great anticipation of
                            thousands, "The kingdoms of this world will become the kingdoms of our Lord," there need be
                            no doubt, and his "people will dwell in peaceable habitations, and in quiet resting places."
                            Jesus was eminently the Son of God in that he was led, so fully, by the spirit of God, and
                            in lifting man from his low estate of selfishness and tyranny, and to interest himself so
                            thoroughly in the happiness and prosperity of his brother man. Jesus would not only have men
                            to be peacemakers among themselves, but he would have them merciful and forgiving. His
                            testimony urged them to keep the Mosaic law, and then to perfect themselves, spiritually,
                            and become the sons and daughters of God and be perfect even as their father in heaven is
                            perfect. His work was God's work inasmuch as he said,"I and my Father are one." It was his
                            will to do the will of God and he prayed that the divine will might be done on earth, as it
                            is done in heaven. Had this work which Jesus, the Judean peasant, came to inaugurate among
                            men, been vitalized in the lives of his so-called followers, the whole earth, to-day, would
                            have been as the paradise of God, and the prophets prediction would have been verified in
                            full. The swords would have been beaten into ploughshares, and war spears would have been
                            beaten into pruning-hooks, and the nations would know war no more. Jesus declared
                            emphatically that his Kingdom was not of this world, and that his soldiers or disciples
                            would not fight with carnal weapons. His mission and his testimony was equally as strong
                            against all the self- <pb n="82" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 82 THE MANIFESTO. ish relations of the human
                            mind. These were to be forsaken if there was any expectation of gaining eternal life. Is the
                            Christian world to-day, giving divine honors to this Judean peasant, this teacher of
                            righteousness, this son of God? He said to his followers, If ye love me ye will keep my
                            commandments. Does the Christian church keep his commandments, and manifest a love for him
                            and for his word ? Another personage must be introduced here as a pattern which the church
                            has accepted. Paul rather than Jesus stands at the head of the Christian church, and is the
                            oracle to be consulted on every occasion. Jesus preached a full cross, while Paul gave
                            permission for certain deviations, and all of these liberties which Paul permitted among the
                            polygamous Corinthians are seized with avidity by the Christian church and held up as the
                            words of the divine Teacher. Jesus taught in the spirit of the regeneration, which was a
                            call to his disciples to come out from the carnal relations of the world and consecrate
                            their souls to God, while Paul allowed his church members to live in the order of
                            generation. All the strength that is obtained in favor of a physical resurrection is
                            obtained from the writings of Paul, which a worldly church has twisted into an unexplainable
                            mystery. Very little of the testimony of Jesus is left in the church. He said, Pray for
                            those who despitefully use you, but the church has declared unrelenting war against all who
                            differ from her in either civil or religious rights. Christian soldiers have been on the
                            list of fighters since the second century, while thousands of persons have been forced into
                            Christianity, or into the church at the poiDt of the sword. It is questionable if Jesus
                            would accept these demonstrations as marks of divine honor, and it is passing strange how a
                            class of people can live so diametrically opposite to his order of life, and then claim to
                            follow in his footsteps. Paul contended earnestly in the manifestations of his own life for
                            the testimony of the cross of Christ, but as soon as he came in contact with the Ephesians,
                            Corinthians, or Galatians, he left them nearly on a level with the children of this world,
                            and proffered them salvation by grace through faith. He worked with indefatigable zeal to
                            preach hig word among the Gentiles, but under all these liberties of a worldly generative
                            life, the Christian church has hid itself for many hundreds of years, and at the same time
                            claimed to be offering divine honors to Jesus, the Christ.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/>H. C. Blinn.</byline></div2><pb n="83" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. MAY, 1896. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is pu Wished by the "United
                            Soclety of Believers" on the first of each month, aud is the only work issued regularly by
                            the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the religious
                            views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. Address all communications
                            to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. One copy one year, postage paid. .50</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. March. Thermometer. Ruin. Snow. 1895. 28.1 1 in. 5 in.
                                1896. 26.5 4 " 5 " Highest Temp, during this mo. 50 above 0 Lowest " " " " 0 " ! Number
                                of rainy days '' " 5 " " snowy " " " 7 " clear " " " 10 " cloudy" " " 9 C. G. Reed.
                                April, 1896. Who has been to the North Pole and left the door ajar? No one answers. It
                                would seem that something ought to be closed, if we are to have the "seedtime" promised
                                in the "good book." Still it is best not to be over anxious for any thing. Nature will
                                have her way regardless of praise or censure; and to fret over the weather is simply an
                                absurdity; for "There are sunny days in winter after all." With others we regret the
                                absence of the bluebirds; but would rather think it was due to natural causes, like an
                                inclement winter than that they fell a prey to the caprice of fashion. We are glad to
                                learn that new birds are being added to our list, and hope that Connecticut will share
                                her treasures with New York. One new kind has also been with us most of the winter. The
                                usual work of early spring is progressing with as much zest as though it was something
                                new. The Great Creative power made the seasons just long enough in our latitude to allow
                                no time for idleness. Seed-time, growing-time and harvest, succeed so punctually that
                                those who delay the first, miss the whole. Such is life! Nature and grace are
                                counterparts, and where the former gives an annual lesson we are wise to adopt its rules
                                in our life work. Amelia J. Culver. North. Family. April, 1896. It would seem that any
                                reasonable weather clerk might have been satisfied with the blusters and storms of last
                                month without extending a March into April; but perhaps it has all been calculated for
                                the best. Not having appeared in this department last month, it may not be out of place
                                to state that Washington's birthday was appropriately celebrated by the school children
                                with many interesting recitations many of which were written for the occasion. To give
                                opportunity to those who desired to attend, the exercises were repeated a second day.
                                The pupils did honor to their teachers and themselves, and have doubtless thereby
                                derived much historical knowledge and an awakened interest in that which pertains to
                                Eepublican institutions. They were carefully instructed in the difference between patri
                                otism and a party spirit. The school laws of our state require ev TERMS. <pb n="84" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 84 TKE MANIFESTO. ery state school to be identified by the flag of the
                                Union whenever not stormy, during the school term. As this violated no principle of our
                                faith we complied. "La Grippe" invaded our home with the bold intrusion of a vandal who
                                had no respect for the high ideals of mental scientists or the philosophy of deep
                                breathing, morning walks, vegetarianism, or other habits of wholesome living, yet we are
                                not intending to let go the measure of truth in possession, but will press forward for
                                that fuller knowledge of Godliness which will insure a fuller salvation. We are thankful
                                to say that all have been restored to active duty without the aid of any physician not
                                of the Communitj. Yesterday, Easter Sunday, in unison with the millions whose hearts
                                were upturned to the "risen Christ," we sought and found a renewal of that divine love
                                which is indeed the power of the true resurrection. In the afternoon we met at Second
                                family to offer a last, loving tribute to our departed Sister Johannah Freeborn whose
                                life had been such as to assure us that she was "not dead, but only arisen." Catherine
                                Allen.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">North JETamily. April 5, 1896. The remarks of Mother Lucy Wright which commenced
                                publication in the April Manifesto, reminds us that the "ancients of the city" have not
                                passed away, although removed from our material recognition; but are near to us many
                                times when we are not cognizant of their presence. Why the Reaper could not have spared
                                Elder John B. Vance for a while longer is past the comprehension of our finite
                                understanding. We well remember his first visit to our western home in the summer of
                                1869, and though we were but a child his personality impressed itself upon us to the
                                realization of his exalted character. March maintained her record by giving us the
                                heaviest snow storm of the season. In comparison with the spring before, the present one
                                will he late. At present writing many snow drifts are visible, and winter is loth to
                                surrender its claims. Hamilton DeQruw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harvard, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Harvard, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">May, 1896. Looking at the calendar we are reminded of our duty to The Manifesto. If we
                                wish our magazine to prosper and continue to regale us both spiritually and mentally we
                                must not fail to contribute what we are able to its support. The sad demise of our
                                beloved Elder John Yance brought the Central Ministry East, and they sojourned with us a
                                few days at Harvard and Shirley. Their presence was refreshing and comforting. How can
                                we but sorrow when the good, the true,to whom we look in confidence for help and
                                sympathy in times of need are taken from us and we see them no more? Our next winter's
                                supply of wood is all housed. The maples are now yielding up their sweets, which keeps
                                some of our people busy gathering it and reducing it to syrup. Spring work on the farm
                                is progressing finely for the late spring. Crocusses and snowdrops are opening their
                                petals to catch the sun's rays, and a few robbins and bluebirds have made their
                                appearance among the leafless trees. Joyfully we hail the spring. Marcia M.
                            Billiard.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">April, 1896. The approach of the glorious springtide has the effect to raise us from the
                                tomb of materiality that would tend to render inactive the purer qualities of our being,
                                into a high spiritual atmosphere. Seeking to follow Christ we should look above our
                                natural desires, and do the work the gospel of self-denial bids, loving mankind even as
                                Christ, with a love untainted by the lust of selfishness or animal emotion. <pb n="85" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 85 "God's glory is a wcmd'rous thing, Most strange in all
                                its ways; And of all things on earth, least like What men agree to praise." We have
                                recently enjoyed a festal season of love and soul strength in the visitation of one of
                                Zion's honored, well tried veterans, Eldress Marion Patric, of Enfield Conn. Why may we
                                not often enjoy such seasons? The conscience and character of our communal homes is
                                embodied in the personalities of the older members of our Church, and is it not their
                                duty to keep before the younger minds the soul cleansing testimony of Christ? To the
                                awakened conscience ever rings out the appeal, Now is the day of your salvation, give
                                all for Christ. We send renewed love to all the readers of our Manifesto. George II.
                                Baxter.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">April, 1896. With spring time comes the beginning of new life. Everything seems to
                                understand that the time of inaction has past away. It is surprising what a change is
                                wrought in the human mind as the snow and ice-banks fade from view and the early flowers
                                rise from their winter beds. The winter has past but we shall remember gratefully the
                                ice that was formed for our mid-summer comfort. 2592 cakes, 22 inches square and 16
                                inches thick have been secured. These cakes weigh nearly 240 lbs. each. The work at the
                                saw mill has demanded the attention of several work men during the greater part of the
                                winter. Some 100, 000 ft. of lumber has been hauled some four miles, and sawed into
                                boards, shingles and lathes, and are now ready for the market. Our herdsmen have two
                                silos of 100 tons each. These are 32 ft. deep and 11x13 ft. square. On the 1st day of
                                April some 10 tons were still to be found in one silo. For several months nearly one
                                ton, each day, was fed to the cattle. A late report gives 87 gallons of milk per day.
                                Two Jersey cows have just been added to the stock and their two Jersey calves are
                                creatures of beauty. Not many birds visit the mountains of New Hampshire during the
                                winter. An occasional caller this year was probably the Pine Grosbeak. His head and
                                shoulders are dull red, and he carries white wing bands. These birds are very tame.
                                Henry C. Blinn.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pleasant Hill, Kentucky" TEIform="index"/>Pleasant Hill, Ky.</head><p TEIform="p">Mar. 1896. I have in mind a sermon by Dr. Talmadge on "Lost Opportunities." How many of
                                us can say, we never have passed carelessly by an opportunity where we might have added
                                comfort to some one by a kind word or deed. Our example will live when we are gone. What
                                an amount of good we might do by obeying the precepts of our Lord, Jesus Christ. A kind
                                word, a helping hand may have assisted some fallen discouraged brother or sister on the
                                highway to happiness. We have had a very mild and pleasant winter. The mercury reached
                                zero only twice and in the next twenty-six hours was 16 degrees above. We had four light
                                snow falls, none of which lasted more than four days. The grass is quite green and birds
                                of various kinds are now singing- , We are being blest with all the necessary comforts
                                of life, but regret to say that our ice-house will remain useless the coming season.
                                However we have a never failing spring of pure, cold water, and for this we have many
                                thanks. Nancy L. Rupe.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station, Ct.</head><p TEIform="p">April 1896. "Strive to enter in at the straight gate." What a flood of happiness fills
                                our souls when we have striven for overcoming power and feel that we are made better for
                                those strivings. Constant, selfdenying efforts will insure us a sure passport to
                                heavenly mansions. <pb n="86" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> THE MA NIFES TO. It is our privilege to live so
                                tli.it heavenly treasures will be ours. The first point is to start right, and keep in
                                the heavenly pathwayit is plain. A virtuous life brings lasting peace but thousands
                                prize it not. "Virtue aione is happiness," and happiness is heaven. Virtue is a bright
                                jewel, richer than gold or precious gems. To obtain it, our hearts, which are the seat
                                of principles, must be purified by the cross. Duties, in small things, as well as in
                                great, are duties still. Row often are today's opportunities, to-day's privileges
                                neglected, and time lost in anticipation of some good we are to gain in the future.
                                Greater opportunities will not come tomorrow unless we are faithful to improve those
                                that God has given us to-day. Let us be wary, watch and pray, and shun pitfalls. ******
                                * To obtain a good supply of eggs in winter we must have young hens. Pullets hatched in
                                April or May will prove most satisfactory. Daniel Orcutt.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Sabbathday Lake, Me.</head><p TEIform="p">April, 1896. The sudden death of our beloved Elder John Vance necessarily called the
                                Central Ministry to our aid. In their great kindness they came to our home March 24th,
                                bringing with them love and comfort such as gentle parents are wont to bestow on their
                                sorrowing children. They tarried three days, leaving a blessing with us. Elder William
                                Dumont has been chosen to fill Elder John's place in the Ministry and also retain his
                                position as Elder and Trustee of this Society. Eldress Lizzie Noyes and Sister Aurelia
                                Mace were also appointed Trustees. These three faithful souls we trust implicitly for
                                our spiritual and temporal welfare. The new greenhouse erected last fall is now full of
                                seedlings. The Brethren expect to have 400 doz. tomato plants to sell and 200 doz.
                                celery plants for the Poland Spring market. The Sisters are starting their flower seeds
                                and find it much more convenient than formerly when they had but the light and sun of
                                the windows. We have almost every requisite for plant growing. The winter has been one
                                of the most trying seasons for many years. Twice recently we have been visited with a
                                distemper known as La Grippe. Some of the members are now confined to their rooms
                                battling with the ugly monster. The lumber at the saw mill is now being sawed. The
                                coming week the firewood w ill be sawed with the Portable engine. During the past month
                                we have had a great deal of snow. On the 3rd inst. a foot of snow fell in one night, and
                                even now one would think it were mid-winter ins.ead of spring by the way the wind blows
                                the snow around. Ada S. Cummings.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Narcoossa, Florida" TEIform="index"/>Narcoossa, Florida</head><p TEIform="p">April 8, 1896. On April 4th, Elder Louis Basting came to see us, lie will return to us
                                Thursday and stay over the Sabbath. We have just sent to market 10 bbls. of nice
                                potatoes. Today it looks and feels like Indian summer. The garden is suffering for want
                                of rain, of which we have had but two light showers for a month. The days are often hot
                                but the nights are cool. There are beautiful flowers in front and the rear of our house,
                                which Sister Minerva has planted and tended, with great care. Brother Egbert has
                                assisted in watering the same and so we all do what we can. Our pasture is at its best
                                and cattle are recuperating from the effects of dry forage and cold weather. Brother
                                Charles has commenced a six acre clearing next to our station gate on the north, in dry
                                pine woods. We expect to cattle pen it and raise corn and sweet potatoes. Elder Andrew
                                takes care of the crops at home while Br. Egbert and writer are clearing the oak hammock
                                at the center. 86 <pb n="87" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 87 We have good meetings here,
                                and en- mons,"Well done, good and faithful joy it much when we receive such good
                                servant, enter thou into the joy of thy letters, for which we are greatly indebted
                                Lord." to you all, our gospel friends. Henry Hoilisier.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tribute of love to the memory of elder John B. Vance" TEIform="index"/>A Tribute of Love to
                            the Memory of ELDER JOHN B. VANCE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Walker, Mary Ann" TEIform="persName"/>By Mary Ann Walker.</byline><p TEIform="p">With hearts bowed in grief we have assembled to-day to pay the last tribute of loving care to
                            our beloved father, Elder John who has passed from this life to a higher sphere. We need
                            erect no costly monument to his sainted memory as his life was full of love and blessing for
                            every earnest toiler in the vineyard of the Lord. His pure and godly example will ever prove
                            a shining star to guide us safely to that beautiful, spiritual home. His spirit now resting
                            in the embraces of infinite love, must rejoice that he has kept his early vows of
                            consecration to follow the life of Christ. The dear departed was a man of God, and was
                            beloved by all his Brethren and Sisters. His charity for the erring was unbounded and he has
                            often said:"I would gladly bear all your crosses and trials it' it would save your souls,
                            but each one must do his part toward gaining the prize of salvation, and my advice would be,
                            always yield obedience to the small voice of conscience and you will have strength given
                            urito you to persevere to the end." His testimony was as a two-edged sword against sin, yet
                            no one ever sought his aid in vain, or failed to receive strength in the hour of need, and
                            by his prayerful ministration souls found relief and forgiveness. Words fail to tell how
                            much we shall miss our beloved Elder, and though we mourn at our loss, to him it may be
                            great gain. O may thy blessed spirit ever be near to guide us through our journey here
                            below, that when our time shall come to pass over the river, we can rejoice among the
                            ransomed, and hear the same joyful sumAlfred, Maine.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To my Friends of the United Society of Sabbathday Lake..." TEIform="index"/>
                            To my Friends of the United Society of Sabbathday Lake...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Gloucester, March 21, 1895" TEIform="index"/> Gloucester, March 21, 1896.</dateline><p TEIform="p">To my Friends of the United Society of Sabbatiiday Lake :It is with feelings of profound
                            sorrow that I learned of the death of Elder John Yance. My acquaintance with him was quite
                            short, though it covered a number of years, yet brief as it Avas, I learned to respect,
                            admire and love the man and at his death I can but mourn as at the loss of a friend. A
                            humble member of the great public I can but sympathize as far as in me lies with the Society
                            of which he was so distinguished a member in their great loss, which it seems to me must be
                            well nigh irreparable. His own Society are not the only ones that suffer great loss by the
                            death of Elder John, as he was familiarly called; the public at large are great losers also.
                            Endowed with an unmeasured gift in public speech, being both eloquent and persuasive, he was
                            undoubtedly horn to ! bo a leader of men. Sagacious and upright in business ever casting his
                            influence by both precept and example on the side of I the purest and highest morality, he
                            exhibI ited the noblest traits of a well rounded manhood. Alas! The world produces few such
                            men and when by some mysterious ruling of divine Providence one such is cut down, at what
                            seems an untimely hour, when in the midst of his usefulness and in the full maturity of his
                            manly strength the busy public may well pause in its daily rush of business and drop a tear
                            on his bier. The memory of Elder John will doubtless be kept fresh and green for many a year
                            by his Society friends and his power for good on the world at large within the circle of his
                            influence must extend into the future for many years to come, indeed we are told that ones
                            influence for good for or evil never dies, how far reaching New <pb n="88" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 88 THE
                            MA NIFES TO. then must be the influence of a man like Elder John, the great cycles of
                            oncoming time can not compass it. The thousands who have listened to his words so carefully
                            drawn forth in eloquent and persuasive speech, as he upheld the doctrine of his church or
                            sought to lift men to a higher and purer life, as they turn memory backward, will feel that
                            they received a new inspiration that has been uplifting and helpful amid the trials and
                            temptations of life's devious journey. It seems sad to know that we shall see the comely
                            presence and manly form of Elder John no more, and that his kindly greeting and cheering
                            words are now to be only in remembrance, yet it is becoming in man to be submissive to
                            Divine decrees, and we can only add the word, Farewell! Eespectf ully,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Haskell, Charles Peter" TEIform="persName"/>CHARLES PETER HASKELL.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary.</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="One of the frequent errors of early education..." TEIform="index"/>One of the frequent errors of early education...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">One of the frequent errors of early ed ucation has been mentioned. It is that of
                                enlarging the stomach quite beyond its natural size, till it comes to demand a most
                                unreasonable quantity in order to be satisfied. Multitudes of old and young people
                                distend their stomachs too much every day they live. Children from the very first are
                                trained to be gluttonous. Preserved food whether by salt, salt petre, smoke, spices,
                                spirits &amp;c, &amp;c, are more or less objectionable for the stomach. One
                                great objection to pickles is that they are so changed by vinegar, salt or other
                                appliances as have been used for preservation, as to resist chymification, and even
                                solution. Green grapes, green tomatoes, green cucumbers, green peppers and the like are
                                of themselves insoluble and unwholesome. Medicated food is opposed more or less, to the
                                natural operations to the system. Of medicated substances which in one ilace or
                                anotlier,are either found in food or added to it, are saleratus, sal-soda-assaietida,
                                ginger, allspice and common salt. Many tilings which we eat contain sugar enough for our
                                health, without any additions at our tables. Thus wheat flour contains eight per cent,
                                oatmeal eight; cherries eighteen; plums eleven; beets five; milk seven; peas, corn and
                                rye contain from one to three per cent of this substance.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Alcott" TEIform="persName"/>Dr. Alcott.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">Mackintoshes and Rubber Clothing large commissions can be earned by retailing to users.
                            Sample free. Manufacturer, P. O. 1871 New York. articles have been received, too late for
                            the May Manifesto. bear in mind that the Manifesto is eight pages less than last year, and
                            the articles for insertion must be abreviated in proportion. 200 words is about right for
                            Home Notes.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The world is my Country..." TEIform="index"/>The world is my Country...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The world is my Country, Mankind are my Brethren, and to do good is my religion.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Paine, Thomas" TEIform="persName"/>Thomas Paine.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ray, David" TEIform="index"/>David Ray
                            </head><p TEIform="p">David Ray, at Center Family, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. March 26, 1896. Age 73 years, 2 mo. and
                                25 days. Br. David has lived in the Community since Sept. 1828 and has been a quiet,
                                faithful worker in his gospel home. A. G. H. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Freeborn, Johannah E." TEIform="index"/>Johannah E. Freeborn
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Johannah E. Freeborn, at Second Family, Mt.
                                Lebanon, N. Y. March 31, 1896. Age 62 years, 3 mo. and 18 days. Sr. Johannah has been a
                                Belies er in the faith some ten years. J. E. S. 'Several, "Please</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p19"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
Word and Works for April informs us that
the month is to be one of showers, and that
there may be hail storms before the month
closes.
Other interesting chapters are to be found
in this number as follows:Defends England;
The Coming King; Magnifying Eftect of
Planetary Atmosphere; The Ethics of Courtesy; Is he Right; Hard Times; Proof in Practice; Immortality; Idumeu; The Great Sabbath; etc., etc.
Published by Word and Works Co. 2201 Locust Street, St.Louis, Mo.
The Phrenological Journal for April has
an extended and illustrated notice of Henry
George, the friend of the working man.
A very interesting chapter on the Intellectual and Aristocratic noses of women illustrated by not less than twelve well known individuals. A Sculptor's opinion of Phrenology.
An Illustrated article on the Faculty of Orderby Prof. Sizer. Innocent or Guilty or Phrenology in a delicate Case, has reference to the
Rev. C. O. Brown of San Francisco California. A study of the hands, of the handwriting and of the ears will interest the readers: and then a chapter on Candidates for
Manhood, so prettily illustrated will claim a
passing notice from every reader.
FoAvler & Wells Co., 27 East 21st N. Y.
Willey's Book of Nutfield. Part 1st of
Vol. I. is before us, As this number is suppos
ed to be a fair representative of what the
whole Volume may be, we need not hesitate
in saying ttiat it will be a beautiful and a val 
uable work. These forty page? are so carefully printed and so profusely illustrated with
Half-tones and Steel engravings that the
whole work must become a valuable contribution among the Histoiies of New Hampshire.
No one can avoid being interested in the
early history of New Hampshire and especially when it is presented in a form so entertaining, and in a work so beautifully arranged.
The Wonderful Law, by H. L. Hastings.
It is, indeed, wonderful that at so early an age
in the history of mankind, that a system of
laws could have been brought forward for the
govern'merit of the Jewish nation, which has
has a world wide influence. The writer
 says;"Translated into hundreds of languages, printed in thousands of editions, and
scattered by hundreds of millions of copies,
that law has gone into all the earth, and its
words unto the ends of the world." Believers
in Christianity should read and understand
the law, as Jesus has said that it should not
fail, till the whole was fulfilled.
Published at 47 Cornhill, Boston, Mass.
The Pulpit for March has a table of Contents so spread for the religiously inclined
that certainly should be satisfactory. Wrath
turned to Praise, by a Congregationalist.Is
the man safe? by a Baptist of Canada,Gateway to the Kingdom, by D. L. Moody.What
about the i'heater, by a Baptist of S. C 
Knowledge of Iniquity and Failure to Restrain, by a Lutheran.Church Members who
are Sinners, by an Episcopal Bishop.
Published by G. Holzapfel, Fredericksburg.
Pa.   $1.50 a year.
THE SHAKER COVENANT.
This work sets forth the form of appointment, the qualifications and powers of the
several
ORDERS    OF   OFFICERS
in the Community : of the
PRIVILEGES  and OBLIGATIONS
of all the Members, and of the
DEDICATION     AND     CONSECRATION
of persons and property.
The book will afford interest to all, and at
he same time, afford instruction to all   inquiring  minds.    Price 5  cts. each,   postage
paid, or 36 cts. per doz.
"INTERPRETING PROPHECY
AND  THE
"Appearing of Christ,"
is the title of a neat little pamphlet of
some forty pages, just sent out by A. G.
Hollister of Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.
The many at the present time who are
interested in the fulfillment of prophecy
and in its mathematical calculation, will
find themselves by the side of the gjood
old prophet Daniel, and with him illustrating the Coming of Christ so clear 1
that no occasion can arise for the least
doubt.                             Price, 10 cts.
<pb n="" id="p20"/>
THE   MANIFESTO,
POWDER
Absolutely Pure.
For Information and free Handbook write to
MUNN & CO., 361 Broadway, New York.
Oldest bureau for securing patents in America
Every patent taken out by us is brought before
the public by a notice given free of charge in the
Largest circulation of any scientific paper In t^o
world. Splendidly illustrated. No ijltyliig-'- 6
man should be without it. Weekly, &3.C a
year; $1.50 six months. Address, 3IU.VN  CO,,
Publishers, Hiil Broadway, New York City.
SKETCHES OF SHAKERS
AND
SH AKERISM.
A synopsis of Theology of the United   Society  of   Believers   in   Christ's
Second Appearing.    Illustrated.
By Giles B. Avery.
Price,  15 cts.
A cream of  tartar  baking   powder.
Highest of all in leavening strength.
-Latest   United   States   Government
Food report.
Eoyal Baking Powder Co.
106 Wall St., N. Y.
BRIEF EXPOSITION
of the
Principles and Begulations
of the
SOCIETY   OF   BELIEVEES.
Price, 10 cts.
WASTED
Good reliable men,   to sell
our   Choice    and    Hardy
Nursery Stock such as Fruit
Trees, Roses Shrubs and Ornamentals. Ladies make this business a success. Easy work, pleasant, light and profitable. Outfit Free. Apply at once, with references, and secure choice of territory.
F.  N.  MAY   COMPANY,
Nurserymen and Saedsmen, Itoclies.
ter, N. Y.
HUMAN NATURE
is an illustrated Monthly, now only 50 cts.
per    year,    devoted   to   PHEEN0L0GY,
PHYSIOGNOMY, HEALTH, MEDICAL
& SOCIAL EEPOEM.
Would you like a copy?
Send 5 cts. for Sample to Prof. Haddock,
Phrenologist, 1016 Market St.,
San Francisco, Cal.
Tea and Coffee Pots that pour by the lid without lifting or tipping.     Simple beyond belief.
Practical and artistic.   Send for pnmphlet.
THE ASEURY=PAINB MFC. CO., Phila., Pa.
This ia a good thingEd.
POUR
By Pressing the Lid.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>