<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm1601" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">28</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">16</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">1</biblScope><date value="18860101" TEIform="date">January 1886</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">1-24</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="16" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="1" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                    <pb id="p1"/>
                     <p>JANUARY THE MANIFESTO. Published by the United Societies, " Every plant which my heavenly Father hath not planted
                        shall be rooted up." —Matt. XV, 13. SHAKER VILLAGE, N. H. 1886. </p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    --><pb n="1" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><!--<div2 type="none">
                        <p>CONTENTS. Page, Page. The Four Dispensations, 1 Work for Willing Laborers, 16 An Interior
                            View 3 Sanitary, 18 Why I want to be a Shaker, 5 Facts worth remembering, Good Desires, 7
                            Christmas, 19 Calling the Angels in, Friendship, » A Just Criterion, Kind Words, 20
                            Comforting Reflections, 8 AS A MAN EATETH, Translation op Isaiah, 9 Rev. Samuel Jones, »
                            Experience, » Tobacco, » Letter from B. B. Dunlavy, 10 Mt Creed, " " Betsey Johnson, 11 Be
                            Silent, P. B. Alsop, 12 Music—Not one Sparrow, 21 " . " M. A. GlLLESPIE, . " Diary of B.
                            Whitcher, 22 We Shall Know, 14 Guided, 23 Tale-bearer, 15 Books and Papers, 24 Zion's Glory,
                            " Tobacco, Notes, .... " 16 Five points, Calvinism, Vol. XVI. JANUARY, 1886. No. 1.</p>
                    </div2>--><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Four dispensations" TEIform="index"/>THE FOUR DISPENSATIONS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Meacham, Joseph" TEIform="persName"/>ELDER JOSEPH MEACHAM</byline><p TEIform="p">First Dispensation. We helieve that the first light of salvation was given or made known to
                            the patriarchs by promise ; and they that believed in the promise of Christ, and were
                            obedient to the command of God made known unto them, were the people of God and were
                            accepted of God, as righteous, or perfect in their generations ; according to the measure of
                            light and truth manifested unto them ; which was as waters to the ankles, signified by
                            Ezekiel's vision of the holy waters. (Chap, xlvii.) And although they could not receive
                            regeneration, or the fullness of salvation from the fleshly nature in this life ; because
                            the fullness of time was not yet come, that they should receive the baptism of the Holy
                            Spirit and fire ; for the destruction of the body of sin, and purification of the soul.
                            Abram being called and chosen of God as the father of the faithful; was received into
                            covenant relation with God by promise ; that in him, (and his seed which was Christ,) all
                            the families of the earth should be blessed ; and these earthly blessings which were prom-
                            ised to Abram, were a shadow of gosptl or spiritual blessings to come. So that Abram, though
                            in the full faith of the promise ; yet, as he did sot receive the substance of the thing
                            promised, his hope of eternal salvation was in Christ, by the gospel to be attained in the
                            resurrection from the dead. Second Dispensation. The second dispensation was the law <pb n="2" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. that was given of God to Israel, by the hand of Moses ;
                            which was a further manifestation of that salvation which was promised through Christ by the
                            gospel, both in the order and ordinances which were instituted and given to Israel, as the
                            church and people of God, according to that dispensation ; which was as waters to the knees,
                            (Ezekiel, xlvii,) by which they were distinguished from all the families of the earth. For,
                            while they were strictly obedient to all the commands, ordinances and statutes that God gave
                            them, they were approbated of God according to the promise of life ; and blessing was
                            promised unto them in the line of obedience, cursing and death in disobedience ; for God,
                            who is ever jealous for the honor and glory of his own great name, always dealt with them
                            according to his word ; for while they were obedient to the command of God, and purged out
                            sin from .amongst them, God was with them. But when they disobeyed the command of God, and
                            committed sin, and became like other people, the hand of the Lord was turned against them ;
                            and those evils came upon them which God had threatened; so we see that they who were wholly
                            obedient to the will of God made known in that dispensation, were accepted as just or
                            righteous ; yet, as the dispensation was short, they did not attain that salvation which was
                            promised in the gospel; so that as it respected the new-birth, or real purification of the
                            man from all sin ; the law made nothing perfect, but was a shadow of good things to come ;
                            their only hope of eternal redemption was in the promise of Christ, by the gospel to be
                            attained in the resurrection from the dead. Acts, xxvi., 6, 7. Third Dispensation. The third
                            dispensation was the gospel of Christ's first appearance, in the flesh ; and that salvation
                            which took place in consequence of his life, death, resurrection and ascension at the right
                            hand of the Father, being accepted in his obedience, as the first-born among many brethren ;
                            he received power and authority to administer the power of the resurrection and eternal
                            judgment to all the children of men; so that he has become the author of salvation to all
                            that obey him. And as Christ has this power in himself, he did administer power and
                            authority to his church at the day of pentecost, as his .body ; with all the gifts that he
                            had promised them, which was the first gift of the Holy Spirit as an indwelling comforter to
                            abide with them forever ; and by which they were baptized into Christ's death ; death to all
                            sin ; and were in the hope of the resurrection from the dead, through the operation of the
                            power of God, which wrought in them. And as they received the substance of the promise of
                            Christ come in the flesh, by the gift and power of the Holy Spirit : they had power to
                            preach the gospel in Christ's name to every creature,— and to administer the power of God to
                            as many as believed, and were obedient to the gospel which they preached ; and also to remit
                            and retain sin in the name and authority of Christ on earth. So that they who believed in
                            the gospel, and were obedient to that form of doctrine which was taught them, by denying all
                            ungodliness and worldly lusts ; and became entirely dead to the law by the body of Christ,
                            or power of the Holy Spirit were in the travel of 2 <pb n="3" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. the
                            resurrection from the dead, or the redemption of the body. So that they who took up a full
                            cross against the world, flesh and devil; and who forsook all for Christ's sake, and
                            followed him in the regeneration, by persevering in that line of obedience to the end, found
                            the resurrection from the dead and eternal salvation in that dispensation. But as the
                            measure ot that dispensation was only as water to the loins ; the mystery of God was not
                            finished, but there was another day prophesied of, called the second appearance of Christ.
                            or final and last display of God's grace to a lost world, in which the mystery of God should
                            be finished as he has spoken by his prophets since the world b jgan ; which day could not
                            come, except there was a falling away from that faith and power that the church then stood
                            in ; in which time anti-christ was to have his reign, whom Christ should destroy with the
                            spirit of his mouth and brightness of his appearance ; which falling away began soon after
                            the apostles, and gradually increased in the church, until about four hundred and
                            fifty-seven years from Christ's birth (or thereabouts) at which time the power of the holy
                            people, or church of Christ was scattered or lost by reason of transgression ; and
                            antichrist or false religion got to be established. Since that time the witnesses of Christ
                            have prophesied in sackcloth or under darkness; although many have been faithful to testify
                            against sin, even to the laying down of their lives for the testimony which they held ; so
                            that God accepted them in their obedience, while they were faithful and just to live or walk
                            to the measure of light and truth of God, revealed or made known unto them, but as it is
                            written, All they that will live godly in Christ Jesus, shall suffer persecution ; and so it
                            has been, and those faithful witnesses lost their lives by those falsely called the church
                            of Christ, which is anti-christ; for the true church of Christ never persecuted any, but
                            were inoffensive, harmless, separate from sin ; for the true church of Christ by taking up
                            their cross against the world, flesh and devil, and all sin, living in obedience to God they
                            earnestly contend for the same. Therefore it may be plainly seen and known, where the true
                            church of Christ is ; but as it is written, anti-christs or false churches should prevail
                            against the saints and overcome them, before Christ's second appearance. (To be Continued
                        )</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Interior view, no. 1" TEIform="index"/>AN INTERIOR VIEW. NO. 1</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, Oliver C." TEIform="persName"/>OLIVER C. HAMPTON</byline><p TEIform="p">"¦Days should speak, and the multitude of years should teach wisdom. There is a spirit in man
                            and the inspiration of the Almighty giveth them understanding. Hearken to me, I will also
                            show mine opinion." Job xxxii., 7, 8, 10. "In the beginning was the word, and the word was
                            with God, and the word was God. All things were made (evolved) by him (the word) and without
                            Him was not anything made that was made. In him (the word) was life and the life was the
                            light of men." John, i., 1, 3, 4. My first premise is, if the principles of our Institution
                            are not of eternal duration and energy, it will go to pieces, as it can endure no longer
                            than its sub. 3 <pb n="4" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. structure. The word spoken of above, was
                            first "of God" because it was an emanation, and secondly "was God" because it was Divine
                            Energy. This emanation of the Infinite Wisdom and Love (Our Heavenly Father and Moth- er) is
                            the Christ of the Universe, the cause of the evolution or projection of all visible
                            entities. John also says, i., 14. " And the word was made flesh and dwelt among us, and we
                            beheld his glory the glory as of the only begotten of the Father, full of grace and truth."
                            This was for the progress and perfection of undeveloped humanity in all worlds, even "God
                            manifested in the flesh." (1 Tim. iii., 16.) Whether the man Jesus was the first visible
                            male representative of the Christ of the Universe, and Ann Lee the first female thereof is
                            of no consequence, as we are certain they are descendants from the same heavenly fountain of
                            Divine Energy and their mission one of redemption and emancipation of man from all that is
                            sinful, wretched and painful into the glorious liberty of spiritual peace and perfection.
                            The great fact is, that this benevolent manifestation of our invisible Parents, has been
                            made in the flesh and was evolved through its spiritual power, an organization or living
                            church wherein all mankind may find an asylum of forgiveness and atonement with God and all
                            their fellow beings. The internal as well as external form of this organization, is an
                            unassailable proof of the goodness and blessedness of the divine energy or emanation Avhich
                            evolved it. This form with its entire practical operation is based on a law of the Universe
                            enunciated by St. Paul, Heb. vii., 7. "Without all contradiction the less is blessed of the
                            better." This law of eternal evolution, is parental in its character and operations,
                            energizing all visible creation and moving the same to higher and higher perfections, man
                            more than all else. It has a visible representation in Jesus and Mother Ann whose power and
                            inspiration, have opened a way of peace and perfection in holiness for all humanity in this
                            our poor imperfect rudimental sphere, for all time and all eternity. In vieAv of so great a
                            boon, may we not exclaim in the sublime words of the rapt poet. " Lo earth receives him
                            (them) from the bending skies Sink down ye mountains and ye valleys rise Eternal Hope thy
                            glittering wings explore Earth's loneliest bounds and Ocean's wildest shore.' The character
                            as well as the form of this church are beautifully and perfectly represented in the one
                            established by Jesus and the Apostles 1800 years ago and which was re-organized, re
                            established and re-vitalized by Mother Ann Lee a little more than 100 years ago. Jj Its
                            character, relative to its powersand the peculiar administration of its government have by
                            Believers received the general name of "the visible Order of God." In this visible Order are
                            included the principles, rules, regulations etc., necessary for the conduct, government,
                            direction and protection, as well as the perpetuity of the organization in all things
                            temporal and spiritual. It also implies a willing and cheerful compliance of all and every
                            of its members, with the requirements of those [appointed as spiritual and temporal
                            directors and burden bearers ; of which, in the true Order there should be an equal number
                            of each sex. None need ever be mortified or chagrined at this organization of leaders 4 <pb n="5" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. and followers, because in the evolution of the ages every
                            single human being in the universe will at some time in his or her experience, be both a
                            leader and follower. The law above quoted from Paul is universal and eternal. The parable oi
                            Jesus adverting to a servant was, "Well done—thou shalt be ruler of two, five, ten cities."
                            But probably the reader may inquire, Does this leadership or parentage always succeed in
                            doing justly and righteously according to the dictates of Wisdom and Love in their treatment
                            of those in their charge? Answer. liudimental human nature is weak and imperfect, and these
                            leaders having imperfections like unto their Brethren and Sisters, do not always succeed in
                            walking perfectly in this matter, even with their utmost vigilance. But these leaders and
                            directors are required to suffer the pangs of self-discipline and self-abnegation, till all
                            this dross of rudimentalism is thoroughly purged from the floor of their daily practical
                            life and their dealing with those in their charge. ]f they are un- willing to meet this
                            ordeal, they are unfit for leaders and are succeeded by those who are willing to sacrifice
                            themselves and all their faculties and talents for Christ's sake and the good of their
                            Brethren and Sisters, as well as all humanity. And we do aver moreover, that any wrong or
                            injustice done as above inquired about, is many times compensated by the peace and
                            protection received from this visible Order, and the immunity from the galling yoke of a
                            guilty conscience and the perfect atonement with God and all our fellow beinjrs thus gained
                            by every faithful Zion traveler. In our next article, we shall more par- ticularly refer to
                            the practical issues growing out of this visible Order as embodied in our own experience and
                            observation. Union Village, Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Why I want to be a shaker" TEIform="index"/>Why I want to be a Shaker</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Beauchamp, W. A. J." TEIform="persName"/>W. A. J. BEAUCHAMP</byline><p TEIform="p">Looking over our little planet we find, first, that it has interspersed over its surface,
                            beings bearing so close a resemblance to each other as to justify the conclusion of a common
                            origin, a common brotherhood—a "family." Second, we find this order of beings classified
                            into various nationalities, each having characteristics peculiar to itself. There are
                            dissimilarities in the languages spoken, in the forms of government, in the social customs ;
                            but, perhaps, the strongest marks of distinction are to be found in the various secular and
                            sectarian ideas respecting those emotional feelings and exercises classed under the common
                            appellation of religion. As intelligencies transcending all other orders of being experience
                            proves that as the grand aim of life, among all people and in all climes, is centered in the
                            desire to enjoy life, and as certain conditions of life give a certain bias to temperament
                            in the moulding of character, more or less, to surrounding circum- stances, it became matter
                            of expedience to organize this one great family intd political and social orders composed of
                            members temperamentally adapted to such order as is found most congenial to theirkt
                            peculiar" temperament. Of course 5 <pb n="6" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 6 THE MANIFESTO. I allude only to the
                            various orders of the Adamic family. So great is this disparity and such the idiosyncrasies
                            influencing the ruling powers that the common desire to foster and enjoy life does not halt
                            at the legitimate means which the laws of being point to as the best, but those means are,
                            by the masses, stultified, perverted, in the unnatural effort to secure happiness at the
                            expense or cost of others. How often do we hear it declared, even from the pulpit, that this
                            is "human nature." Is it not rather the inhuman in nature as adopted by the higher ( ?)
                            intelligencies from the lower orders of creation? In justification of the slaying propensity
                            how often are we reminded that the lower orders of creation do the same, i.e. prey upon each
                            other ; as if they were to be regarded as our natural tutors and we were to look to them for
                            an exact standard of morals. In view of the various idiosyncracies referred to, together
                            with the fact that all and each seek life's enjoyment and each on his or her own plane I
                            will ask you to imagine yourself shipAvrecked O"J some "inhospitable shore" where you find
                            yourself surrounded by those of the "common brotherhood of man" whom we are pleased to term
                            " savage.'' Imagine your ears constantly assailed by a jargon of words as meaningless to
                            your inner senses as they are harsh and discordant to the ear. In addition to this imagine
                            yourself daily constrained to witness spectacles of religious worship utterly revolting to
                            your ideas of consistency. To them the pleasures of life in religious fellowship may be as
                            complete as the nature of outward circumstances will admit. To them life's pleasures are
                            unalloyed. But oh ! who but thysslf can depict the horror to you consequent on your forced
                            relation to systems and practices so utterly repugnant to your conception of pleasures
                            refined. Now let us change the picture. In this dreary region of your heart's desolation
                            imagine yourself strolling listlessly along the beach. You observe something at a distance
                            which proves to be a bundle which the waves have cast ashore. An examination of the packet
                            discovers some printed papers. Yes, aud now your heart leaps as you discover the familiar
                            title of magazine or newspaper whose plain English type enables you to comprehend every word
                            as word by word sends a thrill of joy to your lonely heart. How eagerly you scan the
                            treasured pages hoping to catch—ah ! yes, here it is now—a friendly comprehensive
                            communication from a well known friend, and Oh, the eager longing that possesses you to be
                            gone from these harrowing, discordant and uncongenial scenes to join the friends you know.
                            Friends whose every gesture, nay almost every thought awakens a kindred response. "Where hai
                            monies sweet in accord meet. Friends who understand you. Friends who speak to you
                            understandingly. Where with veil of mystery rent, Life and time are sweetly spent. Friends
                            who, like yourself, perchance, have chosen that belter part and seek through
                            "transformation" grace to fulfill the sabred injunctions of the "golden rule. " Where
                            heartbeats to heart and joys unconfined Insure a perfect rest unto the peaceful mind.
                            Reader, have I not told j ou Avhy I want to be a Shaker? Orange, Orange Co., Tex.</p></div2><pb n="7" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good desires" TEIform="index"/>GOOD DESIRES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>MARTHA J. ANDERSON</byline><p TEIform="p">I would that my hands were swifter Love's duties to fulfill, To meet life's needs in earnest
                            deeds, As prompts the heart and will. I would that my feet were fleeter To move with the
                            mind intent, To answer the call, do good to all, On heavenly missions bent. I would that my
                            tongue in praises Might tenderly, lovingly speak, That never a word by passion stirred,
                            Would injure the strong or weak. I would that my lips might seal the vow, That nectar may
                            from them fall, Life's golden cup with joy fill up, And blessing bring to all. I would that
                            my eyes were clearer; Their vision reaching far Might pierce the trail through the misty
                            vale And the gates of heaven unbar. I would that my ears were dull to sounds, That rise from
                            the world's great strife, And could only hear from the inner sphere The songs of eternal
                            life. I would that my heart's full measure O'erflowed in its melody, To meet the strain of
                            the glad refrain That floats from eternity. Oh, sun of my being's centre, Immortal and
                            God-like soul! Through outward things thy life takes wings Unto perfection's goal. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Calling the angels in" TEIform="index"/>CALLING THE ANGELS IN
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">We mean to do it. Some day, some day, We mean to slacken
                                    this fevered rush That is wearing our very souls away; And grant to our loaded
                                    hearts a hush That is only enough to let them hear The footsteps of angels drawing
                                    near. We mean to do it. Oh, never doubt, When the burden of daytime broil is o'er,
                                    We'll sit and muse while the stars come out, As the patriarchs sat at the open door
                                    Of their tents, with a heavenward-gazing eye, To watch for the angels passing by.
                                    We've seen them afar at high noontide, When fiercely the world's hot flashing beat:
                                    Yet never have bidden them turn aside, And tarry a while in converse sweet; Nor
                                    prayed them to hallow the cheer we spread To drink of our wine and break our bread.
                                    We promise our hearts that when the stress Of the life-work reaches the longed-for
                                    close [less, When the weight that we groan with, hinders We'll loosen o'^r thoughts
                                    to such repose As banishes Care's disturbing din. And then—we'll call the angels in.
                                    The day that we dreamed of comes at length, When, tired of every mocking quest, And
                                    broken in spirit and shorn of strength, We drop, indeed, at the door of rest, And
                                    wait and watch as the day wanes on— But the angels we meant to call are gone !</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Just criterion" TEIform="index"/>A JUST CRITERION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Calver, Amelia" TEIform="persName"/>AMELIA CALVER</byline><p TEIform="p">"How" said an earnest disciple of one of earth's truest noblemen, " shall I know in what
                            estimation I am held by my fellow man." " An easy problem that" was the allwise reply "
                            study to know what is your estimation of those whose minds you seek to read. " k'Ah but how
                            can that be a true measure, when we have occasion for so wide a difference in our
                            appreciation of others ; some you know are worthy of all honor ; some, merit it only at
                            times ; others are, by their very nature repulsive to any kindly thought ; I am sure I
                            cannot yet be measured by the first; I must not by the last, nor do I wish a fluctuating
                            merit like the second of the three classes. " " Indeed," was again the reply, " it is not by
                            any one act of your life, that its worth is weighed ; 7 <pb n="8" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO.
                            neither will your color of thought for any one individual, so reflect its corresponding ray,
                            as to brighten or blacken your whole life ; mass the thoughts you have for others, good, bad
                            and indifferent, find their average, and you have the picture of yourself, as reflected upon
                            the mind's retina of your surrounding friends." If, by lack of methodical thinking, this is
                            a knotty problem for you, write Jowa a list of all with whom you come in contact, and
                            opposite each name, write your general thought of the individual. Love and confidence
                            against those to whom it is due. Charity for those whose faults you reluctantly see ; thus
                            using every good in its various shades; but by no means neglect the evil you think of
                            others. Envy and jealousy, twin cause and effect; distrust with all its malignant train,
                            must stand to the front; and when after a careful assortment, you find the pre-eminence,
                            that you may take as your average standard, in the estimation of others. And furthermore, I
                            would say, if you wish to know what people say of you, measure yourself by this same rule ;
                            and should you find your list of evil speaking, longer than your kindly words for others,
                            beware, for such will inevitably be your harvest, unless your lot is fortunately cast among
                            those of an exceeding high grade of moral excellence, this is an exception, not the rule. On
                            the other hand, you may be kindly disposed to all, yet be unjustly represented for a season
                            ; this also is an exception which will naturally right itself in time. We can find no better
                            criterion by which to judge other's thoughts or words concerning us ; for we shall reap what
                            we sow if not all. This sensitiveness of reputation is an excellent guard, even where
                            conscience would be dilatory in its correction, if we can only remember not to say of
                            others, that which we do not wish said of us ; but pity, O, pity is for those, who so lost
                            to all right, all delicacy, that in their wrecklessness they do not care what others think
                            of them,— if there be such,—they alone are a bane of life for which there is no antidote.
                          Mt. Lebanon N. Y..</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Comforting reflections" TEIform="index"/>COMFORTING REFLECTIONS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Shepard, Harriet" TEIform="persName"/>HARRIET SHEPARD</byline><p TEIform="p">Where our Heavenly Father permits one angel to afflict, He always sends many more to comfort.
                            I have many angel friends who love me well. Their gentle expressions lead me by pleasant
                            ways, and their musical voices and the kindness of their words make me better. The passages
                            of scripture are pictures of immortality, dews of heavenly perception ; pearls of celestial
                            sweetness, and gems of divine wisdom. The Bible breathes of love, the home of the saints and
                            pleasures too pure to die. Would more of its divine instructions were practically mine and I
                            had strength and prudence enough to make them my constant guide. "Lo ! I am with you always"
                            is not a promise, but a declaration. Happiness does not so much depend on circumstances as
                            we think. Within our souls the fountain must abide, or no number of tributaries can long
                            keep active its joyous, gushing, delightful streams. If the consciousness of making others
                            happy is earth's purest happiness, may we not all learn how to obtain it? As the heavens are
                            higher than the 8 <pb n="9" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. earth, so are God's ways above our
                            ways ; it is not always the most useful who dwell longest in this mundane sphere, or to whom
                            the power of doing good is longest preserved. Let us all become more philanthropic ; lovers
                            of mankind ; sympathize more deeply with suffering, and open a hand more readily and more
                            widely to relieve it. "As the ancients held sacred the oak riven by the lightning, so a
                            sympathetic mind always regards one who has been afflicted, asiftouchedbythe hand of God
                            himself. " As in nature, the brightest sunshine casts the deepest shadow, so human life is
                            made up of contrasts of lights and shades, calms and storms, pleasures and sufferings. Now
                            the sky is covered with clouds, showers of rain are falling fast. Oh ! that the showers of
                            heavenly love and the sweets of forgiveness would so descend upon mankind as to make it all
                            like a well watered garden, bringing forth plentifully the fruits of righteousness. The
                            future is bright before many of my readers, and its emblems are big with joyous meaning.
                            Were I to ask a boon for each of you, it would not be a life free from adverse winds and
                            storms. Pleasure hath her ministers, but affliction alone subdues and strengthens the
                            spirit. As the rod of the sainted Hebrew brought grateful waters from the rock so sorrow
                            moves the susceptible springs of the heart. Forget not the farewell words of a good
                            Professor, "First of all be Bible students. " To be unenlightened in anything else may be
                            palliated, but if we lack knowledge of the Scriptures we have no apology. It will add
                            knowledge to our thoughts, tranquillity to our lives and thereby advantage will be ours, and
                            life shall be prolonged. North Union, Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Translation of the fifty-third chapter of Isaiah" TEIform="index"/>Translation of the
                            Fifty-third Chapter of Isaiah</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="McNemar, Richard" TEIform="persName"/>RICHARD MCNEMAR</byline><p TEIform="p">" Whoso hath confidently embraced our testimony, and in whom the seed of Jehovah hath
                            produced a change, he shall shoot forth as a young twig before him, and as a root out of dry
                            ground no form to him, no liberty to go about and be seen,and no appearance that he should
                            be lusted after. Despised and totally neglected of personalities, a person of the appearance
                            of a conjurer, feeling (or causing to feel) the most exquisite pain and as concealing his
                            aspect from us, he is despised and esteemed as nothing, surely he hath borne with our
                            weakness, and been burdened with our evil spirits! and at present we esteem him, in this
                            manner, in contact with God and humbling himself but he was pierced with our transgressions
                            and humbled by our acting upon him. To teach us, the way of peace is laid on him, and by
                            joining to him health, and soundness is restored to us. We all like sheep have gone astray,
                            Each one has turned to his own way; On him Jehovah caused to light, The only gift to set as
                            right. " Union Village, Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Experience" TEIform="index"/>EXPERIENCE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>MARY WHITCHER</byline><p TEIform="p">When farthest from this world of ours, And nearer to the distant shore, We feel the strength
                            of higher powers Which we have never felt before. How plain this truth to understand,— A
                            giving up ere we obtain What is above us or beyond, [claim. Though earth and heaven we both
                            might. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><pb n="10" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pleasant Hill, Kentucky, October 1885" TEIform="index"/>Pleasant Hill, Ky. Oct. 1885</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Brothek ;—Enclosed, please find draft on New York for amount of subscription to the
                                Manifesto by the Society at Pleasant Hill, Ky., for the current year, which we hope may
                                reach you in safety. We hope it may aid in the good cause, to keep the bright banner of
                                Truth waving, as hitherto, as a beacon light, with increasing effulgence, before a
                                benighted world, and lead them in the paths of Wisdom,—which are peace and pleasantness
                                to the Fountain of all good—Eternal Life—vuerethe sin-sick, sin-forsaking, upright
                                souls, can be freed from the bondage of sin, and find peace and rest, and dwell together
                                in the unity of the spirit and in the bonds of peace. And may that true light so shine
                                as to penetrate the mist of darkness that broods over a slumbering and sinful world, and
                                minister that word "which is quick and powerful, sharper than any two-edged sword ;" and
                                awaken and carry conviction into the hearts of the lovers and partakers of sin and
                                pleasures; and kindle that fire that shall burn as an oven, and lay bare the fountains
                                of iniqtiity that corrupt the world, and fill the earth with violence, " that all the
                                proud, yea all that do wickedly," may be consumed as stubble, that it may leave them
                                neither root nor branch in their sinful life, " For the wrath of God is revealed from
                                heaven, against all ungodliness and unrighteousness of men, who hold the truth in
                                unrighteousness." Professing to have the truth of salvation from sin, while living in
                                sin. All unrighteousness is sin, and sin when it is finished bringeth forth death. The
                                soul that sinneth it shall die. O ! the deceitfulness of the father of lies ; to blind
                                and deceive poor lost mortals in such manner, that they can lay the nattering unction to
                                their souls, that they can be saved in their sins. If they remain in their sins they are
                                not saved from sin, then what are they saved from ? But the voice of God to the fallen
                                race in mercy is, " Cleanse your hands, ye sinners, and purify your hearts, ye double
                                minded, and turn to the Lord and he will have mercy upon you, and to our God for he will
                                abundantly pardon." This will bring salvation from sin, and give peace and rest to the
                                soul. This standard is raised, a refuge for the weary travelers and sin-sick souls to
                                find peace and rest. And may the Herald of truth spread the tidings, to the ends of the
                                earth, and the light continue to glow with increasing splendor, a id the fire to burn
                                more fervently and sume the dross, till "the earth sh tl &gt;e filled with the
                                knowledge of the glorv of the Lord, as the waters cover the s a. "</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dunlavy, B. B." TEIform="persName"/>B. B. Dunlavy</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield, Massachusetts, December 1885" TEIform="index"/>West Pittsfield, Mass.
                                Dec. 1885</head><p TEIform="p">Our esteemed Manifesto :—We have often wished, for months past, to greet you with
                                encouraging expressions ; but for reasons (we do not like to tell you just yet,) we have
                                failed to respond to our promptings. There is an adage, something like this, that "Manas
                                he grows older, grows wiser and better. " This is true in some cases with both men and
                                women. But we are about to adapt this saying to you <pb n="11" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO.
                                11 dear Manifesto, thinking it can well be applied. You come to us every month promptly,
                                and every time laden with something worthy our thought, consideration and attention. We
                                find you maintaining the beautiful spirit of humility and peace. This spirit, we
                                realize, every religious reader is pleased with and will recommend. We would like here
                                to notice, and make mention of the many good and spiritually inspiring articles you have
                                given us within the year from dear Brethren and Sisters, as well as worthy selec- tions
                                from other auth . Here is an opportunity for sacrifice, and we must try and be brief,
                                knowing your love and necessity for this element,—brevity. We cannot do much but render
                                praise, and our hearty thanks to your contributors both aged and youth—all who have
                                worked in the least for yovir and our interest, and in behalf of those who do not
                                understand the "Way. " Your testimony has been calculated to point to religion "pure and
                                undefiled," full ol heavenly virtue. In Feb. No. (1885) Sister N. G. Danforth describes
                                the " Way, the Truth and the Life ;'' and then says, " in this way we crucify self. "
                                When this is accomplished we have no inclination to follow any other course. Then shall
                                we be filled with all the fullness of love, and inherit the reward of sweet peace when
                                we have come to our heavenly Parentage not by believing merely, but by actually living,
                                the "Way, the Truth and the Life. " The intelligent mind can see how that by cultivating
                                the higher and more spiritual part of the garden of the soul, the noxious and foul weeds
                                must wither and die out. These latter, Jesus said, "The Father hath not planted. " All
                                may be sure then that He will never recoguize or tolerate them. We must just mention
                                those wise sayings occasionally inserted by our well tried sister H. H. " Such as abide
                                in the light, no power can harm them. " And then those verses and short poems by dear
                                sister M. W. so often filling up your spaces give evidence and manifest the interest and
                                soul activity of such as have lived " unspotted before the world." It is good for us to
                                contemplate how these have made themselves white by coming up through tribulation and
                                risen above the "earth earthy," by living the "pure virgin life." Others we would like
                                to notice who have added to your wealth and ornament for the special benefit and better
                                understanding of your readers, of the Way and the Life of principles which hold the
                                saving power. Now dear Manifesto we dare not, must not, will not fail of accepting the "
                                Good Word" you have brought from time to time ; for in this we have a surety of being
                                partakers of the "Powers of the world to come." We will not engage your attention but a
                                few moments more. We have perused all your "Notes" with pleasure and pronounced them
                                good and for the interest of the people of all lands. Time has passed away so swiftly
                                that we cannot recall your age, but we know you are somewhat advanced in years, possibly
                                you will tell us sometime how old you are, at least how old you "think you are." The
                                passing year and your labors and kindly visits during its continuance are nearing the
                                end ; we again say, thanks for all your toil. And we wish that the New Year so close at
                                hand may open <pb n="12" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 12 THE MANIFESTO. upon you and all Christian
                                co-workers with manifold blessings. May they have clear vision and behold the prospect
                                of the glorious reward promised to such as endure and prove faithful to the end. Kindly
                                adieu,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Johnson, Betsey" TEIform="persName"/>Betsey Johnson</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="London, England, September 1885" TEIform="index"/>London, England, Sept. 1885</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Elbee Evans :—I have read the three years' numbers of the "Shaker and Shakeress" you
                                so kindly sent me, and cannot help expressing how agreeably surprised I was to find in
                                its pages so much in accordance with my own, and my wife's views. I have been much blest
                                in my soul in its perusal. Many of the sentiments contained therein we can fully indorse
                                ; and it is difficult to specialize any one article, as the best one, for the unity and
                                harmony of the writers are all of a price. They speak one pure language ; which I
                                believe is ultimately to be the language of the race—the universal Fatherhood and
                                Motherhood of God, and the Brotherhood of Man. Admitting of course the law of growth
                                from the lower kingdoms up to the perfected earthly one, and from thence into the
                                Kingdom of our Lord Jesus Christ; "where they neither marry nor are given in marriage
                                but are as the angels of God." We have been both delighted with the experiences of
                                different Brothers and Sisters who have been so many years in Shaker Communities, many
                                of them of an advanced age. Bless God they were ever brought into his kingdom on earth.
                                Such blessed testimonies speak for themselves and send a thrill of joy to the responsive
                                heart of those in the world who have not yet found a true home among true kindred
                                spirits. Ourselves pant for a fellowship that we cannot find in the churches of today. O
                                how empty are the professions of all man made creeds ; there is no room for the soul to
                                grow, you dare not express your thoughts, you are cramped and stunted at every turn.
                                There is no freedom for the spirit to work, or evolve a new thought, the mouth of
                                inspiration is closed, new revelations are not allowed in the churches. I find by the "
                                Shaker and Shakeress" that true inspiration is encouraged and truth from any source is
                                acceptable whether manifested by the saviors of the past, or by those of our times
                                through whom Christ, the spirit, makes known the will of God to men. Jesus said, on this
                                rock, namely, Christ the Spirit, will I build my Church, against which the gates of all
                                the hells shall not prevail. I feel 1 could say a good deal on this subject but forbear
                                at present. My wife joins me in love to you and to all the dear Brethren and Sisters. I
                                remain yours respectfully</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Alsop, P. B." TEIform="persName"/>P. B. Alsop</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Gloucester, Maine, December 1885" TEIform="index"/>West Gloucester, Me. Dec. 1885</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Readers, of our Excellent Magazine, The Manifesto:—In this world, a little time is
                                alloted us, in which we may do good to others and prepare ourselves, for the unseen fu-
                                ture "The Beautiful Beyond." Each of us have a mission here, to fulfill, therefore I
                                feel anxious to '' D© what good I can with care, " and as little harm as possible.
                                Wherever I see an opening for religious conversation I love to step in <pb n="13" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 13 and be a hearer of the word, and, hearing I would also
                                be a doer of the work. The human mind is something wonderful ! In it is a broad field of
                                thought, of labor. Our Magazine may be likened to a field of grain ; we sometimes find
                                in the farmer's field, several kinds of cereals sown, Wheat, Rye, Barley, Oats, and
                                perhaps Buckwheat, (all good and wholesome) all growing in one great field. Each, goes
                                to sustain life, the physical, so in our Manifesto, we find beautiful gems of thought
                                and precious grains of truth, purity and love and each is a lesson in and of itself, to
                                be learned, by the wise and prudent. Here also we find the names of our Brethren and
                                Sisters, who are fervent in spirit and who are to day, building their houses, not upon
                                the sands of time, but, upon the everlasting rock, the rock of ages. Let the rains
                                descend, and let the floods beat against houses like these, and they will stand unmoved
                                and unmarred through time and through all eternity. Who shall say that Shakerism is a
                                thing of the past, and is fast dying out ? Not I ! It is not in my heart, and may I
                                never be left to utter words like these. I firmly believe if we who are already called,
                                should dwindle and die out Shakerism would live. Its principles are living and not
                                dying; Life and not Death. Let us live, let us breathe in a clearer, purer atmosphere,
                                keeping alive o"ur good faith, by corresponding works of righteousness. Let us not keep
                                our lips closed, for the testimony of our good mother, must be preserved in its purity
                                and sweetness. How shall it be done? If these shall hold their peace, the very stones
                                will cry out against them, (said one anciently. ) Will it not be said of us, if we keep
                                silent? In this Book of ours, I find still other names, those whose names are registered
                                in the Heaven's, "The Lamb's Book of Life, " and while I read the sacred records which
                                they left, let me not read them, as I would, some "old, old story, " which perhaps might
                                please and interest for the moment; nay I would read with care and thoughtfulness, with
                                deep concern, and a desire to be profited thereby. I would compare my life with their
                                lives, my sacrifices with their consecrations, my religion, with the religion which they
                                taught and which they as earnestly lived. These have passed from death unto life, they
                                have gone up higher to enjoy the sweets of immortality, the fruits of their labor. To
                                these dear ones has come the harvest time; they are reaping those golden grains, to
                                which we refer sometimes in our beautiful songs. Let us hold their names in loving
                                remembrance, and emulate their glorious example. I am reminded just here of another
                                little Book, very precious to most of us, we could not well do without it. It is the
                                book of memory. Let us turn back some of the leaves and carefully read those well filled
                                pages, they tell us of wonderful things. We read that about the year 1840 and 41, there
                                was a revival of tru-3 religion, in the Shaker Churches, throughout the land. The angels
                                of the Lord came down and great power was manifest (many were blest with heavenly
                                visions, prior to this time) but now came something greater, a baptism of the Holy
                                Spirit and fire. It was then I received this heavenly baptism. One by one I confessed my
                                sins, as 1 committed them and this I did <pb n="14" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 14 THE MANIFESTO. without
                                making any reserve. Full well did I know then as now, that the Ananias • and Sapphira,
                                spirit, could not, would not prosper. I wanted no part nor lot in it. I aspired only to
                                be a true heir to a gospel inheritance, a child of God. How glad I am that I began this
                                work, early in life and gave my heart to God. The little sacrifices I have made from
                                time to time, are but small when compared with the blessings I have received,—the
                                blessings of a Gospel Parentage. Dear Friends, I believe in inspiration. The inspiration
                                of to day, which leads good men and women to do noble deeds of love ; to speak words of
                                truth, which the world hath no power to gainsay. These are the able workers of our time.
                                They speak out and tell the people, what are the crying evils in our land; the secret
                                abominations, that bring down the judgments of God, upon the people. These men and these
                                women are called of the Lord. They are the servants of the Most High, and this is their
                                work, none others can do it as effectually as they. Blessed, yea thrice blessed are all
                                such. Go on dear friends, friends in the cause of right. Friends to our glorious
                                institution, go on, and may the Lord sustain you, and his right arm of power be your
                                support. The world needs you, every one. Ye are workers in the Master's great field, and
                                each will receive a just reward, at the harvest time. Life is short. Let us dear gospel
                                friends, do our work faithfully, cheerfully and keep our identity ; that by the lives we
                                live, the dress we wear, and the language we speak, we may be a " Light to the world,"
                                (not hidden under a bushel) but a shining light which will never go down, but will grow
                                brighter and brighter unto the perfect day. 80 will our fathers and our mothers bless us
                                and we shall become a strong people, whose God is the Lord, and it shall not be heard in
                                all Israel, " Shakerism is a thing of the past and is fast dying out, " but those who
                                are known as Shakers, will live in the hearts of the people, a praise in the Earth a
                                glory in all the Land, while their names will appear in the u Book of Life," wrought in
                                letters of Gold.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Gillespie, Mary A." TEIform="persName"/>Mary A. Gillespie</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We shall know" TEIform="index"/>WE SHALL KNOW
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lanphere, A. T." TEIform="persName"/>A. T. LANPHERE
                        </byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> We shall know when in the future Death shall roll
                                    the mists away, Hiding from our earthly vision Glimpses of the coming day; When the
                                    shadows o'er us passing Shall be merged in joyous light, And earth's sombre eolored
                                    garments Shall be changed for spotless white. We shall know when in the morning We
                                    awake to clearer light, Freed from all the doubts and darkness That environ us at
                                    night; When the sunshine of our being Shines in splendor o'er the hills, And the
                                    beauty of existence All our joyous being fills. We shall know, Ah ! golden vision,
                                    When life's weary watch is o'er, Why our barques are rudely driven Ere they reach
                                    the quiet shore ; Why the storms of passion raging Throw their shadows o'er our way,
                                    Ere the night of sin and sorrow Ripens into perfect day. We shall know why death
                                    hath veiled us From the presence of our own; Why our dearest ones have left us In
                                    this world of care alone; Why these partings, and these longings For the dear ones
                                    gone before; <pb n="15" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 15 Why we ford the stream of
                                    sorrow Ere we reach the further shore. We shall know why the Eternal In his wisdom
                                    placed us here, Why we pass through earthly shadows Ere we reach life's golden
                                    sphere ; Why the sunshine follows darkness— Why the morning follows night— Why the
                                    darkest hour in passing Ushers in the morning light. We shall know, Ah! blest
                                    assurance, More than mortal mind can know ; We shall roam where crystal fountains
                                    O'er the sands of knowledge flow ; All our sorrows will be banished By the joys of
                                    love divine, While the light from God's eternal Throne, shall round about us shine.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Religio-philosophical journal" TEIform="index"/>Religio-Philosophical Journal</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tale-bearer" TEIform="index"/>TALE-BEARER
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The words that can never be recalled. A penitent to a holy father
                                    went; Confession of her sins was her intent, And so her misdemeanors, great and
                                    small, She faithfully rehearsed them all; And chief in her catalogue of sin, She
                                    owned that she a tale-bearer had heen And borne a bit of scandal up and down To all
                                    the long-tongued gossips in the town. The holy father for her other sins, Granted
                                    the absolution asked of him; But while for all the rest he pardon gave, He told her
                                    this offence was very grave, And that to do lit penance she must go Out by the
                                    wayside, where the thistles grow, And gathering the largest, ripest one, Scatter its
                                    seeds, and that when this was done, She must come back again another day To tell
                                    him; his commands she must obey.---Feeling right glad she had escaped feo well, She
                                    went next day but one, the priest to tell; The priest sat still, and heard her story
                                    through, Then said, there's something still for you to do; Those little thistle
                                    seeds which you have sown, I bid you to re-gather every one. The woman said, " But
                                    father, it would be in vain To try to gather up these seeds again; The winds have
                                    scattered them both far and wide; O'er the meadowed vale and mountain side, " The
                                    father answered; " May I hope from this, The lesson I have taught you will not miss
                                    ? You cannot gather back the scattered seeds, Which far and wide will grow to
                                    noxious weeds, Nor can the mischief once by scandal sown, By any penance be again
                                    undone. "</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If God's omnipotent, and reigns o'er all..." TEIform="index"/>
                            If God's omnipotent, and reigns o'er all...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">If God's omnipotent, and reigns o'er all, The starry systems, great and small! Two hundred
                            millions: they count at least, While billions of creatures on each would And provisions
                            there for all. [feast, Yet puny, selfish, erring man, On this small world, for God, will
                            plan ; Be teaching daily, what He should do, To save his race, or, at least a few! Perhaps
                            'tis best that He can do, From " Adam's fabled fall. " Why should a God to man not say;
                            ''Leave me alone, I beg, I pray! For, should I your pleadings all obey, My God-ship would be
                            cast away! And you would rule ; not I! Did I make worlds, and all life too, And know not
                            then, what's best to do? That worms of dust, Yea erring man Should knuw what's best, and for
                            me plan ! Don't I all life supply? Who brings your Seasons, rain and snow; Who makes all
                            things on worlds to grow? Your fruits and flowers, all grain and seed, Your fish and beasts,
                            all fowls I feed, Without their prayers each day ! Can you not learn—all Nature's plan ? How
                            all was made for beast and man ! Can you not live and honest be ? Then never; need you pray
                            to Me ! So I might rest, I pray ! " (Amen.)</p><byline TEIform="byline">— <persName reg="Newcomer, George" TEIform="persName"/>George Newcomer, M. D. Cleveland, Ohio</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Zion's glory and advancement..." TEIform="index"/>Zion's glory and advancement...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Zion's glory and advancement, depend on the advocacy and maintenance of heavenly principles
                            and beatitudes, that shall be an out-growth from within, of true spirituality and soul
                            travel. All the outward adornment and beautifying of her courts, cannot compensate for the
                            lack of redeeming and resurrecting power, that binds souls together in the unity of the
                            spirit of Christ, and makes them strong pillars in her temple, to go no more out.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="A., M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. A.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is just as much of a duty to commend a person for doing well, as to reprove him for doing ill" TEIform="index"/>
                            It is just as much of a duty to commend a person for doing well, as to reprove him for doing ill
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">It is just as much of a duty to commend a person for doing well, as to reprove
                                    him for doing ill.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A bright day may as truly exist without light, as true religion without love" TEIform="index"/>
                            A bright day may as truly exist without light, as true religion without love
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A bright day may as truly exist without light, as true religion without love.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="16" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>THE MANIFESTO. JANUARY, 1886</head><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Manifesto. 1886" TEIform="index"/>THE MANIFESTO. 1886.</head><p TEIform="p">Office of publication. The Manifesto is published at Shaker Village, Mer. Co. N. H. All
                                articles for publication should be addressed to Henry C. Blinn, and all letters on
                                financial business to A. Y. Cochran. TERMS. One copy per year, postage paid, .75 " " six
                                months, " .40 Send two cent stamp for specimen copy.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="1886: more work for willing laborers" TEIform="index"/>1886. More Work for Willing
                                Laborers</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Again we welcome the dawning of a New Year ! Hail Happy, New Year ! May it be filled with
                                abundant blessings to every one; with an out-pouring of the gifts and graces of the
                                Divine Spirit, and bring to us that increase which may be desired by a pure and honest
                                heart. In the rapid march of time it seems but a few days since we were calling the
                                attention of our readers, of the Manifesto, to this same duty, at the introduction of a
                                previous year. Since that date our little messenger, in the spirit of the sacred
                                Teacher, has gone into the homes of thousands and carried to them the revelation of
                                God's love to man. All who have taken an interest in this beautiful work of glad tidings
                                and in helping to sow the seeds of goodness and truth in the hearts of mankind, will
                                most assuredly feel a blessing of God in their souls. Those who work for God are earning
                                a treasure which the world can neither give nor take away. In the simplicity of our
                                souls we love to take a review and accept the comforting assurance that while our
                                efforts are but a feeble offering, yet it has been one of which we need not be ashamed.
                                Our labor is that of Love. God in his merciful kindness has given to us of the abundance
                                of his blessings, and as worthy and faithful sons and daughters, we should anxiously
                                proffer the same to our fellow man so far as we are able. "Freely ye have received,
                                freely give." The opening of the New Year should also awaken new thoughts and clothe us
                                with inspirational zeal to bear in our lives that light which shall safely direct the
                                Zion traveler into Wisdom's ways of pleasantness and into her paths of peace. It should
                                impress upon our minds the necessity of active and continued efforts in the work which
                                has become our haven of rest in this life, and our assurance of the promise of our
                                Savior in the world to come. We should work while our day lasts, and send out from month
                                to month that testimony of truth which we have received from God, and which in the
                                honesty of our hearts we, believe is for the peace and happiness of our fellow man. It
                                requires but a limited observation to see quite readily the urgent demands that are
                                needed on every hand. Angels of mercy and charity are at every door, while there is so
                                much sin and suffering. The appalling flood of intemperance that is in the land must
                                make the heart of every sensitive Christian man and woman tremble, through dread of the
                                fearful consequences that may overtake them from day to day. Our order cannot wholly
                                escape the burdens which come through the wide spread traffic in intoxicating liquors.
                                While we regret the sad havoc that has been made in many noble minds, "we can JANUARY,
                                    <pb n="17" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 17 only be assured of preservation by vigilant
                                watch through every coming day. The Manifesto is a witness for the testimony of Jesus
                                Christ, in its selfdenial, in its separation from the world, in its virgin life, and in
                                its consecration of soul and body to the service *of God. For the term of fifteen years
                                it has maintained, unflinchingly, a straight forward course in the advocacy of a better
                                and better life for man and woman. If the march from the habits and practices of the
                                world has been slow, we trust that it has been satisfactory and that what may have been
                                gained in the principles of righteousness, will not fade away and be lost from our
                                spiritual home.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If the church would have power over the world..." TEIform="index"/>
                                If the church would have power over the world...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">—If the church would have power over the world and be able to bring men to Christ, she
                                must be zealous in spirit, pure in heart and holy in life. She cannot successfully
                                convince men of the necessity of salvation, unless she practically exhibits its
                                blessings and its virtues. By her daily walk she must demonstrate that there is a higher
                                and holier plain of life tban tbe world occupies. By this she must convince men that
                                vital piety is the inheritance of the Saint, and that a life and a walk with God, means
                                separation from all that is worldly, sinful and impure. If she fails to do this, and
                                becomes formal and cold-bearted, her arm for good will become palsied and her glory
                                depart. In that degree that she lays asidft her holy seriousness, in the same degree,
                                she not only dishonors her Lord, but loses her hold en the confidence of men.—-Star and
                                Crown. It is with pleasure that we take the above from the Star and Grown and present it
                                to our readers as a thoughtful and careful admonition. It is in the interest of the
                                church and we will say of the church militant which must keep up an aggressive warfare
                                against the sins of the world. It is an interest of right over wrong in which the
                                witnesses of God arise to teach men to walk and work in practical righteousness, through
                                which is to come the salvation of the race. Any manifestation which awakens us to more
                                active duty, that stimulates care and sympathy for all our fellow men, is the
                                inspiration of God which will sustain us through all trials, and direct us to that home
                                eternal in the heavens. The church of Christ has a mission, indeed, of life and light to
                                perform which may not be deferred. It is a duty which carries with it weighty responsi-
                                bilities. "I must work the works of him that sent me, while it is day," said Jesus, for
                                "the night cometh, when no man can work." If the church would have power over the world,
                                it must be an honest representative of the divine Teacher. The work is clearly defined ;
                                there is not the shadow of mystery. "Let your light so shine before men, that they may
                                see your good works, and glorify your Father which is in heaven. " There must be light
                                and by this light will be seen the pure in heart, the spirit of peace and the anxiety
                                for righteousness. The church can have no influence for direct good, if it condescends
                                to walk with the world. Wherever this is done, in the least degree, the church becomes
                                crippled, loses its spiritual power and suffers, in its fulness, the penalty which the
                                transgression inflicts. Kighteousness and unrighteousness cannot be expected to
                                harmonize, and the attempt to reconcile both in one mind will always prove a failure.
                                The apostle has left for our careful consideration this wise remark.—To be spiritually
                                    <pb n="18" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 18 THE MANIFp;STO. minded is life and peace, but to be car-
                                nally minded is death. In this the church has its course so carefully laid out that
                                there can be no need of failure, if the plan is carefully regarded.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Facts worth remembering" TEIform="index"/>FACTS WORTH REMEMBERING</head><p TEIform="p">Sudden Deaths do not come from heart disease, one case in twenty, but from congestion of
                                the lungs or brain, or from apoplexy. More die from congestion of the lungs than of the
                                brain, and more of congestion of the brain than from apoplexy. Sudden death from heart
                                disease is usually caused by rupture of some large artery near the heart; from
                                congestion of the lungs, by instantly stopping the breath; from congestion of the brain,
                                by causing pressure on the brain, which paralyzes and instantly destroys life; from
                                apoplexy, by hemorrhage in the brain. Heart disease most frequently results from
                                neglected or improperly-treated rheumatism. It more often follows mild rheumatism than
                                the severe kind, because severe rheumatism receives prompt treatment, while the mild
                                form is often neglected and left to work its way to the heart. Persons who suppose
                                themselves suffering from heart disease, because they have pain in the region of the
                                heart, palpitation, seldom have any disease of that organ. In nine cases out of ten,
                                they are sufferers from dyspepsia—nothing more. Congestion of the lungs is most
                                frequently caused by a sudden change from the heat of an ill-ventilated room or railroad
                                car, or street car, to the cold air outside, without being protected by sufficient
                                clothing; hence, many persons thus seized drop dead in the streets. Congestion of the
                                brain most frequently results from trouble and anxiety of mind, producing sleeplessness,
                                followed by engorgement of the small blood vessels of the brain, sudden loss of vital
                                power, and almost instant death. Apoplexy may be an inherited disease, or it may be
                                induced by too free living, or its opposite, too great abstemiousness. Paralysis may
                                affect only a small portion of the body, from a finger or toe to an entire limb, or it
                                may disable half the body, or the whole body, when death soon follows. When half the
                                body is affected by paralysis, we may be certain that the seat of the disease is in the
                                opposite side of the brain, because nerve fibres cross. Partial paralysis is often
                                temporary when caused by the rupture of a small bloodvessel, if the clot is got rid of
                                by absorption or otherwise. Although this is a disease that all classes of people are
                                liable to, its most destructive work is done among the depraved and dissipated. There is
                                no doubt that the habitual use of tobacco is one of the most prominent causes of
                                paralysis and other nerve diseases. A Severe Cold can be soonest cured byremaining
                                within doors, in a warm room and near the fire, until all signs of.it have disap-
                                peared. Then care should be taken to prevent a relapse by having the feet warmly clad,
                                and the whole body, and particularly the chest and the back of the neck, well protected
                                when going out. A Kecent Cough will almost always yield to the following treatment
                                within two or three days : Mix in a bottle 4 ounces of glycerine, 2 ounces of alcohol, 2
                                ounces of water, 2 grains of morphine. Shake well. Dose for an adult, 1 to 2
                                teaspoonfuls every 2 or 3 hours. Half this quantity to children from 10 to 15 years. It
                                is not safe to give it to infants or children under 10 years of age. To Stop Bleeding,
                                if from a cavity in the jaw after a tooth has been extracted, shape a cork into the
                                proper form and size to cover the bleeding cavity, and long enough to be kept firmly in
                                place when the mouth is closed. This, we believe, is our own invention, and we have
                                never known it to fail. It has served us in desperate cases. When an Artery is Cut, the
                                red blood spurts out at each pulsation. Press the thumb firmly over the artery, near the
                                wound, and on the side toward the heart. Press hard enough to stop the bleeding, and
                                wait till a physician comes. The wounded person is <pb n="19" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO.
                                19 often able to do this himself, if he has the requisite knowledge. The main object of
                                this "Journal" is to teach its readers, not only how to protect themselves from
                                diseases, but how to save life in accidents and emergencies. Simple Fractures may be
                                adjusted by almost any one. Get the limb as near as possible in the natural position,
                                and then send for a doctor. There is no great urgency in such cases. In Case of
                                Poisoning, the simple rule is to get the poison out of the stomach as soon as possible.
                                Mustard and salt act promptly as emetics, and they are always at hand. Stir a
                                tablespooniul in a glass of water, and let the person swallow it quickly. If it does not
                                cause vomiting in five minutes, repeat the dose. After vomiting, give the whites of two
                                or three eggs, and send for the doctor. In Fracture of the Skull, with compression and
                                loss of consciousness, examine the wound, and if possible, raise the broken edges of the
                                skull so as to relieve the pressure on the brain. Prompt action would often save life.
                                Burns and Scalds are soonest relieved by an application of cold water. Dry carbonate of
                                soda, or baking soda, sprinkled over the burned spot, is the latest remedy, and is said
                                to be very effectual. These means are only temporary. In severe cases, a physician
                                should be sent for. — HalVs Journal of Health.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christmas" TEIform="index"/>CHRISTMAS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bush, Cornelius" TEIform="persName"/>CORNELIUS BUSH</byline><p TEIform="p">How the tinkle, tinkle of the bells carry our minds back to our childhood. The gentle snow so
                            soft and white seems to come for the delight of children both old and young, for, although
                            our hair may turn gray, and our eyes grow dim. yet the fi'rst sight of the snow, which is an
                            emblem of purity and innocence, seems to make us all young, so that the boy of fifty can
                            feel the life and glow of the boy of ten, and almost forgets the intervening space of years.
                            It is truly said that the soul which is the source of the mind, is forever young ; that it
                            is only the body that grows old, and sometimes I think, that when we have laid off this
                            garment, which'we call our body, we shall find ourselves only children, with one Father, and
                            one Mother, God ! and that other children, some older than ourselves, will as of old, help
                            us over the rough paths, and dark places, and although to our eyes the waiting may seem
                            long, yet in good time, we shall all be gathered to our Father's and Mother's home in
                            heaven. North Un io n, Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Friendship" TEIform="index"/>FRIENDSHIP
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">How hard it is to find a friend, One on whom we can depend. Sometimes
                                    we think the treasure got Till trial proves we have it not. Many, to serve their
                                    selfish ends, Warmly declare they are your friends : But soon as serving self is
                                    o'er, Behold they are your friends no more. Others will act a part more base,—
                                    Always be friendly to your face; You turn your back, then they your name Expose to
                                    obloquy and shame. Apparent friendship others show, That you may confidence bestow ;
                                    Your secrets thus they oft obtain, And use to injure your good name. Those who of
                                    others tell you much, My counsel is, Beware of such ; They bring your neighbor's
                                    faults to view, And, absent, speak the same of you. A faithful friend I highly
                                    prize, But mere pretense I do despise. Whene'er disposed a friend to trust, Be
                                    always sure to prove him first.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="20" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kind words" TEIform="index"/>KIND WORDS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hancock, Massachusetts, September 1885" TEIform="index"/>Hancock, Mass., Sep. 1885</head><p TEIform="p">We are glad that you continue to publish the MANIFESTO. It is a neat and most welcome
                                messenger,—soul feasting and morally uplifting. We pray for its continuance.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sweet, Julia L." TEIform="persName"/>Julia L. Sweet</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York, September 1885" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., Sept. 1885</head><p TEIform="p">The Circulars, "What shall I DO to Become a Shaker " and " Information for Inquirers "
                                are at hand. They are neatly printed and fully satisfactory. We have sent some into
                                several of the states and have also sent some to England. We will circulate our leaflets
                                and pamphlets and books to herald the Christian Invitation. Your Brother</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>Giles B. Avery</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York, October 1885" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., Oct. 1885.</head><p TEIform="p">Prosperity to the MANIFESTO.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Basting, Louis" TEIform="persName"/>Louis Basting</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Canton Missouri, October 1885" TEIform="index"/>Canton Mo., Oct. 1885</head><p TEIform="p">The Oct. MANIFESTO is at hand, addressed to "Risk's Library. " I have read it myself, and
                                find valuable information in each number. Thanks. It will always be distributed among
                                appreciative readers. Your brother, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Risk, J. C." TEIform="persName"/>J. C. Risk</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Turner Public Library" TEIform="index"/>TURNER PUBLIC LIBRARY</head><p TEIform="p">Randolph Mass. Nov., 1885. Editor of the Manifesto, Dear Sir :—Permit me to officially
                                recognize your favor, and thank you heartily for your kindness in placing at our
                                disposal your very neat and estimable publication, "The Manifesto." Its pages are bright
                                with good words and Christian cheer. The MANIFESTO—so characteristic of the Shaker world
                                and ways—is ever welcome, always read and carefully preserved. Yours very truly</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Farnham, Charles C." TEIform="persName"/>Charles C. Farnham, Librarian</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Concord, New Hampshire, December 1885" TEIform="index"/>Concord, N. IL, Dec. 1885</head><p TEIform="p">The trustees of the "Concord Public Library" gratefully acknowledge the receipt of one
                                copy of the MANIFESTO from Jan. to Dec. 1885.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Secomb, D. F." TEIform="persName"/>D. F. Secomb. Librarian</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="As a man eateth so is he" TEIform="index"/>AS A MAN EATETH SO IS HE
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Who, temperate, lives On fruit and grain, Is clear in
                                    thought And free from pain.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Star and crown" TEIform="index"/>Star and Crown.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Rev. Samuel Jones, the southern Evangelist..." TEIform="index"/>
                            The Rev. Samuel Jones, the southern Evangelist...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The Rev. Samuel Jones, the southern Evangelist, says in one of his sermons,— "Every man and
                            woman has to get every vestige of the hog element out of their characters before they can
                            become Christians. I am here to assist in destroying this hog element. 0 Lord, come down and
                            help us kill hogs. I want this to be a regular hog killing meeting.'' The Rev. Samuel hits
                            the nail square on the head. He is right. The hog element should be driven out. Men and
                            women, north and south need something better to warrant them a recommendation into the ''
                            Holy City." By all means keep the hog out of the souls and bodies of the Christians. Thirty
                            thousand acres of tobacco are under cultivation in the state of Wisconsin. The Methodist
                            conferences held in the state declare their belief that Christian men ought not to raise or
                            sell tobacco.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My creed" TEIform="index"/>MY CREED</head><p TEIform="p">I hold that Christian grace abounds Where charity is seen; that, when We climb to heaven,
                            'tis on the rounds Of love to men. This I moreover hold, and dare Affirm where'er my rhyme
                            may go : Whatever things be sweet or fair, Love makes them so.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cary, Alice" TEIform="persName"/>Alice Cary</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Either be silent, or say something..." TEIform="index"/>Either be silent, or say something...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">" Either be silent, or say something that is better than silence, " was the advice of a
                            Heathen sage, which it would be well for all to ponder.</p></div2><pb n="21" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Not one sparrow" TEIform="index"/>NOT ONE SPARROW</head><p TEIform="p">Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. Not one sparrow is for gotten, E'en the raven God will feed; And the lily
                            of the valley From his bounty hath its need. Then shall I not trust Thee, Father, In thy
                            mercy have a share? And through faith and prayer, my Mother, Merit thy protecting care?</p></div2><pb n="22" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Diary: a trip to Sodus Bay, New York" TEIform="index"/>DIARY. A Trip to Sodus Bay, N. Y.</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Whitcher, Benjamin" TEIform="persName"/>ELDER BENJ. WHITCHER</byline><p TEIform="p">On the 9th. of June 1834 we, the Ministry,! leave the Society of Enfield, N. H., at three
                            o'clock A. M. and reach Windser Vt., a distance of twenty two miles, where we stop a few
                            hours for the good of ourselves and our horses. We pass through Wethersfield, Chester and
                            into Andover. We are now fifty three miles from Enfield, and conclude to remain here through
                            the night. June 10th. We pass through Peru, Arlington and reach Jackson, and stop in this
                            place the second night. June Hth. On reaching Pittstown we meet Br. Frederic Wicker and two
                            Sisters from the Society in Watervliet, N. Y. They have come some thirteen miles to see us
                            and to welcome us to their home, where we arrive at five o'clock, P. M., a distance of one
                            hundred and thirty seven miles from Enfield. Among these gospel friends we receive a very
                            kind welcome, from the Ministry, Elders, Brethren and Sisters. June 12th. AVe walk to the
                            orchards and to the gardens. Every thing is flourishing. In the garden we find several
                            Sisters picking strawberries. We pass to the mill where some of the Brethren are engaged in
                            the carding of wool. At the Second Order we meet Br Aaron Wood, and listen with pleasure,
                            while he sings some of the beautiful songs that he learned of Mother Ann and the Elders. The
                            children at the Second Family make a recitation of some Scripture lessons, which are useful
                            to them and very interesting to us. June 14th. We make a short visit in the South Family On
                            our return to the First Family in the P. M., we enter the Cemetery. Every thing is neatly
                            and simply arranged. The stones, instead of bearing the whole name of the individual, had
                            only the initials. June 15. A public service is held in the A. M., which is well attended.
                            At 1.30 P. M., the Church Family held a service in the t Elder Benjamin Whitcher, Br. Joseph
                            Johnson, Eldress Esther Ferrin, Sr. Lucy Williams. same place which was a season of
                            spiritual refreshment. These stand among the first of our gospel blessings, and for which we
                            should ever return our humble thanks and praise to our Heavenly Father. June 16th. We leave
                            our kind friends at Watervliet and are taken to Schenectady, where we expect to enter a "
                            Packet Boat. " Two rail roads enter this place; one from the City of Albany and the other
                            from Bawlstown. This manner of traveling was entirely new to all in our company and we were
                            very much interested to see the cars come and go. They were drawn by horses and as many as
                            thirty persons left the cars that were drawn by one horse. At eleven o'clock we went on
                            board the " Packet. " It was the United States, under the direction of captain Boswell
                            Ilaskill. Our journey is now through a beautiful section of country, dotted here and there
                            with fields of wheat, rye, oats and corn. Our boat glides pleasantly along at a moderate
                            speed, giving us ample time to view the surrounding country, which proves to be very
                            satisfactory. At nine P. M., the passengers are all called upon to choose their berths for
                            the nightAs there were fifty or more persons on board, it was rather an amusing scene, and
                            very much like a child's play. Being strangers to this mode of traveling, the captain very
                            kindly made choice for us. The hours of night finally passed away and we had the
                            satisfaction of enjoying some rest. June 17th. On the approach of daylight we are again on
                            deck, enjoying the beautiful scenery that is spread out for several miles on each side of
                            the canal. We pass the village of Frankfort at five o'clock, A. M. We were interested in the
                            very nice appearance of the meeting house. It was attractive. We also observe several
                            stores, two taverns and some of the dwellings which had, recently, been finished. At Utica
                            we go on board of another boat, the " Swan, " which is under the direction of Captain
                            Wellington. With all our baggage on board, we start with a good team and a brisk wind for
                            Rochester. It is said that our speed is quite rapid for canal navigation. Excellent farms
                            are constantly before us which represent the industry of the managers. Contrasted with the
                            farms <pb n="23" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 23 of New Hampshire, this becomes a wonderful
                            country. We pass the village of Whitestown and the buildings are so neatly painted, and all
                            being white, that everything looks apparently new. We now pass through extensive woodlands
                            where a variety of trees may be seen. It is a level expanse as far as the sight can ex-
                            tend. A large stone building is seen, and we are informed that it is the U. S. Arsenal. The
                            roof'is covered with tin. We speak particularly of this, as it is the first building that we
                            have seen covered in this manner. In the great prophetic future when nations shall learn war
                            no more, and when pruning hooks shall be used instead of spears, a more peaceful occupation
                            may be carried on within these beautiful walls. It is raining and the passengers are driven
                            below. Some twenty persons are doing the best they can to pass the time pleasantly. The best
                            of order is maintained and we sail along quite comfortably. Two Indian boys are running by
                            the side of our boat. It was some time before we could comprehend what this could mean, but
                            soon learned that they were money catchers, and that they would sometimes follow the boat
                            for several miles to obtain a few pennies. It was, in fact, a matter of business. Some of
                            the passengers to have a little sport would occasionally throw a few cents into the muddy
                            bank, when the little fellows would spring to see which should get to them first. In their
                            eagerness to obtain the pennies they covered themselves quite freely with mud. June 18th. As
                            the sun rises, we rise and again go on deck. A beautiful country is before us of evergreen
                            pastures and fruitful fields. We enjoy, more and more, the loveliness of the scenery which
                            is so varied and at the same time so beautifully new. We pass an extensive track of land
                            called the marshes of Montezuma. Thousands of acres are covered with flags, flat grass and
                            rushes. Passing this we enter a beautiful country where the wheat fields are in advance of
                            anything that we have yet seen. At the village of Lyons we meet several of the Brethren and
                            Sisters who live in the Society at Sodus. They are twelve miles from their home. We accomany
                            them to the tavern where they have prepared tor us a sumptuous meal. We accept the kindness
                            with thankful hearts and rejoice with them that we have arrived safely so near the home of
                            our gospel friends. At 3.30 P. M. we are in the Believers'settlement and are received with
                            great kindness. June 19th. We have an interview with the me:r,bers of the Church Family,
                            which numbers about fifty persons. June 20th. We join our friends and take a ride to the
                            shore of Sodus Bay. It is a very enjoyable privilege and affords us much pleasure in the new
                            forms of scenery. The company are taken into a small boat and we sail across the bay to the
                            shore of Lake Ontario. We are near the site of a temporary fort that was thrown up in the
                            war of 1812. On a high point of land, not far distant, where the bank of the lake is nearly
                            thirty feet in height, we had an excellent view of this great body of water. In the distance
                            we discover a ship and a steamboat. After partaking of a refreshing lunch we go on board our
                            boat and row along on the north side of the bay. On our return we call at the East Family,
                            which numbers about twenty persons. At this place we measure the stump of a chestnut tree
                            and find it to be five feet and four inches in diameter. Everything seems to have a
                            wonderful growth. For a smoke house, in which to cure meat, the Brethren had made use of a
                            hollow Sycamore tree. (To BE CONCLUDED.)</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Guided" TEIform="index"/>GUIDED</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>MARY WHITCHER</byline><p TEIform="p">Through reason and conscience The Spirit meets me ; I hear not a voice And no object I see. I
                            feel, heaven grant it The guide of the true,— And with this sweet influence My course I
                            pursue. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Most men mistake the love for the practice of virtue, and are not so much good men as the friends of goodness" TEIform="index"/>
                            Most men mistake the love for the practice of virtue, and are not so much good men as the friends of goodness
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Most men mistake the love for the practice of virtue, and are not so much good
                                    men as the friends of goodness.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="24" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pansy" TEIform="index"/>The Pansy
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pansy" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The Pansy edited by "Pansy" herself holds a place in the hearts of the children and also
                                of the parents. Reaching Out wiH be Pansy's serial story for 1886. Golden Text stories
                                will be an interesting feature. The story of St. George and the Dbagon, by Margaret
                                Sidney will run through the year. Stories of discoveries, inventions, people etc., will
                                be told by Rev. C. M.Livingstone. Pansy will write under the title—Where I went and what
                                I gaw,—Each number will contain selections from our standard poets, suitable for
                                recitation, &amp;c. Space will be devoted to answers to correspondents. Fully
                                illustrated. $1.00 a year. Address orders to D. Lothrop and Co. Franklin and Hawley St.
                                Boston, Mass. " WIT A T TOMMY DID. " John llabberton author of "Helen's Babies'' says:
                                "'What Tommy Did' would be worthy of the serious consideration of parents if it were
                                possible for any one to be other than wildly mirthful over the saintlinesses and
                                dreadfulnesses of the little'hero. Tommy is an ideal boy—one of (lie kind which are by
                                turns unendurable and angelic, which changes parents from young to old, and from old to
                                young again many times a day. We pity parents who fail to read this book; there is no
                                time in the day, nor any day in the week, in which its pages will not dispel care. ' The
                                Chicago Tribune pronounces it a book that " will delight every boy and girl, and every
                                mother too, who will find in it a book that can be read over and over again to suit the
                                insatiable appetites, of you1 hful listeners, and yet never sicken the reader with any
                                weakness or nonsense in its composition. "--It has just been published in dainty
                                delightful shape, fine cloth, richly ornamented binding by Alden, the "Revolution"
                                publisher, at half its formei price, 50 cents. Alden's 148-page illustrated catalogue
                                (price 4 cents—condensed catalogue free,) of his immense list of standard books, is a
                                wonder as well as joy to book-lovers. John B. Alden, Publisher, New "York. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Herald of health" TEIform="index"/>Herald of
                                Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Herald of
                                Health for Dec. gives the best of medical advice and among other good things says. " It
                                is a sin to be sick. " M. L. Holbrook, M. D. 13&amp;15 Laight St. N. Y. $1.00 per
                                year. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>
                                The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Phrenological Journal and Science oe Health. December, Contents: Prof. Hubert
                                A. Newton; Indications of Character in Handwriting; Self-esteem and Approbativeness; The
                                Highland Home of the Queen; Biometry; Is it worth while? The Squires " Come-up-ance;
                                Elizabeth Fry; The Christian Church; Paralysis of the Organ of Language; Scarlet Fever;
                                Catarrh Remedies; Notes in Science, etc., etc. Fowler and Wells Co. 753 Broadway N. Y.
                                $2.00 per year. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/>Hall's Journal of Health</head><p TEIform="p">Hall's Journal or Health, for November has a long list of excellent
                                articles, for the promotion of health. Only 10 cts. per copy or $ 1.00 per year. Office
                                75&amp;77 Barclay St. N. Y.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Manners make a man" TEIform="index"/>Manners make a man
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Manners make a man.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tobacco" TEIform="index"/>TOBACCO</head><p TEIform="p">I advise you to quit.—Gentlemen I advise you to clean yourselves and quit. You will smell
                            better, and that will be a relief to the noses of your intimate friends. It is a nasty,
                            ruinous habit. Some one will say, " I can't give it up; I have tried, and can't do it. " If
                            you are so enslaved that you can't break your chains, I will help you a little. Stop at
                            oner. Don't use any to-morrow. The first day is not very hard, but the second day is pretty
                            tough. Along in the evening of the second day your memory is a little doubtful. You can't
                            say exactly whether it was one brother or three brothers that came over. Things are a little
                            mixed. Be patient. The third morning brings the tug. Now go and take an old-fashioned sweat.
                            Place an alcohol-lamp under your chair, three or four blankets round your shoulders, letting
                            the other ends rest on the floor, and sweat until the skin is fairly parboiled. You will be
                            iust as comfortable for one day as you could wish. There will be no dryness of the mouth, no
                            nervousness. You are perfectly comfortable for one day. The next day you will be in trouble
                            again. Take another Sweat; take even a third or a fourth one. Sweating does not hurt people,
                            sometimes it is good for them. Take three or four thorough sweats, and you will go off under
                            easy sail and have no further trouble from your enemy. This narcotic, a native of America,
                            now cultivated extensively in many parts of the world, is a powerful poison. It is used by
                            man in many different ways;—chewing, smoking, snuffing, snuff'-rubbing, smoke- swallowing
                            and plugging</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Lewis, Dio." TEIform="persName"/>Dio. Lewis, M. D.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The five points—not of Calvinism..." TEIform="index"/>The five points—not of Calvinism...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> The five points—not of Calvinism—but of Ritualism, are "eastward position, altar
                                    lights, vestments, wafer bread and mixed chalice. " Paul does not mention them, nor
                                    yet Peter, nor John. If to-morrow they all vanish from the earth the gospel of Jesus
                                    Christ would be as complete, as effectual, and as gracious as it ever was.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Evangelical Churchman" TEIform="index"/>—Evangelical Churchman.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Debt is the worst poverty" TEIform="index"/>Debt is the worst poverty
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Debt is the worst poverty.</p></div2><pb n="25" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Advertisements" TEIform="index"/>[Advertisements]</head><p TEIform="p">[Advertisements deleted.]</p></div2><pb n="26" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="figure" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/> ENFIELD, CONN.</head><p TEIform="p">[Figure]</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>