<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ss0407" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">Shaker and Shakeress</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Society</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Mount Lebanon, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">4</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">7</biblScope><date value="18740701" TEIform="date">July 1874</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">49-56</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="4" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="49" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="7" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!-- 
                        <p>Vol. IV. No. 7. F. W. EVANS, ElHTOR. PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETY, Mt. Lebanon, Col. Co. N. Y. July, 1874, Fifty
                        Cents per annum.</p>
                    --><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakerism scientific" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERISM SCIENTIFIC</head><p TEIform="p">" In Christ, are hid all the treasures of wisdom and knowledge." If this be so, then is the
                            cross of Christ scientific. And the Shaker, who, on a spiritual plane, lives a celibate
                            life, is no less naturally normal than the truly married man, or woman, on the earthly
                            plane, who, like the inferior animals, observes propagative laws, and abstains from all "
                            unfruitful works of darkness "— unfruitful sexual intercourse. When love has conceived, it
                            brings forth life —like begetting like. When lust has conceived, it brings forth sin — is
                            sin — and when sin is finished, it brings forth death. Disease is the forerunner of death.
                            All loves — affections of the soul—¦ produce corresponding bodily secretions. It is
                            therefore scientifically true, that they who sin, sin against their own bodies. Their
                            soul-inordinate loves create diseased bodily secretions. The lust of Opium, Tobacco, Betel
                            root, of alcoholic mixtures, produces thoughts, and those thoughts create secretions. It is
                            the same of all loves, and of all lusts. " Keep the heart with all diligence, for out of it
                            are the issues of life "— and of death. Exactly so. " Thou shalt love the Lord thy God, with
                            all thy heart, might, mind and strength. Love the good and true — desire to do only right —
                            to be in use, whether it be in eating, or drinking, or any other bodily function, perform it
                            only in the love of God, and for the honor of humanity, which is the honor and glory of God.
                            For in man and woman is the highest manifestation of Deity. That there is a God — Father and
                            Mother — that there are intermediate orders of intelligences— male and female — who, by
                            duration of existence, accumulated experience, extending back hundreds, thousands and
                            millions of years and ages, is a glorious idea — a tremendous fact. The capacity to conceive
                            it demonstrates its verity. Hunger — a demand for supply of earth elements to support
                            physical life — is an appetite for food. The thought is of some particular kind of food. At
                            once, the glands of the mouth secrete saliva; the glands of the stomach, gastric juice. "
                            Blessed are the pure in heart"— pure in thought — they see God — are like God — having no
                            unhealthy, diseased secretions — " God being in all their thoughts." "He that looketh —
                            thinketh — on a woman, to lust after her, hath committed adultery already with her in his
                            heart — by his secretions — the result of abnormal, ungodly, unscientific desires. Human
                            love, or license, under the name and cover of marriage, does not, cannot change the nature
                            of an act. It dops not transmute lust into love, wrong into right, nor uncleanness,
                            lasciviousness, fornication, adultery, wantonness, into chastity. The legal marriage bed is
                            too short, the covering too narrow. " For though thou wash thee with nitre, and take unto
                            thee much soap, thy sin is marked before me, and thine iniquity is not hid — may every true
                            Shaker say, to all anti- Christian-married-people. They are not Jews, keeping the natural
                            laws, nor are they Chris- tians, risen with Jesus, in the resurrection — where marriage hath
                            an end. The cross of Christ is self-denial of all perverted appetites, disorderly
                            affections, disease- producing, abnormal propensities. " My loins are filled with a
                            loathesome disease," was the exclamation of the "man after God's own heart"—the heart of the
                            God of Israel. David was a Saint, in that dispensation. But he was a sinner in the next
                            dispensation. " David had not ascended into the heavens," was the Christian testimony — not
                            into the Christ heavens. He needed the gospel preached unto him. He needed the cross of
                            Christ, against his own generative life, the root of his warring and fighting. He was a man
                            of blood, and was not permitted to build the outward temple. Neither can marrying,
                            generating, fighting Christians build the Spiritual Temple — a Pentecostal Church, or
                            community of goods. Christian celibacy is, therefore, as scientifically normal to the
                            natural man and woman, when they grow up to it, as is manhood and womanhood to the boy and
                            girl. The Church and State governments of Christendom have legalized generative lust, in
                            Priest and People. They have incorporated war into every constitution, civil and
                            ecclesiastical. It is established by statute, and sanctified by the Priesthood. Yet the
                            universal voice of instinct, in animate nature, is " Thou shalt not kill" me. All war, is
                            all murder. Moses could not separate generation from its lusts, and therefore he required a
                            sin offering for each and every act of sexuality, as defilement, whether of the single or
                            married. Jesus, by the cross of Christ, against his generative life, by living iipon
                            vegetables, fruits and farinacea, escaped from bondage to the Mosaic Priesthood. Penal laws
                            were made for transgressors. Jesus ceased to be transgressor, in diet, generation, or
                            property. His last supper was of unleavened bread, of unbolted wheat, eaten with twelve
                            celibates, in a community of goods. All their money was put into one bag, and that bag was
                            carried by Judas. " The covenant with death is now annulled," and " the agreement with hell
                            " can no longer stand before either the light of science, or the Gift of Revelation.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Walking with God" TEIform="index"/>WALKING WITH GOD</head><p TEIform="p">The vision, of human conditions, to day, perceives man so far strayed from his Creator, that
                            a portion of the race is seriously questioning the existence of a Supreme Being. Other
                            millions, admitting the fact, are so blinded by transgression of the laws of God, that they
                            are forming idol gods, imaginary deities, professing all the transitory and passional
                            characteristics of degraded humanity. In fact, man has for ages been wandering in a sinful
                            night of darkness, lost from God. But light is beaming forth from the throne of Truth; a
                            portion of the race is being warmed into life by the rays of the sun of righteousness.
                            Myriads of Angels from the Heavens are on pilgrimages of mercy and love to humanity, on the
                            shores of time, to return lost man to a knowledge of, and union with, his Maker. Humanity is
                            boldly toiling in a wondrous field of truth, From her palsied age recoiling, putting on
                            immortal youth, Science, art, religion, peering, to the Soul's mysterious realms, Truth's
                            blest mariners are nearing Heaven's port, with virtue's helm. The characteristic order, of
                            creation itself, is a living testimony of the relation of man to his Maker. From the lowest
                            grade of animate existence, manifesting instinct, to the highest intelligence, exhibiting
                            philosophical powers of research into laws that underlie science, and art, still upward to
                            supreme intention, there is a rising scale of being ; until it is anchored in God, the
                            Supreme Intelligence. " We cannot properly study science, and ignore God, who is at the
                            beginning of it," from the vast realms of space, occupied with innumerable worlds, obeying
                            fixed laws of motion, to the delicate forms of the most tiny mite. '• But, to godly men,
                            physical and metaphysical proofs of the existence of God, have no interest; they feel the
                            Divine within themselves." And, in all forms of intelligent existence there is a degree of
                            intuitive knowledge ; the voice of the Creator, giving law to the creature ; talking with
                            him. The crowning model of God's handiwork — man — has not only instinct, but intuitive
                            knowledge, and reason, a susceptibility to spirit influence —the consciousness of
                            ministrations of angels and spirits, not clothed in mortality. <pb n="50" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 5O
                            SHAKER A.ND In his normal relations to universal creation, lie is sympathetically conscious
                            of the laws that govern all inferior creation ; and sensible to the consequent happiness,
                            attachable to all life, by moving in conformity to those laws ; or the misery, sufferable,
                            by their infraction. All his senses could appreciate the presence of God, giving minute
                            instruction in the ways and duties of life; saying, This plant, or its seed, is good for
                            food, eat it; that is poisonous — a scavenger of the atmosphere, and the soil — touch it
                            not; this fruit is wholesome ; that contains the bitterness of death. This knowledge is
                            profitable, receive it, for out of it are the issues of life ; this is a sophism; taste it
                            not; drink not at its Lethean pool. Thy senses were given thee for happiness, surfeit them
                            not; and thy pleasures shall not end in pain. Bide the seasons of thy development ; creep
                            till thou cans't walk; walk till thou cans't run ; and ape not the bird, in thy pursuit, but
                            observe the laws of thy own being ; let thy pleasures be confined to use, and their usage
                            shall not bring thee sorrow. Thus, in every lane of life, man, when perfect, walked with
                            God. He gave him law in regard to the use of every pleasure, and the performance of every
                            duty; and the law of God was the normal delight of the Edenic man, while living in
                            submission and obedience to the Divine behest of his Creator. Man was the gladsome compeer
                            of Angels and the laws of the Heavens were open continually to his enchanted vision. Man
                            recognized God, as he recognized his fellow, and the love of God enshrouded him as a garment
                            and magnetized his whole being with bliss. He had no need of creeds of faith in God; he
                            believed in the possession of absolute conscious knowledge of his continual presence
                            administering His will and law. Living in obedience to the Divine law of his existence, man
                            would talk with God as a child would talk with its father and mother; receive his law
                            through instinct, understand it with reason, perceive His purpose by intuition, love it
                            through affection, and thus be guided in his every step of progress. Revelation of the laws
                            of God was an afterthought, an adaptation to man's condition, when, by disobedience, he had
                            lost sight of God's presence and his law. Returned to God by obedience to His laws, man will
                            need no abnormal supernal visions to behold the laws of God and the movements of the
                            Heavens. Eising from the material to the spiritual: from the sensual to the inspirational,
                            God will be in him ; He will not speak to him from without, as in the thunderings from
                            Sinai, but from within. Gushing from his own heart, will he hear his Heavenly Father's and
                            Mother's will, as Jesus when perfected by suffering, lived in the bosom of God, by
                            uninterrupted communication. Thus conditioned, in the Edenic state, man would not behold God
                            as through telescopic vision — afar off; nor yet as through the dreamy land; but, in his
                            fellow man, see Him stand erect, and hear Him speaking in the desires of his own heart. So
                            lived Jesus, and this gave him authority to preach ; not creeds; but," Follow me, and thou
                            shalt have treasure in Heaven." To the man redeemed from sin, and thus returned to Edenic
                            union with his Creator, the foibles and follies of sinful humanity are as froth on the
                            ocean's surf, the waves of life roll on and heed them not. Assurance of the triumph of
                            righteousness possesses his soul; in calm confidence he sees the hand of God guiding
                            humanity's bark to salvation and rest; dwelling in God's love, he has hope, robed in surety,
                            shorn of fears of disappointment; spiritual life, an eternal well-spring of action, gushing
                            forth from the eternal fountains ; and peace flows like a river as he recognizes, himself
                            bosomed in God.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles" TEIform="persName"/>Elder Giles Avery, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Duty of Elders" TEIform="index"/>DUTY OF ELDERS</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Elder Frederick W. Evans. — By a forward number of your May issue you ask that each
                            society contribute " one short wellwritten, well-condensed article for the S. &amp; S."
                            I propose to furnish " one short" article. If the requisites of " well-written,
                            well-condensed," should not be manifest, you are quite at liberty to consign it among your "
                            choice contributions." What I may write may be of no particular interest to our own people,
                            but may furnish some reflection, if not information, to outside readers of our little sheet.
                            I often hear erroneous ideas set forth in regard to the government of our institutions, by
                            our friends in outside society, and no class among us are more misjudged than Elders. To
                            correct these wrong impressions will be the object of this article so far as it goes. What
                            are the duties of a Shaker Elder? To answer this we will quote from our " Con- stitution,
                            article 4th, section 2nd,' Duties of Elders ' — As faithful watchmen upon the walls of Zion,
                            it becomes the duty of the Elders to watch over their respective families, to instruct the
                            members in their several duties, to counsel, encourage and admonish, exhort and reprove, as
                            occasion may require ; to lead the worship, to be examples to the members, of obedience to
                            the principles and orders of the Gospel, and to see that the orders, rules and regulations
                            pertaining to their respective families are properly kept." From the foregoing it might
                            appear to the uninitiated that the Elders are empowered with, and do exercise at pleasure,
                            arbitrary influence over the members of their respective families. But so far from this is
                            it, that in truth they are the most self-sacrificing individuals in the fraternity, as we
                            can make appear by letting the reader look behind the scene that shuts us from the view of
                            common society. For a number of years the writer of this article had the honor of occupying
                            as an Elder in a large family of about 100 persons, of both sexes, ranging in age from six
                            years to ninety. There were four persons of us who constituted the Eldership, and, as is the
                            case in all our government arrangements, the sisters were represented by two of their own
                            sex and the brethren by two of their sex, and these four constituted what we call the Elders
                            Order, and correspond to what is known in outside society as the parentage of the family.
                            And although there are great powers to govern placed in their hands, it is used very seldom,
                            and only in extreme cases, just as wise and loving parents would do in a wellregulated
                            family. The secret of a Shaker Elder's influence to govern mainly consists in the amount of
                            individual consecration and devotion with which he lives out the principles and teachings of
                            Jesus the Saviour. The golden rule " Do to others as ye would have others do to you," must
                            be kept continually before the mind. In fact he must be a living example of the Christ life,
                            and a bright and shining light going before his brethren and sisters. And above all things
                            he must live out in daily life the virgin continent life of his profession. Again, another
                            very effectual way, that a Shaker Elder gains influence with his people, is by the amount of
                            diligence and industry he practices in hand labor. Paul's rule on this point is fully
                            believed in — " If any work not, neither should he eat;" therefore, it is a precept with us,
                            that a good man must be an industrious man; and this precept has been inculcated from the
                            beginning or origin of our society. " Hands to work and hearts to God," was one of the
                            maxims left by our truly wise Mother, Ann Lee, to her followers, and by them believed in to
                            this day. It is a trite saying among our people that the Elder who can only say Go, to his
                            brethren and sisters, seldom has the confidence or respect of his people ; while the Elder
                            who addresses his people in the magic language of Come, brethren and sisters, let us pull
                            together, and then places himself at the head of the undertaking, be it never so
                            disagreeable to perform, seldom fails of having the love and confidence of his people. These
                            are some of the secret silken cords that bind the Shaker order into a brotherhood and
                            sisterhood, and these are the things that the dishonest and insincere are little disposed to
                            counterfeit. Such an Elder is not obeyed because of his official position in society, but
                            rather that he is loved. Sometimes people, in outside society, have said to me, " If I could
                            only be one of the head men among the Shakers I would be willing to be a Shaker." The way is
                            open into the kingdom and you may become a " head man," but first you must " drink of the
                            cup " and be baptized with the baptism that will kill those ambitious feelings, and then you
                            will occupy that place which by nature and grace you are qualified to fill.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Reynolds, W." TEIform="persName"/>Elder W. Reynolds, Union Village, O.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harvest field" TEIform="index"/>HARVEST FIELD</head><p TEIform="p">On a certain occasion, when Jesus' Disciples were putting off the Spiritual Harvest-day, he
                            rebuked and instructed them; for they were dull of comprehension. He said, " Behold! Lift up
                            your eyes and look on the fields — the villages and cities of Judea — for they are white,
                            already, to harvest." Ready for the willing and earnest reapers. " Can ye not observe the
                            signs of the times ? " " Ye can discern the face of the sky and of the earth. How is it that
                            ye cannot discern this time ? " Spring, Summer, Autumn, Winter are divisions of time, well
                            calculated to meet the natural wants of man. With these the Spiritual seasons harmonize. And
                            he who, by the laws of correspondence, discovers these, and acts accordingly, will have
                            reason to rejoice, when the Lord's '' summer is ended and the harvest time passed;" for he
                            has worked with God. The great field of God's care is the whole world. In this his servants
                            have been sowing and reaping, alternately, from the beginning. To-day, the same work is no
                            less demanded. To-day, well might we catch the inspiration of Jesus, so potent to all who
                            have accepted his life. Lift up your eyes! Behold the harvest field!! Are you waiting for
                            other signs to come to pass, before you commence your work? Lift up your eyes and watch the
                            course of the Angels of God, and go with them into the field. Reap while your day lasts. Now
                            is the harvest time! Work !! From the past and present, we may, to a certain extent, be
                            justified in anticipating the future. 'There may be a hundred thousand or a million of
                            servants, working in the Lord's vineyard. They are shaking the old heavens and earth, from
                            center to circumference, causing their very foundations to pass away, with much noise and
                            battles of shaking. What a victory for the right was the gift of freedom, to the millions of
                            slaves, in America, and of serfs, in Russia. No less important was the freedom of religious
                            thought in Spain and Italy. God's care is over all advanced minds, who are earnestly toiling
                            to elevate their fellowmen, and women, from moral and physical degradation. Over those,
                            enlisted in the cause of temperance, leaving their homes of afflu- ence, and taking the
                            responsibility to act in the name of the Lord, through prayer. Over the great body of
                            Iconoclasts, who are sweeping so rapidly over the earth, and preparing <pb n="51" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/>
                            8HAKERESS, 51 the way for other minds, whom God has raised up, to manifest his spirit for
                            the redemption of the world. All belong to the armies of the Lord. Each division has its
                            duty assigned, and will reap a blessing, corresponding with his and her faithfulness in the
                            work. If we — Shakers — were alone in the contest, how trifling would he all that we might
                            accomplish. May we, in the gift of our high calling, lift up our eyes and behold the
                            manifestation of the spirit of power, which is abundantly illuminating the earth. Indeed,
                            Shakers are in the land, as the stars of heaven for multitude —" of all nations, kindreds,
                            tongues and people." Development is the law, from sphere to sphere. All goodness emanated
                            from God, and every order of workmen must pass up the ascending grade of goodness, which
                            finally culminates in the spirit of union and love.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/>Elder H. C. Blinn, Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="shaker-history" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Testimony" TEIform="index"/>TESTIMONY</head><p TEIform="p">" They overcame him by the blood of the Lamb, and by the word of their testimony." Kev. xii.,
                            The founders of our several societies lived in a slanderous age. Orthodoxy was rampant. It
                            held that belief, not works, was the one thing needful. That a wrong article of faith might
                            consign a human soul to everlasting broiling, in the eternal world. That lies, told by the
                            saints, about heretics and infidels, were acceptable to a God of truth and justice. " The
                            Dragon poured, out of his mouth, a flood to carry away the woman"—Ann Lee " and the remnant
                            of her seed " — the Shakers. The priests and people, whom they used as their tools, were the
                            most unrelenting enemies of the early Shakers. Falsehood was their cannon — lies, their
                            ammunition. It took fifty years to establish, in the public mind, what is now admitted — to
                            wit, that Shakers do live as they profess — pure, celibate or virgin lives. The Life of
                            Christ is the Blood of Christ. They who do not wish so to live, go out from among us,
                            because they are not of us. The black sheep do not remain in the fold. The time is coming,
                            and now is, " when the accuser of the Brethren and Sisters, is cast down, which accused them
                            before our God day and night. They overcame him — the tongue of slander, by the blood — life
                            of the Lamb, and by the word of their testimony." No testimony is having more weight and
                            influence, at the present time, than what is communicated, monthly, by and through the
                            columns of the Shaker and Shakeress, which is read with increasing interest, by many in
                            Northern Ohio. One man said he felt amply paid for his subscription, by reading those two
                            messages from Edwin M. Stanton, late Secretary of War, given through a reliable medium of
                            Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. He believed every word of them, and wished they might be copied and
                            republished in every Spiritual and Secular paper in the United States. They were copied,
                            verbatim, into the R. P. Journal, in Chicago, 111., and some other papers. Such
                            communications will have weight in the minds of all candid people. We have also seen
                            articles published in Melbourne, Australia, copied from the Shaker and Shakeress. Thus, our
                            little Missionary is doing a work—bearing a testimony, as a witness for the truth, unto all
                            nations. But this can never supersede the necessity of a verbal testimony, by living
                            witnesses, at home and abroad. They, who live the life of Christ, can bear a testimony, that
                            none others can, against the " social evil," and all other evils which afflict human
                            society, and it becomes their duty to do it.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescott, James S." TEIform="persName"/>James S. Prescott, North Union, Ohio</byline></div2><div2 type="Article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cremation" TEIform="index"/>CREMATION</head><p TEIform="p">The idea of being buried alive, is, to me, perfectly horrible. This awful dread is, no doubt,
                            shared by thousands. We have reason to believe, that throughout this wide world, there are
                            many, every year of our Lord, who wake up and find themselves boxed and buried, six feet
                            under ground. To poor mortals, in this situation, a few minutes must seem like an eternity.
                            No language can describe the anguish of a human being thus incarcerated. The horrible
                            accounts, we frequently have, of persons buried alive, are enough to sicken the heart of
                            humanity. Cremation is now agitating the public mind. I have, of late, read many articles on
                            the subject. Many good arguments have been advanced, in favor of cremation. But one, most
                            important, has, in my opinion, been overlooked— to wit, cremation puts the danger of being
                            buried alive entirely out of the question. So I go in strong for cremation. Hallelujah ! the
                            day dawns, that when our spirits shall have shuffled off these mortal bodies, the elements
                            that composed them shall melt with fervent heat.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sizer, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Slzer, Canaan, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The male editor, of this little waif, advocates trenching all land..." TEIform="index"/>The male editor, of this little waif, advocates trenching all land...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The male Editor, of this little waif, advocates trenching all land. Digging graves six feet
                            deep, and planting a tree by every grave. The graves to be ten feet apart each way. This
                            would insure the blessing of each generation, upon the preceding generation, for the good
                            they had done with their bodies.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Influence" TEIform="index"/>INFLUENCE</head><p TEIform="p">We throw off our magnetism all around us, carrying with us our own atmosphere. According to
                            the condition of our minds, our influence imbues the house in which we live. Very sensitive
                            persons can feel this quite distinctly. On entering a room, they know, by the impressions
                            they receive, whether the persons, there living, are good or bad. A person being in the
                            habit of going every day, at a certain hour, into a closet to pray, drew such heavenly
                            influences around him, that the whole closet was filled with them; and others, on entering
                            that little room, felt such divine sensations, that they dropped involuntarily on their
                            knees, and prayed fervently. A virtuous man, not knowing what had transpired in a certain
                            room, inhabited by vicious people, on entering, felt directly a very disgusting and
                            oppressive feeling — a shudder of horror shook his whole frame. And why ? The magnetism of
                            these wicked people was left in the room, and the virtuous man felt it. We cannot set our
                            feet upon the ground, without leaving an impression, a part of our magnetism behind us. We
                            must be very careful with whom we associate, because we are drawn into their magnetic
                            atmosphere, and absorb their peculiarities. Many persons without knowing the cause, have
                            adopted the habits of others, by exposing themselves carelessly to their magnetic influence.
                            If two persons meet, both being very positive, there will be a harmonious blending of
                            feeling. If one be positive and the other less so, he who has more magnetism will impart to
                            the one less favored, till both are equal. But, if one is positive and the other negative,
                            there will be a clashing. An antagonistic feeling will arise between them. This explains
                            why, at the first meeting of some persons, they feel instantaneously drawn toward each
                            other, or the reverse. Those who are of one mind, who are spiritually minded, of a refined
                            and elevated culture, feel their souls flow together as drops of water. But those whose
                            desires are of a more earthly nature, cannot find their happiness in the intimate fellowship
                            of the pure-minded. Neither will the last-mentioned blend with the worldly-minded, but both
                            seek the society of like-minded persons, each living in his or her own appropriate sphere.
                            Our Creator has so constituted the human race, that they act and react upon each other, and
                            are dependent upon each other for strength and support, both temporal and spiritual. We
                            cannot come in contact with any one, but our emanations impart something to him or her, and
                            we in return receive. Every silent thought, as well as the utterance of our thoughts, helps
                            form our character. They work into our spiritual natures, and leave an enduring impression
                            on our souls; and the influence is felt, sometimes years afterward. The Angels exert their
                            influence over us, more than we are aware of; and if we would live more spiritual lives, we
                            would be more able to commune with the blessed Angels, and the loved ones gone before, who
                            are in close associations with us. Our spiritual eyes would be more opened, our inward
                            senses more quickened, and we could behold the rapturous beauty and glory of the
                            Spirit-land. We could better appreciate the benedictions, the tender watchful care and
                            protection of our resurrection Spirit-Guides.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sevester, Edwin" TEIform="persName"/>Edwin Sevester, Groveland, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Witchcraft" TEIform="index"/>WITCHCRAFT.</head><p TEIform="p">In Gathering Families, where many of the most powerful and influential minds concentrate,
                            great care and watchfulness is required on the part of those who come into communication
                            with them, to preserve intact a spiritual gift. For a spiritual person to be magnetized, by
                            a mere natural man or woman, is to be beicitched — to descend from a higher to a lower
                            sphere, for unworthy purposes. This may occur, without any well defined intent on either
                            side.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Out of the belly of Hell" TEIform="index"/>OUT OF THE BELLY OF HELL</head><p TEIform="p">"Out of the belly of Hell, cried I, O Lord, and thou heardst my voice."—Jonah. On the subject
                            of religion, men think alike less than they feel alike, although on one point sensible men
                            may be found to think substantially the same. That the mass of humans grovel, pursuing
                            things beneath their dignity, needs no argument ; the painful fact is patent. The religious
                            element, in our make up, is the lever whereby the powers above us, can lift us to higher
                            planes of being. In this cardinal, philosophic truth, sensible people agree. To enable a
                            soul to cry unto the Lord, out of the belly of Hell, 'tis not needful to be swal- lowed by a
                            whale. When, by the Divine Afflatus, the religious element in us is stirred — when our souls
                            reach out to grasp the purity of angels — when the strong current of lower law influence
                            sweeps us back only to the things we abhor — when we feel our want of power to be what we
                            seem to be — when, for lack of moral stamina, we do the things we would not — then out of
                            the belly of hell we may, and will, cry unto the Lord, and our voice will be heard. When we
                            say, Lord, what shall I do to be saved from the things I detest — things beneath my proper
                            dignity ? When reverently we bow to our holiest, aspiration, by hand unseen will we be led
                            in a way we know not; and when our integrity has been tested, we will hear a voice from the
                            interior, saying, flg§T This is the way, walk ye in it. And now comes the tug of war, the
                            test of manhood and womanhood.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wrath" TEIform="index"/>WRATH</head><p TEIform="p">"The wrath of man worketh not the righteousness of God." But the wrath of God revealed from
                            heaven, against all that defiles the temple of God, is Heaven's richest blessing; it should
                            be regarded as a friend. We shall need much of such Divine displeasure to fit us for the
                            mansions of eternal brightness.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="P., O." TEIform="persName"/>O. P. Mt. Lebanon, April 26,18T4</byline></div2><pb n="52" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Horticulture" TEIform="index"/>HORTICULTURE</head><p TEIform="p">In the fall of 1872, after gathering the exceptionally large crop of apples of that season,
                            we organized a corps of pruners. Going through our several orchards, we took off, first, the
                            unfruitful lower limbs. Then the superfluous branches, giving the trees a heavy trim- ming.
                            Rationale. Reasoning thus. These trees have so exhausted their vitality, that next year,
                            they will not bear. We will help them, by removing all that can be spared without det-
                            riment. Thus the strength, of the whole system of roots, will be concentrated in what limbs
                            and branches remain. This fall, the trees will form fewer, but stronger fruit buds, for next
                            season. We will have a middling fair crop of apples, in the ensuing non-bearing year.
                            Result. One thousand bushels of apples — giving us an ample supply, and we sold $500 worth
                            of apples and other fruit, in the panic, when $100 were equal to $200 in ordinary times. The
                            wounds made, heal sweetly — clean as clean can be. Last year, we let the orchards alone, to
                            recuperate. This season, we are thinning out the branches, to reduce the excess of blossoms,
                            that give promise of a large crop the present year. This process we propose to continue
                            through June and July, thinning out, where we had previously trimmed. Small apples will go
                            mercilessly, if they set before we get through. Borers. In the past, having washed our apple
                            trees with strong soap-suds and potash once or twice a year, no borers have made their
                            appearance in our orchards. In Heathen orchards, they are making havoc, or labor. It may be
                            well to state, that a shovel full of tan bark, or two, has been put around the young trees,
                            in the fall. This is to keep the mice away. Perhaps the borers do not approve of it.
                            Inasmuch as "the Lord our God" blesses our orchards, by inspiring us to observe Nature's
                            Laws, may we not hope He will do the same with our own bodies, so far as we " mind the same
                            thing and walk by the same rule " ?</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="One of the foremost of English medical writers, Dr. James Johnson, emphatically says..." TEIform="index"/>One of the foremost of English medical writers, Dr. James Johnson, emphatically says...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">One of the foremost of English medical writers, Dr. James Johnson, emphatically says: " I
                            declare my conscientious opinion, founded on long observation and reflection, that if there
                            was not a single physician, surgeon, apothecary, chemist, druggist, or drug, on the face of
                            the earth, there would be less sickness and less mortality than now obtains." And Professor
                            Magendie is reported to have addressed his students at the Medical College in Paris to the
                            following effect: " Gentlemen, medicine is a great humbug; I know it is called a science.
                            Science indeed—it is nothing like science. Doctors are mere empirics when they are not
                            charlatans. We are as ignorant as men can be. Who knows any thing in the world about
                            medicine ? Gentlemen, you have done me the honor to attend my lectures, and T must tell you
                            frankly that I know nothing about medicine. True, we are gathering facts every day. We can
                            produce typhus fever, for example, by injecting a certain substance into the veins of a dog;
                            we can alleviate diabetes; and I see distinctly we are fast approaching the day when
                            phthisis can be cured as easily as any disease. But I repeat it to you, there is no such
                            thing now as medical science. I grant you, people are cured ; but how? Nature does a great
                            deal; imagination does a great deal; doctors do — devilish little. Watch for little
                            opportunities of pleasing, and put little annoyances out of the way.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Worship of mammon" TEIform="index"/>THE WORSHIP OF MAMMON</head><p TEIform="p">" Ye cannot serve God and Mammon." Matt. vi. 24. If it be granted — and who but the Atheist
                            will deny it? — that eternity should be the theme of deepest study and most serious con-
                            templation, and to do the will of God our constant and most earnest aim and endeavor, an end
                            to which every thought and action should be subordinate; and further, if the definition be
                            accepted, that religion is a living faith in a future spiritual existence, and a consequent
                            present effort at preparation for that existence, then we shall get a view of the world
                            sufficiently sad and sorrowful, for the millions of the earth, whatever profession they may
                            make, are really and indeed without religion. Or, if (admitting a wider definition) it be
                            conceded that a man's predominant passion, that which shapes and directs his life, and the
                            code of morals which, spite of Sabbath day sentiment and canting hypocrisy, really regulates
                            his intercourse with his fellow-man ; if these practically constitute his " religion," then
                            the people of the earth, deadening their spiritual senses in a cold and dreary selfishness,
                            are engaged — not in the service of God — but heart and soul in the worship of Mammon. In
                            England, see how false pride and a selfish, narrow spirit of exclusiveness — the vile
                            offspring of a vicious God-supplanting idol yclept " Respectability " — rear Impassable
                            social barriers between the different classes of the community. What emotion there so strong
                            as the love of caste and a contempt for those lower in the social scale ? A contempt by no
                            means confined to the aristocrat, who with his long lineage and " blue blood," is naturally
                            proud and haughty, but permeating the whole rotten system of British society. The
                            professional man despises the retail trader. The diploma-dubbed doctor unmercifully snubs
                            the pill and draught-dispensing druggist, and he in turn scorns the companionship of the
                            butcher and baker. The goldsmith contemns the blacksmith and the blacksmith the tinker; and
                            it is presumable that the very tinker is tinctured with this wide-spread idiotic mania and
                            denies the social equality of some other brainless nonentity. In short, a contempt for those
                            beneath them on the social ladder, and an envy-tempered reverence for those above them, is
                            the strongest sentiment of British society, before which the truths of Christianity pale, as
                            the fading stars before the Orient sun. Is a preparation for the life to come by curbing the
                            animal propensities and developing the spiritual powers and perceptions, the leading
                            characteristic of the French people! Is it not rather the indulgence in gross sensual
                            pleasure — a stimulating dietary, an uncontrolled exercise of the sexual emotions, lewd and
                            libidinous stage plays and feuilletons, lust awakening dress, dances and music, and all the
                            wicked folly of the cafe chantant ? Or what does the more stolid Teuton prize above his huge
                            tobacco pipe and his Rhein wein or lager bier ? How blithely roll forth the rich gutturals
                            under this powerful but unholy inspiration ! Or the " Sing-verein" and its roaring
                            patriotism flashing, dashing and foaming over with enthusiastic love for the Fatherland and
                            hatred of all its enemies ? What recks our Teuton of love of God and hatred of all
                            unrighteousness ? Or does the Brazilian fazendeiro value most the gain and welfare of his
                            immortal soul, or his coffee, and cotton plantations, and the chattels, in God's image, who
                            till the rich Virgin soil, wait upon the person of their owner and minister to his lustful
                            passions in return for the privilege of existence ? Or what is the chief concern — nay, the
                            allabsorbing aim of the American people ? Not to live a Godly, righteous and sober life, but
                            to amass wealth. An insatiable greed of gold resulting in tricky trading, legalized robbery,
                            and custom sanctioned swindling, and a sel- fish strife of political parties for place,
                            power and pelf, such is the " religion " of America. And so the wide world over, in lands
                            Christian and civilized, as in Pagan and barbarian, do not human beings seem to lack all
                            conception of the solemnity and meaning of existence, and utterly to ignore the great fact
                            of human immortality ? Do they even aspire to riseGodward? Are they not'all worshiping
                            mammon ? " Where are thy joys O babbling earth? Whence does thy glory come? Hast thou the
                            pearl of priceless worth? Art thou the pilgrim's home? In thee does Mammon reign supreme And
                            seas of passion roll. In thee does pleasure's fickle dream Bring sorrow to the soul." Happy
                            the little songstress that could pen these verses — happy while yet an infant to have
                            escaped from the turmoil of Babylon and found shelter within the walls of peaceful Zion.
                            Thrice happy to have exchanged the life of self-indulgence for the life of selfdenial — for
                            the service of God, the worship of Mammon!</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Brown, Hewson" TEIform="persName"/>Hewson Brown, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religion needed" TEIform="index"/>THE RELIGION NEEDED</head><p TEIform="p">The religion needed is the only religion there is. But we need to have this religion applied.
                            Science is well, but. the chief use of science is in its application to human wants. The
                            chief business of the Minister of the Gospel is to apply it in the manner indicated below,
                            by the Christian Times of August 2. The fearful developments since will suggest other
                            applications: We want a religion that bears heavily not only on the " exceeding sinfulness
                            of sin," but on the exceeding rascality of lying and stealing—a religion that banishes small
                            measures from the counter, small baskets from stalls, pebbles from the cotton bags, clay
                            from the paper, sand from sugar, chicory from coffee, alum from bread, and water from the
                            milk cans. The religion that is to save the world will not put all the big strawberries at
                            the top, and all little ones at the bottom. It will not make one-half pair of shoes of good
                            leather, and the other half of poor leather, so that the first shall redound to the maker's
                            credit, and the second to the cash. It will not put Jouvin's stamp on Jenkins' kid gloves,
                            nor make Paris bonnets in the back room of a Boston milliner's shop ; nor let apiece of
                            velvet, that professes to measure twelve yards, come to an untimely end in the tenth ; nor a
                            spool of sewing silk, that vouches for twenty yards, be nipped in the bud at fourteen and
                            a-half; nor all-wool delaines and all-linen handkerchiefs be amalgamated with clandestine
                            cotton; nor coats made of old rags pressed together, be sold to the unsuspecting public for
                            legal broadcloth. It does not put bricks at five dollars per thousand into chimneys it
                            contracts to build of seven-dollar material; nor smuggle white pine into floors that have
                            paid for hard pine ; nor leave yawning cracks In closets where boards ought to join; nor
                            daub the ceilings that ought to be smoothly plastered; nor make window blinds with slats
                            that oannot stand the wind, and paint that cannot stand the sun, and fastenings that maybe
                            looked at, but are on no account to be touched. The religion that is going to sanctify the
                            world pays its debts. It does not consider that forty cents returned for one hundred cents
                            given, is not according to the Gospel though it may be according to law. It looks on a man
                            who has failed in trade, and who continues to live in luxury, as a thief .—Ex. Will He
                            Succeed? — In nine cases out of ten man's life will not be a success if he does not bear
                            burdens in his childhood. If the fondness or the vanity of father or mother have kept him
                            from hard work; if another always helped him out at the end of his row; if instead of taking
                            his turn at pitching off, he stowed away all the time—in short, if what was light always
                            fell to him, and what was heavy about the same work to some one else; if he has been
                            permitted to shrink until shrinking has become a habit—unless a miracle has been wrought,
                            his life will be a failure, and the blame will not be half so much his as that of weak,
                            foolish parents. On the other hand, if a boy has been brought to do his part,neyer allowed
                            to shrink from any legitimate responsibility, or to dodge work, whether or not it made his
                            head ache, or soiled his hands, until bearing burdens becomes a matter of pride, the heavy
                            end of the wood his choice — parents as they bid him good-bye may dismiss their fears. His
                            life will not be a business failure. The elements of success are his, and at some time and
                            in some way the world will recognize his capacity. Think before you speak, and think before
                            whom you speak, think why you speak, and think what you speak.</p></div2><pb n="53" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakeress: honesty and continence" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERESS: HONESTY AND CONTINENCE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">Honesty and Continence are the king and queen Principles. Through fidelity to those
                            principles, martyrs have been crowned with victory. Cold, cheerless prisons have been made
                            to smile with gladness, when God's noblemen and women, through inspired hope, and with the
                            approval of Angels, have pledged their all, even life itself, rather, than through fear of
                            sufferings of the body, to sacrifice conscience — the law that Deity has placed in the human
                            soul, for its guidance—¦ which, if honestly adhered to, is superior to any law that men can
                            form. Many monarchs have swayed the sceptre of power, and gained eclat from mortals, whose
                            names have come down to posterity through shining pages of history, written by men; but,
                            when those records appear as written by Angels, who see, and judge differently from men,they
                            will illy compare wiblithe records of many individuals, in more humble capacities who so
                            loved truth, that they would not sell their Continence and Honesty, through sin- ister
                            motives, nor in seeking vain glory. But the strong love of virtue, and force of con-
                            science, caused them to approach the stake and its devouring flames with heroic fortitude,
                            and face the rack with its tortures, and venemous reptiles, and ferocious beasts, without
                            fear. Neither could the syren chants, that sought to allure to pleasure, and open up a
                            flowery path before them, induce them to swerve from their integrity, and throw themselves
                            into a caldron of unholy love. Nor, to rest upon hopes that were vain and worthless. They
                            saw that goodness and truth, maintained through honesty of purpose, were all that could be
                            relied upon ; and without which, the soul would be like a garden where flowers had ceased to
                            bloom,— the rose-leaf had withered, and naught but dry and thorny stalks remained. Honest
                            men and women are always alive to increasing truth ; and are found traveling the highway of
                            spiritual progression. Such persons never wrap themselves in a garment woven of selfish,
                            individual ideas, nor take a seat in some easy chair, at the expense of others ; vainly
                            trusting in the attainments, or in the goodness, of any human being. Neither will they bound
                            their faith, nor limit their sacrifices by time-honored persons or customs. Honesty will
                            lead every intelligent being to seek to know what God requires of them; what to do, and what
                            to suffer for the advancement of true principles. Intellectual culture may lead to honor and
                            renown, in the eyes of the finite; but goodness and continence are of far greater worth in
                            the sight of the Infinite. Without those principles in operation, there would be no salt in
                            the earth — no balancing power, to keep the nations of the earth from dashing one against
                            another like the wild waves of the great ocean. As society now exists, land-sharks are quite
                            as numerous, and are as ready to devour those who have less teeth than themselves, as sharks
                            that float in the waters, and live upon smaller fishes. We often hear the remark, that it is
                            seemingly an impossibility for an honest man, or woman, to keep from starving at the present
                            time. That all trade, aa now conducted, is based o\\ fraud. " Double dealing " is its true
                            name and character ; and it is guarded, and guided by false and lying spirits, here in this
                            professedly Christian nation ! Could we not take some profitable lessons from Mohammedans in
                            this respect ? A Platonic philosopher once said, " Why persuade me to embrace this new
                            religion ? I have been cheated by Christians; but 1 never defrauded any man. A Christian has
                            broken his oath to me; but 1 never violated my simple word to any man." That honest
                            philosopher would not have feared to look any man, woman, or child in the face, as far as
                            honesty was concerned. Dishonesty, if allowed between man and man, will lead to dishonesty
                            between the soul and God. There is no fraud in God's creation (when un- perverted), from the
                            least atom, to the most majestic mountain ; all are subject to laws within their own sphere
                            ; and the same hand that guides the destinies of nations, feeds the ravens, and clothes the
                            lilies. And the same sun that gilds the mountain tops, sends its rays to cheer and vivify
                            the valleys below. The trees are not at variance with each other; if some reach a higher
                            altitude than others, it is through a normal growth, and not through strife; and the
                            loftiest and most vigorous trees shelter and protect the smaller ones from the rude storms,
                            as naturally as the mother protects her infant child. If there be abstraction from, or
                            blight upon, any of God's creation, it has come through man's influence. When man was placed
                            as lord and ruler over the lower orders of creation, the forces of nature were young, and
                            immature; but they were not corrupt; and they possessed latent powers, capable of
                            development and growth into strength and beauty. And, as the ages roll on, God's work will
                            be accomplished, and his plans will be perfected. The great book of life, which contains the
                            history of nations, and empires, is stored in the archives of the unseen world,— ever open
                            to the inspection of those Angels who hold the scales of mercy and j ustice in their hands —
                            ready to give to all a just recompense; not a farthing more nor less. It has been said
                            truly, that " an honest man is the noblest work of God." And we add : A virtuous, continent
                            woman, is the glory of an honest man,— the joy of Angels,— and will be blest and honored by
                            the Mother in Deity. The heavens are open to receive such souls ; but the hells are not
                            strong enough to hold them ! Purity of heart is the soil, and Honesty is the central plant
                            in the garden of the soul, around which all other virtues cluster. In- dustry and Innocence
                            (her handmaid) hold sweet communion together, as they wend their way to the city of Light
                            and Love. Rev. Thomas K. Beechbb, brother of Henry Ward Beecher, has created no little stir
                            among the Congregational brethren in New York by an elaborate essay in one of the leading
                            religious weeklies, in justification and advocacy of auricular confession. A few years ago
                            the Congregationalists were afraid this reverend gentleman was going to turn Episcopalian.
                            Now, they are a little apprehensive that he is going beyond ritualism even, if not to
                            Catholicism itself. Among other things of the same kind, Mr. Beecher says : " If it were the
                            habit of a man to go to some reverend and trusted man of God once in two months and unbosom
                            himself truthfully, can any sane man doubt that he would receive a benefit? * * * Penitence
                            of sins is usually much deepened when a fellow man knows of it." Ex.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker woman's rights" TEIform="index"/>THE SHAKER WOMAN'S RIGHTS</head><p TEIform="p">There is much written and spoken in these days with regard to " Woman's Rights," though we do
                            not remember to have seen any article treating upon this subject with the qualifying word
                            Shaker prefixed to the title. We, therefore, propose to say something about a class of women
                            who have already obtained their rights, and who, though among the humblest in a worldly
                            point of view, are the only women, we believe, whose rights of body, soul and spirit, are
                            truly respected. " Ah ! " says the reader, who glances at the title, " A Shaker Woman's
                            Rights ! In what do they consist 1 A woman of the Shaker Order, if I am rightly informed, is
                            cloistered for years within the confines of a rural home, possessing, apparently, but little
                            actual knowledge of the busy world without — its rights or its wrongs — and how is she able
                            to appreciate the rights of woman ? " Again, living in a communistic order, surrounded by
                            diverse dispositions, one might suppose each individual would incline to cherish her own
                            favorite views of happiness, seeking to secure her personal rights at the expense of others.
                            Can she obtain these rights and the result be harmony ? With all due respect to jour mode of
                            reasoning, dear reader, permit us to repeat that, notwithstanding we fully comprehend your
                            views on this subject, we still claim that those to whom we especially allude are the only
                            persons in the civilized world who have equal rights with their brothers in the daily strug-
                            gles of an earthly career. Here let us state that it is by virtue of our loyalty to our God
                            and to the covenant which we maintain, that we come into possession of all that truly
                            ennobles, elevates and enfranchises woman. True, we are daily associated with various minds,
                            where all strive to square their lives by the Saviour's Golden Rule. They are also bound to
                            respect the rights of their sister companions ; and where many live according to the
                            dictates of an enlightened conscience, mutual good feeling prevails and harmony is the rule.
                            Do not think it a disadvantage, my friends, to be in daily sympathy with many kindred
                            spirits, to be greeted by friendly countenances wherever your duty calls, and to feel a
                            right to this pleasant association by living, yourself, mentally and morally independent of
                            selfishness. Is not this state desirable above all others to the truly aspiring mind '? Our
                            Shaker brothers, who have been impressed with singular views of their moral obligations
                            toward God and their earthly companions, have also left all for Christ's sake and the
                            gospel, and share with us the discipline of self-denial. These are among the best advocates
                            of woman's rights, though their voices may never gain the popular ear by eloquent appeals
                            for her independence. Yet the God-like influence exerted by our brothers, combined with
                            their unselfish lives, is a power to aid us in living virtuously. It is thus that they help
                            to secure, to their sisters, the inalienable rights of Virgins. We wish to be clearly
                            understood that selfdenial is the first, the second, and the third requisite, by which one
                            may attain to the position of a truly enfranchised woman. One must " put Christ fully on,"
                            before realizing the depth of love possessed, the height of joy experienced, and the moral
                            grandeur and beauty of the lives of those persons, whose characters are molded by the
                            universal law of love, by which the Shaker sisterhood is guided. Come then, kind reader,
                            investigate, analyze and discuss the vitalizing principles of our communistic church, and
                            see if the blessings of equality do not exist therein ; where all have the Right to think,
                            act, and live according to their highest conceptions of divine light, and where each aspires
                            to wear, as her chief ornament, the royal insignia of Virgin Purity.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stickney, Asenath" TEIform="persName"/>Ascnath C. Stickney, Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cold words freeze people, and hot words scorch them, and bitter words..." TEIform="index"/>Cold words freeze people, and hot words scorch them, and bitter words...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Cold words freeze people, and hot words scorch them, and bitter words make them wrathful.
                            Kind words make people good-natured. Though they do not cost much, yet they accomplish
                            much.—</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pascal" TEIform="persName"/>Pascal</byline></div2><pb n="54" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Simple vision" TEIform="index"/>A SIMPLE VISION</head><p TEIform="p">While in deep thought discussing a grave subject, I seemed gradually and gently lifted mid
                            clouds, fog and mist, in which for a moment I was enveloped. Suddenly the clouds parted and
                            I emerged through the rift, when lo ! such a lovely panorama 11 Houses, farms, gardens,
                            forests and shade trees, beautifully interspersed with lakes and meadows, opened to my view
                            as I had never before conceived. The avenue through which I passed then closed. I remained
                            seated on the billowy clouds, as they seemed to continue their undulatory motion, without
                            disturbing my repose. The landscape before me was of the richest green, the buildings pure
                            white. No dazzling brightness pained my sight. A soft mellow light pervaded the atmosphere
                            as far as my vision extended, rendering it marvelously transparent, so that I could discern
                            the remotest object. The nearest approach to any type of loveliness is the sweet, fragrant
                            atmosphere, succeeding a short, refreshing shower in the balmy month of June, when earth is
                            attired in her richest mantle of green; when every leaf and blade of grass glistens with the
                            cooling rain drops, their tiny vessels have retained. So boundless the expanse I seemed lost
                            in infinite space — my whole being absorbed in intense delight. While surveying the
                            beautiful scene I was impressed that it was a view of Believers' possessions ; bat whether
                            in this or the spirit world I could not tell. A crowd of thoughts rushed through my mind as
                            follows : How deeply would I regret had I proved recreant to my faith — my high, sacred
                            trust — and lost my place in the gospel work. I clasped my hands in joy and thank- fulness,
                            that I had kept my integrity through the vicissitudes of my short life, while a tinge of
                            sadness somewhat neutralized my joy as my many imperfections passed before me, causing every
                            cross and trial endured to sink into comparative insignificance, in view of God's love and
                            goodness to one so erring. Then, a deep shade of sorrow and regret for those who had fallen
                            by the way, losing the inheritance reserved for such as end are to the end. On returning to
                            consciousness of my surroundings I found only a few moments had elapsed, yet, they seemed
                            expanded into hours, so much had I experienced in the interim. The day was bright, yet the
                            very sunshine was murky from, the contrast so plainly realized. To those gifted ones, often
                            blessed with beautiful visions of the better land, the momentary glimpse enjoyed by me will
                            seem of little value. As a drop in the boundless ocean of God's love, through the
                            multiplicity of avenues open for spiritual ministration, I hold it as a choice and precious
                            gift, having been seldom privileged with so bright a ray from that beautiful shore — my
                            spirit home. Or, perchance, the future of our Zion home on earth.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Kaime, Joanna J." TEIform="persName"/>Eldress Joanna J. Kaime, Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Love of truth" TEIform="index"/>LOVE OF TRUTH</head><p TEIform="p">The Holy Spirit must find access to the inmost feelings of the soul, in order to educate,
                            instruct, and become the governing influence to bring forth deeds of righteousness, that
                            will form a Christian character, thus casting evil out of the soul. Some imagine that God,
                            or His Holy Presence, may be found in any place, and everywhere, because he fills immensity.
                            But we have many evidences that God never intended that man should hide his transgressions
                            from his fellow man, and he cannot hide from God who is everywhere present. And in this, the
                            Fourth Dispensation, there are both male and female Confessors. The most hardened in
                            transgression acknowledge some authority, and feel the need of some atonement at a distance;
                            but a present Savior, or Redeemer, is what every one needs, to help them to cast off their
                            old imperfections and to become new creatures. To do this, souls must come before human
                            witnesses, and make an oral confession of every known sin, and transgression of the moral or
                            religious, laws of their being. Many say, it is their choice to confess sin to God in
                            secret, whom they fear and regard more than any man, or woman ; yet have not these same
                            people more fear of a man, or woman, like themselves, than they have of the invisible
                            presence of God ? Because when souls are confessing their sins, or praying to God in secret
                            for remission, without any fear or dread, were they conscious that a person of like passions
                            with themselves, especially a hater of sin, were within hearing, would they not be alarmed
                            and filled with consternation, simply because the fear of the individual presence of man, or
                            woman, is deeper in the heart than the fear of an unseen Deity ? If, then, it is infinitely
                            more mortifying to confess sins with faith and honesty in the presence of a witness, than to
                            confess them to God abstractly, it conclusively proves that this is the deepest work; and
                            that evil is more effectually slain before a witness; and thus confession before God's
                            appointed witness is the nearest possible approach to purification. This work is not a mere
                            ceremony ; but it is a direct act of duty, to be continued throughout the process of
                            redemption. It is a fixed principle ; and every soul walking in the light will love this
                            essential obligation. It is clear to the wise and considerate, because it proves sure death
                            to the generative life of nature, and gives complete victory over sin. Those who desire to
                            know what they shall do to be saved from the power of evil, will be willing to make any
                            sacrifice, that they may come into the light which will redeem them.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blake, Rhoda" TEIform="persName"/>Rhoda Blake, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Woman's sphere" TEIform="index"/>WOMAN'S SPHERE</head><p TEIform="p">We hear a great deal about woman's sphere as though there was but one calling in which woman
                            could move without robbing herself of feminine accomplishments. There are many occupations
                            in which women labor with advantage to themselves and others. Are these women in their
                            element? Do they not know their sphere as well as men ? Must all educated, intelligent women
                            perform household service, to be crowned with the plaudit: " She has labored in her sphere "
                            ? In barbarous nations women are used as beasts of burden, having no association with their
                            lords and masters except for sensual indulgence. Are those women in their sphere ? And among
                            other nations, more civilized, females are articles of merchandise. Are they in their sphere
                            on the auction block ? What of our America — our own free, noble and would-be-liberal
                            republic? Civilization has taken as deep a hold here as in any country on the globe. Yet,
                            woman is a slave. An unpleasant declaration, but true. Cradled in folly, dandled on the knee
                            of fashion, taught to esteem personal charms above moral excellence, how can she be
                            otherwise ? In the marriage relation, when woman has not the control of her own person, is
                            subject to legalized outrage, without any regard to nature's laws or physical ability — is
                            she in her sphere ? What of the poor sewing girls in our large cities, who work eighteen
                            hours of twentyfour for a mere pittance on which they can scarcely subsist, frequently
                            compelled to sell their chastity to live — are they in their sphere ? Why should the sphere
                            of woman be limited more than the sphere of man ? A law compelling all men to be farmers
                            would seem bad legislation. Do not women make as good lecturers, writers, teachers, as men ?
                            Why could they not make as good lawyers, senators and presidents ? Against woman suffrage we
                            have the argument— "It would tend to the neglect of domestic duties." Would the number of
                            women detained from the polls by domestic cares exceed the number of men who are absent from
                            sheer indifference ? What shall be done with the surplus women? They cannot all be wives and
                            mothers unless polygamy be adopted. Another argument is: "The majority of women do not want
                            to vote." Is that any reason why those who do should be disfranchised ? Woman's sphere, as
                            well as man's, should be working in humanity's cause, each bearing part in public service.
                            Thank God there are noble-hearted men and women who dare be independent, who brave public
                            opinion, who protest against the vices of the age, and devote their powers to reform and
                            elevate the down-trodden. May their numbers increase, and may God bless their labors, and
                            may all the people say Amen.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Morse, Rosie" TEIform="persName"/>Rosie Morse, Shirley, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harmony" TEIform="index"/>HARMONY</head><p TEIform="p">TnE word Harmony presents to the human mind a fitness of one thing with another, and bears
                            the impress of congeniality and consistency. If God's creation had not been perverted, it
                            would have been like a musical scale, differing in tone, and degree, but acting in concert;
                            the natural in its place, the spiritual in its place; each doing its proper work, in its
                            time and season, in perfect accord. Harmony would form a covert of peace and love; and would
                            bid mankind lay aside all envy, and malice, caused by its opposite — inharmony — and take
                            shelter under its gentle wings, and be at rest. It is sad indeed, to witness the effects of
                            inharmonious relations existing in the human family at the present time ; to see how hatred,
                            strife and revenge bear rule; and how often its subjects resort to violent measures to
                            accomplish their evil designs; and that spirit, if indulged, knows no limit. Disobedience to
                            law always produces inharmony. According to Bible history, the first parents of our race
                            sowed the seed of discord which brought forth its fruit; and for which they lost their abode
                            in paradise. The sin of disobedience has been more or less augmented and propagated by their
                            descendants, down to the present time. The effect has been—suffering. The causes of
                            inharmony have become so deeply rooted in the human heart that it is natural for every one,
                            unless influenced by a higher law, to bring forth works that will cause dissension and
                            division in the relations of life, instead of union — the cementing bond which harmonizes
                            and blends in one. We all exert an influence for good or evil. Each act, word, or look,
                            produces an effect. The founders of our institution realized this fact; and they set the
                            example of crucifying the lusts of the flesh, and of the mind; and putting away the causes
                            of inharmony. They destroyed the foundation principles in them- selves, which would divide
                            soul from soul, and prevent them from gaining and enjoying heaven. They received a baptism
                            of spiritual faith, that taught them to cultivate union, harmony and peace ; and which
                            caused them to look forward, through hope, to a more glorious future. They were pioneers in
                            the Gospel work ; and of necessity passed through a fiery ordeal. But their faith in God
                            sustained them. Discord, is a reef, whereon many vessels have stranded, that were sailing on
                            life's sea. But obedience to those principles which create harmony, will give all a safe
                            passport to the haven of rest.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Weldon, Jane" TEIform="persName"/>Jane Weldon, Union Village, Ohio.</byline></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A late number of that stirring Calcutta weekly, 'The Friend of India,' says..." TEIform="index"/>A late number of that stirring Calcutta weekly, 'The Friend of India,' says...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> A late number of that stirring Calcutta weekly, "The Friend of India," says that a
                            remarkable movement "headed by a native has set in among the people of Eastern Bengal." They
                            read the Scriptures, live up to the examples of the apostles, have visions, discard
                            medicines, and heal the sick by "laying on of hands." They are rigid vegetarians, and have
                            great faith in the efficacy of prayer. Though nominally Christian Hindoos, this "native" and
                            his followers are Spiritualists. "The gift of healing" was highly esteemed in the apostolic
                            age — why not now? Are mineral and vegetable medicines ever necessary? is a question yet to
                            be settled. Dr. E. D. Babbitt, 437 Fourth avenue, N. Y., has just brought out a volume
                            entitled the "Health Guide," which must prove exceedingly valuable to both the physically
                            and mentally afflicted. Dr. Babbitt not only tells the people, in this volume, how to get,
                            but how to keep well!</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ex." TEIform="persName"/>Ex.</byline></div2><pb n="55" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reformation" TEIform="index"/>REFORMATION</head><p TEIform="p">I LOOKED upon society and wept, "because of the flood of sensuality and crime deluging the
                            earth! Then, through faith in immortality, hope sprang up within me. I looked again ; and lo
                            ! I saw the thick darkness that had so long enveloped the earth begin to pass away before
                            the sunlight of millennial day. Intemperance, of every kind, creates darkness. Intemperance
                            in eating and drinking destroys physical health — demoralizing individuals and nations. In
                            streets and lanes of great cities, where wantonness is most rife, groggeries abound.
                            Intemperance has draped the land in mourning; and we rejoice in the present movement for its
                            suppression. Our prayer is, that it be not only rebuked but abolished! This great work
                            effected, the way will be open for practical reformation in other things. One wave of truth
                            will be followed by others in the work of human progress. Let us bless even the shadow that
                            precedes the substance. The things pertaining to this life, if temperately used, are
                            blessings. The reverse, when used beyond the actual needs of physical sustenance. Plain,
                            simple diet is far more healthful to the body than highly concentrated food with condiments
                            and viands of the most delicate kinds. The former, as it gives health physically, is also
                            conducive to sound, healthy mind—keeps it calm and collected—and gives good moral tone to
                            the whole being. The latter engenders disease, and enfeebles both body and mind. Many times
                            children inherit diseases, desires and appetites of their parents ; thus the effect of
                            wrong-doing descends from generation to generation. Intemperance is not a new evil. The
                            Israelites, in olden time, ate and drank, and rose up to play (commit fornication). They ate
                            and drank for pleasure — not use — therein they sinned — were self-corrupters. Children in
                            this day are precocious — they reach beyond the childhood state at an early age — and show
                            unnatural development of intellect, and of the passional nature. They crave the indulgence
                            of animal appetites; they taste, and are not satisfied; but cry, give, give, and the more
                            they have, the more they want. And thus they fever body and brain, often resulting in
                            premature death; and many opening rosebuds are crushed before fully blossoming into life.
                            What a pity that the vital energies should be thus wasted in self- gratification. A century
                            has now passed by, since a band of listening souls heard a voice, saying, " Cast off'the
                            garments of sin—wash in the river of judgment — renounce all carnal indulgences, and be
                            temperate in all things." That voice came from the interior spiritual heavens, and taught
                            that there was more to be done. The ax of truth must be applied to the root — the very
                            nature whence sin proceeds. As we have listened to sad experiences of disappointed,
                            heart-broken mothers and children, who have been made wretched by the power of intoxicating
                            drink, we have looked for the helper; knowing, that when the proper time arrived, Woman
                            would have a part to perform. Now, that Woman begins to awaken to duty — is finding her
                            proper sphere of action, and putting forth her energies in the right direc- tion— there is
                            hope. "We see many noble workers of our sex, bending their knees and bowing their souls in
                            prayer to God, asking in deep tones — not vengeance, but mercy for the inebriate. We, in our
                            interior Zion home, also bow and supplicate our Heavenly Father and Mother to bless the
                            work, and aid the toilers in the field of temperance reform.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Byrdsall, Charlotte" TEIform="persName"/>Charlotte Byrdsall, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dr. Charles Drysdale has written a very sharp reply to Herbert Spencer's saying that..." TEIform="index"/>Dr. Charles Drysdale has written a very sharp reply to Herbert Spencer's saying that...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">. . . Dr. Charles Drysdale has written a very sharp reply to Herbert Spencer's saying that
                            the " arrest of evolution" in the female brain is the cost she has to pay for the functions
                            of maternity. " Whenever," writes Dr. Drysdale, " science has decided that women are nobler,
                            happier, more useful, and less apt to deluge the world with excessive numbers of children,
                            when educated and enfranchised, than when ignorant and tied to domestic servitude, I admit
                            that evolution has brought about the time for us to insist on the enfranchisement and
                            education of the sex." So it seems to us.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Growth of the soul" TEIform="index"/>GROWTH OF THE SOUL</head><p TEIform="p">The soul's capacity for growth, and its longings for something higher and more enduring than
                            earth can give, is a subject that has engrossed the attention of mankind, and should
                            continue to claim deep and earnest thought. The soul is often spoken of as a vessel that may
                            be filled with wisdom and virtue, and vice versa. Some have thought that view conveyed the
                            idea of limitation to the soul's advancement, in contradistinction to the sublime truth of
                            eternal progression in knowledge and goodness, and that it would have a tendency to check
                            the aspirations for growth and improvement. But shall we not conclude, that if the vessel is
                            the soul, then the vessel expands from time to time and makes room for more, and still more.
                            The mind of a little child may be fully occupied to-day, but its unfolding life capacitates
                            it for increased receptivity tomorrow. If spirit existence and progression are to be
                            represented by material things, I would select the fairest type of seed that can be found in
                            the vegetable kingdom, which contains within itself the germs of future life and unfoldment.
                            In each seed, within its tender rind, Where golden threads in endless circles wind, Maze
                            within maze, the shining web is rolled. And as they burst, the living germs unfold. In the
                            material world, the germ exhausts itself in growth; but the spirit is ever increasing its
                            capacity and gaining more strength and vigor, being watered by the dews of a perpetual
                            spring, and the soul is continually putting forth new branches and forms of beauty. There is
                            an innate desire in every intelligent soul to grow and to rise into higher conditions. As a
                            child aspires to manhood, so does man seek a broader, wider range of thought, and to enlarge
                            his sphere of action.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Martin, Florence" TEIform="persName"/>Florence Martin, Union Village, O.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Editress" TEIform="index"/>Dear Editress</head><p TEIform="p">— Although I have not been a contributor to the bright little Herald of Truth (The " Shaker
                            and Shakeress "), I have felt a deep interest in its growth and prosperity, and have read
                            its pages fraught with so much good, with real satisfaction. And my prayers have been
                            fervent, my hopes firm, and my faith strong, that it may, and will be, a Light-spreading
                            medium, and that it may be a means of raising the banner of truth higher, which must
                            eventually prevail over error. I have felt for a long time past, that God is at work on the
                            earth (though somewhat out of sight of the natural mind), to bring about an effectual
                            change. And when I read the first published account of the " Temperance movement," I was
                            impressed that its origin was spiritual, and I was glad to learn through the columns of our
                            paper, that my feelings were in unison with those of my brethren and sisters, in this
                            respect. I fully believe that earnest, soul prayer, will be more effective in pulling down
                            the strongholds of sin, and conquering the dragon power of intoxicating drink, than any
                            carnal weapon or destructive instrument that men can invent. Let our united prayer be, that
                            the work may increase until the evils which flow from intemperance may flee the land. In
                            faith, let us say unto this great sin which has become a mountain, " Be thou cast into the
                            sea," or abolished. And to my sisters, who compose the Virgin Band, I would say : Let us
                            toil on—pray on — hope on. We will not be faint-hearted; for God is with us. If we work for
                            Him, He will hold us as in the hollow of his hand, and keep us from all harm.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Young, Louisa" TEIform="persName"/>Louisa Young, Groveland, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Pythagorean Hierocles said, 'there is nothing more worth seeing than the Brahmins of India'..." TEIform="index"/>The Pythagorean Hierocles said, 'there is nothing more worth seeing than the Brahmins of India'...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hierocles" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The Pythagorean Hierocles said, " there is nothing more worth seeing than the Brahmins of
                            India, a people addicted to philosophy, who eat no manner of flesh, who live almost entirely
                            in the open air, who have all things in common, who maintain continence, who cultivate the
                            truth, who wear clothes made of linen, and who when eating adapt their motions to
                        music."</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Man judges of the inward disposition by the outward acts : God judges of                                 the outward acts by the inward disposition" TEIform="index"/>Man judges of the inward disposition by the outward acts...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Man judges of the inward disposition by the outward acts : God judges of the outward acts by
                            the inward disposition.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Individuality and communism" TEIform="index"/>INDIVIDUALITY AND COMMUNISM</head><p TEIform="p">When Jesus, after instructing his handful of followers, that they were the salt or saving
                            principle of the earth, said further to them, " Have salt in yourselves," he was giving the
                            most direct confirmation to the idea of individuality. The righteousness of Noah or David
                            was nothing to them, nor even his own, vicariously. Enough of this salt, or saving princi-
                            ple, in the soul, to make the individual invincible to all the attractions which lower the
                            tone of goodness is essential. How can the salt retain its savor and be resistant to the
                            putrefying and destructive elements around ? A slight sprinkling of salt gives a relish and
                            zest to some articles of food and is a stimulus to vegetable growth; even as the society of
                            individuals, polished by some of the Christian graces, is highly prized, even by worldly
                            men. But the integrity of the salt itself is lost by entering into chemical combination with
                            the elements to which it is thus subjected; and unless in quantities sufficient to be
                            decidedly unpalatable, is not saving. But, if gathered to its like, and sheltered from all
                            unnecessary-exposure to the elements, it can retain its characteristics and be ready, if
                            needed, to furnish the evidence of its savor, pungency, and use. Continually are operating
                            on our spirits the unselfishness or the ambition which will transform the latent good into
                            pollution or decay, if the testimony pungent and strong is not burning within us, which
                            prevents all compromising with evil, or amalgamating with deceit. Perfect transparency, as
                            illustrated by those whom the Kevelator saw " standing on the sea of glass," is desirable.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webster, E. H." TEIform="persName"/>E. H. Webster, Harvard, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Eldress A.:" TEIform="index"/>Dear Eldress A.:</head><p TEIform="p">In a recent Number of the " Shaker and Shakeress, I read some remarks made by the '
                            Travailing Daughters of New York.' " And I was strongly impressed with the importance of
                            Woman's sphere and duty; and that she should clearly understand her mission, and not run as
                            uncertain, nor fight as those who beat the air. Woman, through ignorance and false educa-
                            tion, has been a medium of unholy loves and vain hopes to man, and has ministered to his
                            sensual desires and appetites, by seeking to be to him an object of pleasure, rather than a
                            minister of principle, arid a preserver of integrity. Now, a neAv Era is dawning. Divine
                            light is breaking forth, dispelling the dark clouds which ignorance, superstition, and
                            sinful practices have formed ; and its piercing rays have entered woman's soul — vivified
                            her conscience — and she is found praying. Now with strong cries she is heard to say — "
                            Lord, what shall / do to be saved ? " and what can I do to save my brother from ruin ? The
                            answer to that prayer will be, Let Woman come forth, and through toil and a self-sacrificing
                            spirit, act well her part in raising the standard of moral purity higher than it has ever
                            been raised before, and become an example to her own sex, in regard to dress and wasteful
                            expenditure in every department of life. Then, she will shed a saving influence, and be a
                            bright example of virtue and integrity. And in thus doing, she will speed the day when men
                            and women will act in concert together in all the duties of life, and be found side by side
                            in the Council Halls of the nation as mutual guides and helps to each other. In ethics, in
                            religion, and in civil government, the voice of Woman will be heard,and by her quick
                            intuitive perception of right, and her inspirational emotions springing from the love
                            element of her nature, she will be as a cloud of glory overshadowing man in his arduous
                            labors ; and her counsel will be sweet solace, and will help to solve many dark problems,
                            and dispose of intricate subjects, and disrobe malice and envy of their power.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Van Houten, C." TEIform="persName"/>C. Van Houten, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Celibacy and wedlock" TEIform="index"/>Celibacy and wedlock</head><p TEIform="p">If single life is bad, then it stands to reason that double life is twice as bad.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Van Houten, C." TEIform="persName"/>C. Van Houten, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The bread of life is love..." TEIform="index"/>The bread of life is love...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The bread of life is love; the salt of life is work; the sweetness of life, poesy; the
                            water of life, faith.</p></div2><pb n="56" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>HOME</head><p TEIform="p">We have a home from the cold world hid, A spot consecrated to God; And our feet are shod for
                            the blest highway Here we can ban ish the cares of earth, And fancies that lead astray; 'Tis
                            here we strive that the angel death Here waves of love around us roll, And open the beauties
                            of grace; Till their power of good be comes for us Which the ransom'd before have trod. Here
                            the star of Innocence for ever shines; And beams of Charity glow; May never becloud our way.
                            Thus the growth of a life in God is ours, The strength of the Conqueror's light, A heavenly
                            home and place. And thus we're hid from a cold world's gaze, To know of a sinless rest; Here
                            The When the inner thoughts are attuned through faith, To virtue's melodious flow, To
                            virtue's melod'ious flow, joy that futurity's bliss reveals, With immortality bright, With
                            immortality bright, the breath of our being upward wings, To float in the land of the blest,
                            To float in the land of the blest. O home for the soul, Heaven begun below; We'll sing of
                            thy beauty and tell of thy joys, Till all thy glory shall know.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Valediction" TEIform="index"/>VALEDICTION</head><p TEIform="p">Farewell, blessed of thy Father! Enter now thy bright abode! Well beloved of thy mother,—
                            Cherish'd by the saints of God. Dearest sister, " very pleasant Thou hast ever been to me ;"
                            Still, O may I feel thee present, Breathing love and purity! Now, thy loss, we'll not
                            deplore it, Though it may seem hard to bear ; God is good, He will restore it, With his
                            blessing everywhere. We will mark thy footsteps lowly, Walk the path of peace and love, And
                            with Angels blest and holy, We shall join with thee above.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hall, Catharine" TEIform="persName"/>Catharine Hall, Harvard, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="shaker-press" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Charles Nordhoff has been engaged in collecting the materials for..." TEIform="index"/>Charles Nordhoff has been engaged in collecting the materials for...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Charles Nordhoff has been engaged in collecting the materials for a detailed account of the
                            Communistic Societies now existing in the United States. He has been visiting and personally
                            examining all of these societies —no slight undertaking, as they are scattered from Maine to
                            Oregon. He proposes to give an account of the religious creeds and practices, the peculiar
                            social customs and regulations, the history and present numbers, condition and industries of
                            each society. The subject is novel and attractive, and the facts collected by him will be so
                            presented as to be not only of interest to the reader for amusement, but of value to the
                            student of social science, for their practical bearing and illustration of the possibilities
                            and difficulties of a community of goods, a subject which is now widely agitated among
                            workingmen here and in Europe. Such a work will be a valuable contribution to the
                            discussion.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Curse of the age" TEIform="index"/>THE CURSE OF THE AGE</head><p TEIform="p">The words which should be written in every home and impressed upon every mind are that the
                            education that is to avail in this life is not to be learned from books, piano-stools,
                            drawing-schools, and French tutors alone. This idea has cursed the people of this country
                            long enough. Men and women are to-day wandering about with nothing to do, who have spent
                            time enough poring over Greek and Latin, or drumming on a piano, and mental and muscular
                            force enough, too, to have acquired knowledge of and skill in a business or trade that would
                            have placed them beyond the possibility of want. The field for intelligent and skillful
                            labor in this country is large and poorly supplied ; that for accomplished imbeciles is
                            small and terribly overstocked.</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In a late number of the New Haven Evening Register, we find the following paragraph..." TEIform="index"/>In a late number of the New Haven Evening Register, we find the following paragraph...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">In a late number of the New Haven Evening Register, we find the following paragraph : It is
                            said that there is not now living a single descendant in the male line of Chaucer,
                            Shakspeare, Spencer, Milton, Cowley, Butler, Dryden,Pope, Cowper, Goldsmith, Scott, Byron,
                            Moore, Sir Philip Sidney, Sir Walter Raleigh, Drake, Cromwell, Hampden, Monk, Marlborough,
                            Peterborough, Nelson, Stafford, Ormond, Clarendon, Addison, Swift, Johnson, Walpole,
                            Bollingbroke, Chatham, Pitt, Fox, Burke, Grattan, Canning, Bacon, Locke, Newton, Davy, Hume,
                            Gibbon, Macaulay, Hogarth, Sir Joshua Reynolds, David Garrick, John Kemble or Edmund Kean.
                            There is a law under which the procreative forces pass from the back brain to the
                            intellectual and turn from the intellectual to the spiritual faculties.</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">NOVITIATE ELDERS AND ELDRESSES. Elders. Post-office Address. Eldresses. Elder F. W.
                            Evans................ Mt. Lebanon, Columbia county, N. Y. Eldress Antoinette Doolittle. " O.
                            A. Lamas................. Shakers, Albany county, N. Y........ " Harriet M. Bullard. " CO.
                            Reed................ Sonyea, Livingston county, N. Y..... " Abigail Crosman, " Simon
                            Mabee................. West Pittsfield, Mass................. " Betsey Sneydon. " H. S.
                            Kellogg................. Thompsonville, Conn................ " Anna Ervin. " A. J.
                            Battles................. South Lee, Mass..................... " Harriet Storer. " Wm.
                            Leonard............... Ayer, Mass............................ " Nancy Fairbanks. " H.
                            Tabor.................... Shirley Village, Mass.................. " Lucretia Godfrey. "
                            Henry Cummings............ Enfield, N. H........................... " Hannah Taylor. " B.H.
                            Smith.................. Shaker Village, N. H.................. " Harriet March. " J.B.
                            Vance.................. Alfred, Me............................ " Eliza Smith. " Nehemiah
                            Trull.............. West Gloucester, Me................. " Hannah Davis. " J. S.
                            Prescott................. Cleveland (Shakers), O................ " Prudence Sawyer. " Isaac
                            Beals............... Lebanon (Shakers), O................ " Susannah Farnham. " Jacob
                            Kulp................... Pleasant Hill, Ky...................... " Betsy Spalding. " John R.
                            Cooper............. South Union, Ky..................... " Sarah Small. " Ezra
                            Sherman.............. Preston, Hamilton county, 0........ " Betsy G. Gass. "
                            StephenBall.................. Dayton (Shakers), O.................. " Adaline Wills.</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>