<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1306" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">13</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">6</biblScope><date value="18830601" TEIform="date">June 1883</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">121-144</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="13" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="6" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                <pb n="t.p." id="p1"/>
    <p> VOL. XIII. JUNE. NO. 6. SHAKER MANIFESTO Published by the United Societies. OUR HOMB AT SHAKERS,
                        N. Y. "Blessed are those that hear the word of God and keep it." SHAKER VILLAGE, N. H. 1883. </p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p> [Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
--><pb n="121" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><!--
                    <div2 type="none">
                        <p> CONTENTS. The Mythical Shaker Bible , Comb up Higher, Goodness, Hope, - - Fervency of Spirit, Tribute to Gospel
                            Friends, New Jerusalem, Truth, RepiiY, No. 1, To an Erring One, The Coming Era, Spiritualism, The Shakers,
                            Letter from S. Mabee, Sensual, Visit to the Shakers, Page. - 121 122 - 124 125 127 128 129 130 131 132 133 134
                            Age, A Moment's Reverie, Letter Box, Notes, Life in the Woods, Hot and Cold Drinks, Apples for Food, Finger
                            Nails, Selected, Building up Character, Example, Three Words of Strength, Music ;—Trust in God, Books and
                            Papers, Deaths, Kind Words for 1882, Page- 136 1ST 138 - 139 140 141 143 144 Vol. XIII. JUNE, 1883. No. 6. </p>
                    </div2>
                    --><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mythical 'Shaker' Bible" TEIform="index"/> THE MYTHICAL "SHAKER BIBLE."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Roberts, J. M." TEIform="persName"/> J. M. Roberts</byline><p TEIform="p"> :— Much Esteemed Friend :—We observe in Mind and Matter of 10th inst., a paragraph in a
                            lecture delivered by Annie T. Anderson, in St Louis, Mo., on January 28th, which says : "The
                            sect of Shakers have Mother Ann's Bible. They do not pretend to need any other." etc. As
                            this statement is entirely erroneous, it is due the public that it should be corrected, as
                            it is calculated to prejudice and mislead many minds. To meet this misstatement directly, we
                            must say the Shakers never had any different Bible from that of all other professed Jewish
                            and Christian denominations,—the translation of King James ! The story of the Shaker Bible
                            is a rehearsal of an old remark that was probably originated some seventy years since to
                            deride a book written and published by the Shaker's Society in 1810, entitled, "Christ's
                            Second Appearing," being a general review of all church history, with quotations and
                            criticisms, together with a statement of the principles of religious light and faith, which
                            had been revealed to, and accepted by the people called Shakers at that, time. This work has
                            undergone some four revisions. Neither this book, nor' any other book written and published
                            by the Shakers, is a Bible in any different. sense than the writings of John Calvin, Martin
                            Luther, George Fox, John Wesley, or George Whitfield, may be called Bibles. Its testimony is
                            not a creed; the Shakers have no creed, in the ordinary sense in which that term is used,,
                            that is, a fixed boundary of religious ideas and supposed revelations of truth beyond which
                            there is no further revela-<pb n="122" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/>tion of light and truth, and duty. But the
                            Shakers believe in a continuous revelation of Divine light and truth. That all truth is
                            eternal, and its plenary revelation to man may require infinity of ages and cycles of
                            progress, arid, that true Christianity embraces the whole of it, and the Shakers believe
                            that they have need of the whole of it, instead of as Annie T. Anderson says, "They (the
                            Shakers) do not pretend to need any other Bible." O, yea, Annie, the Shakers claim to need
                            all the truth ever revealed to man, through any and every means ! The Shakers'book entitled
                            "Christ's Second Appearing," was presented to Thomas Jefferson, when he said, "I have read
                            it through three times, and I pronounce it the best Church History that ever was written,
                            and, if its exegesis of Christian principles is maintained, and sustained by a practical
                            life, it is destined, eventually, to overthrow all other religions." Annie tells the people
                            that "Shakerism is already failing to establish that elysium in Shaker fields it was
                            revealed to do a half century ago." No failure at all in this, Annie ! Those who truly and
                            faithfully live the Shaker Christian life, do find a present salvation from sin and its
                            consequent sorrows, and eventuate in a power of redemption from the nature of sin. The
                            Shakers never anticipated, nor proposed to the world an unruffled "elysium" until all souls
                            are redeemed from sin and its consequences, and garnered into the kingdom of God. This was
                            our Mother Ann Lee's testimony, "sufferings in the Church will never cease until all souls
                            are redeemed to God," it is a demonstration of true Christian sympathy. The Shakers find
                            true the declaration of Jesus, viz., "The Kingdom of Heaven is like a net cast into the sea,
                            that gathers of every kind, which, when it is drawn ashore, men gather the good into
                            vessels, and cast the bad away." Now, while these bad fish are in the net, they make trouble
                            among the good fish ;—retrench on the "elysian" fields of the wood and true, so that a true
                            Christian Saint, a real virtuoso, comes up through great tribulation to be clad in white
                            robes of redemption, and garnered into the Kingdom of God. Nevertheless, :n the
                            congregations of the true Saints of God, who really live the Christ life, there is a very
                            present heaven and a prepared Heavenly Mansion in that "House not made with hands," in the
                            eternal Kingdom of Glory. Giles B. Avkkt. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Come up higher" TEIform="index"/> COME UP HIGHER.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/>ANTOINETTE DOOLITTLE.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Many and profound are the problems of human life to be solved in the coming future, which
                            can only be done as events transpire and living issues arise to call forth deeper thought,
                            and changed or enlarged action. We may do +iie work of our day and time faithfully, and
                            answer the demands of a good conscience, and leave broad fields of labor for incoming
                            generations ; and they in turn may do the work of their day and close their eyes upon its
                            setting sun ; but other suns will arise and new days will follow in succession and there
                            will yet be work enough to be done. At the present, we see multitudes— lured by passion and
                            pleasure-seeking, getting wealth by stealth, heaping up earthly treasures at the expense of
                            others, <pb n="123" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 123 that they may live in luxury and ease, and
                            revel in sensuality and intemperance, which fill the land with incest, legalized adultery
                            and infanticide, to an alarming extent, so that many are fearful lest the earth become
                            depopulated and deluged with crime—unless a higher standard \&gt;2 raised, and
                            trumpet-tongued ministers arise who will not fear to declare the Avhole truth, and testify
                            against the gross sins of this demoralized generation ;—and they cry out in dismay "Help,
                            Lord, for the godly man ceaseth." If the great evils in society were confined chiefly to the
                            poorer and more ignorant classes, it would seem more hopeful and pardonable. As it is, the
                            more educated and wealthy, who are honored by men, and move in the higher circles. are as
                            deeply imbued, as the lower classes, and who by their money and influence, hire and persuade
                            many of the orthodox clergy to preach smooth things that will fall pleasantly up°n their
                            ears, and will not prick their consciences. Thus the priests and the people are found
                            wallowing in the ditch of sin and shame together. The indwellers in God's spiritual house
                            which in the ages long ago, was seen in vision by the prophet Isaiah, that woulc be
                            established on the top of the mountain above all hills—and which prediction is now being
                            fulfilled—look out upon the broad expanse below and see myriads of toilers in the fields of
                            mora and physical reform, inspired and aidec by spirits in spheres above them ; but who have
                            not as yet risen above the generative plane into the Christ, or Resurrection heavens,
                            working diligent ly to uplift the lowly, and as far as they have sight to see—to "destroy
                            the cover ing of iniquity—cast over all nations,' ind show them a better way ; but it will
                            )e a long time before they will be able o see and walk in the most excellent way. The
                            extreme Sensualist most be rebrmed by degrees. Inebriates, who lave lost all self-control,
                            and become callous to conscience and reason, are difficult to reach ; through the faith and
                            by the prayers of othei-s, they must be reformed, if at all. The aspiring bloodthirsty
                            warrior, whose ambitious desires for military fame and glory, blunt all moral sensibilities,
                            so that he will not listen to the voice of his own conscience, nor heed the entreaties of
                            friends, who would persuade him to desist from doing acts, which only demons should perform,
                            if any ; but all such solicitations avail little. When wars cease, there will be less crime
                            ! Reformers have a difficult task to perform ; but they are doing a good work. We find an
                            illustration of the ladder which Jacob of olden time saw in vision, which reached from earth
                            to heaven. The ascension from low to higher conditions, must be by progressive steps; and by
                            persevering effort it will be effected. Woman in her sphere is acting a noble part. In the
                            cause of Peace and Temperance, she works diligently. She lifts her voice against legalized
                            prostitution, and is bold to affirm, that it is no better in the sight of God and Angels,
                            than when out of wedlock ; that woman has a-right to her own person, and that man has no
                            right to rule over her. And furthermore, that the marriage institution should be used, as
                            originally designed i. e. propagation ; not for sensual gratification ! But we claim, that
                            the highest standard of moral ethics that can be raised <pb n="124" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/>on the natural
                            generative plane, is not the- highest possibility of attainment, even while dwelling in
                            mortal form ; that there is still another ladder that may be climbed ; that there is a
                            spiritual destiny awaiting human souls ; and when the top-most round of the ladder is
                            reached which Jacob saw, then a proper and firm foundation is laid for a still higher
                            ascension into the resurrection heavens, towering above the generative plane and above the
                            hills or religious organizations which rest upon that basis ; where marriage iv. its highest
                            form is not found ; but the angelic lift is attained. To those Avho are able to hear what
                            the spirit saith, the call is, ''Come up higher into the Christ sphere, where the heavenly
                            Bridegroom and Bride—in a dual capacity—-work harmoniously together, and the heavens are
                            filled with God's glory and praise ! Mt. Lebanon., N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Goodness" TEIform="index"/> GOODNESS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>MARY WHITCHER.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Selfishness, the soul of sin, Let us'strive to overcome. Good without from good within, Is
                            the goodness to be won. Not a cloak for Christian life Made of "seeming to be good," But the
                            real, without strife, Welling up in life to God. Here the accent of the voice Is the breath
                            of love within; With the neighbor we rejoice In his joy, and mourn his pain. . Children of
                            the living God, Born anew through Christ the Lamb, Through his life, which is the blood, We
                            are sacrificed for Him. Here the resurrection stands,— Man arisen from the dead, With pure
                            heart and cleansed hands, Doing as the Savior did. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hope" TEIform="index"/>Hope</head><p TEIform="p"> "WRITTEN FOR THE MANIFESTO. HOPE. I place my ruler where I wish to mark, It casts a heavy
                            shadow there, so dark,— I cannot see, yet it will guide aright, If I but turn the work
                            toward the light. I cannot see through all the clouds to-day, But if I turn and go the other
                            way, Perhaps 'twill clearer be and God's sweet smile Will not be lost by shining through the
                            mist, But beaming brightly o'er me all the while, My heart will be as flowers by sunlight
                            kissed.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fervency of spirit" TEIform="index"/> FERVENCY OF SPIRIT.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Martin, Elizabeth" TEIform="persName"/>ELIZABETH MARTIN.</byline><p TEIform="p"> When we view the ranks of our church, and number the soids whom the Father has drawn to his
                            people, whom it has been our privilege in the past to assist, we think : Where are they who
                            to-day should be the most active workers in the Lord's vineyard ? Did we exert an influence
                            of godliness as disciples of Christ to hold them to their discipleship ? Were we interested
                            in them actively, stretching out our hands and our hearts sufficiently in charitable,
                            forgiving, and uplifting deeds to manifest that interest in their labors, and for their
                            salvation? Our love, as disciples of Christ, is too limited, too narrow, vague, indifferent,
                            not intensified by an. active concern,—a perfect fulfilling of the law in our own life
                            duties, to the out-stretching of our hearts with a determined, fervent intent, that every
                            child called of God, shall succeed in all things that pertain to their spiritual prosperity
                            and growth. "Love is the fulfilling of the law." "Love casteth out fear." Love is the great
                            lever of salvation, talk of it as we may, it is the most powerful agent to win souls to
                            Christ. It is the Prime <pb n="125" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> Minister of the heavenly Courts. If we would
                            be Saviors, we must serve the Lord our God, with all our "mind, might and strength, and love
                            our neighbor as ourself." No time to be idle, no right to make reserves for self-pleasure ;
                            but ever "fervent in spirit, serving the Lord" is the motto for the Christian. We are
                            students in the school of Christ;—for what purpose are students learning? Is it that they
                            alone may know of the doctrine of Christ's kingdom, be passively good themselves, keeping
                            free from the grosser sins to which humanity are heirs, while they carelessly gaze upon a
                            world of iniquity ? Or are they to become thoroughly learned in the word of God by actively
                            working the works of righteousness ; thus becoming fully imbued with the spirit of the
                            Divine Master, enabled to lift up the fallen, to consume sin in- the exceeding righteousness
                            of the spirit, and bind the sinner to his Christian duty forever. That our church suffers
                            drouth to-day from the sloth and indifference of its members, its want of "fervency of
                            spirit" is plainly to be seen. It is not enough that we understand Christian principles, and
                            dwell in the church built thereon, thinking it will stand without our aid ; God will ever
                            work through agencies ; the luke-warm and indifferent lie "will spew from his mouth." The
                            looker-on sometimes asks : "In what degree is your church better than other churches?" "Oh,"
                            the thoughtless member will reply, "of course we are better—we don't marry, we live
                            unselfishly by holding our property in common,—and we don't mingle with the people of the
                            world." Well, so far, so good ; but let us reflect a little : What is the duty of a
                            Christian? "Let him that names the name of Christ, depart from all iniquity," all forms oi'
                            selfishness, injustice, revenge, malice, envy, and every other name and shade of an inherent
                            fallen nature. "Well," says the passive member, "I do nothing day by day, for which I feel
                            condemned, am I not a Christian?" "By their fruits ye shall know them." "Do men gather
                            grapes of thorns, or figs of thistles?" If we bear no fruit, and the Master coming, fiudeth
                            only leaves, to what can we be likened? Is there not need of rallying the forces of Israel,
                            to save not only the geetiles, but its indifferent self? Who is to sound the awakening
                            trumpet ? "God is no respector of persons." It is fully time for our church to arise, shake
                            off her drowsy condition, and putting her trust in God, go forth into the harvest fields,
                            and with "fervency of spirit," call clown upon the ripened earth the pentecostal baptism
                            just at hand. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tribute to Gospel friends" TEIform="index"/> TRIBUTE TO GOSPEL FRIENDS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, Catherine" TEIform="persName"/>CATHARINE ALLEN.</byline><p TEIform="p"> When contemplating the joy and ever unfolding glory, with which our Zion Home is rife, my
                            heart fills with praise to the Dispenser of all good, and turns with thankful emotion to
                            those whose sacrifice for truth in past and present time, has ultimated in this beautiful
                            heritage ; particularly to my older brethren and sisters of the Household of Faith, to whom
                            I am indebted more immediately for the blessings I share. To them I would pledge to dedicate
                            my life, sincerely and fully, to the principles they teach by precept and example, trust-
                                <pb n="126" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/>ing that although a small offering for so great a boon, it will be
                            acceptable ; as I realize that it is only through consecration, that any talent or
                            gift.—however valuable in itself,—may be serviceable in the house of God, where all are
                            called to crucify selfishness in every form, and where the fires of vain ambition for
                            personal glorification, must be quenched by the baptismal waters of pentecostal love. In the
                            true community relation, which sprung from, and can only be maintained in this gift ef ever
                            expanding love, all useful labor is redeemed from the blight which monopoly, class and caste
                            have thrown upon it; and of whatever name or nature, is made alike honorable to those upon
                            whom different branches may devolve. It is the motive, and devotion to the Cause, far more
                            than the amount apparently accomplished, which yields benefit and blessing to the individual
                            member, or collective body. In this united capacity, where all are bound by sacred covenant
                            to live for, and serve one another, there is in reality no gift or honor, that does not
                            belong equally to each member of the body, proportionate to that sacrifice of self, which
                            identifies the person with the Cause, and keeps open the a emits whence good gifts are
                            given. Thus I am prompted to write, by no means as instructing those whose life works
                            bespeak these sentiments, but as expressive of that faith, which I humbly feel is leading me
                            step by step away from error, into the sphere of those mortals, and immortals, who have
                            freed their souls from its chains, and can worship God and live for truth more fully than J
                            am yet able to do. I am continually helped and blest by the ministrations of faithful souls,
                            who have been willing to pay any price to save from the grasp of those who would gladly draw
                            to earth, the snowy banner of Virgin Purity, which now waves aloft in the sunlight of the
                            resurrection spheres and is an ensign to the nations, of peace and liberty from the
                            thralldom of sensual passions. They claim my reverence, affection and gratitude ; this I
                            would prove by earnestly striving in obedience to the inward conviction that calls me to the
                            same beautiful, soulredeeming work. When the curtain of retirement is lifted, and we look
                            for a moment on earth's restless throng, how repulsive and painful many of the scenes which
                            unbidden rise before the vision, of political and social organizations, discordant with the
                            laws of God and of nature. Crime in high and in low places ; poverty, ignorance and distress
                            ; wild irrational pleasure-seeking through selfindulgence, reckless of consequences here or
                            hereafter. Do not angels weep as they look down upon such, knowing how much suffering must
                            be borne ere they find releasement from the chains thus forged in the fires of passion? But
                            earth is not all shrouded in darkness. We gladly recognize many who are nobly struggling
                            against foes within and without, that the laws of justice uud truth may be established in
                            the councils of nations and in the hearts of the people. All reformers, in whatever field,
                            are bringing nearer the Millennial day. When I catch glimpses of the work of God in its
                            future unfoldings, I feel an urgent zeal to do my little part earnestly and faithfully in
                            the practical acceptance of the truth revealed to-day, although it <pb n="127" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/>
                            calls for much sacrifice ; remembering that the seeds of the harvest we are reaping, have
                            been sown in tears, and nourished by the Mood of martyrs ; and that thus we must sow for
                            others to reap. We mark upon Time's dial-plate, as the hands move round from space to space,
                            how the prophets' words aglow with inspiration, uttered long centuries ago, and the visions
                            of seers in their most exalted seasons, all radiant in glory are now being fulfilled. The
                            prophets' fire still burns in the hearts of many in our own midst; and still bright visions
                            thrill the souls of those who look with Faith's clairvoyant eye to the increase of the
                            future, and around are angel messengers, prompting to deeper devotion, and more self-denial,
                            which alone can open the portals to new degrees of revelation . Mount Lebanon, iV". Y. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New Jerusalem" TEIform="index"/> NEW JERUSALEM.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Danforth, Nancy G." TEIform="persName"/>NANCY G. DANFORTH.</byline><p TEIform="p">The Savior said, "In my Father's house are many mansions, I go to prepare a place for you."
                            What are those mansions and what is meant by preparing a place for his disciples ? We are
                            all in our Father's house, his watchful care is over all the works of his hands, and there
                            are many mansions, or dwelling places appropriate to different conditions : thus we find a
                            person who is very degraded, sunk in every species of vice and crime, such an one dwells in
                            the lowest mansions, yet is he not forgotten of his God. At length some small ray of
                            conviction reaches him and he is induced to leave off someone sin, thus step up into the
                            next mansion, where those of the same grade may be found for associates ; in this manner he
                            can proceed until he becomes a moral man and all this before attempting to take a single
                            step in the Christ life. The Savior says, "I go to prepare a place for you." Was there then
                            no mansion ready for them, and why not? Mankind had not travelled up to that higher order to
                            which they are now called. Jesus, knowing there would be a still greater work, says, "If I
                            go and prepare a place for you I will come again and receive you unto myself." Accordingly,
                            He went to the spirit world and there established the order of perfect purity, which, in due
                            time was made known on earth by special Revelations where a city is described as coming down
                            '"from God out of heaven," and a voice said, "The tabernacle of God is with men," showing
                            that "the way into the Holy of Holies is now made manifest." Now look at the order and
                            appointments of this beautiful city. In the first place it lieth four square, the height,
                            length, and breadth of it are equal, which shows the perfect equality in all things, which
                            is to exist amongst God's people. The foundations are of precious stones, the true
                            principles of godliness, truth, hope, honesty, continence, innocence, simplicity, meeknessr
                            | humility, prudence, patience, thankfulness and charity, upon which the Church of Christ is
                            built, and they can never be tarnished. The gates are of pearl, the beautiful graces of the
                            spirit which adorn the true Christian. The city and the streets are of pure gold, like unto
                            transparent glass ; this shows the state of purity we must attain in all the walks of life ;
                            our every thought, word and action must breathe perfect purity; this is the more evident, as
                            no unclean thing, noth- <pb n="128" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/>ing that in any way defiles can enter within
                            the walls of this Holy City, neither dogs nor sorcerers, nor adulterers, and we find by the
                            Savior's words it does not always take the openly vile to constitute these characters, but
                            all who harbor these feelings in their hearts are the detiled, inasmuch as every impure
                            thought defiloth the imagination, therefore such feelings can have no place there. "And 1
                            saw no temple therein, for the Lord God and the Lamb are the temple thereof." No idol
                            worship is acceptable, but every soul must present himself as a living temple for the
                            worship of the one true God. Again,' 'The city had no need of the sun, neither of the moon
                            to shine in it, for the glory of God did lighten it, and the Lam? is the light thereof; and
                            there shall be no night there." Wher3 purity reigns no gloomy shades of night prevail, as
                            sin constitutes the works of darkness and is the covering cast over all nations ; but the
                            spirit of God, as a burning lamp, will search the dark recesses of every heart, where its
                            bright rays are admitted ; it will cleanse and refine from all dross, thus prepare the soul
                            to dwell in the perfect light of God made manifest in his chosen witness for the cleansing
                            of the Sanctuary. We also find a river of life flowing through the City, with the tree of
                            life on either side. The river signifies the waters of judgment and true repentance, through
                            which every soul must pass in order to be redeemed ; and this judgment is dispensed by and
                            through his witnesses both male and female representing the tree of life on either eide of
                            the river, whose leaves, or words are for the healing of every sin-sick soul of whatever
                            nation, or tongue. Thus we see that those mansions are not locations, but the different
                            conditions of the soul, and when following the light of God, it can travel from one degree
                            of grace to another, until it arrives at that state of perfect purity which can be likened
                            to this beautiful vision of the Revelator. It is the redeemed who shall walk there, while
                            all nations and their rulers, shall bring their glory and honor into it. Therefore we need
                            not fear, for earthly good will not be with-held, but all that will beautify the Lord's
                            house will in due time be made subservient to his people, while the law and perishable
                            pleasures of time, will cease to allure the soul who seeks to be redeemed from sin, by
                            bathing in these pure waters of life, and thu? become worthy to dwell in the Holy City, even
                            New Jerusalem. Canterbury, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Truth" TEIform="index"/> TRUTH.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fields, Floyd C." TEIform="persName"/> FLOYD C. FIELDS.</byline><p TEIform="p"> I thirst for truth: truth which eternally shall stand, 'Twill bear the test, in every age.
                            in every land, Principles which are eternal, which can never die, Truths which are
                            irrefragable, ah, for these I sigh. Truths which we can realize, and know that we are right,
                            Truths by which we can face all, and fairly win the fight, With truth upon our banner, we
                            its glory will unfold, For truth to us more precious is than honor, fame or gold. Truths
                            given by the Infinite, great Father of all right, Who always was and always is— grand
                            Center, love and light. Imperishable truths which evermore shall stand, <pb n="129" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> Though storms may beat and floods may surge on every hand. Yea truths that shall
                            eradicate false theories of old, And dogmas, void of reason, which the superstitious hold.
                            And though it causes anguish for the priesthood of our land Let vs do our own thinking and
                            for truth we'll take a stand. Some doubtless have been honest, these old fancies to
                            maintain, Yet others have proclaimed them to enrich themselves with gain. But sorely has
                            been deadened, cramped, the growth of many a mind By using not their reason, the grand
                            truths to seek and find. The mind of man—the great and crowning work of all, Why! nature
                            'thout a mind, the universe would fall! Without a mind we would become e'en worse than
                            naught; Without a mind no valued treasures could be sought. Treasures of knowledge, gems of
                            truth,—sublime and grand,— Of principles upon which earth's foundations stand. Jewels of
                            light transmitted from the eternal sun, Grandeur of intellect, by which all truths are won.
                            May truths sublime illuminate our very soul, As mysteries we fathom of th' eternal whole ;
                            For knowledge, wisdom, finite man can soon impart, If at the fount of truth he sips to take
                            the stai't. As superstitions, dogmas, errors, fast will pass away, Soon universal free
                            thought will the scepter sway. So let us gird the armor on of progress and of right, And
                            we'll march on to victory equipped with truth and light, Yea we will shout the vict'ry when
                            the battle's won, And Truth, our banner, then shall shine as doth the sun. While in
                            progression we'll continue still to rise, Far in the ambient air of the eternal skies.
                            Union, Ky </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reply, No. 1" TEIform="index"/> REPLY, NO. 1.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ervin, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>ANNA ERVIN.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Respected Friend;—Your welcome letter is received. It is always our desire to treat with
                            respect the enquiries of upright souls who are struggling for light. It is our prayer that
                            you may yet find a conviction of the truth of those things, which are now a stumbling block
                            to you. We suppose from your remarks, that you are convinced that a life of purity and
                            holiness is the only means whereby man can find acceptance with God, and that whatever may
                            be his profession of religion, he cannot gain redemption from evil short of bearing fully
                            the cross of Christ. We will not dwell now on this subject. We hope to be able to offer some
                            remarks respecting the appearance of Christ in the order of the female, which may relieve
                            your present difficulties. To the candid inquiring mind there has ever been on this matter a
                            fruitful field of thought. You probably suppose that we worship the woman, Ann Lee. But such
                            an idea is quite erroneous, and arises because sufficient attention has not been paid to our
                            explanations. We worship neither Jesus of Nazareth nor Ann Lee, but the Creator alone. All
                            nature goes to show that the Deity is dual, male and female. Both the animal and vegetable
                            kingdoms are dual, and even in the subtle element of electricity and in the earth of our
                            globe we find the dual principle, positive and negative. St. Paul declares that "the
                            invisible things of Him from the creation of the world are clearly seen, being understood by
                            the things that are made, even his eternal power and Godhead." Eom. ii. 20. We see in nature
                            that, for the purpose of reproduction, there must be male and female powers, so do we see,
                            according to the Apostle's declaration, that for God to produce anything He must possess
                            within Himself the elements of male and female powers. This, indeed, is clearly expressed in
                            Genesis, i. 27. "God created man in His own image; male and female created He them." Those
                            who have been brought up to consider God as a stern Father, will find it a refreshing
                            thought to learn that there is a new revelation of God on the earth as a loving, heavenly,
                            Mother, <pb n="130" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/>This grand idea being once firmly grasped, a revolution will
                            shortly be produced in the religious opinions of the sincere. From an arbitrary being
                            dispensing rewards and punishments on account of a belief or disbelief of the mind, thereby
                            condemning millions of human beings to eternal misery merely on account of ignorance, or
                            from disgust at the evil lives of professing Christians, we turn to view the pleasing
                            character of a Divine Father and Mother, giving to every one, Jew or Gentile, professing
                            Christian, open heathen or atheist, "according as his works shall be." Rev. xxiv. 12. Thus
                            after death all will find themselves in that degree of happiness or misery which their works
                            have earned, but with capacity to progress. Beliefs or disbeliefs are nothing towards
                            salvation or condemnation, save as such beliefs lead us to live in a virtuous or vicious
                            manner. Yet we do not require those coming among us to believe immediately as we do ; but
                            require them to be virtuous. Having stated our reasons for belief in the Motherhood as well
                            as the Fatherhood of God, we will proceed to point out our views respecting the appearance
                            of Christ in the order of the female. Christ, in our view, is one who is anointed. The
                            Jewish Kings were anointed with oil, frequently by a recognized prophet of God: as for
                            instance, Saul, David and Solomon, as the supreme head of the Nation. This was typical of
                            the spiritual anointing which Jesus would receive. The fullness of time having come, the law
                            as an educator having done its work and produced a man of intelligence sufficient to
                            receive, digest, and work out into his life a superior degree of enlightenment as to the
                            nature of man's separation from his Creator and the means of his return, Gal. iii. 24., the
                            man Jesus was selected to be anointed with the Divine Spirit. Under the influence of these
                            inward spiritual experiences he came to see that the cause of man's unhappiness was his
                            selfishness, and his independence. Jesus by his punctual observance of every requirement of
                            the Jewish law, and his willing subjection to his parents, he fitted himself to become the
                            recipient of deeper spiritual truths. By the humiliation of his spirit, the judgment he was
                            under, like other natural men, was taken away. Acts, viii. 33. He was, as St. Paul has
                            stated, continually in "cryings and tears" to his Creator, Heb. v. 7, that he might gain
                            understanding and be endowed with strength to carry into practice the light he received. It
                            was opened to his understanding that the restrictions of the law on the works of generation
                            were, in the kingdom of heaven on earth, to find their legitimate consummation in
                            extinction. Other matters gradually opened to his understanding, which avc have not space to
                            mention. He tenaciously held every unfoldment of the Divine mind to his understanding. He
                            did always those things which pleased his Heavenly Father. John, viii. 2!). He became
                            entirely dependent on the divine will. John, v. 30. As he proved his obedience he
                            continually received evidences of divine approval and divine support. (To be continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To an erring one" TEIform="index"/> TO AN ERRING ONE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Chandler, Olive F." TEIform="persName"/>OLIVE F. CHANDLER.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Dearest youth, why dostthou wander, Far away from friends and home; Wilt thou sever ties so
                            tender, And away in deserts roam? On the sea of life there's danger. Pause, dear pilgrim, as
                            you move ; Trust in truth, her ways are grander And she's ever near to soothe. Heed thou not
                            the Syren tempter, Let her charms ne'er touch thy heart; Nor refrains from this vile
                            songster, Cause thee from the truth to part. Virtue's charms are e'er enduring She will ever
                            cheer thee on; These, dear youth, are worth securing Gather these, while in life's morn.
                            Does the tempest round thee thicken, Threat'ning clouds their shadows cast. Every earthly
                            love seem stricken, Chilling winds, thy -hopes to blast. Turn to Jesus, he has power, He
                            will hush the troubled sea; Trust him in the darkest hour, And his love shall make thee
                            free. Harvard, Mass</p></div2><pb n="131" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Coming era" TEIform="index"/>The Coming Era</head><p TEIform="p"> WRITTEN FOB THE MANIFESTO. THE COMIKG ERA. ¦Was it a Dream? Once, worn and tired with
                            earthly toil and care, Life's petty ills so grievous seemed to bear, In resignation I sat
                            down at last To ponder on the present and the past. I sank into a happy reverie; The future
                            ope'd in vision bright on me; I dreamed the "coming era" was at hand And free'lorn reigned
                            in this our favored land. From those who long in bondage had been found, I saw the shackles
                            fall upon the ground; And those who'd ruled the earth with tyrant's power Were servants to
                            the ones they'd lorded o'er. I saw the sexes free and equal stand ; Old office-holders
                            moving at command; The nation once engaged in war and strife, Walked in the paths of sweet
                            and peaceful life. In politics, corruption could not stand! No "sal'ry grabbers"' found in
                            all the land! The caucuses and polls were free from guile ! Upon our Government the saints
                            could smile. Monopolies were wholly past—unknown; The love of pelf, and greed of gain had
                            flown; No rich, no poor, no high nor low were found, For equal rights and privileges abound.
                            I saw stern Fashion's follies cast aside, And in the rear went avarice and pride. The
                            monstrous frauds, (now practiced in our day,) Oblivion had claimed and borne away. No
                            gambling hells, no dens of vice were seen; No felon's cell, so dark—to intervene; No house
                            of alms, no rendezvous for sin, For vagrants were not found to dwell therein. All alcoholic
                            liquors were eschewed, Tobacco vile, was neither smoked nor chewed; Narcotic pois'ning too
                            was quite unknown; And quacks and medicines had also flown. Adulterations ceased in every
                            grade, And merchants dealt just honestly in trade; •I saw a table spread with simple fare,
                            No stimulating food existed there. No animals were killed by human hand, No place of
                            slaughter was, in all the land. The boys were happy found without the hook, Fishes swam in
                            freedom through the brook. No sickness or disease at all was there; For nature's laws were
                            kept with strictest care; Compuls'ry education ruled the land, Old creeds and dogmas died,
                            that truth might stand. Old ceremonies too had passed away, And Justice triumphed, right and
                            peace bore sway. The young were reared with care for moral worth, No foolish novel-reading
                            had a birth; And all that would degrade the human mind Was to the old forgotten days
                            confined. I saw in earth new beauty—gospel light Had spread throughout, consuming sin and
                            blight. The sun's effulgence o'er the landscape broke,— Proclaimed the coming era, and I
                            woke; But soon a cloud my brightened sky o'er cast, This prospect, surely, was too bright to
                            last. I fervent prayed while pond'ring on the scene : God speed like day, that will not
                            prove a dream! (To BE CONTINUED.)</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Treasures" TEIform="index"/> TREASURES.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Witham, Maria" TEIform="persName"/>MARIA WITHAM.</byline><p TEIform="p"> In this selfish, world-engrossed age, how many do we see laying up for themselves
                            treastires, where moth and rust doth not corrupt, and thieves break not through to steal?
                            The great mass of humanity are bending and toiling over heaps ot clay, or dust, glittering
                            with gold, and charming the eye, but not satisfying the heart. They toil, ever grasping more
                            and more eagerly, the implements of feverish labor. They strive with commendable industry
                            and patience, but the end over which they strive is that over which angels weep. "The things
                            which are seen, are temporal, but the things which are unseen are eternal." And in being
                            careful and troubled about many things, is it the part of wisdom to forget the better part
                            which can never be taken from us ? , A crown of life stands in infinite contrast to all
                            earthly treasures. Earth-bought honors and distinctions often bring sorrow to the possessor.
                            Earthly pleasure wreathes herself in flowers to captivate willing eyes, and unsanctified
                            learning would persuade the seeker after worldly treasures that there is no glittering crown
                            for the true Christian. Enfield, Conn.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spiritualism" TEIform="index"/> SPIRITUALISM.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescott, James S." TEIform="persName"/>JAMES S. PRESCOTT.</byline><p TEIform="p"> He who rejects modern spiritualism without investigating it, or making a discrimination
                            between the true and the false, may be likened unto a man who rejects gold and cilver coin
                            because some spurious pieces are found among them, or, like unto a man who throws away a
                            field of wheat, because he found some tares growing among the precious grain. How unwise!
                            True spiritualism is <pb n="132" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/>something to be sought after. "Seek and ye shall
                            find." And when found, it will be the "pearl of great price." A key that unlocks the
                            mysteries of the past, inspires the living present and unfolds the brightness of the future.
                            He who believes the Bible to be the infallible word of God just as it is, indorses ancient
                            spiritualism, just as it was, which was no better than modern spiritualism, just as it is,
                            and if the former was true and the Bible originated from it, so is the Eevelation of modern
                            spiritualism equally true, and infallible, and more authentic, because it has never been
                            perverted by translators, and is adapted to the day and age in which we live. North Union,
                            Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="shaker-press" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers" TEIform="index"/>The Shakers</head><p TEIform="p">[From the Bangor Messenger] <cit TEIform="cit"><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Bangor Messenger" TEIform="index"/>Bangor messenger</bibl><quote TEIform="quote">West Gloucester, Me. Jan. 1883. Editors of the Bangor Messenger;—As you are
                                    getting so many subscribers, I thought they might like to know something of the
                                    Shaker Order, and will write from the heart of the village, of this peculiar people.
                                    I am a Shaker myself, have been from childhood and know whereof I speak. Now that
                                    the valuable medicine which is here manufactured, is becoming so widely known, the
                                    public will desire to be better acquainted with our principles and manner of life.
                                    Nothing could be more pleasing to us than to have all know of the hope that is in
                                    nn, of that well-spring from which we drink, that has kept this community in gradual
                                    growth for more than one hundred years. It is favorable to any people to be liked
                                    best where they are best known. We find this to be the case with us. Shaker Village
                                    in West Gloucester is very pleasantly situated on the eastern side of a small hill,
                                    surrounded on all sides by the higher land. I can no better describe the place than
                                    in the words of an aged Shaker brother, now visiting us from the society in
                                    Cleveland, Ohio. He says: "Take a large wooden bowl and invert a smaller one inside
                                    of it, and you will get some idea of the situation." The village on the side of the
                                    smaller bowl with a beautiful lake at its base, is half a mile from the village on
                                    the east. We have a very fine view of the lake with the woodlands surrounding it at
                                    all seasons of the year; but in autumn the scenery is magnificent, abounding in many
                                    colors, with the passing clouds throwing their shadows upon them. The lake derived
                                    its name from a party of hunters, who, in the olden time, met' regularly on its
                                    shores every Sunday hence the Sabbath Day lake. Our government is a Theocracy, We
                                    find a mother as well as a father in God, and are held together by bonds of true
                                    love. Nothing else could do it. The life that Jesus lived is our example, and our
                                    order is founded upon the principles of that church that was organized at Jerusalem
                                    by his disciples. We have given up the private family life, and found in its place
                                    the great brotherhood and sisterhood which Jesus promised to those who would become
                                    his followers. All are loved and cared for. The rich and exalted come down and the
                                    poor are raised up, bringing all upon a Christian level. We have a literature in the
                                    form of a pamphlet, called "The Manifesto." By enclosing sixty cents and addressing
                                    Publisher of Manifesto, Shaker Village, Merrirnac Co., N. H., it will be sent to
                                    you, monthly, for one year. After taking it that length of time I do not doubt but
                                    that you will want it longer. Two miles north of us are the famous Poland Mineral
                                    Springs, with two large hotels accommodating many invalids, during the summer
                                    season. Just one mile south are the Centennial Springs. We are surrounded by healing
                                    waters. It has been but little more than a year since we commenced the business of
                                    manufacturing the Shaker Tamar Laxative; it is fast getting into favor, and is
                                    highly spoken of everywhere that it has been used, as the best remedy for
                                    constipation and many other diseases. You will need it in your family. It is not
                                    unpleasant to the taste, even to children. You can have a box of the lozenges sent
                                    to your address, postpaid, by sending sixty cents to William Dumont, West
                                    Gloucester, Me. Full directions are with each box, also the formula. All druggists
                                    have <pb n="133" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/>them or they can be obtained from our wholesale agents.
                                    Thus you see that as it was prophesied in days of old, the sun of righteousness has
                                    arisen upon us with healing in his wings, and there is a balm in Gilead by which the
                                    wounds of both soul and body can be healed. There is among us that Platonic love
                                    which goes out to the suffering sons and daughters of men. Have you a desire to know
                                    more of this peculiar people? "Ask and ye shall receive." Aurblia.</quote></cit></p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Letter from a venerable Shaker" TEIform="index"/>Letter from a Venerable Shaker</head><p TEIform="p">[To the Editor of the Religio-Philosophical Journal:] <cit TEIform="cit"><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Religio-philosophical journal" TEIform="index"/></bibl><quote TEIform="quote">Letter from a Venerable Shaker, My attention has been called to a message
                                    purporting to come from Ann Lee. My experience has been such that I place no
                                    confidence in the message, believing that it did not come from Mother Ann, it being
                                    so contrary to all the messages received by our people, the Shakers, from her ;
                                    contrary to her testimony while she was on the earth ; contrary to the life she
                                    lived and taught, her testimony being the same as that taught by Jesus Christ. Jesus
                                    Christ laid a foundation that all souls can build upon in safety. "When I was
                                    between nine and ten years old, 1806, I went to live with the believers of Mother
                                    Ann's doctrine. They had gathered into a community. Some had farms and other
                                    property, which they dedicated, as well as themselves, to build up one common
                                    interest, agreeable to the Apostolic order. They allowed no selfish interest to
                                    operate among them. Those who had wives lived as though they had none, living as
                                    brothers and sisters. They wTere the first founders of this society : they were
                                    noble and worked hard to build comfortable homes. They laid a foundation for a new
                                    heaven and a new earth wherein naught should dwell but righteousness and peace ;
                                    they prospered in their temporal and spiritual labors. They enjoyed the blessings
                                    which Jesus spoke of in his Sermon on the Mount :"Blessed are the pure in heart;
                                    blessed are the peacemakers," etc. Sometimes I looked abroad to see if I could
                                    discover any that lived pure Christian lives. I found that among the professed
                                    Christians some would get up revivals, make a great noise, and perhaps some good
                                    would be accomplished for a short period of time ; but I put no confidence in such
                                    revivals as affording any lasting benefit. It was not "the still small voice." Jesus
                                    said: "Straight is the gate and narrow is the way that leadeth unto life and few
                                    there be that find it;" but wide is the gate and broad is the way that leadeth unto
                                    destruction, and many are going in thereat." It eeems that there were some who came
                                    to Jesus thinking to get a pass ; they professed to have done many wonderful works,
                                    had cast out devils in the name of Jesus, but he said unto them, "I know ye not,
                                    depart from me ye workers of iniquity." No doubt they were much disappointed. What
                                    was the matter ? They had not cast out the devil in themselves. They were living in
                                    the indulgence of their own impure natures, living according to the course of the
                                    world. No doubt there are many remarkable manifestations at the present time from
                                    the Spirit-world. It is not however salvation, but it showTs that there is a power
                                    beyond man. I am an old man, in my 87th year, and am now enjoying the fruits of my
                                    past labor, both spiritual and temporal. Simon Mabee. West Pittsfield, Mass.</quote></cit></p></div2><pb n="134" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sensual" TEIform="index"/> SENSUAL.</head><p TEIform="p"> The materialistic spirit of the age appears to have made its way everywhere. People whom we
                            would least suspect are brought under its influence. The Shakers are a sect which has
                            separated itself from the world for the avowed purpose of securing the greater sanctity of
                            its members. They live in communities by themselves. They do not even live in the marriage
                            relation. The men and women dwell apart. A friend of ours, some years ago, was in the employ
                            of the Shakers. The Elder who was in charge of the establishment reproved very sharply any
                            men in his employ whom he found smoking. A while since my friend met this same Shaker,
                            puffing away at his cigar. "How is this," he exclaimed. "What does this mean? You smoking?"
                            "Yes," replied the Shaker, "I do not know anything about the other world, and so I am going
                            to get all the enjoyment out of this I can." Dr. Redfleld used to say that if any get to
                            Heaven from a city which he named, he would be like Lot going out of Sodom, a bright
                            particular star when he got there. It would seem as if the remark might be applied to this
                            age, when a leader among professed ascetics finds his consolation in such a low grade of
                            sensualism as smoking tobacco. — The Earnest Christian. We clip the above from a religious
                            magazine that the Brethren may see in what light they are at times represented before the
                            world. It is, to say the least, a sad picture. We should pity any Shaker who would
                            unblushiugly make such an admission. To be a Shaker, means to dedicate soul and body to God,
                            and in this we can do no better than to regard the advice of St. Paul, "Whether ye eat or
                            drink or whatsoever ye do, do it to the glory of God." If we should allow ourself to stand
                            on the street corners or in public places poisoning the atmosphere with the fumes of
                            tobacco, we fear we should be a little shaky in trying to make any one believe it was all
                            "for the glory of God." To turn to the smoking of a pipe, or to the chewing of tobacco, with
                            the idea of obtaining even a worldly enjoyment must be a very low estimate of human
                            happiness. For forty years the Shakers have more or less directly advised all their members
                            to abstain from the use of tobacco, in every form, and we have all reason to be thankful for
                            their successful efforts in this direction. As all of our accessions are from the ranks of
                            the world it has been found to be a difficult matter to maintain, as would be desirable,
                            such a worthy spirit of reform. The universal use of tobacco has its influence in a Shaker
                            Society, as well as in the Sunday school, or in the church or even in the pulpit. The
                            physician who uses tobacco does not hesitate to prescribe it for his patient, and an intense
                            desire for it is frequently transmitted from the parent to the child. When the temperance
                            people can reach an elevation high enough to be able to abandon the filthiness of tobacco as
                            they urge upon others to abandon that of alcohol, a new and a better day for religionists
                            will dawn upon the world.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/> H. C. Blinn.</byline></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Visit to the Shakers" TEIform="index"/>Visit to the Shakers</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pomeroy, M. M." TEIform="persName"/>M. M. Pomeroy</byline><p TEIform="p"> [From Pomekoy's Demockat.] VISIT TO THE SHAKERS. BY M. M. rOHEKOT. (Continued fkom last
                            number.) It is also a principle of the Shakers that children who are faithful and obedient
                            to their parents until they become of age are justly entitled to their equal portion of the
                            estate of their parents whether they remain with the <pb n="135" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/>society or not.
                            If an unbelieving wife separates from a believing husband, the husband must give her a just
                            and reasonable share of his property before he can become a member, and if they have
                            children who choose to go with the mother they must not be disinherited by the father on
                            that account. In their family discipline industry, temperance, frugality, kindness of speech
                            and regard for others are essential principles. So one who is able to labor can live in
                            idleness or on the labor of others. Even the Elders, Deacons and Ministers are required to
                            perform some manual work according to their abilities, when not engaged in other necessary
                            duties during the hours set apart for labor. Children taken here are kindly and lovingly
                            cared for, taught and educated, but if they are not satisfied or prove to be ungrateful,
                            quarrelsome and unfit associates with the well-disposed they are kindly sent away. As these
                            children grow up if they are not reconciled to the faith, order and method of management of
                            the society, they cannot remain as members, but are by the trustees or officers quietly
                            advised to depart. The temporal affairs of the society are committed to trustees duly
                            selected by the Elders and Ministers, and are invested with the legal fee of the estate
                            belonging to the family. All of the property of the society is in their charge, and all they
                            do in a business way is in behalf of and for the benefit of all concerned, and not for their
                            private use. But no person, no matter Avhat his position, can contract debts of any kind in
                            behalf of the society. The leading authority is invested in a Ministry, generally consisting
                            of four persons two brothers and two sisters of the society. These must deserve and then
                            they receive the general approbation of all. By the very essential principle of the
                            combination no creed can be framed to limit the growth of ideas or progress of improvement.
                            They believe in the great truth that Divine light, that is, disposition to mental growth is
                            unlimited. Thus whatever of gifts or talents each person has, it is their duty to improve to
                            the fullest possible extent. No corporal punishment is permitted. Reason is the guide and
                            conscience the judge. Better religion than this no man can have. There are classes of this
                            society. First, or Novitiate, are those who receive the faith, but choose to live in their
                            own families and manage their own temporal affairs. Any who choose can thus live and be
                            owned as brothers and sisters in the faith, so long as they honor its requirements. But in
                            such cases, and they are numerous, parents must be kind, loving and dutiful to each other,
                            shun what is evil, provide for their family and bring their children up respectably, etc.
                            They can attend worship as Believers, and if they are out of debt can make d nations to the
                            society. This is a degree of honesty never yet reached by Christian churches, so-called, as
                            they strive to obtain gifts or donations from all, no matter if what they thus receive may,
                            by right, belong to some starving creditor. That taking to a church that which, by right,
                            belongs to some one else, is robbing. Religious robbery, but still it is robbery, or
                            stealing away from one person that which belongs to another. On the day of our visit we find
                            the family of about 130 members in good health. We were shown into a neat reception room and
                            kindly welcomed. A little bit of a stove not larger than a hand valise gave out steady
                            warmth. The floor of the room was painted yellow, and was cleaner than half of the dishes at
                            ordinary restaurants. All about on the floor were little rag carpet mats under the rocking
                            chairs and for the feet. There were books in the library, attractions all about, neatness
                            everywhere and such an air of quiet and loving rest that here an angel might camp forever
                            and never be ruffled. In the corner of the room was a neat wash stand water, towels, etc.
                            The windows are so arranged that wooden blinds are lifted up so as to exclude all of light
                            and cold if need be, day and night. From the reception room, by invitation, we visited the
                            office and other rooms in this building to find the same degree of comfort, order and
                            cleanliness. Then we crossed the road andwent into the "village," enclosed by neat, well
                            kept up fences. Here we found a printing office with a few pleasant-spoken, industrious
                            girls therein at work, but with time to chat a moment. Brother Blinn and Mary Whitcher, who
                            has been with the <pb n="136" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/>society about fifty years were our cicerones. They
                            showed us the way to Brother Blinn's sanctum and curiosity shop wherein are to be found
                            hundreds of curiosities of the mineral, mechanical and other kingdoms, including
                            old-fashioned pipes, smoking tongs, warming pans, candlesticks and such odds and ends of
                            bric-a-brac relics of the past. Then we visited the large family dining room where sixty
                            persons can be seated at a time beside the long table. The vinegar cruets hang suspended
                            over the tables, while the backs of the chairs are so low that they are stood clear under
                            the tables. In the bakery we found two sisters in charge. They arise at five in the morning,
                            and have their work out of the way about noon. For four weeks they have charge herei do the
                            baking of bread, cakes, pies, etc., as wanted for the family, then go into some other
                            department while two other sisters are selected to fill their places. This work is
                            alternated, all take a hand in, and nothing becomes irksome. In the kitchen, as in other
                            rooms, is the same regularity and comparative lightness of labor. The cooking, table
                            service, domestic labor, laundry work, etc., is all thus done in order, and the newest and
                            best appliances are to be seen on every side. In the store room we saw rows of pies, cakes,
                            loaves of white bread, brown bread and goodies by the bushel. There is a place for
                            everything and everything in its place. The wood boxes are built into the walls like
                            closets, with trap doors to them close by the stoves, so that no wood, splinters or dirt is
                            seen. In the various buildings and rooms we found the sisters at their several avocations,
                            cheerful, neat, pleasant-spoken and industrious. Some were making, some were mending—-all
                            were at their industries. In the lecture room were three or four young girls from 18 to 17
                            years old, practicing singing to an organ accompaniment. They have hours for work and hours
                            for recreation, such as visiting, talking, reading, music, etc., etc. fty nine o'clock all
                            are off to bed and peace reigns supremeThe men and boys work in their shops, take care of
                            the stock, get up and get in the fire wood, do choree, help each other and grow up with the
                            family as useful members thereof. They have about forty good cows, with horses and other
                            stock, all fat, sleek, contented. There is no yelling, pounding, clubbing, whipping,
                            maltreating and swearing at horses, cattle, or other occupants of the premises. They make
                            money by the sale of produce and productions, expend it in useful articles, such as books,
                            papers, improvements of various kinds, and are well to do generally. The men dress plain and
                            comfortably like prosperous farmers but are not confined to one color of cloth. The women
                            all wear little lace caps, uniform in style, dress generally in gray, have their furs,
                            mittens, heavy wraps, etc., etc., and quite often goto Concord and other places in company
                            with some of the Elders or Trustees, to see what is going on, purchase needed articles and
                            have a day of relaxation. After a pleasant and busy visit of about three hours here, mostly
                            spent in asking questions and receiving straight-forward, direct, honest answers—after
                            seeing more and more in their religion and daily walk and conversation to admire and to take
                            in as good example, we bade our kind friends and hosts adieu, and in a little more than an
                            hour after leaving the quiet Shaker village, were again in our room at the hotel in Concord,
                            thinking and writing of what we had seen, heard and learned. Thus ends what we now have to
                            say about these excellent people.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Age" TEIform="index"/> AGE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/> MARY WHITCHER.</byline><p TEIform="p"> "We're growing old," How strange is life and fate ! We're born, we live, and soon are told
                            We must be gone, 'tis growing late. How stealthily the seasons pass; And yet how slow,
                            through toil and xjain We count the ill, the good, alas, Moves on without a thought or name.
                            Let even measure take the stand, The debt and credit of this life ;— We've nought to hold
                            and nought to hand, As over balance through the strife. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><pb n="137" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Moment's Reverie" TEIform="index"/> A MOMENT'S REVERIE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="H., H." TEIform="persName"/>H. H.</byline><p TEIform="p"> "When from active scenes turned aside, and reflection Presents to the mind shadows passed
                            down the years Of hopes and of promises, friendships worth tasted, The book of life opens,
                            mid doubting and fears. I read on its page how in foul and fair weather My outward bound
                            vessel cleared each rocky coast; How grandly, how proud, thro' rude tempest she bore With my
                            trusted Pilot e'er true to his post. [me, I read, while in sight of the shore just receding,
                            The perilous journey yet scarcely begun, That assailed, still defiant, as bold, self-reliant
                            As the undaunted eagle that soars to'ard the sun. O'er the turbulent ocean of sin, pain and
                            fretting, With Thee my Commander, my Pilot, I'll go; Where from the wretchedness of vain
                            regretting, Serene words of virtue I'll evermore know. To more glorious life a bright future
                            is dawning, And may this my voyage the prelude now be, That home from the contest I'll come
                            with rejoicing From earth's gloom and shadows forever set free. Tho' night time of darkness,
                            and doubt yet o'er take mei Unwavering trust in this Pilot of mine Shall bear my heart
                            upward and beckon me onward, Till affliction and trial my soul shall refine. Each sensuous
                            pleasure, each inward foe vanquished, My tranquilized mind new delights entertain; No
                            tortuous paths now my feet more shall tread in, Safe anchored within my good Pilot's domain.
                            Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="These fanes erected to the 'living God'' will be gradually transformed..." TEIform="index"/>
                            These fanes erected to the 'living God'' will be gradually transformed...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, E." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">[Contributed by E. Myrick.] "These fanes erected to the "living God'' will be gradually
                            transformed into temples where science will take the place of superstition ; the priests who
                            minister before the altars of the "Unknown God." will become Sages and Teachers of the
                            knowable in art, science, literature and religion. Sunday the brightest of all the week,
                            instead of being devoted to unmeaning formality and tedious hypocrisy, will become the
                            universal day of rest, leisure and Spiritual culture. And the chimes from many an ivyclad
                            church tower instead of tolling funeral knells, and peal ing forth notes of eternal doom,
                            will proclaim liberty, peace and joy throughout the land."</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Letter Box</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Children;—Pure thoughts, virtuous deeds, and a clean conscience..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Dear Children;—Pure thoughts, virtuous deeds, and a clean conscience...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Connecticut, Enfield" TEIform="index"/> Enfield, Conn.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Children;—Pure thoughts, virtuous deeds, and a clean conscience, are of priceless
                                worth. Sinful thoughts are germs of sinful habits, and if allowed to take root in your
                                minds, to spring up and grow, they will produce bitter fruits of grief and condemnation.
                                Sinful thoughts, if not erased, will tell on your future destiny. The adversary will
                                fill your minds with bad thoughts and suggestions, if you do not resist them. It is
                                often easier to receive bad guests than to expel them. Evil deeds are produced by evil
                                thoughts. Shun poisonous thoughts, as you would shun poisonous reptiles. If you
                                entertain impure thoughts, you will illustrate them in your lives. Keep evil thoughts at
                                bay. "God is not in the thoughts of the wicked." Uproot all sinful inclinations. "One
                                thought upon another, shapes every life at will; one deed upon another, tells a story,
                                good or ill." "Good thoughts are excellent company." If your thoughts are pure, your
                                lives will be spotless. Purity brings sweet refreshing thoughts—jewels and gems of
                                wisdom. You can possess the power to cherish good thoughts, and to dismiss bad ones ; to
                                encourage those that raise you up, and discard those that draw you down. It is as
                                necessary to turn from evil thoughts, as from evil books, and evil companions. Let your
                                thoughts be such as will blossom and bear good fruit. Let your thoughts be refining and
                                soul-elevating; thoughts that will find their highest use, in being wrought into lives
                                of unselfishness, truth and purity. Your Brother, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dog" TEIform="index"/> THE DOG.</head><p TEIform="p">In the barnyard there is a dog and it is a Shepherd dog. This dog will sometimes bite and
                                sometimes he will not bite. He is kept to drive the cows home from the pasture. One day
                                my Grandmother sent her dog to the store before he had his breakfast with a basket and a
                                note m his mouth. And when he reached the store the man took the paper and the basket,
                                and gave it to him ; and when the dog got out of the store he smelt meat. He let go of
                                the basket and ate the meat all up. When he reached the house, Grandmother took the
                                basket and looked in the paper and found it empty. So she went to the store and asked
                                the man if he had read the note, the man said, he had and had given the dog what was
                                called for, which proved to Grandmother that the dog had eaten the meat all up, because
                                she had sent him without his breakfast. H. Mansir.—Age, 10.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Mansir, H." TEIform="persName"/>H. Mansir</byline></div3><pb n="138" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes" TEIform="index"/>NOTES.</head><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Voice of Jesus was the voice of love..." TEIform="index"/>The voice of Jesus was the
                                voice of love...</head><p TEIform="p"> The voice of Jesus was the voice of love {'or humanity ; it was the spirit of goodness,
                                and hence, the voice of God. It prays with us and for us ; it exhorts, admonishes and
                                encourages us as none hut a divine teacher would be able to do. live that their good
                                works, their honesty, their Vindness and their brotherly love might be seen, and through
                                this others might be led to glorify God. He has warned us against the appearance of
                                saint-ship, against an affectation in religious duties and tells us that we may cry,
                                "Lord! Lord!! wonderful works have we done in thy name," and yet he will, at that same
                                time, protest,— "I never knew you." We hear the word, are interested in it it would seem
                                that the truth of and feel assured that we shall walk and Christ's word and life must be
                                thoroughwork by the spirit of the testimony. ! ly impressed upon the mind. The disJesus
                                has told us that his disciples are {ciples may even be righteous, and the tlua light of
                                the world, and we accept all | promise of receiving a righteous man's that he
                                condescends to say in regard to reward must have been very satisfactory, those whom he
                                has chosen, or to the sacred work into which they are called. tie would have them
                                spiritually minded, because that brings life and peace. He hag said to them that men who
                                do not bear the cross that he bears, or who despise the yoke that he wears, love but
                                Jesus passes beyond this in his determined effort to establish the kingdom of God. Your
                                righteousness, in whatever form it may be found, must excel that of the Scribes and
                                Pharisees ; it must be a better righteousness than is found among darkness because their
                                deeds are evil. | the children of men or you cannot enter a close fellowThis certainly
                                should be a warning to those who would be with the disciples and yet try to maintain
                                ship with the world. The testimony of Jesus was light, and Hus light is the revelation
                                of God. It reveals in all clearness the works of man, whether they be good or whether
                                they be evil. Nothing can be concealed. If is like a city that is set on a hill. If we
                                accept and maintain it, we have life ; if" we neglect it, death is inevitable. In this
                                city and among these disciples, Cod and his works only, should abound, lest we bring a
                                reproach, and evil eyes are not slow to detect what belongs exclusively to their order.
                                This was so apparent that Jesus exinto the kingdom of God. We do not wonder that he was
                                impressed to say, the way is so narrow*, but few are able to find it. It was a new way,
                                leading out from the old inheritance of selfishness, and from all the relations that
                                makes of us "one flesh." But people generally, preferred the established, old way, the
                                broad way where they could buy and sell and accumulate treasures for this world. Jesus
                                lived to see but very few who chose to pass into the kingdom through that "strait gate."
                                Generation after generation have passed away since that date and yet the same
                                life-giving testimony of Christ is held up before the world through hope that some may
                                be horted those who walked with him to so | saved. The cross does its work no less <pb n="139" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> effectually, and the light shines no less clearly in the heart of
                                every true disciple, to the condemnation of all evil.</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Br. Albert, by urgent request from several of the societies..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Br. Albert, by urgent request from several of the societies...
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">[From Elder Giles B. Avery.] Br. Albert, by urgent request from several of the societies
                                has just got out a new edition of Plain Talks. He offers them for $4.00 per 100 copies.
                                It seems, to us, that it is one of the very best pamphlets now out, for circulation of
                                our testimony, and that for the interests of that precious, glorious Cause—The
                                Institution and establishment of the kingdom of Heaven upon Earth. Every society and
                                family of Believers ought to have on hand a few hundred copies for circulation. The cost
                                is trifling, and the good that we pray may be effected, great. Address, Geo. Albert
                                Lomas, Shakers, Albany Co., N. Y.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life in the woods, no. 4" TEIform="index"/> LIFE IN THE WOODS, NO.4.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sproat, Granville T." TEIform="persName"/>GRANVILLE T. SPROAT.</byline><p TEIform="p"> The Indian no longer walks straight. He has learned to walk two ways at once, like the Pale
                            Face. He has two tongues. The one that spoke the truth stands "till. The lying tongue walks
                            very fast. It is like the hrook that runs over the stones. No one can stop its babbling. The
                            Indians were friendly and social in their habits, ^hey seemed to take the greatest interest
                            in each others welfare, and exhibited great fondness for children, whom they seldom piinish
                            by blows. It her child proved refractory, or got into a heat of passion, the mother would
                            throw cold water into his face, to cool him off. And this practice, I noticed, succeeded to
                            a charm in most cases. "My child is not a dog," said the Indian, "that I should beat him."
                            They thought, that by so doing, they would break his spirit, and unfit him for a warrior
                            Yet, as a general rule, they had the respect and obedience of their children. It was sad to
                            hear their wail on the loss of their children. The mother would go out into the woods at
                            eventide, and make all the air ring with her cries. " Oh-nin-guis! ninguis!" or "ne-dah-nis!
                            ne-dah-nis! (Oh my son! my son ! or, my daughter ! my daughter !") Sometimes they would cut.
                            themselves with sharp stones to "let out the ache," they said, "that lay so heavy on the
                            heart." I have seen some instances where they appeared to believe in the transmigration of
                            souls. The mother, if she could kill a humming bird, or a golden robin, would suspend it
                            from the image of her child, which she had made up, and strapped to its cradle-board, with
                            the same ornaments and dress that the child used to wear. She would talk to it, as if it
                            were alive, and say, "If thou hadst known how much I loved thee, lost one, thou couidst not
                            left me. Come to thy mother once more, for there is a shadow come over our home, and we miss
                            thee in our solitary wigwam. Come! Oh, come!" and she would stretch out her hands, as if
                            vainly striving to grasp the spirit of her child. They would sometimes try to stay the
                            spirit of the child, on its departure to the land of souls I recollect the old chief of
                            Leech Like, A7hose child lay dying, and a dog, belonging to the boy, laj sleeping by the
                            fire ;— just as the child's spirit departed, the old man arose, seized a tomahawk, and
                            dashed out the brains of the dog; then, with one frantic bound, threw himself upon the dead
                            body of the child, saying to the spirit, "Come again! come again! have I not sent the dog
                            after thee, to bring thee back?"—thus hoping, for a while, to stay the spirit of the child,
                            on its outward flight. Mothers trembled to think, "How will my liitle one be able to cross
                            that pole, that stretches across the river?"—And if the child had a dog, or any favorite'
                            animal, they would kill it, and lay it into the grave, that it might accompany the child on
                            its long journey, and over the dangerous river. But we will leave the Indians for a while,
                            and all that appertains to the manners and customs of their camp life, and go on with the
                            narration of our journey. (To BE CONTINUED.)</p></div2><pb n="140" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary</head><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In the year 1851 I begged Senor Ermeneta, the proprietor of some of the richest mines in Chili..." TEIform="index"/>
                                In the year 1851 I begged Senor Ermeneta, the proprietor of some of the richest mines in Chili...
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Field, Frederic" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">In the year 1851 I begged Senor Ermeneta, the proprietor of some of the
                                        richest mines in Chili, to send some specimens for the great exhibition as
                                        samples of Chilian wealth. He forwarded me two large stones, one weighing three
                                        hundred and fifty six pounds, and the other three hundred and forty nine pounds
                                        and told me that perhaps the strength of the miner who excavated these masses,
                                        and brought them from the mine, was as striking as the richness of the specimens
                                        themselves. Both stones had been taken from a depth of more than three hundred
                                        feet, and had separately been borne on the shoulders of a man, he having to
                                        ascend, not by ladders or other aid, but by climbing up the nearly perpendicular
                                        slope of the mine. The food the miner lives upon is an interesting subject to
                                        physiologists. His chief diet is the haricot bean, and without this nutritious
                                        vegetable he could never get through the work required of him. The beans are
                                        boiled until they are quite soft, and eaten with bread. Extract from a letter by
                                        Frederic Field, in Herald, of Health.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Herald of health" TEIform="index"/>Herald of Health</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hot and cold drinks" TEIform="index"/> HOI AND COLD DRINKS.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A correspondent of knowledge calls attention to some of the disadvantages of
                                        hot drinks. Cold drinks are natural to man, though most people now adays are so
                                        used to hot drinks that they do not feel satisfaction— really stimulation—unless
                                        they have them. Hot drinks are injurious to the tongue, for they deaden its
                                        sensation, and, after taking hot soup or drink, the tongue becomes quite numb
                                        and unable to taste the finer flavors of a dish. The teeth are greatly injured
                                        by them, and many dentists say caries (decay) is due to them alone. They crack
                                        the enamel and thus allow caries to set in. When caries has once set in, hot
                                        drinks are a common cause of Deuralgia. Hot drinks are specially hurtful to the
                                        stomach. They cause irritation of the nerves of the stomach and consequent mild
                                        inflammation of that organ, so that after a hot drink the stomach is red and
                                        congested; in time a debilitated condition is set up. A temperature of 100
                                        degrees Fahrenheit also destroys the active ferment of the gastric
                                        juice—pepsin—and so leads to indigestion. If the stomach is at all disordered,
                                        hot drinks give rise to much griping pain, and in many cases to vomiting. In
                                        cases of diarrhowi, too, hot drinks only increase it, while cold ones tend to
                                        lessen it. Thirst is not common in winter, unless sugary, saity or hot spiced
                                        foods have been taken. In cold weather the air contains more moisture than in
                                        hot, and in cold weather there is less perspiration. Hot drinks increase the
                                        volume of heat in the body, and if that is not required, it is quickly got rid
                                        of by the skin. Water is the best thirst-quencher, but if simple food be taken,
                                        the need of drinks will be small. Many vegetarians drink nothing from month to
                                        month, the only fluid they get being the juices of the fruits which they eat.
                                        But pleasant drinks, like tea, coffee, etc., may be taken lukewarm for a long
                                        time with little apparent damage. The least injurious is cocoa, made with plenty
                                        of milk, and allowed to stand until nearly cool. A good test is to apply the
                                        little finger to the drink, and if it be not hot to it, then it may be safely
                                        taken.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Apples for food" TEIform="index"/> APPLES FOR FOOD.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl><quote TEIform="quote">The highest medical authority asserts that cooked apples, either boiled or
                                        baked, are the bes,t food for patients in the fevered condition of small-pox,
                                        typhoid fever and erysipelas. It has been well said that "apples are general
                                        favorites." Every eye covets, every hand reaches to them. An apple is a noble
                                        fruit, and its virtues blush to be tasted. Every muse delights in it, as its
                                        mythology shows, from the garden of Hesperides to the orchards of Plato. A
                                        basket of pearmains, golden russets, or any of the choice kinds, standing in
                                        sight, shall perfume the scholar's composition as much as it refreshes his
                                        genius. Apples are now considered to contain far more brain food than any other
                                        fruit or vegetable, and to be much more nutritious than potatoes, which enter so
                                        largely into the component parts of every meal. At present, apples are
                                        principally used in the form of pud" <pb n="141" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/>dings, pies, tarts
                                        and sauces, and are also eaten raw, in which state they are more wholesome than
                                        when mingled witli butter, eggs and flour. But they are very delicious when
                                        simply baked, and served at every meal; and substituted for pickles and such
                                        condiments, they would surely be found beneficial. Sweet baked apples are a most
                                        desirable addition to the breakfast and tea-table, and far more healthful,
                                        appropriate and sustaining than half the dishes usually esteemed essential at
                                        such times. Served with milk and bread, they make the best diet that young
                                        children can partake of, and are very satisfying in their nature. Baked apples
                                        without meat, are far more substantial food than potatoes can possibly be made,
                                        and to us the delicious aroma and flavor are always most appetizing. We would
                                        rather go without our daily bread than our daily baked sweet apples. We presume
                                        there are many families who will not use a barrel of them for the table this
                                        season, but will devour at least six barrels of potatoes. Let us beg of them to
                                        equalize the two a little more, and purchase at least three barrels of apples to
                                        five of potatoes. They will find that less flour, eggs, sugar and butter will be
                                        consumed in a family when a plentiful supply of apples is stored in the cellar.
                                        Selected. </quote></cit></p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Finger-nails grow out about three times a year..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Finger-nails grow out about three times a year...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Finger-nails grow out about three times a year; they should be trimmed with
                                        scissors once a week, not so close as to leave no room for the dirt to gather,
                                        for then they do not protect the ends of the fingers, as was designed by nature;
                                        besides, it trimmed too close at the corners, there is danger of their growing
                                        into the flesh, causing inconvenience, and sometimes great pain. The collections
                                        under the ends of the nails should not be removed by anything harder than a
                                        brush or a soft piece of wood; nor should the nails be scraped with a penknife
                                        or other metalic substance, as it destroys the delicacy of their structure, and
                                        will at length give them an unnatural thickness. We are not favorably impressed
                                        as to the cleanliness of a person who keeps his nails trimmed to the quick, as
                                        it is often done to prevent dirt gathering there; whereas, if a margin were
                                        allowed, it would be an index to the cleanliness of the hands, from which the
                                        collections under the finger-nails are made. Leave a margin, then,, and the
                                        moment you observe that these collections need removal, you may know that the
                                        hands ne^d washing, when they and the nails are both cleansed together. Most
                                        persons are familiar with those troublesome bits of skin which loosen at the
                                        root of the fingernails ; it is caused by the skin adhering to the nail, which,
                                        growing outward, drags the skin along with it, stretching it until one end gives
                                        way. To prevent this, the skin should be loosened from the nail once a week, not
                                        with a knife or scissors, but with something blunt, such as the end of an ivory
                                        paper-cutter ; this is best done after soaking the fingers in warm water, then
                                        pushing the skin back gently and slowly; the white specks on the nails are made
                                        by scraping the nail with a knife at the point where it emerges from the skin.
                                        Biting off the finger-nails is an uncleanly practice, for thus the unsightly
                                        collections at the ends are kept eaten clean! Children may be broken of such a
                                        filthy habit by causing them to dip the ends of their fingers several times a
                                        day in wormwood bitters, without letting them know the object; if this is not
                                        sufficient, cause them to wear caps on each finger until the practice is
                                        disconiinued.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/>Hall's Journal of Health.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>Selected</head><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Building up character" TEIform="index"/> BUILDING UP CHARACTER.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The truest life is that which dares to stand ia the street in broad day
                                        light. The truest and holiest religion is that which shuns no selfrevelation,
                                        and never so sharply as now did the universal world demand that all that is most
                                        sacred be also most open. Spiritual seances that can be held only in the dark
                                        are distrusted. A religion that has no victories, save those of the closet and
                                        still hour is discounted. Let men bow in worship as they will behind colored
                                        lights, when they emerge from the low doors they at once pass into the presence
                                        of unsparing light. The world turns all its electric flashes up- <pb n="142" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/>on them. It would know how they live and act, how they walk and
                                        talk, and it severely discounts or utterly rejects all inner raptures that
                                        cannot be translated into honesty, integrity, courage and kindness, not only
                                        must our religion bear this day light test, not only must it submit to rude,
                                        unsympathetic measurements by people who cannot understand what is best in it,
                                        but it must demonstrate its capacity to grow not only in the church but in the
                                        street. It expects most sensitive spiritual feeliugs will take root and flourish
                                        in the crowded ways. Amid the storms of temptation it wants to see us anchor the
                                        more firmly in divine truths; and little compassion is there for a Christian who
                                        in any gale must strike his colors. To meet such tests so unrelentingly applied
                                        to Christian conduct, there must be deep, true Christian experience, and that
                                        can be secured not in the rattle of the street, not in the whirls of business,
                                        or tornadoes of temptation. Religion is indeed an action, a heavenly progress, a
                                        great sympathy with men, a vast brotherhood that sends us swiftly toward our
                                        kind, but behind these its high endeavors is the place of communion with self
                                        and with God, and for this more time is needed than is usually given. Spiritual
                                        feeling can come in the flesh. Tears can be extemporized. We can get pathetic or
                                        jubilant on the wave of an occasion. A revival or a providence may bring us
                                        these like a dash of rain, but the growth of religious character must come
                                        through the truth apprehended by the patience of the mind and that undisturbed
                                        reflection which does not come in the hurry of the day, but at its solemn
                                        evening. We live in a time when truth is thrust upon us. So we become indolent
                                        to personal search. We imagine we can take it on the wing, that enough to serve
                                        us will filter into our life without personal effort. But only the truth sought
                                        in secret becomes bread to the soul. Astronomers sailed half around the globe to
                                        make one observation of the transit of Venus. So if we seek for the truth, and
                                        in the silence of the night wait for its disclosures, it wculd be to us a wealth
                                        of experience and so a strength of character which can endure the tests of
                                        temptation and criticism.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Elmira Sunday telegram" TEIform="index"/>Elmira Sunday Telegram,.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Example" TEIform="index"/> EXAMPLE.</head><p TEIform="p">We scatter seeds with careless hand, And dream we ne'er shall see them more; But for a
                                thousand years Their fruit appears, In weeds that mar the land, Or healthful store. The
                                deeds we do, the words we say, Into still air they seem to fleet; We count them ever
                                past; In the dread of judgment they And we shall meet. I charge thee by the years gone
                                by, For the love's sake of brethren dear, Keep, then, the one true way In work and play,
                                Lest in that world their cry Of woe thou hear.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Keble, John" TEIform="persName"/>John Keble </byline></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Three words of strength" TEIform="index"/> THREE WORDS OF STRENGTH.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Schiller" TEIform="persName"/>Schiller</byline><p TEIform="p">BY SCHILLER. There are three lessons I would write— Three words as with a burning pen, In
                                tracings of eternal light, Upon the hearts of men. Have Hope. Though clouds environ now,
                                And gladness hides her face in scorn, Put thou the shadow from thy brow— No night but
                                hath its morn. Have Faith. Where'er thy bark is driven— The calm's disport, the
                                tempest's mirth— Know this—God rules the hosts of heaven, Th' inhabitants of earth. Have
                                Love. Not love alone for one, But man, as man, thy brothers call, And scatter like the
                                circling sun Thy charities on all. Thus grave these lessons on thy soul— Hope, Faith,
                                and Love—and thou shalt find Strength when life's surges rudest roll, Lijfht when thou
                                else wert blind.</p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Man of kindness to his beast is kind..." TEIform="index"/>A man of kindness to his beast
                                is kind</head><p TEIform="p"> A man of kindness to his beast is kind, But brutal actions show a brutal mind; Remember!
                                He who made thee, made the brute, Who gave thee speech and reason, formed him mute.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cowper" TEIform="persName"/>Cowper.</byline></div3><pb n="143" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Trust in God" TEIform="index"/> TRUST IN GOD.</head><p TEIform="p"> Mount Lebanon, N. Y. O'er the suntipped hills gleams a promise bright, In letters of
                                gold it is cast: It telleth of hope and trust in God, That the storm will not always
                                last. Tho' clouds may threaten, and muttering winds Defiantly sweep o'er our souls;
                                Far sweeter is the calm with peace for a robe, We may wear when the storm backward
                                rolls. </p></div3></div2><pb n="144" id="p128" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological Journal and Science of Health" TEIform="index"/>
                                PHRENOLOGICAL JOURNAL and SCIENCE OF HEALTH
                            </head><p TEIform="p">PHRENOLOGICAL JOURNAL and SCIENCE OF HEALTH, May; Contents; Adolf Eric Nordenskjold, the
                                discoverer of the North-east passage, Portrait, Our Ancestors, Vegetable Life,
                                Illustrated, How they Talked, Intellectual and Moral Culture, Language, No. 3, The Aines
                                as they are, Chains, an object lesson, Prince Gortschakoff, Portrait, Scolding accounted
                                for, Fat as a Disease, Diabetes, Its eai'ly symptoms, A Dutch Lady Doctor, Kitchen
                                Leaflets, No. 16, Notes in Science and Agriculture, Editorials, etc. etc. Published by
                                Fowler and Wells, 753 Broadway, N. Y.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/>Hall's Journal of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Hall's Journal of Health, April; Contents; Colds, Appropriate Foods, Salted Meats, Rice
                                and Beans, Constipation, Feet and Shoes, Weak Eyes, Slaves of the Cooking Stoves, Cold
                                Feet. Food Adulterations, etc. etc. E. H. Gibbs, A. M. M. D. Editor. No. 21, Eighth St.
                                N. Y. Termsjfl.OO per year.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Herald of health" TEIform="index"/>Herald of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Herald of Health, May; Contents; The Treatment of a Criminal, North Dakota's Health. The
                                Nutritive Value of Food, The Good Health Society, Women as Fruit Growers, Value of
                                Hygiene, etc. etc. M. L. Holbrook, M. D. Publisher. 13 &amp; 15 Laight St. N. Y.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Taylor, Betty" TEIform="index"/>Betty Taylor
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Betty Taylor, March 29, at Second Family Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. Age, 81 yrs. 2 mo. and 17
                                days. A good and faithful sister. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ames, Rufus" TEIform="index"/>Rufus Ames
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Rufus Ames, April 10, at Second Family, Mt. Lebanon,
                               N. Y.. Age 85 yrs. 3 mo. and 6 days. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Barrows, H. G." TEIform="index"/>Dr. H. G. Barrows
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Dr. H. G. Barrows, April 16, at Shirley, Mass.
                                Age, 66 yrs. He had been a member of the society about four months. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cojer, Amarilla" TEIform="index"/>Amarilla Cojer
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Amarilla Cojer,
                                April 12, of the Mill Family, North Union, Ohio. Age 74 yrs. 9 mo. and 17 days. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Damon, Arthur" TEIform="index"/>Arthur Damon
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Arthur
                                Damon, April 14, at Enfield, Conn. Age 88 yrs. and 6 rno. Brother Arthur was respected
                                at home and abroad and has been faithful in the Zion of our God for more than fifty
                                years. A. G.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nature is very exacting, therefore we should not grant a wish that we are unwilling should prove a demand" TEIform="index"/>
                            Nature is very exacting, therefore we should not grant a wish that we are unwilling should prove a demand
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Nature is very exacting, therefore we should not grant a wish that we are unwilling should
                            prove a demand.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/> Kind Words for the Year 1882.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hoping this may find each one well in..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Hoping this may find each one well in...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Ohio, Watervliet, December 1882" TEIform="index"/></dateline><p TEIform="p">Watervliet, Ohio, Dec. 1882. Hoping this may find each one well in the New Hampshire
                                branch of our Zion home, and with many good wishes for the success and continued
                                prosperity of our "Manifesto," I am your brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dayle, Alfred, E." TEIform="persName"/>Alfred E. Dayle.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Every number of 'The Manifesto' is an..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Every number of 'The Manifesto' is an...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Ohio, Union Village, December 1882" TEIform="index"/></dateline><p TEIform="p"> Union Village, Ohio, Dec. 1882. Every number of "The Manifesto" is an improvement upon
                                its predecessor and we are very glad of its publication. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, O. C." TEIform="persName"/>O. C. Hampton.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shall wish for the same no. of copies of..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Shall wish for the same no. of copies of...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Maine, Alfred, December 1882" TEIform="index"/> Alfred, Me. Dec. 1882.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Shall wish for the same No. of copies of "The Manifesto" as last year. We feel very
                                grateful to the Editor and Publisher for being willing to assume the burden of our
                                little monthly, and think you do credit to yourselves and to society. Your brother, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Vance, J. B." TEIform="persName"/>J. B. Vance.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enclosed find subscription price for..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Enclosed find subscription price for...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Missouri, Calhoun, December 1882" TEIform="index"/>Calhoun, Mo. Dec. 1882.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Enclosed find subscription price for "The Manifesto" to Jan. 1884. Accept thanks for the
                                faithfulness of your teachings to your readers and to the world of mankind.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bushnell, E." TEIform="persName"/>E. Bushnell.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Danger of handling domestic pets" TEIform="index"/>
                            Danger of handling domestic pets
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">DANGER OF HANDLING DOMESTIC PETS. Dr. McCall Anderson in a paper on "The
                                    Diagnosis of Diseases of the Skin," in the Medical Times and Gazette, (p. 601),
                                    traces the development of the disease known as "Favus" in human beings to mice
                                    suffering from the disease. Cats, which eat the mice, catch the disease, and
                                    communicate the same to children who handle them. The danger of allowing children to
                                    handle domestic pets which are suffering from skin disease is probably often
                                    overlooked, and deserves to be made known more widely than it is at present. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Housekeeper's friend" TEIform="index"/>Housekeeper's Friend.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Creeds, empires, systems, rot with age..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Creeds, empires, systems, rot with age...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> "Creeds, Empires. Systems, rot with age, But the great People's ever youthful! And it shall
                            write the Future's page, To our humanity more truthful! The gnarliest heart hath tender
                            chords, To waken at the name of 'Brother;' And time comes when brain-sccrpion words We shall
                            not speak to sting each other."</p></div2><!--
    <pb n="145" id="p29"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]<pb id="p30"/>
                            <pb id="p31"/>
                            <pb id="p32"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>