<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1207" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">12</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">7</biblScope><date value="18820701" TEIform="date">July 1882</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">145- 168</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="12" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="7" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--                     <pb id="p1"/>
                    <p>VOL. XII. JULY. NO. 7. SHAKER MANIFESTO. Published by the United Societies. OUR HOME AT SHAKERS, N. Y"Blessed are
                        those that hear the word of God and keep it." SHAKER VILLAGE, N. H. . 1882. </p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
--><pb n="145" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dialogue" TEIform="index"/>A DIALOGUE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescott, James S." TEIform="persName"/>JAMES S. PRESCOTT</byline><p TEIform="p">Betweeti a Shaker and a Clergyman. (Continued from last number.) C. And again, the
                            qualifications of Bishop's and Deacon's wives were given, and we know that the Apostles of
                            Jesus Christ had wives with but very few exceptions. Again, Jesus Christ the foundation of
                            all our hopes, the faithful and true witness performed his first miracle at Cana of Galilee,
                            at a marriage, at which he and his Mother attended. S. If there is a Bishop or a Deacon
                            belonging to any Orthodox church, who will come forward and say with uplifted hands, that he
                            cannot possibly avoid fornication, we will agree with Paul and say, let him have his one
                            wife, and confine him to monogamic marriage for the time being, until he can do better, for
                            this was the reason that Paul assigned as an apology for his innovation upon original
                            Christianity. Peter was the only exception among the apostles who had a wife, and he soon
                            became a celibate for the sake of following the example of his divine Lord. Marriage is
                            honorable only where it is made so, by keeping the law of marriage, in the order where it
                            belongs. In reply to your quotation from I. Timothy iv ; 1, 2. I will say, that it will
                            apply only to apostates, and apostate churches, whenever found in ancient or modern times.
                            You say, forbidding to marry was a prominent feature in the apostate church. How is this? Do
                            you not make Paul to blow hot and cold, with the same breath, and in the same chapter?—when
                            he said, "But the younger widows refuse : for ¦when they have begun to wax wanton against
                            Christ, they will marry ; Having damnation because they have cast oft their first faith."
                            See I. Timothy v: 1], 12. And then allowing the younger women to marry &amp;c. There we
                            find Paul forbidding marriage in the gentile church, and annexing a terrible
                            penalty,—"having damnation" because they had apostatized from their first faith, and what
                            was that? Evidently, it was to live lives of virgin celibacy as they did at Jerusalem.
                            Because marriage in the church, was against Christ, i. e. anti. Here we have Paul's
                            definition of marriage in the church and the beginning of the reign of Antichrist in the
                            churches, from that day to this. C In short any man who denies the propriety of the marriage
                            relation, must first have rejected the scriptures as the only sufficient rule of faith and
                            practice,| for it was <pb n="146" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 146 SHAKER MANIFESTO. the first ordinance that
                            God instituted for man, and will continue no doubt until the end. Christ has uniformly
                            sanctioned it, and those who oppose it, are anti, or against Christ, and if he }.revail they
                            must fall. But I will not dwell any longer on this part of the subject. Dear brother, your
                            declaration compels me to say, in Christian faithfulness, that judging from your language,
                            you have either fallen, into the snare of the devil, and should cry mightily to God to break
                            the snare, and liberate your soul, or else you manifest that you are in the gall of
                            bitterness and in the bonds of iniquity. S. Here we find Paul, your highest authority,
                            denying the propriety of the marriage relation in the gentile church, by refusing to take
                            young widows into that number, under sixty years of age, having damnation as a consequence
                            of marrying in the church, in that day, because it was against, i. e. antichristian and if
                            marriage was against Christ in that day, how much more must it be in the nineteenth century.
                            It is true that Paul did tolerate monogamic marriage among the polygamists of that day, to
                            avoid a greater evil, at the same time telling them "that the time is short, it remaineth,
                            that both they that have wives, be as though they had none." I. Cor. vii: 29. Why? Because
                            he had already denounced marriage in the church as being antichristian and therefore, could
                            not be a "Christian institution," much less authority for succeeding generations. Jesus
                            attended a wedding at Cana of Galilee, to show forth his glory, by performing a miracle, and
                            his disciples believed on him, and this confirmed their faith in his divine mission. But
                            this did not sanction or encourage marriage, any more than it did drunkenness, or publicans
                            and harlots, for he came to seek and save that which was lost, and he was now beginning to
                            fulfill his divine mission. (TO BE CONTINUED.)</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God's goodness overshadows all the sorrows and afflictions that beset us on our pilgrimage through time" TEIform="index"/>
                            God's goodness overshadows all the sorrows and afflictions that beset us on our pilgrimage through time
                        </head><p TEIform="p">God's goodness overshadows all the sorrows and afflictions that beset us on our pilgrimage
                            through time.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Godly life" TEIform="index"/>A GODLY LIFE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sherman, Louisa" TEIform="persName"/>LOUISA SHERMAN</byline><p TEIform="p"> "A godly life has a voice, it speaks when the tongue is silent, and is either a constant
                            attraction or a perfect reproof." An attraction to those who love purity and goodness, and a
                            reproof to those who love the ways of evil. Uprightness of life is of inestimable worth.
                            "The good alone are great;" whatever may be the qualifications of a human being, however
                            much worldly wisdom they may possess, if they lack true moral virtue, "if the truth is not
                            written in their inward parts," their whole life work will be a failure. Because we possess
                            two natures, there is necessarily a conflict between good and evil in every heart. Blessed
                            is the soul that has the strength and courage to resist evil ; who can say with the
                            authority of his own free will, I can, and will deny myself of this wrong practice, of that
                            unholy desire, of this injurious habit and that unsanctified manner. All our actions should
                            be under the direction of conscience. God's voice in the human soul. Greater are they who
                            govern their own spirits than kings or queens who ru;e empires. Let us learn to govern our
                            thoughts ; they are the springs of action "From purity of thought all pleasure springs, and
                            from an humble spirit all our peace." If the intents of the heart are right, there will be
                            corresponding good effects flow therefrom. It is very necessary that in early life, we
                            assiduously cultivate those principles, that shall lay the foundation of a godly life. Every
                            day is a golden opportunity, which the all wise Father, <pb n="147" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. 147 and loving mother have placed in our hands for the purpose of
                            self-improvement. Full time is awarded us for the cultivation and improvement of the noblest
                            faculties of our being. Let us not idly squander it; but, in this precious seed-time, let us
                            sow unto righteousness, purity and peace, that we may enjoy their immortal fruits, in that
                            glorious inheritance which awaits the faithful in the blessed land of souls. Canaan, N.
                        Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Little efforts" TEIform="index"/>LITTLE EFFORTS</head><p TEIform="p"> WRITTEN FOlt THE MANIFESTO, Little efforts are like little seeds, Which spring to flowers,
                            or grow to weeds. We can make them for good, or for ill. Just as our hearts dictate and
                            will. We can make them now, and by and by, A new star may shine in Fame's blue sky; We can
                            make them by and by, and wait A little longer at Fortune's gate. We can make them not at
                            all, and stand With our feet fast buried in deep sand. « We can make them always, and so,
                            prove Their worth by progress of which we move; But ever and aye, the efforts we make, Be
                            they for noble, or selfish sake. Will surely grow, as the little seeds, Which are certain of
                            either flowers or weeds, Into grand results which Trial perfects, Or to weed-like follies,
                            with poor effects. Ah! just as our hearts dictate and will, Are our efforts made for good or
                            ill; And who hath triumphed, hath truly learned That little by little, is triumph earned.
                            Ah! little efforts are wonderful things, God's work carried on through sufferings. God's
                            truth changing our human hearts, God's love healing their severed parts. All praise to the
                            Poet-heart who sings 'None shall despise the day of small things !" All praise to the
                            Master-heart, who makes Continuous efforts for worthy sakes. He hath learned by trial their
                            true avail, And knows not the word, or meaning of fail. Then let us make efforts, or little,
                            or great, But noble and pure, may our hearts dictate; For ever, and aye, our efforts, like
                            seeds, Will grow beautiful flowers, or worthless weeds.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prophetic conference" TEIform="index"/>THE PROPHETIC CONFERENCE</head><p TEIform="p"> (Continued fbom last numbeb.) Wars and rumors of wars, famine and pestilence, anxiety and
                            unrest everywhere, scientific men burning incense to their own vanity, appalling crimes and
                            shocking villanies loading the columns of our daily journals, infidelity garrisoned within
                            the church, the world blaspheming in its rage and pain, the virgins asleep—such is the
                            picture our Lord liitnself drew of the course of the present a.ge, "till he come." To prove
                            that the second coming of Christ must necessarily be the personal appearance of the man
                            Jesus, it was maintained that the scriptures plainly declared this; that the literal sense
                            was always to be taken, and not to be spiritualized, except when the context makes it
                            absurd; for, it was said, were it permitted to spiritualize where a literal meaning is
                            intended, almost anything might be proven from the Bible. These are some of the leading
                            ideas that engrossed the attention of that learned convention and what a state of the
                            thought and spirituality of what is styled the "orthodox" church, is revealed. They have
                            preached salvation through faith in the blood of Jesus, but of all the many millions that
                            believe, "what a little flock really follow the Good Shepherd!" They despair of converting
                            the world, therefore they look for Jesus to come again that by a mighty miracle he might
                            accomplish what they have failed to do, although the voices of 1800 years proclaim that hope
                            to be a vain and futile one. Like the Pharisees of old, looking for the Messiah as a
                            conquering King, failed to discern him in the humble Nazarene when he stood in their midst
                            denouncing sin, so these wise theologians of today, worshipping the letter of the "word of
                            God," look for Christ to <pb n="148" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 148 SHAKER MANIFESTO. come with overpowering
                            might and splendor, forgetting that it is written, "to them that look for him, he shall
                            appear the second time without sin unto salvation." Not by might nor power, but by his
                            Spirit will God redeem the world. And as the first appearing took place among the lowliest
                            of earth's children, so in the second appearing, the same Spirit who found utterance through
                            Jesus, became manifested through a poor and ignorant woman ; but through her was also
                            revealed the Man of Sin, the Mystery of Iniquity, that Wicked, which should precede tl.e
                            second comisg. It was Ann Lee that laid bare the poisonous fountain that has done its
                            corrupting work in every human heart; but through her came also deliverance from that
                            universal curse and was ministered a baptism that cleanses the sinful soul and makes it anew
                            in God. And the effect of that regenerating work upon those who enter into it in truth and
                            verity is that it makes them humble and child-like, they flee every lust of the flesh and
                            the mind, confessing their sins before God's witnesses; they live together in purity as
                            brethren and sisters, holding woman in honor—not contempt; they put their hands to work and
                            their hearts to God, sharing alike the fruits of their labor ; they discard the vanities of
                            the world and consider a pure and stainless life as the most precious gift; they live in
                            contentment with their lot and they die in serenity and peace, blessing God for his
                            goodness, for, having found salvation through obedience to the cross of Christ, they feel
                            assured of eternal life. Two pictures are placed before us. One painted by the hands of its
                            own adherents presents the condition of a worldly church ; failure is stamped upon it. Jesus
                            said, by their fruits shall ye know them. Mother Ann said, when ye see the branches grow and
                            flourish, then know ye that the root is holy. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="And what if some do not believe..." TEIform="index"/>And what if some do not believe...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W.</byline><p TEIform="p">"And what if some do not believe," Shall this make truth without effect? Or what if such do
                            not receive— To speak the truth shall we neglect?</p></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hannah Goodrich" TEIform="index"/>HANNAH GOODRICH</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>HENRY C. BLINN</byline><p TEIform="p">BY Hannah Goodrich was a daughter of Dea. Daniel Goodrich. She was born in the town of
                            Hancock, Mass. April 26, 1763. Her parents, and all of their family became members of the
                            Shaker Community, at Hancock iD 1780. Daniel Goodrich, her father, was a deacon in the
                            Baptist church, under the ministration of the Rev. Valentine Rathbone, sen. Her father
                            visited the Shakers in Albany in 1779 and reported them as being in possession of the
                            beautiful apostolic gifts. So convinced was he that they were a good and religious people
                            that he embraced their testimony and professed their faith. In June 1780 Hannah Goodrich,
                            the subject of our sketch, and her brother Daniel made a journey to the town of Watervliet,
                            N. Y. for the express purpose of making a visit to the Shakers. They arrived on Sunday
                            morning and arranged to attend the public Service. A large body of people were present, many
                            of whom would be known only as spectators. In relating the incidents of this first visit,
                            Hannah said, "We heard the elders preach, and at the same time bear a faithful testimony
                            against every form of a sinful life. Mother and her little family after being seated all
                            sung in such a solemn and heavenly manner that I felt as though I was among the heavenly
                            host. "At the time of this interview I began my acquaintance with Mother Ann and the Elders.
                            After the closing of the meeting, Mother informed us that if we desired to be followers of
                            Christ and ob- <pb n="149" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 149 tain the prize of salvation, we
                            must confess our sins to God, in the presence of his witnesses and then forsake them
                            forever. That we must take up our crosses against every propensity which caused us to commit
                            sin and by so doing we should obtain forgiveness and the favor of God. "In obedience to this
                            instruction from Mother Ann I have proved the truth ot her testimony, and in thankfulness
                            have blessed God that I was made able to receive it. The precepts which she taught were pure
                            and heavenly, full of wisdom and understanding, and in perfect conformity to the life of
                            Jesus Christ, whom she always acknowledged as her head and Lord. The exemplary life and
                            conversation of Mother Ann were truly worthy of Christian imitation." On the 11th, of May
                            1792, Hannah Goodrich, who was till this date a member of the Society of Hancock, Mass., was
                            by the authority of the Ministry of New Lebanon, N. Y. appointed to the office of the
                            Ministry over the Societies at Canterbury and Enfield, N. H. and at the same time received
                            the title of Mother. Although she was now only twenty nine years of age, she was very kindly
                            received by the people in both of the Societies, and ever after known as Mother Hannah. As
                            her calling was wholly in the spiritual order, she became an earnest worker for the general
                            prosperity of the people over whom she presided. She taught that neatness, prudence and
                            honesty should become prominent in the mind of every Christian. That as we gave our hands to
                            work, we should at the same time, give our heart to God. Mother Hannah Goodrich was gifted
                            with a loving and affectionate disposition and was always ready to assist those who were in
                            the bonds of affliction. By her kindness and parental care she won the confidence of all who
                            came to see her, and through this, commanded their love and respect. In person she was above
                            the medium height, thick set, strongly built, and well proportioned. Her complexion was
                            rather dark but fair. Her hair and eyes were black. She was highly gifted with a rich,
                            musical voice, and as a singer was able to administer, through that spirit, some of the
                            choicest of God's blessings. (To BE CONTINUED.)</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God bless the little children" TEIform="index"/>GOD BLESS THE LITTLE CHILDREN
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Barr, Lillie E." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">BY LILLIE B. BARR. God bless the little children,
                                    Wherever they may be ! Far on the silent prairie, Down by the sounding sea— Like
                                    flowers in the crowded city, Like birds in the forest free, God bless the little
                                    children, Wherever they may be ! Whether they walk in splendid homes, With
                                    satin-sandalled feet, Or wearily run barefooted Adown the busy street; Whether they
                                    kneel at eventide Beside a mother's knee, Or lonely sleep in orphan homes, Still
                                    tenderly pray we, "God bless the little children, Wherever they may be !" God bless
                                    the little children, No matter whose they are ! The peasant's child may come to be,
                                    In wit, in wealth, or war, Far, far beyond our dreaming; For poverty's no bar. God
                                    bless the little children, No matter whose they are ! <pb n="150" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 150
                                    SHAKER MANIFESTO. God bless the little children, No matter where they be ! They sit
                                    like angels on our hearths, And angels soon may be. A week bonce, or a day hence,
                                    They may be gone away ; Oh, guide them with a solemn love While yet awhile they
                                    stay. God bless the little children. For yet we do not see What good men, what great
                                    men, These little ones shall be— What preachers, and what poets, What men of noble
                                    mind; What true and lovjng women. What wives and mothers kind ! God bless the little
                                    children, For in their bauds they hold The t'ui ure of this hopeful earth, The
                                    coming age of gold ; For they must carry on our work When we in quiet sleep, And
                                    where our hands so hardly sowed, Their happy hands shall reap. So tenderly and
                                    graciously Let little children grow ; They may be linked with hosts above, Or heroc
                                    s be below ; For as they sit around our hearths, Who can their future see? So may
                                    God bless them, every one, Wherever they may be!</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Exchange" TEIform="index"/>Exchange.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fragmentary thoughts" TEIform="index"/>FRAGMENTARY THOUGHTS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName"/>ABRAHAM PERKINS</byline><p TEIform="p"> Many different classes and grades of men walk the earth. All are leaving footprints of life
                            and character, stamping creation with marks of elevation or debasement by their example and
                            influence ; thus transmitting both to present and future generations relief or burden,
                            happiness or misery. In the life of every individual, something is continually cropping out
                            which has its effect more or less upou the lives of others. Even as sunshine and rain
                            develop bud, flower and fruit, or as frost seres and dwarfs the tender vine and upon the
                            vegetab!e kingdom brings disease and death, so is the human heart acted upon, and exalted or
                            abased by human example and influence. It is said three powers rule the world : to
                            wit,—intellect, wealth and fame. Even in the church of Christ, to become successful in
                            missionary labors, each power is a necessity. Ignorance Minds and lays waste ; and says
                            Goethe, ¦•Nothing is more terrible than active ignorance." Wealth, though the love of it may
                            be the root of all evil, is mighty to revolutionize men and nations and accomplish the gr
                            atest reforms in civilization and morality. Latly without sonic of the excellence of fame,
                            suspicion and jealousy are upon the heels of progress to destroy confidence, and thus retard
                            and counteract good, effective operations. With the best use of these powers, they are
                            unavailing in the kingdom of Christ, to bring the baptism and fire of the heavens, unless
                            associated with the spirit of the Messiah and governed by the principles of the angel world.
                            Nothing short of genuine Christianity gives to man perfect control over himself. Devoid of
                            that element, self underlies action and blasts every noble, manly principle of the soul.
                            Hence, unamalgamated religion as taught by Jesus, which combines philosohpy, science and
                            reason, is the only means of resurrection to man, which can be learned or.ly as it meets his
                            understanding logically. Consequently to receive its benefits and enjoy them, we must fully
                            comprehend the nature of the work that gives them, and cheerfully sacrifice ev-ery opposing
                            principle of the heart that is at war with the element of purity as found in the life of
                            Christ. What is that life? It is simply admitting the light of truth to shine upon every act
                            performed, every word uttered and every thought conceived ; honestly living the truth as
                            revealed, heing loyal to our God, true to our fellow men and to the convictions of our own
                            souls ; bearing to the extent of our ability our own burdens, never shirking the cross,
                            evading duty, or crying to heaven for help when power lies at our feet and we can work with
                            our hands to secure it. Honesty, chastity, purity in all things constitute the Christian
                            religion ; without which, no man can see God. Enfield, N. H. </p></div2><pb n="151" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Because" TEIform="index"/>BECAUSE
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Kidder, M. A." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">BY MRS. M. A. KIDDER. Because I've failed to do a task As well as I
                                    would have it done, Shall I desist and idly shrink As life's bright sands drop one
                                    by one? No ! let me try, yet once again, Take greater pains, use greater care, The
                                    cunning hand we all may train To do our bidding everywhere ! Because my feet slip on
                                    the way, The upward way that leads to life, Shall I turn back without delay, And
                                    mingle with the sin and strife? No ! good right foot take firmer hold, And soon the
                                    left will follow thee ; Naught should discourage pilgrims bold, Not e'en the wild
                                    tempestuous sea. Because I spoke a bitter word That hurt a friend or wronged a foe,
                                    Shall I still keep my anger stirred And drink the gall as on I go ? No ! though the
                                    bitter word can ne'er Be taken back as long years roll; The wounds I may bind up
                                    while here, Before we meet at yonder goal! Because today I quite despair Of sunshine
                                    when the clouds hang low, Shall I remain cast down with care, Nor watch for the
                                    returning glow? No ! let me still with hope look up, While hands and feet their
                                    tasks obey; For well I know that all life's ills In heaven's good time will pass
                                    away.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New York weekly" TEIform="index"/>N. Y. Weekly.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers at Everett Hall" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERS AT EVERETT HALL</head><p TEIform="p"> THE Everett Hall was crowded to its doors, the occasion being the Women's Conference, at
                            which several Shakers made addresses. The meeting was opened by Mr. Nichols, the chairman of
                            the meeting, who introduced Mr. Frank Brown. This gentleman was followed by Mrs. Jennie
                            Foster, who spoke on woman's mission in Spiritualism, and was followed by ELDRESS ANTOINETTE
                            DOOLITTLE, of the Mt. Lebanon Shaker Society. The Eldress is a well preserved elderly lady,
                            the picture of rosy health and the possessor of a face that is the embodiment of good nature
                            and kindly instincts. Advancing to the platform she thanked her audience for the welcome
                            extended her, and said that if Paul could hear the utterances listened to during the evening
                            he would perhaps regret his proposition to have the women keep silence in meetings. Brother
                            Paul was a good man, and well meaning and honest in his convictions. Not inspired,
                            certainly, when he uttered much that has come down to us as his words. What he said was well
                            enough for his time, but that time is passed. We are inclined now to accept as law teachings
                            that suited an age and a condition of things far different from our own. The Shakers, she
                            stated, are in hearty sympathy with every effort made to better the condition of <pb n="152" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 152 SHAKER MANIFESTO. humanity, and watch with deep interest the removing of
                            the old hindrances that from antiquity have circumscribed the race. Old time creeds and
                            dogmas are losing their power, and wom.in it is whose hands are at work removing the
                            barriers that stand in the way of her progress. She did :;ot 'Aish to underrate the
                            theologies of the past and present, but the day of narrow creeds is nearly spent. A new day
                            is dawning, and in it woman will stand released from orthodox control and permitted to hold
                            her right place in the order of creation. We do not ask, said the speaker, for moru male
                            rulers, law makers, judges or lawyers. What is wanted is relief from the one sided power
                            that has ruled the world so long. There is less need of costly churches and tine public
                            buildings than of common sense and justice in the making and the administering of the laws.
                            When women have the power that belongs to them, there will be less war, less of
                            intemperence, and less of sensuality in the world. When this is the case, then will have
                            commenced the millennium on earth, for which we ought all to prepare to meet. She was
                            followed by Martha Anderson, a Shakeress, who closed her interesting speech with a song.
                            Mrs. Cooley, M. D., was the last speaker of the evening and her address was heard with
                            attention. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Conference,  Saturday eve. March,   1882, at Poland Hill, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Conference,
                            Saturday eve. March, 1882, at Poland Hill, Me.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Mace, Sophia" TEIform="persName"/>Sophia Mace</byline><p TEIform="p"> Conference, Saturday eve. March, 1882, at Poland Hill, Me. Introductory piece, sung.— In the
                            great day of the Lord we are living, And the great future is close at hand; New truths are
                            given! Inspiration from heaven, Truths immortal and grand. Awake thou that sleepest! Arouse
                            from your slumber, Come forth into newness of life ! Even the angels of heaven are calling
                            away, Away from sill discord and strife. Elder Nehemiah Trull then spoke as follows;— Do we
                            realize the true sentiment of what we have sung? Are we awake to the divine inspiration of
                            our songs and hymns. Does the word of God, so richly bestowed, feed our souls? Does it lead
                            us to make a greater sacrifice of our selfish life. So plain and simple is the way that the
                            way-faring man, though a fool, may not err therein. If we walk in submission to the call of
                            God, agreeably to its present revelation, we need not err therein. We must all pass through
                            the same self-denying work to insure redemption. Christ overcame the world. To become his
                            followers we also must be crucified to the world, for the lust of the flesh, the lust of the
                            eyes and the pride of life are not of the Father, but of the world. We cannot overcome the
                            world while indulging in any depraved appetite! This power is not gained in one day or one
                            year, but we grow into Christ, our living, resurrected head. Let us at the same time cherish
                            the testimony of our blessed Mother Ann, in which there can be no failure. This teaches us
                            to crucify the flesh with all its affections and lusts, and to bring every deed of darkness
                            to the light, by an honest confession befjre God, in the presence of his witnesses. What if
                            it does cost all that we have, yea; and our own life also to gain this pearl of great price,
                            our God requires the whole, soul, body and spirit. What if we suffer affliction and
                            privation, are these things not needed to bring us nearer to God? Whom the Lord loveth he
                            chasteneth, and scourgeth every son and daughter whom he receiveth. Let us endure faithfully
                            what is for us, and labor for reconciliation to God. For one, I am bound to make the
                            sacrifice the Lord does require. </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To the blessed eternity itself there is no other handle than this instant" TEIform="index"/>
                            To the blessed eternity itself there is no other handle than this instant
                        </head><p TEIform="p">To the blessed eternity itself there is no other handle than this instant.</p></div2><pb n="153" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian experience" TEIform="index"/>CHRISTIAN EXPERIENCE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webster, Ruth" TEIform="persName"/>RUTH WEBSTER</byline><p TEIform="p"> If consistency is a jewel where can it shine with brighter luster than in things pertaining
                            to our spiritual welfare? Many set out to be religious yet are so inconsistent that they
                            only bring a blot on the cause which they have espoused. Instead of digging deep and
                            building on a sure foundation they take the opposite course and many times have no
                            foundation at all, a mere castle in the air. We respect those who are sincere and consistent
                            in whatever profession they make, as it shows that they are honest hearted though they may
                            be in an error. The true followers of Christ are those who believe that his teachings and
                            example are superior to any other, hence, they have enlisted u::der his banner to follow his
                            example and practice his precepts. As he said, 'Tie that will come after me let him deny
                            himself take up his cross daily and follow me." He was called the Prince of Peace and he
                            said his followers would not fight. Were all those that named his name consistent and
                            followed after those things that make peace, there would be no occasion for warring one
                            against another. We have a warfare and we should be thoroughly equipped, by putting on the
                            whole armor ; for the lack of this, many make very little head way against the enemy of all
                            righteousness, but with this they can with zeal turn the battle to the gate. Some are
                            disgusted with the very name of Christ because there has been so much blood shed, and
                            wickedness practiced by those who profess to be followers of the meek and lowly Jesus. There
                            are many counterfeits, but who would think of rejecting the true coin on that account? Jesus
                            said, "If I go away I will not leave you comfortless, I will send the Comforter the spirit
                            of truth which the world cannot receive." Again he spoke of the Comforter as the Holy Ghost.
                            Who can comfort us like a tender Mother? I am thankful to my Heavenly Parents that uXo
                            longer an orphan I roam, I have found a true Mother and she's gathered me home." Union
                            'Village, Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Not where to lay his head" TEIform="index"/>NOT WHERE TO LAY HIS HEAD</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>MARY WHITCHER</byline><p TEIform="p"> Who understands the meaning Of what the Savior said? Left without friends, and seeming "Not
                            where to lay his head." Was this the earth condition? Or did his soul repine Eor some
                            new-born relation, Akin to the Divine? We trust he had a father And mother, as we have; Was
                            near to sister, brother, Who held him in their love. But here we see the lesson,-— We must
                            be "born again," To find a new relation To God, through Christ the Lamb. Old things of
                            earth's begetting Must die and pass away ; While in the New Creation New light illumes the
                            day. And here with Christ the Savior We ask; who are our kin? 'Tis those who love the
                            Father, And give their life to Him. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="All sects are different because they come from men ; morality is everywhere the same because it comes from God" TEIform="index"/>
                            All sects are different because they come from men ; morality is everywhere the same because it comes from God
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Voltaire" TEIform="persName"/>Voltaire</byline><p TEIform="p">All sects are different because they come from men ; morality is everywhere the same because
                            it comes from God.— .</p></div2><pb n="154" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Influence" TEIform="index"/>INFLUENCE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Byrdsall, Charlotte" TEIform="persName"/>CHARLOTTE BYRDSALL</byline><p TEIform="p"> Our life begins in the senses ; from material things, the growth is upward, and onward, to
                            reason, intelligence, and spirituality. On the natural plane of existence, seeking and
                            striving after shadows, or influences, comprise a portion of human history ; what we may be,
                            and attain, is ever before us, corresponding with the flowing thought in the varied grades
                            of existence. The Laws of Life require trueness to one's self, right exertion of spirit and
                            power to do. "The kingdom of heaven suifereth violence ; and the violent take it by force."
                            This kingdom is in germ life in all : the soul is an atom of the Universe of righteousness ;
                            the body is the material casket, to preserve it from the tumult and oppression of natural
                            tempest and storm. As we regulate, and rerine this, from errors that contract like worms
                            that gnaw, and undermine, so we cast upon our spiritual beings, upright and clear shadows of
                            truth. Right living becomes right thinking; and others share the love and respect which we
                            have molded to ourselves, through the silent, but wielding power of influence. We cannot
                            cause oblivion of thought nor feeling ; whatever we esteem within reflects outwardly, though
                            sometimes the channel of conveyance may be imperfect ; yet through all the dim perfections,
                            shadows, and blanks, the internal aim will eventually be apparent. Life is a circle "round
                            by round the starry way, and golden summit's won." Many times, we would pause in diffusing
                            ideas, or shadows of such, if we clearly perceived the intimate connection between mind and
                            mind ; the web-like threads, that unite soul to soul, which are strengthened or weakened, by
                            the reflection of a thought, or motive, causing a momentary cessation of forces in the
                            kingdom of bodily and spiritual righteousness ; what we impart and receive, constitute our
                            existence. Throughout creation, all animate objects bear relation one with another, through
                            influence, corresponding with that between human beings. This law is for the progress of
                            goodness, tending to develop the better nature, and elevate to higher and higher
                            aspirations. For heart to heart within life's circling bounds, Must share the aWthat with
                            each one abounds. Beautiful the institution of communism, the blending of God-given and
                            sustaining influences ! Through the rolling ages of spiritual acclivities and declensions,
                            shadows, or influences, were God's emblems of Hope and immortality ; these have been, and
                            are often purblindly received and appropriated, like unto those sometimes cast from the
                            human heart. We see too much through a glass darkly, and not cause to cause. Under the
                            boundless influence of Godly love, the free outpouring of inspirational life and power,
                            naught but righteous influences should be shed. Where right is power, and truth is love, we
                            may gather, and scatter, the roses of peace, and flowers of virtue, through holy influences.
                            Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God's will is so high above humanity..." TEIform="index"/>God's will is so high above humanity...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Browning, E. B." TEIform="persName"/>E. B. Browning</byline><p TEIform="p">God's will is so high above humanity, that its goodness and perfectness cannot be scanned at
                            a glance, and would be very terrible if it were not for His manifested love, manifested in
                            Jesus Christ. Only that holds our hearts together when He shatters the world.</p></div2><pb n="155" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prayerfulness" TEIform="index"/>PRAYERFULNESS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Danforth, Nancy G." TEIform="persName"/>NANCY G. DANFORTH</byline><p TEIform="p">In considering this subject, we cannot better express our thoughts than by it few quotations.
                            ''He continued all night in prayer to God." Luke vi. 12. "We speak of this or that Christian
                            as a man of prayer. Jesus was emphatically so. The spirit was 'poured upon Him without
                            measure,' yet.—He prayed ! lie was incarnate wisdom 'needing not that any should teach Him,'
                            yet, He prayed! How deeply sacred the prayerful memories which hover around the solitude of
                            Olivet, and the shore of Tiberias ! 'He seemed often to turn night into day to redeem
                            moments for prayer, rather than lose the blessed privilege. We are rarely indeed, admitted
                            into the solemnities of his inner life. The vail of night is generally between us and the
                            Great High priest, when He entered the -holiest of all,' but we have enough to reveal the
                            depth and fervor, the tenderness and confidingness of this intercommunion with his heavenly
                            Father,—'He wakeneth morning by morning ; He wakeneth mine ear to hear as the learned.'
                            Beautiful description! A praying Redeemer wakening as at early dawn, the ear of his Father,
                            to get fresh supplies for the duties and trials of the day: All his public acts were
                            consecrated by prayer,—his baptism, his transfiguration, his miracles, his agony and his
                            death. 'How sweet to think in holding communion- with God—Jesus drank of this very brook !
                            'Do we complain of languid spirits, of fitful affections, or luke-warm love? May avc not
                            trace much of what we deplore, to an un frequented chamber? The treasures are locked up from
                            us, because we leave the key to rust, the hands hang down, because they have ceased to be
                            lifted up in prayer. 'Without prayer ; It is the pilgrim without a staff—the seaman without
                            a compass—the soldier going unarmed and unharnessed to the battle. Beware of encouraging
                            what indisposes to prayer, going to the audience chamber with soiled garments, the din of
                            the world following us, its distracting thoughts hovering unbidden over our spirits. Can we
                            wonder that the living waters refuse to flow through obstructed channels or the heavenly
                            light to pierce murky vapors—make every event in life a reason for fresh going to Him : If
                            bowed down with anticipated trial fearing to enter the cloud, remember Christ's preparation
                            ; 'Sit ye here while I go and pray yonder!' Let prayer consecrate every thing, our
                            time,'talents, joys, sorrows, losses and our crosses." Therefore let us pray believing Him
                            who hath said, "Ask what ye will in my name, and it shall be given you." We must ask
                            according to his spirit, agreeably to the faith which he has bestowed upon us ; not doubting
                            the power and gift of God. Then may we trustingly expect to be heard and answered.
                            Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Foods and how to use them" TEIform="index"/>FOODS AND HOW TO USE THEM</head><p TEIform="p">Wholesome, nutritious foods, those that supply the system most readily with what is required
                            to give it vigor and endurance, are those foods that are cheapest and most generally
                            distributed over the earth. These are <pb n="156" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 156 SHAKER MANIFESTO. the
                            cereals and other direct products of vegetation. There is as much nutriment in cne pound of
                            beans, wheat or rice, as there is in three pounds of beef, mutton or poultry. There is not a
                            sturdier race of people in the world than the Chilians, nor a race capable of greater
                            phmical endurance. This fact has been again demonstrated in their war with Peru and Bolivia;
                            a war waged against vastly superior numbers and possessing far greater wealth; yet the
                            Chilians conquered them in their own homes, and still hold and govern these countries. The
                            food of that class from which soldiers are made consists almost exclusively of beans and
                            wheat. These are abundant and cheap in Chili, while animal food is comparatively dear and
                            beyond the reach of the common people, who are miserably poor. In the cities and villages of
                            Chili, instead of the peanut stands that obstruct the streets of American towns, you see
                            tubs filled with boiled wheat in water, which is served at one cent for a pint bowlful, and
                            a spoon is furnished to eat it with. Bean soup or beans boiled or baked cost no more, and
                            one cent is the regular«price for two large bread rolls. Three cents there will buy an
                            abundant meal of most wholesome and nutritious food. This seems a very low price ; and many
                            persons will be snrprised to learn that these are about the average prices for such foods in
                            this country. Nearly half the people in the world live almost exclusively on rice. I do not
                            profess to be a vegetarian. I do not believe that it would be entirely safe for a person
                            accustomed all his life to animal food to change his diet at once. Such changes have fre.
                            quently been followed by serious organic diseases, usually of the kidneys. The Chilians,
                            like many other people and tribes, have for ages been accustomed to an almost exclusively
                            vegetable diet, and they are robust and strong. Were the present generation to change to a
                            mixed diet, largely composed of animal food, there can be but little doubt they would suffer
                            by the change, just as the people of this country would suffer by changing to an exclusively
                            vegetable diet. There can be no doubt, however, that a medium course would be most
                            desirable, both in respect to health and economy. The amount of meat consumed, in this land
                            of abundance, is out of all proportion to the consumption of other foods. If people were to
                            inform themselves better in regard to the properties of various foods, and live up to the
                            knowledge acquired, there would be fewer cases of dyspepsia and' kindred diseases. A larger
                            consumption of acid fruits should be encouraged. Among animals there are those that are
                            exclusively carniverous, as the dog and cat; and those that are exclusively herbiverous as
                            the horse. Nature has provided the former with "canine" teeth with which to tear off and
                            divide flesh so that it may be swallowed; but they have no teeth with which to grind their
                            food; flesh then is their natural food. Horses have "incisors" to cut off the grass, and
                            "grinders" with which to masticate grasses and grains. Marl is provided with the three kinds
                            of teeth, "incisors," "canine teeth" and "grinding teeth." Nature then plainly indicates
                            that we should live on a variety of foods.—Hall's Journal of Health.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mission of the manifesto" TEIform="index"/>MISSION OF THE MANIFESTO</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>GILES B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p"> Go forth to the nations and tell the glad story, The Kingdom of Heaven is now brought to
                            earth; Lo, Christ hath appear'd and doth now sit in "Glory," Proclaiming to nations, a
                            heavenly birth. Declare to truth seekers the " Word" that is Power, Whose precepts were
                            utter'd by Zion's true King. Proclaim to the sin sick a heavenly dower To souls who their
                            off'rings to Mount Zion bring. Go, bearing a light to all souls now in darkness, And help
                            them to enter Christ's straight narrow way; Point out to their vision the heavenly largess
                            Of "beauty for ashes," for darkness, New Day. An argosy heav'nly on time's ruffled, ocean, A
                            Captain, and Pilots who know well the coast, And will clear for the harbor that's free from
                            commotion, That pirates may plan, or that Neptune may boast. Go, send forth the reapers, the
                            tares pull and burn them With coals off [he altar of Heaven's pure Shrine, Then harvest the
                            souls that are ripe and return them To garners secure in the mansions Divine. A "Harvest"
                            proclaim to all kindreds and nations Of sheaves that are ripe for the Kingdom of God; To a
                            Heavenly Garner,—a port of salvation, A peace from the strife, and a rest from the plod. <pb n="157" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 157 Of souls who are journeying sin's dreary
                            pathway, And weary with wand'rings in gloom and despair, Or, doubting God's goodness mid
                            pilgrim's sad"halfway " And buffeted yet with the "Prince of the Air." Go, bearing a balm to
                            all souls who lie wounded In strifes with temptations, where passions betray, (io, tell them
                            the trump of the healer is sounded, And healing is cenain to all who obey! The Old and the
                            New dispensations from Heaven Of God's love and mercy to erring lost: man, Portray with
                            precision, and dispense their leaven, And show how the Christ wrought through good Mother
                            Ann. To burst the strong bands of a gross carnal nature And ransom the soul from the world's
                            sordid claim. From man made false creeds be an emancipator And publish the truth that in
                            Mount Zion reigns. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="science" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Carniverous parrots" TEIform="index"/>CARNIVEROUS PARROTS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, Frederic W." TEIform="persName"/>FREDERIC W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p"> New Zealand is credited with 33,000,000 Sheep. Thousands are slaughtered for market, and the
                            Australian and New Zealand Wools are a staple commodity in the markets of the world. The
                            Scientific American says that a species of bird called the Kea, or Mountain Parrot, which,
                            in the days and under the rule of the Moari, were an innocent bird, have, by seeing so many
                            sheep prepared for the tables of the English Christians, that were left hanging in the open
                            meat sheds as they were called,p learned first to pick up scraps, finally became
                            carniverous, until now, they attack live sheep and destroy hundreds of them. They select the
                            fat sheep and pick them all in one particular spot over the kidneys where the fat of the
                            sheep principally lies. It is stated that from 3, to 5 per cent of the immense flocks are
                            destroyed by this Mountain Parrot. That the natural habits of a wild bird could be thus
                            changed, is among the wonders of animal life. Out of one nock of twenty sheep, nineteen were
                            killed. In another of 300, only 105 remained. The writer continues, "These repulsive flesh
                            devouring propensities may have been acquired by the bird in a severe winter, being forced
                            to visit the stations in search of food, and by feeding on what it found, a carniverous
                            appetite was formed of such strength that its former frugivorous tastes are entirely
                            destroyed, and flesh now forms its sole food." If this change of habit was confined to a few
                            individuals of a specie in a domestic state, we might assign, as cause for it, some
                            accidental digression. But, that a whole species, in their wild condition, should undergo an
                            apparent constitutional change, is simply wonderful. And that it should occur in the animal
                            which approaches nearest to man in the Gift of speech, only adds to our surprise. It leaves
                            the impression that man has, or may, corrupt the whole Creation and cause them to groan
                            together, that he, himself, was, not what he now is. In descending, he has the power of
                            dragging down other kinds of animals as well as his own kind. It solves the problem of the
                            fail of man. If Parrots can fall, why may not man have fallen? Now, he is carniverous.
                            Originally, like parrots, he was frugivorous. War has resulted from his flesh eating
                            propensities. He may change and again become frugivorous and live in peace with all animated
                            nature, neither harming nor hurting things cognizant of suffering. But for the poor Mountain
                            Parrot, whom he has perverted, there is evidently no hope but in the extinction of the
                            species of birds thus added to the list of carniverous, or consign them over to Darwin as
                            manifold witness of constitutional development of retrogression, back to a primitive and
                            more barbarous ancestry that existed before the earth produced the grains and fruits af a
                            New Zealand climate. If the Parrot may eat flesh, like the Vulture, why not the Lion learn
                            to eat grass like the Ox, in the coming days, when he that slayeth an Ox shall be as he that
                            killeth a man, and as the days of a tree, like the Washingtonian, so shall the days of God's
                            People be a farinaceous, fruit eating, long lived People, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="There is no man so friendless but that he can find a friend sincere enough to tell him disagreeable truths" TEIform="index"/>
                            There is no man so friendless but that he can find a friend sincere enough to tell him disagreeable truths
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lytton, Bulwer" TEIform="persName"/>Bulwer Lytton</byline><p TEIform="p">There is no man so friendless but that he can find a friend sincere enough to tell him
                            disagreeable truths.—</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Many actions, like the Rhone, have two sources—one pure, the other impure" TEIform="index"/>
                            Many actions, like the Rhone, have two sources—one pure, the other impure
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hare, J. C." TEIform="persName"/>J. C. Hare</byline><p TEIform="p">Many actions, like the Rhone, have two sources—one pure, the other impure.—</p></div2><pb n="158" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker manifesto" TEIform="index"/>SHAKER MANIFESTO</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">JULY, 1H83. Office of Publication. The "Shaker Manifesto" is published at Shaker Village,
                            Mer. Co., N. H. All business matters connected with the financial department of the paper
                            will be directed to the Publisher of Manifesto, Shaker Village, N. H. All other
                            communications may be ad" dressed, Editor of Manifesto, . Shaker Village, N. H. One Copy
                            per. year, Postage paid, .00 six months, " " .35 Enclose a two cent stamp for a specimen
                            copy. To avoid mistakes, those who send money, should write the name of their Post Office,
                            County and State. TO One inch, one insertion " " three " " " six " " " twelve " " column
                            ---- $ 1.00 each .75 " .f&gt;5 " .50 ------ (5.00 Larger spaces, rates in same
                            proportion.</p></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes" TEIform="index"/>NOTES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">It is very pleasant for us that the mission of "good news" still continues to cheer us, and
                            that a little light is occasionally permitted to shine for the comfort of those who are on
                            their pilgrimage from earth to heaven. That touching appeal for aid from on high,—"Watching
                            and Waiting" has entered the heart of our good Brother, Watson Andrews, of North Union,
                            Ohio, and he has, with others of his order proposed to send one dollar each month for twenty
                            copies of the Manifesto, which are to be distributed gratuitously. This certainly looks like
                            the vitality of a living faith. -It is giving to the poor of this world, which is godlv
                            service, whether they are poor in spiritual gifts or in bank bills. Our faith is far better
                            illustrated by our works -in assisting others to know of the troth, than by a multitide of
                            protestations of goodness or sanctity. We would like to have every family interest
                            themselves ill this subject aud see if it is cot possible, and more than this, if it is not
                            our godly duty as children of the Light to publish our Community life more extensively, and
                            send it into the world as free as the "waters of salvation." Take no thought of your life,
                            what ye shall eat, so say the scriptures, and the good, Christian city of Boston are giving
                            the passage a very liberal interpretation. An article in the Journal informs us that one
                            dealer in that city sells not less than 1/&gt;0,000 frogs a year for food. Men are
                            employed to go through the states of Massachusetts, Maine and New Hampshire, catching frogs
                            for the market. Those who believe that what a man eats, acts largely upon his soul life, may
                            expect hereafter to find the list of leapers and croakers wonderfully increased. A few years
                            since one of our medical Journals advocated the eating of horse flesh, and recommended horse
                            beef to be as good for the table as ox beef. We sWltiot dispute the point. In all
                            probability we may soon expect to hear this appetizing invitation,—Allow me to help you to a
                            small piece of horse beef or to a piece of bull frog ? While we may not have any
                            conscientious samples against eating the meat of i\.UVEItTISEK.S. <pb n="159" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/>
                            SHAKER MANIFESTO. 159 horses and frogs, we are free to say— we don't hanker after it.
                            Shirley Mass. From the annual Report of the School Committee of the town of Shirley for the
                            year 1881, we obtain the following; "On the good judgment and sustaining power of parents,
                            rests the chief responsibility of any school. In proof of this we point to the Shakers.
                            Nothing is ever wrong there. More progress is made in six months attendance there, than in a
                            year in any other school in town, by pupils of like grade. Why? All work to one end,—the
                            Elders of both sexes as well as the teachers ; attendance is good; of truancy, there is none
                            ; grumblers are not there ; the teacher is one of the Community ; no attempt is made to
                            develop new physiological facts? or to curtail the creative laws of nature. Here is seen
                            what a Community, what united effort, can do." The school was taught by Jennie L. •Jencks.
                            Number of pupils, 14. Average attendance, 9. Wages of teacher, per month, $16,66. Length of
                            school, in weeks, 12. On our recent visit to the school in Shirley, we were much interested
                            in the recitations, of the pupils, as well as in their general order and mannerly
                            deportment. The school room was well lighted, and amply furnished with everything that the
                            pupils needed for their advancement. The Society at this place has no building kept
                            expressly for a school house, but for many years have held the school session in one of the
                            rooms of their brick dwelling. Those who send communications to the Manifesto should always
                            write their whole name, and place of residence. If the article is to be published, the name
                            of the individual can be withheld if the writer requests it.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Clifford, Onto. Apr. 1882" TEIform="index"/>Clifford, Onto. Apr. 1882</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W." TEIform="persName"/>W.</byline><p TEIform="p"> [The following Correspondence was selected from some, letters written to Elder John
                                Whiteley, of Shirley Mass, by one of his friends in England.] Clifford, Onto. Apr. 1882
                                My Dear Friend :—I have been writing letters all day to go by this week's steamer for my
                                friends in England, and as I have had much to say about the Shakers, I send you one for
                                perusal. I have thought it might interest you to know my thoughts of the Shakers as I
                                representthem to my friends. I have not forgotten my promise of a letter to you, but
                                after about nine hours writing I feel disposed to subscribe myself briefly— Yours truly,
                            </p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Extract from a letter to H.—Southpobt, England, by W." TEIform="index"/>Extract from a
                                letter to H.—Southpobt, England, by W.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W." TEIform="persName"/>W.</byline><p TEIform="p"> [Extract from a letter to H.—Southpobt, England, by W.] "You seem s-urprised that I have
                                gone to the States, although it was my intention from the first to go there, but I did
                                not think that I should have something like a three month's trip through that
                                interesting eountry—one month of this time I spent very profitably and very agreeably
                                amongst that peculiar people, the. Shakers. I was favorably circumstanced for doing
                                this, having met with an old friend from Huddersfield who has been amongst them over
                                thirty years, and who holds an influential position amongst them. In their religion,
                                worship and organization they are strikingly singular, but the more you become
                                acquainted with them, and come to understand them, the better you like them. They lead
                                celibate lives, the sexes associating together as brothers and sisters of one family,
                                and for purposes of discipline and regularity they are divided into separate families so
                                that in one settlement, there may be some three, four or five families, each having
                                their own affairs in their own hands subject to a general governing power. They are
                                liberal in their views, strict in their conduct and discipline, and honest in all they
                                do. <pb n="160" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 160 SHAKER MANIFESTO. Their homes are the abode of comfort,
                                social happiness and plenty, and their lives are virtuous and self-denying. Industrious
                                and frugal they are quite well off, and living in Community with all their property in
                                common, there is none of that struggling and anxiety for existence that we see in the
                                outward world. All work that are able but not excessively, and they have plenty of time
                                for reading and the cultivation of their intellectual and spiritual natures. Their homes
                                are a Paradise of cleanness surrounded with fields and woods, and orchards and gardens
                                to the extent of thousands of acres. They have sheep and cattle, horses and poultry,
                                fruits and barns and store houses in abundance, and their settlements are located in
                                some of the most beautiful spots in America. There are seventeen of these settlements in
                                the States, and although they number at the present time less than 3,000 members some
                                idea of their possessions may be formed when I tell you that they own over 100,000 acres
                                of land. A large portion of this is devoted to growing timber and more or less
                                mountainous and barren land, but they have hundreds of acres of excellent Peaches,
                                Plums, Cherries, Apples, Pears, Strawberries, Currants and other fruits, with flowers
                                and vegetables that would more than supply Covert Garden Market. Besides this they carry
                                on certain trades such as broom making, chair making,—preserving and drying fruits,
                                growing and preparing herbs with some special preparations of medicines all of which
                                they sell. Their greatest need is an increase of active young men, piously disposed,
                                such as the Young Men's Christian Association in England could supply, and they are
                                prepared to offer good homes, with agreeable occupations to 5,000 of such without money
                                and without price, provided they are prepared to lead useful and pious lives. There is
                                no real difficulty in joining them. The only difficulty is in living useful and godly
                                lives as they do, in self-denying duties and in the cultivation of the Christ life. I
                                can tell you this a young man or a young woman might do much worse than to join the
                                Shakers."</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Moldgreen, Huddersfield, Apr. 1882" TEIform="index"/>Moldgreen, Huddersfield, Apr. 1882</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="S." TEIform="persName"/>S.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Moldgreen, Huddersfield, Apr. 1882 To my dear Friend W.;—I beg to thank you and Mr. W.
                                for your kindness in sending me the papers and also the Shaker Literature, which I have
                                carefully read, but do not yet fully comprehend; so that I shall probably go over them
                                again in order to fully understand the Shaker System. I think you are fortunate in
                                meeting with Br. W. who will give you some interesting information and also renew old
                                acquaintanceship. My mind has very vividly gone back forty years and recalled the happy
                                hours we spent together as teachers in the Sabbath School, and prayer leaders at the
                                Cottage houses. I confess I do not fully comprehend the Shaker System, but I presume
                                that they mainly hold the same faith in Jesus as we do, but they differ in their mode of
                                worship and discipline or government. I send you a paper along with this letter, and I
                                wish you to give my very kind thanks to my friend W. and say that if ever it should be
                                my happiness to cross the Atlantic I should esteem it a pleasure to call at Shirley and
                                see him, as whatever peculiarities attach to Shakerism, all agree that they are
                                extremely hospitable, and if he should ever again visit the land of his birth and the
                                scenes of his youth, I should be glad to entertain him at my house during his stay here.
                                Accept my very kind regards.—S.</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Clifford, Onto. May, 1882" TEIform="index"/>Clifford, Onto. May, 1882</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W." TEIform="persName"/>W.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Clifford, Onto. May, 1882 My Dear Friend ;—You wish me to give my impressions of Mt.
                                Lebanon * * * * * It more than confirmed my previously surprised impressions of your
                                organization. Nothing but a religious fervor of the most intense character could have
                                accomplished what has been accomplished by Ann Lee and her followers. Whether the
                                altered circumstances of the world, will still favor a further development on the same
                                lines of demarcation, may I think be doubted, but under any circumstance there are the
                                facts of what has already been accomplished. The teachings, the organization, the wealth
                                and acquired prosperity of your church must in the long run have an important influence
                                upon the world, but in what peculiar direction I am not prepared to say. Elder E. thinks
                                the time has come when you should make yourselves better known in England, than you have
                                hith- <pb n="161" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 161 erto done, and perhaps this may be
                                the next development. Nothing now exists in the laws of the old Country to prevent this
                                being done and, without let or hindrance, you may then propagate your doctrines and
                                establish your Communities as freely as you do in America, and thus return to the
                                country the enlightenment from which you first received it. To send out your
                                missionaries and retain your head quarters in the States would be, simply to act upon
                                the lines of other churches and might possibly lead to an important increase of your
                                members. Under the care of a German, at L. I saw some 500 or COO sheep with three or
                                four hundred lambs, and this shepherd had been thus employed for many years, although
                                not a member of your order. The same thing might be done at Shirley. Instead of fifty
                                sheep, why not have five hundred and all these of good and profitable breeds? * * * By
                                the end of this month 1 hope to go to Thunder Bay to see G. and then it will be time to
                                think of returning home. I have little news. My health is about the same. With kind
                                regards to all the friends at Shirley and fully reciprocating all good wishes, Believe
                                me yours very truly,— </p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Written for the manifesto" TEIform="index"/>WRITTEN FOR THE MANIFESTO</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bailey, B. F." TEIform="persName"/>B. F. BAILEY</byline><p TEIform="p">Lines written, on seeing a tearful little girl, pushed from the walk in a crowded street.
                            There, my little girl, don't cry, 'Twas but the hand of unthinking rudeness ; Beneath the
                            garb of thoughtlessness, doth lie Much good, in crudeness. You'll find in passing, all
                            through life, Much to embitter; This world is full of ceaseless strife, And show, and
                            glitter. There's a hand, to guide thy little feet, On it rely, Once more, the rough and
                            crowded street; Don't fear to try. Your little heart will often feel The cruel blow, And
                            grief will cause thee to unseal The fountain's flow. For, 'tis by suffering cruel wrong We
                            learn to feel, For other's sorrows, and grow strong; And true as steel. So, cheer up my
                            child, and meet the crowd With eyes more bright, "There's a silver lining to every cloud,"
                            To cheer thy sight.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prentiss, Laura" TEIform="index"/>Laura Prentiss</head><p TEIform="p">, at Watervliet, N. Y. May 7. Age 72 years, 8 mo. and 2 days. A very worthy sister,
                                    and an intelligent and able member of the society.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kendall, Susan" TEIform="index"/>Susan Kendall</head><p TEIform="p">, at Harvard Mass. May 9. Age, 75 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reynolds, Ann Maria" TEIform="index"/>Ann Maria Reynolds</head><p TEIform="p">, at Watervliet, N. Y. May 11). Age 75 years, 11 mo. and 20 days.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dow, Lovey" TEIform="index"/>Lovey Dow</head><p TEIform="p">, at Canterbury, N. H.; May, 30. Age, 79 years, 5 mo. and 21 days.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miner, Charles" TEIform="index"/>Charles Miner
                                </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> Charles Miner, a well known member of the North Family Shakers, Enfield,
                                            N. H. committed suicide sometime during Monday night, on May 1st., by
                                            shooting himself through the head with a small rifle, in his room, at Shaker
                                            Village. He was about 62 years of age. This Spring he had charge of the
                                            sugar camp and to the many who visited him there, seemed to be social and
                                            happy, but at other times he has shown signs of being a little "out" Lately
                                            he has talked of leaving the Shakers, and only the P.M. before he shot
                                            himself, he was over in the village at North Enfield, endeavoring to Obtain
                                            employment. His dead body was discovered in his room, on Tuesday morning,
                                            the rifle by his side. No one heard the report. Dr. Manahan and selectman
                                            Spencer, were called but did not consider it necessary to order an inquest.
                                            We understand he has a brother living in Haverhill, N. H. but no relatives
                                            about here.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Granite State, Free press" TEIform="index"/>Granite State, Free Press.</bibl></cit></p></div4></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editor, Manifesto;" TEIform="index"/>Editor, Manifesto;</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wetherell, J. K." TEIform="persName"/>J. K. Wetherell</byline><p TEIform="p">Editor, Manifesto;—The Berkshire hills claim the palm for longevity. Since the first of
                                Jan. 1800, (our records not being complete earlier than the beginning of the present
                                century,) there has been two hundred and fifty eight deaths in our Village. DEATHS. <pb n="162" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 162 SHAKER MANIFESTO. One hundred and eighteen males, and one
                                hundred and forty females. One hundred and forty eight (mere than one half) were over
                                seventy years of age, seventy two were over eighty, and twenty were between ninety and
                                ninety nine. The average age is sixty six years, nine months, and twenty days. The males
                                average nearly sixty eight years and the females a little over sixty four. Since the
                                society discontinued the use of pork, about thirty five years ago, the average age lias
                                increased from less than sixty four, to over sixty eight years. Hancock, Mass. ) . May
                                1882. /</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>Juvenile</head><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rhymes of animals" TEIform="index"/>RHYMES OF ANIMALS</head><p TEIform="p">A correspondent of the Cincinnati Gazette writes. "I strung the following rhymes'
                                together to tickle the ears of my little boys, four and six years old. They tease their
                                mamma to read it over and over again, and they fetch the big illustrated dictionary to
                                have her point out the funny animals with such strange names and tell what she can about
                                them. This fancy for rhyme and rhythm is, I suppose, a characteristic of nearly all
                                children, ami perhaps the publication of this will amuse a wider circle than my little
                                household. The aim has been, after euphony, to have the most incongruous animals in
                                juxtaposition." Alligator, Beetle, Porcupine, Whale, Bobolink, Panther, Dragonfly,
                                Snail, Crocodile, Monkey, Buffalo, Hare, Dromedary, Leopard, Mudturtle, Bear, Elephant,
                                Badger, Pelican, Ox, Flyingfish, Reindeer, Anaconda, Fox, Guineapig, Dolphin, xlntelope,
                                Goose, Hummingbird, Weasel, Pickerel, Moose, Ibex, Rhinoceros, Owl, Kangaroo, Jackal,
                                Opossum, Toad, Cockatoo, Kingfisher, Peacock, Anteater, Bat, Lizard, Ichneumon,
                                Honeybee, Eat, Mockingbird, Camel, Grasshopper, Mouse, Nightingale, Spider, Cuttlefish,
                                Grouse, Ocelot, Pheasant, Wolverine, Auk, Periwinkle, Ermine, Katydid, Hawk, Quail,
                                Hippopotamus, Armadillo, Moth, Rattlesnake, Lion, Woodpecker, Sloth, Salamander,
                                Goldfinch, Angleworm, Dog, Tiger, Flamingo, Scorpion, Frogr Unicorn, Ostrich, Nautilus,
                                Mole, Viper, Gorilla, Basilisk, Sole, Whippoorwill, Beaver, Centipede, Fawn, Xantho,
                                Canary, Pollivrog, Swan, Yellowhammer, Eagle, Hyena, Lark. Zebra, Chameleon, Butterfly,
                                Sha"k.</p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Boy full of the bible" TEIform="index"/>A BOY FULL OF THE BIBLE</head><p TEIform="p">There was once a little boy who went to Sunday-school regularly, and learned all his
                                lessons well, so that he had a great many Bible verses in his mind. He was a temperance
                                boy. This boy was on a steamboat, making a journey. One day, as he sat alone on deck
                                looking down into the water, two ungodly men gentlemen I cannot call them) agreed that
                                one of them should go and persuade him to drink. So the wicked man drew near the boy,
                                and in an exceedingly pleasant voice and manner invited him to go and drink a glass of
                                liquor with him. "I thank you, sir," said the little fellow, '¦but I never drink
                                liquor." "Never mind, my lad ; it will not hurt you. Come and drink with me" " 'Wine is
                                a mocker, strong drink is raging, and whosoever is deceived thereby is not wise,'" was
                                the boy's ready reply. •'You need not be deceived by it. I would not have you drink too
                                much. A little will do you no harm, and will make you feel pleasantly " " 'At last it
                                biteth like a serpent and stingeth like an adder,' " said the boy. "And I feel safer,
                                and certainly think it wiser, not to play with adders." "My fine little fellow," said
                                the crafty man, '•it will give me pleasure if you will come and drink a glass of my best
                                wine with me." "My Bible says, 'If sinners entice thee, consent thou not,' " was his
                                reply. That was a stunning blow to the tempter, and he went back to his companion. "How
                                did you succeed?"' said he. "Oh, the fact ;s," replied the man, "that little fellow is
                                so full of the Bible that you can't do anything with him." So may it be with all boys
                                and girls.—Ex. Do the duties of to-day, and leave the cares of to-morrow till they
                            come,</p></div3><pb n="163" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Keep your lips" TEIform="index"/>KEEP Y0UR LIPS
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">If you your lips Would keep from slips, Five things observe
                                        with care : Of whom you speak. To whom you speak, And how, and when, and where
                                        If you your ears Would save from jeers, These things keep meekly hid : Myself
                                        and I, And mine and my, And how I do or did.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Select" TEIform="index"/>Select.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My little bed" TEIform="index"/>MY LITTLE BED</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bowers, Lucy S." TEIform="persName"/>LUCY S. BOWERs</byline><p TEIform="p">Written with, and for the little girls. A long time since in the mossy turf, Where the
                                brooklet babbled by ; Grew a lovely tree from a seed as small, As the pupil of your eye.
                                'Twas not the oak of the mountain top; For those from acorns grow ; But the emerald
                                boughs of the forest-pine, In the valley just below. Yea the lovely pine, where' the
                                little birds. Attuned their rapturous praise, And a covert found in the dewy night, And
                                from noon-tide's scorching rays. 'Twas from this tree so fine and large, That my
                                bedstead small was made ; On which I rest when the stars shine out. In their silvery
                                light arrayed. It was hewed apart from it's native soil, By the woodman's swinging tool;
                                Of branches shorn, and brought to the mill,' And sawed by the sawyer's rule. Then,
                                grooved and planed by the carpenter It's frame was all complete ; And covered well by
                                the painter's oil, It was handsome strong and neat. A tick well filled with husks, or
                                straw, From the farmer's grain, or corn, Makes soft and warm my nightly lodge, From
                                early eve, till morn Two sheets, as white as the driven snow, Or the blue sky's fleecy
                                cloud,— Are spread all over my little bed, A sweet and cleanly shroud. They came from
                                the land of golJen fruit Where the grand Mississippi flows ; And the Gulf-Stream washes
                                the shining sands And many a beauty growrs. For there on the broad plantation grounds,
                                Where the Negroes toil and sing, Grows the cotton-shrub with it's tassel bloom, And a
                                harvest rich they bring. The blossoms plucked by the tawny hand, Are placed in a large
                                machine, Where the seeds are cast from the downy turf, And makes them white and clean.
                                Then drawn into threads of wond'rous length, By spindles of glittering steel; While the
                                warp, and woof with rattling loom The power of skill reveal. And this is the way my
                                sheets are made, By many a busy hand: And bought with a sum of golden coin, From the
                                vender's trading-stand. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. (To be continued.)</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Letter Box</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Village, N. 11. May, 1882" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Village, N. 11. May, 1882</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Emma" TEIform="persName"/>Emma</byline><p TEIform="p"> Shaker Village, N. 11. May, 1882 Dear Sister Sarah;—I felt so thankful this morning
                                during our season of worship for my privilege to grow up in a Christian home, with such
                                true, kind friends who teach me how to live a pure life that 1 resolved I would make
                                myself worthy through obedience and carefulness each day. When I am led to confess and
                                repent of my faults, through the forgiving love of my friends, I feel so happy I can
                                hardly express it. I am told that by this means my conscience is kept tender, and I
                                shall never be left to fall into sin, and I do want to be always pure at heart. I mean
                                to pray continually for strength to resist each evil temptation that I may grow up pure
                                and true like you, dear sister and finally become one of the "flowers of Heaven." <pb n="164" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 164 SHAKER MANIFESTO. I am trying very hard to improve my time in
                                school, there are so many things I want to learn that I may be useful, and able to be a
                                teacher myself some day. My scripture text for this week is "Ask and it shall be given
                                you, seek and ye shall find." Now, please remember in your prayers, the teachers,
                                scholars, and also, Your little girl—'Emma.</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Village, N. H." TEIform="index"/>Shaker Village, N. H.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Woods, S. S." TEIform="persName"/>S. S. Woods</byline><p TEIform="p">Shaker Village, N. H. My Dear Emma;—Your pretty letter of May 11, was an agreeable
                                surprise, it gave me pleasure to know that you so well understood the gospel testimony
                                which requires confession and repentance of all sin, and that you are striving to make
                                this knowledge practical, to the purifying of your own heart, that you m:iy become one
                                of the blest number who "shall see God." Your thought of prayer for spiritual guidance
                                and help in the time of temptation, you will find a safe course to pursue, while the
                                discipline of self-control will be refining and beautifying; for ''He that ruleth his
                                spirit^is better than he that taketh a city." I am pleased also that you realize the
                                importance of devoting yourself to study with energy and zeal, the remaining terms of
                                your school days, that you may attain the most satisfactory results, and avoid regret
                                for misspent time, in the future "Whatsoever thy hand findeth to do, do it with thy
                                might." A few more years and you will be old enough to take some responsibilities and be
                                a support to those who have borne the burdens of life, while loving and caring for you.
                                I trust you may then have the desired fitness to meet the hopes and expectations of your
                                Christian friends who are praying that you may become a loyal daughter, pure and true,
                                in the home of your parents. "Godliness is profitable unto all things, having the
                                promise of the life that now is, and of that which is to come." I am pleased that the
                                children are so interested in learning scripture texts, it is so much better to have the
                                mind stored with the beautiful, the true and pure expressions in th' Bible, than, to
                                have the heart filled with evi thoughts which work ill to the possessor, and only evil,
                                so far as their influence extends. My dear young fri nd, never allow yourself to trifle
                                with prayer or a religious life. Cultivate reverence to God, and to your superiors in
                                goodness, rank and age ; thus grow respect, affection and love for the pure and the
                                true, that your own spirit may aspire to attain this excellence of character which is so
                                lovely in the possessor. "He that loveth pureness of heart, for the grace of his lips,
                                the king shall he his friend." I have quoted some texts expressive of my interest in
                                you, hoping you may he impressed with their sentiments. Lovingly yours, S. S. Woods</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sheep" TEIform="index"/>SHEEP</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Albertis" TEIform="persName"/>Albertis</byline><p TEIform="p">Sheep are very useful animals ; If it were not for the sheep we would lose many warm
                                garments. 1 love to sue the lambs they are so playful. I think it is very nice to take
                                care of the sheep. The brother who had the care of the stock gave me a little lamb, but
                                I did not feed it for I was too small, but I could see it when I wanted to. I thought
                                very much of it. I think I treated him very well for when he was grown up to be a sheep,
                                I could call him from the rest of the flock and he would come up to me. I used to carry
                                him apples or a few beans or carrots. This ends my story. 12 years. *</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>House-hold</head><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If you want good starch..." TEIform="index"/>If you want good starch...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">If you want good starch, mix it with cold water; add boiling water until it thickens,
                                then add a dessert-spoonful of .sugar and a small piece of butter. This makes a stiff
                                and glossy finish equal to that of the laundry.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If tableclothes, napkins and handkerchiefs..." TEIform="index"/>If tableclothes, napkins and handkerchiefs...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">If tablecloths, napkins, and handkerchiefs are folded an inch or two beyond the middle
                                they will last much longer; it is on the edges of folds where they first wear, and
                                folding them not on a middle line, each ironing, they get a new crease.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tar" TEIform="index"/>Tar</head><p TEIform="p">may be instantaneously removed from the hand and fingers by rubbing with the outside of
                                fresh lemon or orange peel, and wiping dry immediately after.</p></div3><pb n="165" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In grating nutmegs" TEIform="index"/>In grating nutmegs</head><p TEIform="p"> begin at the flower end ; if you commence at the other, there will be a hole all the way
                                through.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Old boot-tops" TEIform="index"/>Old boot-tops</head><p TEIform="p"> lined make excellent ironholders.</p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Canning vegetables" TEIform="index"/>Canning Vegetables</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Peas and beans may be prepared for canning by simply cooking them as you
                                        would for the table, leaving out the seasoning, and filling the cans quite tup
                                        to the top while boiling hot. Have the peas and beans rather young and tender.
                                        Add the seasoning when you open the cans to use them. Keep them in a cool, dark
                                        place, free from dampness. Corn, to can, should be young and tender, but full
                                        grown. Strip off the outside leaves and silk, but leave on the inner leaves—this
                                        will keep the sweetness in. Let it boil fifteen minutes. Take it up, cut the
                                        kernels through the middle, and then off the cob. Pack your cans as full as you
                                        can with the corn, and then take a cob that will fit in the jar without its
                                        being broken, and press it into the middle of the corn, and screw the tops on.
                                        Have the cans and the corn as hot as possible.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Country gentleman" TEIform="index"/>Country Gentleman.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good egg will sink in water..." TEIform="index"/>A good egg will sink in water...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A good egg will sink in water. A boiled egg which is done will dry quickly on the shell
                                when taken from the kettle. The boiled eggs which adhere to the shell are fresh
                            laid.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Alum" TEIform="index"/>Alum</head><p TEIform="p"> dissolved in water will kill bed-bugs if applied where it is most needed.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To clean painted wood work" TEIform="index"/>To cean painted wood work</head><p TEIform="p">To one pint of soap add two table spoonfuls of spirits turpentine; then take two quarts
                                of warm water and one pint of skimmed milk, putting enough of the soap in to make a weak
                                suds; with this wash the wood work. It will cleanse and leave a gloss wherever it is
                                used.—Enfield, Conn.</p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tough meat" TEIform="index"/>Tough meat</head><p TEIform="p"> may be made quite tender by soaking it in vinegar and water for six or seven hours.</p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Never allow salt meats of any kind to boil hard" TEIform="index"/>Never allow salt meats of any kind to boil hard
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Never allow salt meats of any kind to boil hard.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>Farm and Garden</head><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sawdust for bedding" TEIform="index"/>SAWDUST FOR BEDDING</head><p TEIform="p">Sawdust affords an excellent material for bedding. It is cleanly and a good absorbent.
                                Its chemical composition is about the same as that of straw, so that manure with which
                                it is mixed would apparently be of about the same value as that with which straw is
                                mixed. The straw, however, is more easily decomposed than the sawdust, and its elements
                                would sooner become available for plant use. The sawdust has the advantage of being a
                                better absorbent than straw, and its use will save a larger portion of the liquid manure
                                than will be saved when straw is used. Some object to the use of sawdust on the ground
                                that it injures the land to which it is applied. This we regard as an unfounded
                                supposition. If applied to light land, it wilj render it more retentive of moisture, and
                                impede the excessive drying of the soil. If applied to heavy land, it lightens it and
                                renders it more easily penetrated by rains, air and warmth. Wherever sawdust is easily
                                attainable, it will probably be found advisable to use it for bedding and as an
                                absorbent. Watchman.</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let old and young fowls enjoy a range..." TEIform="index"/>Let old and young fowls enjoy a range...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Let old and young fowls enjoy a range, if possible, the larger this is the better.</p></div3><div3 type="equipment" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Care of the buggy" TEIform="index"/>Care of the Buggy</head><p TEIform="p">.—We lay it down as an axiom that the farmer who cannot afford a cover for his implements
                                and vehicles has no business with a buggy. A buggy is too frail and delicate to stand
                                heat and storms. The buggy must be kept housed when not in use. When brought out of the
                                house it should be dusted off with a feather duster. If it comes home muddy, it should
                                be cleaned before putting in the house. It may be inconvenient, but in the end it will
                                pay. There is no need of taking it to a creek and there attack it with the old scrub
                                broom. Take a bucket or two of water and a sponge and gently wash the top, then the bed,
                                and wring out a chamois and wipe so no water stands on the varnish. Wherever water dries
                                on varnish it will lose its lustre. A bucket and a sponge and chain- <pb n="166" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/> 166 SHAKER MANIFESTO. ois and feather duster are as necessary adjuncts to
                                a fanner's buggy as a wrench A careful man will have his buggy look neat and last three
                                times as long as the class firs named. The average farmer can ill afford to buy a buggy
                                and harness for pleasure. And neither he nor any other farmer can afford lo neglect and
                                destroy them. Wastefulness treads on the heels of extravagance, and the model farmer
                                will not tolerate either on his premises.—Ex.</p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Measuring hay in a mow" TEIform="index"/>Measuring Hay in a Mow</head><p TEIform="p"> .—Four hundred cubic feet of hard-packed Timothy hay wilj make a ton; so will 500 cubic
                                feet of mixed Clover and Timothy hard packed. Clover alone requires GOO to 700 cubic
                                feet for a ton and common mixed meadow hay, including a large proportion of Red Top and
                                June grass , will require 700 to 800 feet. The weight depends somewhat upon the ripeness
                                of the hay; ripe hay is heavier than that made from early cut grass- No rule can
                                therefore be given that will give accurately correct results ; but the general rule is :
                                Multiply the length in yards by the height in yards and the product by the width in
                                yards and divide the product by 15; the quotient will be approii. mately the number of
                                tons.—Ex.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books and papers" TEIform="index"/>Books and papers</head><p TEIform="p">Hall's Journal of Health; May; Pub. by E. H. Gibbs. A.M., M.D. 141 Eighth St. near
                                Broadway, N. Y. Contents. How to Exercise; Beauty's Tyranny; The Management of Sick
                                Children; Prevention of Disease; India Rubber Hunting; Mind and Health; Ignorance and
                                111 Health; Rheumatism; How to save a drowning person; Shaving the Beard; Reason in all
                                things, etc., etc. Freeman's Monthly Magazine is a neat and well conducted periodical.
                                No one should be without it—Edited by Ozias S. Freeman, N. Y. The St. Louis Magazine for
                                May, comes to us with its usual supply of interesting illustrations and reading matter.
                                It will be especially desira' ble to all who would like a view of some of the most
                                prominent buildings of St. Louis, including the New U.S. Custom House and Post Office,
                                and the new building of the St. Louis Cotton Exchange with a sketch ot the City. Send
                                ten cents to the Publishers and receive a sample copy of the Magazine and a set of
                                beautiful, picture cards. Address St. Louis Magazine Co. 213 N. Eighth St. St. Louis,
                                Mo. Herald op Health ; June; Pub. by M. L. Holbrook, 13 &amp; 15 Laight St., N. Y.
                                Contents. The Tubercle Parasite,—A new theory of Consumption. The Effects of Tobacco.
                                Public Hygiene, Is it of any use? Quantity of Food. Deaths of Darwin, Emerson and
                                Longfellow. Habits of Darwin. Feeble Children. Acidity of the Stomach, etc. A History
                                worth having.—The new and charmingly beautiful, as well as wonderfully cheap edition of
                                "Green's Larger History of the English People" which is being published by The Useful
                                Knowledge Publishing Co., New York, is most deservedly finding a place in thousands of
                                home libraries. So history is better worthy of a place in even the smallest library,
                                and, though formerly published by the Harper's at $10, it is now easily within the reach
                                of any one, the prices varying in the several forms, from 65 cts. in one volume, octavo,
                                Utility binding, to $2.35 in 5 vols. Elzevir edition, half Russia binding. It also forms
                                a part of the first volume of the Cyclopedia of History which is shortly to appear.
                                These editions are for sale by enterprising booksellers, and club agents and canvassers
                                are wanted everywhere by the publishers, to whom are offered very unusual inducements
                                and facilities. The Homiletic Monthly—Pub. by Funk * Wagnalls, 10 &amp; 12 Dey St.
                                New York. Contents; Sermonic; The Resurrection of Christ, Christ's Solution of David's
                                assertion; The first Beatitude; The Light in the Clouds; The originality of Christ's
                                Character; The uprooted Plants; Building with Hewn Stone; Christ's desire for his
                                people's company; Soul saving the Christian's Business; The uncreated Sun; Funeral
                                Service; Sunday School Service. Among the other papers, are Lectures to my Students;
                                Prayer meeting service; Homiletic studies in the book of Hebrews;—Sermonic criticism;
                                Suggestive themes for sermons, etc. etc. $2.50 a year, single number, 25 cts.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>Select</head><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A tutor of one of the Oxford Colleges who limped in his walk, was..." TEIform="index"/>
                                A tutor of one of the Oxford Colleges who limped in his walk, was...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A tutor of one of the Oxford Colleges who limped in his walk, was some years
                                        after accosted by a well-known politician, who asked him if he was not the
                                        chaplain of the college at such a time, naming the year. The doctor replied that
                                        he was. The interrogator observed: "I knew you by your limp.' "Well" said the
                                        doctor, "It seems that my limping made a deeper impression than my preaching."
                                        "Ah, doctor," was the reply, with ready wit, "it is the highest compliment we
                                        can pay to a minister to say that he is <pb n="167" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO.
                                        167 known by his walk rather than by his conversation.''</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Woman's journal" TEIform="index"/>Womans' Journal.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="history" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Coffee" TEIform="index"/>Coffee</head><p TEIform="p">, was first sold in London in 1652, by a Greek, whose handbill read: "The virtue of the
                                coffee drink first publiquely made and sold in England by Pasqua Rosee, in St. Michael's
                                Alley, Cornhill, at the sign of his own head."</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Have some aim" TEIform="index"/>HAVE SOME AIM</head><p TEIform="p">. ' If we could all be great—if each of us in this grand and beautiful world might win
                                fame and horor—if we might gain the praise of the multitude, and be pointed out in the
                                throng as the gifted artist, author, or statesman—it would be very pleasant, doubtless,
                                and soothing to our pride. But if all were eminent there would be no eminence. If every
                                one stood at the top of the ladder, this would be a very humdrum world, for the
                                mainspring of trying to win any good thing is emulation. But it is certain that all
                                cannot be at the top. Society is made up of all grades, but while some will always
                                remain in the humble ranks of plodders, even the lowest may accomplish some great
                                object, which, though it does not secure fame, may win peace and joy. The golden rule of
                                life is to ''Do everything the very best you can." We may make our mark as well in one
                                place as another, though perhaps not as. plainly; but if, in the beginning of our
                                career, we make up our minds to do every duty promptly which comes in our way, to act
                                and speak kindly as we have opportunity, to make life easier to others, if we can do so;
                                in short, to do what we can toward making the world a pleasant place to live in, we will
                                win something far more precious than fame—the love of those around us, and the approval
                                of God. //. V.</p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Model lawyer" TEIform="index"/>A MODEL LAWYER</head><p TEIform="p">. 'Squire Johnson was a model lawyer, as the following anecdote will show : Jones once
                                rushed into the Squire's office in a great passion, and said : "That scoundrel of a
                                cobbler, Smith, has sued me for five dollars for a pair of boots." "Then you owe him
                                five dollars?" "To be sure I do, but he's gone and sued me—sued me !" "Then why don't
                                you pay him, if you owe him?" "Because he sued me, when a man does that I'll never pay
                                him till it costs him more than lie gets. I want you to make it cost him all you can."
                                "But it will cost you something, too." "I don't care for that. What do you charge to
                                begin with?" "Ten dollars, and more if there's much extra trouble." "All right? There's
                                the X. Now go ahead." No sooner was the client gone than 'Squire Johnson stepped across
                                to his neighbor, Smith, and offered to pay the bill on condition that the suit was
                                withdrawn. The shoemaker gladly accepted—all he wanted was his pay. The lawyer retained
                                the other five for his fee, and as the case was not troublesome, lie made no demand upon
                                his client. Ten days after, .Jones came to see how his case was getting on. "All right,"
                                said the lawyer: "You won't have any trouble about that. I put it to Smith so strongly
                                that he was glad to withdraw the suit altogether." "Capital!" cried the exulting Jones.
                                ''You have done it browr ! You shall have all my business hereafter."</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Here is a curious picture..." TEIform="index"/>Here is a curious picture...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Here is a curious picture of the way in which Sunday was spent in early English times
                                :—'"The minister used to sit on a Sunday afternoon on the green at Hatton with his pipe
                                and his jug and witness the exertions of his parishioners in the truly English game of
                                cricket, making only one provision, that none should join the party who had not
                                previously been to church. It is needless to say that his presence was an effectual
                                check on all disorderly conduct. He was beloved by his flock during his life, and
                                sincerely lamented at his death."</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Men in responsible situations cannot..." TEIform="index"/>Men in responsible situations cannot...
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Washington" TEIform="persName"/>Washington</byline><p TEIform="p">Men in responsible situations cannot, like those in private life, be governed solely by
                                the dictates of their own inclinations, or by such motives as can only affect
                                themselves. — .</p></div3></div2><pb n="168" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Purity" TEIform="index"/>PURITY</head><p TEIform="p">Canterbury, N. H. 1. O sacred cause of purity, We pledge a new our 2. Thou sun and center of
                            our hope, IIlumed by thee we 3. Again, we pledge to keep thy law, And light and love and
                            lives to thee, Thou art our joy, our happiness, And source of endneed not grope, For want of
                            light, to gild the way From moral dark beauty draw From all thy precepts, tried and true,
                            Until the perless life and peace. ness, up to day. Sweet purity, thou art in truth A crown
                            to age, a charm feet life we know. to youth; We'll cherish thee throughout all life, And
                            glory in the noble strife. </p></div2><pb id="p29" TEIform="pb"/><!--                     <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>