<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm0807" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title><editor role="editor" TEIform="editor"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/></editor></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">36</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">N. A. Briggs</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">8</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">7</biblScope><date value="18780701" TEIform="date">July 1878</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">153-179</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="8" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="7" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                        <pb id="p1"/>
<p>Vol. VIII. NO. 7. JULY 60 Cts. per Annum, POST PAID. MANIFESTO OFFICIAL MONTHLY PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES.
                        OUR HOME AT SHIRLEY, MASS. "GO PREACH THE KINGDOM OF GOD!" 1878. PUBLISHED AND PRINTED AT SHAKER; VILLAGE, N. H. N.
                        A. BRIGGS, Publisher. THE SHAKER</p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <p> CONTENTS I'raver l.">;> i Editorial Notes 1(17 The Underground Kail-road fo5 ; A good beginning I(!S
                        The Essential' 1"J For the children ld!> Education ¦ I .)7 ! ('orrespondenee -1 ~ 1 lailiansNo. .">
                        |5Home Topics 17:! Metallic Salts ]>, Farm «!i (Jardcn 174 A timely suggestion [(',?, j Selected 174 Ann
                        I>ee l(!4 | (riviiiij1 one's life 17"> Life as a River , Kip ' Hook Table 17K 'I'm; SiiAKKi:
                        Maxikksto-:—Are Sliak'cvism j (>l)itiiarv 177 and ('hristianity synonyms? ICC Music 17S Progression TERMS OF
                        ADVERTISING. For one inch, one insertion $ 1. 00 one half column, ' -S 3. 00 one " " " $ C>. 00 ' page, " "
                        $12.00 Continued insertion for three months, 20 per ct. discount. ,, sjx „ 25 „ „ " one year, ?>o| "
                        Subscriptions, Sixty cents, |>eryear. Address, X. A. Briggs, . Shaker Village;. I\Ier. Co., N. H.,
                        •¦>¦ Subnet'ipt.ufn ii'iu oo.fjin when order /.s ri'oeit?cd,—iVo bud: iiuiiihefs.</p>
                        --><pb n="153" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><p TEIform="p"> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO AN OFFICIAL MONTHLY. G. A.. LOMA8 Editor. Shakers, 3ST. Y. VOL. VIII.—JULY.
                        1878.—No. VII.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prayer" TEIform="index"/>PRAYER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName">ELDER GILES B. AVERY</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">There is a deeply seated corruption in human nature ; and its influence is widely
                            disseminated. While this remains, humanity soils, blots and adulterates nearly all it
                            grasps. So does it affect the gifts of prayer, praise and worshipthey are banefully made a
                            trade. There is an illustrative story, of a Chinese habit of having prayers printed on rolls
                            of paper, and wound off by machinery, while the suppliant utters, as he hies to his
                            slumbers. "Those, O Lord, are my sentiments." It is also related of General Putman, when
                            admonished by General Washington for swearing, that he replied, "Which is the worse, to
                            swear thinking no evil, or to pray thinking no good?" The present theological standards of
                            the creeds of Christendom, (so called,) are immensely humanized, corrupted; making truth
                            mystified ; consequently, when simple truth is revealed, and shines upon these banners,
                            multitudes of sincere and unsophisticated souls cannot march under their authority; thus
                            church going—meetings for religious devotion and culture—are largely abandoned. Under this
                            influence, the unenlightened, and multitudes of the young and unstable, are left without a
                            proper Christian culture, even without church discipline, (which is measurably good in all
                            denominations,) to grow up under the influence of giddy worldliness, almost amounting to
                            barbarism ; and infidelity to all religion, perhaps, to Grod ! So of the gift of prayer, it
                            has been so pharisaically used, so mixed with human ambition, pride and vain glory, by those
                            of the character admonished by our Savior, "Who love to pray standing in the market places
                            and in the streets that they may be seen of men." Or "love to make long prayers" verbally,
                            "that they may be honored for their much speaking," as to be a curse rather than a blessing.
                            The observation of this fact produces a tendency in weak, unbalanced minds, to neglect
                            prayer, or, to reject the sacred service altogether. Experience manifests this to be a very
                            grave error, the effects of which are cognizant to any well matured, observing mind, and
                            keenly felt by every living spirit. Of sincere, earnest, unadulterated prayer, it has been
                            truly observed : Praying will cause souls to leave off sinning; Or sinning will cause them
                            to leave off praying. <pb n="154" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE But, there are three kinds of prayer:
                            The praying trade ; the prayer of hope and faith,—dependent confidence ; and the prayer of
                            works. The two latter alone are available. Hypocrisy, used in the profession oi a virtue, or
                            the practice of a principle in the conduct of life, or the misuse and abuse of a virtue,
                            brings it into disrepute, in the estimation of the sincere. A laborer, toiling for wages,
                            and paid in counterfeit bank bills, would contract a very poor opinion of bank notes. Thus,
                            the profession of Christianity, with all its devotional duties, having many counterfeit
                            creeds of faith, and hypocritical ceremonies of devotion, while the actual life-character of
                            multitudes of its professors gives their Chris- tian profession the lie ; causes
                            Christianity to be spurned by many non-professors, and by heathen nations, these not being
                            able to appreciate such Christianity as a blessing. The same principle is applicable to many
                            of the best graces and gifts of a godly life. Singing, rightly used, is a most beautiful
                            gift to humanity, and among the most excellent in the devotions of a Christian, but, being
                            abused by multitudes,—used to minister to human, evil passions, folly and sin, the honest
                            Quaker rejects it, as being inappropriate to the worship of God. The same may be said of
                            dancing ; and, perhaps, no gift has been more lamentably abused than the Christian ordinance
                            of auricular confession to God of sin, in presence of living witnesses ; corrupting the
                            ordinance, so as to become an abominable curse, in the manner that multitudes use it, thus
                            inducing a determination to reject it altogether ; although used in a godly manner, it is
                            the basis of soul freedom from the power of sin. A proper object of prayer, of the genuine
                            type, is to produce a soul fitness for the reception of God's blessings ; to give it
                            possession of dependence, hope and confidence Godvvard ; to open unto the soul the avenues
                            of spiritual light, life, love and peace ; and to introduce to it communion with the
                            heavenly hosts. The prayer of works, in conformity to God's laAvs, should accompany the
                            prayer of supplication. Even the products of the material world, manifest this phase of
                            prayer, so that the poet has deftly sung: "The unknown mountains send forth their voices to
                            the stars," (for balancing force.) "Even the rocks become poetic" (speaking firmness) "And
                            the shrubs sing," (in supplications for light and moisture.) The suppliant tendril of the
                            slender vine imploringly reaches forth its tiny arms for aid, in support of the vine : the
                            blushing flower leans its filmy petals to the light, supplicating the tender kisses of the
                            sunbeams ; each opening flower bud, every expanding leaf and stretching shoot, or pendant
                            branch, manifests its silent prayer, dependent upon dew and sunshine. And, in the language
                            of philosophy even the minerals and waters become linguists, and answer to the silent prayer
                            of dependence in man for aid in all the multiform issues of life. But, to obtain the
                            benefits of these bounteous provisions, man must exercise a working prayer ; seek out the
                            most advantageous methods, apply his talent, skill, give his earnest attention to the object
                            of his pursuit; he cannot receive the answer of his prayers while he sits idly, resting in
                            supine indifference. Spiritual elements are no less real;, and spiritual cause and
                            consequence no m: .ajsttetesto . 154= <pb n="155" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER 155 less secure.
                            Beyond all question, the moving forces of creation are spiritual; "For what is form, or what
                            is face, But the soul's index, or its case?" Thus, even more potently does there exist, in
                            the spirit spheres, the substances and powers requisite to respond to all the supplicating
                            needs of humanity. Seeing, feeling, and possessing positive knowledge of this fountain,
                            having been ministered unto bountifully therefrom in answer to prayer, Jesus could
                            appropriately teach : "Seek, and ye shall find, ask, and ye shall receive ; knock, and it
                            shall be opened unto you ; for he that seeketh, findeth; and, unto him that knocketh, it
                            shall be opened." "If a man ask bread, will ye give him a stone ? if he ask a fish will ye
                            give him a serpent? If ye, then, being evil, know how to give good gifts unto your children,
                            how much more shall your Heavenly Father know how to give good gifts to them who ask Him !"
                            Thus, prayer is a Christian duty. And the soul, to obtain spiritual power and treasure, must
                            work for it, as really as the physical body does for its support. Souls who thus keep a
                            sacred habitation in their hearts for God, and humbly, prayerfully, earnestly, and
                            persistently seek His blessing, place them- selves in a state of recipiency of His bountiful
                            provisions, thus procuring a supply, even though our God were not the dispenser of Special
                            Providences.Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Underground railroad" TEIform="index"/>THE UNDERGROUND RAILROAD Thoughts suggested upon
                            hearing a lecture delivered by Edwin H. Coats.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Devyr, Cecelia" TEIform="persName">CECELIA DEVYR</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">Were its directors monied kings, Who buy the statesman from his trust? Or politicians of the
                            rings That chain the Nation in the dust? Nay, they were Men and Women too, Whose souls were
                            roused by slavery's crimes : God's inspiration thrilled them through, And nerved them for
                            those dangerous times. They had no leaders, and no plan Save that which reached them from
                            above; 'Twas love to God, and love to man, That made their work effective prove. On them no
                            Congress e'er bestowed In bounteous boons the public lands ; And no appropriations flowed To
                            them, through great official hands. They had their Charter from the Lord; Their bonds were
                            sacred in His sight; But slavery's base and hireling horde Encompassed them with watchful
                            might. The law, but was it law indeed! And not infringement bold and strong? Can a Republic
                            plant the seed That bears the bitter fruits of wrong? They called it law—the cruel code That
                            gave to slavery its desire ; They called it law, until its load Exploded in rebellion fire.
                            It was the proud aggressor's will, And not the Nation's own decree ; Her olden edict
                            glitters still, That all are equal born, and free. A sword of state that vengeance flamed,
                            Dark prison walls that hugged their gloom, Pines, bloodhounds,—tyrannies unnamed— Combined
                            to work for Freedom's doom. But up and down through every State, This grand mysterious
                            railroad wound; Its baffled foes in rage and hate Declared that it was Underground. For
                            through the solitude, and crowd, It was concealed from selfish eyes ; 'Twas like the pillar
                            and the cloud, It guided and it wrought disguise. Who saw the fire that moved the car? Who
                            knew the signal of alarm? They passed it close, to seek afar, Whose hearts were brooding
                            aught of harm Oft from his hut through storm and rain, Came forth some ssecient tottering
                            slave, To be the foremost at the train, The flying fugitive to save. It always bore its
                            trembling freight Through shadows of the darkest night; M^NTFiraSTO. <pb n="156" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/>
                            156 THE SHAKEE And cleft the folded glooms of fate, With but the North Star for a light. No
                            gladness, only tears, and prayers, And anguish passed along that road, Wild maddening fears
                            and crushing cares, That sent the simple hearts to God. The train that sped the slave away
                            Through solitudes, and busy marts, Still rolled its wheels by night and day, On Abolition
                            hearts. They knew its weight, they knew its strain, And nobly kept their solemn pledge, To
                            bear the burden and the pain, And be for God an opening wedge. A future outline, rough and
                            dim, Grave bodings round the bondman thrown, But childlike faith sufficed for him: He felt,
                            he knew, the yet unknown, For e'en friend Whittier ne'er divined The end, how distant, nor
                            how nigh; But said with firm prophetic mind, That "Every wrong shall die. For laws of
                            changeless justice bind Oppressor with oppressed, And close as sin and suffering joined, We
                            march to fate abreast." O! as we read these words that'gleam, And view that miracle—the
                            Past, We know that God with even beam, Shall mete our measure at the last. For when the
                            South her judgement bore, Did East and West and North escape? She had the streaming crimson
                            gore, And they the sable crape. Both symbolize the parted breath Of ghastly soldiers on the
                            field, Who died when slavery met its death; When cannon balls the compact sealed. And still
                            with Whittier, our trust O'er sin and sorrow rises high ; "We only know that God is just,
                            ,and every wrong shall die," Toil on brave workers, "Mind the light," The Orient flashes
                            o'er the sky, By that great victory won at night, Take courage, "Every wrong shall die.''
                            Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A bishop asked a little child, 'my little friend tell me where God is...'" TEIform="index"/>A bishop asked a little child, 'my little friend tell me where God is...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A bishop asked a little child, 'My little friend tell me where God is, and I will give you an
                            orange.' 'My Lord,' replied the child, 'tell me where he is not, and I will give you
                        two,'</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Essential [with printing errors]" TEIform="index"/>THE ESSENTIAL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName">WM. H. BUSSELL</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">The grades and forms of life appear to be innumerable. Doubtless, each has some special
                            significance, though, in many cases, not yet made evident to the human mind. To the Infinite
                            all things are simple, but to the finite capacity many seem complicated and difficult of
                            solution. Man needs to know what among the whole are necessary for his present welfare, and
                            to feel the assurance that all things will become clear in the future as his power to
                            investigate increases. There seems no limit to this power in man. At the present time he
                            contains within him- self the treasures of all past ages. Those, it ns true, have been
                            handed down embedded in a mass of apparent rubbish, like gold in the midst of various other
                            materials. But however tenacious of their treasure these may be, they are obliged to yield
                            to the separating forces applied to them, and the valued metal appears at last free from all
                            its incumbrances. Truth is essential. Though from age to age it has seemed to be mixed with
                            error, yet its nature has not been changed thereby. It never was the Divine intention to
                            reveal all truth at once, only that which is essential for the time being; its highest forms
                            are reserved for the latest times ; or it would have been so revealed, and there would have
                            been no need of investigating and inquiring here and there where truth is to be found; in
                            fact, there would have been in man no faculty for investigation and discovery. Is the
                            All-Wise anxious in respect to the estimation in which he shall be held by his creatures? If
                            so, he would have endowed them at once with the proper powers of appreciating himself. But
                            from the beginning the objects of Divine worship have been, the sun, moon and stars; beasts
                            of various kinds ; men remarkable for their physical endowments ; creatures of the
                            imagination— gods and goddesses—possessing all the human passions and vices; an eternal
                            beingstyled God, yet limited in his attributes and mode of existence ; and yet another who,
                            according to some theological authorities, ventured to set himself up as the rival of the
                            last M-AJVEFEISTO. <pb n="157" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKBE M-AJNTEETESTO. 15 r gradual learner. The
                            most essential thing is that each individual should know himself thoroughly and what is best
                            adapted to his particular case. There are general laws applicable to all persons, and there
                            are particular rules far more numerous than the general. These are all stringent because
                            they are intended to make strictly upright men and women— ' 'Who know their rights and
                            knowing dare maintain," in spite of the clamor of appetites and passions pleading for self
                            indulgence. Who shall know also how to respect the rights of each other in all the relations
                            of social life and yet make social life infinitely preferable to the solitary's cell. When
                            all shall have learned to govern themselves in accordance with Divine Love, then those
                            cumbersome machines called civil government will no longer be needed. Religious parties and
                            theological rules will be superseded by a state of things in which the in- dividual shall
                            belong completely to the whole and the whole devoted supremely to the individual. Groveland,
                            2V. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Education" TEIform="index"/>EDUCATION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName">MARTHA J. ANDERSON</persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> "All should be embraced in education, which can promote the formation of the man (and woman)
                            and prepare them for the eternal destiny of their spirits." Education in its broadest
                            meaning includes not only the culture of the intellectual faculties, but the moral and
                            spiritual also ; while a proper training of the physical powers should not be overlooked. An
                            exclusive development of the intellective group of organs may make the scholar, while the
                            combined unfoldment and harmonious action of mind and body, moulds manhood and womanhood to
                            completeness. There has been a struggle for the right form of education ever since the light
                            of intelligence overcame the gross ignorance of the dark ages, and the long cloistered
                            volumes of classical lore were again opened by the student of letters. At one time the study
                            of the classics was deemed the only means through which a thorough education could be
                            obtained. Greece and Rome were the conservatories of sound learning, and the Greek and Latin
                            authors were infallible guides to the temple of fame. Taste, beauty, exalted sentiment in
                            oratory, and poetic strain, filled the grand ideal of intellectual greatness. While
                            excessive application was required to compass this sphere of knowledge, the effort often
                            resulted in overcrowding the mental with much which was unpractical; and many whose
                            unfolding minds reached forth in a broader freer sphere, became disgusted with learning, or
                            the mode of acquiring mental wealth, because of the undue discipline required to master the
                            thoughts of others. Knowledge should be attractive, and as it becomes subjective and
                            practical, it will draw the youthful mind by its magnetic influences to the pursuance of
                            those studies, and the acquisition of that learning, which shall prove pleasure instead of
                            pain. Much admired ancient authors educated their minds in the contemplation of nature, and
                            study of man; hence they built monuments of thought and painted on life's can- vass, scenes
                            that time cannot erase, nor the blight of ages crumble. It is just this contract we all need
                            to quicken the inert capabilities of the mind, and generate the germs of new born thoughts,
                            that shall be evolved in every living form of grace and beauty. "Behold what high capacious
                            powers lie folded up in man" and woman, awaiting development in the sphere of education.
                            Strengthen the physical constitution and powers through exercise and labor; invigorate and
                            purify the moral nature in the sunshine of self-denial and temperance, and a basis for an
                            intellectual culture is formed that not only makes the scholar but the man. Those characters
                            are strongest who are selfmade ; and life's exigencies call forth innate powers that expand
                            the mind, and discipline the spirit. The thoughts should not be allowed to run in one
                            channel, or concrete in any set form; this tends to bigotry, superstition and misanthropy. A
                            self-poised individuality, broadening in the sunshine of universal goodness, overleaps the
                            narrow walls <pb n="158" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> ZL5S THE SHAKBE built by dwarfed pigmies ; and, impelled
                            by the unseen but powerful forces; correlated to the ceaseless activities of nature's
                            arcana; the soul develops a life harvest of good, fitted for humanity's needs. An active
                            intelligence should be displayed in all that we do; this ennobles labor, and places on her
                            brow the diamond crown which symbolizes her true worth. The sons and daughters of honest
                            toil, who "earn their bread by the sweat of their brow," may de- velop a genius of mind as
                            broad as he who measures the distances of stars, discovers the laws of motion, scintillates
                            in the galaxy of oratory, or excels in ethical philosophy. Only give to education its
                            broadest meaning, then will the masses rise, and the hard hands that till the soil and
                            prepare the viands necessary for the building up of nerve and muscle, be actuated by higher
                            motives in serving than they now are. Science on the farm and in the household, will turn
                            life's drudgery to pleasant occupation. What is an overtaxed brain in a weak and dwarfed
                            body? Children should not only be educated in letters, but also imbued from early childhood
                            with a wholesome love of labor ; apart from school they should be carefully trained in some
                            useful avocation that is adapted to the development of the muscular system. Ancient Rome
                            recognized this in the training of her youth, and her greatest statesmen and generals were
                            proud of their title to the land from which they earned their own subsistence. The great
                            eastern world, still bound to olden customs, and fixed in modes of thought, have never
                            expanded in liberal sentiment toward the education of woman; it remained for the new growing
                            West—where woman seemed naturally to be held in high esteem— to place her on an equal
                            footing with man in spheres of education, and even now with the limited advantages as yet
                            yielded, she quite proves his equal. A young woman—graduate of one of our modern
                            schools—remarked in a sensible essay on the duties of life, that no girl should be allowed
                            to pass examination, nor receive a diploma, unless she could make good bread; as this was
                            the staff of life, and so few housekeepers were proficient in the art; she further suggested
                            that a cuisine department be attached to each seminary where the scholars could be initiated
                            in the proper preparation of food. We add, that land should join all academies, where boys
                            may be taught farming, especially cereal culture; both departments would prove excellent
                            gymnasiums for physical development. The superfluous accomplishments of fashionable society,
                            while they pander to vanity, and self-love, but feebly man the barque that drifts adown the
                            stream of fortune, knowing not on what desolate shore it may strand. It requires strength,
                            courage, and the tactics of stern self-discipline to steer well among the shoals and
                            quicksands of life's restless sea. Man was not created a useless parasite, nor woman a
                            flitting butterfly The noblest of our race have toiled, and fought, and won, in the varied
                            spheres of life which they have occupied; their deeds are not carved in marble, or blazoned
                            in memorials; but, in the glorious truth, that they have left their work of experience, and
                            have made easier the attainment of knowledge and virtue; thus by persevering effort, we may
                            fill and round out our sphere of usefulness; not imitating individual characteristics,
                            neither striving for an eccentric exhibition of our own; but in the uniform cultivation and
                            development of all those faculties that fill a well balanced mind. We may wisely review the
                            thoughts of others, and take pleasure in committing to the wonderful storehouse of memory,
                            beautiful and truthful utterances from gifted poets, sages or philosophers ; yet must we
                            learn to reflect, to observe, and to elucidate our own thoughts independent of others, if we
                            would become rightly educated. The age of ignorance is passing away, we cannot say passed,
                            while the lingering disposition remains to keep either sex, class, or color, under the heel
                            of despotic power or serfdom. " Increasing intelligence expands throughout the civilized
                            world; yet there is laxity in morals, and spiritual error still darkens the vision of the
                            mentally enlightened. Let us work toward that true form of education, that shall tend to
                            perfect and harmonize man M^LiNrnriESTO. <pb n="159" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE 159 and -woman, bringing
                            into requisition the combined faculties of both; thus shall society find a just and equal
                            balance, and civil and religioms government be administered in equity and peace, yielding
                            the greatest good to the greatest number Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Indians, no. 5" TEIform="index"/>INDIANS. No. 5</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescott, James S." TEIform="persName">JAMES S. PRESCOTT</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">PAST and PRESENT. When the light of the nineteenth century began to dawn upon the earth,
                            which continues to shine with increasing brightness, it showed plainly that war and slavery
                            were relics of barbarism, of pagan origin; that these two evils did not belong to this age
                            of the world and ought to be abolished, especially by allnations, even calling themselves
                            Christians. The popular Christianity of our day is only Christian in name, but very pagan in
                            practice. On the Indian question, the United States stand at least one hundred years behind
                            the age-they stand today where the old English colonies stood in 1760, one hundred and
                            eighteen years ago. To prove this we need only to cite two parallel cases, to exemplify what
                            has commonly taken place during the last 200 years. The town of Lancaster called by the
                            Indians Nashua, (my native town,) in Worcester County, Mass., was 200 years ago one of the
                            frontier towns, and suffered much from Indian wars-the whites then being in the minority.
                            "On the 10th of Feb.oldstyle, 1676, early in the morning, a body of fifteen hundred Indians
                            attacked the town in five distinct squadrons, completely investing it. There were at that
                            time more than fifty families in the town. Of this little band, fifty persons, or more were
                            either killed or taken prisoners. One half, at least, were killed. For more than three years
                            Lancaster remained uninhabited." (See Prescott's Memorial.) The other case is an official
                            account of recent date, which reads as follows: "The unprovoked butchery, of several
                            hundreds of peaceable Indians, chiefly women and children by Colonel Chivington, as detailed
                            in evidence above referred to, is enough to brand with lasting infamy any nation, that could
                            suffer it to pass unpunished. Our community was shocked by the action of the British
                            authorities in India, in blowing from their guns the prisoners of war whom they had captured
                            ; but their deeds of blood pale before the infamous murders by Chivington perpetrated under
                            the authority and in the name of the United States." Report of the Commissioner of Indian
                            Affairs. July 14, 1868. No Avonder the heart of some of the most enlightened reformers in
                            the city of New York was stirred to the very bottom on reading this account of Chivington's
                            outrage, which far exceeded that committed by the Indians in 1676, 202 years ago ; for that
                            was a dark age compared with the light of the age in which we live. Again we quote from
                            Tecumwega whose spirit communication we introduced in our second article of this series. "I
                            came here not to teach Congress how to make laws, nor statesmen, judges, nor lawyers to
                            enforce them ; but I have come with a message from the Great Spirit, who says all men are
                            born equal, red, black, or white, with equal rights and privileges under similar
                            circumstances. This great republic has SHAJKJER MAJSTIIPESTO. <pb n="160" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> ICO THE
                            SHAKER JVLAJSTrETESTO. grown strong and powerful, and its people have become as proud and
                            lofty, in their imaginations, as the tall cedars of the forest. "You say sir, my white
                            brother, that the Indian loves to roam throughout the dense forest, in pursuit of the deer,
                            and so he does. You say you have now and then educated one of his number and as soon as he
                            was educated he went again to his people in the far west. You also say that it is perfectly
                            natural for him to hunt and fish for a living and he is in his element in doing so. All this
                            is very true. But I would ask my white brother one question : Which would you consider the
                            best course to take with the Indians, to send Missionaries among them and form them into
                            order, and establish schools for the benefit of their children; or take the course you and
                            your forefathers have taken for the last 200 years ? "The leaders of this great republic may
                            take the course which they and their predecessors have taken for all time to come, and the
                            Indian will remain the same poor ignorant native of the soil. But a few years more will roll
                            around when the leaders of this highly favored land, this free Republican Government, will
                            have to make a final decision in regard to the Indians, as to what course they will take,
                            whether to banish them beyond all lands that will ever be annexed to the U. S. or educate
                            them as a people, that they may become useful citizens on a more equal footing with the
                            white man." North Union, Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Hon. Clute Bros, of Schenectady, N. Y. present most excellent encouragements for..." TEIform="index"/>The Hon. Clute Bros, of Schenectady, N. Y. present most excellent encouragements for...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The Hon. Clute Bros, of Schenectady, N. Y. present most excellent encouragements for parties
                            wishing Engines, Boilers, etc. We know, also, of the "Clute Plough" being the best plough
                            yet created, for all kinds of cross ploughing.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Metallic salts" TEIform="index"/>METALLIC SALTS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, Daniel" TEIform="persName">DANIEL FRASER</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">In a recent issue of one of the public papers a few remarks were made on alkaline salts;
                            advising their omission from the dietary of children. My studies have led to the same
                            desirable conclusion. A child, as far as animal life and growth are concerned, is a vital,
                            chemical machine. Observe, for a moment, what an amount of chemical power there is in its
                            system ! The child will take milk, and pulverized grains, and speedily they are transformed
                            into bone, muscle, brain etc. In human food there is a small percentage of alkaline matter,
                            though it is not assimilated. The special design of excretory organs is to remove from our
                            bodies all unassimilable matter ; and it is a remarkable fact, that the bowels and skin
                            co-operate with the kidneys, whose special duty it is to carry off alkaline matter in
                            solution. The study of these organs emphatically indicate, that the removal of the solutions
                            of alkaline matter from within the vital domain, is of primal importance. This is also true
                            of the volatile alkali ; as it is of the metallic salts. Alkaline matters in solution, are
                            the waste products of vital, chemical action; and they are thrown off, as does the chemist
                            the residuum of his works. It is stated that saleratus and soda are metallic salts ; their
                            bases are the metals potassium and sodium. In their caustic state they are poisons ; as used
                            in cookery they are disguised with carbonic acid gas, and like arsenic, when taken in small
                            quantities, are not immediately destructive ; but when the use of <pb n="161" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            SHAKER M-AJSTIIPESTO. 16X them in food is long continued, they are as stated to be,
                            "unfavorable to muscular action." Tired, languid feelings are the inheritance of those who
                            daily use these metallic salts. These poisons communicate their nature to everything they
                            touch; our food, and our blood they strike with a measure of death. They have an affinity
                            for carbonic acid gas—the gas of death,—and venous blood for oxygen—the gas of life and
                            activity. Hence the impropriety, or rather the criminality of countenancing the use of
                            saleratus and soda in food. About twenty five years ago I had charge of a company of young
                            persons. I took care that these chemicals were excluded from their diet. The activity of
                            body and ability of these young people were all I could desire ; and of late I have seen
                            similar results. The sooner the said chemicals are ex- cluded from our dietary, the better.
                            In my next subject, attention will be drawn to the various chemicals, and their
                            adulterations now in use. A concluding article will briefly show how to supply our tables
                            with wholesome and palatable bread, without the use of metallic salts. Attention has already
                            been drawn to the effects of saleratus and soda when used in food. Other chemicals are also
                            used. The following is a list of them and their adulterations : Cream of Tartar is a
                            bitartrate of potash and is largely used both as a medicine and in the preparation of bread
                            and cakes. It has been adulterated with tartrate of lime, chalk, finely ground, white
                            marble, with sulphate of lime, (Plaster of Paris) sand, salt-petre, alum, sulphate of soda,
                            and chloride of potash. Also, it has been found to contain as impurities, iron, copper, lead
                            and arsenic. Acid sulphate of soda, the residuum from making nitric acid has been largely
                            used to adulterate cream tartar ; it has also been found adulterated to the extent of twenty
                            five per cent with plaster of Paris! Professor Charles F. Jackson who had listened to the
                            report of the convention held in Boston, on "Home Adulterations," stated, "that it had come
                            to his notice that the cream of tartar used in making bread, is made up in part of ground
                            rice and alum." Mr. Hollis of Boston, stated, "that soda ash was sold for saleratus ;" and
                            Mr. Dix of New York said, that it was "within his knowledge that one firm in that city used
                            annually one hundred tons of soda ash in manufacturing saleratus, while other establishments
                            used the same article in making saleratus !" Magnesia is also used in food. It is a metallic
                            alkaline earth, and is sold in the form of a white powder. Alum is much used in bread making
                            ; it is a compound of Oil of Vitriol and pure clay ; is called sulphate of alumina, or Blue
                            vitriol—oil of vitriol and copper—has been long in use by public bakers. Baking powders,
                            yeast powders and the chemicals mixed with flour called ''•self 'raising flour," are acid
                            compounds, and carbonated alkalies. The following is a specimen of baking powders : Two
                            tablespoonfuls of cream tartar, one tablespoonful of bi-carbonate of soda; add them to two
                            pints of flour. Here we have three tablespoonfuls of chemicals to two pints of flour. Those
                            who make use of self raising flour, yeast powders &amp;c, subject themselves to
                            continuous drugging; for alkaline matter acidified, is aperient, cathartic, and diuretic.
                            Surely, alkaline matters and their acid <pb n="162" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> TL63 THE SHAKER compounds or
                            combinations, (to say nothing of alum, magnesia, and plaster of Paris) were never intended
                            by the Divine Mind to be served up at our tables in bread and cakes: such a departure from
                            simplicity is evidence of progression in a very wrong direction. If these chemicals and
                            their adulterations referred themselves to, and effected only the digestion which takes
                            place in the stomach and duodenum, and which may be called the gastric and biliary
                            digestions, and had no effect on the relation that man bears to the atmosphere, then the
                            mischief done would be less aggravated : but there is a digestion beyond the gastric and
                            biliary, of a higher order, which takes place in the lungs, wherein atmospheric air is
                            decomposed; one part of it, the oxygen, is appropriated and identified with the blood ; and
                            the other parts are expelled from the body ; this may be termed pneumatic
                            di^gestion—digestion by air. The all-wise Creator has imparted to the blood of all animals a
                            peculiar power, which chemists call an affinity for oxygen : when fresh portions of venous
                            blood arrive at the lungs, the oxygen of the air inhaled is absorbed ; should the process of
                            absorption be arrested but for a few minutes, life would become extinct. Therefore, it is
                            important that nothing enter the circulation with the blood the chemical action of which, is
                            in the least degree antagonistic to the chemical affinity which the Divine hand has
                            impressed on the vital fluid. Now what are the chemical affinities of alkaline matter in
                            solution ? and what are their effects on animal matter ? They have an affinity for carbonic
                            acid gas, and that they will take it from the air ; and that they act energetically on
                            vegetable and animal tissues, changing their character, and impressing them with their own.
                            When solutions of alkaline substances are rubbed between the fingers they produce a soapy
                            feeling, in consequence of a partial decomposition of the cuticle. They cannot be
                            assimilated, and must act according to their nature ; first, they lessen the affinity of the
                            blood for oxygen ; second, they partially decompose the blood. This subject might now be
                            closed, and the reader left to draw his own inferences, and decide whether it is safe to
                            allow such substances as have been described to commingle with his blood; merely reminding
                            him, that the vital fluid is a compound of muscle, bone, nerve, and all the other tissues of
                            his body in a fluid state, easily impressed, and characterized by living, delicate
                            affinities. But seeing that heavy capitals are invested in making chemicals for selfraising
                            flour &amp;c, parties can be found reporting that alkaline matter is not hurtful, but
                            beneficial. For instance "Dyspeptic Saleratus," is brought forth as a medicine, and an array
                            of medical testi- mony to sustain it. Therefore it will be well to meet them on their own
                            ground, and accept their position, to sustain the contrary whereof they affirm. Let us hear
                            what Liebig, the first chemist of our day has to offer on the sxxbject. He states: "All
                            salts with alkaline bases, when administered to man internally, in dilute solutions, may
                            again be detected in the blood; and the transit of these substances produces disturbance in
                            the organism. It is manifest, that the presence of these salts must produce a change in the
                            process of respiration; a part of the oxygen, inspired, which usually combines with the
                            blood, must, when M^NTIPKISTO. <pb n="163" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER 163 they are present,
                            combine with their acids, and thus be prevented from performing its usual office—vitalizing
                            the blood—the consequence of this, must be the formation of arterial blood in less
                            quantity," and one may add of poorer quality. Here we see in the first place, that alkaline
                            matter finds its way to the blood. Second, it produces disturbance in the organism. Third,
                            the quantity of good blood is lessened and impaired by the presence of these salts. Liebig
                            does not stand alone in the above testimony ; he is surrounded by others each a host in
                            himself; such as Schwencke, Pitcairne, and Thackery. They testify, that the carbonate of
                            potash, soda, and ammonia, have a particular effect in attenuating the blood, breaking up
                            its coagulating power, and inducing a diminished vital cohesion of the various textures
                            formed from it. The foregoing testimony covers all the ground we wish to occupy; but here
                            comes the man who presents the highest form of self-raising flour in the market. He has the
                            honor to represent the department of acid phosphate of lime, (old bones acidified) potash,
                            and carbonic acid gas, muriatic acid and soda. He is in a state of considerable concern that
                            the public should know that he has got the article, with numerous adulterations, which can
                            be put in at one end of a loaf of bread, and by a little chemical legerdemain brought out at
                            the other common salt! Let his old bones and acids alone, and the flour that contains them.
                            Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The world never keeps faith with the heart that trusts it..." TEIform="index"/>The world never keeps faith with the heart that trusts it...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The world never keeps faith with the heart that trusts it. Its promises of happiness are
                            perpetually broken. Take it for what it is worth and set your affections on what is worth
                            more.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Timely suggestion" TEIform="index"/>A TIMELY SUGGESTION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, Elijah" TEIform="persName">ELIJAH MYRICK</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">Do not keep the alabaster boxes of your love and tenderness sealed up until your friends are
                            dead. Fill their lives, with sweetness. Speak approving, cheering words while their ears can
                            hear them, and while their hearts can be thrilled by them. The things you mean to say when
                            they are gone, say before they go. The flowers you mean to send for their coffins, send to
                            brighten and sweeten their homes before they leave them. If my friends have alabaster boxes
                            laid away, full of perfumes of sympathy and affection, which they intend to break over my
                            dead body, I would rather they would bring them out in my weary hours, and open them, that I
                            may be refreshed and cheered by them while I need them. I would rather have a bare coffin
                            without a flower, and a funeral without a eulogy, than a life without the sweetness of love
                            and sympathy. Let us learn to anoint our friends be- forehand for their burial. Post-mortem
                            kindnesses do not cheer the burdened spirit. Flowers on the coffin cast no fragrance
                            backward over the weary days. Voice of Angels. Since we make our own heaven, instead of
                            relying on a remote, ideal one, located somewhere; let us heed the ''suggestion" and open
                            our alabaster boxes of precious ointments—love, sympathy, charity, and all the flowering
                            virtues which find expression in willing, generous acts, to those present with us today. Now
                            is our opportunity. The unappreciative dead—the deserted tenements—are not the objects on
                            which to confer such benefits. MLAJsnaErESTO. <pb n="164" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 164 THE SHAKER If
                            through envy, jealousy, or selfishness, we refuse the ointment of friendship and
                            appreciation to the living, our eulogies, and tokens over the dead, are but lying frauds.
                            The most potent requiem is the heart-felt grief at parting with a true friend. The plain
                            coffin, and white emblems of unvarnished honesty, with purity of life, have ever been Shaker
                            customs. Their passport to the next phase of existence is a home-made heaven within. The
                            black shroud, indicative of darkness and death, is banished hence ; since the veil which so
                            long separated the two worlds is pierced by the light of present revelation. "A life sweet
                            in itself, exercised in good, shall survive both name and memory." Harvard, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ann Lee: her work, her people, and their critics, fifth paper" TEIform="index"/>ANN LEE Her
                            work, her People, and their Critics. Fifth Paper.</head><p TEIform="p">During the summer, fall and Avinter of 1780, and until May of 1781, Mother Ann and her
                            associates were visited by great numbers; many coming hundreds of miles, by carriage and on
                            foot, to satisfy themselves of the meaning of the rumors concerning the peculiar people.
                            Among the visitors can be noted some very excellent individuals—some of the first minds of
                            those times, some of whom became converts, and remained as most excellent helpers in the
                            cause. One chronicler, writing of these times, says: "During this time the increase of the
                            work was great beyond expression. The Believers continually increased in power and zeal, in
                            light and understanding. Signs and operations, prophecies, visions and revelations from God
                            greatly abounded. The purifying fire of the gospel searched every heart; the increasing
                            power of salvation and the enduring substance of eternal life daily evinced, to every
                            faithful soul, the reality of the latter day of glory." In May 1781, Mother Ann, with a few
                            companions, set out on foot, to visit sections in the East, where converts of the faith
                            resided, and to which they urgently invited her. Another reason for this visit: She had
                            seen, in vision, while yet in England, a place in this country which she had not found, but
                            of which she often spoke. She started, first for Tucconockf where lived several families
                            named Osborn. Being greatly welcomed, immediate preparations were made for meetings. On
                            Sunday, a large concourse assem- bled, and during the discourse of the testimony, much
                            external operations were manifested, accompanied by keen testimonies against the flesh,
                            which latter roused much opposition. After a tarry of ten days, Mother Ann and company
                            started for Enfield, Conn., a distance of sixty-seven miles, and reaching the home of David
                            Meacham, a convert, halted. Their arrival created great alarm among the inhabitants, for
                            rumor had been busy circulating false reports concerning them. They were threatened with a
                            mob, to prevent which, the Selectmen visited and advised them to leave the place. They
                            however remained for a week, during which "a number believed and confessed their sins." They
                            now proceeded, unmolested, to Grafton, Mass., remaining a week, and from this place
                            journeyed to Upton, remaining several days. Thence, they moved on towards Harvard, remaining
                            at Isaac Willard's, Still Eiver, for a week. Erom here they went to Harvard, sojourning in
                            the "Square House," built, we believe, by the great revivalist and leader, Shadrach Ireland.
                            This was the place Mother Ann had seen in vision, in England. They made a long stay at
                            Harvard, and from it visited the towns of Shirley, Littleton, Woburn and Petersham. The
                            scenes of deep tribulation, persecution and brutal, personal abuse at these places, would
                            require a volume to narrate them, and would read like a fictitious tale of inhuman horrors!
                            Many believing in her testimony, came to visit Mother, which M^jNTrEPESTO. <pb n="165" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE! SHAKEE 165 brought upon all concerned in these visits the enmity of the
                            caviling and inimical. Crowds would commonly assemble around the house, armed with clubs,
                            when some of the believers would address them in a spirit that would put them to shame, and
                            they Would often quietly disperse. They were reported as being British abettors ; as having
                            hundreds of stands of arms; and one man was found, who testified to the credulous, that he
                            had seen "a curious chest at the Square House, filled with fire-arms !" Repeated searches of
                            the House were made, but with ever the same results—the entire absence of what enemies of
                            the faith desired to find—fire-arms. They were ordered to leave Harvard by self-constituted
                            authorities. This they refused to comply with. It was notably the case, that amid the brutal
                            persecutions, to be named hereafter, at this place, many of the persecutors repented and
                            embraced the faith! It has also been worthy of remark, that though the whole time of Mother
                            and companions was devoted to the crowds who visited them, "they never lacked a meal of
                            victuals, nor a sufficiency for the multitude." Concerning this subject Mother Ann said: "We
                            are fed here by the miracles of God; a great many people come, bringing little or nothing
                            with them but their sins; yet they are fed and have plenty. I know this is so by the
                            miracles of God!" Unwilling to have her people grow slothful, and indifferent to their
                            temporal sustenance, she advised industry at work as a means to that end. The brethren at
                            Lebanon, Hancock and Richmond added greatly to the temporal stores of "the little church at
                            Harvard," the reception of which caused a feeling of gratitude that brought them all on
                            their knees. In Dec, Mother and company made a journey to Petersham. On the following
                            Sunday, they found assembled a large concourse of people, desirous of seeing and hearing
                            them, among which were mingled a company, properly named The Blackguard Committee. While one
                            of the number was preaching, at dark, a cry was heard, "Knock out the lights !" the lights
                            were extinguished, and a mob rushed in, part of which siezed Mother Ann and attempted to
                            drag her out, but were prevented by a portly sister, Elizabeth Shattuck, so placing herself
                            in the doorway that they could not get out. They fled. But during the momentary struggle,
                            they tore the dress off from Mother Ann and did other damage. After the assembly had been
                            dismissed, there returned thirty wretches, who burst in the doors, and assaulted all in the
                            house: David Hammond was immediately knocked over and sadly beaten; his wife, with a young
                            child in her arms, was also knocked down and badly bruised about the head. James Whittaker
                            was knocked down and left for dead! All were more or less hurt. Searching the house, they
                            found Mother Ann, and seizing her by the feet, they dragged her out of the house, and threw
                            her into a sleigh, just as the carcase of a beast would have been handled, tearing off her
                            clothes to an indecent degree, under the pretense of be- lieving that she was not a woman! *
                            f Now called Washington, Berkshire Co., Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life as a river" TEIform="index"/>LIFE AS A RIVER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ervin, Anna" TEIform="persName">ANNA ERVIN</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">Nothing presents a more striking emblem of life, than a silent, smooth flowing river. To the
                            careless and inattentive eye it seems always the same, but the various portions of which it
                            is composed are gliding imperceptibly away. This is its common situation ; but at the
                            equinox how are the scenes frequently changed ! Swollen by torrents, the usually placid
                            stream bursts its bounds. Dark, troubled, and impetuous, it rolls along, involving in its
                            wasteful progress, every herb and floAver, which it before had nourished! Thus fares the
                            Christian : While his affections flow in an even current in the way of God's commandments,
                            the beautiful plants and flowers of religious life are exhibited. But no sooner does the
                            storm of passion rise, than every noble M^jsrrEPJssTO. <pb n="166" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 166 THE SHAKER
                            thought, generous feeling, and every excellent purpose is overwhelmed, and for a time, swept
                            away ! Enfield, Ct. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Progression" TEIform="index"/>PROGRESSION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Maria Witham" TEIform="persName">MARIA WITHAM</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">What is it? The power to grasp that knowledge which has no bounds but illimitable space, and
                            no end but eternity—And the object of our material existence is to lay the foundation for
                            that progressive development in the future which is here chained down by the material
                            shackles in the form. No matter what the cause, the effect is the same. The soul having its
                            progress arrested, must feel the loss which it can never recover, whether from want of light
                            or the abuse of it. The law which governs our existence in all its various conditions has
                            its effect on our destiny. How must we obtain the knowledge which will enable us to attain
                            that high desti- ny, to perform the sublime and mighty duties belonging to it, and be able
                            to execute the will of the great Creator, by giving scope to that germ which is speeding its
                            way back to the source from which it emanated? By progression, which is generally of slow
                            growth, and much patience will be required. But we must indeed "put on the whole armor of
                            God," girding with immortal strength those feelings which for the accomplishment of a great
                            and true object, will sacrifice, if needs be every thing of our own individuality. Is it not
                            a beautiful thought that we can ever be progressing upward? The contemplation awakens
                            emotions which cannot be uttered. What is education, what power, or wealth or position? All
                            weighed in the balance are found wanting. Enfield, Conn.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good conscience is better than two witnesses" TEIform="index"/>Good conscience is better than two witnesses
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A good conscience is better than two witnesses. It will consume your grief as the sun
                            dissolves ice. It is a spring when you are thirsty; a staff, when you are weary; a
                            screen,when the sun burns you, and a pillow in death.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Manifesto:--are Shakerism and Christianity synonyms?" TEIform="index"/>THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. Are Shakerism and Christianity Synonyms?</head><p TEIform="p"> Shakerism is not creed-binding in its effects on the mind. It does not claim to be the best
                            religion for the masses ; but rather, it insists that but few are capable of its
                            requirements. We claim that it is a Providential provision for those who are sick unto death
                            of all that constitutes the world ; for those, ripened to the harvest of Christianity, and
                            who are able to die for it daily, and to live for it continually. We claim that it is the
                            best illustration of Christianity today; and now, even as centuries ago was realized, we
                            repeat: "All men cannot receive Shakerism." In the present condition of the people at
                            large—a time when pure, practical religion is at very low ebb—it is very well for Shaker
                            societies, that they are not numerically larger. Every individual in any of these societies,
                            who does not realize that Shakerism is a boon most excellent, in other respects than in mere
                            earthly providences, is an obstacle ; is one too many, and the society is the weaker for his
                            or her presence. We do not plead Shakerism nor Christianity because of the peculiar features
                            per se in the possession of each ; and only because we find in their practical workings,
                            superior and more spiritual manhood and womanhood—find that they make of us fit companions
                            for those whom we esteem angelic beings—do we exalt the systems for the superior salvation
                            of the nations, when, and as fast as they "are able to receive them." Shakerism and
                            Christianity—synonyms—are M.A.IINrrEr'ESTO. <pb n="167" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER 16 7 simply
                            terms, and we claim no more for them, as such, than for any other denominational affixes.
                            There is no salvation in either appellation ; and only as we use the titles to make it
                            understood that our lives are superior to Jews, Gentiles, etc. we disgrace the titles and
                            put our profession to open shame. We believe celibacy—pure virginity— to be superior to
                            marital relations, because it makes us feel better, purer, in our estimation of a most
                            superior happiness. It relieves us from many worldly cares, and from temptations to the
                            practice of many corroding, unspiritual, scortative lusts. Inasmuch as it would make any
                            happier, and those around them more heavenly, it should be practiced at any cost of
                            self-denial. And the time will come, when the world at large will realize greater comfort at
                            the nearer approach of their lives to celibacy, than is, or has ever been felt by a greater
                            departure from it. To every one, approaching the conditions of angelhood in this life, there
                            appears in that degree, heaven on earth. Passing from the earth, such find an easy affinity
                            for those who live as the angels do ; while those who delight only in sensual indulgences
                            will find a selfdenial forced upon them by and by from the fact of an incapability to
                            indulge ; and this incapability will be hell. And so with all Christian peculiarities or
                            demands upon its professors. In the heaven of the Christian there is no marriage nor sexual
                            lusts; no private, selfish interests; no war nor worldly contentions. But pure, unselfish
                            love rules ; and its fruits are heavenly all the time. Those who love the world more than
                            they love to practice the life of Christ, are the children of the world. Let such marry,
                            live selfishly, love their own best; go to war, kill and be killed, live and die gratifying
                            worldly ambitions. But let the children of the Resurrection prove their worthiness to
                            heirship and discipleship by renunciation of the world, and following the Lamb, where the
                            Lamb led in life practice. Only what Christ lived for, and died for, are found in the
                            demands of Shakerism today? Who is a Christian, such is a Shaker.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>EDITORIAL NOTES</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Materializations by spirits" TEIform="index"/>MATERIALIZATIONS BY SPIRITS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The excellent reports we have received of the materializations of scores of Shaker
                                spirits at Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. give large credit to the ideas that such materializations
                                are possible, and genuine facts. In rooms that were quite unused for such
                                representations, and from cabinets arranged under Shaker supervision, there proceeded
                                very many evidences of materializations, by the spirits of whilom, life long companions,
                                whose representations and conversations forbade the idea of fraudulent imposition. We
                                are not sure of the fact, but Mt. Lebanon may yet become a Mecca for those who are now,
                                materialistic unbelievers in truths of spirit returns and physical embodiments.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Metallic salts" TEIform="index"/>"METALLIC SALTS"</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Our Bro. D. Frazer begins a series of articles, which however unready we are to accept as
                                true, will do us all much M^JNTEEHESTO. <pb n="168" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 168 THE SHAKER
                                M^JNTIKESTO. good to study and to investigate by practice. Custom, no doubt, puts down
                                our throats and into our stomachs much poisonous matter ; and yet, many more will become
                                martyrs, because we prefer to die prematurely, than to live longer by living
                                consistently. Let us give his series good heed.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Act your faith" TEIform="index"/>"ACT YOUR FAITH"</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">If we meet with opposition from within or from without, let us endeavor to act according
                                to the best spiritual instruction and belief. It is an unsafe caution for us to "act our
                                faith ;" as evidenced by that earnest defender of consecrated property, who, during the
                                visitation of the Ohio Mob to the Shakers, was stationed at the head of the stairs, with
                                instructions to prevent any one ascending. On the approach of two ruffians, he cried
                                out: "Elder Benjamin, what shall I do?" '¦'¦Act your faith;" came back in response, with
                                all expectation that he would act upon the principle of non-resistance—refraining from
                                physical violence. But iiAll right!" was his response, as raising a chair, he brought it
                                violently down on the head of the leader, at which all fled. The result of this
                                misunderstanding was no doubt fortunate; but in acting our faith, we should, as
                                Christians, act Christ nevertheless.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Progress" TEIform="index"/>PROGRESS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">It is a good sign, to find so many outspoken opponents to war among the ministers of the
                                many denominations professedly Christian. Within fifty years large progress has been
                                made in gaining converts to the truth that war is unchristian in its every phase. We are
                                very glad to be able to count on the increase of so much rationality ; and while not
                                intending to dampen the ardor of every Christian ad- vocate for peace as against war, we
                                use this occasion to express the hope, that Christian light will break upon more
                                multitudes, that they may see that marriage, private property, pride of life and of
                                dress, rich and poor, worldly politics and ambitions, are no more found in Christ than
                                is -war—are no more Christian than is war. A Christian's life is patterned after
                                Christ's.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our banner" TEIform="index"/>OUR BANNER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Millions of dollars are spent by the Churches annually to farther sectarian principles ;
                                and much sincerity of honest belief, is manifested by church goers, through their strong
                                desire to promulgate their especial creeds by giving largely for missionary purposes.
                                Ours is a Church doctrine having no sectarian ends to accomplish other than . to invite,
                                persuade and induce all who are able, to live like Jesus. We thus may find genuine
                                association with every honest professor of Christianity, who, yet unable to live so
                                self-denyingly and unworldly, is yet glad that others are able, and who feels a pride in
                                giving a mite to sustain our Banner—The Manifesto. Let us give our mites, mights and
                                lives to sustain genuine Christ prin- ciples and The Manifesto.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good beginning" TEIform="index"/>A Good Beginning</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> A new, religious movement has just started in Michigan; is "prospering wonderfully,"
                                having as its only test of membership the following, very sensible paragraph. We want to
                                enroll ourselves members of that church, and to hold out the petition for other
                                signatures. We are on the road to a perfect the. <pb n="169" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> ology : "We
                                believe Christianity is not a belief, merely, but rather a life; that the sayings of
                                Christ are the plainest possible statement of religious truth and constitute the only
                                true theology; that any person who believes and earnestly tries to live in accordance
                                with those sayings is entitled to church privileges."</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>For the Children</head><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Quondam sailor, chapter VI" TEIform="index"/>QUONDAM SAILOR CHAP.VI</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Libbey, William G." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> We found our Scotch bonnet a poor protection to our heads under the rays of a tropical
                                sun, and felt needy of a thin, light hat very much. At first we saw no way of supplying
                                this want until finding part of an old hat among the rubbish of the huts. It was made of
                                notched sinnet; and by picking this apart, carefully separating each strand, we were
                                able to braid some like it from a kind of palm that grew near our retreat. Of this
                                material we made us good hats, that afforded ample protection from the sun ; but in
                                sewing them we used nearly all of our good linen thread with which we were very sorry to
                                part. This was in the month of June 1842. We kept our reckoning on a little paper we had
                                brought ashore with us, which was about as large as a common sheet of letter paper. Part
                                of this we used for a notice to put up in our hut when we were absent, stating that
                                there were two men living there who had gone, up the river fishing, but would soon
                                return; also that they were in want of some fishhooks and lines, and would be grateful
                                for a supply. On the edge of the beach before mentioned, were numbers of fine large
                                cocoa-nmt trees whose tops inclined over the water; so much so that when the nuts
                                dropped from the trees, they fell into the water. We loved this little group of trees
                                more than any others we saw on the island; not only because they were beautifully
                                located, but that other forlorn beach compeers had noticed those very trees, we were
                                assured; by the names and dates ingeniously carved on their trunks. The reading of these
                                quaint autographs, seemed to bring us into communion with those American sailors whose
                                hands had traced them; for it was evidently done by hands that had abundant leisure,
                                from the nice finish of the lettering; and that it was the work of the former occupants
                                of the huts, we were sure; as a visit like that of our boats would not have given time
                                for such nice carvings; however, we left it as we found it, and have never learned who
                                completed the work. One day John and I were up to the beach for a feast of roast fish,
                                and cocoa-nuts ; and on our way home came suddenly upon a hen and her chickens. The hen
                                ran under the palmetto bushes out of reach, but John was too quick for the little
                                chicks, and secured his prize by putting his cap over two of them, and taking them home.
                                Among the rubbish of the hut where we tarried, we had found a rudely constructed bird
                                cage, made we supposed by some of our beach combining predecessors. This we attempted to
                                repair as a coop for our little feathered charge, and while I was at work on it, my
                                brother had the sun-glass trying to make a fire by which to cook our supper. The sun was
                                now getting very low, and there were rain clouds drifting across its face, making it
                                difficult to obtain focal heat enough to set fire to the cocoa-nut husk, which he held
                                in his hand; and becoming impatient with his ill-success I offered to change with him.
                                Taking the glass from him, and while waiting for a cloud to pass the sun, I chanced to
                                look closely at the lower edge of the horizon and espied a very small speck not
                                appparently bigger than my little finger; from having often seen vessels on the ocean at
                                a great distance, I knew it was a sail, and in the excitement of the unexpected sight, I
                                shouted, Sail ho ! so loud that my brother jumped up, being startled by my noise, and
                                eagerly asked; Where-away? I pointed to the little speck just at the edge of the western
                                horizon. <pb n="170" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> At first we were fearful that it was our ship coming
                                back to get us, but as the sail neared the island we saw she had but two masts, and was
                                a smaller vessel than the Wm. C. Nye. We succeeded in making a fire with our sun-glass,
                                and collecting a large pile of dry palm leaves we set them on fire, and soon after put
                                on a large amount of green boughs which made a great smoke, this was seen by the men on
                                deck of the vessel; one of whom was the second mate, who I afterwards learned said to
                                the officers ;—"What will you wager that there are not some men there, who will want a
                                passage with us down to Tahiti?" —the place the schooner was then from. This saying of
                                the second mate's proved correct, for it was the place above all others where I wanted
                                to go. The wind being light the little vessel came on toward the island very slowly, at
                                last she passed us, or the point where our hut was, and was lost to our sight behind a
                                point of cocoa-nut trees farther to the eastward. We had almost given up the idea of
                                seeing more of the sail, when a large boat full of men appeared in sight, pulling
                                directly for the shore where we were standing. As they approached we could see that they
                                were all natives except the man who was steering the boat, and when near enough to be
                                heard, we invited him to land, which he did with a native woman—his wife—leaving the
                                crew to pull the boat up the narrow passage into the lagoon. We introduced ourselves to
                                the white man, and learned that his name was Louie, that he was a native of France, and
                                was in the employ of the American Consul at Tahiti, and his partner, Captain Hall of
                                Boston, was on board the schooner, in which he had come to the island for the purpose of
                                making cocoa- nut oil. The natives were from the Parmoto islands —a group east of the
                                Society islands—Fanning's island is very much like the Parmoto, and these natives of
                                Louie's'seemed wild with ("elight. As the boat entered the lagoon one of their number
                                speared a shark, which was drawn up on the beach and was striking violently about with
                                his head and tail, when Louie drew a long Malay Creese which he wore all the time, and
                                thrust it through the shark killing him instantly; they soon had a fire, and were
                                feasting on their shark. They had been on the schooner more than a month, which was
                                serious confinement for these active creatures. Louie told us not to catch any more
                                fish, as the natives would supply us, which they did. The schooner was becalmed off the
                                island two days, and while waiting for it to come in, my brother and I went a long
                                distance to the eastward, with Louie and some of his natives. We went in the capacity of
                                guides, (having previously been around the island) to show our new friends the extensive
                                open plain, or marsh, where we had seen such vast numbers of boobies with their nests on
                                the ground, and which Louie was quite anxious to secure. This we attempted, but gave it
                                up after travelling .several miles, for the sun was getting low, and we made our way
                                back to the hut. When we came to the outlet, or channel of the lagoon, the boat was
                                there ready to take us over to our island home, and I thought as I crossed this channel
                                if we had been the owners of a boat, even a very small one, it would have saved us many
                                a weary mile of travel, in going around the island. On looking out to sea as we crossed
                                the tidal passage, we saw the schooner standing in, and Louie said he would go off to
                                her, and invited me to accompany him and the crew, leaving several natives with my
                                brother on shore. As we neared the schooner we could see that her crew had harpooned one
                                or more porpoises ; one of them had just been hauled in on deck by a fluke line as we
                                came along, and as we clambered up the side and were high enough to look over the
                                bulwarks, a rather comical sight met our view, at least, such of our company as
                                possessed "whaleman's eyes." The porpoise was flapping violently, and had actually
                                cleared the main deck of every body. Some had taken to the rigging for refuge, while the
                                captain and his mates with two native women, were safe on the high quarter deck of the
                                schooner. I had helped catch a great many porpoises, and in cutting them in pieces had
                                learned where they could be killed most easily, so with my sheath knife I tapped the
                                porpoise under the fin killing it instantly. xvo <pb n="171" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER 1-71
                                A negro cook of the vessel who had been on whaling expeditions, seemed delighted at
                                seeing it killed so quickly, and jumped anc shouted saying, "that fellow has broke black
                                skin before." The skin of whales being mostly black, this expression is very common
                                among whalemen. After speaking of harpooning a whale, I was received very kindly by the
                                captain and all on board. The second mate, an Englishman, came in the name oJ the
                                captain, and offered myself and brother a passage to the Society islands, Thanking him
                                for his .offer I very gladly accepted it, a: it was the place I wished to go to most, as
                                I was acquainted in Eimeo having been there two different times during a former passage
                                in the ship Phenix of New London. (to be continued.) </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Bro. Albert: Allow me to say that I am more prone to speak approvingly than..." TEIform="index"/>Dear Bro. Albert: Allow me to say that I am more prone to speak approvingly than...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Massachusetts, Ayer, June 5, 1878" TEIform="index"/>Ayer, Mass. June 5, 1878</dateline><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, Elijah" TEIform="persName"/>Elijah Myrick</byline><p TEIform="p">Dear Bro. Albert: Allow me to say that I am more prone to speak approvingly than
                                otherwise. And you may be sure of my appreciation of the improved appearance, manner and
                                matter of The Shaker Manifesto. And then I can see the editor: the center of criticism,
                                of a very fastidious people; persevering and improving under such training. I begin to
                                fear (judging from the result) you are getting ahead of the rest of us in the school of
                                good experience. I would not attempt to measure experience with you in this regard. You
                                have both my sympathy and respect. I cannot tell you how pleased I was to have a visit
                                from our good Mother Eldress Antoinette, and Elder Frederick, who came to us in spirit
                                through medium of the S. M. We were and are inspired by their presence. We have to thank
                                you too for coming with them with your cogent query and more cogent answer in May No.
                                But I think you will pardon me in saying best of all was "An address to Leaders." That
                                is a subject if rightly considered, and heeded, is fruitful of great good. Where leaders
                                are placed over a people to whom they are not answerable but to whom that people are in
                                every way responsible, it is a delicate relation, a difficult position, and requires
                                great tact, wisdom and forbearance. The Office should be lost sight of by the individual
                                holding it; so far as authority, and superiority is concerned. And principle more than
                                order and assumption should bear influence in all official duties. There is a principle
                                .for which we should have supreme affection, and when assailed or neglected should at
                                once be defended by all. In as much as it is done unto the highest object of our
                                affections it is done unto us. While we would not be without leaders to whom "we, the
                                people," delegate executive authority, yet if this supreme affection for right—for
                                principle—and common interest is wanting, it can never be supplied by dint of authority.
                                The Parental is the only right form of government in my estimation. Parents' love and
                                affection for their children induces them to do all they can to build them up and
                                develop them into noble men and women. A source of laudable pride for which they have
                                laid down their lives—forgotten self. I am reminded of Jethro's advice to Moses. If we
                                are God's peculiar people it is by virtue, not by assumption. "Let's seek the truth
                                wherever found, On Christian and on heathen ground." Such are the thoughts suggested by
                                the article in The Shaker Manifesto.</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Amanda Deyo, Respected friend :— Your kind letter of invitation to attend your Peace                                     Meeting..." TEIform="index"/>Amanda Deyo, Respected friend:...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Mount Lebanon, May 15, 1878" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, May 15, 1878</dateline><p TEIform="p">Amanda Deyo, Respected friend :— Your kind letter of invitation to attend your Peace
                                Meeting, June 8, is received. We thank you for the friendly remembrance. At present, it
                                looks impossible to be present with you at that time and place. In heart and soul we are
                                with you in the Reforms you advocate—Temperance and Peace—They are your whole life—They
                                are episodes M^AJNTIIHESTO. <pb n="172" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> IT'S the: shaebe in our life. We have
                                other and still more radical Reforms to carry out, practically. At present, we are
                                engaged in materializing spirits from the inner world. Do you know that materialization
                                of spirits is one of the latent forces, under divine guidance, to put an end to human
                                wars ? Every good gift comes from God by ¦successive materializations. The earths are
                                the latest forms—the lowest. We have held Seances for a week, in a Room and Cabinet, got
                                up for the occasion. Each seance has exceeded the preceding one in interest and
                                marvelousness. We have had four different classes of spirits visit us. No. 1. are world
                                spirits. No. 2. are world spirits who have some Shaker faith and who come to be
                                instructed. No. 3. are ancient spirits of Prophets and Mediums who lived upon earth
                                thousands ol years ago. Their prophecies are now in process of fulfilment. They are
                                inspired by Christ Angels. They speak like orators by the half hour. They predict the
                                extinction of war, but •only by removing the causes of war. Among these they class,
                                first, perverted sexuality—second, killing and eating other animals. They say, human
                                mothers visiting slaughter houses, drinking blood etc. is the way to breed tigers.
                                Poverty, created by human selfishness—monopolizing the land, in particular, produces the
                                material for armies and navies. Landless people are supported from the soil, but
                                indirectly through the government. The Rulers Say to them, "If you learn war, as a
                                trade, and kill some of your own class of landless people, we will feed you— Otherwise,
                                we will let you starve to death—we want you dead some way— There are too many to eat and
                                propagate. We want to beget as many children as we please, and you must make room for
                                them." Such is the logic of facts. You work away at the trunk and branches of the Upas
                                tree of war. We put the axe of Divine Revelation to the root of war in our own
                                individual selves. In the Spirit World, all, who do this, are as sparks among stubble.
                                They react back upon earth and inspire Amanda Deyoes to bear a testimony beyond their
                                own lives and personal characters. But far more beyond the soul travel of their hearers.
                                It is the accumulated experience of humanity alone that will finally put an end to war
                                as a game for kings and aristocrats to play at—When they have killed people, by
                                destructive diet, by diseases, doctors and infernal wars, they bury them in grave-yards
                                and cemeteries, after inclosing them in air tight coffins, as near embalm them as they
                                can—build costly monuments, each one trying to outvie the other in pomp and pride— Thus
                                they do great harm to the departed spirit. A poor man dies, his body decomposes—he has
                                no monument to feed his pride and tie him to the grave-yard for his friends to come and
                                commune with him—He gets away from earth. The rich man dies and is imprisoned—
                                magnetically—in a costly air tight casket and monument. He cannot get away from earth
                                until the body decays and the monument dissolves by time aud the action of the
                                elements.Thus ever does truth come uppermost and ever is justice done. Souls, sent out
                                of the body by disease, doctors and war, will never res| until they have been avenged.
                                Judgment will be executed upon ev-il workMAJNTIinffiS'TO. <pb n="173" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                                SHAKER M.AJSITETESTO. 173 ers—The Judge of all the earth will do right by all who have
                                been wronged. Wicked people will be punished by their own evils, more effectually than
                                it could be done by any other means. One of the materialized spirits in a seance told
                                this story—"A woman stole a fleece of wool from a neighbor while picking it over, some
                                one knocked at the door. She took it down cellar to pick over, took cold and died, and
                                is now, in the spirit world, down in that cellar, picking over that wool, fearing to be
                                seen." When she confesses the theft and makes restitution, she will be released, not
                                before. It will be just so with warriors like Napoleon—They will be in a hell of their
                                own making. When you convert them to the peace principle, they repent and make
                                confession to all whom they have killed, or caused to be killed, they will find
                                mercy—not till then. Love to you, dear friends, from your Shaker co-operators.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>HOME TOPICS</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Atmospheric air" TEIform="index"/>Atmospheric air
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Atmospheric Air.—The air that passes out of our lungs is quite unfit to support life if
                                breathed again, even when mixed with ten times its bulk of pure air, therefore the air
                                of our sleeping and living rooms must be con- stantly changed or it will soon become
                                poisonous. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Perfumes of the essential oils..." TEIform="index"/>Perfumes of the essential oils...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Perfumes of the essential oils prevent the growth of the vegetation of mouldiness, by
                                which paste, ink and the like may be long preserved. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Coffee placed on a hot shovel..." TEIform="index"/>Coffee placed on a hot shovel...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Coffee placed on a hot shovel and carried through the house will destroy any unpleasant
                                odor, and purify the atmosphere. It is an excellent disinfectant. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="For grinding cutlery and edge tools..." TEIform="index"/>For grinding cutlery and edge tools...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">For grinding cutlery and edge tools, the stone should be dipped in water to prevent the
                                heating of the tools. Careful cutlers use oil for polishing instead of water, when using
                                grindstones of small diameter.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Printers' ink is a good adhesive..." TEIform="index"/>Printers' ink is a good adhesive...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Printers' ink is a good adhesive for leather belts. One application will keep a leather
                                belt in running order for twelve months. </p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="For the toothache" TEIform="index"/>For the toothache
                            </head><p TEIform="p">For the Toothache.—The application of the following remedy for toothache is said to be
                                efficacious in the most desperate cases, provided it be not connected with rheumatism :
                                Alum, reduced to an impalpable powder, two drachms; nitrous spirits of ether, seven
                                drachms ; mix them well and apply them to the tooth, </p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cinders in the eye" TEIform="index"/>Cinders in the eye
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Cinders in the Eye.—Put one or two grains of flaxseed in the eye, and bind a cloth over
                                the organ. In a short time the eye may be washed and the seeds and cinders removed. </p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A method of coating wood..." TEIform="index"/>A method of coating wood...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A method of coating wood with a varnish as hard as ; stone has been recently introduced ;
                                the ingredients are: forty parts of chalk, forty of resin and four of linseed oil, to be
                                melted together in an iron pot. One part of native oxide of copper and one of sulphuric
                                acid are then to be added, after which the composition is ready for use. It is applied
                                hot to the wood with a brush, in the same way as paint, and as before observed, becomes
                                exceedingly hard on drying. </p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To stop bleeding at the nose..." TEIform="index"/>To stop bleeding at the nose...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">To stop bleeding at the nose, says an exchange, exercise the jaws as if in the act of
                                mastication. In the case of a child give it something to chew—a piece of paper, for
                                instance. The motion of the jaw will stop the flow of blood. It is a sure remedy, simple
                                as it seems.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lime in the eye" TEIform="index"/>Lime in the eye
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Limb in the Eye.—The evil effects of lime in the eye are well known, plasterers and
                                white-washers not unfrequently having their eyes seriously injured, if not destroyed, by
                                    <pb n="174" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> ±74. THB SHAEBR the caustic power of the lime. Wells say; "If
                                the patient is seen soon after the accident, an effort should be made at once to
                                neutralize and wash out the lime by a weak solu- tion of vinegar, with a free use of the
                                syringe. Afterwards, cooling and anodyne lotions and general antiphlogistic treatment
                                should be adopted."</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hair tonic" TEIform="index"/>Hair tonic
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Haie Tonic.—-The following is commended as harmless and efficient:— Strong infusion of
                                black tea 1 pint. Bay rum 4 ounces. Oil of lavender 1 drachm. Alcohol 4 ounces.
                                Glycerine 4 ounces. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Saturate pails and tubs..." TEIform="index"/>Saturate pails and tubs...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Saturate pails and tubs with glycerine and they will not shrink. Hard water becomes
                                nearly soft by boiling. A piece of chalk will soften hard spring water.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>FARM and GARDEN</head><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Stable manure is good" TEIform="index"/>Stable manure is good
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">There is nothing better than stable manure, but not enough can be had. Muck
                                        is good if we get the right kind, fibrous and not too much decomposed. It may be
                                        profitably composted with stable manure, six or seven loads to one of the
                                        latter, with ashes and with salt. The coarse grass which grows on muck swamps,
                                        if piled up with it, helps decomposition. Salt was recommended as a good
                                        fertilizer for all kinds of fruit trees It helps to decompose plant food. Ashes
                                        are good, and leached ashes, 300 bushels per acre, are excellent on sandy soils,
                                        helping mechanical texture, and furnishing needed manurial elements.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Rural new yorker" TEIform="index"/>Rural New Yorker</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Use kerosene oil to cure scaly leg in fowls..." TEIform="index"/>Use kerosene oil to cure scaly leg in fowls...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Use kerosene oil to cure scaly leg in fowls. The moment a fowl shows signs of the
                                plague—the scales of the legs become of a whitish slate color and curl upward a
                                little—fill an old fruit-can full of oil and immerse the legs of the fowl in it up to
                                the feathers. If matter has already gathered, the oil will loosen it and it can be
                                scraped off. Of course, it is a painful operation and the bird may suffer with sore legs
                                for a day or two. The experiments of Vcelcker show that farmyard manure does not lose
                                much by exposure to air, heat and light. The de- terioration which illy-managed
                                manureheaps undergo is principally due to losses by drainage. The dark-colored liquid
                                which is often seen flowing away from badly-kept dung-heaps is rich in nitrogen,
                                phosphoric acid, and potash. It has been found through careful experiment that 100 loads
                                of dung kept in the usual wasteful manner were reduced at the end of 81 days to 73.3
                                loads, at the end of 285 days to 64.4 loads, 384 days to 62.5 loads, while at the end of
                                499 days the original 100 loads were reduced to 47.2 loads, sustaining a loss of 52.8
                                loads. Thus in sixteen months more than one half, and that the most valuable portion, of
                                the manure had disappeared, leaving a highly carbonaceous matter poor in all the
                                elements of fertility.</p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The French Journal d'agriculture pratique states that worms can always be got rid of..." TEIform="index"/>The French Journal d'agriculture pratique states that worms can always be got rid of...
                            </head><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Journal d'Agriculture Practique" TEIform="index"/>Journal d'Agriculture Practique
                            </bibl><p TEIform="p">The French Journal d'Agriculture Pratique states that worms can always be got rid of by
                                using for the plants water to which a tenth part of grated Horse Chestnut has been
                                added. Under this treatment, it is said, the worms must either fly or die.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>Selected</head><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What was his creed" TEIform="index"/>What Was His Creed</head><p TEIform="p"> He left a load of anthracite In front of a poor widow's door, When the deep snow, frozen
                                and white, Wrapped street and square, mountain and That was his deed; [moor. He did it
                                well; "What was his creed?" I cannot tell. Slest "in his basket and his store," In
                                sitting down and rising up ; MAJNTrF'ElSTO. <pb n="175" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER ±75 When
                                more he got he gave the more, Withholding not the crust and cup. He took the lead In
                                each good task; "What was his creed?" I did not ask. His charity was like the snow,
                                Soft, white and silken in its fall; Not like the noisy winds that blow From shivering
                                trees the leaves ; a pall, For flower and weed, Dropping below, "What was his creed?"
                                The poor may know. He had great faith in loaves of bread For hungry people, young and
                                old; And hope-inspired kind words he said, To him he sheltered from the cold. For he
                                must feed As well as pray. "What was his creed?" I cannot say. In words he did not put
                                his trust, In faith his words he never writ; He loved to share his cup and crust With
                                all mankind who needed it. In time of need A friend was he. "What was his creed?" He
                                told not me. He put his trust in heaven, and Worked ever on with hand and head; And what
                                he gave in charity Sweetened his sleep and daily bread. Let us take heed, For life is
                                brief! "What was his creed?" "What his belief?"</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hawkeye, Burlington" TEIform="persName">Burlington Hawkeye</persName></byline></div3><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Giving one's life" TEIform="index"/>GIVING ONE'S LIFE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Thompson" TEIform="persName">DR. THOMPSON</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">In the many excellent counsels to candidates for the ministry, given in lectures at New
                                Haven and elsewhere, I have met with nothing upon that power of the pastor which is of
                                all the most rare, the most delicate, the most potent—the power of a vivifying
                                personality. This is the moral analogue of that miracle of Christ which was perhaps the
                                most subtile and spiritual of all his wonders—that is, the most completely dissociated
                                from an open and formal manifestation of power. The woman who had suffered so much from
                                disease and so much more from costly but worthless remedies did not present herself to
                                Jesus for healing, nor so much as call upon him for help; but, feeling the magnetism of
                                his personality, and saying to herself, "If I may touch but his clothes, I shall be
                                whole," she stole behind him through the crowd, and touched his garment, "and
                                straightway the fountain of her blood was dried up, and she felt in her body that she
                                was healed of that plague." Jesus, "immediately knowing in himself that virtue had gone
                                out of him," turned and sought her, and blessed and confirmed her faith. The "virtue,"
                                the power of helping and healing, was in him as part of his personality, and ready to
                                answer the call of faith; and so quick and tender was his sympathy with a confiding
                                sorrow that he was instantly conscious when his strength was drawn upon for relief. He
                                knew when virtue had gone out of him, though it had been drawn by the most silent, timid
                                touch. The text makes the sermon. Have a strength that will draw others to you with the
                                confidence of help. Have a sympathy which will make you conscious that, in giving help,
                                you have parted with something of yourself. This strength lies in thorough manliness, in
                                transparent honesty, in proved unselfishness, in clear and practiced judgment, in nicety
                                of honor, in broad and kindly thought and feeling for mankind, in energy of action . and
                                endurance for the right and the good, in supreme regard for truth and God. These are
                                attributes of personality; and he whose daily life, however modest and retiring,
                                witnesses to such qualities is certain to draw to him such as seek the strength of
                                counsel, the comfort of sympathy, the repose of con- fidence. Some of these qualities
                                are more natural to some men than to others, more in accord with temperament and with
                                circumstances of birth and training; but, wisely cultivated, they make a character like
                                the growth of an oak—hale and sturdy. MANIFESTO. <pb n="176" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER But a
                                strong personality alone would not fulfill the conditions of the text. The personality
                                must also be vivifying. With strength must be blended sympathy; and this not alone the
                                sympathy of impartation, hut the sympathy of participation. There is a sympathy, sincere
                                and helpful, which imparts relief in words and gifts. But far more precious and more
                                sustaining is the sympathy that makes the sorrow its own, and, in giving relief, gives
                                something of its own virtue, and feels the draft upon the inner source of life, which
                                was the sympathy of Christ. "He bore our griefs and carried our sorrows," and no virtue
                                could pass from him without his feeling that a part of his own life had gone forth to
                                heal, to cheer, to save the suppliant. In this qualitv, before all others, the minister
                                of Christ should study tobe like his Master : to give of his strength to the weak so as
                                to feel the giving, to give not words and alms, but soul and life. This is the greatness
                                of his calling—that he gives himself. His sympathy is the transfusion of his own strong,
                                warm heart into the veins of the weak and sinking, that by the virtue that goes out of
                                him others are made sound and strong. When I look upon the grand or the beautiful in
                                art, the sublime in Nature, or hear the finer, nobler strains of music, it is not simply
                                that an impression comes to me through the eye or the ear, which is thereafter to be
                                cherished as a pleasant remembrance. Far, far more than this. There enters into my
                                spiritual organization a new element of life and joy, which shall thenceforth abide with
                                me as a sub-conscious power. I shall be worth so much the more to others by the richness
                                of what I have seen and heard. So, too, when another nature engages my sympathy, I
                                incorporate that being with my own. Not only do I pity, counsel, help, I take up this
                                life into mine to cherish and vitalize with the spiritual forces of my own soul. The
                                minister preaches virtue in the moral sense; but his nobler function is to impart
                                "virtue," in the good old Bible sense of vivifying power. It is in this wise, indeed,
                                that he who would follow Christ may still take his life in Ms hand; for there is no
                                strain upon the vital forces like this conscious giving forth of "virtue." Study may
                                tell upon the thoughtfunction of the brain; but this sympathy strains the innermost
                                fibres of being. But he who thus sacrifices his own strength in a healing, saving
                                sympathy may die content, in that the virtue that has gone out of him has made of others
                                a new life and power. — The Independent.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/> BOOK TABLE</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religio philosophical journal" TEIform="index"/>l</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Business calculator and accountants' assistant" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Buddhism and Christianity face to face; or an oral discussion between the Rev. Migettuwatte,                                     a Budhist priest, and Rev. D. Silva, and English clergyman" TEIform="index"/></head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Peebles, J. M." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Law of population" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Champions of the church" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Principles of light and color" TEIform="index"/></head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Babbitt, E. D." TEIform="persName"/>E. D. Babbitt </byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> "The Religio Philosophical Journal" grows decidedly enterprising. Its present volume
                                exceeds in value any previous one. It abhors frauds. It exposes spiritual tricksters,
                                and thereby gains confidence of honest thinkers. It has no special "Message Department,"
                                (and we are glad of it;) and by this exception, gives less cause for suspicions that
                                frauds through its columns are perpetrated. It gives plain, proven, spiritualistic
                                facts, and is worthy of having its legions of friends multiplied. Address as above,
                                Chicago, 111. "Business Calculator and Accountants' Assistant." Such is the title of a
                                very valuable book. Its best features exist in the fact, that it is most useful to the
                                common people— the farmer, mechanic, storekeeper and those who have but little
                                education—an.l tells all one needs to know in very short space. It contains hundreds of
                                such common truisms : How to measure capacities of cisterns, grain bins, corn houses ;
                                surfaces; solids ; interest tables ; commission; and is withal a book for every business
                                man, and would be considered an invaluable present by any aspiring, intelligent boy. Its
                                price is one dollar. Ordered through this office, in connection with the Manifesto both
                                can be had for the same price. BUDDHISM AND CHRISTIANITY FACE TO FACE; or an oral
                                Discussion between the Rev. Migettuwatte, a Buddhist Priest, and Rev. D. Silva, an
                                English Clergyman with an Introduction and Annotations, by J. M. Peebles, M. D. London:
                                published by James Burns, 15 Southampton Row, 1878.</p><pb n="177" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><p TEIform="p">This is a discussion in which the merits of the two "Bibles," Sanscrit and Hebrew, are
                                compared by two of their ablest advocates ; and we think all ' candid minds, in perusing
                                these pages, will be convinced of the fact, that the disciple of Buddha advanced far
                                more logical proofs in favor of his religion and far more damaging testimony against the
                                claims of his opponent, than the representative of Christianity could bring forward on
                                his side ; and this, too, by one of the ablest minds engaged in the effort to "convert
                                the heathen." Beligio Phil. Journal. The Law of Population: This work is too valuable a
                                pamphlet to pass by with slender comments. While we do not endorse some of its
                                suggestions, we deem the subject a weighty one, and will treat of it hereafter. Asa K.
                                Butts, Publisher, New York. Relief to Labor: "Settling our lands with the laborer, the
                                best substitute for a standing army." This is a speech by Benjamin F. Butler, and is
                                very worthy of careful consideration. We return thanks to the Congressman for early
                                copy. R. J. Wright, an eminent writer upon social subjects has sent us a work of less
                                than a score of pages upon the above subject. The leaven is working. True Communism will
                                prevail. We would here herald two forth-coming works of great interest: "¦The Champions
                                of The Church" by D. M Bennett, 141 Eighth St. New York; and " The principles of light
                                and color" by B. D. Barrett, D. M. same address. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kimbal, Jacob" TEIform="index"/>Jacob Kimbal
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> At North Union, Ohio, May 2, 1878, <persName reg="Kimbal, Jacob" TEIform="persName">Jacob
                                Kimbal</persName>, aged 65 years.</p><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ketchel, Joanna" TEIform="index"/>Joanna Ketchel
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Ketchel, Joanna" TEIform="persName">Joanna Ketchel</persName> departed this life at Mount
                                Lebanon, N. Y., May 25, 1878. Nearly 82 years of age.</p><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phillips, Freeman" TEIform="index"/>Freeman Phillips
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> At North Union, Ohio, June 3, 1878, <persName reg="Phillips, Freeman" TEIform="persName">Freeman
                                Phillips</persName>, aged 76 years, 9 months, and 8 days.</p><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gould, Samuel" TEIform="index"/>Samuel Gould
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> At Shakers, N. Y. June 7, <persName reg="Gould, Samuel" TEIform="persName">Samuel Gould</persName> late of
                                Troy, N. Y-, aged 49 years.</p><p TEIform="p"/></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial Notes.</head><p TEIform="p"> We are using a number of The Bickford Knitting Machines; and they are very satisfactory
                            indeed, Being among "the wonders in this age" of machinery. Their utility and expedition in
                            business should be exp e rienced by all, at so small cost. Material for Fences of wood
                            variety is getting scarce. We must soon accept the alternative of no fences, or rely on the
                            metal ones offered us by Washburn, Moen Co. We are at a loss to speak as yet, of the best
                            Wat eb Wheel ; but we are at no loss to say that the firms of Leffel &amp; Co. and N. F.
                            Burnham, who enter into friend-, ly competition in our columns, are both most honor able
                            Oftentimes, we are led to regret, that there are unscrupulous persons, who, realizing the
                            solid benefits of judicious advertising, will use it most freely on some useless or worse
                            than useless articles, and soon retire with fortunes of ill-earned gains. But we can still
                            point to thousands who by a wholesome judicious judgment, have used advertising to their
                            exceeding profit! and to the most creditable advancement of useful materials. Such, we
                            believe our patrons to be. We have taken considerable and particular pains to acquaint
                            ourself with Dr. Frazier's remedies, and find from those using them, only a good report. His
                            Bitters are purely medicinal, and not an intoxicant beverage. Elder James S. Prescott gives
                            his endorsement of Dr. Frazier's Cough Remedy—and he is good authority. We find Stinson and
                            Co. very honorable in their dealing. Try them. We hope "everybody and his neighbor" will
                            send us six cents for a copy of "Plain Talks;" or ten cents, for two copies post paid. It is
                            a pretty book. Please procure it and present it to your friend.</p></div2><pb n="178" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Faith and hope" TEIform="index"/>FAITH AND HOPE</head><p TEIform="p"> CANAAN, N. Y. 1. Our journey through time may seem lengthened By the 2. We will brave the
                            rough storm on the river, And we'll 3. We may feel that our burdens depress us, That the
                            harrowing burdens of strife, And our pilgrim staff may be heed not the billowy spray,
                            For it may be an angel cross is too heavy to bear, Do we think that a bright crown broken
                            While climbing the highway of life ; But the hope of stands ready To anchor us safe in
                            the bay ; Far away on awaits us The meed for true labor and prayer ? O ! the faith of
                            MANIFESTO. <pb n="179" id="p29" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. those beautiful lands, the evergreen shores, the martyrs we need, Out stretched on the Where Jordan shall Lest we walk
                            the dark mountains of peacefully valley tin God The roll, There shod, And soul's finite
                            brightly an fail of the vision expands To see the heavenly road. Eden shall bloom,
                            The long sweet home of the soul, hope that will lead Thro'joy and sorrow to God.</p></div2><!--
                    <div2 type="section">
                    <pb id="p30"/>
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[advertisements deleted]</p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>