<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm1703" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">23</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">17</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">03</biblScope><date value="18870301" TEIform="date">March 1887</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">49-72</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="17" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="03" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!-- 
<pb id="p1"/>
MARCH.
THE
MANIFESTO.
Published by the United Societies,
" Every plant which my heavenly Father hath not planted shall be rooted
up." - -Matt. XV, 13.
SHAKER  VILLAGE,  N.  H.
1887.

<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
CONTENTS.
The Gospel Testimony,
Spiritual Communism,
Come out of tlie Mud,
Kiiijjdi>m of God,
Jo\ in ihe Cross,
Kcccssity of Expansion,
IlcvivaU,
Causes of Unbelief,
God's Host,        .  - -
Notes- -Christianity,
Ideal Sleeping Room, Letter- - Ernest Pick,
Live for Something,
Limitation Act,
Christian Brotherhood,
On tlje Wiiy,       1 One Tiling I Know,
Eqnalitv,
Keeping Unspotted,
Kind Words,          -    .
Revelation,
Books & I'apers,   - -
Deaths,                     ' 49
52
53
57
58
60
03
M
65
88
8"
08
69
n
After Forty years'
experience in tho
preparation of more
1hiin One Hundred
Thousand implications for patents in
the United Mutes iir.d Koreicn conntries, the publishers of the Scientific
American continue to net as Po'icitoru
for patents, caveats, trade-murks, copyriishls. etc.. for the United Stntes. and
to obtain patents in Canada, England, France,
Germany, and all other countries Their experience is uriequaled and their facilities are unsurpassed.
Drawings and specifications prepared and filed
in the 1'at.ent Oflioe oti short notice, Terms very
reasonable. No charge for examination of models
or drawings     Advice by mail free
Patents obtained through Mnnn & Co.aro noticed
in the SCIENTIFIC AftTEttlC AN, which has
the largest circulation and is the moat influential
newspaper of its kind published in the world.
The advantages of such a notice every patentee
understands
This larsre nnd ppipmlidlv il'nstrnfed newspaper
Is published WEEKLY*; $3.00 a year, nnd is
admitted to be the best paper devoted to science
mechanics, inventions, engineering works and
other departments of industrial progress, publis ed in any country. It contains the names of
all patentees and title of even invention patented
each week. Try it four months for ono dollar.
Sold by all newsdealers.
If you have an  invention  (o  patent write to
Munn A Co., publishers ot' Suientitio American,
361 Brondwny. New York
Handbook about patents mailed rreo.
SENDf0ne^rIlhsiratea CATALOGUE
\ egviaoie. Slower, Kieid tfj jcr *- - - - sr% ^
I'ants. Bulbs Implem'is. - -3 EL &Z> BJ'O
C O CT fC   hy inafl on application.
- -    - -%. b. Im  Don't neglect writing for It.
HIRAM SIBLEY & CO.
ROCHESTER, U. Y.        CHICAGO, ILL
322-S23 S. Main Ct.
12-11II. Clsri Ct.
e?>TH
SEWING-MACHINE
HAS NO EQUAL.
PERFECT SATISFACTION
Hew Home Sewing Machine Co.
- -ORANGE, MASS.- -
30 Union Square, N. Y.   Chicago, 111.   St. Louis, Mo.
Allinla, Ca.   Dallas, Tex.   San Francisco, Cd.
KOR  SALE   BY
<pb n="" id="p"/>
Vol. XVII.
MARCH,  1887.
No. 3. --><pb n="25" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gospel testimony of Mother Ann Lee and the elders, William Lee and James Whittaker no. 12" TEIform="index"/> The Gospel Testimony of Mother Ann Lee and the Elders, William Lee and James Whittaker.
                            No. 12.</head><p TEIform="p"> Published expressly for the several Covimundties of Believers in IS 16. Re-written by Henry
                            C. Blinn. Mother Ann and the Elders, visit Ashfield, Mass. "We forbid that woman, Ann Lee,
                            and those Elders ever to enter the town of Enfield again. You are very fortunate in escaping
                            puuishment at this time, and if you should ever come again, you may expect tarring,
                            feathering and ducking. " The officer ordered the speech to be closed, and after a few
                            timely words the mob dispersed. He then jumped on board the boat and crossed the river with
                            the Believers. On landing he was made the recipient of grateful acknowledgements from Mother
                            Ann and her companions, for his great kindness to them, in their affliction. Such a
                            manifestation of regard, to those who were entire strangers, was not often to be met on the
                            journey of life. Such generosity on his part to protect the Believers from the abuse of an
                            angry mob, was, indeed a miraculous interposition of divine Providence. Leaving the boat the
                            young man passed on his way. Subsequently it was ascertained that the young officer was.
                            Elijah Janes of Lansingburgh, N. YHe was at the time of this incident a* lieutenant in a
                            regiment of dragoons. Being out on business he was providentially led through the town, just
                            at the time of the above mentioned occurrence, and was an instrument in the hands of" God to
                            protect the Believers from the. cruelty of mob violence. Mother Ann in speaking of this re*
                            markable deliverance would often say&gt; "God sent that young man to aid in our
                            protection and deliverance." The Believers passed on to West Springfield, and then recrossed
                            the river and entered Kingston. David Meacham who had accompanied them to this place,
                            returned to his home, in Enfield, to obtain a carriage, for the better accommodation of the
                            company. At Kingston they made a tarry over one day, the Sabbath, and then moved or* to
                            Granby and visited some Believers in that place. They then entered the town of Belcher and
                            on to the town of Montague. In Montague they stopped at the home of Peter Bishop, whose
                            familj had accepted the faith. Peter was sur-<pb n="50" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> rounded by unbelieving
                            neighbors, and some of these were very unkind to them, on account of their faith. This
                            little famil/ of the church of Christ - -were often exposed to the abuse and injustice of
                            those who threatened to starve them by withholding from them all opportunity of earning
                            their living. Their occupation was weaving, coloring - -and pressing cloth.f Mother Ann made
                            inquires of Abigail (the mother of the family) concerning their temporal circumstances.
                            Abigail replied, "We have but little,*' and then related how they were threatened by some of
                            their neighbors. Mother Ann in reply to this, said, *' Keep your faith in God : I pray that
                            your morsel of meal may be like that of the widow, and like the cruise of oil that did not
                            fail in the time of famine : Trust in God and you will never want for bread. The children of
                            this world will feed you; they will make good measure, pressed down, heaped up and running
                            over, will men measure unto you." Abigail received new courage to trust an the word of God.
                            A few days alter this, a man came to the house and brought some grain, with which to pay a
                            debt. As he measured the grain, Abigail observed that he heaped every measure and pressed it
                            down, and then filled it till it run over. She now rejoiced at God's abounding goodness, and
                            in the fulfillment of the Word spoken to her by Mother Ann. From this date the family always
                            had a plenty and the neighbors became better friends. The Believers remained in Montague o
                            jTius little incident has in it a peculiarly interesting phase, as it represents a system of
                            religious boycotting that occurred more than one hundred years ago. only one night and then
                            traveled on to Sunrlerland. Crossing the river they went to Ashfield and tarried at the
                            house of Asa Bacon. This was a place of retirement. They were away from the clamor of
                            riotous mobs, and the retreat seemed like a great blessing of God. For two months they
                            enjoyed this quiet, having requested the Believers not to disturb them by frequent visits,
                            lest it should create a disturbance among the people and bring on a persecution. They go
                            from this place to Shelburne and call at the home of Aaron Wood. The Believers had been
                            particularly requested to come and see Aaron and had extended some encouragement to the
                            family. As it was distant only five miles they concluded to walk. In the company was Mother
                            Ann, Mary Partington, Elder William Lee, Elder James Whittaker and two Brethren. It was a
                            joyful visit to the whole family and especially to good brother Aaron. His life was in God,
                            and to this work of the gospel of Christ, he devoted both soul and body. As a special
                            ministration he had received many beautiful gifts of the spirit. The company tarried in this
                            place several days and then returned to Ashfield. On the 20th of May they returned to
                            Harvard and during the Summer visited Shirley and Woburn, teaching, strengthening, and
                            encouraging the Believers, to a faithfulness in the work of God. But the spirit of
                            opposition was still restless. The enemies of the cross still thirsted for persecution. The
                            stale charge of foes to the country, fire arms and implements of war, was again renewed as a
                            pretext; nor could they be satisfied short of expelling the testi-<pb n="51" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> mony
                            with all its witnesses from the country. Id the month of July a number of men convened and
                            appointed a committee to post advertisements in several towns and notify the people to meet
                            on Harvard common, and arrange to drive off the Shakers. The advertisements were posted, and
                            the people met on the day appointed. Deacon Fairbanks of the Presbyterian church, accounted
                            the best church member and the greatest Christian in the town of Harvard, sent two barrels
                            of cider to the meeting that the mob might have something to stimulate their zeal. As it was
                            time for the ministers to hold their meeting, the mob were requested to wait -till the
                            Shakers had been seen by them. A committee of four evangelical Pastors were appointed who
                            wrent to the Square House to confer with the Elders, Zabdiel Adams from Lunenburg was the
                            speaker. He asked if there was liberty to suggest a few questions. "Yea," replied Elder
                            James, " any civil questions. " Adams then observed that the people were apprehensive that
                            war like stores were laid up in this house, (Square House) and manifested much concern about
                            it. Elder James who was convinced that they did not believe the charge which they had made,
                            and that it was a mere pretext, replied, "There is liberty to search the house, if you can
                            do it and not wrong your consciences. I repeat, there is liberty to search the house from
                            attic to cellar, if you can do it and not wrong your consciences. " Adams then, addressing
                            the Believers asked, "Are you willing to take up arms against Britain ? " Father William
                            replied, " I have never killed a creature with a gun in my life." "But," said Adams, "Are
                            you friends to America ? " " Yea, " replied Elder James, "we are friends to all the souls of
                            men." "But supposing," said Adams, "one of your people should go into the war and should
                            live to return home again, would he not have to confess it as a sin?" " Yea, surely,"
                            replied Elder James, "if he, himself believes it to be a sin ; but we do not bind me- -'s
                            consciences. " Adams then turning to Aaron Jewett, said, "When you confessed your sins, did
                            you not confess your going into the army as a sin ? " Aaron replied, " I was so far from
                            confessing it as a sin, that 1 never once thought of it. " Many other inquiries were made,
                            which were all promptly and judiciously answered by Elder James and others. The principle
                            object of these interrogations seemed to be to find out the opinion of the Elders,
                            respecting the war, in order to satisfy themselves concerning the general rumors, that the
                            Believers were enemies to the country. Elder James answered them plainly and pointedly
                            respecting this matter. That Believers had nothing to do with the war one way or the other,
                            but said he, "We will fight your enemy, and the enemy of all mankind; that is, the spirit of
                            evil. " After a lengthy conversation on the subject, Elder James suggested that the
                            Believers should sing a hymn, and there was soon a union gift. He then invited the Ministers
                            to dine at the Square House, but they declined, as they must return to the mob, that was
                            waiting to hear the l'eport. It <pb n="52" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> was subsequently learned that all were
                            advised to relinquish their design and let the Shakers alone. One of the Ministers asked
                            Adams what he thought of the Shakers. lie replied, "I think the people better let the
                            Shakers alone." This advice occasioned considerable confusion among the restless characters
                            that formed the mob. Some were urgent to proceed but as the town officers had asked for
                            paper and ink, it was rumored that they expected, to take down the names of all present.
                            This ga- -e them a fright and they began to disperse without doing any violence. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spiritual communism" TEIform="index"/> SPIRITUAL COMMUNISM.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/> MARTHA J. ANDERSON.</byline><p TEIform="p">" Seek first the Jcingdom of God and his righteousness, and all these (material) things will
                            he added thereto." Matt, vi., 23. This divine ideal of life, conceived by the spiritual mind
                            of the lowly iNazarene, was no less than the foundation atone of the superstructure of true
                            communism, which in its truest meaning and effective working, must result in the highest
                            social and spiritual progress, and when it accomplishes this, material benefits are a
                            natural sequence. And who shall form the kingdom of God? An aggregation of souls striving
                            for perfection; animated by a noble spirit of heroic sacrifice and deep earnestness of
                            feeling; having ever this object in view, the uplifting and advancement of humanity in all
                            that is righteous and virtuous; ever realizing in all their efforts, that self-abnegation is
                            the first round on the ladder of progress ; and that greatest service flows through humblest
                            deeds. "For he that would be great among you, let him be the servant of all. " And his
                            righteousness; which is equity, truth and equality; "no high nor Ioav, no rich nor poor."
                            Yielding perfect obedience to the moral and physical law of our being ; also to the higher
                            spiritual law, which cuts souls off from the natural generative life, and makes them iu
                            reality the children of the new kingdom. A modern communist has said, that " Those who agree
                            in what constitutes a righteous life, will inevitably group themselves together, regardless
                            of their differences in education, philosophical views and social standing; and this
                            agreement, together with the earnest desire to be assisted by others, in the work of
                            self-improvement, will cement the community into an organic body. The religion of the gospel
                            of Christ is the abolition of selfishness. "Go sell all that thou hast, give to the poor,
                            and come follow me," i.s ever a hard saying to those whose hearts are attached to worldly
                            gains ; but those who obey, are fully recompensed, receiving the hundred fold increase
                            promised to those who forsake all for the higher life. Under the inspiration of this
                            ennobling spirit, true believers are resolved in one brotherhood and sisterhood; growing
                            away from the contracting influences that bind an individual, and limit his or her interests
                            merely to natural kith and kin ; for it enlarges the sphere of the affections, and increases
                            life's duties of love and fidelity to all who may come within the limit of our philanthropic
                            labor. They who gather themselves* together merely for the acquisition of material wealth,
                            fail in their attempts at organi-<pb n="53" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> zation, as lias been proved over and
                            over again, because self-aggrandizement predominates. " Gather yourselves together and I
                            will break you in pieces," said the spirit by the mouth of the prophet of old. Why? because
                            of the false foundations of their association. Ouly those who are prompted by a high moral
                            impulse to subdue the selfish appetites and propensities, that cause division, strife and
                            animosity among mankind, can form the divine fraternity, in which only angelic relations
                            shall be sustained. Truly God's kingdom, whose law is pure love, whose inheritance is
                            abiding peace, security and abundance, for soul and body. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Come out of the mud" TEIform="index"/> COME OUT OF THE MUD.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/> DANIEL FRASER.</byline><p TEIform="p"> [Compiled from (lie "(jouI of Time" for the Manifesto.] " Odt from the mud my brothers ! Or
                            is it better still to toil and moil Through miry ways, only to seem to rise By trampling
                            down each other- -such a rise Sinking us but the deeper. "We are no angels brothers- -well
                            we know We are no angels : let us live by law ! And as our fathers fell from love to rule,
                            Climbing by law, we put ourselves to school And reach a surer heaven than they lost. The
                            Golden City John in Patmos saw In vision, is no vision now to us. In very fact I see it
                            coming down From heaven to earth- -the city of our hope. I see no temple there, for every
                            one Is there a temple. Sacred every place, There every act is worship; every thought a
                            [prayer. I see no priests, for all are priests; no king, For all are kings; no law but love,
                            and that Is written on the hearts of men. No work is menial, and no state is low, And
                            meanest vessel of the common weal Is holy; for all is holy, holy in its ends. O glorious
                            sight! 0 bright abode of consummated joys Where life is one perpetual dance and song And
                            jubilant procession ! [wants " Very well for angels, but not suited to our We men and women
                            of clay ! No ! No !" " Give us a human city," say 3re? Well, 1 grant this city is heaven ;
                            but not, the less 'Tis earth and heaven also. Only those Who make a heaven on earth, as best
                            they can Will find a heaven hereafter : human all Arc angels' joys, for angels are but men
                            Advanced to perfect manhood. What say ye brothers? Is it worth our while To bate a little of
                            our selfish aims, * And budge a step or two for such a prize? Hoping that the enclosed may
                            be profitable I have the happiness to be ever your friend. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kingdom of God" TEIform="index"/> THE KINGDOM OF GOD.</head><p TEIform="p"> That the prophets were interested in the promises of God, to Israel, we may learn from ]
                            Peter, i., 7, 10, 13. It was of a future glorious kingdom that was to be set up on the
                            earth. They searched diligently to know what the spirit of Christ signified, as it testified
                            of his sufferings and also of his glory. Unto vrhora it was revealed that not unto
                            themselves, but unto us did they minister those things. Us upon whom the ends of the world
                            have come. These prophecies were given for instruction to these who are to be the actors in
                            their fulfilment, that they might be of the wise that should understand. "Many shall be
                            purified and made whole and tried, but the wicked shall do wickedly; and none of the wicked
                            shall understand, but the wise shall understand." Dan. xii., 10. These promises were also
                            given that God's people might understand the signs of the times in which they lived. If God
                            promised to set up a kingdom on the earth, he also promised that the saints should possess
                            it. Is it not important for us to know of the time in which God promised to set up his
                            kingdom on the earth? If the prophecy has been fulfilled, may we not be ignorant of the
                            fact, and be left to wonder and perish? Hav-<pb n="54" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> ing no oil in our lamps and
                            yet waiting for the Bridegroom. "For as a thief shall he come. " "And as a snare shall it
                            come on ail them that dwell on the face of the whole earth." Luke ii., 34, 35. It is evident
                            that Nebuchadnezzar's dream of the image, and Daniel's explanation, (Dan. ii.) his after
                            visions of the beasts, (vii., 8.) and John's visions of the beasts, (Rev. xii., 13.) are
                            prophetic histories of the same powers and are given more definitely, as we pass down the
                            course of time. They were given, no doubt, for a wise purpose, that the wise need not walk
                            in darkness. Four universal kingdoms were to be set up on the earth, and before the fourth
                            should pass away, God would set up a kingdom which should never be destroyed. (Dan. ii.,
                            44.) It may be duty to search diligently into these promises and see what may be learned
                            from them. In the second chapter of Daniel we have the explanation of the king's dream. He
                            says, ''Thou, 0 king art a king of kings for the God of heaven hath given thee a kingdom,
                            power and strength and glory and wheresoever the children of men dwell, the beasts of the
                            field and the fowls of heaven, hath be given into thine hand, and hath made thee ruler over
                            them all. Thou art this head of gold. " Dan. ii.. 87, 38. We need no further evidence to
                            establish the first kingdom and that it is Babylon, B. C. 603. The s &gt;cond kingdom.
                            "His breast and his arms were of silver. " Dan. ii., 32. This was Media and Persia, as we
                            learn from the following:- - -" Belshazzar, the king, made a great feast to a thousand of
                            his lords, and drank wine before the thousand, " "In the same hour came forth fingers of a
                            man's hand, and wrote over against the candlestick upon the plaster of the wall, of the
                            king's palace." Dan. v., 25, 28. That night Belshazzar, the king of the Chaldeans was slain,
                            and Darius the Median took the kingdom. J5y this conquest the first kingdom passed into that
                            of the second, B. C 538. "Four great beasts came up from the sea, diverse one from the
                            other. The first, like a lion, had eagles' wings; I beheld till the wings thereof were
                            plucked, and it was lifted up from the earth, and made to stand upon the feet as a man, and
                            a man's heart was given to it." Dan. vii., 8, 4. Babylon in its glory was like a lion,
                            soaring with eagles' wings, hut in Belshazzar's time, it lost its wings and became weak as
                            the heart of man. "And behold another beast, a second, like to a bear, and it raised up
                            itself on one side, and it had three ribs in its mouth, between its teeth, and they said
                            unto it, arise, devour much flesh." Dan. vii., 5. Ancient historians stigmatize the Medes
                            and Persians as the greatest robbers and spoilers that ever oppressed the nations. "I saw
                            and behold there stood before the river a ram which had two horns. And the ram pushed
                            westward, northward and southward, so that no beast might stand before him, neither was
                            there any that could deliver out of his hand; but he did according to his will and became
                            great." Dan. viii., 3, 4-. The angel Gabriel explained to Daniel that the two horns were the
                            kings of Media and Persia. This vision took place, B. C. 555, two years after the vision of
                            the lion, bear and leopard. The head of gold and the lion representing Babylon, were of no
                            farther use in the vision and according to Lightfoot, Townsend and other eminent
                            chronologists, it was after the fall of Babylon, hence, Daniel was in Shushan the capital of
                            Persia, ^hus Media and Persia are established to be the second kingdom, B. C. 538. The third
                            kingdom was Grecia. "His belly and thighs of brass. And another third kingdom of brass that
                            shall bear rule over all the earth." Dan. ii., 82, 80. "After this I beheld, and lo, another
                            like a leopard, which had upon the back of it, four wings of a fowl; the beast had also four
                            heads, and dominion was given to it. " Dan. vii., (5. " And as I was considering behold a
                            goat came from the west, on the face of tiie whole earth, and touched not the ground; and he
                            had a notable horn between his eyes, and he came to the ram that had two horns, and ran into
                            him in the fury of his power, and smote him, and brake his two horns : and there was<pb n="55" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> no power in the ram to stand before him, but he cast him down to the
                            ground and stamped upon him." "Therefore the goat waxed very great, and when he was strong
                            the great horn was broken ; and for it came up four notable ones, toward the four winds of
                            heaven." Dan. viii. Gabriel informed Daniel that the goat was Grecia, and that the great
                            horn was the first king; and history informs us that the king was Alexander. "The great horn
                            being broken (by the death of Alexander the Great) for it came up four notable ones. " The
                            four horns are four kingdoms that shall stand up out of the nation, towards the four winds
                            of heaven. ' Macedonia, west; Thrace, north: Syria, east and Egypt, south. "The goat came
                            from the west, (so did Grecia) on the face of the whole earth and touched not the ground,"
                            denoting swift flight. Grecia conquered Media, B. C. 331. The fourth and last kingdom must
                            have commenced according to the visions and prophecies at the end of the third. la this
                            fourth kingdom the God of heaven promised to set up his everlasting kingdom, and should not
                            the fulfilment of these prophecies and visions be to us a subject of the highest importance?
                            This establishes in our mind that Grecia was the third kingdom. " The fourth kingdom shall
                            be strong as iron; forasmuch as iron breaketh in pieces and subdueth all things." This
                            kingdom was weakened with potter's clay, and divided and thus became partly strong and
                            partly broken. " After this I saw in the night visions and behold a fourth beast, dreadful
                            and terrible, and strong exceedingly; and it had great iron teeth; it devoured and brake in
                            pieces, and it was diverse from all the beasts that were before it, and it had ten herns. "
                            Dan. vii., 7. The image had ten toes. The fourth beast shall be the fourth kingdom upon the
                            eartli, and the ten horns are the ten kings that shall arise. " Dan. vii., 23, 24. Thus far
                            the history of Rome corresponds with the visions. "I considered the horns, and behold, there
                            came up among them another little horn, before whom there were three of the first horns
                            plucked up by the roots, and behold, in the horn were eyes as the eyes of a man, and a mouth
                            speaking great things. " Dan. vii., 8. Daniel prayed to know the truth of the fourth beast
                            and received this answer. "These four beasts are four kings which shall arise out of the
                            earth. The fourth beast shall be the fourth kingdom upon eartli. And the ten horns out of
                            his kingdom are ten kings that shall arise, and another shall rise after them, and he shall
                            be diverse from the first, and he shall subdue three kings. " The ten horns which are ten
                            kings, arose as follows :- - - -1st The Huns, A. D. 35G. 2nd The Ostrogoths, A. D. 877. 3rd
                            The Visgoths, A. D. 378. 4th The Franks, A. D. 407. 5th The Vandals, A. D. 407. 6th The
                            Sueves, A. D. 407. 7th The Burgundians, A. D. 407 8th The Saxons, A. D. 47G. 9th The
                            Herulians, A. D. 476. 10th The Lombards, A. D. 483. Home arose at a later date and subdued
                            three. Ileruli in Italy, A. D. 493. The Vandals, A. D. 534 and the Ostrogoths in 538. We
                            need but compare St. John's visions of the beasts with Daniel's vision of the fourth beast
                            to-be convinced that they represent the same power. The red dragon having seven heads and
                            ten horns. The horns represent the same kingdoms, as do the toes. St. John saw a beast rise
                            up out of the sea, havi~~ seven heads and ten horns. " Rev. xiii., 8. "And these are seven
                            kings," denoting seven forms of Roman government. "And the beast which I saw was like a
                            leopard and his feet as the feet of a bear, and his mouth asthe mouth ot a lion; and the
                            dragon gave him his power and his seat and great authority. " Rev. xiii., 2. And there was
                            given him a mouth speaking great things and blasphemies, an power was given him to continue
                            forty and twomonths. " "And it was given him to make war with the saints and to overcome
                            them' and power was given him over all kindred* and tongues and nations. " All this agrees
                            with the seventh and eighth chapters of Daniel. - ' " And there went out a decree from
                            Caesar Augustus that all the world should be taxed." Luke ii., 1, 2, 3. At that time Joseph
                            and Mary went to be taxed. At which time Jesus was born. This establishes the fact that Rome
                            was the fourth kingdom. Although it may be tally established that<pb n="56" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> the
                            fourth beast of Daniel's visions and St. - -John's beasts were symbols of the Roman power
                            and last universal kingdom, and that in the day of these kings, the God of heaven - -would
                            set up his kingdom that should stand - -forever; and that the kingdom of God is already set
                            up, nevertheless, we wish to add a few more evidences as farther proof to those -who are
                            h-rd to convince, and are infidel and skeptical in divine revelation and inspiration. .No
                            stronger proof can b* given to the unbeliever in the word of God, than the prophecies that
                            have foretold future events, hundreds of years prior to their fulfilment, and yet have been
                            fulfilled to the letter. Most of vthe prophecies where time is given in days or months have
                            been fulfilled to the letter. A day signifying a year. It was so counted in Ezekiel. "Thou
                            shalt hear the iniquity of the house of Judah forty days. I have appointed thce each day for
                            a year. " It was so fulfilled iij the prophecy of the seventy weeks. "Seventy weeks are
                            determined upon thy people and upon thy holy city, to finish the transgression and to make
                            an end of sin, and to make reconciliation for iniquity, and to bring in everlasting
                            righteousness, :and to seal up the vision and prophecy, and : to anoint the Most Holy. "
                            "Know therefore and understand that - -from the going forth of tho commandment to .restore
                            and to build Jerusalem, unto the .Messiah, the Prince, shall be seven weeks, sthree score
                            and two weeks; the streets shall &gt;t&gt;e built again and the walls, even in
                            troublous times. " Dan. ix. This was in the year ;B. C. 457, and agrees with Nehemiah, iv.,
                            10. Now, seven, sixty and two weeks make sixty nine weeks, and seven days in a week make 483
                            days. Each day a year brings us from ..13. C. 457, to A. D. 20. Add twenty six to - -four
                            hundred and fifty seven and we have - -483. His birth occurring four years prior to A. D. 1,
                            would make him about thirty years - -of age. Jesus was baptized, A. D. 2G. Therefore it is
                            evident that the coming of the .Messiah, was at the baptism and not at the birth of Jesus.
                            This is established beyond - -dispute by Daniel ix. "And he shall confirm the covenant with
                            many for one week. " Seven days added to :26 and we have A. D. 33, the year that Jesus was
                            crucified. This fills out the seventy weeks, 490 days, in y^ars, from the time the decree
                            went forth to Ezra, B. C. 457. This establishes the authenticity of inspiration, visions and
                            prophecy, and it ought to convince the Jews, skeptics and infidels that Jesus Christ was the
                            promised Messiah. "And from the time the daily sacrifice shall be taken away, and the
                            abomination that maketh desolate set up, there shall be 1290 days." The daily sacrifice was
                            taken away in A. ]). 508, when the pagan kings we^e converted to Christianity. See Gibbon,
                            Vol. 3rd, page 262. To 508 add 1290 years and we have A. I). 1798, the year the Pope was led
                            into captivity. When the Pope lost his power we have established the ending - -f the 1290
                            days. " And the dragon gave his power unto the beast; and a mouth was given him speaking
                            great things and blasphemies, and power was given unto him to continue forty and two months,
                            12G0 days, beginning A. D. 538, add 12C0 and it brings us again, A. I). 1798, the end of the
                            beast. This is the same as in Daniel vil. The same persecuting power, wearing out the
                            saints, and it shall reign time 1, times, 2, and half time, %=3}4 years, 42 months or 12C0
                            years, ending in A. D. 1798. Is not the scattering of the holy people accomplished, and we
                            therefore beyond the time times, and half time? Did not those kings pass away from the power
                            and dominion of the fourth kingdom, and did not God promise to set up his everlasting
                            kingdom, in the days of those kings, while in the fourth kingdom? Is not the kingdom of God
                            now set up on the earth? When prophecies are in the past and fulfilled, and history has
                            sealed them to be true, may they not then be understood? And is it of no consequence that
                            God's people should know when the time has arrived in which he promised to give them the
                            kingdom? Had the Jews known the time of their prophecies and their fulfilment would they
                            have done as they did? And these being facts, is it not the duty, and in the interest of all
                            mankind to seek the kingdom of God and its righteousness? These prophecies were evidently
                            given for the good of God's people, or why were they given thousands of vears before the
                                events<pb n="57" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> were fulfilled? The time of the end has come, (Dan. xii.)
                            and the time has arrived for visions to be unsealed. The promise is, "Seek and ye shall
                            find; knock and it shall be opened unto you. For every one that asketh receiveth, and he
                            that seekethfindeth, and to him that knocketh it shall be opened. White Water, Ohio. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Joy in the cross" TEIform="index"/> JOY IN THE CROSS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Andrews, Watson" TEIform="persName"/>WATSON ANDREWS.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Let me sing of the joy in the cross, Of the joy in the gaia of my soul, Of the fire that
                            consumeth the dross And the love that is gaining control; O ! the pure gospel love That is
                            gained in this beautiful way. O the sweet gospel love, That in seeking we find day by day.
                            Let me tell of this beautiful way, Of this plan of redemption from wrong, That the thousands
                            who still are astray May return and unite in my song; All ye wand'ring of earth Who are
                            hung'ring and thirsting to-day All ye wand'ring of earth Ye may share in this beautiful way.
                            Do you thirst for the waters of life? Do you hunger for bread from above? Would you dwell
                            where the billows of strife Sink to rest in the calm of pure love? O ! then come to the
                            fount, To the fountain that's open and free, Come and drink at the fount, That is flowing
                            for you as for me; Come, and yield to the sway of the cross, Come, to pour out your spirits
                            in prayer, Come, to show up the depths of your loss And resign all to heav'ns high care;
                            There the blessing of God From this Fountain will flow to your souls, And to manifest God,
                            You will joyfully yield the control. North Union, Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Would we have a noble mind..." TEIform="index"/>Would we have a noble mind...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Would we have a noble mind we must entertain noble thoughts; the finest edifice would be a
                            nuisance if inhabited by nothing but vermin.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="C., A. J." TEIform="persName"/>- -A. J. C.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Necessity of expansion" TEIform="index"/> NECESSITY OF EXPANSION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, Oliver C." TEIform="persName"/>OLIVER C. HAMPTON. </byline><p TEIform="p"> One of the laws of the universe of finite beings and things is progress- -im-_ provement-
                            -evolution (i.e.) rolling out or unfolding from lower to higher degrees of perfection.
                            Between the finite spirit of man and the Infinite spirit of the All Good there is an eternal
                            attraction. This attraction subsists between all finite and Infinite conditions. This
                            attraction makes it possible for man and all other finite creatures and things to progress
                            to higher degrees of perfection. Higher and higher conditions of perfection, evolve higher
                            and higher conditions of hnppiness. In our rudimental life and sensuous existence we are
                            little better than unborn. "Wrapped about with the cerements of selfishness in which we have
                            been embalmed, and buried in the chaotic elements of the world (viz.) "The lust of the
                            flesh, the lust of the eye and the pride of life," we are exceedinglyhard to resurrect.
                            Nevertheless through the above named attraction, resurrection is possible. For in spite of
                            all drawbacks the blessed attraction of the l;ve of the Infinite Father and Mother is in
                            eternal and persistent energy and activity, and so, sooner or later we shall all be saved.
                            It may be- -nay- -will be "so as by fire" by sufferings, by constant self-sacrifice for the
                            good of others, but be of good cheer, we shall all be able in the long run to meet and bear
                            these, and go on to perfection. Now forms are evanescent and changeable, but principles are
                            eternal and unchangeable. Every discreet unfoldment of higher truth to finite man requires a
                            new form to ex-<pb n="58" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> press itself in. This is because it is some little
                            different from any thing which preceded it. Especially is this true of unimportant
                            externalities. Their present forms must give way to new ones as fast as any improvements
                            suggest themselves. It would be ridiculous to employ the old forms for the transmission of
                            nsAgs by the old methods since the truths and facts of the Telephone and Telegraph have been
                            reached by man. To be sure truth is truth and never changes, but man's finite apprehension
                            of it takes a new form every time he makes any progress towards perfection in higher and
                            better perceptions of the same. Forms, fashions, customs, external rules all have to bow to
                            the fiat of evolution and progress toward that which is more perfect. This need not alarm
                            the most conservative Believer. For unless we keep pace with the progress of the universe
                            our individual progress will be an impossibility. We shall be whirled,off at some side
                            station and relegated to the limbo of worn out- -superannuated and used up institutions. A
                            jacket with weather-boarding sown on to the lower end of it costing more time and labor than
                            the whole garment without, won't do in this day of economy of time and resources- -this day
                            of improvement in all - -directions. I suppose the most reasonable course for any to pursue,
                            lies between the two extremes of radicalism and conservatism just as it lies between all
                            other extremes. But we have a sure word of prophecy in the instructions from our good
                            Ministry of the Mother Church, who so far have led us in perfect safety and prosperity in
                            the exact degree to which we have yielded a filial obedience to their instructions. The
                            Christ of the universe is met face to face in that sublime order and organization
                            acknowledged and maintained among us even "God manifested in the flesh" by which the weaker
                            and less experienced are ministered to by those further advanced and these again by higher
                            and higher circles of intelligence, wisdom, and love. Our foundation rests upon this eternal
                            and impersonal principle and is impregnable to any and all assaults from below. And whatever
                            new forms or changes may be necessary to meet the continually changing scenes of time or
                            eternity inside or outside of Zion, will be made conducive to our well-being- -protection
                            and progress, so long as we adhere to this fundamental principle of organization and yield
                            unfailing obedience and allegiance thereto. Thus shall we escape the Scylla of conservatism
                            and death on the one hand, and the Charybdis of destruction through radicalism on the other.
                            I have lived a long time in strict compliance with this bedrock principle of organization
                            and it has never failed me in a single instance, but through its divine instrumentality I
                            have always been saved- -protected- -resurrected from rudimental conditions of sorrow and
                            unrest; and so I can safely recommend the same to all who hunger and thirst after
                            righteousness. Union Village, Ohio. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Revivals" TEIform="index"/> REVIVALS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Barrett, Andrew" TEIform="persName"/> ANDREW BARRETT.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Much has been said and written about a renewal of the pentecostal fire and spirit among the
                            people, to start anew that strong faith of our fathers and mothers, wherein the spirit of
                                convic-<pb n="59" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> tion would work in the soul to tell the individual the
                            difference between right and wrong. I don't see it come. What's the cause? Why does a
                            gracious Father withhold from his children bread for which they are perishing? As we pass
                            through Zion's decimated ranks, from death and apostasy to the principles, we read on the
                            countenances of. many that are left, discouragement. Should this be the case with those who
                            have through a long life stood by the principles of truth and purity? Occasionally we meet
                            the stinging epithet, you Shakers seem to be decreasing or ruuning out. What is the cause? A
                            quick response- -As we have been harvested from the worldly into the heavenly order- -the
                            works of the generative order are left behind, and this throws the responsibility upon you
                            to supply us with material to build up our societies. What do we find among the masses that
                            are sent among us from your order to become members of our institution? Not many are able to
                            comprehend ihe meaning of the principles upon which our society is based. A Virgin Life.
                            Community of interests and equality of the sexes ; the noblest and surest and only
                            principles whereon a society can stand and keep out the destructive wolf, selfishness, that
                            has broken to pieces so many organizations that have started with good heart but lo ! fell
                            to the ground for want of spiritual support. This they will have if based upon these
                            principles. Do you wonder that under these conditions our numbers are growing less ? The eld
                            and faithful veterans who have fought long in the struggle for right, are passing one after
                            another, over to their homes on the evergreen shores, and none coming in to fill their
                            places. Are you willing, friends, that principles as noble as these should be lost to the
                            world? Are not these the balancing wheel, the salt, the leaven, among mankind to still hold
                            them in union with the higher powers, and link them in the golden chain with the angels? Let
                            us start anew our revival spirit and let the young men and women of your cities, your towns
                            and villages pray again that the pentecostal fire and holy spirit may come down upon them to
                            show them that lust, pride, and worldly affection are not the elements of righteousness.
                            They are not of the spirit of Christ and no man or woman can live in that element and be a
                            true follower of the Christ spirit. Friends, we make an application to you. You whose souls
                            are hungering after a higher character than a worldly life has given you, to come and see if
                            there is not a healing balm in Gilead, (the Shaker order,) that you cannot find elsewhere.
                            To know of the doctrine whether it is of Christ or not you must come and prove it for
                            yourselves. Come, bearing these credentials. To shake yourselves from all prejudice, all
                            evil of every name and nature. Wishing to live a pure virgin life. Expecting to work out
                            your own salvation. Desiring to attain the highest good in this life. Thankful for a place
                            to control the appetites and passions and a willingness to confess all sin and stop sinning.
                            In this spirit we invite all who are willing to come and help us carry forward these
                            principles, the assurance of a happy home, and a blessed relationship where by obedience
                            they can work out a true Christian character.<pb n="60" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/>"We are few in numbers,
                            fewer we may be, but few or many our resolves are to hold on to the living faith and
                            principles which we have struggled so hard to maintain and we value more than our natural
                            lives. We often hear the cry, u Come down half way from your full cross and you will have
                            members enough to fill your ranks." But woe ! to Shakeriem should this be the case. Like
                            causes would produce like effects. There is uo more assurance of the success of our
                            institution than there was of the Oueida or Owenite only by living out the principles. Let
                            us put on the whole armor of God and make no compromise with tempting worldly overtures. If
                            we fail to do this, there will be another falling away of the church and another era of dark
                            ages inaugurated. Let us have another pentecostal revival. We can get it by prayer. When the
                            Holy Spirit came down upon the disciples in the temple they were having a prayer meeting.
                            The same labor and struggle will bring the same results in our day. "Ask and ye shall
                            receive, seek and ye shall find, knock and it shall be opened unto you." What could be more
                            plain and simple. Let us on the strength of these promises put our whole souls into the work
                            and success will crown our labors. Ayer, Mass. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My belief" TEIform="index"/> MY BELIEF.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hohman, Leopold" TEIform="persName"/> LEOPOLD HOHMAN.</byline><p TEIform="p"> An all embracing Mother heart and Father intellect Which permeating nature, universal,
                            endless space Is ever conscious of the tiniest creature's ends and aims Providing gifts of
                            love and wisdom with a lavish hand We're free to make or mar, to grovel, sit or soar Our
                            characters to build, our now returns no more. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Causes of unbelief" TEIform="index"/> CAUSES OF UNBELIEF.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bisbee, F. A." TEIform="persName"/> BY REV. F. A. BISBEE. </byline><p TEIform="p"> [Contributed by Geo. Wickerpham.] Three tirades of Itelig-ious Houl- -t- -Im. poNNiltle to
                            Kndorse Contradictions- - The True View of iod. the Hiltle a- -ul future Punishment. The
                            Rev. Frederick A. Bisbee, pastor of the Universalist Church of the Restoration, Master above
                            Sixteenth, preached to a good sized congregation yesterday morning on "Unbelief," from ihe
                            text, " Help Thou mine Unbelief, " Mark ix., 24. He said : Until there is a religious belief
                            common to mankind, every man must in some degree be an unbeliever. The orthodox Christian is
                            no less an unbeliever to the Mohammedan than the Mohammedan is to the Christian. But it is
                            not in this sense I use the word. Custom rather than dictionary defines terms, and in this
                            age and country an unbeliever is anyone who does not accept the view of Christianity
                            proclaimed by the popular churches. To those whose society is fixed largely by church
                            associations, it appears that all the world not only attends church, but attends their
                            church ; whereas, the proportion of Christians to the population of the world, about one
                            third, is about the ratio to express the proportion of believers to unbelievers in a
                            Christian community. It is no doubt startling to consider these figures in connection with
                            the fact that the terms believer and unbeliever, in the judgment of the majority of the
                            churches, mark not only a distinction in this life, but determine as well eternal happiness
                            and eternal misery in the world to come. And yet a knowledge of the facts will show that<pb n="61" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> these figures are not exaggerated. The seven hundred churches in this
                            great city cannot count in membership one third of the population, and seldom, if ever, have
                            that number in attendance, and even among the attendants there is to-day more or less
                            unbelief. CLASSIFICATION OF UNBELIEVERS. The flood of so-called free thought which has swept
                            over this country in the last i'ew years has carried many away. The time was when men did
                            not question the authority of religious dogma, but accepted whatever was given them as the
                            condition of salvation, but to-day there is a very large number who deny many of the
                            fundamental positions of the Christian church, and these unbelievers may be divided itto
                            three classes. First. The unbelief of antagonism- - those who are in open opposition to
                            Christianity, who, under the leadership of Mr. Ingersoll and other radicals, ridicule and
                            denounce as false and absurd the whole system of religion. Next. The unbelief of
                            indifference- - a class so surprisingly large that it is worthy of especial mention. All
                            over the city, in the stores, the factories find the offices, it is easy to find vast
                            numbers of men, not bad in behavior, but who seldom think of religion, and have no church
                            relationship, unless it is that formed by their children's connection with some Sunday
                            school, the entertainments of which are attractive. They are people into whose lives a
                            thought of God is never suffered to enter, until the shadow of death falls across the home.
                            The third class includes a species of practical unbelief found in the churches themselves,
                            people whose profession of belief, made by their presence and support of churches as well as
                            by word of mouth, is strictly orthodox, but who fail to make an application of their
                            Christian principles in their practical daily life ; those who say they believe in God aud
                            yet go through life without taking God into account in their various plans; those who say
                            they believe in the brotherhood of man, yet in their dealings with men assume that every mi
                            n is a scamp and an enemy ; those who profess to be followers of Jesus aud pray lor His
                            judgment of right and wrong ; who would not openly steal a cent, yet do not hesitate to
                            enter into stock shearing and getting their share of wool from the lambs, or under the cloak
                            of a Government contract steal from tax payers, or, in smaller matters, get two rides on the
                            railroad for one ticket; send two letters for one postage stamp, or even defraud the poor
                            traction company by a misuse of pass or transfer. THE PREVALENT FORM. This third class of
                            unbelief is more prevalent than it is pleasant to acknowledge, but in a just estimate of the
                            unbelief of the age cannot be ignored. They swell to a mulitude beyond ability to number the
                            unbelievers on whom the judgment of punishment is pronounced by all the churches. With these
                            facts in view a special interest is given to the origin of so much unbelief anrl the remedy
                            for it. A fundamental cause is found in the unwillingness on the part of theologians to
                            acknowledge growth of thought in religion, and in times past they have even gone farther and
                            condemned new ideas in other fields of life. But the growth of man while hindered, could not
                            be stopped. Unless religion keeps up with the advancement of the<pb n="62" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> world,
                            there must be unbelief, and it is a fact that while there has been progress in every other
                            field of thought, religion has been clogged by foolish prejudice and superstition until the
                            views that were once held sacred are now ridiculed. Men say if that is religion I want
                            nothing of it. Now what do I mean by growth? I do not mean that truth can be outgrown ; I do
                            not mean that the principles of life proclaimed by Jesus can be outgrown, but that of
                            religious truth, as well as of any other truth, we can have new views. Electricity was a
                            great force one hundred years ago ; electricity has not changed, but men have wiser and
                            better views of its nature and uses. So the religion of Jesus Christ has not changed, but
                            men, after eighteen hundred years of its influence, should be better able to understand,
                            state and apply it to-day than ever before. Another cause is found in the fact that we
                            cannot believe the unbelievable however much we may wish to. Real belief is determined by
                            evidence and not by desire. It is possible to believe a fact that is beyond our
                            comprehension, but it is not possible to believe a contradiction, and there grew up in the
                            past many views that were positive contradictions. God is unchangeable, but as we draw
                            nearer to Him our view? of Him change, but there are those who still look at Him only from
                            the distant past, and proclaiming what they see, thoughtful men recognize such
                            contradictions, so that unbelief, is but the natural revolt of the judgment. The existence
                            of God is proclaimed. and God to be God must be absolutely perfect in all His attributes. To
                            find a defect in God is to destroy His essential uature, and yet those who proclaim a God of
                            omnipotence also proclaim that there is and always will be a power successfully opposing
                            Him. They proclaim that God is love, and yet that He will do unlovely things ; that He is a
                            father, and yet will do unfatherly things. They say that this infinitely good being, all
                            love, and wisdom and power has created children sensitive to pain, knowing those children
                            will live a brief life of happiness or misery, and then through all the unending ages of
                            eternity will suffer the most excruciating tortures. Against such ideas the best in man
                            revolts. And good and thoughtful men of to-day say such a God does not rise to the level of
                            humanity, much less of divinity. We would not do such things with our children, and
                            certainly He must be better than we ? REMEDY FOR UNBELIEF. Finally, if from the Bible has
                            come such an extent of unbelief a lively interest must be awakened in a remedy. There are a
                            good many ways of looking at Christianity; men of equal intelligence and sincerity differ
                            decidedly, each church represents a different interpretation of one or more points ; is it
                            not possible to find a belief among these that will satisfy the den.ands of reason and
                            utility? Now, I believe m God, in Christ, the Bible, immortality and the certainty of
                            rewards and punishments, and yet there are those who say I am not a Christian because I do
                            not believe in their interpretation of these terms. I might with equal propriety say they
                            are not Christians because they do not believe in my interpretation of them- - it is no
                            farther from their house to mine than it is from mine to theirs. If God has made a
                            revelation to man it is but<pb n="63" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> natural to suppose that He would speak so
                            we can understand. There are views of all the various points of Christian theology that are
                            in perfect accord with man's best judgment and can accomplish the end for which religion was
                            designed. There is a view of God that proclaims Him absolutely perfect in all His attributes
                            ; the Creator of the universe, conceived in love, planned in wisdom and executing with
                            power. Any other view of Him is impossible witho.ut destroying the very idea of God.
                            Incidental to creation there must always be more or less destruction. It is not finished
                            yet. We are not the climax of humanity, we are but a step in progress, and these things that
                            we so deplore are incidents in the process of creation, and sometime we will see what God
                            has always seen. THE TRUE VIEW OF CHRIST. The name of Jesus Christ has been so covered with
                            mystery that it is difficult to get people to consider it in the light of common sense. He
                            is our Savior, but by that I do not mean that He stands between us and God to receive the
                            angry blow we deserve. By salvation I do not mean the saving of a soul from a place of
                            eternal torture in the future life, but I mean the saving of the moral and spiritual nature,
                            not by any mystery or magic, but by a perfectly natural process. Christ is our Savior
                            because He taught perfect principles of life and then exemplified them. As we learn His
                            principles and to exemplify them we become Chriitlike, we become Christians, we are saved in
                            proportion to our Christian character just as we are saved from ignorance in proportion to
                            our acquisition of knowladge. The Bible is not the truth, but contains the truth and is
                            valuable only so far as we can take its truth and make it practical n our lives. The idea
                            that the future life has in it an eternal division, and iu one place certain of God's
                            children are forever blessed and in the other certain of God's children are forever to
                            suffer, is abhorrent. Of course the consequeuces of our life go out into the next world and
                            we must suffer for eyery sin, but our punishment there, as everywhere, must be reformatory
                            in its nature. The infinite God would not institute an inefficient punishment, but His
                            punishment will correct until the soul is corrected, however long it may be, and will go on
                            correcting until each and every soul comes to itself, recognizes its own divine nature and
                            turns to God as naturally as the flowers turn theirLfaces to the sun. If we would do away
                            with unbelief we must do away with unbelievable and useless doctrines, proclaim Christianity
                            as Christ himself did as the right principles of life, showing our proper relations to God
                            and to man.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God's rest" TEIform="index"/> GOD'S REST. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Furber, Aurilla" TEIform="persName"/>AURILLA FURBER.</byline><p TEIform="p"> [Contributed by Harriet Hastings.]God give you peace! your life will have its longinj I
                            would not ask they be less keen and deep; The soul that firmly stand, upon the mountains
                            Must know the footing of the pathway steep: It must have trod the vallies dim and^low And
                            tented where the streams of silence flow. For you no blank content of heart or brain I
                            crave, but I would have you, friends, to drain The cup of all wide living, feed and grow
                            Full rich in wealth of feeling, have you know The strength of strong desire, and bruvely
                            face The close temptations of our struggling race. [ would not spare you strife and
                            weariness Nor beg that powers of darkness never press Anear your feet; yet ever do I pray
                            The rest of God be with you all the way! Cottage Grove, Minn. </p></div2><pb n="64" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>NOTES</head><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> THE MANIFESTO. MAECH, 1887. Office of publication. The Manifesto is published at Shaker
                                Village, Mer. Co. N. H. All articles for publication should be addressed to Henry C.
                                Blinn, and all letters on financial business to A. Y. Cochran. .75 .40 One copy per
                                year, postage paid, " " six months, " Send for specimen copy, free.</p></div3><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christianity" TEIform="index"/> CHRISTIANITY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> To be good and to do good is about the sum total of the Christian discipline. In this
                                may be found a salvation from all that is wrong or a protection from the sins of the
                                world. As simple as this formula may be, all the laws that have been made, all the
                                creeds that have been written, and all the exhortations that have been held forth, have
                                not been able to accomplish anything more beneficial for humanity, or redound more to
                                the glory of God. Even the prophet, as he became anxious for the protecting spirit of
                                God to be manifested toward the children of Israel, urged them as an essential
                                preparation for the divine presence, to "cease to do evil and learn to do well." They
                                had listened for years to a record of laws and carnal ordinances that had covered all
                                the transgressions that they did or might do, and still their advancement was very
                                limited in the essential works of righteousness. It was not uncommon for religionists to
                                build with one hand and to destroy with the other. Man's humanity for man was mixed
                                largely with selfishness, while man's love for the god-like qualities of the mind were,
                                indeed, very low. The New Testament is equally simple in its exhortations toward a godly
                                life. The divine Teacher was earnest in his ministration to save his people from their
                                sins ; to learn them, that to make the Lord's path strait, was at the same time making
                                their own path strait, and that no time should be lost in the needless repetition of
                                long prayers, or in committing to memory the commandments of men. In this wonderful
                                simplicity of the gospel work, the Scribes and Pharisees found not the least chance for
                                the exhibition of their profound learning or for their fine spun theories, so essential
                                as they thought, to propitiate the favor of God. "Seek first the kingdom of God," said
                                Jesus, and in obtaining this you have the key to success in securing all other needed
                                blessings. God's kingdom is the embodiment of righteousness and those who entered by the
                                door became the sons and daughters of a heavenly order. To have this it is essential to
                                love mercy, to live humbly and to keep unspotted from the world. In this way we enter in
                                at the strait gate, which leads to life. All of this experience through which mankind
                                have passed, has no doubt, been the needed lesson which has brought them to the pi ice
                                which they now occupy. It probably could not have been reached in any other way, and
                                even at this late date in the history of man, there are conditions which present
                                themselves most forcibly to us, by the exhibition of so much that is coarse, cruel and
                                savage, that they THE TERMS.<pb n="65" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 65 belong to the
                                curliest ages of mankind. The ferocity of the wild beast could not be more signally
                                displayed in its own home, than it is in the society of some men Avho are said to have
                                been made in the image of God. Here we find the necessity for the restraining influence
                                of the Levitical laws, of the condign punishment of the willing transgressor, and of the
                                bars and bolts that are used to hold in check the wild and reckless conditions of the
                                human family. We arc quite willing however, to believe that there has been, from age to
                                age, a gradual change for | the better, and that the higher faculties of the mind are
                                now in many cases, occupying the foremost place, and that all are actively at work for
                                the salvation of the race. Wherever this goodness may be found we find the manifestation
                                of the love of God. It may, sometimes appear among those whom we denominate ".evil"' or
                                "unjust" and yet as the sun shines, or the rain falls, it reaches these conditions,
                                under the guidance of a heavenly Father's care, as effectually as it does upon the
                                "good" and upon the "just.'' How very limited and selfish are our conceptions of God's
                                work when we foolishly circumscribe it to the little circle in which we move, while to
                                be better informed, we are positively assured that "his love is everywhere. " "For modes
                                of faith, Let graceless zealots tight," as they ever have done, and reap as they
                                eventually will, the fruit of their own selfishness. Whatever the system of religious
                                belief may be, unless it teaches men to deny themselves of "all ungodliness and every
                                worldly lust," it cannot find itself in harmonious action with that taught by the divine
                                Teacher. It may be expressed in so simple a&gt; form that no one can fail to
                                understand the foundation work upon which it rests, and be equally as able to walk in
                                its light, as they are to breathe the air around them. </p></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> Please write the articles that are intended for publication on sheets of NOTE SIZE, 5x8
                                inches and much oblige the printers of the Manifesto.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary </head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ideal sleeping room" TEIform="index"/>THE IDEAL SLEEPING ROOM
                            </head><p TEIform="p">[Contributed by Rachel Webb.] <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">JLt 32.ust Ite Well Ventilated and Hare Plenty of
                                        Sunshine. The "ideal sleeping room" will face the east. It will be not less than
                                        fifteen feet square, with windows on two sides for light and ventilation. For
                                        farther ventilation it will have an open fireplace. The walls will be
                                        hard-finished and tinted a colur that will be restfal to the eye. The woodwork
                                        will be finished in its natural color, paint not being admitted. The floor will
                                        be of hard, polished wood, with small rugs for comfort that arc shakeable
                                        weekly. Everything that would invite dust will be strictly excluded, therefore
                                        the furniture will have no extra carvings. The one hair mattress will be of the
                                        best quality, made in two parts for convenience in turning and airing, with a
                                        woven wire spring beneath. The bed clothing will be the lightest, at the same
                                        time warmest, consisting of blankets and white spread. All extra adornments of
                                        lambrequins and fancy things of no use will not find a place here. The curtains
                                        Avill be of thin, washable material. The " coming woman " will plan to heve her
                                        bed set away from the wall for health's sake as well as convenience. Modern "
                                        conveniences " will be let alone as far as stationary washbasin with hot and
                                        cold water is concerned, the portable washstand being used in-<pb n="66" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> stead, she preferring to do a little extra work to running any
                                        risk ot being slowly and genteelly poisoned. Tier bed will be well spread open
                                        the first thing in the morning, and the sunshine and air invited in to do its
                                        part toward airing and cleansing of the same, and the making of the bed will be
                                        the last of the morning duties. The "coming woman" will plan a big closet in
                                        each sleeping room, with a window for ventilation, if a possible thing. It will
                                        not be a receptacle for old boots or shoes, nor antiquated bonnets, hats or
                                        soiled clothing. There will be plenty of hooks at the proper height for her to
                                        reach- -not the carpenter- - not forgetting to put those in the children's
                                        closet at a. suitable height for them. The children will be remembered in this
                                        house and will have a room with a hard wood floor where all their belongings can
                                        be kept and they can play to their heart's content, without being told not to do
                                        this or that for fear of hurting the carpet or furniture ; where everything
                                        shall be usable and bangable, plenty of old chairs and boxes for steam-cars or
                                        circuses ; where they can decorate the walls with pictures, and have a good time
                                        generally.- - M. J. I'lumstead, in</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Good housekeeping" TEIform="index"/> Good Housekeeping.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear elder Frederic: Overlooking my obligations..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Dear elder Frederic: Overlooking my obligations...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Austria, Libie, Decemeber 1886" TEIform="index"/> Libie, Austria, Dec, 1886. </dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Elder Frederic :- -Overlooking my obligations to be fulfilled before the close of this
                            year, I find I owe you an account of my voyage to Europe. After a pleasant voyage of
                            thirteen days, and an inward sunshine not to be marred by rough weather, we landed at
                            Hamburg. There, I called on the Vegetarian Society, and gave some of the books you kindly
                            gave me for distribution, in order to make Shakerism understood in Germany. At Berlin, they
                            were greatly interested in my information, and a short notice in the Vegetarian Review,
                            attracted the attention of a lar re circle. After a rest of a few days, with my parents, I
                            started for Vienna. My principal aim being to open my brother's eyes and heart to
                            righteousness. I succeeded, and I am thankful for it. Sabbath night, the 11th of Dec, I held
                            a public meeting about Shakers. The audience showed great interest, and liberally manifested
                            their approbation and joy. I finally made a visible impression, by enumerating all the
                            abominations of the world, which we have overcome. Many came forth to shake hands, and to
                            send their respects and love to the Shakers. I have no doubt but a German Compendium would
                            be a great benefit here. The Vegetarian societies are the most fertile grounds for our seed.
                            In my humble opinion the vegetarian principle of righteousness will be the next step of
                            progress for Believers ; and I fervently hope, after twenty or more years, to look back upon
                            meat eating Shakers, as we do now upon our ancestors who freely used alcohol and tobacco.
                            With due forbearance Avith human appetites, I have faith, that sooner or later, Believers
                            must overcome this last remnant of heathenism. I cannot help write it down, hoping nobody
                            will take offence who has not the same faith. A Shaker cannot be a butcher, and to hire a
                            man, will not do. In the meantime, in bearing and forbearing I greatly rejoice, and am
                            thankful that a new year cannot be but a happy and blessed one with Believers. This wish so
                            often vainly repeated by the world, is fulfilled forever and ever to true Christians. The
                            least of one of these, sends his best love and respects to all the hearts of purity.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pick, Ernest" TEIform="persName">Ernest Pick.</persName></byline></div2><pb n="67" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Live for something" TEIform="index"/>LIVE FOR SOMETHING
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Live for something ; be not idle- - Look about thee for
                                    employ; Sit not down to useless dreaming- - Labor is the sweetest joy. Folded hands
                                    are ever weary, Selfish hearts are never gay, Life for thee hath many duties- -
                                    Active be, then, while you may ! Scatter blessings in thy pathway ; Gentle words and
                                    cheering smiles Better are than gold or silver, With their grief-dispelling wiles.
                                    As the pleasant sunshine falleth Ever on the grateful earth, So let sympathy and
                                    kindness Gladden Avell the darkened hearth! Hearts there are oppressed and wearyDrop
                                    the tear of sympathy; Whisper words of hope and comfort, Give, and thy reward shall
                                    be Joy unto thy soul returning from this perfect fountain-head ; Freely, as thou
                                    freely givest, Shall the grateful light be shed ! </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Catholic" TEIform="index"/> The Catholic.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker land limitation act" TEIform="index"/> Shaker Land Limitation Act.</head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Henry George, Dear Friend ; The Christ, whom Christendom recognizes, was Jesus of Nazareth.
                            Jesus did not marry, owned no land. Did not allow his disciples to have "private porperty in
                            land." And when he said, "Blessed are the meek for they shall inherit the earth," it was as
                            a joint inheritance, not individually, as "private property in land." Thanks for the Eagle
                            containing your "Two forms of slavery." "It must be so; thou reasonest well" from true
                            premises. When John the Baptist came in Judea, men said, it is Elias materialized. They knew
                            that Elias and Mo.'.es had materialized to Jesus and disciples on the mount of
                            transfiguration. Now, I think George Henry Evaus has materialized in Henry George. If it be
                            not so, I can no more help it than I can help seeing that you have entered into his labors.
                            You are teaching the truths which cost George Henry his life. I have seen nothing better
                            upon the subject of land than your article. All honor to the Brooklyn Eagle for publishing
                            such radical truths as proceed from your pen. Garret Smith exclaimed in a burst of
                            eloquence, "The sea! the sea!! God be praised for the sea ! ! !" It belonged to all mankind.
                            Nobody owns the sea. May we not say, God be praised for modern Christianity- -for the
                            Shakers? who having abundance of land, have no private property in land," neither can they
                            say of aught they possess it is mine or thine. Land and its products being held in common.
                            Jefferson affirmed, that "no man had right to land only in usufruct"- -what he or she can
                            use. Mother Ann said, " the light of the gospel will increase. " In that increasing light,
                            the Shakers begin to see that they have sinned, as communities, by monopolizing land. They
                            have bought all that joined them, to the extent of their means. In the things wherein they
                            sinned in the same have they been punished. An honest confession is good for the soul. The
                            care of the surplus land absorbed the energies of those who should have been missionaries to
                            supply the societies with prepared souls to build up the Kingdom of Heaven upon earth. The
                            kingdom for which Christians are all praying. We are now selling off real estate, but more
                            as a matter of necessity than from conviction or a religious principle.<pb n="68" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/>The Shakers Avere educated in the world- -Christendom- -inhere in us as a people. We do
                            not hold land as "private property," but, as communities, (of which there are some sixty in
                            different States.) we monopolize it without limit. Cannot the Legislature help us to do
                            right, by passing a SHAKER LAND LIMITATION LAW ? Gladstone says, Government should make it
                            easy for the people to do right. Why not? Unlimited land possessions has proved a curse, not
                            a blessing, to Shaker Communities, as it has to all the seventy communities of which Noyes
                            and Nordhoff give the history. If there be an Act limiting the number of acres that any
                            Shaker Community, or any other community, association, co-operation, or Syndicate, may
                            possess in any of the United States, and compelling them to dispose of all lands, above the
                            legal limit, within a given set time, it will help the Shakers to resist the temptation to
                            society selfishness- -help us to obey our faith, so that we do not join house to house and
                            acre to acre until there be no place but some eleemosynary or penal institution for the
                            landless poor. As an appendix to the Act I would suggest none b?:t citizens of the United
                            States may hereafter become freeholders. And that all lands now held by foreigners, as
                            individuals, may be sold ; but, not passed by will to heirs, unless those heirs are citizens
                            of the United States. If held by syndicates, give them a reasonable time to dispose of their
                            lands under pain of forfeiture to the United States. Citizens, in this Shaker land
                            limitation act shall mean Indians, male and female, of legal age. And all other men and
                            women, whether native, or naturalized, of whatever color or race. But, no such citizen, as
                            above defined, shall after the date of this Act, buy and become possessed of more than one
                            hundred acres of land or such other amount as the wisdom of Congress may fix upon as the
                            legal limit. When a landholder dies, his or her heirs may inherit with the proviso, that all
                            land above the legal limit to each h- - -ir, shall be sold within an appointed time, or be
                            forieited to the United States. Each state, county, and town shall seek to make every
                            citizen a freeholder. And homesteads shall be inalienable to the end, that there be no poor
                            in the land and no poor not possessed of laud. That no American citizen- -one of the
                            sovereign people and joint owners of this landless continent, become a tramp or an inmate of
                            a pauper house or prison. And that no Shaker, or other community, be a land monopolist.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/> F. W. Evans.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian brotherhood" TEIform="index"/> CHRISTIAN BROTHERHOOD.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dibble, Chauncy" TEIform="persName"/>CHAUNCY DIBBLE.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Christian brotherhood in practical operation must be founded on purity, love and universal
                            peace. With this, all who have a prophetic view coincide. But should an institution spring
                            up which has for its object the practical living out of these principles, would the world
                            bless it as an approximation towards the long prayed for reform. The spirit of Christ
                            manifested through whatever medium, is ever an offense to a worldly spirit. Jesus said if ye
                            were of the world it would love its own. The Jews did not accept him as the<pb n="69" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/>Messiah yet were obliged to acknowledge his goodness and that he spake the
                            truth. They could not permit of any deviation from their creeds. Even now should any
                            revelation of truth be manifested conflicting with the dogmas of the sectarian church of
                            to-day it would doubtless be rejected. Jesus would not conceive of a God that delighted in j
                            blood. His was a God of love and j peace. He never quoted God as a lead- ! er of battles or
                            gave any such coloring to his character ; but a universal Parent., as the sun shining upon
                            the just and the unjust. Called to be a Savior, Jesus felt the necessity of reforming
                            himself aud as he grew in years, so in j wisdom and power to govern his own spirit. Men of
                            ordinary fortitude can face death, but it requires most enduring courage to face the truth
                            in our daily lives and walk by it at the expense of ease and indulgence. It became the
                            Savior of mankind that he should be fashioned like unto his brethren, to be a perfect
                            pattern. We accept Jesus resurrected out of Adam's race through the aid of divine
                            inspiration wherewith all may be baptized and rise with him who was the first born among
                            many brethren. And in proportion as we rise with him into an element of purity we become
                            saviors to others. Every intelligent being, man or woman, is endowed with a spark of Deity
                            which if cultivated will constitute him or her a son or daughter of the living God who
                            imparted to man the boon of eternal life. We shall exist in that degree of happiness to
                            which we attain by our own exertion aided by each other aud ministering spirits. In
                            Christian brotherhood there is most happiness and protection. Such is the order of Heaven.
                            Watervliet, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="On the way" TEIform="index"/> ON THE WAY.</head><p TEIform="p"> The object of my life is to attain the highest degree of perfection, to cultivate the deep
                            emotions of my soul and mind, so as to feel that my duties to humanity and to God are above
                            my own selfishness and pleasure. This is my precious ideal. The surest, shortest way I have
                            found at last to realize it, is to be true to the precepts of the gospel, to be true and
                            obedient to the substance of itsteachings. I have read many chapters of the Gospel very
                            diligently, over and over again, and as much as I understand it I will be true to it. This
                            will be my guide throughout my earthly life, because my life is concentrated on the
                            principles of the gospel. To be true to the gospel, means to follow the footsteps of Jesus
                            Christ, to live as pure as he lived, to be ready to suffer and die in the body for the sake
                            of truth and universal happiness. To crucify in our own hearts, the lower elements of the
                            world with all its bad habits, its narrow egotism, ambition, affections and lusts. After the
                            lower propensities are trodden down under the feet, the pure, unstained heart can be filled
                            with righteousness. There can be sown in it seed that will bring, forth fruit worthy to live
                            and to struggle for. Again, I sustain that only through simplicity and strict obedience to
                            the gospel; the gospel that embraces the highest moral principle of life. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="One thing I know" TEIform="index"/> ONE THING I KNOW.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bowers, Grace H." TEIform="persName"/>GRACE H. BOWERS.</byline><p TEIform="p"> One thing I know to be divinely true, That God is dual, male and female tco v A holy
                            Fatherhood and Motherhood, Embodying all that's beautiful and good..<pb n="70" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> By
                            earthly things we all may plainly see The First Great Cause is not a Trinity, Composed of
                            Father, Son and Holy Ghost All worshiped by the vast angelic host. I pray unto my Heavenly
                            Father wise, To bless me in my daily sacrifice; [near The while my Heavenly Mother draws me
                            Unto Her pure embrace, why need I fear". And many sons upon the earth have trod, Most true
                            and worthy in the sight of God While sainted daughters from all sin made Adore their God in
                            perfect liberty; [free, For with the Holy Ghost their souls are [filled, While on the rock
                            of truth alone they build. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Equality" TEIform="index"/> EQUALITY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescott, James S." TEIform="persName"/> JAMES S. PRESCOTT.</byline><p TEIform="p"> God's ways are equal- -man's ways are unequal and the end of all reforms is to bring about
                            an equality ot the human race and place them on the level of love where God made them in the
                            beginning. The distinction between the rich and the poor has been charged to God, but this
                            is false. It originated in the wickedness of man and woman combined. It never emanated from
                            God. God's ways are equal. Man's ways are unequal and selfish in the extreme. God's law is
                            the lav/ of love and kindness, and good-will to all the human race. Man's ways are full of
                            hatred, envy, strife and contention, which never came from God, but is of the wicked one.
                            God is infinite, and we cannot go where he is not. We cannot get away from Him, and I would
                            not if I could. I want to love Him more and serve Him better than I ever did. Yea ! I want
                            to love Him more, with all my heart, soul, mind, might and strength, and my neighbor as
                            myself. "On these two commandments hang all the law and the prophets." It is said on good
                            authority, that the licentiousness of man and woman, at the present day, are greater than
                            they were in any preceding age of the world ; and more aggravating, because committed under
                            greater light, and who can deny it? Is it any wonder that the world is ripe for destruction,
                            and the calamities are pressing hard on every hand ? What is the 1'emedy ? Alas ! only one !
                            Put away the cause and the effect will c?ase. If this is not done speedily, the Avorld is
                            doomed to destruction, and no power on earth can save it. North Union, Ohio. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Keeping ourselves unspotted from the world" TEIform="index"/> Keeping ourselves unspotted
                            from the world.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Shepard, Harriet" TEIform="persName"/> HARRIET SHEPARD. </byline><p TEIform="p">Chkist said, "Lay up for yourselves treasures in heaven where neither moth nor rust doth
                            consume, and where thieves do not break through nor steal; for where thy treasure is, there
                            will thy heart be also. The lamp of the body is the eye : if therefore thine eye be single,
                            thy whole body shall be full of light. But if thine eye be evil thy whole body shall be full
                            of darkness. If therefore the light that is iu thee be darkness, how great is the darkness!
                            No man can serve two masters ; for either he will late the one and love the other, or else
                            le will hold to one, and despise the other. Ye cannot serve God and mammon." Matt, vi., 20-
                            -24. To do the will of his heavenly Faher, Christ was very energetic and enhusiastic. In so
                            doing he kept himself mspotted from the world, and set us a aright example of purity, love,
                                meek-<pb n="71" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> ness and devotion to the cause of God : which it is our duty,
                            God enlightening and strengthening us, to follow. Let us devote the remainder of our lives
                            to the service of God, soul, body and spirit. Let us earnestly, trustingly and lovingly seek
                            to know and do his will. Let Him be our guide continually, on whom we every moment depend to
                            lead - -our every step in wisdom, meekness and love ; understanding not ourselves, trusting
                            all the care to Him who knoweth our hearts, and longing to be guided into all wisdom. Let
                            Him be constantly our support and strength, never forgetting the promise that we may do all
                            things through Christ who strengtheneth us. May we make every trial and affliction a
                            necessity for prayer and live in the spirit and power of our heavenly Parents, expecting
                            their blessing ; and put in them our trust and confidence for deliverance from evil, not
                            forgetting that - -" all things work together for good to those who lo^ethe Lord." May we
                            feel as did our precious Mother, who said, I am among you as one that serveth. Let us not
                            carry Avith us a, weary weight of worriment and perplexity, but while we do our whole duty,
                            give the care and responsibility all to Him who said "Come unto me all ye who labor and are
                            heavy laden and I will give you rest. " Let us not be looking at our afflictions but always
                            at the coming conquest. So shall we forget ourselves, and feel that our greatest joy is in
                            gaining and treasuring a store of heavenly love; the more blessed to give than to receive.
                            So let us lose no opportunity of doing good and blessing; thinking of clearer ways of
                            benefiting others. May we be prayerful, joyous, living in the light of the resurrection and
                            praising God from whom all blessings flow. May we have the spirit of Christ in us to do the
                            works of self-denial which He did and we shall reap a rich harvest of peace, justification
                            and joy if we faint not. How sweet to be able through his divine influence to come
                            trustingly and lovingly so near as to commune with Him and feel his blessing and strength.
                            Let our hearts be filled with rejoicing and in everything give thanks. We must pray for the
                            erring, and learn the meaning of the ministry of prayer ; and particularly let us seek the
                            gaining of souls. Let us experience a state far more elevated, profound, heavenly, happy and
                            God-like than any we ever yet have found. Pray Avithout ceasing. May our greatest interest
                            and administration be to deal with God for souls. Let us gain in this way, those that we
                            cannot in any other. Let us be obedient to our highest inspiration from above and look for
                            issues that we have never before ventured to claim ; and let the most blessed recollections
                            of another year be marvelous answers to prayer. (See July number of The Manifesto for 1886,
                            page 149.) "Seek first the kingdom of heaven and its righteousness and all else shall be
                            added." We would intimate the thought of making a little memorandum of our prayers and leave
                            a space to insert the ansAvers. Let us not be cast down, but live in the lWit and life of
                            Christ and Mother. Let us bury the past and 'lay hold of the new, that which is vitalizing,
                            energizing and uplifting into sweet communion Avith the pure the good and just. God has in
                            store for us treasures new, rich, verdant and life giving. Speak often one to another Avords
                                of<pb n="72" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/> love, encouragement and appreciation and we shall not lose our
                            reward. Le us hold fast that which we have gained and seek greater spiritual blessings. I
                            has truly been said, ""The whole mis sion of our Savior was to draw his dis ciples from the
                            world. North Union. Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>KIND WORDS.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear sir; I have the honor to..." TEIform="index"/>Dear sir; I have the honor to...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Indiana, Greencastle, January 1887" TEIform="index"/> Greencastlc, Ind. Jan 1887.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Dear Sir;- -I have the honor to acknowl edge the receipt of the Manifesto for 188(1
                                which has been received and placed on file in the Library of De Pauw University. The
                                Library and its readers highly appreciate your favor and we wish to thank you for
                                sending us the magazine. Most respectfully yours.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Longden, Henry B." TEIform="persName"/> Henry B. Longden, Lib. of De Pauw
                            University</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Revelation" TEIform="index"/>"REVELATION." 
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Barnes, Eva A. H." TEIform="persName"/>BY EVA A. H. BARNES
                        </byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">. Tis being written day by day - - Its sacred
                                    mystic pages Shall gleam athwart life's darkened way And bless the future ages- -
                                    Wherever hearts flame out anew With Truth's most perfect splendor, And tongue and
                                    pen leap strong and true To bear the message tender : Wherever soul speaks unto soul
                                    The word that satisfies, Revealing Life a mighty Whole Reaching beyond the skies,
                                    There we may find "God's Word" divine Revealing in wondrous measure, There find upon
                                    a holy shrine The soul's most perfect treasure. The Past has had its prophets, seers
                                    ; The Present greets the morning Foretold by them ; and now appears New Light the
                                    heights adorning. Then let us read the magic scroll With thankful, reverent feeling,
                                    Accepting as Truth's mighty whole The Word" of wondrous healing. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="World's advance thought" TEIform="index"/>From The World's Advance Thought. </bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers.
                        </head><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Herald of health" TEIform="index"/>Herald of Health</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>Phrenological Journal and
                                Science of Health</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> Herald of Health. February. Contents. The Health and Working lnibits of President
                                Cleveland; Artificial Sleep as a Curative Agent; A Disgusting Practice in Congress;
                                Women and the Household; Mothers and 1he Nursery, etc., etc. Herald of Health Co., 13
                                Laight St., N. Y. Phrenological Journal and Science of Health. February. Contents,
                                Michael Munckacsy; John A. Logan; Familiar Talks with youngReaders; Our Corner Man; A
                                Di\ ided Republic; Flowers of Old English Poetry; Progress of the Emancipated Race;
                                Heredity not Fatalism ; A Look to the Future; Chained to a Carcass; Health Papers, etc.,
                                etc. Fowler &amp; Wells Co., 753 Broadway, N. Y. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.
                        </head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Blakey, Polly" TEIform="index"/>Polly Blackey</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Callaway, Matilda" TEIform="index"/>Matilda Callaway</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="E., H. L." TEIform="persName"/>H. L. E.</byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Avery, Julia Ann" TEIform="index"/>Julia Ann Avery</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., G." TEIform="persName"/>G. W.</byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Avery, Eliza" TEIform="index"/>Eliza Avery</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="S., E. A." TEIform="persName"/>E. A. S.</byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> Polly Blakey, at South Union Ky. Aug. 17 1886. Age 87 yrs. i mo. and 23 days. A veteran
                                and faithful soldier of the cross for sixty-four years. Matilda Callaway, at South
                                Union, Ky. Nov. 21, 1886. Age 90 yrs. 11 mo. and 3 days. A veteran of eighty-seven
                                years, H. L. E. Julia Ann Avery, at Enfield, Conn. Dec. 10, 1886. Age 81 yrs. and 4 mo.
                                Having spent seventy-five years of her life most peacefully among ISelievers. G. W.
                                Eliza Avery at Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. Dec 30, Io86. Age 72 yrs. 10 mo. and 18 days. She was
                                much beloved by her surroundng friends. From early childhood her life vas consecrated to
                                the service of truth, in obedience to her highest convictions of right, n her character
                                she most beautifully exmplified the heavenly graces of Love, /"eace, Charity, Meekness,
                                and Humility, ruly lightening the pathway of all around, trengthening the over burdened
                                and careworn spirit. E. A. S.</p></div3></div2><pb n="73" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><!--   
THE MANIFESTO.
ANNOUNCEMENT OF
Ben: Perley   Poore's   Book.
Sixty years of a busy journalist's life at
Washington are epitomized in Maj. Ben:
Perley Pooe's two superb volumes. One of
the admirers of the Major recently said that
"at a judiciously ripe period of life the
Major stopped growing old, and since then,
like some of the choice Madeira of which he
writes with so much feeling, he lias only
been accumulating bouquet and flavor." Maj.
Poore has been one of the best known and
one of the most knowing men in Washington society for a half a cen'-ury. His is the
sunny temperament delighting in bright social intercourse. Yet his connection with
daily journalism and his position in the U. S.
Senate placed him always in the thick of
political aff.iirs and social gossip. He was
ever in the Washington "Swim," breasting
the waves with jovial vigor, and never failing to hear or see what was said and done.
The M.ijor could never be very solemn,
and in his ripened sketches of Washington
life every phase reminds him of half a dozen
amusing anecdotes. lie has a rare gift in
telling a story, and his anecdotes are inexhaustible.
His book will not only add lustre to his
fame as a writer, but is of so unique a character and so intensely interesting in matter
that it will prove a valuable contribution to
the literature of-the country. It has mirtl
for the mirthful, -wit for the witty, information for all, and we doubt if it lnls been
equalled by any subscription book since
the war.
It is being issued by the well-known
house of Ilubbard Bros., and is sold exclusively by subscriptlo-i.
65
A MONTH
3  ^ tiujig .Men
and  hi-i'uft e<
a month )     j
 ami BOARD Guaranteed
 r Lariivs in each country,
 nimi'Oiion paid (often $150
 lv  JIOOK  silr.-:dy on
TTTlALWAVE
OF SUCCESS
in North and South America, - -t the Ice-Bound
Poles, <>vcr the lands of the Midnight Sun, under the
E juator, through the Dark Continent, lunpngthe Old
Temples of India, hi iho Flowery Kingdoms t.f China
and Japan, ainiil the ruins of Incas, Aztecs and Zun;, within Canons, Ciif 'Building*, and Gardens of
the Gods, on ihe Isles of the Sea, and in ;ill parts of
the globe. 300 engravings, Low Price. Quick Salen.
Send for Circular, p. W. Ziegler, &Co., 720 Chestnut St. Philadelphia) Pa,
MEDAL   MACHINES.
HEW Y02K STATE AQSICULTUBAIi WOBZS,
1st. Premiums at all Competitive Trials
Itailtvay, Chain mill JT,- -'v- -'r II<- -!- - - - - - - - Po- -i'ri- -,Tlir- -'Kli4'r- - ami (Iciiiii'ik, THr- - - - - -li- -T- -
tfc ftliakcr- -, Clovoi- EIiiIUm-n. V- - - - - - - - - -! C'ntI<- -!- - - -, - - lii'c! llai'ot' EtaKow, II<>!'- - - I'itchl'iirlt- -. Kliiim-lv .fliii*hiii - - -. Mtraw I*r-K*rvin- - - ISjf 'I'lir Mli r- -. Ik- -M'tiil>l NK'iiin-Eiliri iiiil- -" i" wild %Viii- - - - JTIIIIh - -ml I* !- - - - - -!- - - - - - - -.- -*,
Itog* iinii four I'liwrrn. iftiMC Harrows
iV  .**(H1iiia1.v X<K- -t!l     llMirona.      "Robinson's Hay Press, of four sizes- Will
work as easy with one horse> as
others with two. Made with Steel
G3aring wnich can no; bD brok3n."
WHEELER & MELICK Co.,
ALHAW, - -*. Y.
Send stamp for Circular and report of Centennial
trial.
AGENTS "WANTED to sell " REMINISCENCES"
of 60 YEAUS in the   NATIONAL M3TEO70LTS,
byBEN PERLEY POORE
Illustrating the Wit, Humor, mid Eccentricities of
nj>t- -'cclvliritii'N. A. vid.ly i55it- -trat <l treiit of inner Society History, froin "ye
olden time" to the wedding of Cleveland. Won- -l- -Ti'- -ilSy I*<- -mi"iii-. Agents report rapid
wall's*. Address (or circular and term?.
M 5J lilt A It IB KKUM., Pub's, Boston, Mass.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
PLEASANT HILL, Ky.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
 --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>