<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm1704" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">23</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">17</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">04</biblScope><date value="18870401" TEIform="date">April 1887</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">73-96</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="17" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="04" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!-- 
<pb id="p1"/>
APRIL.
MANIFESTO
Published by the United Societies,
"Every plant which my heavenly Father hath not planted shall be rooted
up."- -Matt, xv., 13.
Canterbury, N. H.
1887.
THE
<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
SIBLEY'S
S TESTED   
EEDS
SEND "SS'llhitaW CATALOGUE
Vtbl    Fl         Fild O ET ET F% C
SEND "SS'h
Vegetable, Flower, Field
Plants, Bulbs. Implem'ts.                 .
C D C ET  "y mal1 on application.
~ w\. Km d Don't neglect writing for It.
HIRAM SIBLEY & CO.
ROCHESTER, N. Y.
322-326 E. Main St.
CHICAGO, ILL
12-14 N. Clark St.
After Forty years'
experience in the
preparation of more
than One Hundred
Thousand applications for patents in
the United States and Foreign countries, the publishers of the Scientific
American continue to net as solicitors
for patents, eiiveats. trade-marks, copyrights, etc., for the United States, and
to obtain patents in Canada, England, France,
Germany, and all other countries Their experience is unequaled and their facilities are unsurpassed.
Drawings and specifications prepared and filed
in the Patent Office on short notice. Terms very
reasonable. No charge for examination of models
or drawings     Advice by mni1 free
Patents obtained through - -'nun.tCo.arenoticed
inthe SCIENTIFIC - -                 'AS, which has
the largest circulation and \s tre most influential
newspaper of its kind published in the world.
The advantages of such a notice every patentee
understands
This large and splendidly illustrated newspaper
is published WEEKLY - -t $3.00 a year, and is
admitted to be the best paper devoted to science,
mechanics, inventions, engineering works, and
Other departments of industrial progress, published in any country. It contains the names of
all patentees and title of every invention patented
each week. Try it four months for one dollar.
Sold by all newsdealers.
If you have an invention  to  patent write to
Munn & Oo., publishers of Scientific American,
361 Broadway, New York.
Handbook about patents mailed free.
New Theology Herald stands for spiritual unity with intellectual freedom. It is published biweekly, at Jamestown, N. Y. Editors Rev. J. G.
Townsend and Solon Laucr.    $1. per. year.
Georgetown College Magazine, is issued
monthly during the collegiate year, by the literary
Societies of Georgetown College, Ky. $1. per
annum.
CONTENTS.
Gospel Testimony, No. 13,	-   73
Amended Translations,	76
Liberty Enlightening the "World,	-    78
Be Born Again,	79
One at a Time,	.     - -
True and Faithful,	
Baptism,        -	-   80
The Beyond,	81
Christian Communism, No. 1,	-   82
A Chapel in the Heart,	86
A Tribute of Affection,	-   87
Might have been,	- -
Notes;- -The Cross of Christ,	-   88
Self Cure,	89
Water in Food,	.     - -
Zipporah Cory,	90
Consolation,              ...	-   93
Devotional,	- -
Petitions,       ....	.     - -
How strange,	- -
Music;- -Life's Victories,   -	-   94
Youths' Bible class,	95
Little Children,	- -
Items,	
Books & Papers,	-    96
Kind Words,       -	.    - -        "
Deaths,          .... - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -4 Jfc h- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -	
The Shaker Seed Co., of Mt. Lebanon,
N. Y., have sent out a beautifully illustrated
Catalogue for 1887. As one is generally interested in the frontispiece of a new book,
they will find in this a very pretty picture of
the "Livingston's Beauty Tomato," the sight
of which, at this early date, makes us think
of the " good time a coming.' The book also contains, amo'-g many other good things,
an Amateur's guide to the " Flower and Vegetable garden " which will be read with much
interest.
Herald of Health. March, Contents: Health
Habits of Queen Victoria; Curing by Sympathy;
Diphtheria; Woman and the Household; Mothers
and the Nursery; Hei.lth Inventions; etc., etc.
Herald of Health Co.   13 Laight St., N. Y.
Hall's Journal of Health. March, Contents :
Somniloquism; Woodlands and Malaria; Sore
Eyes; The Skin, its functions; The Heart, its functions ; Singular Pre-natal affliction; etc. Office 206
Broadway, N. Y.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
Vol. XVII.
APRIL,  1887.
No. 4. --><pb n="73" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gospel testimony of Mother Ann Lee and the elders, William Lee and James Whittaker no. 13" TEIform="index"/> The Gospel Testimony of Mother Ann Lee and the Elders, William Lee and James Whittaker.
                            No. 13.</head><p TEIform="p"> Published expressly for the several Communities of Believers in 1816. Re-written by Henry 0.
                            Blinn. The Believers driven from Harvard, Mass., Aug. 1782, and cruelly abused. As all
                            previous attempts to expel the witnesses^ of truth from the town of Harvard ha^ signally
                            failed, a class of malicious minds that were filled, and intent upon "- -breathing out of
                            threatenings and slaughter," made renewed and determined attempts, by the aid of mob
                            violence to consummate their wicked design. It was near the close of the harvest season that
                            a large number of Believers from New Lebanon, Hancock and other places had gathered to the
                            Church in Harvard, that they might attend the meetings that would be held in that place.
                            This large body of people in their attendance upon the services of their worship, with a
                            testimony that was like the two edged sword against the sins of the world, and their many
                            manifestations of the gifts of the holy spirit, all conspired to increase the persecuting
                            spirit of those who hated the word of God. Under the cover of this large gathering a lawless
                            class of men found a favorable opportunity for executing their nefarious work. As their
                            especial hatred was against Mother Ann and the Elders, it was a source of great disquietude
                            to find that these leaders were not among the Believers at Harvard. Through the kindness of
                            an overruling Providence, Mother Ann had received a warning that her safety depended on her
                            immediate removal to another section of the state. She had seen, in vision, the gathering of
                            the mob, had seen them marching toward the " Square House," and learned that their hearts
                            were as the heart of Cain. Accepting this warning as from God, Mother Ann aud the Elders
                            arranged to leave the town of Harvard for a short season, and accept a home among the
                            Believers in another place. Previous to the time of departure the company assembled to
                            receive the farewell blessing of each other, and to renew the bonds of love and friendship
                            for their spiritual Parents in the church of Christ. All were bowed in prayer. Tears of
                            sorrow and anxious hope were poured out in humble petitions to the Father of mercies, for
                            the protection o*'<pb n="74" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> Mother Ann and the Elders. Among this company were to
                            be found many stout-hearted men ; men that feared no danger, and who never quailed before
                            the face of man. Some of them were battle scarred veterans who had passed through the war of
                            the Revolution and had offered their lives a living sacrifice, that liberty of conscience
                            might be the free gift of the nation. But in this contest, their weapons were not carnal,
                            they could use only the testimony of Jesus Christ, the Peace-maker, and then patiently bear
                            the persecution that was inflicted upon them. At this time however, a blessing was
                            administered to them, as Mother Ann addressed the assembly. "Brethren and Sisters, be of
                            good cheer, my spirit shall be with you." There was time for only a few words, and the
                            meeting was closed. The Elders hurriedly mounted their horses in preparation for their
                            journey. At this moment a company of Believers arrived from a distant part of the state. The
                            Elders alighted from their horses as the whole company kneeled in prayer, and asked a
                            blessing upon every one who had received the gospel into an honest heart. It was the baptism
                            of the Holy Spirit, and they covenanted anew, in their zealous and simple petitions, that
                            the spirit of truth might guide them in the path of duty and obedience. Soon the last
                            petition was made, the last farewell was said and the Elders hurriedly remounted their
                            horses, and were soon away on the road, with the hope of reaching the residence of Abel
                            Jewett in the town of Littleton. It was near the close of the day when Br. Abel, welcomed
                            the messengers of God. In the morning they continued their journey till they reached the
                            home of Nathan Kendall in Woburn. Here they felt a peaceful rest, and the assurance that
                            they had escaped the cruel rage of their wicked persecutors. After the departure of the
                            Elders, the Believers at the Dwelling in Harvard, returned to their several duties about the
                            farm and the house. It was a time of sadness, of gloomy forebodings. Their property and
                            their lives were in danger, if a company of lawless characters should enter their
                            possessions. The Believers crave their thoughts to prayer, as they asked that the spirit of
                            peace might abound. On the Sabbath, public worship was held at the Square House. A large
                            body of Believers were present from Harvard and the adjoining towns, and several from other
                            states. The spirit of God was manifested in the assembly, as they gave their souls in
                            earnest prayer and spoke and sung and shouted as they were led by the divine light, that had
                            separated them from the children of this world. The influence of the gift of God was not
                            wholly confined to those who had professed faith in the testimony of Mother Ann, but many
                            who were strangers to the family shared in the blessings of the meeting, and as the
                            Believers kneeled in prayer the spectators united with them. This season of spiritual
                            service gave joy to the faithful seeker after righteousness, as their songs of praise and
                            their shouts of victory, ascended to Him who could read the aspiration of each heart. The
                            meeting continued most of the day and evening with short intermissions. After its dismissal,
                            those living in the vicinity, returned to their homes, while<pb n="75" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/>many of the
                            Believers accommodated invited guests. While these disciples of our Lord were engaged iu
                            their religious service, and proclaiming the testimony of the sharp sword, against the sins
                            of the world, the enemies of the cross of Christ were busily employed in collecting their
                            forces for au anticipated assault upou the Brethren and Sisters.f. At an early hour on the
                            morning of the 19th. of Aug., the mob began to assemble near the "Square House," while
                            several were already within the boiriudaries of the yard. An pged brother having occasion to
                            open the door, several persons pushed their way into the house and conducted themselves very
                            rudely. They assumed the right to make a search, and passed from room to room, threatening
                            violence to any one who opposed their progress. They were disappointed, and vexed as they
                            had failed to find the object of their search. They roughly demanded that the Elders should
                            come forward and give themselves up to the officers of their party. Lucy Wright, a young
                            sister, stood fearless before them, and endeavored, by kind and geutle words, to calm their
                            ferocious spirits, informing them that Mother Ann and the Elders were not in the house. Her
                            words to them were idle tales, and they refused to listen. They even threatened her with
                            violence unless she remained quiet. From this interview the Believers understood quite well
                            the object of the search, and Lucy immediately planned to escape from the f It was
                            subsequently learned that the mob had designed to keep their plans a secret from the
                            Believers, but signally failed, as has already been shown. place. She informed Mary
                            Partington of the case and then taking some milk pails, they passed safely through the mob
                            on their way to the barn, ostensibly for the purpose of obtaining some milk. Safely within
                            the barn, the pails were carefully laid aside, and the two sisters took their flight across
                            the fields to the residence of Solomon Cooper. Messages were immediately dispatched to the
                            several families of Believers, with all needed information, and many of them Avere soon upon
                            the scene of action. The mob had gathered in front of the Square House, armed with whips,
                            canes and cudgels, aud were evidently bent on mischief. Up to this time no violence of
                            magnitude had been committed and the Brethren and Sisters as they arrived from their homes,
                            were allowed to pass into the house without molestation. The mob was estimated to number
                            about four hundred, and in this unchristian and lawless crowd, were " ministers aud deacons
                            and men honorable (?) in Society. " Elder John Hocknell, who had the management of the
                            place, directed the Believers to assemble in one of the large rooms, aud unite in prayer to
                            God for protection and for wisdom to guide them in the path of their duty, in this hour of
                            their great affliction. So soon as the mob discovered the position that the Believers had
                            taken, they burst open the doors and roughly seizing the Brethren aud Sisters, by their
                            garments or by the hair of the head, inhumanly dragged them from the house and delivered
                            them into the custody of the party who remained in front of the building. Resistance was of
                            but little use, and the proceedings were very much as one might expect <pb n="76" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/>
                            from a persecuting licentious class. While engaged in this transaction, they seemed to be
                            divested of the feelings of our common humanity. The Believers were overpowered, and in some
                            things must submit to this mob rule. Orders were now given, by these disciples of
                            Torquemada, for all who lived in the vicinity, to return to their own homes, while those
                            from distant parts of the state, should leave the town at an hour, which they would
                            designate. This order was accompanied by a severe threat, in case any of those from a
                            distance should again be seen in the town of ilarvard. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Amended translations" TEIform="index"/>AMENDED TRANSLATIONS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo G." TEIform="persName"/>ALONZO G. HOLLISTER. </byline><p TEIform="p">Luke, ii., 14. The song of the heavenly hosts at the birth of Jesus, literally translated,
                            reads ' Glory in the highest to God, and on earth peace, in men good-will." Good-will in men
                            leads to all proper conduct as soon as the mind is instructed aright, and the true knowledge
                            instead of being opposed and rejected, is industriously sought as the greatest treasure, and
                            immediately applied to practice, at whatever cost of self-sacrifice, or of self-denial. But
                            this good-will in men, if allowed, would contradict the total depravity doctrine of the time
                            in which the Scriptures were translated, the effect of which is not yet altogether annulled.
                            Therefore we have in different versions, in place of the Greek preposition (en) in, the
                            prepositions to, towards, and among men. Good-will to be among men must of necessity be in
                            them, as the motive power of their actions, for it cannot be outside of them. Probably no
                            one will dispute that so far as God and His messengers are concerned, there has always been
                            good-will to and towards men, although there has been aa immense amount of ill-will and
                            depravity in men, and the latter has been the cause of all the wars and woes that have
                            cursed their generations since men have been upon the earth. The song of the Angels heralded
                            a change to be effected by substituting good-will, or a good cause, inside of men, in place
                            of the ill which has caused all the mischief. This good-will was to execute the law of God
                            according to a new covenant, placed in the inward parts of understanding, and written in the
                            heart, the core and center of man's love, and spring of all his actions. Gal. v., 16. But I
                            say, Walk in the spirit, and perform not the desire of the flesh. For the flesh desires
                            against the spirit, and the spirit against the flesh ; these are opposed to each other, so
                            that the things ye wish uot, the- -e should ye do. Thus the conflict is carried out in the
                            cross to be borne against the inferior desires of the flesh, by performing those higher
                            things of the understanding which are opposed to carnal desire, and in which, the carnal
                            mind takes no pleasure nor stock. The old translation besides being false to the original,
                            is false in fact, because it teaches that the will of a Christian is not free, and that he
                            is not able to serve God by doing right, even when he has the desire. "They who are of
                            Christ, have crucified the flesh with its affections and lusts." Here the idea of the
                            original is preserved. 1 Cor. xiv., 34. Let your wives be silent in the congregations, for
                            it has not been committed (or entrusted) to<pb n="77" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/>them to speak, but to be in
                            subjection as even the law says. But if th?y will learn anything let them ask in a house of
                            their own husbands. For it is a shame for wives to speak in a congregation. In the N. T.
                            Greek, the word for woman and wife is the same, and is translated wife above eighty times.
                            By the context only, can we determine whether wife or woman expresses the thought of the
                            writer. In this place, there can be no doubt, for any novice knows that every woman who owns
                            a hus'i'aud is a wife. But why this discrimination against wives? Because Christianity pure
                            and simple, is not sentiment merely, but a life which either rules in the will of man or
                            woman, as the case may be, or is excluded by its opposite, the carnal life of the world.
                            Hence as marriage is of the world, and a provision for its orderly continuance, a forsaking
                            of the wife relation by all who were married was an indispensible condition to their
                            becoming Christian disciples. See Luke, xiv., 26 and 33. Matt, xix., 27 and other places.
                            This is too evident to be disputed by any unbiased student of the Gospels, and the Epistles
                            of Paul. Reuan and other ratio alists free from modern orthodoxy readily admit it. Hence a
                            wife, whose first and strongest love bound her to a mortal husband, was not free to give her
                            first love to Christ, nor her whole heart to God, as the Apostle testifies in 1 Cor. vii.,
                            and therefore could not in any case be a suitable proclaimer of that kingdom of God from
                            whence all carnal ties are excluded. A husband also, whose strongest attachment is to a wife
                            ; and is unwilling to forsake that relation and treat her as a sister, for Christ's sake, is
                            subject to the same disability; for how can one communicate that which he does not possess ?
                            In the Gentile churches, planted by Paul, these converts to a belief which discarded only
                            the sius and immoralities of the married life, were held in union as hearers, and formed a
                            kind of outer court to the Christian temple,- -an intermediate class which shielded the
                            genuine disciples in a measure from their less enlightened neighbors. They did not form the
                            worshippers writhia the temple, which John was directed to measure, but were the precursors
                            of the Roman and Greek churches of the preseut day. Rev. xi. Paul to Timothy, says, Receive
                            not a widow into the number, of less than sixty years of age. * * Younger widows refuse, for
                            when they have begun to wax wanton against Christ, they will marry, having condemnation,
                            because they have cast off their first faith. Their first faith then, must have been not to
                            marry, but to follow the example of Jesus, John and Paul. Wives were commanded to be in
                            subjection to their husbands, to preserve order in that class of society to which they chose
                            to belong. And unmarried women were required to have their heads covered when praying or
                            prophesying in the congregation, out of respect to the customs of a country where a veil on
                            a woman appearing in public, is both a badge of honorable distinction, and a protection from
                            insult, to this day. (See Thompson's Land and Book.) The primary reason assigned by the
                            Apostle for the restriction laid upon wives, was that they had not been permitted or
                            authorized to teach in the congregation, and he adds by way of emphasis, "For did the word
                            of God go<pb n="78" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/>out from you, or only.to you did it come?" All of which
                            indicates that they were yet in a state of vassalage to the powers of nature and the
                            elements of the world. The time for their complete liberation had not come. They had not
                            grown up to it. The typical and perfect woman who was herself the revealed Word, had not yet
                            appeared to lead them out of bondage. But now the conditions have changed, for the Word not
                            only came to, but went out from the woman (Ana Lee) who had been a wife, but whose own arm
                            wrought emancipation and salvation through the power of God that was given her, for herself
                            and her sex, and for as many of both sexes as shall receive her message. And women in this
                            part of the we rid, are making it evident they have grown to it. For now has come to pass
                            the saying "The Lord hath created a new thing in the earth ; woman shall compass maxi, " in
                            both parts of his manhood; for so does the new woman compass man in his fallen and
                            distracted state, and surround him with wisdom and knowledge to rise out of it if he will,
                            into a pure, redeemed and perfect state from which he cannot fall, because when gained,
                            there will be nothing in him that can be attracted to lower conditions. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.
                        </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Liberty enlightening the world" TEIform="index"/> "LIBERTY ENLIGHTENING THE WORLD."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stevens, Annie R." TEIform="persName"/>ANNIE R. STEVENS.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Goddess of Liberty! enlightening the nations, Pedestaled lefty on freedom's broad shore,
                            Rising majestic from thy once lowly station, Telling of victories for truth evermore.
                            Goddess of Liberty! thy triumph is glorious, Long by oppression and wrong trodden down, Thou
                            hast risen at last in thy strength victorious; Unveil forever the gems of thy crown. Hold
                            forth in the darkness thy torch-light unshaken, A beacon to ships that come in from sea,
                            Hailing the wanderer, the poor, the forsaken, To this " home of Ihe brave- -land of the
                            free." The dark rolling waves of the billowy ocean, May dash on the shore, or break on thee
                            now, Not the ebony night, nor storm cloud's commotion, Can ever bedim thy star-lighted brow.
                            O glorious symbol! the good of all ages Rolls up with time's waves like pearls on the shore,
                            And the freedom obtained by martyrs and sages, Forever is ours to praise and adore. But a
                            voice ringeth out with thrilling e'motion, Its echoes float over the land and sea, As we
                            gaze on earth's wrongs, its constant commotion 'Tis humanity calling, " are we free? "
                            Monopoly rules as with a girdle of iron, The weak are depressed by the rich and the strong,
                            Crime, poverty, sin, walk abroad like a lion; Our souls cry aloud, there's still something
                            wrong. We pray for God's kingdom a blessed elysium, When Love's royal scepter shall sway;
                            but when? O, Liberty! dwell not alone in our vision; But come make thy home in the hearts of
                            men. Adown through the aisles of time's moss-covered ages, Our minds revert to thy struggle
                            for life; And read the dark deeds writ on history's pages, Thy patience and trials, thy
                            conquests and strife. Manacled- -fettered by despotic oppression, For centuries held like a
                            slave in chains; Hopeless and helpless, bereft of compassion, Dying for light and God's
                            truth that sustains. Many have fought for thee, Goddess of Liberty, Prayed that thy day-star
                            might rise ne'er to wane, Suffered and sorrowed and lived for thee, died for thee And won by
                            the rack a true martyr's fame. It is ours to labor with purpose unshaken, To conquer as they
                            with banners unfurled, To lift up the lowly, the poor, the forsaken, And bring lasting peace
                            to a sin-bound world. Tight on, brave of heart, though ye die in the trial, Redemption's
                            great work is only begun; We may conquer sin's hosts by stern self-denial, We must finish
                            the labor left undone. What a hope is ours, like a sun bursting o'er us, The dawn of a
                            golden era is near; The deeds of great souls like a cloud goes before us, Why heed the
                            foam-crested billows of fear. 'Tis God that is with us in deeds of devotion, 'Tis God that
                            sustains through the night of fears; He sends forth his heralds to calm earth's commotion,
                            He sends forth his truth to gild the dark years. We'll faint not nor doubt, but have hope
                            for our guidThat helpeth our eyes the future to see; | ing, We know that the spirit of truth
                            is abiding, Its voice rolleth up like waves of the sea. Stand in thy majesty, Statue of
                            Liberty I A structure sublime of man s grandest art, A symbol to all of the God-given
                            victory, Thou ever wilt bring to each struggling heart.<pb n="79" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> Oh! hold forth
                            thy torch, let the whole world be lightAnd freedom's true reign of triumph begin, [ed, Till
                            the old is made new, each wrong thing is righted, May the stars of thy coronal ue'er grow
                            dim. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Be ye born again" TEIform="index"/> BE YE BORN AGAIN.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL FRASER. </byline><p TEIform="p"> To be born of the Holy Spirit, is not ouly within the scope of human possibilities, bit it
                            is in our destiny to be so born- -to be sinless, and to be holy- -to live for others- -to
                            organize heaven upon earth, or in the laud ot souls. The spiritual emotions of our lower- -
                            the human animal life, organizes family relationships and family partialities. These give
                            form to the civilizations " of earth. It is within the scope of man's will that these
                            civilizations be just or malignant. If malignant, then there will be kingdoms divided
                            against themselves as is the case to-day. To receive the Holy Spirit as a little child, be
                            created, and help others to be created anew, are the beginnings of heavenly wisdom. That
                            spirit created the Pentecostal church. And in these "latter days," Shaker Communities. They
                            are the products of the Holy Spirit; they-cm be sustained only by, and through its
                            operation. Separate yourself from everything untoward and ye shall receive the Holy Spirit.
                            Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="One at a time" TEIform="index"/>"ONE AT A TIME."
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Tharin, C. G." TEIform="persName"/> C. G. THARIN. 
                        </byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> One step at a time, and that well placed, We
                                    reach the grandest height; One stroke at a time, earth's hidden stores Will slowly
                                    come to light; One seed at a time, and the forest grows; One drop at a time and the
                                    river flows Into the boundless sea. One word at a tinu1, and the greatest book Is
                                    written and is read; One stone at a time, a palace rears Aloft its stately liead;
                                    One blow at a time, and the tree's cleft thro' And a city will stand where the
                                    forest grew A few short years before. One foe at a time, and he subdued, And the
                                    conflict will be won; One grain at a time, and the sands of life Will slowly all be
                                    run. One minute, another, the hours fly; One day at a time, and our lives speed by
                                    Into eternity. [stored; One grain of knowledge, and that well Another, and more on
                                    them ; [shine And, as time rolls on, your mind will With many a garnered gem Of
                                    thought and wisdom. And time will tell. "One thing at a time, and that done well,"
                                    Is wisdom's proven rule. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Golden days" TEIform="index"/> Golden Days.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True and faithful" TEIform="index"/> TRUE AND FAITHFUL.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sutton, Elizaette" TEIform="persName"/> ELIZAETTE SUTTON.</byline><p TEIform="p"> As 1 was passing from one building to another the other day, some one said to me "true and
                            faithful." My heart bounded with joy. 1 thought, if this is applied to me, what more could I
                            wish at the termination of my life's journey, than that these two words might be spoken to
                            me in the fulness of their meaning ; that the merits of my character might be summed up in
                            this simple language. For a moment I doubted whether I had ever convinced any one, by actual
                            works of this ; or that intelligences above could justly award me this high encomium. Then I
                            listened to my thoughts awhile, and drew therefrom this information. We are true, if we
                            conform to the pattern given us, we<pb n="80" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> are faithful if allegiance to it is
                            unreserved. In works of art we use our natural senses. The eye is the close observer of the
                            object to be copied, and the more we bring this into requisition the more exact will be our
                            copy. We look at our design with intensified feelings, and the hand seems to be imbued with
                            the soul of sight, and works it out. We turn, and gaze upon it, and then pronounce it a true
                            duplicate. The eye was not all that was needed, the purpose entered the heart, and found a
                            resting place, the seat of emotion and study. The astronomer goes to his telescope, watches
                            the heavenly bodies ia their motion, and can discern their movements, positions, heights,
                            and developments, through that instrument. With what avidity he studies their laws, and
                            buries the science in his bosom, as a part and parcel of himself. His true nature in this,
                            is a power in his being, a magnet joining him to his subject, and he be comes the avenue of
                            intellectual history throughout the world. The scholar in Natural History, absorbs himself
                            in the theme he has adopted, and nothing deters him from a full accomplishment of it. What
                            if the knowledge that has been hidden in the iield of nature, embodied in the ocean, in the
                            mountain, the earth under our feet, and in the world of living matter, wrought out with zest
                            by the truest part of humanity, is cultivating, educating men and women for another and
                            higher degree of information, belonging to their present and future'- -welfare and
                            development ? The beam of light from Bartholdi's Statue of Liberty renews the question,- -
                            Will the souvenir of France, which surpasses all preceding luminaries of the world, and
                            which is calling people from far off countries to witness its splendor, and its electric
                            flashes that are flooding the land; startle them into deeper thoughts, with a broad base of
                            the Infinite worker? If the scientist is not a religionist nominally, he may be a trusty
                            servant, to direct mankind into such paths, as will lead them to the Author of all truth.
                            The effect of his studies may be like the leaven, which the woman hid in three measures of
                            meal; though out of sight, the process of fermentation is effectual but gradual. True to its
                            nature and office it leavens the whole ma3S for a wise purpose. What if the issue of his
                            knowledge to man, blends the earth and the heavens together ? Why, symmetrical lives will
                            adorn our homes and country, and the palm of success and triumph will lie on the threshold
                            of our mortal habitations. If all that is true in two spheres, will rest and abide with us,
                            will not the happiness we long for be ours? We seek, and we wish to fiud. If we are faithful
                            to pursue specified plans, can our conditions be better in this, or in a future life? Our
                            pattern, Jesus, must be studied, and through faithfulness to imitate him, will the duplicate
                            be made perfect. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="But I have a baptism to be..." TEIform="index"/>But I have a baptism to be...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Newton, Agnes E." TEIform="persName"/>AGNES E. NEWTON. </byline><p TEIform="p"> " But I have a baptism to be baptized with; and how am I straitened untilit be
                            accomplished." These are the words of Him upon whose soul rested the mission of the
                            Christ-life. Possessed of human loves, appetites and ambitions to a degree that<pb n="81" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/>rendered him susceptible to all of the temptations that beset the human heart,
                            yet never swerving trom the path of duty ; the will of his Heavenly Father the guide of his
                            life. After having received the baptism of the Holy Spirit, at the Jordan, when the Heavens
                            were opened and God's blessing descended upon Him, and the voice was heard declwiug Him to
                            be the beloved son in whom the Father was well pleased, came the soul trial and testing
                            which proved Him to be the Christ- -the anointed of G-ol. In the wilderness of trial and
                            upon the mountain of temptation, we interpret to be a state of the mind, where all the
                            Kingdoms and glories of this world were alluringly placed before Him. Obedience to his
                            sacred mission manifested itself in the soul meaning expression, " Get thee hence, Satan ;
                            for it is written thou shalt worship the Lord thy God, and Him only shalt thou serve. " How
                            complete the triumph, when the powers of evil surrendered and angels came and ministered
                            unto Him. Can the followers of Christ do less than did their Lord and Master and expect to
                            reign with Him in the Kingdom of God? "Except a man forsake not all that he hath he cannot
                            be my disciple;" are words sufficiently plain for a mind of ordinary capacity fully to
                            comprehend. Our Savior himself declared that all men could not receive his saying. They were
                            more directly to those for whose benefit they were especially given. We would infer from
                            this that He referred to the spiritually enlightened class, those who had felt the drawings
                            of the Father and were willing for the Kingdom of Heaven's sake to forsake all; and thus
                            inherit the beautiful promise given to Peter, when he said to the Savior, "Lo, we have left
                            all and followed thee. " Jesus said unto him, " Verily I say unto you, There is no man that
                            hath left house, or parents, or brethren, or wife, or children, for the Kingdom of God's
                            sake, who shall not receive manifold more in this present time and in the world to come
                            everlasting life." The followers of Christ must indeed drink of the same cup and be baptized
                            with the same baptism as was the pattern ; and how straitened, careful and prayerful they
                            should be until the perfect work of Grace be fully consummated. Canterbury, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beyond" TEIform="index"/>THE BEYOND
                        </head><p TEIform="p">[Contributed by Mary.] <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> It seemeth such a little way to me, Across to that strange country-
                                    -the beyond: And yet not strange, for it has grown to be The home of those of whom I
                                    am so fond. What makes it seem familiar and most dear, As journeying friends bring
                                    distant regions near. So close it lies that when my sight is clear, I think I almost
                                    see the gleaming strand; I know I feel those who have gone from here Come near
                                    enough sometimes to touch my hand. I often think but for our veiled eyes, We should
                                    find heaven round about us lies. I cannot make it seem a day to dread When from this
                                    dear earth I shall journey out To that still dearer country of the dead, And join
                                    the loved ones I have dreamed about. I love this world, but I shall love to go And
                                    meet the friends who wait for me, I know. I never stand alone awhile and see The
                                    seal of death set on some well loved face, But that I think one more to welcome me
                                    When I shall cross the intervening space Between this land and that one over there-
                                    - One more to make the strange beyond more fair. And as for me there is no sting to
                                    death, And so the grave has lost its victory; It is but crossing, with a bated
                                    breath, And white set face, a little strip of sea, To fin 1 the loved ones waiting
                                    on the shore More beautiful, more precious than before. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Be thy purpose just though hidden" TEIform="index"/>Be thy purpose just though hidden
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Be thy purpose just though hidden.</p></div2><pb n="82" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian communism no. 1" TEIform="index"/> CHRISTIAN
                            COMMUNISM. NO. 1.</head><p TEIform="p">[TAKEN PROM THE CINCINNATI POST.] How the Shaker Society was founded in Ohio. Great times on the banks of Turtle Creek. Armed
                            Mobs, Calumnies and bitter Persecution. The Shakers have the open secret of a happy and
                            worthy life. The wintry day of March 22, 1805, was well progressed when three men, clad in
                            strange garb and tramping one after the other through the snow in Indian file, emerged from
                            the great forest which then covered the divide between the Big and Little Miamis into
                            Malcham Worley's stumpy clearing, near Turtle creek, about four miles from the present town
                            of Lebanon, Warren Co., 0. They advanced to the door of Worley's double log cabin and
                            knocked. With true Western hospitality they were invited in and given seats before the fire
                            which glowed and blazed in the great fireplace. They introduced themselves as John Meacham,
                            Benjamin Youngs and Issacher Bates. Briefly and in simple language they told how they had
                            come a thousand miles, THROUGH THE WILDERNESS from Mt. Lebanon, in the eastern part of N. Y.
                            State, near the point where the three States of N. Y., Mass, and Conn. meet. They told of
                            their march in the dead of winter through leagues of unbroken forests, how they had crossed
                            the Hudson, the Delaware, the Susquehanna, the Chenango, the Chemung, the Allegheny, the
                            Mahoning, the Tuscarawas, the Muskingum and the Scioto as they pushed westward. "We have
                            heard at Mt. Lebanon of the great revival of religion you have had in Ky. and heie in
                            Southern Ohio, " said they, "and we are now on our way to Kentucky to tell them of the happy
                            mode kof primitive Christian life we have found at Mt. Lebanon, and to ascertain whether
                            there be not some among the converts of your great revival who want to embrace what we are
                            constrained to believe the better part." Eeligion at that time was the great theme of the
                            settlement on Turtle creek; anybody who had anything new and useful to tell on the absorbing
                            subject was a welcome guest. In answer to eager questions, the three strange brethren told
                            how they lived at Mt. Lebanon. SECRET OF A HAPPY LIFE. "None of us count anything our own,
                            but we have all things in common. We have no rich man, who comes in and is told to sit here
                            in a good place, and no poor man, who is told to stand aside there, out of the way. We all '
                            work, laboring with our own hands, ' that we may 'provide things honest in the sight of all
                            men,' for, says St. Paul, 'if any man will not work, neither let him eat.' We are none of us
                            perfect, but we ' confess our sins one to another,' because the promise is to him who '
                            confesseth and forsaketh sin.' We all live as brothers and sisters, and not as husbands and
                            wives, patterning in this, as in all other respects, after the Lord Jesus Christ, our 'Elder
                            Brother,' with whom, in spirit, we walk from day to day; and, according to the promise, He
                            and His Father come in unto us and sup with us. We seek and enjoy the blessing promised to
                            the poor in spirit, to the meek, to the pure in heart, to the peace-makers, to those who
                            hunger and thirst after righteousness, and to those who are reviled for Jesus' sake." " And
                            who taught you all this and first started you in this mode of life?" was the interested
                            query of the Worlt ys. " We find it all in the New Testament, which is our sure word of
                            testimony, and having which we neither desire nor need any written creed. The first one to
                            point out to us how plainly this 'better part' is taught in the New Testament, and to start
                            us in this mode of life, was that holy and inspired woman of God, Mother Ann Lee, who spent
                            her whole time in nothing else except to preach this gospel of the New Testament, and to
                            exhort all persons whom she met to forsake their sins and turn to God, who will have mercy,
                            and to our God, for He will abundantly pardon. She traveled all over Eastern New York, Mass,
                            and Conn., teaching, exhorting and preaching this gospel of the kingdom, and gathering
                            societies in different places. Her word was ' with demonstration of the spirit and with
                            power from on high.'" A SENSATION ON TURTLE CREEK This was wonderful new light to the
                                Wor-<pb n="83" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> leys, who were inclined gladly to receive it, but first they
                            wanted to know what their pastor, Rev. Richard McNemar, thought of it, and he was brought to
                            the Worley cabin in the evening to hear and see the strangers and to discuss the subject
                            with them. For this Rev. Richard McNemar, pastor of the Turtle creek Presbyterian church,
                            was a mighty man in the Scriptures. He could read the Old Testament in the Hebrew and the
                            New Testament in Greek, and was equally at home in the Septuagint and Vulgate translations.
                            He was a " son of thunder." Mr. Worley himself was a " man of liberal education, independent
                            fortune and unblemished reputation," one of the pillars of the Turtle creek Presbyterian
                            church. In front of the roaring log fire in the big fire-place that wintry evening of March
                            22, 1805, were seated Mr. and Mrs. Worley and their numerous children, the three strangers
                            in their queer garb, Rev. Mr. McNemar and possibly some of the neighbors. Tall, gaunt and of
                            thoughtful countenance, Mr. McNemar turned his piercing eyes from one to another of the
                            strangers as they told again the story of their New Testament life. "But you must certainly
                            recognize the fact that God who ' hath set the earth in families ' would not have the human
                            race to cease, as it certainly would if all should adopt celibacy." " Yea." " And even in
                            the church, if its members should join themselves to communities lik^ yours, the children of
                            the church would cease, and what then would become of the promises of God, which are to us
                            and to our children? Would you have us make of none effect these promises? " BETTER MARRY
                            THAN BURN. " Nay. ' He that is able to receive it, let him receive it.' All are not able,
                            and it is better to marry than to burn.' Nevertheless ' the kingdom ot heaven still
                            sufFereth violence and the violent take it by force.' " Now and then Mrs. Worley rose during
                            this discussion and snuffed the guttering "tallow dips " and poked the wick out wide so that
                            the flame would be larger, and Mr. Worley heaped the wood on the big fire. "But surely
                            fatherhood and motherhood are essential elements of the perfect human character. It is by
                            our fatherhood that we apprehend and appreciate the fatherhood of God, and the New Testament
                            is full of injunctions regarding marriage, and the reciprocal duties of husbands and wives
                            and parents and children. One of the Ten Commandments relates to the duties of children to
                            their parents." After this manner Rev. Mr. McNemar argued. " Yea: but we do not hold that
                            all should lead a celibate life. We maintain that it is the best way to live, if one is
                            able, and that ' the time is come when they that have wives should be as they that have them
                            not.' But we concede that all are not called thereto, nor are all able therefore." THE
                            JERKS. With such discourse the evening wore away and Mr. McNemar, before they separated for
                            the night, told the strangers of the great work of God in Kentucky in 1801, in which he had
                            a part, being at that time preaching in Kentucky. He told how scores and hundreds had fallen
                            like dead men under the power of the Word and of the strange phenomenon of "the jerks." "
                            You never saw this manifestation of the spirit which we call the jerks?" queried Mr.
                            McNemar. " Nay." " Well, there is nothing in nature could better represent this strange and
                            unaccountable operation than for one to goad another alternately on every side with a piece
                            of hot iron The exercise commonly began in the head, which would fly backward and forward
                            and from side to side with a quick jolt, which the person would naturally labor to suppress,
                            but in vain; and the more any one labored to steady himself and be sober, the more he
                            staggered, and the more his twitches increased. He must necessarily go as he was inclined,
                            whether with a violent dash to the ground and bounce from place to place like a football, or
                            hop round with head, limbs and trunk twitching and jolting in every direction as if they
                            must invariably fall asunder. And how such could escape without injury was no small wonder
                            among spectators. "By this strange operation the human frame was commonly so transformed and
                                dis-<pb n="84" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/>figured as to lose every trace of its natural appearance.
                            Sometimes the face would be twitched right and left to a half round with such velocity that
                            not a feature could be discovered, and the face appeared as much behind as before ; and in
                            the quick progressive jerking it would seem as if the person were transformed into some
                            other species of creature. Head dresses were of little account among the female jerks. Even
                            handkerchiefs, bound tight around the head would be flirted off almost with the first
                            twitch, and the hair put into the utmost confusion. This was a very great inconvenience, and
                            the generality of the women therefore were shorn, though contrary to their confession of
                            faith. Such as were seized with the jerks were wrested, not only from under their own
                            government, but that of everyone else, so that it was dansrerous to attempt confining them
                            or touching them in any manner. But whatever danger they were exposed to, yet few were hurt,
                            except it were such as rebelled against the operation through self-will and deliberate
                            enmity, and refused to comply with the injunctions it had come to enforce." [The above is
                            taken from McNemar's writings. Peter Cartright, the famous Methodist pioneer preacher, says
                            of the "jerks : " "I have seen more than 500 persons jerking at once in my large
                            congregations. To see these proud, well-dressed gentlemen and ladies take the jerks would
                            often make me laugh. The first jerk or so, you would see their fine bonnets, caps and combs
                            fly, and so sudden would be the jerking that their long, loose hair would crack almost as
                            loud as a wagoner's whip."] NEW CONVEBTS. The outcome of the evening's discussion was that
                            Malcham Worley and his wife were convinced of the desirability of the Shaker mode of life,
                            and they decided to be the first to embrace it and to found on Turtle creek a society the
                            counterpart of that at Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. Before Richard McNemar returned to his own home
                            that evening he had invited the three Shaker brethren to preach in Turtle creek Presbyterian
                            church the following Sunday, and they had consented. Great was the interest throughout all
                            that region when the appointment was noised abroad. Ordinarily Eev. Mr. McNemar had
                            overflowing congregations, so that in summer adjournment to the adjoining grove had to be
                            resorted to to accommodate the throngs, and on Sunday evenings in winter log fires were
                            built about the church to warm those who could not get inside the church for the crowd. When
                            Sunday came the congregations both morning and evening were phenomenal and many were
                            convinced of the beauty of the simple and primitive, loving, Christ-like life preached by
                            the Shakers. In the next few weeks a dozen families embraced the new mode of life and among
                            them was that of Mr. McNemar, who himself had become an ardent and influential convert. THE
                            SOCIETY ORGANIZES. May 25, 1805, nine weeks after the arrival of the brethren from Mt.
                            Lebanon, they organized the society of Union Village on the banks of Turtle creek. In July
                            of that year other Shakers came out from Mt. Lebanon, and in the following year several
                            others. In three years the number of persons in the society had increased to 150. Many of
                            the converts were land owners and men of high standing in the community. Naturally the new
                            movement awakened a very strong opposition from those who remained "out in the world." Great
                            bitterness was felt by relatives and prospective heirs of those who joined the society and
                            took with them their earthly possessions, which they consecrated forever to the common use
                            of the society. Among the fiercest denouncers and persecutors of the community and its
                            members were those who called themselves Christians, and who were known to the outside world
                            as "NewLights." GO TO KEEPING HOUSE. On June 6 of the following year, 1806, the society
                            removed from Malcham Worley's to its own house called "South House." In September of that
                            year a blacksmith shop was put up, and the next month the foundations of a frame house were
                            laid. Two years later the society built its first sawmill, and on Jan. 8 of the following
                            year, 1809, the society held its first services in the first meeting-house built by it.
                            Meantime persecution and calumny had<pb n="85" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> steadily increased. There were
                            many fears of an Indian uprising against the white settlers. These constant anxieties on
                            this account were not finally dispelled till the signal victory of Gen. (afterward
                            President) Harrison over the Indians at the battle of Tippecanoe, on Tippecanoe river,
                            Indiana, in 1811. The Shakers have always made it a part of their religion to hospitably
                            entertain all who sought their hospitality. Hence, when half starved bands of Indians camped
                            in their vicinity, and asked of them food, they gave it to them without money and without
                            price, that they might "be the children of their Father in Heaven; for He maketh His sun to
                            shine on the evil and on the good, and sendeth His rain on the just and on the unjust." This
                            Christian kindness of the Shakers to the Indians was misinterpreted by the white settlers of
                            the two Miami valleys, and the story soon gained circulation and wide credence that the
                            Shakers and the Indians were in league to rise and massacre all the settlers in the two
                            valleys and possess their lands. READY-MADE LIES The human mind is ever ready to conjecture
                            ill where none exists, and "many men living in the vicinity of Union Village believed that
                            the leaders of the new sect were designing imposters, living in secret sins of the darkest
                            dye," and these neighbors of the simple-mannered and kindly community were ready to wage a
                            war of extermination against it, and drive it from the land. " Reports were also circulated
                            of their keeping women and children with them against their consent, and holding them by
                            force in bondage from which they were seeking to escape." These false accusations finally
                            resulted, Aug. 27, 1810, in the raising of an armed mob of nearly 500 men led by a
                            Presbyterian minister named Matthew G. Wallace, which marched against the village with the
                            avowed purpose of releasing all the women and children confined there and of driving the
                            members of the community from the country. News of the gathering of the mob reached Lebanon
                            in advance of the arrival of the shouting rioters at the Shaker village, and a number of
                            cool-headed, law-abiding citizens hastened over to the community, four miles away, to help
                            preserve the peace. Francis Dunlavy, presiding Judge of the Court of Common Pleas, then in
                            session, adjourned court, and on a fleet horse rode over to Union Village, arriving there in
                            time to read the Riot act to the angry and blustering mob. "Joshua Corbett, Matthias Corwin,
                            sr., and a number of intelligent men did all in their power to protect the Shakers from
                            violence." ARMED FORCE VS. CHRISTIAN MEEKNESS. Here was the first great public test of the
                            peace principles of the new, little community. Arrayed against the little band of about 200
                            unarmed and unresisting men, women and children, was a company of twice as many men armed
                            with guns, pistols, swords, pikes and all conceivable weapons. Before the raging, hooting
                            mob, "breathing out threatenings and slaughter," stood the few men of the society speaking
                            words of peace and soberness. When some sort of quiet had been gained Rev. Mr. Wallace, with
                            eleven others, advanced and in the name ot the mob demanded that the community should
                            relinquish its principles, property, mode of worship and manner of living, or quit the
                            country. " The answer of the elders of the community was mild and calm, but plain and
                            positive. It was in substance that they esteemed their faith dearer than their lives, and
                            were determined to maintain it whatever might be the consequences. As to quitting the
                            country, they were upon their own land which they had purchased with their own money, and
                            that they were entitled to those liberties which were granted by the laws of their country,
                            including liberty of conscience." THE PREMISES SEARCHED. "As to false and lying reports that
                            any are detained here against their will," continued the spokesman for the community, "or
                            that any children are harshly or cruelly treated by us in any particular, our buildings and
                            premises are opened to you. Send a committee of your own selection through them. Freely
                            question any you meet and satisfy yourselves that we are a quiet, orderly people trying to
                            serve God in the manner He has prescribed in His word." A committee was appointed by the mob
                            and a thorough search of the premises was<pb n="86" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> made. On my visit to Union
                            Village last week, I met bright, vivacious old ladies, considerably past eighty years of
                            age, who told me of their recollections of that search, and of their timorous wonder when
                            the committee called them and questioned them of their treatment an i of their wish, whether
                            to go away from the community or to stay there. The committee on its return to the mob was
                            compelled to report that it found everything orderly and attractive, and that everbody, from
                            the little tottlers playing in the yard to the oldest man and woman in the community, was to
                            all appearance, as well as by his own confession, contented, well-cared for and happy. The
                            mob thereupon went away in great confusion of mind, firing its guns in the air and making a
                            great show of bravado to show its chagrin and shamefacedness. The result was a great
                            accession to the numbers of the little community. In 1813 and 1817, and at other times
                            previous to 1820, smaller mobs visited the community, but did no harm beyond breaking the
                            front door down on one occasion. GREAT PROSPERITY On Jan. 14, 1812, the first ministry was
                            constituted and the church covenant signed. There were 370 members in the community at that
                            time. A carding-house was built in 1813, a gristmill in 1815 and an oilmill in 1816. In the
                            diary of the society appears this quaint record : " 1819 ; The Sheriff takes a horse and
                            yoke of oxen for muster fines. Nathan Sharp, finding the animals in Lebanon, turns v;hem
                            loose and they return home." In 1829 the society reached its highest point in respect of
                            numbers, having 304 "covenant members" and 500 persons in the community all told. Two years
                            later there was the largest defection from the membership of any year of its history. It was
                            at this time, and for a few years afterward, that much property of the society was destroyed
                            by incendiary fires. On Mar. 25 of that year the society's flax barn was burned. Two weeks
                            later the West sawmill was set on fire, but the flames were put out. On June 9, 1835, Turtle
                            creek rose with the greatest flood of its history. Three mills and the clothier's shop were
                            swept away, and the oilmill and gristmill were much damaged, so that it took $10,000 to
                            repair the losses. Nathan Sharp, "leading man of the society," also left it that year. On
                            the whole, it was a disastrous year. There were only 330 members. In 1839 Rev. Richard
                            McNemar died. In 1852-54 the society began the importation of registered Short-horn (Durham)
                            stock, and made a good deal of money by raising and selling this stocK. The society yet
                            breeds the Durham cattle. In 1860 the members numbered 364. Since that time the numbers have
                            steadily decreased by death, till now there are only about 125 members, all told. To-morrow
                            I hope to tell of the habits and practices of the society, and of the incidents of my very
                            pleasant stay there.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Kaiandri, Theodore" TEIform="persName"/> Theo. Kaiandri. </byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Chapel in the heart" TEIform="index"/>A CHAPEL IN THE HEART
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> Thrice blessed is the man who keeps From other things
                                    apart A secret-room- -a holy place- - A chapel in the heart. For there, when all the
                                    world without Grows dark unto his sight, He may retire and find within His chapel
                                    full of light. And there, when jangling sounds of earth Fall discord on the ear, He
                                    can return, and, undisturbed, The eternal music hear; And there he hastens when the
                                    world Loud praises to confess, With deep and true humility, His own unworthiness.
                                    Thither, when with a golden snare Temptation hems his way, He quickly turns, with
                                    trembling lip, And bated breath, to pray. Thrice blessed is the man who keeps, From
                                    other things apart, This secret-room, this holy place, This chapel in the heart.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Messenger of peace" TEIform="index"/>Messenger of Peace.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is easier to act..." TEIform="index"/>It is easier to act...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> It is easier to act the Martyr than to conquer one's temper.</p></div2><pb n="87" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tribute of affection to the memory of Bro. Granville T. Sproat" TEIform="index"/> A Tribute
                            of Affection to the Memory of Bro. Granville T. Sproat. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Staples, Florence" TEIform="persName"/>FLORENCE STAPLES.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Calm and serene from out a cloudless sky 'Mid roseate, amber hues, a sun hath set The
                            lengthening shadows, twilight gray The hallowed hush, with hope and faith were met, By one
                            who gladly trod the path of life, Till time was o'er and its short span was run; Or one who
                            waited patiently to hear The summons from the Father, ta- -k is done! No sable pall
                            enshrouds his spirit form, For death is not; but final triumph's given. As here he shares
                            his peace, his rest in God, As here he shares the state of bliss, of heaven. Awoke to
                            glories of a grand beyond, The real; the type of which revealed we see; To realize the
                            blessedness of faith, A life in truth to God devoted free. Why mourn, O mortals, and in
                            anguish weep? Why seek to wrestle from the hand of fate? Firm reason in her magic sceptered
                            sway Through stern affliction, bids us hope, and wait. He lingers near, his presence still
                            we feel As angel choirs a song of welcome sing: The grave! the grave! Ah! hath its victory?
                            And death yea death! where is its blight or sting? Above the tomb the drapery of night Whose
                            cold embrace conceals the casket frail; The spirit greets the cheerful morning light, Beyond
                            the confines of time's misty veil. O upward step! Oh resurrection grand! Thro' thee
                            progression's march is on and on, The goal of life- -perfection's heights attained, The rich
                            reward- -the conqueror's crown is won. Life, life the breath of inspiration given, Soul of
                            existence quenchless living flame; From the eternal source and fountain given Recedes unto
                            its origin again. 'Tis change, revolving elements attest; Its truth sublime in clear
                            imperial light Gleams forth in lessons from the glittering page, Whereen we trace no
                            darkening shades of blight. The fragile flower, in dewy splendor graced, Kissed by the fair
                            the rosy light of morn; Ere noontide melts to soften shades of eve; The withering blast may
                            tear its fairy form. Fond recollection still survives, and cheers, And the sweet incense of
                            its perfumed breath Exhaled upon the gale defines the law, Declares the truth, 'tis change,
                            'tis change! not death. The pure and noble- -wealth immortalize, The structure reared in
                            dignity and grace, The soul's true merit, high attainments wrought, Time's fingers ne'er can
                            on these tarnish trace. But ere expanding in the great beyond The Godlike powers unlimited
                            and free Finds growth eternal; 'tis man's destiny Through rolling ages of eternity. O sweet
                            assurance, trust, and living hope; No vague ideal enshrines our spirits now, Bright scenes
                            sublime in grandeur to us ope, Before thy shrine all must in reverence bow. We know ajar the
                            shining portals stand And feel the angel's ministry to day; The visitants from the blest
                            summer land Who've come to bear the dear loved one away. But not a far, nay, not a distant
                            land, 'Tis but a veil that screens it from our view, His spirit triumphs in the victory now,
                            The conquest of the noble, pure and true. The long, the glorious race is fully run; The
                            Master calls, and faithful to obey He hears the welcome, my beloved well done ! And enters
                            realms of everlasting day. Canaan, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Might have been" TEIform="index"/>MIGHT HAVE BEEN
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cooper, George" TEIform="persName"/>GEORGE COOPER
                        </byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">I might have been more patient- - Ah ! would the
                                    angry word Upon my lips had perished, LTnuttered and unheard! Some heart would now
                                    be lighter To wend its toilsome way; Some life would be more cheerful, More sunshiny
                                    to-day. I might have been more kindly- - Hovr trifling is the cost Of simple deeds
                                    of goodness, Whose power is never lost! The golden moment vanished, And never to
                                    return; The glory of bestowing, Too late, too late I learn! I might have been more
                                    loving To those who hold me dear; What little deeds, neglected, Had soothed their
                                    pathway here ! The hasty word or action That pained a gentle heart, Ah! will its
                                    mournful memory From out our life depart? "I might have been ! "- -sad burden Of
                                    life's remorseful song, Within the heart forever Its haunting echoes throng. Oh,
                                    youth, upon the threshold, To this sweet lesson bow : For deeds of love and
                                    kindness, Life has one season- -Now!</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/> Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="88" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p"> THE MANIFESTO. APRIL, 1887. Office of publication. The Manifesto is published at Shaker
                            Village, Mer. Co. N. H. All articles for publication should be addressed to Henry C. Blinn,
                            and all letters on financial busines to A. Y. Cochran. One copy per year, postage paid, " "
                            six months, " " Send for specimen copy, free. .75 .40 I0TS8. T</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>NOTES. </head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cross of Christ" TEIform="index"/> THE CROSS OF CHRIST.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> It should become a subject of the deepest interest, to ascertain what may be the
                                essential features of a religious order that bears within itself the elements of eternal
                                life. Those who read the record that has so miraculously escaped the floods and flames,
                                and see the self-sacrificing life work of the humble Nazarene, may have cause for
                                serious reflection, upon the seemingly mysterious ways of Providence. Long before the
                                advent of Jesus, the revelation of God to man presented a cross which demanded an order
                                of life peculiarly characteristic of the guiding spirit that sent it. It was the
                                introduction of a moral law. Men began to bridle their tongues and their passions, and
                                to study the humanity of man. To do this effectually demanded rigid laws,
                                self-discipline and a constant presentation of the cross of that dispensation. Although
                                the Mosaic order has been termed a law of carnal commandments, of meats and drinks, it
                                was evidently one of the essential progressive steps for the race to take, that we might
                                occupy the place, which in the Providence of God, is proffered to this generation. Every
                                nation presents some form of a cross to its people, and indeed, every in dividual is
                                obliged, either voluntarily or iuvoluutarily to accept a cross, a measure of
                                self-discipline in order to maintain a place among men. In whatever way this may come
                                and secure a position in the mind of man, its influence must be for the development of
                                an advanced thought. It may come through laws, wars, floods or flames. The old, the
                                effete passes away, and a better takes its place. It was after the sanguinary and
                                conquering wars of the Romans, and in the peaceful reigu of the Caesar, that Jesus
                                proclaimed the coming of the Kingdom of God. Fearfully devastating wars had also humbled
                                the Jewish nation, and opened the door through which a new and a better order of things
                                could pass. Jesus came, and although he found, in the heart of man, many plants which
                                the Heavenly Father had not planted, he had the pleasure of finding a few congenial
                                minds who were ready to accept the message which he had been commissioned to bring. It
                                was a new order of the Cross, a new discipline for the mind, a new system for the
                                domestic relations, for those who believed on him. Every thing was to be established on
                                a new basis. If there had been a heaven, or a heaven of heavens, where the faithful
                                servants of God of former generations had been gathered to rest from their labors there
                                was to be formed, in this sys,em, a new heaven into which nothing 88 TERMS.<pb n="89" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> could enter that was defiled or false, or that did not bear the impress
                                of the resurrection spirit, as manifested in the life ot Jesus. The old earth which had
                                nourished and protected the selfish and sensual, was like the old heavens, to pass away,
                                and in its place would appear the new earth in which should dwell righteousness and
                                peace. If we have not found an abode in the new heavens and new earth, "wherein dwelleth
                                righteousness," then it io quite certain that we have not found the Kingdom of God,
                                where the spirit of Christ rei ns, and equally as certain that we have not found the
                                cross of Christ, which teaches, that unless we deny ourselves of all ungodliness and
                                every worldly lust we cannot become a disciple of our Lord, Jesus Christ. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary. </head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Self-cure" TEIform="index"/>SELF-CURE
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> The body, to a large extent, is a machine which, when disarranged,
                                        repairs itself. Physicians tell us of the vis mcdica, rix natures- -the power to
                                        heal inherent in nature. It is natural to get well. The body's recuperative
                                        resources are not equal to every need, but they are very great. It is because of
                                        this even that the well man tends to keep well, if he conforms to nature's laws,
                                        for the system is ever full of poison from its own waste, the disposal of which
                                        nature has provided for, better than any city has for the disposal of its deadly
                                        sewerage. Take the case of an ordinary wound. It needs only to have its
                                        disrupted parts brought together and nature does the healing; and even in many
                                        cases where the parts are not brought together, nature fills up the space with
                                        new flesh. So nature will mend a broken bone, on the simple condition that the
                                        adjusted parts be allowed the requisite rest. Dyspepsia, whether induced by
                                        improper eating, the neglect of exercise, brain overwork, or care, worry and
                                        fret, will in time wholly disappear on removal of the cause and compliance with
                                        the laws of nature. The best physicians now freely admit that typhoid patients,
                                        in the great majority of cases, would recover without a drop of medicine ; that
                                        they need medicine mainly to promote ease and comfort, and that pure air is
                                        better for them tlian all drugs. The same is true of some other diseases. More
                                        and more is it being admitted that, in no case, no drugs have any curative
                                        powers, but only aid nature, as the surgeon aids in the case of a badly broken
                                        limb, by removing irritating bits, spiculse, etc., and securing the proper
                                        adjustment and fixation of the parts. The old-time doctors greatly overdosed
                                        people- -in multitudes of cases literally dosed people fo death. Within less
                                        than twenty years a personal friend, called to watch with a neighbor far gone in
                                        consumption, was shown eleven different medicines, each of which she was to
                                        administer during the night, according to the varying symptoms. It cannot be too
                                        strongly emphasized that those who observe the laws of their physical nature are
                                        likely to keep well- -and even infectious diseases have little power over such
                                        persons, and would wholly disappear if all observed these laws.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/>Hall's Journal of Health.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Water in food" TEIform="index"/>WATER IN FOOD
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> The action of water in our food, says a medical writer, is
                                        very important. There would be no carrying of food into the system but for the
                                        agency of water. It dissolve* everything that we take, and nothing that we take
                                        as food can become nutriment that is not dissolved in water. It would not do to
                                        test that by taking things and putting them into water and seeing whether they
                                        dissolve, and rejecting them as food according to that circumstance ; because
                                        food undergoes a considerable change in the stomach. It undergoes a change, to
                                        begin with, in our mouth. One of the great objects of that change is to render
                                        things soluble which have been before<pb n="90" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> insoluble in water.
                                        Starch, which we cannot dissolve in water out of the stomach, is dissolved in
                                        water directly it gets into the mouth, for the starch is changed by the saliva
                                        into sugar, and that which would lie unchanged in water for months is so changed
                                        by the saliva of the mouth and the gastric juice of the stomach that it is
                                        speedily dissolved. Hence, when we are taking considerable quantities of dry
                                        food, it becomes absolutely necessary that we should add a certain quan. tity of
                                        water, so that this dry food should become dissolved. Such things as oats,
                                        barley, wheat, rice, maize and other articles of diet containing little water,
                                        must have water added, in order that their starch, fat and gluten may be
                                        dissolved and enter into the system.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/>Hall's Journal of Health. </bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Testimony of Zipporah Cory" TEIform="index"/> TESTIMONY of ZIPPORAH CORY.</head><p TEIform="p">I was born in Plaiufield, Connecticut, April 4th, 1765. When I was eleven years of age, I had
                            very serious reflections concerning the salvation of my soul, and often retired alone to cry
                            and pray to God in the best manner I was able. When I was twelve, my parents moved into
                            Cheshire, Massachusetts. At the age of fourteen I began to go into company, and by that
                            means wore off my conviction ; but in about two years it returned upon me heavier than ever.
                            In this state of mind I was naturally led to look around upon the professors of religion, to
                            see if they lived any better than I did ; but 1 did not see any in whom I could wholly
                            confide : for they would allow themselves in that which I knew to be wicked. I used to tell
                            some of the young people who professed to be Christians, that they were no better than I
                            was, and I did not profess any religion. In the spring of 1781, being then sixteen years of
                            age, I went with, a number of young people, to attend a meeting of the Believers, in
                            Cheshire. My mother had visited the family before, and had received faith ; but my father
                            was a great opposer. By what I saw and heard of their doctrine, worship and manner of life,
                            I was soon convinced that they were of God, While they were in the worship of God, I
                            observed one of the sisters and her countenance was very solemn, and she wept. I believed
                            them to be the people of God aud thought I was left to be lost with the wicked. Ob ou"
                            return home, some of my companions were very rude, and mocked the exercises they had seen. I
                            desired them not to do so ; for I really believed they were the people of God. When 1 came
                            to consider the matter, I did not feel as though I could take up my cross and deny myself,
                            as I knew I must, in order to be one with them. I thought I would try to stifle my
                            conviction, if it was possible ; and strove to do it, but I felt very serious reflections
                            within. I heard my mother say she believed they were the people of God. " O mother, how can
                            you think so?" said I, and then mentioned the conduct of a certain person who had been
                            disorderly, and who afterwards left the Society. My mind, at that time, was in a situation
                            to seize upon any occasion that might seem to operate against the faith of the Society, and
                            prove their religion false ; but I soon found it was all in vain. \ I continued, however, to
                            strive against my conviction more than a year; though I visited the people twice during that
                            time. In the spring of 1782, I attended their meeting at Br. Bennett's. At this time I saw
                            Lucy, his daughter-inlaw engaged in the worship. Her coun-<pb n="91" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. 91 tenance was solemn and serene, the tears were running down her cheeks. This
                            filled me with the most serious impressions ; and I thought, surely, such solemnity and
                            sincerity as I saw among these people, was certainly of God. I went home fully determined,
                            if possible, to stifle my conscience. I went on as light as I was able ; so that it was
                            observed by my friends, that they never saw me so light and airy before. And though at
                            times, when alone, I was obliged to give way to a flood of tears ; yet I was determined to
                            suppress all conviction, if possible; but found I could not do it: for the spirit,of God was
                            evidently at work with me, and it became evident that I must yield at last: thus I went on
                            fighting against my own conviction, and feeling the smart of it. In October following I went
                            again, in company with Diana Martin, and attended their meeting at the same place. While
                            they were in worship Diana united with them. This struck me very forcibly, and these words
                            rushed into my mind : '* Two women shall be grinding at the mill; the one shall be taken and
                            the other left." (See Matt, xxiv., 41.) I felt as though I was left." About two week^ after
                            this, I attended a meeting again on the Sabbath. At this time Mother and the Elders were at
                            Br. Bennett's. Elder James Whittaker delivered a lengthy discourse which sunk deep into my
                            heart, and I was fully determined to confess my sins before I returned home. I kept with the
                            Believers all day ; but felt so diffident that I had not resolution enough to speak and tell
                            them what I wanted. In the evening I happened to be sitting in the same room with Mother
                            Ann. Elder Calvin Harlow soon came into the room, and advanced towards Mother, as though he
                            was going to speak to her; but seeing me he turned and asked me if I loved the Believers. I
                            answered yes. He asked me if I had confessed my sins. I told him I had noL He then went out.
                            In a few minutes Mother rose and came and took me by the hand, and I then confessed my sins
                            freely and heartily, and was glad of such a privilege, and felt greatly released by it. She
                            counselled me to forsake sin and turn to God with my whole heart; to leave my pride and
                            vanity, and pray to God for his protection ; to kneel in prayer before lying down at night,
                            and after rising in the morning ; and also before and after eating. I tarried until the next
                            day, and was instructed how to live a godly life, and conduct myself in a godly manner. I
                            was at that time engaged in work at the house of a Quaker preacher. When I returned the
                            people of the house discovered an alteration in me, and thought I was sick. As I was very
                            diffident I thought I could not take up my cross and kneel before them; and for this reason
                            I went without my supper and breakfast. But I went to my work, and while 1 was spinning at
                            my wheel, the power of God came upon me and suddenly brought me upon my knees. The family
                            then discovered that I was a Shaker, and all my acquaintances tried to reclaim me, by their
                            exhortations and warnings against delusion. People of different sects beset me with
                            persuasions and flatteries, to join their respective churches and societies. Stephen
                            Carpenter, a deacon of the Baptist church, used his utmost endeavors to convince me that I
                            was deluded with a false religion, till his talk became very wearisome. Because I had set<pb n="92" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> out to forsake everything that was sinful and live to God, he seemed
                            to have a great concern for me "Ah," said he, "you seem to be part Ashdod; sometimes you
                            talk ^ood and sometimes bad." lie then left me, and I was not troubled with the Bapiist
                            deacon any more. I finished my work at this place as soon as I could, and went home. There I
                            found still greater troubles to encounter. My father abused my mother very much, because of
                            her faith ; and I was so persecuted that I really stood in fear of my life. Many times when
                            I lay down at night, I did not expect to see the light of another day. At one time my fears
                            were so great on account of the extreme abuse, that I often went into the woods and cried to
                            God in my great sorrow. All this persecution I suffered, because I had set out to forsake
                            sin and live a godly life. Before this, I was beloved by the family and neighbors and
                            suffered no persecution. My little brother that was five years old, could not speak a word,
                            nor help himself any more than an infant of three months. One day I kneeled in prayer to
                            God, near where this child was sitting on the floor. While I was on my knees, the child
                            suddenly rose and stood on his feet, which he had never done before, and spoke distinctly,
                            saying, Lord God, three times and then sat down again. He never spoke before nor afterwards
                            to my knowledge. This alarmed my father very much. "The dumb speaks to me," said he ; and it
                            convicted him, so that he went and confessed his sins, but in about a month, he was as bad
                            or worse than ever. In all my afflictions and persecutions, I felt a rejoicing within, that
                            I had found a way to escape tho horrors t f a guilty conscience. I felt strong in my faith,
                            and was determined to maintain it, even to the sacrifice of my life. I went to meeting every
                            Sabbath, on foot, to Joseph Bennett's, which was four and a half miles across the fields,
                            the way I generally went. By this means I gained strength of soul, and was more and more
                            confirmed in my faith and understanding. I lived with my parents about two years and a half
                            after I embraced the gospel ; they then moved into Connecticut. I was nearly twenty years of
                            age, and had my freedom and enjoyed my faith undisturbed. My mother had faith, and would
                            gladly have enjoyed a privilege with Believers ; but could not on account of my father's
                            opposition. In all the opportunities and privileges I have had with Mother Ann and the
                            Elders, I never saw the least imperfection in them. They taught me to live a life of purity
                            and godliness, and I always found an example of it in them. They were an upright and godly
                            people in all things. Mother Ann's spirit was a strong advocate for temperance of every
                            kind, and her testimony was a powerful and swift witness against every deviation. I
                            certainly know, by the evidence of divine truth in my own soul, that she was chosen and
                            anointed of God, and that the spirit of Christ was revealed through her ministration. I have
                            lived in obedience to her testimony nearly forty-four years, and have always found that it
                            does save me from all sin. I feel thankful that I am now able to bear witness to the purity
                            of that gospel which I received through her ministration, and m<pb n="93" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/>which I
                            have found peace and solid rest. I feel myself to be the eeed of a fre woman, and au heir to
                            the promised inheritance. I have a spiritual relation of Elders, Brethren and Sisters, who
                            are dearer to me than any of my natural kindred ever were. In these I can confide, and with
                            these I can unite and partake of the true bread of life, and drink of the pure waters of
                            life, and enjoy, in heavenly harmony, one Lord one faith and one baptism. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.
                        </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Consolation" TEIform="index"/>CONSOLATION
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A lark and a linnet sat on a limb That hung o'er the old mill-pond.
                                    Said linnet to lark as she smiled at him, "You've heard of the Audubon? " The lark
                                    lifted his foot and stretched his wing And poised his wise little head- - This
                                    wearing of birds is a cruel thing And killing us all," she said. And therefore I'm
                                    glad, " said linnet quite gay " That steps are taking, though late, To break the
                                    mandates of fashion's sway And save us from such sad fate. " The Audubon " asks that
                                    birds shall be free In their haunts and wild wood home, From the sportsman's shot
                                    and the fiendish glee, Of the boy with his sling and stone. " That our nests shall
                                    be safe from spoiler's hands, Our fledglings watched over too, And the use of our
                                    eggs for science's demands Be given to only a few." 'Then joy notes of song o'er the
                                    world shall be heard Spite the decree of Queen Mab. And dear silly girls in lieu of
                                    the bird Can wear lobster, cuttle, or crab. " Thus consoling each other the little
                                    birds sat On the tree by the old mill-pond- - As they whistled good-bye to the
                                    fashionable hat, And good luck to the Audubon.- -E. B. in </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Bird call" TEIform="index"/>The Bird Call.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God helps us though our fellow men..." TEIform="index"/>God helps us though our fellow men...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> God helps us through our fellow men,- - How well that we he made To see and feel, bestowing
                            when Our fellow sufferer hath the need.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W. </byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="He is doubly a conqueror..." TEIform="index"/>He is doubly a conqueror...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> He is doubly a conqueror, who, when a conqueror, can conquer himself.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cyrus" TEIform="persName"/>- -Cyrus.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Devotional feelings should be..." TEIform="index"/>Devotional feelings should be...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Devotional feelings should be impressed as early as possible on the infant mind. They cannot
                            he impressed too soon, and a child to be truly religious ought not to be able to remember
                            the time when he had n8 idea of God. We should endeavor wisely to impress the mind by
                            connecting religion with all that is pleasant, pure and good, that even a child may
                            comprehend God and a religious life, as the choicest of all knowledge and acquisitions. The
                            Savior has so beautifully illustrated, the pearl of great price, the treasure hid in the
                            field; for which all other considerations should be but secondary.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="T., M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. T. Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Petitions" TEIform="index"/> PETITIONS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hohman, Leopold" TEIform="persName"/> LEOPOLD HOHMAN.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Lighten our sorrows and tribulations Heighten the joys of our small creations Quieten
                            unworthier aspirations Brighten the rays of our inspirations Blighten our mean little
                            retaliations. Whiten our souls to purification Tighten resolves of determination Frighten
                            our foes to mystification Highten each wrong to good regulation I tend you love and our
                            adoration. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How strange it is..." TEIform="index"/>How strange it is...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> How strange it is that souls can live With those who sacrifice each day, And never feel or
                            think to give A thought for others by the way; I would not live on earth with men But to the
                            desert would repair And with wild beasts procure my den, And there enjoy my couch or lair,
                            Unless my gifts could equal those Who are the Savior's chosen few; No debts accruing by
                            repose, And no false name of good and true. Canterbury, N. H.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/> M. W.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What signs do follow those who are alive in Christ..." TEIform="index"/>
                            What signs do follow those who are alive in Christ...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> What signs do follow those who are alive in Christ? They love God above all things, and
                            their neighbors as themselves. They manifest the commandments in their daily lives. Such are
                            indeed and in truth, alive in Christ.-</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Erickson, Larz" TEIform="persName"/>-Larz Erickson.</byline></div2><pb n="94" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life's victories" TEIform="index"/>LIFE'S VICTORIES.</head><p TEIform="p"> Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. 1. I'll follow Thee, O blessed Guide, Till all thy walks I trace! 2. To
                            01 i vet how oft retired, Blest mount of praise and pray'r ; 3. Hath not each soul a
                            hallow'd place, A chalice and a shrine, And seek the fields where Thou hast won The
                            corq'ring strength Where aspiration spread her wings, And soared from ev' An altar pure,
                            where Christ shall bring The bread and liv of gracery careing wine? I The struggle in the
                            wilderness, Temptation without sin; 'Tis When trials compassed Thee around, How sacred that
                            retreat, A The garden with its agony Faith's final test may prove; For here the glorious
                            lessons Of life's grand victories begin lone to pour thy soul to God, And heav'nly unction
                            meet. God each human heart shall try, Till perfect in his love. </p></div2><pb n="95" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bible Class" TEIform="index"/> From the Youths' Bible Class.</head><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="By thy words thou..." TEIform="index"/>By thy words thou...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> " By thy words thou shalt be justified, and by thy words thou shalt be condemned. Matt,
                                xii., 37This text shows us the necessity of guarding our words. We should guard equally
                                as well our actions and motives. Words, we know, are the expression of the thoughts and
                                feelings of the mind; and if by these we are to be justified how many should be the
                                truthful, honest words; if by these we are to be condemned how few should be the hasty
                                or unkind words that fall from our lips. If we regard more carefully the maxim " think
                                twice before you speak" we should be less apt to wound the feelings of others by unkind,
                                unjust words. We cannot recall the words once spoken though we may in a measure atone
                                for the harm they have done. Let us who are young remember the lesson that this text
                                teaches, to guard our lips from speaking words that would cause harm in the least
                                degree; by so doing our lives and the lives of those around us will be made happy. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Loude, Jennie" TEIform="persName"/>Jennie Loude.</byline></div3><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Take my yoke upon you..." TEIform="index"/>Take my yoke upon you...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> " Take my yoke upon you, and learn of one, for I am meek awd lowly in heart: and ye
                                shall find rest unto your souls. Matt, xi., 29. We think the important part of the text
                                is this, " learn of me. " Although this is the teaching of Jesus to His disciples, yet
                                it applies to our lives and commands us to learn of those who are our Saviors in the
                                present time ; those whose lives are pure and good, who have walked the path of
                                self-denial and have gained the beautiful gift of humility. In this way only can we gain
                                the virtues of a pure life. I think of no greater adorning for the young Christian than
                                a meek, lamblike spirit. I believe as we live in self-denial and the cross, denying
                                ourselves of all that does not belong to a pure life, we are taking upon us the yoke of
                                Christ, our pattern, whose life we strive to imitate. I think inasmuch as we live
                                carefully and obediently to our convictions of right we shall find rest unto our souls,
                                that true rest that we could not find in any other course of life. Let us strive to walk
                                in this way and guard our words, our ways, and manners especially when in the presence
                                of those younger than ourselves; for whatever seed we may sow in their minds we may
                                expect to reap in after years.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Gould, Edith Inez" TEIform="persName"/> Edith Inez Gould. Enfield, N. H</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/> From the Little Children. </head><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Manners at school" TEIform="index"/> MANNERS AT SCHOOL.</head><p TEIform="p"> We should not play in school when we are reading. We should not gaze. We should not
                                disobey our teachers. We should sit erect. We should learn all our lessons before we
                                play. We should not come to school before we have washed our hands and face. We should
                                not bring play-things to school. When we come to school we should not run in school but
                                walk. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lorret, Johnnie" TEIform="persName"/>Johnnie Lorret. 8yrs. old.</byline></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="An aged and devoted minister was tried very much in his mind..." TEIform="index"/>
                                An aged and devoted minister was tried very much in his mind...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">An aged and devoted minister was tried very much in his mind by the
                                        persistent use of tobacco by a brother in the church. At last he said to the
                                        brother, " How it would look, my brother, if you was in heaven, for the Lord to
                                        send an angel around after you with a mop to clean up the floor. " The good
                                        brother has never "chewed" since.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Lewiston journal" TEIform="index"/>Lewiston Journal.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Worcestershire sauce is composed of..." TEIform="index"/>Worcestershire sauce is composed of...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Worcestershire sauce is composed of vinegar, allspice, cloves, black pepper,
                                        mustard, ginger, salt, shallots, sugar, tamarinds, sherry, curry powder and
                                        cayenne pepper. A writer in the Cook, says : " The design of the man who
                                        invented this compound was to furnish a universal table disinfectant by the use
                                        of which objectionable food might be rendered tolerable. It extinguishes the
                                        native flavor of everything upon which it is used, and makes all taste alike.
                                        Only the ignorant mistake it for a true sauce ; it should rank with carbolic
                                        acid and chloride of lime as a powerful disinfectant. "</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Footers monthly" TEIform="index"/>Footers Monthly.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><pb n="96" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers. </head><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bird call" TEIform="index"/>The Bird Call</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>Phrenological Journal and
                                Science of Health</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Elements of English" TEIform="index"/>Elements of English</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> Some of the friends in Philadelphia have sent us a copy of a very pretty little paper.
                                Accept our thanks for the notice. The paperU published by the Audubon Society of Perm.,
                                and bears this attractive title, "This Bird Call." The preservation of our little
                                musical messengers of peace should become a matter of interest with persons of every
                                age, and we shall wish for the merciful " Call" a pleasant reception in every home. The
                                Phrenological Journal and Science of Health. March. Contents. John Roach; Familiar talks
                                with our Young Folks; Trinidad; Language ; A Wolf Man; A Divided Republic; Shakespeare
                                vs Bacon; Dysentery; Smoking and Heart Disease; Notes in Science, Poetry, etc., etc.
                                Fowler &amp; Wells Co. 753 Broadway, N. Y. $2 a year. Elements of English. An
                                Introduction to English Grammar, for tke use of schools. By George Hodgdon Ricker, A. M.
                                The Interstate Publishing Company, Chicago and Boston. Price 80 cents. The author who
                                ventures into the much-tilled field of text-books on English grammar should be something
                                more than a theorist, or even a grammarian. Since the days of Murray, scores of books
                                have been written for schools, some labelled " language les sons" and some " grammar^,"
                                and still the teachers, the pupils, and the parents are not satisfied. There has been a
                                gradual but increasing tendency to cut loose from the so-called technical grammar, and
                                substitute a sort of mixture of everything kindred to it but none at all of the real
                                thing, until recently there has again arisen a call for more of the old English grammar
                                of the former years. So unsatisfactory have been the books and the methods of teaching
                                this subject, that in many places, as in Boston for instance, no book at all has been
                                used for some years. But this extreme course has also proved unsatisfactory, and
                                teachers and committees are on the lookout for a suitable book- -one which shall not be
                                too technical, but- -just technical enough. Who is the author venturesome enough to make
                                it? Who hopes to succeed where so many have failed? Surely no one but a teacher of much
                                experience can hope to do so. An examination of the book shows the author's claim to be
                                correct as to the matter it contains. The most striking feature seems to be its
                                simplicity and yet its fulness. The whole subject is gone over within the compass of a
                                hundred pages, and more than half the space is occupied with exercises of a practical
                                kind, which must prove much more valuable to young children than any amount of theory.
                                It would be rash to say that this little book is just what has been so long wanted, yet
                                really we can see no reason why it should not be a success. It is concise and simple in
                                its definitions. It is dignified yet bright. It omits needless technicalities, yet does
                                not ignore the distinctions and uses of the various parts of speech. As an introduction
                                to English grammar it is sure to command the attention of teachers. Its study must be a
                                delight to any child. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>KIND WORDS. </head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pub. of Manifesto; Your donation to the..." TEIform="index"/>Pub. of Manifesto; Your donation to the...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, March 4, 1887" TEIform="index"/> The Union League Club of New York. Mar.
                                4,:1887. </dateline><p TEIform="p">Pub. of Manifesto ;- -Your donation to the Library of the Manifesto for 1886, has been
                                received, for which, in behalf of the Club, the Library Committee returns its grateful
                                acknowledgements. Eespectfully</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Totten, Ellsworth" TEIform="persName"/> Ellsworth Totten, Librarian.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Manifesto is ever a..." TEIform="index"/>The Manifesto is ever a...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon" TEIform="index"/> Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> The Manifesto is ever a welcome guest.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="S., E. A." TEIform="persName"/> E. A. S. </byline></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We live not for ourselves alone..." TEIform="index"/>We live not for ourselves alone...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> We live not for ourselves alone, but for the benefit of humanity, and our own lives are
                            included in that benefit.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="H., E." TEIform="persName"/>- -E. H. </byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths. </head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sproat, Granville T." TEIform="index"/>Granville T. Sproat</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Boston, Susan" TEIform="index"/>Susan Boston</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Montgommery, Murtle" TEIform="index"/>Murtle Montgommery</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="White, Nehemiah" TEIform="index"/>Nehemiah White</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Brackett, Charles" TEIform="index"/>Charles Brackett</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Chandler, Olive" TEIform="index"/>Olive Chandler</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="M., E." TEIform="persName"/>E. M.</byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> Granville T. Sproat, at Canaan, N. Y., Feb. 3, 1887. Age 78 yrs Eldress Susan Boston, at
                                West Family Pleasant Hill, Ky., Feb. 15, 1887. Age 52 yrs. 2 mo. and 5 daysMurtle
                                Montgonimery at Center Family, Pleasant Hill, Ky., Feb. 19, 1887. Age 11 yrs. 8 mo. and
                                27 days. Nehemiah White, at Watervliet, N. Y., Feb. 25, 1887. Age 63 yrs. 3 mo. and 2
                                days. He had been a resident of the Society, from early childhood and toiled unselfishly
                                for the gospel cause. Elder Charles Brackett, at Watervliet, N. Y., Feb 26, 1887. Age 80
                                yrs. and 8 days. He had been a resident of the Society, from early youth, and
                                consecrated time, talent and strength to his gospel home. Olive Chandler, at Harvard,
                                Mass. March 8, 1887. Age 73 yrs. 4 mo. and 24 days. Her entire life was spent in sincere
                                and active devotion to the cause of truth and purity. E. M.</p></div3></div2><pb n="27" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><!-- 
THE  MANIFESTO.
65
A MONTH   and BOAED Guaranteed
3 Young Men or Ladies in each  country,'
and  highest commission paid (often $150
a month )    UTEW  BOOK aln-MJy  on
TIDAL WAVE
OF SUCCESS Ufc3=F!701ffDEIlS
in North and South America, at the Ice-Bound
Poles, over the lands of thcMicnight Sun, lamhr the
Equator, through the Dark Continent, among the Old
Temples of India, in the Flowery Kingdoms of China
and Japan, amid the ruins of Incas, Aztecs and Zuni, within Canons, Clijf Buildings, and Gardens of
the Gods, on the Isles of the Sea, and in all parts of
the globe. 300 engravings, Low Price. Quick Sales.
Send for Circular. P, W. Ziegler, & Co., 720 Ohes'.nutSt, Philadelphia, Pa,
MEDAL   MACHINES.
NEW TOSS STATE AGBICCTLTUBAL W03ESlst. Premiums at all Competitive Trials
Railway, Cliain and Iev- -rH- -r- -c Powers, Threshers ami Cleaners, TliresHer& Shakers, Clover Hnllers, Feed Cutters, Wheel Horse Bakes, Horse Pitchforks, SHing-le Ulacuines. Straw Preserving' Bye Threshers, Portable Steam- Engines. Cider anil Wine Ittills and Presses,
Dog- and Pony Powers, Disc Harrow*
& Springy Tooth    Harrows.      " Robinson's Hay Press, of four sizes- Will
work as easy with one horse, as
others with two. Made with Steel
Gearing which can not be broken."
WHEELER & MEL1CFC Co.,
ALBANY N. Y.
Send stamp for Circular and report  of Cetiteimi .1
trial.
AGENTS WANTED to sell " REMINISCENCES"
of 60 YEARS in the   NATIONAL ^METROPOLIS,
1EBEN PERLEY POORE
Illustrating the Wit, Humor, and Eccentricities of
noted celebrities. A. richly illustrated treat of inner Society History, from " ye
olden time " to the wedding of Cleveland. "Wonderfully Ponular. Agents report rapid
sales. Address for circular and terms.
II (It It All I- - BROS., Pub's, Boston, Mass.
The Cosmopolitan
The handsomest, most entertaining, low price,
illustrated family magazine in the world.
($2.50 per year, with a $2.25 premium
free.) Sixty-four beautifully printed pages in
each number, filled with short stories, sketches,
travels, adventures, bright and brief scientific
and literary articles, by distinguished American
and foreign writers, such as Julian Hawthorne,
Harriet Prescott Spofford, George Parsons
Lathrop, Louise Chandler Moulton, T. Macdonald Oxley, Ella Wheeler Wilcox, H. H.
Boyesen, Catherine Owen, Rev. R. Heber
Newton, Alphonse Daudet, Paul Hevse, Count
Tolstoi; Th. Dostoivsky, William Westall and
many, others. Also entertaining JUVE1VII.E
andinvaluable HOUSEHOLD departments.
Gne or more illustrated articles and several fullpage engravings in every number.
A Shannon   Letter and
Bill File or a Shannon
Sheet-Music Binder
Free   to   every
Subscriber.
These premiums sell
everywhere for $2.25
each. The File is the most
perfect device ever invented for the preservation and
classification (alphabetically and according to date)
of all letters, bills, etc.
Any paper can be referred
to, taken out and put back
without disturbing the
others. With the Binder
one can insert or take out
any piece of music without
disturbing any other sheet.
Get SAMPLE COPY at NEWS STAND or
send 20 Cents to publishers.
AGENTS WANTED. BI& COMMISSIONS PAID.
Schlicht & Field Co., Rochester, N. Y.
The War Crv. is the official Gazette of
the Salvation Army ot America. The paper
contains reports of the work of this religious
order from all pirts of the IT. S. We follow
the evangelizing spirit of this body of religionists with a great deal of interest- The
self-sacrifice which they make, and the zeal
with which they prosecute their work is
worthy of emulation by every Christian professor. With no creed to trammel the inspiration that is -ttfit from God, they preach
a simple faith which must be accepted by a
change of lite, a daily self-denial. Whether
we smile or frown upon the religious exercises which the Salvationists have heen
pleased to adopt, they will, no doubt, continue to fight the battles of the Lord, and to
receive the reward of "well done faithful
servant.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
INFORMATION FOE INQUIRERS.
In   Reference to the   " United
Society of Believers. "
For the better understanding of those who
wish to know of the rules and regulations of
mir religious home, we have prepared the following brief summary. Further information
may be obtained by addressing any member
of the order.
1.  The form of government in the Society is adapted to the different orders of
which it is composed : its powers and authorities growing out of the mutual faith,
love and confidence of the members.
2.  No one is excluded from the privilege of becoming a member on  account
of poverty ; nor will   they be accepted
because of wealth.
3.  Plain and explicit facts will be laid
before the  investigator.    To   become a
member, is a voluntary concession of the
individual.
4.  Those who accept the privilege to
reside with us, as well as those who visit the Society as inquirers, are expected
to regard the rules of the family where
they are entertained.
5.  By the  principles   of this Society,
no believing husband or wife is allowed
to separate from an unbelieving partner,
except by mutual or legal agreement.
6.  Parents that enter a Society   having in charge one or more children, will
be expected" to conform   to the rules and
regulations of the   Family   they   enter
and may or may not continue   the   care
of their children.      This   must  be   arranged by the  officers  of   the  Society
which they enter.
7.  In the  order  and  government  oi
the Society, no corporal punishment is
approved nor any external force or vioence exercised on any rational person
who has come to years of understanding.
X. It is expected that the children admitted into the Society, will receive an
educ-ition siitable for the general management of business.
I.      obationnry members may retain
the lawful ownership of their property,
but the interest accruing therefrom will
be devoted to the benefit of the Society,
until by their own free will, and the consent of the   Trustees, they shall conseerate said property to the support of the
family where they reside.
10. The Society will not be responsible for debts contracted by persons, previous to the time of their membership.
II.  A person   wishing to   become  a
member of the Society,  must rectify all
his wrongs, and discharge all just and legal claims.
12.  Those who   ask for admission to
our Home   are   supposed to be in search
of more truth   and light,   hence, an important principle in the Shaker Church,
is the confession   of sin to   God,   in the
presence of a witness.
13.  Those who have dedicated their
property, and afterward withdraw from
the   Society,- -according to the law  of
justice and equity, there can be no ground
for retraction.
14.  To live   as Brethren and Sisters
in the gospel of Christ, we can hold no
private correspondence.    All communications sent  from or received into   the
family, whether printed or written, will
be subject to the examination and advice
of the Elders of the family.
15.  The leading authority of the Society is vested in a Ministry, consisting
of two Brothers and two Sisters. Elders
and Trustees are also appointed.    These
orders constitute the general government,
of the Society, in all of its branches.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
 --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>