<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0603" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shakers, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">6</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">3</biblScope><date value="18760301" TEIform="date">March 1876</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">17-24</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="6" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="17" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="3" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!-- Official Monthly.—Published by the United Societies. "WHiVT IS TRUTH?" "THE ETERNAL BELINQUISHMENT OF ERROR." Vol.
                        VI. G. A. LOMAS, EDITOR. ollAMilo, JN. L, luilnUn, 10/u. MIAKM vlUAufi, a. n. \ publishek. \ i>ia rf --><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home work" TEIform="index"/>HOME WORK</head><byline TEIform="byline">The following hymn was written by <persName reg="Lawrence, Garret K" TEIform="persName"/>Garret K.
                            Lawrence— the Shaker poet, physician and faithful brother — in 1835. It has been in constant
                            song ever since. We commend it to general use, even if some may think " there's more truth
                            than poetry " in it; for be it remembered, this has ever been the very just charge against
                            all Shaker religion and life. — Ed.</byline><p TEIform="p">This is the burden of my song — Neve?- to look abroad for wrong; I find enough to do at home,
                            With all my best exertions; Then why seek evil in another, Or try to injure a dear brother?
                            Such are not children of our Mother, But slaves to basest passions. How easy for the carnal
                            mind, Evil in other souls to find; While to their own, how very blind — They're scarcely
                            worth observing. But when old nature don't confound us, And we survey the saints around us,
                            We fliid the good, the just surround us; Of heaven how deserving! O, may I evermore be wise,
                            And make a right use of my eyes; Not be a fool, and miss the prize For lack of self-denial.
                            This search of self, if you believe me, And my experience don't deceive me, Is solemn work;
                            then do not leave me, But help me bear the trial. Henceforth, be this my daily toil: At home
                            to cultivate the soil; A faulting serpent shall not coil Within my breast, I'll kill it!
                            This work will make me kind and clever To all around me, yea, for ever; Then love, and joy,
                            and peace, will never Forsake my soul, but fill it. Now, in this resurrection morn, We can't
                            believe they're heaven-born Who shun the rose, but pluck the thorn, That they may torment
                            others; For here, in Zion's fragrant bowers, Where heaven sends such lovely showers, We seek
                            the buds, the opening flowers — Kind Sisters and kind Brothers.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Law and the gospel" TEIform="index"/>THE LAW AND THE GOSPEL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo" TEIform="persName"/>ALONZO HOLLISTER</byline><p TEIform="p">" The Law was a shadow of good things to come ;" for though the substance to which the law
                            pointed, existed, it could not come to man, until he was prepared, by growth, to comprehend
                            it. So also the natural creation was formed to typify eternal things to which man was made
                            heir, and destined to enter into possession, when sufficiently disciplined in temporal
                            things, that he make no mistakes while dealing with eternal substances ; and sufficiently
                            unfolded to apprehend those substances, from the manifestation of figures representing them
                            to his outward senses ; as children learn from signs, called letters, to comprehend what is
                            contained in books. The reflection of this eternal substance upon man's consciousness,
                            causes some sagacious minds to the opinion, that there can be no such things as miracles, or
                            special providences ; because God operates by unchangeable laws. And so he does, where those
                            laws are not violated ; for, where all is perfect order, harmonious adaptation of means to
                            ends, there is probably no need of specials. Laws are not self-operators, but principles
                            through which intelligent agency is manifested. In the rudhnental stage of signs, shadows,
                            types and figures, the confusion caused by a wide departure from primitive law, man created
                            needs that would not otherwise have existed ; and these necessities increase in proportion
                            to the extent of departure. Accordingly as we near the eternal substance, by obedience to
                            the law of eternal life, revealed in Christ, through whom the substance is manifested, the
                            need of special providences is much diminished — in consequence of that uniform action, and
                            adaptation of means to ends, which characterize all works of creation, over which the will
                            of Infinite Wisdom exercises supreme control. The intimate connection of the visible and
                            invisible worlds, was first interrupted by man's fall from moral rectitude. God, in
                            compassion for man's frailty, then promised, to all who would repent, a restoration of
                            relationship to the higher order. That is, where the purpose of the natural order was so far
                            accomplished, that the work designed to supersede it, would begin in those sufficiently
                            unfolded to accept it. Though a large portion of mankind, presuming upon the goodness, and
                            emboldened by the forbearance of God, continued adding sin to sin — and many hardened their
                            hearts against all entreaty — despised the law of God, and trampled under foot his offers of
                            mercy, yet there remained a resolute few, who chose to keep God's commandments, at whatever
                            cost of selfish ease and carnal pleasure ; and through these the restitution began,
                            according to the promise of God. By them, the way of the tree of life has been held in trust
                            for the race — in them, the kingdom of heaven, comprising the substance of all previous
                            signs, types, and shadows, continues to be revealed; whereby a restitution of peace, order
                            and union will be effected in all who will obey its laws, to the sacrifice of selfish life,
                            and the things that pertain thereto. Without this sacrifice the works of death cannot be
                            destroyed from the soul, nor the sting of death be taken away. But by this sacrifice, the
                            soul is liberated from the power of temptation, and restored to union with its creator, from
                            whom all good gifts flow, to perfect the soul in works of righteousness, which bring
                            contentment and everlasting peace.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Chemistry of breathing" TEIform="index"/>THE CHEMISTRY OF BREATHING</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Frazer, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>D. FRAZER</byline><p TEIform="p">What is the use of breathing? is it merely to draw in a portion of the atmosphere and then
                            expel it ? Of all the processes involved in the manifestation of animal life, the act of
                            breathing is the most important. We can live without food for days, but to live without air
                            we cannot ; we breathe about one thousand times an hour. If the process of breathing ceases
                            but for a few minutes, life is at an end. Hence the necessity of breathing deeply of good
                            air; just in proportion to our ability to absorb oxygen from the air, have we life. This
                            absorption of oxygen by the venous blood is a chemical act. Therefore, to breathe rightly,
                            first, have good air ; second, let nothing enter the circulation which impairs the affinity
                            of the blood for oxygen. Soda and saleratus should never be used in food, and the habit of
                            taking much salt is amiss. In former times when large open fire places were in use, and our
                            houses loosely built, attention to ventilation was not required. Now that we live in close
                            apartments with no open fire places, we are shut off from a true relation to the vitalizing
                            oxygen of the air. Hence colds are frequent, and they are catching on the approach of cold
                            weather. Closely-confined air to breathe, associated with alkaline matter in our blood,
                            cannot but be favorable to the formation of soft, flaccid, muscular tissue, just the pabulum
                            in which the seeds of scrofula and consumption can grow apace. A word to the wise is
                            sufficient.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God in the soul" TEIform="index"/>GOD IN THE SOUL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wentworth, Lois" TEIform="persName"/>LOIS WENTWORTH</byline><p TEIform="p">The world, with all its honors and riches, is nothing compared with God's favor. The reward
                            felt by doing his will daily is all satisfying. Yielding the heart to God, nothing is lost,
                            every thing gained — and the gain is an eternal one. The enjoyments of the perishable things
                            of earth are cut short at the grave. The gains of earth are short-lived at longest. Its
                            scenes and pursuits soon fail to affect us ; and then, one unselfish thought or act is worth
                            all years of selfish exertion. Our life has its trials — which seem hard to bear — these are
                            important to prove us ; for how will God prove us, unless we are tried ? God requires the
                            whole heart, a willing offering, a living sacrifice. Feeling that we have rendered these, a
                            restfulness of soul ensues ; and all passionate tumults, feeling the power of good in our
                            souls, will, like the tossing waves of the sea of Galilee, obey the mandate, " Peace, be
                            still! "</p></div2><pb n="18" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Necessity of order in commune life" TEIform="index"/>NECESSITY OF ORDER IN COMMUNE LIFE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, O. C." TEIform="persName"/>O. C. HAMPTON</byline><p TEIform="p">Order is a systematic arrangement of the different elements composing our practical life,
                            including our physical, mental and spiritual existence. Although this is a restriction to
                            the full meaning of the term, it applies with equal force to the entire phenomena of the
                            universe. It is patent to all experience and observation, that without some systematic
                            arrangement in the affairs of individual life, and a regular recurrence of the details
                            thereof, very little good can be accomplished, and little enjoyment or contentment of mind
                            secured. While man has not yet quite "worn out the make of heaven," and retains something of
                            the genius of his original being, he spontaneously gravitates toward orderly arrangements in
                            all the details of his life. He feels, moreover, a logical necessity for some kind of
                            system, in all the departments of his existence as an individual, to secure the highest
                            degree of satisfaction— enjoyment and peace — from his surroundings. Much more does the
                            necessity of order exist in a community of individuals; for here the problem of happiness
                            and peace is very complicated, and the heterogeneous elements of its members, incline to run
                            things into almost inextricable confusion. I do not conceive any necessary relations to
                            exist between the two entities " Order and Government "—although in this rudimental sphere
                            they are generally found in combination. I wish to be understood as dealing with order
                            alone. In communities whose purpose is to be practical exponents of the social relations of
                            human life, certain precepts and rules are agreed upon by the members, as canons of
                            regulation, for the practical evolution of order and regularity throughout all the
                            departments of such communities, and the very fact of the existence of these communities,
                            implies that canons of regulation have been adopted by general consent of the members. And
                            in so far as this is not the case, any disaffected persons happening to drift into such
                            communities, are really not bonafide members, but schismatics, and should not be tolerated.
                            I would be ashamed to repeat the hackneyed proposition, (rather truism), that, no one should
                            impose on a community, who is unwilling to comply with its constitution and by-laws, were it
                            not my unhappy experience, to find that this is too constantly committed upon Shaker
                            communities, and notoriously persisted in from year to year, with a perfidious perseverance
                            only equaled by the false charity of any community, which allows itself to be weighed down
                            by such undeserving material. It seems to me that no one in reason can fail to see the
                            logical consistency of so correct a theory. In my opinion ninety-nine one-hundretlis of all
                            the afflictions of Believers, arise from the entertainment in our midst of persons at
                            variance with the spirit and practice of our orderly, systematic arrangements ; and who not
                            only fail in finding satisfaction by their connection with us, but are clogs and curses in
                            every department of society. And in the proportion that society fails to dispose of this
                            class, it will gradually increase and overpower the conservative elements, and then farewell
                            to Shakerism. It is fatal folly to shut our eyes against truths, or mince matters one atom;
                            for natural laws and results never turn aside, to save any community which ignores the
                            dictates of common sense — much less the wisdom of both experience and inspiration. Some of
                            the reasons why we should keep good order, and hold rigidly to systematic arrangements in
                            life are as follows : (1) In order to be happy we must avoid infringing upon the territory
                            and rights of others; and good order will secure this desideratum when all other means will
                            have failed. (2) We have too little time to do the much good we ought to do in this life ;
                            and a systematical ordering of our time and precious opportunities will enhance our
                            facilities for benevolence, a hundred-fold. (8) Without regularity, periodicity, and
                            permanence, in our domestic and public duties, the poetry of life, and that sublime
                            constellation of spiritual and social amenities, termed the dignity of Christian Repose are
                            quite impossible ; but with good order these blessed amenities constantly recur, bringing us
                            into fythmical unison with that holy gong of joy, which trembles through the universe
                            forever. (4) That the bright rivers of blessing may flow from the infinite fountain, in the
                            lines of least resistance; and these lines are the beautiful, geometrical lines of good
                            order. These are the " streams that make glad the city of God, the holy place of the Most
                            High."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True criterion" TEIform="index"/>THE TRUE CRITERION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Neal, Sarah Ann" TEIform="persName"/>SARAH ANN NEAL</byline><p TEIform="p">Since the first dawn of the Christian era, many individuals, under the title of prophets,
                            have arisen with apparently great., but shallow power, to declare the doctrines of some
                            socalled, new life ; their ideas of the only true road to heaven and happiness. Not
                            satisfied with the simple, yet plain teachings of the Christ, they have endeavored to soothe
                            their own minds into an unchristrian belief, and by false theories of meaningless words,
                            (better adapted to sustain the selfish proclivities of perverted dispositions,) have
                            exercised their artificial powers, to wield an influence over the minds of general humanity,
                            that would veil the genuine truth of the Christian gospel, from the undeveloped spiritual
                            understanding. But, humanity in very many instances have failed to become convinced of the
                            truth of these false theories. Nor is it to be wondered at; for fruits of spirit growth have
                            not evolved from their teachings. And now in this age of reason, intelligence and advanced
                            spiritual light, it is not even to be conjectured, that religious quacks are going to
                            appease the restless, agitated minds of individuals with false and erroneous doctrines. But
                            the results of so much false teaching, is, to-day, manifested by the infidels extant in the
                            world; who failing to find in professional churches the truth their souls so much desire and
                            need, become the infidels they are. The " spirit of the letter," even, is not there; hence
                            no spiritual good is obtained. But, it is better to be unbelieving, than thoroughly imbued
                            with error. The standard of truth as lived by Jesus, the Christ, is the true criterion by
                            which we may know the relation we bear to the infinite spirit of goodness, by whose power we
                            have our existence, and to whose acceptance we should daily live. Nor is the momentous truth
                            of Christian testimony to be mistaken for the eloquence of artificial creeds, whose sounds
                            greet the ear pleasantly, but affect the soul wrongly. The purity of Christian life and
                            testimony is the line of demarcation, which separates those who embrace and fully practice
                            its pure principles, from the natural, sensual order of the world, and the elements which
                            constitute that order. And the work of the day, for those who would realize a salvation from
                            sin, and a power to live above the practices thereof, is to learn and obey the truth, as
                            taught and lived, by our Christian predecessors. Keep this line of demarcation drawn,
                            between the elements of good and evil, and the result will be a growth of soul, by the
                            practice of heavenly principles, that will dispossess the human mind of every doubt it may
                            entertain in regard to what truly is a religious life. Make the heart a pure temple for the
                            indwelling of the holy spirit, then will our actions give expression to pure minds, and our
                            words be mediums to convey to others chaste and holy thoughts.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gospel, in a nutshell" TEIform="index"/>THE GOSPEL, IN A NUTSHELL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Messner, Matthew" TEIform="persName"/>MATTHEW MESSNER</byline><p TEIform="p">Jesus was what the system he introduced made him — an illustration of the practical workings
                            of Christianity. He differed from others, only as far as life-practice made him to differ.
                            He was a model, for all who would be Christians — holding animal nature in subjection to
                            spiritual life. He was a high hope to humanity — is now — as to what human nature can attain
                            unto. With similar propensities ; tempted in all points as we are ; yet using the good power
                            in him to defeat all selfish ends. Jesus, being like other men, he was the proper person to
                            be our examplar ; had he been born without a similar nature, he would not have been the
                            needed, desired model. His gospel is an exemplification of dominion over every perverted and
                            unspiritual appetite; giving hope and power, unto every soul, to accomplish salvation and
                            redemption, by daily self-denial and the spiritual cross. His life was the result of
                            compliance with the higher laws of his being — and by similar compliance to the same laws,
                            every man and woman can, cheered by his example," go and do likewise." If we want the
                            salvation which was in Jesus, we must live as he lived; or we may want salvation from sin,
                            time, and eternity without end, and never obtain it, except we " take up our crosses," and
                            live his life. Shakers, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Diet" TEIform="index"/>DIET</head><p TEIform="p">Elder J. S. Prescott calls our attention to an experiment in dieting, which a person in
                            Medina, O., has practiced with increasingly beneficial effects. As an economical experiment
                            it certainly is forcibly interesting. We condense : " For breakfast, five graham gems with
                            butter; no inconvenience nor hunger followed — cost three cents. Dinner, % lb. rice, one
                            ounce each of sugar and butter — a good meal — cost five cents. Supper, % lb. corn meal, %
                            pint milk, cost three cents. One day's cost 11 cents. For a change, one gill of beans which,
                            by the quart, cost less than half a cent." The correspondent claims to have worked hard, ate
                            nothing between meals, is renewing his age and youthfulness,and only dreads the lonesomeness
                            to be experienced by living to a very great age.</p></div2><pb n="19" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian duty measured by knowledge" TEIform="index"/>CHRISTIAN DUTY MEASURED BY KNOWLEDGE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, A." TEIform="persName"/>ELDER A. PERKINS</byline><p TEIform="p">In consideration of doctrines so palpable as those given by the immediate apostles in
                            confirmation of the teachings of Jesus, in reference to real Christian life and character,
                            that, with intelligent minds, there should exist such extreme ignorance, I am exceedingly
                            puzzled. Listen: 1st John 2: 16. "All that is in the world, the lust of the flesh, the lust
                            of the eyes, and the pride of life, is not of the Father, but is of the world." The spirit
                            arising from these three branches, which constitute the world, is almost universally the
                            ruling element in man — professor and profane. Paul tells the Galatians that '' He that
                            soweth to his flesh, shall of the flesh reap corruption; but he that soweth to the spirit,
                            shall of the spirit reap life everlasting." Also, that " The flesh lusteth against the
                            spirit and the spirit against the flesh, and these are contrary, the one to the other. The
                            works of the flesh are manifest, which are these: adultery, fornication, uncleanness,
                            lasciviousness, idolatry, witchcraft, hatred, variance, emulations, wrath, strife,
                            seditions, heresies, envyings, murders, drunkenness, revilings and such like." Can language
                            be clearer and more to the point, showing the tree which bears such fruit? Such testimony,
                            with the example of Jesus before us, together with a thorough knowledge of ourselves, gives
                            unequivocal evidence of this fact — that in this world is to be found only a shadow of
                            genuine Christianity. The fruits of the tree we cultivate will crop out, no matter what the
                            profession; our works follow us, declaring our condition ; we are known by our fruits.
                            Verily, we see an extensive field open for labor; the marvel being that conviction seems so
                            withdrawn from the earth; it is so limited in its operations, that with all that has been
                            done to christianize man, so little manifestly exists, of real, genuine Christianity; that
                            in man and in the fruit of his work, there is to be found such a destitution of the
                            character and spirit of the gospel of Christ. And while we would recognize the good we
                            realize exists in the earth — while we would defend and preserve it, we should also feel
                            bound to be severe upon error and in our condemnation of evil. Not because of custom or
                            popular feeling should we uphold a wrong, bless it, or give it any other than its true and
                            legitimate name; not because our fathers had not received a clear vision and perfect sight
                            of science or religion, and thus through ignorance were in any degree led by false faith,
                            should we shut out the light and continue to walk in darkness, allowing no growth,
                            unfoldment or progression ; but as patience will give a perfect work, so let wisdom render
                            hers. By promise indubitable, the earth is to be full of the knowledge of the Lord, and a
                            highway is to be cast up, which will give souls a privilege to travel in and find an
                            increase of righteousness, which will extend unto and beyond the confines of earth.
                            Otherwise, why the mission of the Saviour to preach to the spirits in prison which were
                            disobedient in the days of Noah! Jesus was commissioned to perform no foolish errand. In his
                            mission, he evidently did a work of mercy, whose result gave not only knowledge to those
                            ignorant transgressors, but power by which they could improve. Progress is eternal: Tell us
                            no more that it ends with earthly life. This is a contradiction of the declaration of the
                            Saviour of the world, in that he was the only door of hope to lost humanity; a denial of the
                            justice of God. No soul is deprived of mercy and cut off from God, without a knowledge of
                            the revelation of this plan of salvation. There is no condemnation without disobedience to
                            known light; the destiny of no man is fixed, so long as he is ignorant of truth; and equally
                            inconsistent is the doctrine, that man is saved and reigns with Christ, without a knowledge
                            of him and his requirements, and a baptism into his holy spirit. What then? The answer is
                            clear; if man receives not the full revelation of his duty to God, to his fellow-man and to
                            himself while in this world, (which is the case with all who preceded the advent of the
                            Saviour, and which is equally true of millions who have departed this life since that date),
                            God in His justice will open the way for knowledge to those who are waiting in the spirit
                            land, as were those who were ignorant, and on whom the long-suffering of God waited in the
                            days of Noah.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Another hour in the day of progress" TEIform="index"/>ANOTHER HOUR IN THE DAY OF PROGRESS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, G. B." TEIform="persName"/>ELDER G. B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p">Purity of Life, not amalgamation of religious professions, nor union of professors who are
                            antichristian in their life practice, is the panacea for the human race. Realizing a want of
                            power over sin, of ability to rise above the level of worldly elements, and their sorrowful
                            life-experiences— a want of strength to sustain even the religious professions of nominal
                            Christianity — the divided and subdivided sects of Christian professors are looking to
                            amalgamation of creedal faiths — union of religious societies, and harmony of religious
                            professors, in the belief that Jesus paid the whole debt of sufferings, for all the sins
                            that believers in his name commit, as the catholicon for curing the physical, moral and
                            spiritual ills of the human family. But the light of truth reveals this to be a most
                            prominent error. No combination or amalgamation of any number of impotent medical
                            preparations is equal to the cure of disease, whether physical, moral or spiritual! Mankind
                            are religiously diseased — a cancerous tumor of the imputed righteousness of Jesus is eating
                            out their soul's life. A palsy, consisting of the belief that the animal blood of the man
                            Jesus, shed upon the Calvary cross, is the atonement for all the sins of believers in
                            Christ, is curdling the spiritual blood in the veins of nearly all souls in professional
                            Christendom. The lamentable fact is that all the popular religious creeds propose salvation,
                            by the sufferings of Jesus, from the guilt, condemnation and powerful consequences of sin,
                            instead of salvation from sin itself, by a personal cross against all sinful indulgences.
                            This is a base plan of salvation, never conceived by the Divine Mind, nor taught by Jesus;
                            and is instituted as an accommodation to a sin-loving race, who are still undesirous of
                            being saved from its pleasures. It is a religious malpractice, engrafted on almost the
                            entire tree of human development, and characterizes the physico-medical practice of our
                            race, applicable to both body and soul, in all the lanes of life; prescribing remedies for,
                            rather than preventives of disease. It is no less characteristic of the moral and religious
                            therapeutics of the popular masses of so-called moral reformers, and Doctors of Divinity.
                            Painkillers — in other words, nerve deathdealers, to benumb human sensibility; put the body
                            to sleep; tone down the moral sense to the point of indifference, and bring the spiritual
                            consciousness to a level so low, that no condemnation is felt for violations of spiritual
                            law which result in death of soul, are the prescribed remedies for human ills! The simple
                            truth is, mankind do not want to be saved from sin, but in the indulgence of sin; they
                            desire to enjoy its pleasures, but to be saved from the consequences. They crave the
                            disposition that engenders disease, but to be saved from sickness; hence, the physician who
                            teaches hygienic laws, for either body or soul — laws requiring self-denial, purity of
                            thought, word and deed are distasteful to the majority. A religion embracing the power of
                            salvation from sin, is, by the popular throng, as undesirable as a frost in June, because it
                            cuts off the anticipated harvest of sinful pleasures. Thus the ship of human reform for
                            health and happiness in body, mind or spirit, is embarrassed by blockades on all seas of
                            life; and a work of redemption which might be accomplished in a twelvemonth, by the adoption
                            of Purity, — abstinence from the lusts of the flesh, from thoughts that blush with shame,
                            indulgence in stimulants that fire the blood, in narcotics that benumb the senses is not
                            wrought out in a thousand years. The harmony of religious faith — the inspiration of
                            heavenly baptisms that would flow from the honest confession and leaving off of sin in a
                            week, are voluminously written about, oratorically talked of, and animatedly draped in song,
                            as in the distant future, but are only known as in a dream of things yet to be. A religious
                            life in its present, popular wake, is a golden farce! Why should not the rising generation,
                            as they really are, be stupid to its semblances; infidel to its arid professions; its mock
                            Salvation ; its hollow holiness; its sinful saintliness; its indulgent sacrificial altar;
                            its wholesale, silent, hypocritical confessional; and consequently unrepentant life, since
                                <pb n="20" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 2O THE 9HAKEK. these are but a mockery to the name of religion?
                            But, as our race has a religion embracing, 1st, Practical Purity of life — abstinence from
                            all that defiles the senses and stupefies the soul; 2d, Consecration to God; 3d, Forgiveness
                            and love to man, instead of war and strife; 4th, Living for the good of Brethren, Sisters,
                            neighbors, and all humanity, instead of self alone — a universal Christian patriotism ; 5th,
                            A baptism of heavenly inspirations, ministering to the aspirations of soul-life; and all
                            mankind will bow in spirit, acknowledging its truth, and be blessed by its benedictions of
                            love and charity; the march of human redemption will be with vigorous, perpetual youth. Such
                            a religion cannot be reproached, if not adopted by all. But a union of all denominations of
                            professed Christendom into one brotherhood embracing the idea of salvation in sinand/Vwft
                            its consequences, by the sacrifice of Jesus, would only more heavily curse the world;
                            binding it with still stronger thongs of theological death; and leave mankind to the only
                            sure hope of seeking a religion, gushing with heavenly baptisms of pe-ntecostal power; the
                            gift of salvation from sin, and a merciful and loving God.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vision" TEIform="index"/>For The Shaker. A VISION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Child, Henry T." TEIform="persName"/>HENRY T. CHILD, M. D.</byline><p TEIform="p">"Behold I set before thee an open door, and no man can shut it."—Rev. 3, viii. As I was
                            musing upon this text I beheld a vision. I saw a great multitude of people going up a very
                            steep hill, the paths were exceedingly rough and thorny, and sometimes great rocks were in
                            the way which it seemed almost impossible to get over. There were all sorts of wild beasts
                            in the road, among them I saw lizards and serpents of various kinds, and other slimy,
                            creeping things. Many of the people had some of these animals traveling with them. Most
                            persons seemed to be troubled and were glad to make companions of the animals, for they were
                            nearer to them, and did not seem inclined to help one another, but generally they were
                            taking advantage of each other. I saw women, who were wearied with their journey, and they
                            sat down by the way-side, and as the men came along they did not take any notice of them,
                            but would step on them and walk over them, not heeding in the least their cries. All along
                            this road I could see open places in the form of crosses, and I heard a voice saying: "
                            Behold I set before thee an open door, and no man can shut it." I watched them closely, and
                            after a time I saw one who was about to enter in, having become very weary of the journey of
                            life. I stood near to him and there came two shining angels, who said unto him : " Thou must
                            strip thyself of every thing, even thy garments, and go in without any covering, for behold
                            there are robes of righteousness for all who enter." He began to strip himself, but there
                            were some little things that he desired to take with him, and the angel said in a very firm,
                            but kind voice : " No ! thou must confess, and lay aside every thing, or thou canst not
                            enter in." But he replied: " Oh I cannot do this." So he went on his way, hoping for a more
                            convenient season, and these angels left him. Others came and said to him : " Foolish man
                            that thou art, put on thy clothes and take thy treasures with thee for the road will soon be
                            smoother." Then a little angel, pure and white, whispered in his ear: "See that thou do it
                            not." And strength came to him for he had overcome temptation, and he said: " I will, by the
                            help of God and holy angels, confess and strip off every thing and enter in." Then I saw him
                            take off many things that had been concealed from my vision, and throw them away, and as he
                            passed through the narrow door there was not a hairs' breadth of room for any thing but
                            himself. I watched many others who looked toward the opening, but they were going along with
                            the animals. Some leading these, and others being led by them. I asked one of the spirits
                            that was there if I might look in at one of these cross doors ? He replied, " Yes," and I
                            did so. There I saw a beautiful road, there were green pastures and still waters, but no
                            wild and ferocious animals. The people were all helping each other along, and were very
                            happy, singing songs of praise as they went along.</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE SHAKEE. Monthly—60 cents per annum. A DUAL ADVOCATE OF CHRIST PRINCIPLES.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Grand seal of Christian humanity" TEIform="index"/>THE GRAND SEAL OF CHRISTIAN HUMANITY</head><p TEIform="p">When the millennium shall have dawned — when '' the fulfillment of the law " is established —
                            when the Seal, by which '' men shall know the disciples " of Christ is ever apparent, then
                            shall we realize that Love rules all creation. The golden rule of Confucius, adopted and
                            extended by Jesus, means more than it says. '' All mine are thine — and thine are mine" —
                            fall with crushing weight on the great sin of the world — unchristian selfishness.
                            "Brotherly love" means something more than poesy — Christian fraternity, more than
                            cooperative partnerships. To love others who love us is an easy matter; the drift of all
                            humanity, good and bad alike, agreeably acknowledges this. To love those who please us — who
                            do just as we direct— is an affection as noted in the devils, as in exalted saints. The
                            comparative remark of Jesus: " Greater love than this, hath no man, that he lay down his
                            life for his friend,'1'1 is superlatively surpassed by love for those inimical — for those
                            who do not love us. This love is something more than airy substance, which breaths unmake or
                            make at pleasure — more than rythmic poetry implies, and sterner prose in action, than found
                            in paragraphs. Its name has been usurped by passion, and profaned to unholy uses through all
                            time past, still its eternal principles are pure. The law of heaven is love; — in heaven on
                            earth, no less than elsewhere. To know that God loves us, in our obedience and waywardness
                            alike, every day's blessings bring us to quick conclusions. To know that we love one
                            another, is knowledge unattained, and made impossible, by every exception we actually
                            present, or mentally reserve. No sentiment is more prevalent in Shaker song than Love. It is
                            well. Turn we often from the sentiment, to know that love lives not in song alone ? Do we
                            realize, as we should, that love has head and heart, hands and feet, voice and prayer, and
                            unreserved consecration to every unselfish conclusion ? Do we think, that all barrenness of
                            prayerful offerings — all failures in spiritual struggles— all "aching void," and want of
                            life and zeal, of courage and confidence, have been and may be predicated upon ''
                            remembering thou has aught against thy brother," sister, friend or enemy ? How truly the
                            song : "The wayward and erring most need our affection— " Withhold not this boon." • * •
                            Again : " If we love not each other as sister and brother, " How can we love God ? " And
                            again : 11 My life I'll square, roy habits change, " 'Til love I am possessing." And listen:
                            "Love,love, practical lovk, that will appear in my words and my ways,— " Love that will
                            clothe me, and cause me to speak, kind to the strong and wise to the weak! " And how
                            faithfully do we comply with: " Not alone for those who love you, are you called to do good—
                            "Nor for those who seek your comfort, giving honor to your word— "But bless ye those who
                            curse you — for those who hate you pray, " For if you only give, where much is given to you,
                            why is reward expected ? " Or why the kingdom due ? Love ye your enemies, " Do good, to
                            those who love you not I " And yet, it is so common, the world over, to make " the weak bear
                            their own burdens ;" to fail the helping hand to rise; and oftener give the gibe and kick to
                            those who've stumbled! "The milk of human kindness," and Christian affection, are too seldom
                            seen expressing themselves in reclamation of the erring; while oftener the cold chill of
                            unchristian indifference and sectarian slight replace them! How true it is, where one is
                            found in error, loving souls can only magnify the gospel by helping the sufferer up! Whose
                            value is enhanced, by any unchristian or ignominious action ? Love, not only " worketh no
                            ill," but tcorketh all, and every good. Community Life, like every gift of God, is intended
                            to circumvent selfishness. Brethren, Friends! We are blest with unusual facilities for the
                            outworking of Christian love — as opposed to the me-and-mine principle of the common marital
                            relation. Like every other gift, Communism may be equally perverted, to its selfish opposite
                            — its accumulated force, and genuine aims, be made to contribute to the selfish area of me
                            and those icho oest love me ! but, as standing before high heaven, holding a sacred trust,
                            let us acquit ourselves as men and women of God! If Communism fails, selfishness, and those
                            who practice it, shall bear the responsibility. <pb n="21" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHA.KER. But it
                            must not fail. Let those charged with the treasury of millennial hope, life, energy and
                            human redemption, so unselfishly live that it may be well said: "Behold, how these
                            Christians love one another!" and, as those "passing from death unto life," let us each work
                            and pray with Abou Ben Adhem: " I pray thee, then, Write me as one who loves my fellow men I
                            " *</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Responsibilities of the rich" TEIform="index"/>THE RESPONSIBILITIES OF THE RICH</head><p TEIform="p">The recent deaths of several millionaires — Singer, Astor, Rothschild and others—having
                            quickened the pulse of the people, call into consideration the words of Jesus: "How hardly
                            shall they who have riches enter the kingdom of God." There is an unreasonable antagonism
                            between the poor and rich, caused by the fact that they are so. The mere fact of one person
                            being capable of accumulating millions, while another is not, is an insufficient cause for
                            either self-exaltation or envy. But it is a fact that the great disparity in the ability of
                            individuals to accumulate gold, occasions more inimical feelings, than an excessive ability
                            to accumulate any thing else. The reason of this is patent to everybody—that the power which
                            ever accompanies the accumulation of wealth, is so invariably used to promote excessive
                            selfishness; and not for the ends of philanthropy. For the rich man to feel, that he is in
                            no way responsible for the comfort of his poorer neighbors, is one of the most prominent of
                            human mistakes. There is, no doubt, wealth enough in the world, to make all very
                            comfortable. With those having superior ability to make fortunes, rests the responsibility
                            of being "my brothers' keeper," to an extent equaling their excess of ability to get rich.
                            But while this responsibility is accepted and exercised scarcely anywhere — (probably
                            nowhere, with unreserved, unselfish consecration to philanthropy) — yet we find the best
                            illustrations of this, in the introductory exercises of the early Pentecostal Church, and in
                            Communities, where individuals composing such, have solemnly promised God and each other, to
                            devote their all — wealth, strength, time and talents — for the general good; and to fare
                            and share alike, in all the comforts and misfortunes that may follow. And where this
                            excellent system is honestly practiced, there is neither rich nor poor, master nor slave;
                            neither aristocratic dominancy nor servile mendicancy; but '' we are brethren,'1'' is the
                            happy, general feeling. Has the story of Dives and Lazarus no worthy application in our
                            days? Tell us, you who can, wherein Wni. B. Astor differed from him called Dives, in olden
                            times? Was he not grasping for gold, and most active in "laying up treasurers on earth,"
                            until sickness and death seized him? While he rioted in uncounted millions, did the poor
                            find in him a friend? Would the paltry sums bequeathed by his will, favorably compare with
                            the value of a dime, which some men give to a passing beggar? Holding, the wherewithal to
                            relieve the untold miseries of the thousands on every side of him, did he prove himself the
                            value of a smile, a sunbeam, or a loaf of bread to a single household, other than his own?
                            He died, forced to leave, what he would gladly have held through all eternity. What treasure
                            has he now? " That is the question." With the simplest power to reason upon causes and their
                            effects, who would have lived and died as did he? Instead of being an object of envy and
                            enmity, does he not excite our pity? and his ill-gotten, useless pile of gold, and pyramid
                            of selfish sordidity of character — are not these to be fled from, as from the devil? "It is
                            easier for a camel to pass the ' Needle's Eye,' than for a rich man to enter the kingdom of
                            heaven." Rev. Newman Hall, visiting Jerusalem, writes: " At a certain hour of the night, the
                            gates to the main entrances of the city are closed, and there is no ingress excepting
                            through the ' Needle's Eye '—agate so small and low, that men and women must stoop to pass
                            it; and a camel to pass it, must be unloaded, and crawl through on his knees.'1'' Here's
                            Astor's chance of getting in, and those of like ilk. Rich men and women: Make your wealth an
                            honor and a blessing,— study your eternal interests by devoting it '' to charitable and
                            religious (not sectarian) purposes ; " and let it not bar your entrance to happiness in the
                            eternal world. The subjoined paragraphs may, or may not have been delivered in propria
                            persona, but they are true in principle, agreeably with our instructions. We copy from the
                            Banner of Light: "Gardner Brewer, a wealthy gentleman of Boston, recently deceased, reported
                            himself as follows: " I am strangely bound to the things I called my own, and if I have
                            wings of aspiration, I cannot use them in consequence of this binding. I am absolutely
                            dissatisfied with myself and every thing else, but suppose I shall outlive it, as people who
                            seem to be good in this spirit-world tell me, but how soon God alone knows! I could wish
                            that I had gone out of this life without owning so much as a foot of ground whereon to
                            stand, but I cannot change matters now, so I must take the consequences. I called Boston my
                            home. It was; but I cannot tell now whether I have one or not; but am assured by kind,
                            benevolent spirits who are attendant upon me that I shall gain a better condition by coming
                            here, and taking a new start." *</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Peace congress of nations" TEIform="index"/>PEACE CONGRESS OF NATIONS</head><p TEIform="p">As a war strategist, General Grant won golden opinions and the chief magistracy of the U. S.
                            But, until a recent date, he was not even suspected of brilliancy as a statesman. Some of
                            his recent utterances, however, touching Church and State matters, have, in the eyes of the
                            nation, carried him to a front rank among statesmen; a large number of journals formerly
                            opposing him — among others The N. Y. Tribune — complimenting him with delivering himself of
                            wisdom, which the nation could not reasonably have expected for scores of years to come. The
                            United States will not soon forget, the grand rallying cry of '' Let us have Peace. " In the
                            light, and unprecedented glow, of the amicable settlement of The Alabama Claims, during the
                            service of the present Presidential incumbent, wre urge, hope and pray, for the
                            establishment of a Peace Congress of Nations, to arbitrate the cause of justice among all
                            nations, with a view to banish from the world the curse of War ; and consequently the
                            expensive necessity of standing armies and navies. The time for the abolition of such
                            old-time barbarisms seems fully ripe; and we urge the attention of our own, and all other
                            nations, to a scheme, whose aim is the increased happiness and spirituality of all peoples.
                            With War and its contingencies, as things of the past — with energies that have been
                            perverted, turned into the proper, peaceful channels of agriculture, arts, sciences,
                            literature and manufactures — none will say "I am poor "—for the reign of universal,
                            peaceful brotherhood will be eternally established! This is not a Utopian dream — it is
                            possible — and we therefore raise the undying cry for a Peace Congress of Nations, whose
                            every diplomacy will aim to " Let us have a lasting Peace ": " That golden age, on history's
                            page, shall gleam in truthful lines; For even now, its dawn appears, in bright, prophetic
                            signs." *</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ruskin, to the rescue" TEIform="index"/>RUSKIN, TO THE RESCUE</head><p TEIform="p">Ruskin, the pen-painter of England, believes in the possibility of a heaven on earth; and is
                            about to attempt one of the most gigantic schemes, to relieve his countrymen of the twin
                            curses of pauperism and slavery. A large estate having been secured, it is believed,
                            operations will begin in the early spring. Basing his enterprise on " the nobleness of hnman
                            nature, the majesty of its faculties, the fullness of its mercies and the joy of its love,"
                            he enlists, under the Society of St. George, to make a practical reality, what has long been
                            considered a Utopian dream. Large estates are to be bought by the Society; on these villages
                            are to be inaugurated, the land rented to as many individuals as it will comfortably
                            maintain — the rents being reduced, as the land is improved. Every one must labor for his
                            daily bread ; where manual labor will do the work, no machinery will be permitted ; in
                            proportion as this rule proves a disadvantage, the rents will be reduced. The destruction of
                            timber is prohibited ; the tenants must not " deceive., kill, nor hunt any living creature,
                            nor destroy any beautiful thing;" and must love their neighbors as themselves; and even
                            where this appears impossible, " they must act as if they did I " In every village the
                            population will be restricted, towns and cities being discouraged. Schools will be
                            inaugurated, also museums and libraries. Stores will be established, which will be stocked
                            primarily with food and clothing ; subsequently with books and works of art. The dress will
                            be regulated — " quite as much for the pride of the maid as the mistress, for the man as the
                            master;" everybody must dress well; none will be allowed to wear the cast-off clothing of
                            others, nor sell nor pawn their own to others. None will be permitted to appear in rags on
                            the street. Health, peace, prosperity and plenty are to be aimed at, and every thing must
                            bend to these desiderata. " I do very believe," says Ruskin, " perceive and admit in
                            convinced sorrow, that I live in the midst of a nation of thieves and murderers ; that
                            everybody round me is trying to rob everybody else ; and that not bravely and strongly, but
                            in the most cowardly, and loathesome ways of lying trade! " To prevent these, and to
                            establish every man and woman 21 <pb n="22" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 22 THE SHAKER. ' under their own vine
                            and fig tree," it is his intention to turn the aid of millions of money ; and let us all
                            hope that his expectations may not prove a Utopia. *</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We are not yet a free people" TEIform="index"/>WE ARE NOT YET A FREE PEOPLE. AN OPEN LETTER</head><p TEIform="p">Shaker Village, Shirley, Mass., February 1, 1876. Honored Friend, G. T. Angell, Boston :
                            Allow me to thank you for your many labors of love. In so much as you have done good to any
                            one, you have done it unto me. A presentation of the facts from time to time in the future,
                            which you have already brought before the public, showing, that crime is on the increase in
                            this highly favored State, cannot but do good. As citizens of this republic, we have several
                            grave problems to solve in reference to its perpetuity. The effect of our system of finance,
                            including usury, (one per cent is usury), on the creation of crime, requires serious
                            attention. When the farmers as a body, invest elsewhere than in their farms, trouble is not
                            far off. The existence, and the rapid rise of so many millionaires in our midst, is
                            anomalous with the logic of a republic ; in the nature of things they are the offspring of
                            wrong conditions, and are clothed with power not compatible with the general good. At their
                            will, they can vitiate the sources of law and justice ; and when it suits their interests,
                            can change commercial values, and tax consumers, as the monarchs of the old world do their
                            subjects. The relation of the employer and the employed, increasingly presses itself on
                            public notice. The late existence of slavery was only a labor question. The idea that moral
                            agents, citizens of a republic, should be left by thousands, or even a single citizen, in
                            the hands of millionaires, or companies of capitalists, the latter parties being in
                            possession of the enormous productive energies of our times, and the former to do their will
                            — glut the markets to repletion ; and then suffer destitution from the very abundance they
                            have created — thrown out of employment, on to the labor market as a commodity ! is an
                            astounding crime against the republic. That a moral agent, responsible to his own knowledge
                            of right, to the Supreme Being, to his fellow citizens, and to all the demands of the
                            republic, should be left to compete with iron, steam, and steel, in the hands of these
                            parties, is atrocious — is the hugest crime of the nineteenth century. Just as sure as the
                            labor question at the South was met, so surely will the labor question at the North, press
                            to be adjusted. If not adjusted, then the great republic — the hope of humanity — will prove
                            a failure ; which I think cannot be. Our brethren of the late slave States would not listen
                            to words of wisdom. Their persistence in wrong culminated; then He, who governs the moral
                            universe by law, as He does the material one, met them in their own paths, broke the yoke of
                            bondage, and buried that form of human vassalage, beneath the dead bodies of the oppressor,
                            and with the havoc of war, destroyed their ill-gotten property. Is there not a lesson here
                            for us at the North ? This ever-pressing and momentous subject, if not settled in wisdom,
                            may be solved as was that of slave labor, in awful convulsions, dire calamities, and fearful
                            destruction. With me, it is a matter of deep concern, that the conditions of all the
                            citizens of our loved republic, should be favorable to its perpetuity. Would it not be well
                            for those who have statesmen's hearts, who feel the approaching future, to take steps in
                            gentle ways and manners, and teach us how to secure a healthful distribution of all the
                            products of labor, and thus avert impending evil ? Have we not one common Father? Why should
                            not the blessings of civilization be as equally distributed as the rain which falls alike on
                            all ? Are not the accumulations of wealth the fruits of modern civilization ? If so, is it
                            morally wholesome that it should be left to accumulate at some points to fester into
                            extravagance, and be withdrawn from others, causing want, discontent, degradation and crime
                            ? Would it not be well for every producer to have an interest in the fruit of his labor as
                            has the employer, and so cease to be virtually a slave ? Is it ever taken into
                            consideration, that the domestic surroundings of men of wealth today, exceed those of
                            princes of the fifteenth century ? while in this day, the surroundings of the poor are in
                            many, very many cases destructive of health and life, and the means of living as limited
                            nearly, and more uncertain than of that century ? Again, the wealth alluded to, is the
                            outcome of the intellectual labor, not of a class, but of society. Therefore, the enormously
                            productive energies of mechanical and chemical appliances belong of right to all. They
                            should be assistants, not competitors with moral agents as is now the case. The ancients
                            founded their republics under the light of other ideas than those of our day. The peculiar
                            relation of families to one another, and the existence of a lower stratum of families in
                            their societies, who had neither a hearth, altar nor priest; and of course, had no religious
                            nor political position, necessarily caused great difficulties. When these occurred, there
                            was no way to settle them but by overpowering the ruling families. Hence to maintain social
                            equilibrium, from time to time, those who had amassed much land, were either killed, or
                            driven off, and the land divided. In the histories of these republics, when favorable
                            aspects presented themselves, no doubt their profoundest thinkers favored a somewhat just
                            distribution of the land — an approximation toward Jewish equality. Land being the source of
                            human sustenance, of social and judicial equality; and a regulator of the exchange, and
                            values of commercial equivalents ; to insure perpetuity to modern republics every citizen
                            should be a landholder, or have access to land at all times. To buy and sell, as we do a
                            manufactured commodity, is to make those who cannot buy it, a commodity also ; and is the
                            veriest opposite of the idea of loving the neighbor as we do self. The Jewish idea was an
                            approximation to Christianity — " the land could not be sold for ever;" only to the Jubilee.
                            Under Christian ideas, land can neither be bought nor sold. To do so, is to make servants —
                            slaves of our brethren. Kossuth remarked, " The Christian nation is not yet." Therefore we
                            have troubles enough, and more, and worse in prospect. The earth is the Lord's, not man's.
                            The mission of this republic is justice to all; and is identical with Christian ideas and
                            sentiments. Were the sages of antiquity to appear now, would they not congratulate us, "
                            that we were free from the demoralizing influences which bound them as with iron bands? With
                            them, families with their gods and priests, were little worlds in themselves. Each family
                            and its gods, were isolated from, if not antagonistic to, all other families and their gods
                            ; and in their wars sought the destruction of both. That now, we had the glorious
                            opportunity to accept the human family as a unit, and to have no god but our Father who is
                            in Heaven — who has given to all his children alike, the surface of this planet for their
                            sustenance, as he has given the air we so freely breathe." And further, they could say, "
                            That to lend upon interest, is to tax poverty ; creates false conditions in society ; is
                            contrary to the feeling of benevolence, and to all the higher attributes of our being ; and
                            repellent of the injunction of Him whom we profess to pattern after — lend, hoping for
                            nothing again." Can it be said that the foregoing is impracticable ? Did not the founders of
                            this republic, through many sufferings, bequeath to us a social compact organically just ?
                            Having such magnificent opportunities, shall we fail to render it so? Nay, let us advance a
                            step, be more than just — be beneficent; then it will be easy to be just. The time has
                            indeed arriven for nations and individuals to manifest to each other a divine humanity — to
                            breathe forth into practicability the inspiration of our loved neighbor Emerson : " And each
                            shall care for other. And each to each shall bend, To the poor a noble brother, To the good
                            an equal friend" I have written from the midst of a Shaker Community. Your form of
                            government is organically just. Ours, is organically divine. Carry out your ideas into
                            practice, and permanence, peace, prosperity are yours. Carrying out ours, a stability,
                            peace, and prosperity which has never been exceeded, is ours now. Those who have an inward
                            feeling — a craving to live the higher life —to realize in themselves, in their every day
                            life, the inspiration of the poet we have quoted, may visit us. With sentiments of deep
                            respect, I have the happiness to be your friend.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Fraser</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Love and logic" TEIform="index"/>LOVE AND LOGIC</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p">God is said to be love. It may as truly be said, God is Logic. Love precedes Logic, and logic
                            that does not rest back upon Love, is powerless for good to man. When Rarey convinced a
                            wild, strong horse, of man's superior power, he used that power in love, gaining the
                            confidence and affection of the inferior animal. Before all other emotions, is the emotion
                            of love to a new-born being. Love is the cord that holds the offspring to discipline. Love
                            is unselfish. When we affirm that natural affections are selfish, it is true only as
                            compared with spiritual affections, which supplant and supersede the natural. Blood relation
                            is selfish relation, and is the basis of natural affections — mine and thine. <pb n="23" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHA.KER. 23 Soul travail is from self to God. When called by the Gospel,
                            souls are either in a normal, or abnormal condition. Jesus and His fellows, as natural men
                            and women, were in a relatively normal condition when called by the Christ-Spirit. In
                            reproduction, their parents observed generative law. In education, physiological and
                            dietetic laws. Ann Lee, and her fellows, as natural men and women, were Gentiles. As such,
                            they were in unnatural abnormal conditions. Generative, physiological and property laws were
                            unknown, and of course, unheeded by their parents. Their condition was prophetically
                            foreseen and foretold ages before their existence. See 2d Timothy, 3d chapter : "In the last
                            days perilous times shall come. Men will be lovers of their own selves, covetous, boasters,
                            proud, blasphemous, disobedient to parents, unthankful, unholy, without .natural affections,
                            truce breakers, false accusers, incontinent, fierce, despisers of those that are good,
                            traitors, heady, high-minded, lovers of selfish pleasures, more than lovers of God." As
                            Joannes and Jambros withstood Moses when he was the minister of a more spiritual order than
                            that of Egyptian philosophy and religion, so do these Gentiles resist a far more spiritual
                            truth than was ever revealed to Moses. How hardly shall such enter the Kingdom of Heaven, as
                            those now established on the earth ! Why ? Because the first practical effect of Gospel
                            Truth, upon them, is to convert them back to a normal condition in their affections as
                            natural men and women — as John Baptist turned the heart's affections of parents back to
                            their children, and the same of the children back to their parents—to recreate natural
                            affections, the first form of Love in all the animal kingdom. Men, who had forsaken each
                            other as husbands and wives for years, began to feel conviction, and think they had a duty
                            to reunite with them in a true generative relation. Neglected children, and disobeyed
                            parents, were sought unto. Drawn away and enticed, by their lusts, they became without
                            natural affections. Now they are drawn away and enticed, by those natural affections, to
                            disobey the call of the Christ-Spirit, to come out and be separate from the whole, natural,
                            generative order. Let all, that are called, press into the Kingdom and confer not with flesh
                            and blood relations, nor with the affections created by the love appropriate to that order —
                            but act as did the Apostle Paul — straightway obedient to the Heavenly vision — for where
                            there is no Spiritual vision, the people perish, in and from, both the natural and Spiritual
                            orders. If souls will confidently make the requisite sacrifices, to free them from the lusts
                            and appetites of the natural order, they will have a just inheritance in the Zion of God
                            upon earth, in which ruleth the higher form of Love, having in it less of self and more of
                            God. Let Love and Logic rule. The Sunday Press (Albany, N. Y.) says, The Shaker, while being
                            full of good things, has two prominent faults — too small by one-half, and too seldom by the
                            same measurement.</p></div2><div2 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agricultural" TEIform="index"/>AGRICULTURAL</head><p TEIform="p">"Now try it," in the Country Gentleman — the best agricultural journal in this country— gives
                            us the kernel of success with stock, when he writes the following article. We keep cows for
                            their milk, and to get the largest quantity of this, no reasonable pains should be spared. * <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">COMFORT OF FARM STOCK. The idea of comfort, practically and intelligently
                                    regarded, is the key to success with all farm stock ; other things equal, the most
                                    comfortable animal is the best looking and most profitable. Acting accordingly, some
                                    ten years ago, in December, I devoted a half day's work, $2, to tightening up a
                                    stable for five cows, so that no manure froze in it afterward, and instead of having
                                    less milk every cold snap and more every thaw, it was more right along, in milk,
                                    comfort in milking, cleaning the stable, health of cows and thrift of calves, and
                                    only less in amount of feed required. One small Ayrshire coming in just then didn't
                                    vary three pounds from 35 pounds of milk per day, and 10 pounds of butter per week,
                                    for five months. Publishing my experience in the New England Farmer, led others to
                                    go and do likewise, and some years after, one correspondent said, that one item was
                                    worth more to him than the cost of the paper — and so gave the ball another push, as
                                    all should do. I found that with a properly constructed stable, the animal heat from
                                    a cow will keep a space five times her size above freezing temperature, and still
                                    allow good ventilation about her head, regulated at pleasure by an adjustable door
                                    in front. The winter profits of dairies may be increased a third, in saving of
                                    caloric and food, and increased milk and calf product, by remembering that a kind
                                    man is kind to his beast, and that disregarding their comfort " costs money."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Country gentleman" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Criticism—apple grafting, trimming, etc." TEIform="index"/>CRITICISM—APPLE GRAFTING,
                            TRIMMING, ETC.</head><p TEIform="p">A. Leavens, Amateur Nurseryman, Concord, N. H., writes substantially as follows: "Dear friend
                            Briggs: Your article in Jan. Shaker on ' Starting a Nursery ' interested me much. Thinning
                            the young trees, one-half as much as you suggested, is advisable. Root-grafting, is found by
                            us to be as good as the ckoUar-graftlng which you recommend, and its advantages are, you get
                            several grafts from each seedling—using only a few inches of the root for a graft. "
                            Whip-grafting is generally employed; but any splice that makes a perfect joint of the inner
                            barks, is just as well. Grafts should be set so that the upper bud will just touch the
                            surface, to prevent the graft drying before cohering. I mulch with saw-dust as an additional
                            protection. "FJder Evans is mistaken about trimming trees in the fall — the majority of best
                            pomologists prefer late spring, or June! The wound heals quickly, while trimming in the
                            fall, the rot is more apt to set in. (How these doctors differ! Ed.) "Again: Hen manure and
                            ashes are inferior as top dressing for onions, to plaster and hen manure—the ashes tending
                            to neutralization."</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Simple remedies" TEIform="index"/>SIMPLE REMEDIES</head><p TEIform="p">Croup may be destroyed in a few minutes by grating a teaspoonful of alum, and mixing with
                            double its quantity of sugar. Administer as soon as possible. All throat disorders find in
                            this simple remedy a foe. " A grateful reader of The Shaker since it was first published,"
                            in Grand Rapids, Mich., recommends a tablespoonful or more of dry wheat bran, three times a
                            day, before meals, as a sovereign cure for dyspepsia, when other suggested agents have
                            failed. There's philosophy in the suggestion, and undoubtedly relief. A friend assures us
                            that the destructive "onion worm " can be totally dispelled by a free use of common field
                            plaster, as early as the plants will bear it, and continued. If this is so, every gardener
                            in the country can afford to send the value of one row to the publisher of The Shaker.
                            Hoarseness is relieved by using, thoroughly beaten, the white of an egg, with lemon juice
                            and sugar. Take a teaspoonful occasionally. Corns : Pare closely; apply castor oil every
                            night before retiring. The corn soon assumes the softness of other flesh. Southern Medical
                            Record. Bunions: Take juice of two lemons; put a dozen old pearl buttons into it, place all
                            in a bottle; shake the material occasionally. Apply to the surface twice dally. This remedy
                            is. also recommended for corns and warts. Tooth Ache : The English Mechanic suggests to any
                            one having sore or aching teeth, to put a piece of quicklime, as large as a walnut into a
                            pint of water; rub the teeth and gums therewith once a day, rinsing the mouth afterward.
                            Felon: Common rock salt, dried, pulverized fine, mix an equal amount of spirits of
                            turpentine. Apply on a rag, keeping the felon moist with this for 24 hours. Burns: One dram
                            alum, pulverized; whites of two eggs, teacupful of lard or fresh butter. Cover the surface,
                            change daily.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Speak no ill" TEIform="index"/>SPEAK NO ILL</head><p TEIform="p">" Nay, speak no ill, a kindly word Can never leave a sting behind; And oh, to breathe each
                            tale we've heard, 'Tis far beneath a noble mind. Full oft, a better seed is sown By choosing
                            thus the better plan! For if but little good is known, Still let us speak the best we can. "
                            Give me the heart that fain would hide — Would fain another's faults efface; How can it
                            profit human pride To prove humanity but base ? Nay, let us reach a higher mood — A nobler
                            estimate of man — Be earnest in the search for good, And speak of all the best we can. "Then
                            speak no ill, but lenient be To others' failings, as our own ; If you're the first a fault
                            to see Be not the first to make it known; For life is but a passing day No lip can tell how
                            brief its span; Then oh, the little time we stay Let's speak of all the best we can." Kind
                            Editor: Will you please insert this poem in The Shaker? I think very much of it, and wish it
                            a wider application.</p><byline TEIform="byline"> Your sister, <persName reg="Bowie, Samantha" TEIform="persName"/>Samantha Bowie</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Appreciation" TEIform="index"/>APPRECIATION</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Shaker and Dear Friends: Enclosed please find sixty cents for one year's subscription of
                            "The Shaker," which I have read for several years, and which has been to me a source of
                            great peace and comfort; so much so that it would be a great privation to do without it.
                            Though my life has been one of many cares, and though difficulties have darkened my pathway,
                            and cast gloomy shadows upon the bright prospects of my future; I have pressed on my way
                            with faith, trusting to the guidance of that hand that can lead us safely, even through
                            darkest clouds, and thickest mists. "The Shaker" has been a light to my feet and a lamp to
                            my pathway. It has brightened my hope and renewed my strength. May its light continue to
                            shine, and its might prevail, till all clouds shall be driven away, the rough places made
                            smooth, all wrongs righted, and all shall see the salvation and glory of God. Looking
                            forward to this glorious consummation, I ask to be remembered in your prayers, that I and
                            many others may be strengthened and enabled to go forward in hope and happiness, even to the
                            end. With my best wishes that " The Shaker " may ever continue — doing for others what it
                            has for me — teaching purity and peace on earth that all may enjoy rest and joy in heaven. I
                            remain, hopefully,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., C. E." TEIform="persName"/>C. E. B., Baltimore, Md.</byline></div2><pb n="24" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Zion's watchword" TEIform="index"/>ZION'S WATCHWORD</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Byrdsall, Charlotte" TEIform="persName"/>CHARLOTTE BYRDSALL</byline><p TEIform="p">North, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. When evening zephyrs whisper When morn upon us breaketh It is a
                            constant blessing Of shadows of the night, When twilight nearer gathers In brightness or in
                            gloom, We find the toil of Zion From eve to morning light, A scene of holy union These hours
                            well fraught with labor, Bring goodness rich and new, And this is Zion's stronghold, And
                            sheds her mellow light, Still in our hearts hath room, From morn to shades of night; Her
                            mission glad and true. Then in this realm of beauty, And joyous in its mission, We store the
                            fruits of conquest For labor is the watchword We feel the magic spell That stills the world
                            of action, We hail each opening day, Go forth to meet the burdens Within life's treasury,
                            And day and night bring nearer That will redeem the earth, It is religion's power, And bids
                            the day farewell. That throng the pilgrim's way. The ransom of the free. Her glory and her
                            worth.</p></div2><div2 type="music" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Music, no. 3" TEIform="index"/>MUSIC, NUMBER THREE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, J. G." TEIform="persName"/>J. G. RUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p">Physiologists reveal to us the startling fact that,the human lungs are composed, in part, of
                            little air-cells, numbering nearly or quite six hundred millions; — all of which nature lias
                            designed to be kept thoroughly and constantly active, by the involuntary process of
                            respiration. At this point a few short extracts from reliable authority will best convey the
                            needful information intended by this article. " 1st. The volume of air ordinarily present in
                            the lungs is about twelve pints. 2nd. The volume of air received by the lungs at an ordinary
                            inspiration is one pint. 3rd. The volume of air expelled from the lungs at an ordinary
                            expiration is a little less than one pint." [Dr. Southwood Smith.] Again — "In health, the
                            smallest number of respirations in a minute by an adult, is not less than fourteen, and they
                            rarely exceed twenty-five. Eighteen may be considered an average number." [Gutter.] From the
                            foregoing quotations, the evidence should be sufficiently clear, to prove that a far greater
                            portion of air received into the lungs, is that which has been breathed over a number of
                            times — as for instance — "a school-room thirty feet square and eight feet high contains
                            7,200 cubic feet of air. This room will seat sixty pupils, and allowing ten cubic feet of
                            air to each pupil per minute, all the air in the room will be vitiated in twelve minutes."
                            [Cutter.] And yet how frequent is this occurrence manifest, in many of our music halls,
                            where music is the all-absorbing theme of the hour! The writer is here reminded of a
                            somewhat pleasing interchange of musical ideas between a couple of members of a singing
                            school. The interesting question arose whether the human voice was a wind instrument,
                            musically, or a stringed one. The debate was not long continued, before both parties arrived
                            at a permanent conclusion that the voice was a wind instrument, as otherwise it would have
                            continued its sonorous effects, even when the atmospheric element was in a state of
                            unendurable stagnation. Now, in the effort to remedy this prevailing evil of illventilation,
                            a two-fold barrier presents itself; for while we are striving to remove the vitiated air
                            from our suffering lungs on the one hand, we become exposed to chilly, atmospheric currents
                            on the other. A wide field is here open for architectural improvements in ventilation,
                            which, it is hoped, will be thoroughly investigated, and active measures taken to remedy
                            this physiological evil, throughout the entire length and breadth of our land. It does not
                            seem essential to swell this article with scientific explanations or illustrations, to prove
                            that which is known already — that pure atmospheric air is needful to produce pure and
                            healthy blood. Suffice it to say that the culture of vocal music finds its ground work, as
                            really in the proper development of the respiratory process, as music itself finds its
                            groundwork in the proper arrangement and modulation of tones.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>TO EVERGREEN SHORES</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sargent, Sarah" TEIform="index"/>Sarah Sargent
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Ayer, Mass., Jan. 18, 1876, <persName reg="Sargent, Sarah" TEIform="persName">Sarah Sargent</persName>, aged
                                86.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kimball, Emeline" TEIform="index"/>Emeline Kimball
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Shaker Village, N. H., Feb. 3, 1876, <persName reg="Kimball, Emeline" TEIform="persName">Emeline
                                Kimball</persName>, aged 65. We were more than sorry to hear of this great loss to
                                Canterbury. As a physician, nurse, and dear good Sister, "None knew her but to love her,
                                None named her but to praise,"—She leaves us to bloom among the "Evergreens." *</p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our dear J. M. Peebles" TEIform="index"/>OUR DEAR J. M. PEEBLES</head><p TEIform="p">A communication from this Christ Apostle, we are only sorry to say, came too late for this
                            number; but like every thing from him, it is so good, it will keep until we next appear. Our
                            April number -will reach him in Yucatan, among the ruins of Central America, where, we have
                            long been aware, these have had an attraction for him. Wherever he goes, he works for God;
                            and let every heart lift an offering in his behalf. Here's an excerpt from his genial letter
                            to us: * "How the days, months, years glide by! The Centennial is close upon us. And while
                            our Civil Government is preparing for a grand opening in early summer, should it be
                            forgotten by Believers that it is a hundred years that Ann Lee, the baptized of Christ — Ann
                            Lee, guided by revelation — by vision—by Angel Hosts, landed in this country and established
                            the Millennial Church of purity, peace and 'all things in common ?' And should there be no
                            mass gathering —no public recognition of this Centennial cycle by the body of Believers?
                        "</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Song of praise" TEIform="index"/>SONG OF PRAISE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Johnson, Julia" TEIform="persName"/>JULIA JOHNSON</byline><p TEIform="p">While God inspires my heart to sing, Or gives it life to beat, Praise offerings I will freely
                            bring And lay them at his feet. He feeds my soul with hope and faith, And love which never
                            dies; And sheds on it a living warmth, From his celestial skies. His precious power my
                            spirit fills — My highest themes inspire; His presence, all my being thrills With ardent,
                            pure desire. His blessings, hourly, on me pour His chastening and his love; And mercies rich
                            — an endless store — From his white throne above. His fires are kindled in my heart,
                            Extinguished ne'er to be, Till I from sin and death depart, All stainless, pure and free.
                            I'll do his bidding evermore — While life and strength are given — That I may find when time
                            is o'er A rest with him in heaven.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mr. Ruskin at present is advocating dancing as a part of religious education..." TEIform="index"/>Mr. Ruskin at present is advocating dancing as a part of religious education...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ruskin" TEIform="persName">Mr. Ruskin </persName></byline><p TEIform="p">at present is advocating dancing as a part of religious education, and thus assails young
                            lady Sunday School teachers: <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">"At present," he says, "you keep the dancing to yourselves, and graciously teach
                                    your scholars the catechism. Suppose you were to try for a little while learning the
                                    catechism yourselves and teach them to dance."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Albany express" TEIform="index"/>Albany Express.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Chinese are evidently pagans..." TEIform="index"/>The Chinese are evidently pagans...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The Chinese are evidently pagans. They celebrate all their holidays by paying their debts,
                            forgiving their enemies and shaking hands all around. The civilized people who have gone to
                            China have not yet induced them to relinquish these odd and barbarous habits.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The perfume of a thousand roses soon dies..." TEIform="index"/>The perfume of a thousand roses soon dies...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The perfume of a thousand roses soon dies, but the pain caused by one of their thorns remains
                            long after. A saddened remembrance in the midst of mirth is like that thorn among the
                        roses.</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notice" TEIform="index"/>NOTICE.</head><p TEIform="p">We would very kindly request of our subscribers and agents, in sending names to The Shaker,
                            that each name be written plainly and spelled correctly; also that the county, in which the
                            subscriber's Post Office is located, be, in every instance, designated. Careful attention to
                            these directions will avoid much complaint for non-delivery of papers. — Pub. The " Shaker,"
                            for February, which is now out, is a credit to Elder Lomas. the editor, and also to the
                            house which publishes it, for its make-up and general typographical appearance are
                            admirable. — Ktpreas.</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>