<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0607" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shakers, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">6</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">7</biblScope><date value="18760701" TEIform="date">July 1876</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">49-56</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="6" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="49" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="7" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">SHAKER Official Monthly.—Published by the United Societies. WHAT IS TETJTH P" "THE ETERNAL RELINQUISH^E^T OP ERROR."
                        Vol. VI G. A. LOMAS, EDITOR. PTin/rno v v TTTTV 1OTC SHAKES, N. i., JULY, lo/o, SHAKER VILLAGE, 11 N. A. BRIGGS,
                        PUBLISHER. No. 7.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="World's exposition" TEIform="index"/>THE WORLD'S EXPOSITION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p">•'Let Church and State be forever separate." —Grant. The Centennial Exhibition is closed oneseventh of the time.
                            Thus American citizens, and citizens of every nation, are, by priestly diction, called Christian, precluded the
                            improvement of this great educational opportunity. A minority compactly organized are lording it over the rights
                            and consciences of their peers — true Americans — the legitimate successors of the so-called Infidel founders of
                            our Government — the only Government on earth not sectarian — Church and State combined ; a Government with a
                            constitution that secures the inherent right of all human beings — a right to life, liberty of person, liberty
                            of speech and of religious thought, with its outward expression, such expression not interfering with an equally
                            free expression of citizens of this or any other nationality. A World's Exposition, indeed, under the management
                            of a committee of bigoted, persecuting theological tyrants, inseparable from Church and State rule! If closed on
                            the Christian Sabbath, it were a thousand times better never to have held this gathering in the City of
                            Brotherly Love, among Quakers, who, as Christians, esteem all days alike good, to those who are good. Nor yet in
                            Pennsylvania, founded by William Penn, who proclaimed liberty of conscience to all Men and Women therein.
                            Neither should the Exposition for All the World have assembled in the United States, under a Government founded
                            by such men as Jefferson, Paine and Franklin, and sealed with the martyr blood of a Lincoln — Infidel to a
                            spurious Christianity, scripturally called the " Great Whore," because she perpetually lusts after an adulterous
                            association with the Civil Governments of earth, Governments resting upon the sword, and used for the oppression
                            of the people. The whole American People — Jews, Quakers, Infidels, Freethinkers, Pagan, Chinese, and
                            representatives of all Religions, not AntiChristian, should rise up in mass and open the Exposition on all days
                            of the week, beginning with the Sabbath, or remove the whole mis-representation of a World's Exposition into
                            Spain or Mexico — some legitimate Constitutional Church and State Government. In America it is a gross libel
                            upon our Constitution. The same insidious clerical power that has closed the Exposition upon their typical,
                            ceremonial Sabbath, has, thereby, taken one step toward subverting the Constitution itself. Let free America
                            rebuke that power, and, with Grant, proclaim that, in one nation, Church and State shall forever be separate. In
                            the first Constitutional Convention we were trapped — caught napping. A seed of Slavery was left in the
                            Constitution. We are paying the cost of that error. Shall we commit a second error, and permit subtle
                            priestcraft to sow the seeds of a religious, civil war in our Centennial Constitution? Then shall we have been
                            recreant to our duty as American citizens, false to our profession of liberty of conscience, and faithless to
                            the sacred trust of guardians of the rights and liberties of humanity the world over. Let there be on earth one
                            free government, where the whole world can meet at their own discretion, on everybody's Sabbath day. That will
                            be the great Sabbath of rest from religious persecution — a Sabbath that will forever remain for the People of
                            God. As a Shaker, I believe the Civil Government should be a Pkepublic of citizens — Men and Women of all races
                            and nations, possessed of equal rights to life and land — to liberty, unadulterated by sectarian theology — to
                            freedom from debt, war, poverty or riches. Then we can also have a spiritual church, in God, possessing no
                            earthly power other than the power of truth, as exhibited in holy lives by its communicants. Mt. Lebanon,
                            Columbia County, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Steadfastness" TEIform="index"/>STEADFASTNESS</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Avery, G. B." TEIform="persName"/>G. B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p">The overruling fault of the great throng of Pilgrim Progressionists — that which blights the visionary harvest of
                            rewards of millions who make a bold start in the pathway of progression, is vacillation. The trials incident to
                            an earnest endeavor to rise out of the vast slough of degradation, ignorance, supine indifference to
                            improvement, and shameless folly and sin which is the characteristic element of the massive millions of earth's
                            inhabitants, which goad the feelings of the pilgrim and prompt a return to former conditions, to plod along with
                            the masses in slothful ease, error and dishonor, the jibes, sneers and rebuffs which a pilgrim progressionist
                            has to meet from the idle, careless throng he is leaving behind, are things hard to bear ; and a soul needs the
                            shield and fortification of a firm conviction of the truth and righteousness of the work of progress undertaken,
                            with a godly and heroic philanthropy that points upward the sight, to view a worthier purpose for which to toil
                            through life, and unfalteringly holds up the resolution to live and strive for this purpose, and to accomplish
                            it though companions should flinch and fall on every side. Every Christian Pilgrim Progressionist should
                            remember that never yet did even one soul perseveringly and consecratedly pursue the Christian's pathway but was
                            scoffed at by the world, and deemed an enthusiast, a lunatic, or a fool! Even so in the arena of progress in
                            science, art, or literature. The inventive progressionists — the world's greatest benefactors — those who have
                            awakened the world from torpitude, advanced the development of improvement in human conditions, have generally
                            led lives fifty, one hundred, five hundred, or a thousand years in advance of the masses, and, by them, either
                            looked upon as Utopian dreamers, insane enthusiasts, or fools. But those of this class who have had the dignity
                            and philanthropy to persevere and go ahead, despite all opposition, thus showing themselves true men and women,
                            instead of mere human tools, to be handled by the masses at the nod and beck of fashion, public opinion or
                            prejudice, as the wake and wave of public sentiment might flow for the moment, have been the Benefactors, the
                            Saviours, and Redeemers of the race. These are the only human beings worthy of the title of men and women. And
                            surely none others justly merit the name of Brothers and Sisters in Christ's Kingdom. It is related by the
                            biographer of Demosthenes, that he went into the public halls and called out, " Come unto me all men." The
                            populace began to gather around him, and he commenced to cane them, crying out, " I called for men, these are
                            nothing but excrescences." They were the masses of unstable, weak, foolish, fashionable, giddy and purposeless
                            throng, who were drifting on the ocean of circumstances without a ruddor of fixed purpose to guide their barques
                            to a harbor of progressed improvement and excellence. There has of late been a very great anxiety among
                            Believers in the Kingdom of Christ, to have some council of the wisest and most progressed souls held at some
                            location where such council might discuss the important subject of the most efficient means of awakening a
                            renewed vigor of progress in Gospel Travel, and a manifesto and disbursement of power that should call into
                            Zipn's ranks an abundant harvest of souls, to heighten, enliven and quicken the spiritual and social status of
                            Zion, and make her what she is called to be, " the light of the world," " the salt of the earth." . The city of
                            glory set on a hill as example to the nations of God's righteousness and goodness manifest among men — the true
                            epistle of Christianity to the unbelievers. Ah, we might multiply councils infinitely, and discuss ways and
                            means with the wisdom of the sages of Solomon, suggest stimulants to fire the resolution, and excitements to
                            progress, as numerous as the pearly dew-drops of the morning, but, like them, when the sun of righteousness
                            should shine upon them, all THE <pb n="50" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 5O THE would pass off in vapor, without a soul work of
                            conviction of the siafulness of sin, and the folly and misery of a worldly life, of such force, depth and
                            intensity as to turn souls short about from their worldly career of life, and cause them to be willing, and not
                            only willing but unflinchingly determined to die to its life! to confess sin, repent and turn to God. At present
                            the prevailing wave of public feeling is as fickle as the colors of the rainbow. And the popular religion of the
                            day is largely verbose and so smally actual that its power is mostly swallowed up in a sea of elocution. Its "
                            salt is largely without a savor." But words are like carriages, they may run empty or full of meaning and power,
                            but their fullness is largely due to the embodiment of their sentiment in the life pulsations of the speaker.
                            What is needed, without the aid of a council to dictate it, is an earnest, zealous, persevering stability in
                            living the Christ life, so that a power may flow forth to humanity that is like an ocean's wave — mighty in
                            baptism, with salt enough to save ! Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beautiful rivers" TEIform="index"/>BEAUTIFUL RIVERS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>MARTHA J. ANDEBSON</byline><p TEIform="p">Beautiful rivers, like silvery threads — Coursing their way over dark sandy beds, Sweeping through valleys and
                            circling the hills, Gathering the ripples from thousands of rills,— Flowing from mountain, from rock, and from
                            dell, Ocean-bound waters with music to swell, Brooklet and fountain, and deep placid lake, Greet the bright
                            waves on your surface to break. Beautiful rivers that gladden the earth, Spirit of waters with joy gave you
                            birth ! The smile of her face was impressed on your tide, Beaming forever as onward you glide; Joyously singing
                            the song of the free — Giving with pleasure your wealth to the sea ; Dancing, and glancing, with sunbeams at
                            play, Never shall cloud on your sunny face stay. Beautiful rivers, majestic and grand, Blessing the desert of
                            Egypt's fair land! Waking the verdure 'neath tropical sun, Flowering the sands where your golden streams run;
                            Filling the air with the moisture it needs,— Rising like incense of kind, loving deeds — Forming the clouds over
                            mountain and plain, Falling in copious showers of rain. Beautiful rivers that rolled on your way, Long before
                            man saw the light of the day — Long e'er the light gazelle sought you to drink — Long e'er the wild races dwelt
                            on your brink. They who made hunting and fishing their aim Came and passed on, yet you flowed on the same! Now,
                            all along by your rocky bound course, Shrieks the shrill voice of the fleet iron horse : Civilization, with
                            quick pulse and heart — Bears its bold front and its busiest mart. Beautiful rivers! so calm in your flow,
                            Vessels of freight, safely sail to and fro — Gliding like nymphs o'er your broad open breast, Ploughing the
                            waves to a foam-beaten crest. Thus through the means art and science can wield, Men interchange the rich fruits
                            of the field ; Commerce and trade, with their works of renown Spread their white sails by the city and town.
                            Beautiful rivers! your murmurings sweet Sing to my spirit of ooncord complete; Ev'ry clear drop that may enter
                            your tide, Knows not the spirit that seeks to divide ; 0 ! that life's current thus smoothly might roll, Free
                            from the care that perplexes the soul, Stirring its depths, till the whirlpool of strife Sinks all the good that
                            would gladden our life. 'Tis by the side of some beautiful stream, 1 would sleep my last sleep, and dream my
                            last dream! Waking to joy on the bright sunny shore, To walk by the river of life evermore ! Leaving no trace of
                            my pilgrimage here — Save in the hearts of the loving ones dear — Ripples shall murmur a song soft and low, As
                            the tide of my life on forever shall flow! Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prayer" TEIform="index"/>PRAYER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, O. C." TEIform="persName"/>O. C. HAMPTON</byline><p TEIform="p">Prayer is an earnest petition to God or other intelligences higher than ourselves, for certain blessings and
                            comforts positively ; or, negatively, for assistance and deliverance from sorrows and dangers besetting us,
                            which those higher powers are supposed by the petitioner to be able to bestow. Sometimes these prayers are
                            addressed to kings, presidents, legislative bodies, right here in our own world ; sometimes to angels — Jesus
                            Christ — God. Prayer will continue as long as intercession continues to be a necessity of humanity, and an
                            atonement with better beings and conditions is an active element of man's nature. No matter how much infidelity,
                            nor how many scoffers at prayer there may be in the world — in times of peril, sorrows, sickness (of soul or
                            body) men will continue to pray, infidels and all; and so long as we have sweet and holy aspirations for better
                            things, we shall give expression thereto in. Prayer. If I had been one of the ministers to whom John Tyndall
                            proposed to institute daily prayers for the relief and recovery of the inmates of a certain number of hospitals,
                            for some given number of months, I should not have hesitated a moment to have tried the experiment ; and they
                            showed a most lamentable want of confidence in their own profession by declining his proposal. His proposal was
                            perfectly fair, and if prayer cannot be vindicated on the grounds of his plan it cannot be vindicated at all.
                            Some honest men who would consider it a grievous thing to be called infidels, assert that all God's laws are of
                            necessity bound in chains of everlasting fixity, and therefore cannot be modified by any amount of Prayer. And
                            yet these same persons describe God as a being altogether incomprehensible to finite intelligences. How do they
                            know, then, that eternal fixity is an attribute of a being they know nothing about? For all that can be proven
                            to the contrary, unfixity or eternal change is as much an element in the character of God's laws as eternal
                            fixity. Evolution is supposed to be one of those laws, and what of that V Again we do not know how much of the
                            universe, indeed whether or not all of it is manipulated by finite intelligences in an infinitely ascending
                            category of degrees of power and wisdom. Indeed, there are good reasons for supposing that what are called the
                            laws of the universe are and must continue to be dead or dormant negations, only as they are brought into active
                            visible existence by the finite intelligences of the universe. Take the laws of the transmission of thought
                            around the globe in one hundredth part of a second ! Without a Morse it might have remained a dead negation,
                            incarcerated in a tomb of everlasting silence and inactivity, or had not a finite mind felt the necessity of its
                            active agency and brought the conditions together for its dehibernation. So with steamships without a Watt,
                            Fulton, and so of photographing without a Daguerre. If, then, the laws of the universe appear to be only latent
                            possibilities, with latent powers capable of manipulation by finite minds, not yielding any visible results till
                            they are thus manipulated, why should it be incredible that these laws may be modified in their operation,
                            intensified, or even suspended in their activity for a time, by finite manipulations of the conditions upon
                            which these phenomena depend ! And as we know that finite minds can be moved and propitiated in our favor, how
                            can it be inconsistent to pray for any blessing we are in need of, either temporal or spiritual ? and echo
                            answers why. Union Village, 0.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Animadversion on Parton" TEIform="index"/>ANIMADVERSION ON PARTON</head><p TEIform="p">Editor Shaker: In the May number of The Shaker I noticed an article entitled " Parton's Apology," and I would beg
                            leave to take exceptions to some of the sentiments expressed therein. The historian says : " But it was not
                            Calvin who burned him (Servetus). It was the century. It was imperfectly developed human nature, etc., etc." I
                            would ask, what makes a century or an age characteristic if not the men who are the chief actors in the affairs
                            of their time ? When Napoleon I. caused the murder of the Duke d' Enghien, surely no one will ascribe that
                            horrible outrage to the age, and relieve the imperial criminal from the odium attached to that deed. And when a
                            Belknap shamelessly betrays a high trust and brings dishonor upon his country, who will have the temerity to
                            screen him by pleading in extenuation the nineteenth century? The writer furthermore apologetically suggests, u
                            imperfectly developed human nature." Is a person who can so far forget himself as to cause the excruciating
                            death of his opponent, where the points of difference were at best but trivial, and the unfortunate victim of
                            his hatred, his peer, if not his superior in morality, virtue and learning; a person who at the same time
                            assumes to interpret scripture and to establish a system of religion for mankind, is such a person to be excused
                            by "imperfectly developed human nature?" However charitably we may be disposed toward the tyrant who could so
                            abuse his power, it would be wrong to hide the fact from the world that he never felt remorse or repentance, but
                            in after years ferociously asserted that under like circumstances he would do so again. A deed which would have
                            stained the character of a Nero, becomes a crime of lasting infamy in a Calvin. But the doctrine is false and
                            pernicious. Men are individually responsible for their acts, and no power in heaven nor earth can change the
                            fact. True, there may be extenuating circumstances in every case, yet the deed remains the same after all, and
                            how will you secure justice to the wronged victim ? Whatever James Parton's opinion may be concerning those dark
                            transactions with which the name of the Geneva divine is connected, he is doing a good work in thus bringing
                            them before the public; for there are millions of the followers of Calvin who have never heard the sad story of
                            the unfortunate Michael Servetus. Yours,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Basting, Louis" TEIform="persName"/>Louis Basting. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><pb n="51" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Stormy sea" TEIform="index"/>THE STORMY SEA</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sedgwick, E. A." TEIform="persName"/>E. A. SEDGWICK</byline><p TEIform="p">When troubles and rough feelings come upon our minds making them like the restless ocean, let Christ arise within
                            us, and " rebuke the wind and wave," bringing a peaceful calm. Let reason have its rule ; then we will sail
                            smoothly on the waters of life, unruffled by the tempests of passion. Let us try to live above trouble, counting
                            ourselves the master and not the servant. If the principles of Christ are within us no trouble can sink our
                            souls. West Pittsjield, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Soliloquy" TEIform="index"/>SOLILOQUY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Witham, Maria" TEIform="persName"/>MARIA WITHAM</byline><p TEIform="p">My mind abandons itself to reverie, and is transferred in ecstacy to nature and nature's God. It sees in the
                            simplicity of nature's elements and laws the wisdom and majesty of the great Creator. I feel withdrawn from
                            earth and rise above the little theater of human passions and anxieties to lift my soul in pious contemplation.
                            My mind expands with fervent desires for Truth and Knowledge ; and I scale heaven's pure walls with truthful
                            aspirations rather than worship the good opinion of erring man. In the gilded canopy of heaven, Divinity reigns
                            in all the grandeur of its attributes, greatness and strength, and travels through the dominions of an unlimited
                            monarchy. Fancy may take its flight far beyond the power of eye or the telescope. It may expatiate in the outer
                            regions of all that is visible, yet who shall have the boldness to say that the wonders of the Almighty are at
                            an end, because we can no longer trace his footsteps ! Let me rather say with the Psalmist, " What is man that
                            thon art mindful of him, or the son of man that thou visitest him ! " O bounteous one, what have I not received
                            from thee! Throughout the seasons that are past, I see sweet places everywhere. My body and soul have been fed
                            by the most congenial food. Thy chastening hand has proved a blessing; and looking backward through time that
                            has passed, and along the way my feet have pressed, what have I not received from thee, my strength, my stay. A
                            moment from this outward life I joyfully retreat, and in thy presence tell thee, that within I feel so satisfied
                            thy cross to bear. Oh, do not spare the chastening rod that keeps me by thy side. Oh, sweetly give me strength
                            to bear whatever waits me here. Enfield, Conn.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lighted temple" TEIform="index"/>THE LIGHTED TEMPLE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>MARY WHITCHER</byline><p TEIform="p">" Cast the team, out of thine own eye." Subdue thyself, then beauty will appear Where now thou seest it not; For
                            when the mental sight's not clear, Motes will be seen, and many a seeming blot. Only by light within, and heart
                            made free From sin and all the stains of sin, Art thou prepared to rightly see, And cast thy brother's beam from
                            him. So near to God, then let my spirit move — So full of goodness let my motives be — That I may kindly see,
                            and truly love My fellow men, as God hath love for me. Shaker Village, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes by the way, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>NOTES BY THE WAY-NO. 2</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/>H. C. BLINN</byline><p TEIform="p">As I write the above title, my first thought is to pencil a few religious notes adapted to the necessities of
                            those who are stepping upon the stage of active life. There can be no doubt, that line upon line and precept
                            upon precept will be as much needed for a few years to come, as they were supposed to be in the past, I had no
                            sooner written my first word, when an illustration of real life that some kind friend had sent to me, attracted
                            my attention, and this was no less than a chicken, just emerging from its shell! Already it had assumed an
                            attitude of defiance, and was ready to contend for its privileges, with a character of a full grown of its
                            species. Well, I remarked, here is a lesson for the present generation — a picture for precocious children.
                            Indeed, it might be studied with profit by fond but foolish parents, and with no less care by the would-be-wise.
                            And then herein is a lesson for our own religious order: Dependent as we are upon the world for all accessions,
                            we should not let the subject of children pass carelessly by. Solomon's wisdom has lost its charm over the
                            child, if it ever had any. " Train him up in the way he should go," sounds well, but the attempt to reduce it to
                            practice is something more than sounds. Born into this world, filled to overflowing with an inherited tendency
                            to all the ills of the flesh, it would need an angel on the right and left side to keep him from willingly
                            falling into sin. However, I shall leave the chicken with its fighting proclivities developing so soon after its
                            transition state, and perhaps by-and-by I may learn the great difference, should there be any, between the
                            development 0$ life in this order and that of a class which assumes to be more exalted in the grand scheme of
                            creation. " First that which is natural and afterward that which is spiritual," seems at this time for the
                            writer, as it no doubt often does to others, as an anodyne to the mind. It is, indeed, the legitimate order of
                            our lives in this world and may be all for the best. I must now make reference to the Apostle Peter who took
                            such an active interest in the happiness of those around him, for he speaks thus pleasantly to us: "He that
                            would lots life and see good days, let him refrain his tongue from evil, and his lips that they speak no guile."
                            To those who are young, in an especfal manner, I would commend this exhortation, and urge upon them the
                            necessity of allowing it to shape their lives. " Good days " are an inheritance far preferable to great riches.
                            It is a legacy which the wealthy of this world can never confer upon their heirs at law. Those who are so
                            fortunate as to obtain the treasure, must obtain it through their own labors of gielf-denial — by the cross of
                            Christ., The professor will " love life " because of the good he may do. It is not to those only who are
                            addicted to the use of vulgar and profane language that this has a direct application, but it is equally potent
                            to that class, who profess to be cultivated for the society of the virtuous and refined. Indeed, it is to be
                            more dreaded, in its advances, as it comes from what is assumed to be the higher ranks of society. It is the
                            ferocious beast, lurking under the false garb of cultivation. The viper charming his unsuspecting prey, while
                            the innocent mind thinks only of the external beauty. Let every young person refrain his tongue from evil, or he
                            may have occasion to mourn when it is too late,— when " those days shall come in which he will say I have no
                            pleasure in thee." Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Farewell counsel" TEIform="index"/>FAREWELL COUNSEL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wetherbee, William H." TEIform="persName"/>WILLIAM H. WETHERBEE</byline><p TEIform="p">May God in His mercy be near and direct you. While passing along the rough journey of life ; Blay His angels at
                            all times watch o'er and protect you, Whene'er you sojourn where temptations are rife. Should the phantoms of
                            earth shine brightly upon you, With their promised pleasures that fain would allure, Then stand ye with
                            firmness, let no one take from you The garment of innocence, spotless and pure. When far in the west (if
                            perchance you should go there), And trials and troubles you still there should meet; When you find in your
                            rambles true comfort is nowhere, Then hasten ye back to this lowly retreat. Here peace and true icomfort and
                            justification Are free for the honest, the humble and low ; And though they are found in a meek, humble station,
                            They are worth more than all this earth can bestow. A few days will flit, and will end earthly pleasure, Then
                            tangible objects will vanish like dew ; The spirit immortal will then need a treasure — Remember this, Rose, for
                            'tis written for you. Written for L. R. W. Shirley.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="That dream" TEIform="index"/>THAT DREAM</head><p TEIform="p">Beloved Editor : Your letter, requesting particulars of dream mentioned in Atlantic Monthly for June, is at hand.
                            Uncertain that others will be benefited by my compliance, though to me the dream is a remarkable fact. I wish I
                            could give the inspirational force, which accompanies every remembrance of it, even at the present time. We, my
                            whole family, left Liverpool, March 15, 1842, in the then new Packet, Shekidan. We were four days and five
                            nights clearing St. George's Channel and Irish Sea, experiencing the equinoctial storm, which waa very severe
                            indeed. I kept a daily "journal; and among many interesting incidents that may to-day be read therein, I find
                            entered : " Mar. 22 : Had a most remarkable dream, during the little broken sleep of last night. I was
                            proprietor of large pleasure grounds and gardens in America. Had Father, mother, Mary Ann {then my wife, now my
                            gospel sister, children, with Grand Fathers, Mothers, Uncles, Aunts, and a great many respectable people, all
                            enjoying these beautiful grounds and gardens ! A strange mingling of feelings are mine — bitter and sweet — kind
                            and unkind!" Such is the memorandum. As before intimated, it is quite impossible to communicate the impression
                            made on my mind. And when I came to Shirley, in March, 1849, and recognized that very spot of beauty, what could
                            express my wondering surprise ? I have not seen here, all the parties named in my dream, some, even then, being
                            dead; but 1 Itave met here, some whom I then did see, and whom 1 never met before ! The spot is not in as high
                                <pb n="52" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 52 THE 8HAKEE. a state of cultivation as I then saw it; but what I may realize when my
                            mortal is " put off," or when, like Elisha's servant, my spiritual eyes are opened, I know not. Neither have I,
                            in a worldly view, realized the proprietorship— excepting in the nobler intent of " they that buy, as though
                            they possessed not" — and thus, my dream has been fully experienced. To this day, I cannot approach that
                            particular spot, without a new feeling of gratitude, that my feet were led to Shirley, where I have found so
                            much of good — so much of God manifested. I have ever esteemed the dream as a " special " providence (if you
                            please), to strengthen and confirm my spirit; though what angel ministered it, must be determined in the future.
                            If any others can thereby be comforted, I am glad, and shall feel amply paid for intruding so much of my
                            personal history upon them, in yielding to your request. With never-foiling love, I am, yours, P. S.— I was very
                            much pleased with your communication to the Albany 'Express, and think you will be equally pleased with Elder
                            Daniel Fraser's criticism upon it. We had 275 copies of Howell's article struck off, and have had copies of your
                            Express letter printed to accompany them wherever sent. The world moves! and the call for light and truth is
                            steadily increasing. Let us keep good courage — let it not fail — and if we keep good, we will never be forsaken
                            of God, the great fountain of all good. Farewell. J. W.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whiteley, John" TEIform="persName"/>John Whiteley Shirley Villaae, Mass., May 30,1876.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Love vs. fear" TEIform="index"/>LOVE vs. FEAR</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Woods, Joseph" TEIform="persName"/>JOSEPH 'WOODS</byline><p TEIform="p">The Apostle John says: God is love ; He that dwelleth in love dwelleth in God and God in him. In love there is no
                            fear. He that feareth is not made perfect in the love of God, for he is still in danger of being overcome by the
                            powers of evil, and by the god of this world. The evidence of our love to God will be the manifestation of our
                            love to our brethren and sisters. If a man love not his brother whom he has seen, how can he love God whom he
                            hath not seen! St. Paul feared, after having preached to others, lest he should become blinded by the spirit of
                            this world and turn from God. Have we any less need of watchfulness, until we have overcome the world'{ We have
                            the example of Jesus and many others of being filled with the spirit of God. Ecclesiastes sums up the whole
                            matter in a few words — Fear God and keep his commandments, for this is the whole duty of man. Fear may be well
                            for those who, like Moses, Nehemiah, and King David, regarded God as absolute Judge, taking vengeance on those
                            who knew Him. not. Those who conceive God to be such a being, and the devil corresponding in some respects, full
                            of wrath — going about as the roaring lion seeking whom he may devour — truly with such a frame of belief well
                            might fear lest they be destroyed in whatever course they might pursue. Fear induces a slavish obedience, and in
                            persons of this class, it may, perhaps, out of servile fear, place some restraint upon their passions, lest
                            wrath overtake them. Not that they see any thing lovely in God or goodness or have any the less inclination
                            toward that which is corrupt. But close upon this followrs the law — " What a man soweth that shall he also
                            reap." Laws appertaining to the natural and spiritual world are as essentially God's laws, and a violation of
                            either brings a corresponding penalty — we reap what we sow. This can be no special judgment from God, but
                            rather the condemnation of our own lives. St. Paul says: " He that soweth to the flesh shall of the flesh reap
                            corruption," and this he describes as adultery, fornication, uncleanness, lasciviousness, idolatry, witchcraft,
                            strife, seditions, heresy, envyings, murderers,drunkenness, etc., and that they who commit these things shall
                            not inherit the kingdom of God. Will those who live after the course of the world and harvest to themselves a
                            part or all of the forementioned evils, charge God as the author of the same ? The rational and enlightened mind
                            will no doubt admit that it is the harvest of his own sowing — the fruit of his own labor. It is well for the
                            transgressor to fear God, for falling into his hands is a fearful thing. Some have thought that Jesus taught his
                            disciples to fear God rather than to love him, when he said: "Fear not them which kill the body, but are not
                            able to kill the soul ; but fear Him which is able to destroy both soul and body in hell." Love caateth out
                            fear, and certainly love is preferable, for they that dwell in love dwell in God. Why should we make ourselves
                            miserable, when we might, by obedience to the law of Christ, be happy ? Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="music" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Music, no. 7" TEIform="index"/>MUSIC, NO. 7</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, James G." TEIform="persName"/>JAMES G. RUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p">Although there are specified points in the musical gamut for change in the registers of the voice, such assertion
                            is not without its modification, that singers meet with difficulties seemingly insurmountable. As " command of
                            hand is the soul of penmanship," so likewise, command of tone is the soul of music. Having a theoretical
                            knowledge of the points where the registers change, the inefficient singer will experience a weakness in power
                            of tone at those points where the changes occur, which can be remedied only by a practical acquisition of tone
                            command. A better explanation is unsought for than that given by Bassini, concerning the junction of the chest
                            and medium registers. He says: " In training the voice, the teacher should commence with the chest register; and
                            this from the fact that where the chest and medium registers play into each other, the voice is weak and
                            uncertain, and it is an extremely difficult matter to equalize it. But this equalization is just the important
                            task to be accomplished. The method to be pursued is this : the tones which are common to both the chest and
                            medium registers, must be practiced alternately with each. For just as the skillful workman, who would join two
                            pieces of wood and make the strength at the points of adjustment equal to the rest, will dove-tail the two, by
                            extending the end of one sufficiently far in upon the end of the other to prevent any weakness at the
                            extremities; so the skillful teacher will extend the limit of one register into the middle of the next, until
                            the weak tones of both are blended, and become equally sound and strong — the point of contact being smoothed
                            and obliterated altogether." The quoted remarks apply particularly to the chest and medium registers, as the
                            same author remarks also, that " the medium and head registers do not at all coincide, and have no tones in
                            common — a fact explained by the identity of tube." Prominent, then, in the great field of music culture, is the
                            arduous task of combining the chest and medium registers in a manner, not only to make the tones equally strong
                            where the two registers meet, but also to acquire that command of tone, that the voice never may be injured by
                            an unconscious forcing of the registers beyond their natural position — a fault alarmingly conspicuous, and
                            often attended with most serious consequences on the part of the singer, especially at that critical period of
                            life termed the " age of puberty." At that season the voice is undergoing a decided change in both quality and
                            pitch of tone. With males, the change is peculiarly marked by an anatomical alteration of the larynx, whose
                            enlargement assumes a conspicuous prominence in the throat, the voice descending a whole octave in pitch from
                            the position it occupied in childhood, becomes extremely masculine, and, for a season, frequently beyond power
                            of control. With females, the change is less marked, as the voice retains its pitch, yet changes essentially in
                            quality and volume of tone. But no less injuries are likely to accrue, if due cognizance be not taken of the
                            circumstances attending this peculiar season of voice-changing. The warning words of the eminent Bassini are
                            these: "Many voices are irretrievably lost during this time through carelessness of their possessors, or the
                            ignorance of singing masters." It should become, therefore, the irresistible conviction of every singer, that
                            the laws which govern the musical universe are as fixed and unchangeable as those pertaining to the organism of
                            our physical being; and just as assuredly we must reap the fatal consequences of violated law in the former
                            case, as we would expect to reap them in the latter.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Regrets" TEIform="index"/>REGRETS</head><p TEIform="p">How often for treasures ami pleasures ive sigh, Which, when ours, unnoticed, we permit to pass by! A. Calver. On
                            time's hastening current we are carried along, Each day to our goal drawing near; But how oft we're impressed by
                            an influence strong To pause in our vapid career— To pause for reflection — the past to review, Its good or its
                            evil recount; And thus we can test, if our hearts are but true, The clearness of life's flowing fount. We sigh
                            for the hours that have passed unimproved; They are fled, and we sigh but in vain ; Thus moments misspent are as
                            blanks in our lives, Or as blots we're compelled to retain. We cannot efface from our memory's chart The time we
                            have wasted each day ; Thus treasures escape and we value them not, But sigh when they're far, far away. How
                            many the times, when good might be done, Have slipped unimproved from our grasp,— Where help to a friend or
                            brother in need, Our hearts in true friendship would clasp. For our light and enjoyment increase every time That
                            we shed on our neighbor a ray ; Thus pleasures escape, and we let them pass by, To sigh when they're far, far
                            away. We have health—'tis a treasure that God has bestowed. And each has been blessed with a share ; But if ^Ye
                            neglect His immutable laws, 'Twill be lost — still we seem not to care. At last to our sorrow we find it is
                            gone, We are paralyzed then with dismay ; Thus treasures escape, we have let them pass on, To sigh when they're
                            far, far away. <pb n="53" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE 53 But there is a tie which binds us to earth. 'Tis an anchor which
                            heaven has given ; Were it not for this bond our frail bark, many times, On the rocks of despair might be
                            driven. It lightens our sorrows, and brightens our joys, Dispelling the clouds from our way ; While thro1 storms
                            and temptations it bears us along, Dispensing a life-cheering ray. This treasure is friendship — the friendship
                            of those Who are toiling along by our side, Who have with us rejoiced, and in sorrow have mourned, By
                            temptations alike have been tried ; But how bitter the thought, when, by passion or pride, Or envy, we've
                            severed the tie ! Thus treasures escape, and we value them not, But lament when we find them passed by. Then let
                            us take heed of the warning in time, While these pleasure* and treasures are ours, Nor e'er be decoyed from the
                            pathway of right, By the sheen of a few fading flowers. Our time, health and friendship in season well prize,
                            Improving these treasures each day ; Nor let them escape till they have passed by, To sigh when they're far, far
                            away ! Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE SHAKER. Monthly —CO cents per annum. A DUAL ADVOCATE OF CHRIST PRINCIPLES.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religious test" TEIform="index"/>THE RELIGIOUS TEST</head><p TEIform="p">While many thousands beneath the influences of revival manipulators are " experiencing religion," it appears
                            proper that we, as religious commentators, should consider in what true religion consists. Ere this we have
                            expressed our joy that any and many should perceive and embrace the opportunity to lead a letter life. "We need
                            not ask what the motives were that induced this determination, nor to what particular ism individuals may have
                            given their adhesion; being satisfied that any motives which have prompted men and women to forsake the bad and
                            accept the better, are constituents of true religion. Such " change of heart " evidences a new departure in life
                            practice, and is of incomparable value, while mere theology remains a dead letter. We are confident that our
                            world is in a measure magnetically influenced and attracted by the Christ Spirit. That there are seasons in
                            human life when the polarity of individuals stands corrected by this magnetic influence. With this polarity of
                            spirituality established, the whole life comes en rapport witli angelic goodness, and the fruits of true
                            religion are apparent in their changed life. Corrected thus, the libertine, magdalen and generally immoral
                            sensualist arc confronted by their highest consciousness of right and reform. Thus the drunkard leaves his cups
                            and becomes a saviour to those in his whilom degradation ; and the devotees of all crime are, by this same
                            Christ inspiration, helped to experience that true religion which establishes a polarity in all moral rectitude.
                            We have enumerated some of the worst of classes. But the grand majority which as really needs to "experience
                            religion," and move to superior life is composed of those who congratulate themselves that they are pretty
                            good," and "not so bad as very many who are worse! " who think their present rectitude an all-sufficient apology
                            for not exerting a more discreet polarity with the heavens. No sooner do individuals arrive at a station they
                            once thought good, than true religion presents the better to their view, and they travail toward another
                            satisfactory conclusion, only to be still directed onward. The test of all true religion is nowhere written in
                            theology, but is only expressed by more active, more pure life. Too frequently all the religion people have is
                            in " joining the church." and assenting to certain formulas of theology. Doctrine is fruitless, and mere
                            persuasion that this or that theology is correct is worse than useless, unless the life test is made. The test
                            of the Christian religion is manifest in the fact that its adherents come into complete conformity or polarity
                            with the Christ life, manifested by Jesus' example — whose feminine counterpart in identical life we consider
                            was Ann Lee. Would we make the test of how religious we are, let us compare our daily lives with the same of him
                            who invited "Follow me!" This is the test Shakerism teaches its subjects to make. Unless Shakerism helps the
                            impure to become pure, and these to become exceedingly pure, it is not what is wanted by humanity. Unless it
                            urges laws that change the selfishness of human hearts into active philanthropy for "the household of faith" at
                            least, it will not stand the test. Unless it presents a superior realm of pure and peaceful life than is found
                            on the plane of the best of earthly life, it does not bear the test of true religion. While we urge our
                            brotherhood to an exceeding watchfulness to prevent self and selfishness, like unto an ancient golden calf, from
                            becoming objects of worship, and to be jealous of those heaven-born principles that inculcate, and enforce
                            self-denial to every thing that opposes Purity, Peace, Equality and Unworldly Love and Practice, we invite the
                            investigation by all, of the 'principles of Shakerism as a true religious test, and as the guide of those who
                            would live, like him whose kingdom was not of this world. </p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker institutions" TEIform="index"/>SHAKER INSTITUTIONS</head><p TEIform="p">"[From Albany Express.] Letter from Editor G. A. Lomas, on "The Shaker," Replying to W. D. Howells' Article in
                            the June Atlantic. <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">To the Editors of the Albany Morning Express: Your kindly hint, that Elder Evans or myself should
                                    reply to the excerpt made by the Express from W. D. Howells' Article in the Atlantic for June, is
                                    responsible for this response. The point, which you well knew would grate most keenly on our feelings
                                    —"the unkindest cut of all" — was the one making allusion to "the decay of numbers, which the Shakers
                                    confess with so great regret, etc." Instead of having any denial to make of this assertion, we
                                    acknowledge the point well taken. It is a truth, that can do us no possible good to deny, that we are
                                    not more than half as numerous as we have been in some times past. Nor will we dispute with any that we
                                    deeply regret the fact; nor that the decidence which has obtained has been the cause of much
                                    discomfiture to the faithful, and of deep discouragement, to which very many weak and faithless minds
                                    have succumbed. If Shakerism is dependent upon a steady increase of numbers, it was a decided failure
                                    many years ago. But its principles are just as correct to-day, with its 2,500 adherents, as when 4,000
                                    believed, or as when more or less shall embrace their practice. Being dependent upon those outside our
                                    institutions for our increase — upon those who have consciences in their souls, and sufficient stamina
                                    of both soul and body, to obey their consciences — we are numerically small, and who is to blame? As
                                    Howells says: "I cannot think of one's being a Shaker on any other terms except, of course, a sincere
                                    conviction." And he is correct. But the vast majority who have applied for admission and trial, have
                                    been those whose conviction is summed up in those seven noted principles, "live loaves, and two fishes!"
                                    The regeneration or new creation which we teach of, decidedly requires that men and women should be made
                                    right the first time — before they come to our practice. While even the most successful and best of us
                                    find that we were made none too well to adopt Shaker principles easily, more than ninety-nine in every
                                    hundred that we have labored and sweat over, were those whom we have almost thought even the Almighty
                                    would have given up in despair! Like unto a great draught of fishes, a hundred to one have been
                                    lampreys; that, unfit for use in our temple, were thrown back into the sea, " whose waters cast up mire
                                    and dirt." And we admit the outlook still dubious; for only as fast as you worldly-minded people come to
                                    be sufficiently self-denying and spiritual, will Shakerism enjoy flourishing members. And if we, as
                                    Shakers, become extinct, the barometrical hight of spirituality in the outre terre will know no
                                    significance whatever, as "the salt" will all be gone! Now, gentlemen, let it be understood that our
                                    institutions are made for our better convenience in being Christians; while we are not made for our
                                    institutions. When God questions us and others, He will not ask whether we came from this or that
                                    institution ; whether we were Shakers, Quakers, Methodists, Catholics, Mohammedans, etc, etc., but He
                                    will ask us, " What kind of lives have you lived? " and " How nearly do they accord with the best known
                                    principles of active, practical Christianity?" Our names and institutions are man-made; and if these or
                                    other appendages assist us in being better men or women, God be praised; but in religion, nothing is
                                    worthy of our special attention but the practical in Christ, regardless of sectarian terms. We close by
                                    saying that Howells' article is good, perhaps too good, as it gives a lustre that we, as a people, are
                                    not worthy of, and some of which might be dispelled by active associations; but he appears honest, "
                                    almost persuaded," and worthy of thanks from us and all interested. I am, etc., G. A. Lomas Shakers, May
                                    20.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Albany express" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit></p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/></byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Criticism on the above" TEIform="index"/>CRITICISM ON THE ABOVE</head><p TEIform="p">My Dear G. A. L. — Last night an Albany Express, containing your letter on " Shaker Village," in u Atlantic,"
                            came to hand. Many thanks for such favors. Elder John Whiteley was very much pleased with it; and I was too,
                            excepting the lack of lustre which you infer therein, and which Howells felt impressed to give us. This Society
                            is the smallest in our Israel, yet I can point to more than a dozen, who shine with more lustre, even in the
                            dark of these days, than any measure of jewels that could be procured! One branch of my life is devoted to the
                            cause, that will make the true and single-hearted, even though the least, "to shine!" Don't let us say, "
                            perhaps too good;" or think abouU a lack of lustre ; but rather of a burnishing up. If we do so with a will,
                            there will be lustre enough. Permit me, to think our honored friend, Howells, did not over-estimate the
                            brightness which rests on Shirley. And may he, when visiting Shakers, N. Y., and other societies, find you all
                            luminous — earnestly engaged in manifesting a divine humanity, free from the earthliness of lower self-hood. Let
                            us celebrate the "Centennial" by a general shining forth of purity of life, and the reign of universal peace and
                            good will — at home and abroad. Yours,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Frazer, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel, Frazer Shirley Village, May 30,18T6.</byline></div2><pb n="54" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gratitude" TEIform="index"/>GRATITUDE</head><p TEIform="p">For every blessing I receive — For every gift that comes from heaven — For every ill which I relieve, And every
                            smile that's to me given, I would give thanks. For precious love, unspoken by word — For each endearment
                            understood — For music of the soul, yet heard, And growth of a continual good, Thanks, more than thanks. And
                            while amid these silent meads, My home must be upon the sod, While my humanity has needs Which seek supplies
                            from thee, my G od — Oh, fail me not the blissful thrill — A brother's cheer, a sister's love — With these my
                            soul has measured fill; Without them there's to me no God !</p></div2><div2 type="shaker-press" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our delegate" TEIform="index"/>Our delegate
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Our Delegate. We were pleased beyond measure to read in the Voice of Peace that Elder F. W. Evans, Mt. Lebanon,
                            N. Y., had been selected delegate to, and one of the VicePresidents of the Centennial Peace Convention in
                            Philadelphia beginning July ]0. This was a most fitting selection. We congratulate all who will be fortunate
                            enough to hear what " the Spirit" shall impress him to utter in behalf of Peace and against the barbarisms of
                            any people barbaric enough to learn and practice war.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vindication of shaker social beauties" TEIform="index"/>VINDICATION OF SHAKER SOCIAL BEAUTIES</head><p TEIform="p">[The following extracts are taken from a private letter, written by Eunice Bathrick, of Harvard, Mass., to the
                            writer of the article entitled: " Social Beauties of Christian Communism " in May No. of The Shaker. Coming from
                            one advanced in years, and a thorough Shaker, the remarks have especial value. Ed.] " I often feel while reading
                            The Shaker (which I do with much pleasure), that there is something needed to give more sunshine to Shaker life—
                            to portray in brighter and more glowing colors the beauty of the gains of full consecration. You say : ' Living
                            in the spirit of our gospel testimony, we necessarily renounce many practices which bring pleasure to the
                            worldly mind, and embrace those elements which produce the joys of heaven in our present, social lives, etc' "
                            Now, do not all, who make a. full consecration of ' soul, body and spirit,'— who have, or are daily divesting
                            themselves of every discordant element, enjoy heaven here ? Have not such, a living spring within — a fountain
                            constantly gushing forth sweet waters to supply thirsty and famishing souls ? '•'If so, let us publish it to the
                            world —let them know that we are " happy and free " — that we have not to wait till we cross the dividing line
                            to taste the joys of a heavenly existence. Let them know that we have formed, or are forming, a heaven within. "
                            To present the idea to those not of our body,that'all present comforts and enjoyments are to be sacrificed, in
                            pursuit of future happiness, must look gloomy and uninviting to them. But once picture to their imaginations the
                            real joy that is to be derived from a life of full consecration to God in this state of existence, with the
                            assurance of never-ending felicity in the future, and they will not be so reluctant to make the required
                            sacrifice ; they will see they have only to make an exchange of perishable pleasures for the more exalted and
                            durable. " While sowing the good seed, let the soil be warmed by love from consecrated hearts — from resurrected
                            souls, illumined by the millennial sun, whose rays will cause the seed to germinate, spring up, bud, blossom,
                            and bear fruits acceptable to God. Lov« is all conquering ; it gives light and life to benighted pilgrims, and
                            by its magnetic power, attracts them to a more elevated state of existence, where they can daily be rising into
                            a pure, ethereal atmosphere. This is what is needed to-day— a greater degree of the Christ-love, to warm into
                            action souls now sleeping in sin, who heed not their condition. Without this divine element all else will fail
                            to draw, and hold individuals in the courts of Zion. It has been my aim from early life, to make the way
                            pleasant, not only to my young companions, but to all with whom I converse ; for, having tasted the sweets of a
                            virgin life, I am anxious to have others enjoy the same ; atid as I advance in this soul-refining work this
                            desire increases. I have no doubts of the success of our Cause in the end ; for I see God working through His
                            agents, preparing souls for the millennial harvest. May we all stand ready for whatever work the Father has for
                            us, when his time arrives. I think, as you have ob served, that any useful knowledge which Believers have
                            attained, either in the domestic concerns of life, or otherwise, should be noticed in our paper, as many may be
                            benefited thereby. Any improvement is worthy of circulation. " Your sister in true progression,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bathrick, Eunice" TEIform="persName"/>Eunice Bathrick</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker village" TEIform="index"/>A SHAKER VILLAGE</head><byline TEIform="byline">[The following extracts are from the pen of<persName reg="Howells, W. D" TEIform="persName"/>W. D. Howells, and have particular
                            reference to Shirley village, Mass. We have endeavored to make them more generally interesting by excluding such
                            matter as does not apply to every " Shaker Village " in our land ; at the same time we congratulate Shirley on
                            its success in captivating such an illustrious chronicler. Ed.]</byline><p TEIform="p">(R'om the Atlantic Monthly.) It was our fortune to spend six weeks of last summer in the neighborhood of a
                            community of the people called Shakers — who are chiefly known to the world outside by their apple-sauce, by
                            their garden seeds so punctual in coming up when planted, by their brooms so well made that they sweep clean
                            long after the ordinary new broom of proverb has retired upon its reputation, by the quaintness of their dress,
                            and by the fame of their religious dances. It is well to have one's name such a synonym for honesty that any
                            thing called by it may be bought and sold with perfect confidence, and it is surely no harm to be noted for
                            dressing out of the present fashion, or for dancing before the Lord. But when our summer had come to an end, and
                            we had learned to know the Shakers for so many other qualities, we grew almost to resent their superficial
                            renown among men. We saw in them a sect simple, sincere, and fervently persuaded of the truth of their doctrine
                            striving for the realization of a heavenly ideal upon earth ; and amidst the hard and often sordid commonplace
                            of our ordinary country life, their practice of the austerities to which men and women have devoted themselves
                            in storied times and picturesque lands clothed these Yankee Shakers in something of the pathetic interest which
                            always clings to our thoughts of monks and nuns. Their doctrine has been so often explained that I need not
                            dwell upon it here, but the more curious reader may turn to the volumes of the Atlantic Monthly of 1867 for an
                            authoritative statement of all its points in the autobiography of Elder Evans of Mt. Lebanon. Mainly, their
                            faith is their life ; a life of charity, of labor, of celibacy, which they call the angelic life. Theologically,
                            it can be most succinctly presented in their formula, Christ Jesus and Christ Ann, their belief being that the
                            order of special prophecy was completed by the inspiration of Mother Ann Lee, the wife of the English
                            blacksmith, Stanley. She is their second Christ; their divine mother, whom some of their hymns invoke, and for
                            whom they cherish a filial love. The families of Shirley and Harvard, Massachusetts, were formed in her time,
                            near the close of the last century; at the latter place they show the room in which she lived, and whence she
                            was once dragged by the foolish mob which helps to found every new religion. In regard to other points their
                            minds vary. Generally they do not believe in the miraculous birth or divinity of Christ; he was a divinely good
                            and perfect man, and any of us may become divine by being godlike. Generally, also, I should say that they
                            reject the Puritanic ideas of future rewards and punishments, and accept something like the Swedenborgian notion
                            of the life hereafter. They are all spiritualists, recognizing a succession of inspirations from the earliest
                            times down to our own, when they claim to have been the first spiritual mediums. Five or six years before the
                            spirits who have since animated so many tablelegs, planchettes, phantom shapes, and what not began to knock at
                            Rochester, the Shaker families in New York, Massachusetts, Ohio, and elsewhere were in full communion with the
                            other world, and they were warned of the impending invasion of the world's parlor and dining-room sets. They
                            feel by no means honored, however, by all the results. But they believe that the intercourse between the worlds
                            can be rescued from the evil influences which have perverted it, and they have signs, they say, of an early
                            renewal of the manifestations among themselves. In some ways these have in fact never ceased. Many of the Shaker
                            hymns, words and music, are directly inspirational, coming to this brother or that sister without regard to his
                            or her special genius; they are sung and written down, and are then brought into general use. The poetry is like
                            that which the other world usually furnishes through its agents in this, hardly up to our literary standard; but
                            the music has always something strangely wild, sweet and naive. The Shakers claim to be the purest and most
                            Christian church, proceeding in a straight succession from the church which Christ's life of charity and
                            celibacy established on earth; whereas, all the other churches are sprung from the first Gentile churches, to
                            whose weakness and willfulness certain regrettable things, as slavery, war, private property, and marriage, were
                            permitted. Acknowledging a measure of inspiration in all religions, they also recognize a kindred attraction to
                            the angelic life in the celibate orders of every faith : the Boman vestals, the Peruvian virgins of the sun, and
                            the Buddhist bonzes, as well as the monks and nuns of the Catholic church. They complain that they have not been
                            understood by such alien writers as" have treated of them, and have represented them as chiefly useful in
                            furnishing homes for helpless and destitute people of all ages and sexes. In the words of Elder Frazer, of
                            Shirley, the Shakers claim that their system is " based on the fact that each man has in himself a higher and a
                            lower life," and that Shakerism "is a manifestation of the higher to the exclusion of the lower life. Its object
                            is to gather into one fold all who have risen above their natural propensities," and they think with Paul that
                            though those who marry do well, yet tbJOse who do not marry do better. Their preaching and teaching is largely
                            to this effect; and yet I do not find it quite strange that friends from the world outside regard rather the
                            spectacle of the Shakers' peaceful life, and think mostly of their quiet homes as refuges for those disabled
                            against fate, the poor, the bruised, the hopeless; after all, Christ himself is but this. As I recall their
                            plain, quaint village at Shirley, a sense of its exceeding peace fills me; I see its long, straight street, with
                            the severely simple edifices on either hand ; the gardens up-hill on one side and down-hill on the other; its
                            fragrant orchards and its levels of clovery meadow-land stretching away to buckwheat fields, at the borders of
                            whose milky bloom the bee paused, puzzled which sweet to choose; and it seems to me that one whom the world
                            could flatter no more, one broken <pb n="55" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> in hope, or health, or fortune, could not do better than
                            come hither and meekly ask to be taken into that quiet fold, and kept forever from his sorrows and himself. But
                            —such is the hardness of the natural heart —I cannot think of one's being a Shaker on any other terms, except,
                            of course, a sincere conviction. * * * * * * * * * * We stopped at the office of the Church Family, which is a
                            large brick house, scrupulously plain, like all the rest, and appointed for the transaction of business and the
                            entertainment of visitors. Here three sisters and one brother are in charge, and here are chambers for visitors
                            staying overnight. The Shakers do not keep a public house, and are far from inviting custom, but their theory of
                            Christianity forbids them to turn away one unhoused or unfed from their doors ; the rich pay a moderate charge,
                            and the poor nothing — as that large and flourishing order of fellow-citizens, the tramps, very well know. These
                            overripe fruits of our labor system lurk about in the woods and byways, and turn up at the Shakers' doors after
                            dark, where they are secure of being fed and sheltered in the little dormitory set apart for them. "And some of
                            them," said Elder Frazer, "really look as if the pit had vomited them up." ******* * * * One has somehow the
                            impression that the young people of the Shakers are held in compulsory allegiance, but of course this is not at
                            all the fact. As soon as they are old enough to take care of themselves they are entirely free to go or to stay.
                            Undoubtedly they are constantly taught the advantages of the community over the world, and the superior merit of
                            the virgin life over the married state, which they may be inclined to think of as they grow to be men and women.
                            Marriage is not held to be sinful or dishonorable. "Few things," said one of the elders, "are more pleasing to
                            us than the sight of a happy young couple living rightly in their order," but marriage is earthly and human, and
                            celibacy is divine; as the thoughts are t.urned to higher things, they forsake husband or wife. Nevertheless, if
                            their young women will marry, the Shakers claim the satisfaction of thinking that they have received in the
                            community the best possible training for wives and mothers — that they have been taught diligence, economy, and
                            all branches of domestic knowledge. More than once there have been secessions of young people, which are nearly
                            always stealthy, not because there could be any constraint, but because they hated to face the disappointed
                            hopes of their elders. In after years, these delinquents from the angelic condition sometimes return to thank
                            their benefactors, and to declare that they owe most of their worldly prosperity to their unworldly precepts.
                            The proportion of those reared in Shakerism whom the Shakers expect to keep is small; they can count quite as
                            much for their increase upon accessions of mature men and women from outside, whom the Shaker life and doctrine
                            persuade. These they invite now, as always, very cordially to join them, and they look forward to a time when
                            their dwindling communities shall be restored to more than their old numbers. One bad effect of the present
                            decrease, which all thoughtful Shakers deplore, is the employment of hired labor. This, as communists, they feel
                            to be wrong; but they are loath either to alienate their land or to let it lie idle. A strange and sad state of
                            things results: the most profitable crop that they can now raise is timber, which they harvest once in thirty
                            years, and which it cost nothing to cultivate, whereas it costs more to plant and reap the ordinary farm crops,
                            at the present rate of farm labor, than the crops will sell for. ******* * * * The decay of numbers, then, which
                            the Shakers confess with so great regret, is but their share of the common blight, and how to arrest it is their
                            share of the common perplexity. I could not encourage Elder Frazer to indulge great hopes, when one day in a
                            burst of zeal for Shakerism he said, " We want cultivated people — half the subscribers of the Atlantic Monthly
                            —to come and fill up our vacant ranks." * ******* * * * We often touched upon this subject of the [?Note —This
                            paragraph has had a very extensive circulation by the press of the United States and Canadas, and it is pleasant
                            to observe that our letter concerning it, printed on another page, has been as extensively copied.—Ed. Shaker.]
                            decay of Shakerism, which they face bravely, and not unhopefully, and yet with a care concerning it that was not
                            less than touching. What could it matter to those childless men and women whether any like them should inherit
                            them in this world, to which, while living, they had turned so cold a shoulder? Very little indeed, one would
                            have said, and yet they were clearly anxious that Shakerism should flourish after them. Their anxiety was not so
                            unnatural; none of us can bear to think of leaving the fruits of our long endeavor to chance and the stranger.
                            But I may attribute the largest share of the Shaker reluctance to perish from the earth to zeal for the
                            perpetuation of the true faith—faith which was founded, like all others, in persecution, built up amidst
                            ridicule and obloquy, and now, when its practical expression is received with respect by all the neighboring
                            world, is in some danger of ceasing among men, not through the indifference of believers, but through their
                            inevitable mortal decay. There are several reasons for the present decrease, besides that decrease of the whole
                            rural population which I have mentioned. **** * * **** Whatever it was, it was a time when men's minds turned
                            fervidly from tne hard work-days of this world to the Sabbaths of another; from the winter, the wilderness, the
                            privation of New England, to the eternal summer and glory and fruition of the New Jerusalem. How to get there
                            was their care ; it was for this that wives and husbands rent themselves asunder, and shared their children with
                            strangers ; it was for this that the lover left his love, and the young girl forbade her heart's yearning; we
                            may be sure that it was zeal for heaven, for the imagined service of God, that built up the Shaker communities.
                            Their peculiar dress remembers the now quaint days of their origin ; it is not a costume invented or assumed by
                            them; it is the American dress of a hundred years ago, as our rustic great-grandparents wore it, with such
                            changes as convenience, not fashion, has suggested to the Shakers since. With all its quaintness it has a charm
                            which equally appears whether it is worn by old or by young. To the old, the modest soberness of the colors, the
                            white kerchief crossed upon the breast, the clean stiff cap, were singularly becoming ; and the young had in
                            their simple white Sunday dresses a look of maidenly purity which is after all the finest ornament. The colors
                            we noticed at meeting were for the young mostly white, for the middle-aged and elderly the subdued tints of
                            drab, bronzed, and lead-color, which also prevailed with the men of all ages. Both sexes wear collars that cover
                            the whole neck, and both eschew the vanity of neck-ties ; some of the brothers suffered themselves the gaiety of
                            showing at the ends of their trousers-legs the brighter selvage of the cloth; if indeed this was a gaiety, and
                            not, as one clothed in the world's taste might have accounted it, an added mortification of the spirit. The
                            Shakers used to spin and weave all the stuff they wore, but to do this now would be a waste of time ; they buy
                            the alpaca and linen which both sexes wear in summer, and their substantial woolens for the winter. Some relics
                            of their former skill and taste remain in the handsome counterpanes in their guest-chambers at the office, which
                            were dyed, spun, and woven in the family, and the sisters are still skilled in braiding palmleaf hats and in the
                            old-fashioned art of hooking rugs. But I would not persuade the reader that any Shaker family is otherwise a
                            school of art; one painting I did indeed see, a vigorous sketch in oil of a Durham bull, but this was nailed to
                            the side of a stall far up in the vast gray barn. It was the work of a boy who was in the family years ago; but
                            he never became a Shaker. It would be interesting to know what he did become. In a community it must be that the
                            individual genius is largely sacrificed to the common purpose and tendency, and yet I believe that among the
                            Shakers the sacrifice is compelled only by the private conscience. So it is with regard to every thing. On
                            joining the community the new member gives up nothing, and is cautioned against a too early surrender of his
                            property. He wears, so long as he likes, the fashions of the world, but these make him look as odd in the family
                            as the Shaker dress would outside of it, and he is commonly anxious to assume the garb of simplicity before his
                            mundane clothing is worn out. After due time he may give his property to the family ; if he ever leaves it, he
                            receives back the principal of his contribution without interest; for his labor he has already received his
                            support. There are no formalities observed when a new brother or sister comes among the Shakers. It is
                            understood that they are to go as freely as they have come; and this provision is recalled, as a rule that works
                            both ways, to the mind of any brother whose room is finally found to be better than his company. But this very
                            rarely happens; in twenty-five years Minister Whiteley had been obliged to dismiss only one undesirable brother.
                            The whole polity of the family is very simple. Its affairs are conducted by trustees, who hold the property and
                            handle the funds, and to whom any member goes for money to purchase things not provided for the common use.
                            Reasonable requests of this sort are readily allowed; but it is easy to understand how the indulgence of even
                            very simple private tastes adds to the cost of common living, already enhanced by the decrease of members, and
                            the necessity of keeping in repair the buildings left only partially occupied. **** * * **** At the head of each
                            family there is an elder and an eldress, to whom all complaints are first addressed, and by whom difficulties
                            are settled. I believe there is also a species of confessional, in which those who desire can confide their
                            repentance and good intentions to the elders. Disputes in which the decision of the elders is not satisfactory
                            are appealed to the ministers, whose mind is final in such matters. **** * * **** Of course, nothing like
                            ceremony must be inferred concerning the expression of this regard. They, and all the other brothers aud
                            sisters, are addressed by their first names, and it is liked that strangers in addressing the Shakers should be
                            simple and direct, eschewing the forms and titles which could not be accorded in return. **** * * **** They are
                            plain and homely in their phrase, but they are very courteous, and it is impossible to know them and not
                            perceive how little politeness consists in the tedious palaver that commonly passes by that name. Their
                            sincerity gives them dignity and repose ; it appears that you have but to renounce the world, and you cannot be
                            afraid of it. I should be sorry to give the notion of a gloomy asceticism in the Shaker life. I saw nothing of
                            this, though I saw self-restraint, discipline, quiet, and heard sober, considered, conscientious speech. They
                            had their jesting, also ; and those brothers and sisters who were of a humorous mind seemed all the better liked
                            for their gift of laughing and making laugh. The sum of Shaker asceticism is this : they neither marry nor give
                            in marriage; but this is a good deal. Certain things they would think indecorous rather than wicked, and I do
                            not suppose a Shaker would go twice to the opera bouffe; but such an entertainment as a lecture by our
                            right-hearted humorist, Mark Twain, had been attended by one of the brethren not only without self-reproach, but
                            with great enjoyment. They had also some of them read Mr. Bret Harte's books without apparent fear of the
                            consequences. They are rather strict in the observance of the Sabbath, but not so much, I thought, from
                            conscience as from custom. Our Shaker friends are sometimes embarrassed by visitors who ask to be shown all over
                            their buildings, forgetting that their houses are private houses; and I cannot promise the curious reader
                            visiting Shirley a repetition of the favors done us, whom the Shakers were good enough to show all of their
                            communal life that one could see. In each village is an edifi e known as the Dwelling-House, which is separate
                            from the office and other buildings. In this are the rooms of the brothers and sisters, the kitchen and
                            dining-room, and a large room for family meetings. The first impression of all is cleanliness, with a suggestion
                            of bareness which is not inconsistent, however, with comfort, and which comes chiefly from the aspect of the
                            unpapered walls, the scrubbed floors hidden only by rugs and strips of carpeting, and the plain flat finish of
                            the wood-work. Each chamber accommodates two brothers or two sisters, and is appointed with two beds, two
                            rocking-chairs, two wash-stands and a wood-stove, with abundance of THE BHA.KER. 55 <pb n="56" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> rugs.
                            The rooms of the younger people are above so that (as was explained to us) if the young sisters, especially,
                            wish to talk after they go to bed they need not disturb their elders. There were few tokens of personal taste in
                            the arrangement of the rooms; the most decided expression of character was that of the nonagenarian who required
                            his bed to be made up with a hollow in the middle from top to bottom, which he called his trough, and which he
                            strictly forbade any one to meddle with ; that was all he asked of earth after ninety-six years, not to disturb
                            his trough. It seemed right that the simple demand should be indulged The dining-room was provided with two
                            large tables, at one of which the brothers sat, and at the other the sisters. The monastic rule of silence at
                            meals is observed because, as we were told, the confusion would be too great if all talked together. In the
                            kitchen was an immense cook-stove, with every housekeeping convenience ; and everywhere opened pantry and
                            store-room doors, with capacious cellars underneath— all scoured and scrubbed to the last degree of neatness.
                            The family menage is completed by a wash-house and a dairy-house; there is an infirmary, and a shop for women's
                            work, and under the same roof with the latter, at Shirley, a large school-room, in which the children of the
                            community are taught the usual English branches by a sister. The Shaker village forms a school district, and
                            their school is under the control of the town committee. One day, toward tne end of our sojourn, the
                            office-sisters asked us to spend an afternoon and take tea with them. After tea we sat down in the
                            office-parlor, and the best singers of the family came in with their music books, and sang those tunes which we
                            had severally liked most. It was all done with the friendliest simplicity, and we could not but be charmed.</p></div2><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spirit voices" TEIform="index"/>SPIRIT VOICES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="White, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>ANNA WHITE</byline><p TEIform="p">Mount Lebanon, North Family, 1876. Voices sweet as angel whispers, Come to us from yonder clime, Gentle as the
                            evening zephyrs, Is their song of love divine. Living souls with hope resplendent, And a spirit formed anew,
                            Catch the joyous notes triumphant, Swell the chorus rich and true. Tarry with us blest immortals, We will learn
                            the heavenly song, Press toward the shining portals, Whence the melody was borne. These have left the world
                            forever, Turned from darkness unto light, Thus renouncing every error, That the spirit's growth would blight. Ye
                            who still are waiting —watching, For the bright and morning star, See, the dawn is fast approaching, And the
                            gates are left ajar. And the Bridegroom now appeareth, With his Bride in raiment white, Hear ye what the Spirit
                            sayeth, Come receive the truth, the light. Not in measured form ' tis given, Nor in dogmas of the past, Word of
                            life flows down l'rom heaven, Void of priestly cant or caste. ' Tis the " Rock of Revelation," ' Tis the gift of
                            God to man, Showing all whence comes salvation, The established, gospel plan.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reading sealed letters" TEIform="index"/>READING SEALED LETTERS</head><p TEIform="p">There is so much of humbug connected with modern spiritualism, that we cannot censure any for being wary
                            concerning it. But what can we think of the following ? When Elder Evans and company were in New York, holding a
                            series of meetings, they called, by invitation, upon Dr. J. V. Mansfield, 361 Sixth avenue, New York. The
                            various tests made by them, and as narrated to us by Eldress A. Doolittle, were simply, yet pleasantly
                            astounding. We wrote the doctor that we wanted to make an honorable, but very severe, test. The challenge was
                            invitingly accepted. A noble friend of ours wrote the letter (or we supposed he did) upon paper glazed with blue
                            on the outer side. Especial pains were taken in folding up every line, sealing the same, before writing another
                            line, and fastening the ends with the utmost care and glue. I took the letter, sealed it in a double envelope,
                            making every necessaiy private mark to prevent exposure possible without my knowledge, and sent it. To my own
                            and friend's surprise, the sealed letter was returned undisturbed, with an answer for his wife, who, unknown to
                            me, had addresxed her spirit mother! The answer made references to matters known only to my friend's private
                            family. If Elder H. L. Eades will logically explain how this is done, we will next ask him to satisfy us by
                            elucidating the materializations mentioned in the first fourteen verses of Ezekiel, chapter 37.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>BOOK NOTICES</head><div3 type="book notices" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Relations of the sexes" TEIform="index"/></head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Duffy, E. B." TEIform="persName"/>Mrs. E. B. Duffy</byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="North Star and the Southern Cross" TEIform="index"/></head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Weppner, M." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">Relations of the Sexes : By Mrs. E. B. Duffy. Wood &amp; Holbrook, N. Y. This is a bold movement in the
                                right direction, by a brave, high principled woman. She writes plainly upon the theme she has chosen. She
                                will thereby awaken the progenitors of the race to see their duty to themselves and to those whom they would
                                give and have given existence. She visits thunderbolts on the heads of those engaged in sexual abuses, and
                                upon the various apologies rendered therefor; and if warning was sufficient to make the change that nature
                                demands, we might feel better. But, like nearly all writers upon this subject, the authoress grows weak,
                                even to supineness, when attempting substitutes for and preventives of marital distresses. We boldly and
                                forcibly urge the laws of Moses on all generative men and women, as their only hope. While to those good
                                enough to compare well in their generations with the beasts of the field, we recommend the superior life,
                                and angelic career of Jesus — the Christ — if they would be Christians. The North Star and the Southern
                                Cross : By M. Weppner. Weed, Parsons &amp; Co., Albany, N. Y. This is the journey of a woman round the
                                world, and is written with an ability that has made two very interesting volumes. She writes as only a woman
                                can upon subjects, persons and customs of nations, which would be lost sight of by manly travelers ; and
                                thus the work will please the feminine idea of what a journey round the world should treat of. As the guest
                                of very distinguished persons in other lands than ours, she is made much of, and tells her stories of
                                individuals who used her handsomely or abused her inhospitably, with a keen kindness and rich deserving.
                                Compared with the volumes of Seward, Peebles and others, it stands good. We speak for it a ready and
                                extensive sale.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>TO HAPPIER, EVERGREEN SHORES</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Horton, Gurdon" TEIform="index"/>Gurdon Horton
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Shakers, N. Y., May 18, 1876. <persName reg="Horton, Gurdon" TEIform="persName">Gurdon Horton</persName>, aged 86.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Soule, Melissa" TEIform="index"/>Melissa Soule
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., May 19, 1870, <persName reg="Soule, Melissa" TEIform="persName">Melissa Soule</persName>, aged 31.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wilson, Margaretta" TEIform="index"/>Margaretta Wilson
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Canaan, N. Y., June 13, 1876, <persName reg="Wilson, Margaretta" TEIform="persName">Margaretta Wilson</persName>, aged
                            83.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Apologetic" TEIform="index"/>APOLOGETIC</head><p TEIform="p">The copious extracts which we have transferred from the columns of the Atlantic Monthly to this number of The
                            Shaker, will prove very interesting to all having any sympathy with, or curiosity about us as a people. Although
                            so lengthy, and necessarily crowding out several very excellent articles from good Bros. Peebles, Russell,
                            Fraser, Leggett, and some from equally good sisters, yet we belie,ve we shall be thanked for the space used,
                            while we promise the "excellent articles" in our next. For the same reason we offer apology for the absence of
                            our "Spirit of the Farm." and "Useful Receipts " departments. Our farm notes, we learn from many letters, are
                            appreciated; and we return many thanks for the congratulations tendered us, in that our " Shaker is filled with
                            choice variety, and very interesting." "I have read every word of June number," writes a Sonyea friend, "and
                            consider it the best." Another from Worcester, Mass., says: "Although I take a multitude of papers, TnK Shaker
                            is the only one that I read from beginning to end." We tally one for every such conclusion. Thank you, friends,
                            one and all.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="L., G. A." TEIform="persName"/>G. A. L.</byline></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>