<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1106" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">11</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">6</biblScope><date value="18810601" TEIform="date">June1881</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">121- 144</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="11" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="6" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                    <pb id="p1"/>
                    <p>MANIFESTO. G. A. LOMAS, EDITOR, SHAKERS, H. Y. Published by the United Societies. OUR HOME AT SHAKERS. N. Y. And they
                        shall turn to you for a testimony: " ''Go preach the Kingdom of God!" ADDRESS ALL COMMUNICATIONS TO "The Shaker
                        Manifesto, Shakers, N.D." G. B. AVERY, PUBLISHER. 1881. Vol. XI. ) No. 6. i JUNE, 1881. 60 Cents Per Annum. The
                        Shaker</p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                        <pb id="p3"/>
                        <pb id="p4"/>
                    </div2>
                    --><pb n="121" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Solar system" TEIform="index"/>THE SOLAR SYSTEM</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>MARTHA J. ANDERSON</byline><p TEIform="p">Imperial day, in regal majesty Now gathers up his gold and purple robes, And westward rolls
                            his chariot of light. Grey mists retreat to caverns dark and deep, And twilight shadows,
                            softly stealing o'er, Wrap all creation in a calm repose; While nature, with her myriad
                            voices hushed, In silent awe awaits the opening role That heralds night's resplendent
                            scenery — Pair Venus, peerless 'mid the nightly train That tread their round through sombre
                            ether space In such sublime and awful majesty,— Comes forth in queenly beauty all arrayed;
                            And shining orbs, each to their place assigned, In blazoned grandeur span the ebon arch.
                            Star of all stars, among the countless throng That meets the raptured gaze of mortal eye,
                            For thy transcendent light outshines them all. When the moon wanes and shows its side
                            opaque, Thy beams, throughout the crystal air infused, A weird reflection cast upon the
                            wall, And in the trembling shafts of silvery light, Fantastic shadows dance in revelry, And
                            spectral shapes the silent chamber fill. A world! oh! who shall scan thee wondrous ball
                            Suspended in illimitable space? Thy brilliancy the eyes-of science blinds, And with
                            uncertainty doth man record The measurement of thy circumference. They claim thee as the
                            Sun's fair satelite, With Mercury attending on his course. Earth pales, and Mars' bright
                            lurid glare grow^ dim Eclipsed by the refulgence of thy beams. Great Jupiter, enthroned as
                            king of heaven, With watchful eye and steady light, looks down From depths immeasurable and
                            vast; Too distant, to reveal his wondrous size. And Saturn, luminous with circling rings,
                            Moves with his satelites in realms remote, The great chronologer of passing time, Uranus,
                            mildly beams far, far away ; And Neptune, unperceived by naked eye, Ensphered in light as
                            brilliant as our own, Like sentinel, takes up his march around The boundary line of Sol's
                            great family. Ah! who shall reach infinity? or ere descry By aid of science, keen research,
                            or sight, The wonders of that galaxy of worlds, Whose central orbs, like globes of living
                            tire Illume and vivify their forms opaque? No wonder that the magi of the east In the grey
                            morning of a new-born world, Went up to hill-tops of the Orient, And paid their homage, to
                            the grandest works Displayed in God's created Universe. They knew Him not, yet gazed with
                            thought serene, And sought the secret cause, of all that lived And moved, in such exalted
                            harmony. In lands of cloudless skies and climate warm, The ancient shepherds, on the
                            outstretched plains — While guarding well their chosen flocks by night— <pb n="122" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 122 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. Observed the movements of revolving spheres, And marked from
                            age to age the changing scenes Occurring in the stellar dome on high. Chaldea and Egypt, in
                            their palmy days, And other oriental lands of lore, Mapped out their systems of astronomy,
                            And gave the world the ke\, that has unlocked The occult mysteries of the heavenly vault.
                            And yet, with what perspective art and skill, Man still pursues the study of those laws That
                            operate beyond his finite sight, And hold in poise the constellated spheres ; Whose harmony,
                            like sweet concordant chimes. The great Pythagoras was wont to hear. In ages dark, when
                            priestcraft ruled the earth, The sons of science, doomed beneath their scourge, Dared not
                            promulgate what they know was right; Or, like the brave Galileo, they shared With criminals
                            the dungeon's noisome cell: Yet blessed be their memory, it lives In the resplendent glory
                            of that, truth, Which triumphs over ignorance and pride. The age of reason, dawning o'er the
                            earth, Gives to the minds of men expanse and growth, And elevates the moral sentiment Above
                            the superstitious and the vague, To comprehend diviner attributes ; E'en the Creative Power
                            that fashions worlds And moulds the destiny of human souls.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Soul travel" TEIform="index"/>SOUL TRAVEL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>GILES B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p"> Earth's travelers often intensely interest her inhabitants by wordy pictures of their
                            journeys, the interesting sights they have seen, the curious incidents they have met with ;
                            the laws, customs and manners of different peoples and nations they have witnessed, the
                            wonders of nature and art that have riveted their memories like a spellbound reader, and the
                            different phases of culture, progress and refinement of different peoples. In the
                            understanding and belief of all enlightened peoples, there is a spiritual,— a soul world, as
                            really as a material and it is not alone for those who have "shuffled off the mortal coil,"
                            but those yet residents of time. Of this the travelers therein have reports to make, vastly
                            more important and enchanting than those merely pertaining to the material; they are seeking
                            an audience. Who will listen to their reports ? But where are the historians of soul
                            travelers ? Is there not here a very important link in the chain of human development that
                            needs forging, smoothing and burnishing ? Are there not many links, a chain embettering
                            intelligent life ? Is there not a voluminous and intensely interesting history waiting for
                            the pen of some recording angel to illustrate ? Are we all, as tenants of time, so engrossed
                            with earth's cares, burdens, sorrows and joys that we have no record to portray of the
                            travels of the soul ? After the worrying and harrassing experience of earthly trials and
                            disappointment, or while suffering the effect of the contents of Pandora's box, when, as the
                            hypochondriac would express it,a person "feels the blues," is there no soul record which
                            might be written for the encouragement of fortitude, patience, and calm endurance, or, if
                            need be, energetic struggle, so to guide the life of the forth coming traveler as to shun
                            the like Maelstrom of difficulties ? Or, in the experience of joys so transporting, full of
                            strength and encouragement of spirit as to enable an intelligent human being to sail
                            securely and calmly over all the rough billows of time, is there no reporter, as a heavenly
                            pilot, to tell the approaching sailor how to guide his bark, that he too may be fortified
                            for the trials to be met on the voyage ? We behold around us multitudes of soul pilgrims on
                            their journey through time, destined to some goal, some haven of joy or sorrow, some prison
                            of infamy or some fane of glory, and we anxiously inqure, are there not some means by which
                            each one and all may not only see the temple of honor and the crown of bliss, but be drawn'm
                            the only true direction to it ? Can ye not picture to us, O souls who have sailed on before,
                            and anchored in the ocean of redemption and bliss, the methods you employed to vanquish your
                            adversaries in conflicts with the blandishments of sore temptations and the allurements of
                            sin ? To perceive soul travel in its magnitude, we must retrace human history ; for her <pb n="123" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 123 physical/moral and social, as well as
                            spiritual status has been graded, all along from man's cradle history, up through the untold
                            myriad ages, by the development of progressive degrees of soul enlightenment and
                            enlargement. In the earlier and earliest ages of human existence, the motive power of man's
                            life was, apparently, simply brute force, the strongest, animally speaking, bearing rule ;
                            thus, the male of human kind ruled, for untold ages, over the female, making her his slave,
                            his tool for pleasure ; a condition manifest, even at the present day, by those nations
                            where there has been little development of soul progress. Thus was developed and chosen the
                            Chiefs of savage tribes, and thus ensued the dominance of nations for time unmeasured; the
                            most physically powerful and numerous assuming an autocracy of rule ; the weaker peoples, in
                            unnumbered millions, were enslaved by their physical peers, and made to serve them in any
                            manner which most ministered to their animal pleasures, pride and creature comforts, and
                            apparently without the least thought or concern of the sufferings of the enslaved and
                            toiling myriads they had conquered. The imperishable historical testimony of this soulless
                            state of human society is recorded in the Pyramids and Obelisks of Egypt, the Catacomb
                            cities of the dead, hewn in the imperishable rocks ; the Sarcophagi containing embalmed
                            mummies of rulers and taskmasters wrapped in beaten gold. Human animals fought hand to hand
                            for mastery, as right still the lower orders of creation, Man's servile life in these ages
                            was untold misery without spiritual or social relief. As man became more soul-progressed,
                            fewer have been the wars for conquest, but more forcible the engines of destruction ; thus
                            inciting dread of engagement in strife, and, coupled with this, attention to the sufferings
                            of the wounded, thus manifesting human sympathy — a trace of soul development, an elementary
                            demonstration of soul travel. On, and still onward, is the march of progress, until kingdoms
                            unite to sustain each other by combined counsels ; wars are less frequent, engines of
                            destruction more dreadful, until some of them are so horrible, so Satanic in design and
                            accomplishments for the destruction of life, that they are condemned, even by warriors, as
                            hellish instruments of warfare; another evidence of soul progress, — sympathy for
                            fellow-beings ; an element entirely lacking in the earlier ages, when whole hecatombs of
                            human beings were sacrificed in the gladiatorial sports and feasts of conquering nations, to
                            please the spectators, and the greater the anguish portrayed by the lacerated human
                            sacrifices, the greater joy to the crowd of spectators. No soul manifest here ! Yet forward
                            rolls the wheel of progress, and the travel of soul manifest in earthly conditions, until
                            national grievances are beginning to be settled, among some, once barbaric nations of the
                            earth, by arbitration, and the growth of soul is pleading for the disbanding of standing
                            armies; thus the growth and progress of soul approximating the dawn of that glorious day of
                            soul domi nation predicted by the prophet of the Lord, when nations should " beat their
                            swords into plow shares, and their spears into pruning hooks, and learn war no more." Prom
                            the historical, infantile,social status of human life, all along up through the unnumbered
                            ages, come the evidences of soul travel, plodding its weary way in the socalled religious
                            history of our race. Beginning with primitive humanity we find a degree of apparent innate
                            perception of God : man recognizes some powers superior to himself and worships its products
                            as God. At first, a fetich, his god is some stupenduous material object, as a huge rock, a
                            vast mountain, a noble river, the mighty ocean ; soul, here begins to work, but her aliment
                            is material; next, the spiritual impulse prompts the manufacture of images of animal life to
                            worship, rtie only way the soul can, as yet, give its life expression ; it is an incipient
                            perception and acknowledgment of God in His creation; it is one more step of soul progress.
                            Next comes the worship of the sources of light, and life sustainers, the Sun, Moon and
                            Stars, because man finds them his benefactors, and his innate gratitude begins to germinate
                            and crop out; the soul is climbing, but in material robes. <pb n="124" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 124 THE
                            SHAKER'MANIFESTO. Occult forces hence begin to manifest their power to a portion of the
                            race, and man's spiritual forces institute ideal gods in monstrous forms embracing a
                            combination of the forms of both man, beast and birds, and panoplied with creative powers,
                            as objects of worship ; in this is portrayed Egyptian soul evolution, a glimmering
                            perception of the spiritual ; but we do not tarry here. Next we have the souls incipient
                            perception of a spirit God, and abstract identity, unknown to the unprogressed, material man
                            ; His oracle, Moses, reveals Him as the Unknown, simply " / Am " seeing his backsides only,
                            his face he cannot see and live, for he is yet approaching him only from the rear. But, in
                            this phase the souls of men see God as the Mighty Deliverer from bondage, and the fearful
                            dispenser of justice and judgment, and in this phase of soul travel, '' The fear of the Lord
                            is the beginning of wisdom." But the soul is marching on; and ultimately ceases to fear God,
                            having learned only to " love God as the perfection of wisdom." Next, enters Christ, the
                            evolution of soul to a recognition of God, not as an unknown Monster, to be feared only, but
                            a Heavenly Father, with whom the Son might walk and talk familiarly and lovingly, and take
                            lessons of soul life, — spiritual wisdom. Now Paul, —the Christian Apostle, could declare to
                            the cultured Greeks and Romans, yet lingering in soul travel : " Whom ye ignorantly worship,
                            Him declare I unto you." In this step of soul travel is manifest spiritual power commanding
                            and overreaching the materialistic and literal machinery, in the grooves of which, society
                            had thus far run her spiritual car of progress ; and now begins to be manifest the fact that
                            soul power, — spirit, is the arbiter of the destinies of nations; the ceramanding force of
                            human weal; a power to be investigated, learned, loved and obeyed ! The kingdom of Christ is
                            a Republic in the relation of its citizens to each other — a Kingdom in their relation to
                            Christ, their Lord and Head. It is founded, not on outward forms of social polity, but on
                            the principles of spiritual righteousness, truth and love ; laws written by the finger of
                            God, on the plastic soul, not graven upon stone tables. It contrasts with the Jewish Kingdom
                            by its spiritual freedom. It opposes to the limitation of the Jewish theocracy's boundary
                            line, as being alone able to become God's Chosen People, a universal invitation to all
                            mankind, to become the Children of God, having no restrictions but those of character and
                            conduct ; Citizenship is offered to all who truly repent before God. Christianity is founded
                            on soul life, and perpetuates its power by soul travel; thus it is in direct opposition to
                            stupid dependence on mere customs, ceremonies, formulas of empty rule ! The moribund,
                            Levitical worship and idolatry of ceremony, are wounded to death ! Christianity is not a
                            mechanical servitude, it is a soul travel from a narrow pride of religious bigotry of
                            exclusive Pharisaical righteousness, to the acceptance of goodness in all mankind, wherever,
                            or by whomsoever manifest. " If ye love those only who love you what reward have you ?" this
                            is its benedictory admonition. This, when enunciated by Jesus, and demonstrated in his
                            life's labors of universal benevolence, produced a religious revolution in the history of
                            mankind. Here, is soul travel to a demonstration of Princely dignity, and yet its working,
                            governmental policy is the contrast of a Kingly or Princely Aristocracy. But the march of
                            soul stops not here. Still on she climbs the ladder of destiny, and next perceives a
                            revelation of God, not only as a Heavenly Father, but a Heavenly Mother also. Now man begins
                            to learn his true selfhood, to recognize woman his counterpart, his finishing half, not his
                            mere vassal, but his loving comforter, and spiritual compeer ! In this revelation, love is
                            no longer lust, but is the fruit of purity and peace ; this relation of the sexes, though
                            born from the heavens upon the earth, is not of earthly destiny, it is to inaugurate a
                            Kingdom of Heaven for man's residence, not only in the life to come, but while he is a
                            sojourner on the shores of time. Soul travel, in this relation, develops dignity which is
                            approximating the Divine; dignity princely in power, yet so humble, it affords no awe to the
                            lowly in station — <pb n="125" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEK MANIFESTO. 125 sympathy for the weak and
                            erring, to cheer and uplift the downcast and fallen ; energy and determination of purpose to
                            the innocent, to enable them to keep their garments unspotted by sin — power to reprove with
                            love, and condemn with pity, to bear indignities, yet repress even just resentment. In the
                            finale, this soul travel enables mankind with so much patriotism, and univorsal love, as to
                            give one's life a willing sacrifice to truth ! To enable the race of man to have a soul
                            travel, there must ever be a light in advance of the popular sentiment, in morals, in
                            religion ; and this light must have its torch bearers, consecrated souls to human evolution.
                            Without a soul travel into the vitalizing spirit of religious fervor, and eternal life, the
                            parent of Divine and. eternal love, which produces in its votaries self denial and purity,
                            the history of religious progress in all countries, and among all peoples must perish ! Even
                            Puritan New England, in the 17th century forcibly illustrated this truth, that, the human
                            mind will not continuously bear the strain of strictly religious sentiment and discipline
                            without a spirit travel into the angelic realms of the inspirational and Divine. A
                            nonconformist Divine, in the early days of Puritanism in England, remarked : " Religion has
                            been among us this thirty-five years ; but the more it is published, the more it is
                            contemned, and reproached by many. * * * Thus religion is a by-word, a mocking stock, so
                            that in England, at this day (near the close of the 16th century), the man or woman who
                            begins to profess religion, and to serve God&gt; must resolve with himself to sustain
                            mock and injuries." The magistrates of Massachusetts, a century later, in 1668, remarked "
                            The youth of this age, have degenerated from the strictness of their fathers." But soul
                            travel clothes the being with the garments of everlasting righteousness and eternal
                            constancy in well doing, anc happy being; it leads away from earthly sins and sorrows, to
                            fraternize with angels of God; to such, religion is an eternallj flowing fountain of living,
                            soul inspiring waters, springing up unto everlasting life The bare professor of religion
                            with a lifeless untra/oelled soul, sin bound, and earth hackled, dwells alone, a stranger,
                            though having multitudes around him and is often questioning if " life is worth the living ?
                            " But, he soul traveler, in Christian graces, dwells n heavenly palaces, consociated with
                            heavenly messengers of bliss, the compeers of angels, and worships God in temples not made
                            with hands ; they are never alone, not even while dwelling as denizens of earth, jut wedded
                            to kindred spirits, as light is wedded to the sun, or color to the tinted rose; and as
                            rivers flow to the ocean, so fulfilling the prophetic prediction, shall these soul
                            progressed and progressing spirits "flow together to the goodness of the Lord." Shakers,
                            N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Conservatism vs. progress" TEIform="index"/>CONSERVATISM VS. PROGRESS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline><p TEIform="p">In 1876, during the World's Philadelphia Exhibition, a circular was issued to Believers, in
                            which a worthy and prominent brother suggested to the editor that " If the Shaker is going
                            to be maintained, it must be by Believers, and not by subscribers. Therefore, let nothing
                            find in it a place that any Believer could object to. Let it be purely conservative. " In
                            answer thereto, I wrote, but did not publish —" The American government sustained itself for
                            a long time, with slavery gnawing at its vitals, simply preaching peace — peace — while
                            practically compromising principles—the radical principles of the American government. Did
                            it pay ? When the war between principles and interest came, the debt had to be cancelled.
                            Progress was an inherent law of the American government. When that was ignored—
                            suppressed—an explosion soon followed. Republicanism was a new idea to the race. When the
                            name was indorsed, the fact was resisted. To-day, half the people — the females—are not
                            citizens. Is that Republicanism? Old systems die hard. This is undeniable in earthly
                            governments. The old smothers, chokes, crushes the new. It is one nation against all
                            nations, and all nations against a Republic. Our Spiritual Order parallels that. A true<pb n="126" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 126 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. Christ Church was the idea thrown out to
                            all Christendom—all things new—new theology — new temporal arrangement — new sexual
                            relations — new order of human society. To build up this new creation, material had to be
                            taken from the old. That old material was divided into two parts—Orthodox and Skeptic. The
                            founders of the first cycle of our Order were from the orthodox class. They have had their
                            day and their say— have done well. The founders of the second cycle will be from the ranks
                            of the skeptics —Rationalists—the founders of the American Government. They will have their
                            day and their say. Hope they will do as well. The antagonism will be like Republicanism and
                            Monarchy—Republicanism will prevail. In our first cycle, we have had celibate life,
                            community of goods, and a few fragmentary new theologies, not yet fitted into much of a
                            system — about as much of a Christ Church as the United States government has been of a
                            Republic. The Baptist, the Methodist, the Presbyterian agreed to condemn marriages, per se,
                            as unchristian. Yet they retained just as much of their old heaven views as did not too much
                            conflict with the new faith. Now they want a paper that shall contain no truth, foundational
                            to the coming new cycle, wholly conservative. Rather let it cease to be a professed exponent
                            of a new order, developing from faith to faith as the Spirit of Truth reveals. In the first
                            cycle, the question came up— " Can an infidel to old theologies — to antiChristianity —
                            become a good Shaker ? " In the second cycle,it will be asked, can a fleshly lighting
                            Christian, who has used the reasoning powers to muddle and mystify the spiritual truths of
                            Christ's gospel, become a Christian — a good Believer ? Having lived an amphibious life,
                            like frogs, is it possible for the Christ to redeem them — create them anew in Christ Jesus?
                            Or have they, by desecrating sacred words and things — professing the name of Christ, and
                            living out the character of Antichrist —committed the unpardonable sin against the Holy
                            Spirit of Truth ? Having been Idolators — worshiping Jesus as God, are they not tempted to
                            worship Ann as Goddess? Having, while yet Christians, lived in generative lusts, they now
                            bring down the God of the universe, to this little unfinished planet, to engage in the work
                            of generating a human being — Jesus (see Dunlavy)— thereby building up generation as a pure,
                            holy spiritual work and in stitution, right in the Holy Temple of God in Christ's second
                            appearing — Church. This too, in standard works which aims to hold forth celibacy — a
                            resurrection as the pivotal idea of the new order of true Shakerism—an order which holds
                            that in the Adamic condition, free from sin, Generation was only natural, earthly, animal.
                            As the Heavens are above the earth, so is Resurrection above Generation. Can such Orthodox
                            material ever be redeemed— saved? If so, there is hope in their latter end — and great hope
                            for the infidels. In the spirit world, the infidel, skeptic founders of our government, are
                            building up the waste places of Zion. The Gospel, in its Second degree, is theirs by
                            inheritance. They are the party who said, " I will not go," but repented and went and did
                            the will of God on earth, in founding a new earthly government, the commencement of the new
                            earth, even as our order is the commencement of the new heavens. See the poor, bigoted
                            irrational Moody and Sankeyites, who have closed the gates of a World's Exposition upon one
                            of the seven Sabbath days that their own sect, who visit it have adopted. These inane bigots
                            having lived in the evils of the world until frightened by the prospect of their own eternal
                            hell-fire and brimstone, fall in imagination, at the feet of Jesus, in the belief that " He
                            has done it all." When they die they go to a heaven that, to a good Shaker, would be
                            unendurable. Let us have the new cycle, as fast as the present generation can bear the new
                            truths that will be its foundation stones.</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The old-blooded Puritanism of the Centennial managers in closing the Exhibition on Sunday..." TEIform="index"/>The old-blooded Puritanism of the Centennial managers in closing the Exhibition on Sunday...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">"The cold-blooded Puritanism of the Centennial managers in closing the Exhibition
                                    on Sunday is utterly insufferable, and one more marvelous incident to go down in
                                    history to the account of stupid and intolerable bigotry. Greeks will be there whose
                                    holy day is Monday. Persians will be there <pb n="127" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/>whose holy day is
                                    Tuesday. Assyrians will be there whose holy day is Wednesday Egyptians will be there
                                    whose holy day k Thursday ; and Turks will be there whose holy day is Friday ; and
                                    Jews whose holy day is Saturday. And Scientists, Infidels, Atheists, Freethinkers,
                                    Materialists and Spiritualists who have risen above the mountain of holy days."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Common sense" TEIform="index"/>Common Sense</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Willing obedience" TEIform="index"/>WILLING OBEDIENCE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/>ANTOINETTE DOOLITTLE</byline><p TEIform="p"> God has never left the earth without a witness of Himself. There have been a few—when
                            compared with the many—who feared, loved and served Him according to the degree of knowledge
                            of His will revealed in their time, and of His requirements upon them. Obedience was the
                            condition of blessing and acceptance, as lessons were given from time to time for the
                            uplifting of the race unto higher truths and more sublime thought and action. " If ye be
                            willing and obedient ye shall eat the good (fruit) of the land," and " dwell in the light of
                            God's countenance"— His benign smiles of approval. Upon that law, kept inviolate, hung the
                            promise of reward. God's works bear the insignia' of life, growth and development. Laws and
                            lessons that were given when the race was young and feeble had their uses; without the sus.
                            taining, verifying influences which they imparted even the breath of life that God gave to
                            man, which caused him to be a living soul, endowed with intelligence and reasoning powers,
                            would have been lost. As an infant is fed and nourished by its motherland receives such food
                            as it can digest, so was man, or a race of men, supplied with food befitting its infantile
                            condition. More than that could not have been a blessing at that time. But how far would the
                            food of an infant go toward sustaining a full grown man or woman ? Although indispensable to
                            the then immature condition of age and education, it would fall far short of supplying the
                            demands of full developed manhood. Now, in the nineteenth century, we find the mental food
                            that sufficed in the past — even that which was accepted and relished in one decade in the
                            gone by — does not fully satisfy present investigating minds. As with the mental, so in
                            regard to the spiritual — the soul cravings. The condition of blessing resting upon the law
                            of obedience is as potent and essential at the present as in the past. All progress in
                            ethics or religion is based upon that principle, through whatever agency light may come to
                            us, unless we receive it, grasp and hold it by obeying its teachings, we fail of the full
                            blessing designed. We cannot be justified or condemned from the standpoint of others in the
                            present, neither be satisfied to plant our feet upon the summit of the highest mountain that
                            appeared to Moses and the prophets. They stood upon the heights of the Zion of their day,
                            and drank health and hope from spiritual fountains of inspirations that opened unto them,
                            which caused them to utter beautiful truths that have come down to us in substance through
                            many centuries of time, for which we acknowledge our indebtedness. Other stars have since
                            arisen, and we hope many more may yet arise, that will shine with brighter luster than any
                            that have shone in the past; and while those in the past may in some degree " cease to be
                            glorious by reason of the glory that excelleth," they will still retain their places in the
                            celestial horizon, forming a bright constellation that will be seen in the ages yet to be.
                            Jesus the Anointed came to inaugurate a new dispensation; not to condemn the old, but to
                            break the bread of life in a new form, and to show a more excellent way than the "eye for an
                            eye" system; that to render good for evil was a higher law. He led His disciples on to a
                            more elevated plane than the law-giver Moses had done, and taught that love, ruling the life
                            and conscience, was better than physical force, and forgiveness better than revenge. In the
                            dnys of Jesus few indeed were prepared to accept the message that He was commissioned to
                            bear to the children of men. He took great pains to enlighten His disciples and imbue their
                            minds with the importance of the great fundamental principles of a new spiritual order that
                            it was His <pb n="128" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 128 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. peculiar mission to originate,
                            which were virgin purity, non-resistance, love to God and humanity, practically demonstrated
                            by community of interest in all things pertaining to hody and soul. He said : " All men
                            cannot receive My word. He that is able let him receive it." Even His baptized followers
                            only saw in part; they awaited the growth of the ages for the ushering in of a still more
                            perfect day. In the fullness of time, Ann the Anointed came as a medium to perform a
                            peculiar work that was given her to do. She planted her feet upon the rock of revelation —
                            the foundation that Jesus laid — and worked from and added strength thereto. As Jesus was
                            the first born of many brethren, so was Ann the first born of many daughters, and Jesus-like
                            she faithfully fulfilled her mission. They were not able to perfect the work that they
                            commenced on earth, but looked to their followers to fill the measure which they left
                            unfilled. They opened the gates of the highway that leads up the mount to the city of God,
                            where all things are new, and their dual voice is heard today calling to their children to
                            come up higher and still higher, where they may drink at new springs of inspiration, and
                            receive " beauty for ashes, the oil of gladness for mourning, and a garment of praise for a
                            spirit of heaviness."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prentissiana: hatching chickens by machinery" TEIform="index"/>PRENTISSIANA: Hatching
                            Chickens by Machinery</head><p TEIform="p">Some years ago, a good Catholic lady introduced me to her gallery of well-selected pictures.
                            Prominent in the group were the two Marys, one nursing a baby, the other, in form erect and
                            gallant bearing. The lady adoringly pointed to the firstnamed Mary. Pointing to the other, I
                            said " I like this Mary best." The lady rejoined, " to be sure she is the best looking, but
                            she's not the Mother of God." The other — the Mary Magdalene of Holy Writ — was a choice
                            type of humanity, largely in advance of the age in which she lived. She was above the common
                            level. From her autobiography, we make the following extract : " The men of my period were
                            not the men of my ideal. I did not love them. This was the sum of my offending. When I found
                            an object lovable — a man, coming up to my ideal of manhood, I loved as only true woman can
                            love. The hitherto sealed fountain was opened. I had found one worthy to loose the seal. And
                            now, from my serene abode in the higher spheres, in the simplicity and innocence of early
                            childhood, which I still retain, I would speak a word to the damsels of earth. Squander not
                            your soul's holiest affection on unworthy objects. Keep the treasure, your birthright
                            inheritance, in consecration. It is of more worth to you than the universe without it. If
                            lost, it is not regained in its pristine purity." But what has this to do with the text ?
                            Nothing, sure. The effort to make chickens by machinery is afac simile of the pious effort
                            to make sons and daughters of God by a Trinity of masculines — an abortion. From the sublime
                            center of all vitality, all the way down, the feminine —the affectionate element—is sine qua
                            non. In the most advanced heavens to which we can stretch our spiritual vision, are Seraphim
                            — feminine, as well as Cherubim — masculine angels. And what would heaven be without
                        them?</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Is money the root of all evil?" TEIform="index"/>IS MONEY THE ROOT OF ALL EVIL?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Mills, Anna E." TEIform="persName"/>ANNA E. MILLS</byline><p TEIform="p"> We are not told that it is money, but the love of money that causes the greater part of the
                            evils brought before us either by sight, rumor or through the press of-the present day. And
                            from the annals of history we find on record that the love of money, to a great extent, has
                            been the cause of evil for ages past. But with the increased advantages of the day, and the
                            facilities for improvement and progression on every hand, comes the increased demand for
                            money, and many and hideous are the crimes arising from the de- <pb n="129" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            SHAKER MANIFESTO. 129 sire to obtain that which should be a blessing. Money in the hands of
                            men who have in their hearts truth, honor, and a love for humanity, have bestowed, and are
                            bestowing, broad-cast over the land, noble deeds of charity and compassion, by extending
                            help in various ways to those who need. To such agencies how great the indebtedness for the
                            many charitable institutions with which we are so highly favored. True, on examining the
                            statistics of asylums, children's homes, infirmaries, hospitals, in fact all benevolent
                            institutions, we find a majority of the inmates there from a love of money, ill-gotten in
                            some way, which has step by step led them to resort from necessity to these God-sent places
                            of refuge. Truly, money in some hands is a blessing. But allow me for a moment to present to
                            you the other side of the picture in just one of its phases, and in my mind one that brings
                            death and woe to the participants, and misery and heart-aches to the innocent. The love of
                            the mighty dollar will prompt one man to pass to the hand of his fellow-man perhaps united
                            to him by the ties of nature the intoxicating cup, knowing that in it is concealed that
                            which will deprive him of reason, and madden with frenzy his intellect and manhood; plunging
                            him without mercy beneath the levels of all society demands, even lower than the brute
                            creation ! He will gorgeously deck his den with the beauties of nature, accompanied by the
                            warble of foreign birds ; thus drawing within this net victims of all ages; piling in his
                            coffers that which justly belongs to innocent childhood, or such that from compulsion are
                            entirely helpless ; thus in man's eager desire for obtaining gold, he hardens his heart,
                            checks conscience, closes eyes and ears to the cries of those who are made destitute on
                            account of his money drawer becoming the receptacle of the coin taken from the hand of
                            inebriates, who, to satisfy the appetite which burns like fire within, forgets those who are
                            near and dear to him ; loses sight of firm uprightness; becomes careless and indifferent to
                            the rights of good citizenship, filling all with whom he may come in contact with disgust
                            and abhorrence. Why do men so misuse our greatest blessings ? Casting aside God's holy laws,
                            hurling their own immortal souls from his presence, besides bringing others to utter
                            desolation and want, both here and hereafter. "But godliness with contentment is great
                            gain." " For we brought nothing into this world, and it is certain we can take nothing out."
                            "Fight the good fight of faith, being therewith content with what ye have." Watervliet,
                        0.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What good can I do today?" TEIform="index"/>WHAT GOOD CAN I DO NOW TO-DAY?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Kulp, Jacob S." TEIform="persName"/>JACOB S. KULP</byline><p TEIform="p"> Dear Editor — I thought I would offer my mite to help build up the cause of good ; thus it
                            is i send you my simple efforts in the form of an Acrostic. If you think them worthy a place
                            in the Manifesto,publish them ; if not, consign them to the waste basket, and 1 shall be
                            satisfied in trying each day to do what good I can. Wherefore should the people murmur? Have
                            they any cause at all ? Are the crowd cot in the error? Take ye heed lest ye may fall. GS-od
                            is good and wise and righteous, Over land and sea He reigns ; O'er the ocean and the dry
                            land — Does He not His power proclaim? Cast your bread upon the waters, After days it will
                            return ; Nothing doubting, but be cheerful ; It is not our lot to mourn. Do not fret nor
                            grieve nor sorrow ; On God's providence depend ; ]STor be fearful for to-morrow, — Only
                            trust : God is our friend ! We do all enjoy His favor, Though we may not sense His care ; O,
                            may I receive forever, Divine blessings evermore; Amen ! let each one be thankful ; Ye who
                            claim the Saviour's way. Strive to grow in grace and knowledge, Hoping for a better day.
                            Pleasant Hill, Ky.</p></div2><pb n="130" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., May 10,1881" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., May 10,1881</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Antoinette and Anna" TEIform="persName"/>Antoinette and Anna</byline><p TEIform="p">Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., May 10,1881 Beloved Ministry. — Our sisters were so well pleased with
                                the correspondence in the May number of the Manifesto, that Sister Martha was prompted
                                to respond to Elder Joseph. And if the Ministry feel union, she, and we also, would be
                                pleased to have it find a place in .Tune number, if it will not crtiwd out something
                                more valuable. I In the love of the Gospel,</p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A grateful tribute to a beloved father in Israel, Elder Joseph Brackett,..." TEIform="index"/>A grateful tribute to a beloved father in Israel, Elder Joseph Brackett,...
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. ANDERSON</byline><p TEIform="p">A grateful tribute to a beloved father in Israel, Elder Joseph Brackett, for his
                                beautiful, soul-inspiring words, contributed to the May number of our monthly paper: Ah
                                ! words of truth from living springs sent forth, A father's blessing mingled with his
                                love, Are to the soul what light is to the earth, Or dew and shower distilling from
                                above. Baptized, regenerate and exalted soul ! True to the virgin principle, that gave
                                Thy early manhood power of self control, And bore thee safe above sin's tidal wave. All
                                glorious in the resurrection life, A savior risen on Mount Zion's hight, Where earth,
                                tumultuous in her surging strife, Can never wreck thy battlements of right. A happy
                                greeting from unnumbered hearts Flows forth like ripples on a summer sea; The tide of
                                loving feeling outward starts, Moved by the weighty words there dropped by thee. The
                                golden sheaves of ripe experience We gather in the storehouse of the mind, And realize
                                the goodly recompense The faithful through obedience may find. Thy four-score years to
                                holy service given, Thy consecration to a noble aim, Have made a record in the higher
                                heaven, And placed among the saints thy hallowed name. Just like the worthy patriarch of
                                old, Oh ! may the mantle of thy blessing fall On those who now thy pure example hold,
                                And on truth's altar sacrifice their all. Ah! selfish loves and vain ambition draw Too
                                many souls from purposes of right; The carnal life all good would overawe And dim the
                                brightness of fair Reason's light. The cross forbidding seems to those who seek • The
                                charms of pleasure's evanescent day; But to the innocent, the chaste and meek Tis
                                wreathed in flowers that never fade away. Not vain shall prove your labors in the Lord,
                                Though souls — unwise — the way of life shall spurn, You shall enjoy your merited
                                reward, And many yet to righteousness will turn. Oh, may your few remaining years be
                                crowned With peace and rest, angelic and serene, And heavenly glory to your soul
                                redeemed, When no dark clouds or shadows intervene ! With you our prayer of faith shall
                                never wane; The good you prophesy we know will come, And rich will be that spiritual
                                increase That yet shall bless each happy Zion home.</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Death of Elder William Reynolds" TEIform="index"/>DEATH OF ELDER WILLIAM REYNOLDS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, O. C." TEIform="persName"/>O. C. Hampton</byline><p TEIform="p">Union Village, May 16,1881. Dear Albert :—I know you are not in the habit of giving room
                                in the columns of the Shaker Manifesto for extended obituaries, but this I send you for
                                your own pleasure — condensed as much as I am able to condense an article, and if any
                                small portion thereof can be editorally appropriated, insert; if not, not. Elder William
                                Reynolds, was born April 4, 1815. His parents were of Irish descent, but he was born on
                                one of the Ionian Islands, and spoke the Greek language for twelve or fourteen years of
                                his younger days. He embraced Shakerism in 1837, being then twenty-one years of age.
                                Ever since he became a believer he has been thoroughly upright, sincere and
                                uncompromising in his obedience to the principles, teachings and doctrines of Christ and
                                Mother, and exceedingly exacting with himself to keep every order and regulation of the
                                Institution. His was a pure, unspotted virgin life — rigidly conformed to personal
                                purity and practical<pb n="131" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 131 righteousness. His
                                zeal for the welfare of Zion never flagged, and his anxiety for her prosperity in
                                matters temporal and eternal knew no rest nor intermission. It has even been supposed
                                that his excessive solicitude broke down his nervous sj^stem finally, and was, to SRy
                                the least, an indirect cause of his so sudden and early death. It was said at his
                                funeral that one could look in no direction on the premises of U. V. without seeing the
                                labors of Elder We, and it is generally conceded that he had very superior taste and
                                talent in architectural design and arrangement. Very many expressions of love, thanks
                                and eulogy were united in at the funeral, which was very solemn ; andwe hope, peculiarly
                                blessed to many if not all present thereat. This I have written you at the request of .
                                Elder Matthew Carter, and perhaps a few of the most important points herein mentioned
                                may be found worthy of insertion. Yours truly,</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Revised new testament" TEIform="index"/>THE REVISED NEW TESTAMENT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Through the enterprise and kindness of our friends, I. K. Funk &amp; Co.. 10 and 12
                                Dey street, New York, we have been favored with an early copy of the Revised New
                                Testament. In it may be perceived many changes both verbal and syntactical. But for all
                                the more good it will do toward leading men and women to live better, more like Him of
                                whom it so ardently treats, we have our serious doubts. True, it leads us to know of the
                                better rendering of Jesus' words ; as for instance, " Take no thought," etc., we have
                                rendered, "Be not over-anxious regarding the morrow," etc. What we want is a revision of
                                men's lives in accordance with what has been long known to be the very grandest life on
                                record — the life of Jesus Christ. What we want is a revision of men's thoughts from the
                                death of Jesus, and toward the life of Christ — two vastly different themes. Let the
                                death of Jesus go; but let the life of Christ grow more universally among the people.
                                Then, regardless of verbal and syntactical revisions of the good, old book, we will have
                                living, walking, working revisions, in the newly-inspired disciples of the Lord, to-day.
                                Away, then, with the dead letter, in the presence of the living spirit, working among
                                the. people. Away with all forms that only hinder the flow of the spirit, and cause
                                false hopes by improper renderings. The only hope for the people, in salvation from
                                their sins, is in the life, not death of Jesus. And with that, revisions of New
                                Testaments are comparatively worthless.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian model" TEIform="index"/>THE CHRISTIAN MODEL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">For more than eighteen hundreds of years there has been presented to the world, called
                                Christian, a character, which for beauty, for love, for justice, for exceeding humanity
                                and approach unto godliness has, and had never before been equaled. Our so-called
                                Christian world has not wanted eloquent reminders that this beautiful character once
                                lived, and should now live in the memories and in the lives of Christian followers
                                today. That there have been many tangents made to suit the conveniences of human
                                passions, whereby the complete following of the most illustrious model could be
                                conveniently avoided, and with an apparent show of reason, the theological Baby <pb n="132" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 132 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. Ion of numerous creeds, unlike the
                                simple Christ's, bear ample testimony. "I- am the ivay" still stands; "/ am the life"
                                you should live, is resplendent with Christian testimony; " I am the truth" you should
                                learn as Christians — and learn this truth to live it — is a brilliant and eternal
                                reminder to those who would be Christians. We say eloquent reminders of the most
                                beautiful model have not been wanting — reminders from the most eloquent tongues of
                                grandest human natures. The brilliant, popular theological stars of both the new and the
                                old world vie with each other in magnifying the perfection of the Christian model —
                                Jesus Christ. We are proud of these brilliant linguists ; we are very grateful to them
                                for pleasing our hearings and satisfying our understandings of what a beautiful nature
                                was Christ's. We admit it passes our comprehension how the model for all Christians
                                could be better magnified. But brethren, Spurgeon, Beecher, Talmadge, Thomas, Moody,
                                etc., etc., up to hundreds, why talk of the beautiful model so extravagantly and not
                                live it more personally ? Why talk of Christ and not live like Christ? The grand need of
                                the world to-day is to have some grandest of nature's noblemen — astute in all the
                                elements of perfect, physical manhood and womanhood — combining therewith the spiritual
                                beauties of the unworldly Christ—to live like the Christ—be modern models of the same
                                beautiful pattern. Must we be ever fed on talk ? Is not talk, without the walking after
                                the model, simply husks ? Can we not induce some and many of the strong men and women to
                                be our modern models of what the Christ of old was? *' Oh, that the Christ would come!"
                                Oh, that the determination to live like the model Christ would seize upon the many noble
                                men and women who now are serving self rather than Christ! Let there be a growing
                                determination that Christ may walk to-day in numerous models in equal perfection of
                                olden times, and there will be the dawning of a millennium sung of, hoped for, and now
                                approached. True, there will be a tremendous exercise of denial to selfishness; a new
                                world will open to those who will to be like Christ; the old " will pass away with great
                                noise;" the new will enter with great hope for the world. The beautiful model is still
                                brilliantly apparent. How many will join hands and hearts not only to admire but to live
                                truly like unto it ? ft</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What answer?" TEIform="index"/>WHAT ANSWER?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We ask, with positive composure, " What do the churches think of Christ?" The Shaker
                                church is in a great minority, numerically speaking, and the reasons therefor are
                                apparent. The obligations it imposes on its members, without exception, are such that
                                only a few are able and willing to receive them. Yet these obligations are none other
                                than preached and practiced by the Christ. The popular churches look with disdain and
                                derision upon the sparse membership of the Shaker church, as though there was the first
                                reason for one such look. If the question of what is right depended upon popularity and
                                numbers the followers of Confucius and Ma- <pb n="133" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO.
                                133 hornet could claim the precedence in righteousness. If paucity of numbers positively
                                indicated a want of the truth as found in Christ, then indeed would the Shaker church be
                                poor indeed, unworthy of notice, if not worthy of derision. Still this church has quite
                                a goodly number of ardent advocates, and who would rise to the dignity of their
                                profession to question their contemporaries. When you deride the virgin celibacy taught
                                by the Shaker church, do you deride the virgin celibacy of Jesus, the Christ ? What
                                answer ? As followers of Christ, how nearly do those called Christians pattern the
                                master in this respect? Having made a sacrament of matrimony, who gave the authority to
                                do so under the Christian dispensation ? If any say the life and example and testimony
                                of Jesus in this respect was an error, why not discard Christianity itself ? Is celibacy
                                unnatural ? Jesus declared it to be heavenly, and to compose the heavens. "Thy will be
                                done on earth, as in heaven." We might ask what answer, to several as prominent
                                questions. In regard to the non-resistance, the unretaliation of the Christ— the radical
                                peace advocate. Do the churches generally discountenance war under any and all
                                circumstances ? What say the army chaplains ? In regard to the principle of the
                                non-possession of selfish, personal property, how stand the churches upon this
                                question—"and none possessed aught he called his own." We ask what answers the churches
                                have to make as reasonable excuses for professing a following after Christ, yet walking
                                after their own inclinations, and in nothing resembling the pattern ? We assert Christ's
                                life as most right—as only right for Christians to practice ; as a heavenly practice on
                                the earth ; and whoever makes the profession of Christianity should live like Christ's
                                life. If any are unwilling or unable to live like the self-denying pattern, let him
                                renounce the profession and the title, yielding these to those who are able and willing.
                                We ask the churches wherein the Church, called Shaker, merits any more derision for its
                                peculiar teachings than does the life of Christ. What answer?</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our present issue" TEIform="index"/>Our Present Issue</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">EDITORIAL NOTES. Will be found a very valuable and thoughtful one. Freighted with so many
                                wholesome truths from so many of our foremost and valued contributors, we sail among the
                                seas of error and reason courageously. Ponder well, friends, the beautiful logic of him
                                who writes " Soul Travel," it is worth the time, and will not soon be forgotten. What
                                will the people think now of what constitutes a Christian's "Willing Obedience?" t And
                                we wonder how the people will regard our old pioneer and battle-axe —who stands so
                                straight for progress, as almost to appear to lean to the other side ! Brave Elder Evans
                                — not afraid of progress though approaching his four-score years ! Nevertheless, we have
                                heard of successful "Hatching chickens by machinery." We wonder did Newton, Herschell,
                                Mitchell, or Proctor ever pay a prettier tribute to <pb n="134" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 134 THE
                                SHAKER MANIFESTO. "The Solar System," than has our talented Shaker Girl? "The root of
                                all evil" leads to the consideration of evil ways of getting filthy lucre; and bids do
                                so no more to everybody. Our music is a familiar tune, applied to original words by some
                                of our Mt. Lebanon brethren—how admiringly it applies to the words ! Sing, friends, sing
                                it. Elder Joseph Brackett gets a benefit in this number; and he is worthy of it. We ask
                                especial attention to our cover, as we have only the most reliable firms illustrated
                                thereon, and they can be relied on. After reading this number, friends, pass it to your
                                neighbor—let the good things move broad-cast.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mother dolly" TEIform="index"/>MOTHER DOLLY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The pleasant feature of very advanced age, 105 years, meeting in harmony with those of
                                five years and similar, will be read with great pleasure by many. Mother Dolly came to
                                the Shakers on her fifth birthday, and celebrated not only the beginning of her 106th
                                year, but her hundreth anniversary as a Shakeress.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Elder William Reynolds" TEIform="index"/>ELDER WILLIAM REYNOLDS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Every one*will feel surprised and sorrowful at the news of Elder WmReynolds' demise. We
                                acknowledge being shocked ; and we wonder at the inscrutable ways that take away so
                                valuable a man at such an early age. It isn't loud praying that counts with the Lord so
                                much as giving four quarts for every gallon, sixteen ounces for a pound, and thirty-six
                                inches to the yard ; in fact, doing to others as we would be done bv. y£}xz (\%ilxzurs
                                ffixotto.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>The Children's Grotto</head><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Resisted" TEIform="index"/>RESISTED</head><p TEIform="p">Four young men, clerks and students, while on a summer vacation tramp through Northern
                                New England, engaged for a guide to a certain romantic forest waterfall a boy named
                                Forrest Graves. Forrest was a fine, athletic fellow, who could outwalk and outclimb any
                                amateur in the mountains, and his moral courage was quite equal to his physical health
                                and strength. After he had guided the young men to the waterfall, and they had satisfied
                                themselves with sight-seeing, they invited him to lunch with them. "Thank you, I have my
                                own lunch;" and the boy went away by himself. Later, when full justice had been done to
                                their repast, and a flask of brandy had furnished each of the young men with a
                                stimulating draught, Graves was called. " You must drink with us, if you will not eat
                                with us," now said the owner of the flask, and the most reckless of the party. " No,
                                sir, thank you," was the boy's courteous response. " But I shall insist upon it." " You
                                can do as you please, and I shall do as I please." The young man sprang to his feet, and
                                with a bound stood beside the boy, too much absorbed in his own purpose to heed the
                                quivering lips and flashing eyes of another. " Now you are bound to try my brandy; I
                                always rule." " You can't rule me." These words were scarcely uttered when the flask was
                                seized and hurled into the stream, where the clinking of glass betrayed its utter
                                destruction. Then a clear, defiant tone rang out : " I did it in self-defense. You had
                                no right to tempt me. My father was once a rich and honorable man, but he died a
                                miserable drunkard, and my mother came here to live to keep me away from liquor till I
                                should be old enough to take care of myself. I have promised her a hundred times <pb n="135" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 135 I wouldn't taste it, and I'd die before
                                I'd break my promise." " Bravely said. Forgive me, and let us shake hands. My mother
                                would be a happy woman if I was as brave as you : I wouldn't tempt you to do wrong. I
                                shall never forget you, nor the lesson you have taught me." The most reckless was the
                                most generous, and seeing his error apologized frankly. How many boys need to be kept
                                from strong drink ; and, alas, how many men and women ! Who dares tempt them ? Let it
                                not be you and I. — YoutKs Companion.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Four good rules" TEIform="index"/>FOUR GOOD RULES</head><p TEIform="p">One is : always look at the person you speak to. When you are addressed, look straight at
                                the person who speaks to you. Another is ; speak your words distinctly. Do not mutter or
                                mumble. If your words are worth uttering, they are worth pronouncing clearly and
                                distinctly. Another is • do not say disagreeable things. If you have nothing pleasant to
                                say, keep silent. A fourth is — and, children, remember it all your lives — think three
                                times before you speak once. Have you something to do that you find hard and would
                                prefer not to do? Then listen : Do the hard things first, and get over with them.</p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A minister was once addressing children from the parable of the rich man and Lazarus..." TEIform="index"/>A minister was once addressing children from the parable of the rich man and Lazarus...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A minister was once addressing children from the parable of the rich man and Lazarus. He
                                showed them the poverty and wretchedness of Lazarus and the ease and luxury of the rich
                                man on earth, and then the bliss of Lazarus and the misery of Dives in the world to
                                come. He asked them which of the two they would like to be. A little boy said: "Please,
                                I would like to be the rich man on earth, but Lazarus in heaven." That is the way with
                                some grown-up children ; they want to be Dives here, and enjoy the good things of
                                Mammon, and a safe home in Abraham's bosom after they cannot hold on to Mammon any
                                longer. But this is God's test of our love for Him. If it were not for this test heaven
                                itself might be spoiled by the presence of self-deceiving hypocrites, but this sifts out
                                the chaff.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Read and ponder" TEIform="index"/>Read and Ponder</head><p TEIform="p">.—A muddy stream, flowing into one clear and sparkling, for a time rolls along by itself.
                                A little further down they unite, and the whole is impure. So youth, untouched by sin,
                                may for a time keep its purity in foul company, but a little later and they become
                                impure altogether.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A boy who is polite to his father and mother is..." TEIform="index"/>A boy who is polite to his father and mother is...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A BOY who is polite to his father and mother is likely to be polite to every one else. A
                                boy lacking politeness to his parents may have the semblance of courtesy in society, but
                                is never truly polite in spirit, and is in danger, as he becomes familiar, of betraying
                                his real want of courtesy. We are all in danger of livilig too much for the outside
                                world, for the impression which we make in society, coveting the good opinions of those
                                who are in a sense part of themselves, and who will continue to sustain and be
                                interested in us, notwithstanding these defects of deportment and character. We say to
                                every boy and to every girl, cultivate the habit of courtesy and propriety at home —in
                                the sitting-room and the kitchen as well as in the parlor, and you will be sure in other
                                places to deport yourself in a becoming and attractive manner. When one has a pleasant
                                smile and a graceful demeanor it is a satisfaction to know that these are not put on,
                                but that they belong to the character, and are manifest at all times and under all
                                circumstances.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="There are two kinds of difficulties over which we should not worry..." TEIform="index"/>There are two kinds of difficulties over which we should not worry...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Some one has impressively said: " There are two kinds of difficulties over which we
                                should not worry, the one is those things which we can't help, for it does no good the
                                other is those we can remedy, for it is infinitely better to betake ourselves to the
                                work of overcoming the difficulties rather wearing out our spirits, minds, bodies, and
                                reputations, by worrying over them."</p></div3><pb n="136" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mother Dolly Saxton's visit with the children on her birthday" TEIform="index"/>MOTHER
                                DOLLY SAXTON'S VISIT WITH THE CHILDREN ON HER BIRTHDAY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Potter, Eleanor" TEIform="persName"/>ELEANOR POTTER</byline><p TEIform="p">The Centenarian Shaker ess One Hundred and Five Tears Old. BY On the sixth of May, 1881,
                                the little girls, ten in number, with their caretaker came to pay Mother Dolly a visit.
                                They gathered around her and desired a blessing from her. She gave them the following
                                advice: " Children, I am glad that you have come to see me; I hope you will all be good
                                and make useful sisters in Mother's gospel; and if you want to be happy when you be.
                                come advanced in life, as I am, you must do as I have done. You must be respectful to
                                your teachers and instructors, loving and kind to each other, not quarrelsome nor cross.
                                Be condescending one to another. I want you to remember what I now say: Little children,
                                love one another and be happyI love you all." They* all then kneeled down and she took
                                each one by the hand and bestowed on them a parent's love and blessing. She told them
                                she had been a Shaker one hundred years and had been saved from sin, and she felt
                                thankful and happy, and they could all be very happy if they would be good. She had
                                previously received a present of some raisins ; these were divided into ten packages,
                                and she then gave them to the children with her own hands. They returned their kind
                                thanks for her good counsel and pretty present; then each greeted her with a kiss of
                                love and affection, promising always to be good and bade her adieu.</p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How do you like the Episcopalian service?..." TEIform="index"/>How do you like the Episcopalian service?...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">"How do you like the Episcopalian service?" asked Jones. '" Never heard it,"
                                        replied Fogg; " I dropped in at one of the churches last Sunday. It was quite
                                        early, and so I began reading the service. I didn't read far, though, before I
                                        found that it would never do for me. So I came out." " Why, what was the trouble
                                        ? " " Too many collections." "Too many collections ?" " Yes, on almost every
                                        page it said ' collect.' One collection is all I can afford to respond to* Must
                                        be awfully expensive to be an Episcopalian.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Boston transcript" TEIform="index"/>Boston Transcript.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>DECEASED</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rankin, Polly" TEIform="index"/>Polly Rankin</head><p TEIform="p">At South Union, Ky., April 27, , aged 74 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wheeler, Huldah" TEIform="index"/>Huldah Wheeler</head><p TEIform="p">Our Shirley Shaker friends have to record the death of another of their aged members
                                    — Sister , formerly of Vermont — but for thirty-two years a resident in the society.
                                    She died on Monday, the 25th of April, having just passed the seventy-fifth
                                    anniversary of her birth.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Smith, Phebe" TEIform="index"/>Phebe Smith,</head><p TEIform="p">At Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., May 12, aged 70 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hammond, Lucy A." TEIform="index"/>Lucy A. Hammond</head><p TEIform="p">At Harvard, Mass., May 19, , aged 88.</p></div4></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Received" TEIform="index"/>RECEIVED</head><p TEIform="p">Charles Clapp,................... $10 80 Aug. Blase.....................,. 18 00</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-press" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We all love to hear good things said of us..." TEIform="index"/>We all love to hear good things said of us...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">We all love to hear good things said of us, and we are particularly anxious so to hear of
                                our contributors. The Youths' Mirror, a sprightly and golden monthly, Altoona, Pa.,
                                makes us color a little when it so goodly says : The Shaker Manifesto, for April, is
                                more than ever an intelligent and powerful advocate of the truth. '' Mental Fotografy,"
                                by Catharine Allen, sets forth some startling ideas. "A Letter to Jesus," by Grace Eddy,
                                is a touching and beautiful piece of poetry. The issue for May is also interesting. "
                                Better and Better," by Wm. H. Bussell, points out plainly the truths the author seeks to
                                convey. '' Harmony of God's Universe," is by our favorite, Antoinette Doolittle, who, we
                                think, belies her name. We are very much in love with the Manifesto, which we now
                                receive regularly.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is an old and true saying that opportunity has hair in front..." TEIform="index"/>It is an old and true saying that opportunity has hair in front...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">It is an old and true saying that opportunity has hair in front, but is bald behind. If
                                you catch her by the forelock you can hold her, but if you wait till she gets by, your
                                hand slips and she is gone.</p></div3></div2><pb n="137" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>Home Topics</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to preserve the teeth" TEIform="index"/>How to Preserve the Teeth</head><p TEIform="p">. — The following directions for the care of the teeth have been issued by the medical
                                committee of the National Dental Hospital, London: 1. The teeth should be cleaned at
                                least once a day, the best time being night — the last thing. For this purpose use a
                                soft brush, on which take a little soap, and then some prepared chalk, brushing up and
                                down and across. There is rarely any objection to the friction causing the gum to bleed
                                slightly. 2. Avoid all rough usage of the teeth such as cracking nuts, biting thread,
                                etc., as by so doing even good, sound teeth may be inj ured. 3. When decay is first
                                observed advice should be sought. It is the stopping in a small hole that is of the
                                greatest service, though not (infrequently a large filling preserves the teeth for
                                years. 4. It is of the greatest, importance that children from four years and upward
                                should have their teeth frequently examined by the dental surgeon, to see that the first
                                set, particularly the back teeth, are not decaying too early, and to have the
                                opportunity of timely treatment for the regulation and preservation of the second set.
                                5. Children should be taught to rinse the mouth night and morning, and to begin the use
                                of the tooth-brush early (likewise the toothpick). 6. With regard to the food of
                                children, to those who are old enough, whole meal, bread, porridge and milk should be
                                given* This is much more wholesome and substantial food than white bread. 7. If the
                                foregoing instructions were carried out comparatively few teeth would have to be
                                extracted.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health hints" TEIform="index"/>Health Hints</head><p TEIform="p">. — Gentian root is said to be a tobacco antidote: Buy two ounces or more of Gentian
                                root, coarsely ground. Take as much of it after each meal, or oftener, as amounts to a
                                common quid of "fine-cut." Chew it slowly and swallow the juice. Continue this a few
                                weeks and you will conquer the appetite for tobacco. To stop a flow of blood, take the
                                fine dust of tea, or the scrapings of the inside of tanned leather; bind it upon the
                                wound closely, and blood will soon cease to flow. After the blood has ceased to flow
                                laudanum may be applied to the wound. Due regard to these instructions will save
                                agitation of mind running for a surgeon, who probably will make no better prescription
                                if present than this.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What the microscope says" TEIform="index"/>What the Microscope Says</head><p TEIform="p">. — Insects o'f various kinds may be seen in the cavities of a grain of sand. Mould is a
                                forest of beautiful trees, with the branches, leaves and fruit. Butterflies are fully
                                feathered. Hairs are hollow tubes. The surface of our bodies is covered with scales like
                                a fish ; a single grain of sand would cover 150 of these scales, and yet a scale covers
                                500 pores. Through these narrow openings the perspiration forces itself like water
                                through a sieve. Each drop of stagnant water contains a world of living creatures
                                swimming with as much liberty as whales in the sea. Each leaf has a colony of insects
                                grazing on it like cows on a meadow. Yes, even the ugliest plant that grows shows some
                                remarkable property when closely examined.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cure for sick headache" TEIform="index"/>A Cure for Sick Headache</head><p TEIform="p">—This complaint is the result of eating too much and exercising too little. Often the
                                cause is that the stomach is not able to digest the food last introduced into it, either
                                from its having been unsuitable or excessive in quantity. It is said a diet of bread and
                                butter, with ripe fruits or berries, with moderate, continuous exercise in the open air
                                sufficient to keep up a gentle perspiration, would cure almost every case in a short
                                time. To drink two teaspoonfuls of powdered charcoal in half a glass of water generally
                                gives instant relief. The above sovereign remedies may do in some but not in all cases.
                                A sovereign remedy for this ailment is not easily found. Sick headache is periodical,
                                and is the signal of distress which the stomach raises to<pb n="138" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 138 THE
                                SHAKEK MANIFESTO. inform us that there is an over-alkaline con. dition of its fluids;
                                that it needs a natural acid to restore the battery to its normal working condition.
                                When the first symptoms of a headache appear, take a teaspoonful of clear lemon juice
                                fifteen minutes before each meal and the same dose at bed_ time ; follow this up until
                                all symptoms are passed, taking no other remedies, and you will scon be able to go free
                                from your unwelcome nuisance. Many will object to this because the remedy is too simple,
                                but many cures have been effected in this way. —Boston Transcript.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A 'drop' is a variable quantity..." TEIform="index"/>A 'drop' is a variable quantity...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A " drop " is a variable quantity, although, many people never think about this fact The
                                Journal of Chemistry says that the larg. est drop is formed by syrup of gum-arabic, 44
                                to the dram, and the smallest by chloroform. 250 to the dram. As a general rule,
                                tinctures, fluid extracts and essential oils yield a drop less than one-half the size of
                                water, and acids and solutions give a drop but slightly smaller than water.</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tomato soup" TEIform="index"/>TOMATO SOUP</head><p TEIform="p">The following recipe for " tomato soup " is always timely, as canned tomatoes can be used
                                in place of those growing in season : . One pint of canned tomatoes or four large raw
                                ones, cut up fine. Add one quart of boiling water, and let them boil ten minutes, or
                                until done. Remove from the stove and stir in one teaspoonful of soda. While foaming add
                                one pint of sweet milk, salt and pepper and a small piece of butter. To be eaten hot
                                with crackers, like oyster soup, to which it is almost equal. m. g. r.</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to cook potatoes" TEIform="index"/>How to Cook Potatoes</head><p TEIform="p">.—There are two ways of boiling potatoes — both are good. The first fashion is to put
                                them into well salted cold water : having let them boil until they are nearly done, pour
                                off nearly all the water, set them back on the fire, cover, and let them steam until
                                thoroughly done. Take off the cover, and let them stay a moment or two to evaporate the
                                moisture. The other way is to drop the potatoes into enough boiling water to cover them,
                                and as soon as they are done pour off the water entirely and put back on the range to
                                evaporate the moisture ; put the cover on the ket tie so that about a quarter of the
                                mouth is left open to the air. When boiled in their skins a tiny piece should be cut
                                from the end of each potato. They must boil from thirty to thirty-five minutes. Always
                                select potatoes as nearly of a size as possibe. New potatoes, with delicate skins,
                                should not be pared for boiling. Take a sharp, thin knife and scrape off the skins. In
                                the country new potatoes, just brought in from the garden, do not even need scraping; a
                                few smart turns with a rough-textured cloth take off the" fine skin in a twinkling. But
                                the dwellers in towns don't get these ideal pota. toes. For perfect mashed potatoes,
                                pare and boil them as above, and after every trace of the water has evaporated, mash
                                them with your pestal still in the kettle over the fire; they are naught if not kept
                                hot. Get out every suggestion of a lump, and as you mash put in a generous qnantity of
                                fresh butter, and, if you have it, some cream — if not cream, enough milk to make the
                                potato rich and moist. Salt it to taste, and serve fresh and hot piled up and smoothed
                                over in a hot dish with a little black pepper sifted on top. Mashed potato which has
                                stood on the stove for a while before serving is poor stuff. If you want the top brown,
                                hold over it a salamander or a very hot stove lid — don't push the dish into the oven ;
                                that only makes the contents watery.—Exchange.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To make copygraph pad" TEIform="index"/>To Make Copygraph Pad</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Take gelatine, 1 oz; Glycerine, 6 1-4 fluid ounces (Cooper's gelatine, and
                                        pure concentrated glycerine, answer Avell). Soak the gelatine over night in cold
                                        water, and add the swelled gelatine to the glycerine, heated to about 200°
                                        Farenheit,over a salt-water bath. Continue the heating for several hours,to
                                        expel the water as much as possible. Then pour the clear solution into a shallow
                                        pan. or on a piece of cardboard, placed on a level table, and having its edge
                                        turned up about 1-8 or 1-4 of an inch all around, to retain the mixture, and let
                                        remain for six hours or more, protected from dust. To use it: Rub over the
                                        surface a sponge slightly moistened with water, and let it nearly dry before
                                        making the first transfer.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Boston journal of chemistry" TEIform="index"/>Boston Journal of Chemistry</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><pb n="139" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>FARM AND GARDEN</head><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Onions" TEIform="index"/>Onions</head><p TEIform="p">.— From our own experience and the observation of others, we can fully indorse the
                                testimony of the St. Louis Miller of the healthful properties of the above esculent.
                                Lung and liver complaints are certainly benefited, often cured, by a free consumption of
                                onions, either cooked or •raw. Colds yield to them like magic. Don't be afraid of them.
                                Taken at nighty all offense will be wanting by morning, and the good effects will amply,
                                compensate for the trifling annoyance. Taken regularly, they greatly promote the health
                                of the lungs and the digestive organs. An extract made by boiling down the juice of
                                onions to a syrup, and taken as a medicine, answers the purpose very well; but fried,
                                roasted or boiled onions are better. Onions are a very cheap medicine, within
                                everybody's reach; and they are not by any means as " bad to take " as the costly
                                nostrums a neglect of their use may necessitate.—Scientific American.</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Scratches or cracked heels in horses" TEIform="index"/>Scratches or Cracked Heels in
                                Horses</head><p TEIform="p"> .— A Canadian correspondent gives the following simple remedy for scratches in horses: "
                                Having tried many lotions, etc., only to obtain temporary relief for my horse, I
                                concluded to try a mixture of flour of sulphur and glycerine, which I mixed into a
                                paste, using sufficient glycerine to give it a glossy appearance; and the result I
                                obtained in a short time were truly wonderful. I apply this paste at night, and in the
                                morning before going out I apply plain glycerine."</p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sweet corn for fodder" TEIform="index"/>Sweet Corn for Fodder</head><p TEIform="p">.— Farmers all over the country are becoming convinced of the great value of sweet corn
                                for fodder, not only for use in summer, but, when cured, for winter. We have long used
                                it, and prefer it to the common field sorts, and think it better in every way. It is now
                                time to prepare for sowing corn in drills, as well as planting in hills, and it will
                                cost no more to raise sweet corn for seed another year than other sorts. All the farmer
                                needs is a few quarts of seed to start with, if he cannoi afford to purchase a larger
                                quantity. But sown corn of some kind should find a place on every farm because there is
                                seldom a season in which the pasture will not partially fail during a few weeks, if not
                                longer, and then the fodder corn comes in very opportunely as green food.</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shearing sheep" TEIform="index"/>Shearing Sheep</head><p TEIform="p">.—Early shearing is considered best by most flock masters, and the rule is to begin the
                                operation without delay as soon as the weather will permit. Sheep are usually relieved
                                of their coats by handshearing, tedious and hard work for both man and beast, but care
                                on the part of the operator greatly reduces the inconvenience and suffering to which the
                                animals are subjected afterward. It pays in every sense of the word to handle the sheep
                                carefully and to avoid slashing into flesh as well as wool. There are machines in the
                                market which cut the fleece evenly and shear about ten sheep per hour. Before shearing,
                                all dirt and straw should be removed from the sheen's feet, and any matted tags and
                                locks of wool that require washing, cut off. Shearing is sometimes done on a bench or
                                platform, but the usual plan is to set the sheep on the rump on a smooth, clean floor.
                                The wool is now sheared from its neck and fore-shoulders, then the animal is laid upon
                                one side and the upper side sheared, then turned over and the wool removed from the
                                other side. Good sharp shears are necessary to a rapid and perfect performance of the
                                work, and great care is required to shear the wool reasonably close without cutting the
                                skin. A good shearer does not make second cuts ; the fact that weol had been left by the
                                first cut is evidence that the shears were not properly held, and the wool removed by
                                the second cut is worthless. It therefore is to the farmer's interest that skillful
                                shearers be employed for this important work. When a sheep has received injury by
                                unavoidable cuts in shearing it is advised that tar be smeared over the injured places
                                to prevent flesh flies from depositing their eggs. The loss of their woolly coats is
                                seriously felt by sheep for the first few days, and then it is that many diseases are
                                incurred. At this critical period the animals ought to be <pb n="140" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 140 THE
                                SHAKER MANIFESTO. sheltered, not only during storms, but at night, until there has been
                                time for their systems to become adapted to the change and the weather is quite warm and
                                settled.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Voice of peace: extracts" TEIform="index"/>VOICE OF PEACE: Extracts</head><p TEIform="p"> A full estimate of the expenses, wastes of time, damages, derangement of business, and
                            actual losses during our four years' war would amount to twenty-five thousand millions
                            dollars. This sum, if divided among the inhabitants both North and South, would give five
                            hundred dollars to each person ! War reverses, with respect to its objects, all the
                            principles of morality. It is a temporary repeal of the claims of virtue, and includes
                            nearly all the vices. Napoleon allowed no chaplain in his army; and was accustomed to say,
                            the worse the man, the better the soldier ! The Duke of Wellington is reported to have said
                            •" '' Men of nice scruples about religion have no business in the army." A Secretary of War
                            in the United States once observed: "It will never do to give up the use of ardent spirits
                            in the army and navy, for no one enlists when they are sober."—{Peace Lecture, Zebulon P.
                            White.) War is a school of profanity. For soldiers to swear, is considered by some a mark of
                            gallantry. * * * The present armament of Europe numbers over ten millions of men ; the
                            manhood of the country, trained to arms, involving an expenditure of two thousand million
                            dollars yearly ; causing wholesale emigration from bondage ; conspiracies and
                            assassinations, which threaten the foundations of society. An army bill is before Congress,
                            recommending, among other improvements, that all schools and colleges having one hundred and
                            fifty boys may call on the War Department, and shall be furnished with educated officers of
                            the regular army, to drill the boys in the art of war !</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Choice selections: causes of war" TEIform="index"/>CHOICE SELECTIONS: Causes of War</head><p TEIform="p">A certain king sent to another king saying : " Send me a blue pig with a black tail or else
                            —." The other replied, " I have not got one, and if I had "— On this weighty cause they went
                            to war. After they had exhausted their armies and resources, and laid waste their kingdoms,
                            they began to wish to make peace; but before this could be done it was necessary that the
                            insulting language that led to the trouble should be explained. " What could you mean ? "
                            asked the second king of the first by saying " send me a blue pig with a black tail, or
                            else"—? " Why," said the other, " I meant a blue color." " But what could you mean by
                            saying, ' I have not got one, and if I had "— ? " Why, of course if I had I should have sent
                            it." The explanation was satisfactory, and the peace was accordingly concluded. The story of
                            the two kings ought to serve as. a lesson to us all. Most of the quarrels between
                            individuals are quite as foolish as the war of the blue pig with a black tail.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fear not" TEIform="index"/>Fear Not</head><p TEIform="p">.— There is nothing like being stout-hearted in the midst of difficulties Some men give up at
                            the slightest opposition, while others become grandly enraged by opposition, and wrest the
                            victory from unwilling fortune. " If I have lost the rings, here are the fingers still,"
                            said the bold Spaniard, and into the fray he went again.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="An honest opinion is oftenest given when the speaker is a bit angry..." TEIform="index"/>An honest opinion is oftenest given when the speaker is a bit angry...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">An honest opinion is oftenest given when the speaker is a bit angry. In your placid mood it
                            may be a little difficult to say a disagreeable thing, but when you are suddenly roused by a
                            piece of impertinence the disagreeable thing jerks itself out and is said before you know
                            it. That was a very pointed and possibly a very wholesome bit of sarcasm when a gentleman
                            turned suddenly on a coxcomb who had been making himself offensive, and said : " Sir, you
                            ought to be the happiest man in the world ; you are in love with yourself, and you have no
                            rival."</p></div2><pb n="141" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Skein we wind" TEIform="index"/>THE SKEIN WE WIND.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Klingle, George" TEIform="persName"/>GEORGE KLINGLE.
                        </byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">If you and I, to-day Should stop and lay Our
                                    life-work down, and let our hands fall where they will— Pall down to lie quite
                                    still— And if some other hand should come, and stoop to find The threads we carried,
                                    so that it could wind, Beginning where we stopped; if it should come to keep Our
                                    life-work going; seek To carry on the good design Distinctively made yours, or mine,
                                    What would we find ? Some work we must be doing, true or false; Some threads we
                                    wind; some purpose so exalts Itself that we look up to it, or down, As to a crown To
                                    bow before, and we weave threads Of different lengths and thickness—some mere
                                    shreds— And wind them round Till all the skein of life is bound, Sometimes
                                    forgetting at the task To ask The value of the threads, or choose Strong stuff to
                                    use. No hand but winds some thread; It cannot stand quite still till it is dead, But
                                    what it spins and winds a little skein God made each hand for work—not toil stain Is
                                    required, but every hand Spins, though but ropes of sand. If Love should come,
                                    Stooping above when we are done, To find bright threads That we have held, that it
                                    may spin them longer—find but shreds That break when touched, how cold, Sad,
                                    shivering, portionless, the hands will hold The broken strands and know Fresh cause
                                    for woe.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Christian union" TEIform="index"/>Christian Union.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Solid words" TEIform="index"/>Solid words
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">SOLID WORDS. Ignorance is the mother of all evils. Common sense is not a common
                                    thing. Constancy in mistakes is constant folly. A good character shines by its own
                                    light. No man can be wise on an empty stomach. Nothing is so good as it seems
                                    beforehand. He who has lost his honor can lose nothing more. Love dies of disgust
                                    and is buried by oblivion. One ungrateful man injures all that are in distress.
                                    Politeness is the expression or imitation of social virtues. No conflict is so
                                    severe as his who labors to subdue himself. In love there are no treaties of peace;
                                    there are only truces. A grand safeguard for doing right is to hate all that is
                                    wrong. In the world there are so few voices and so many echoes. True merit is like a
                                    river — the deeper it is the less noise it makes. Favors of every kind are doubted
                                    when they are speedily conferred.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Philadelphia republic" TEIform="index"/>Philadelphia Republic.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Woman's song to woman" TEIform="index"/>A WOMAN'S SONG TO WOMAN</head><p TEIform="p">Pull the needle, swing the broom, Tidy up the littered room, Patch the trousers, darn the
                            shirt, Fight the daily dust and dirt; All around you trust your skill, Confident of kindness
                            still. Stir the gruel, knead the bread ; Tax your hands, and heart, and head Children sick
                            and household hungry; (Though some thoughtless words stung you), All are waiting on your
                            will, Confident of kindness still. Never mind the glance oblique, Never cause of coldness
                            seek, Never notice slight or frown, By your conduct live them down ; All at last will seek
                            your skill, Confident of kindness still. Lift your heart and lift your eyes, Let continual
                            prayer arise ; Think of all the Saviour's wo When he walked with man below, How poor sinners
                            sought his skill, Confident of kindness still. Sing the song and tell the story Of the
                            Saviour's coining glory, To the children whom He blesses With your guidance and caresses,
                            Who for all things wait your will Confident of kindness still. have <pb n="142" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/>
                            142 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. Feed the hungry and the weak, Words of cheer and comfort speak, Be
                            the angel of the poor, Teach them bravely to endure, Show them this, the Fathor's will,
                            Confident of kindness still. Gratitude may be your lot, Then be thankful; but if not, Are
                            you better than your Lord Who endured the cross and sword From those very hands whose skill
                            Waited ever on His will ? Noble is a life of care If a holy zeal be there ; All your little
                            deeds of love Heavenward helps at last may prove, If you seek your Father's will, Trusting
                            in His kindness still.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Genus homo" TEIform="index"/>THE GENUS HOMO</head><p TEIform="p">The average weight of an adult man is 140 pounds 6 ounces. The average weight of a skeleton
                            is 14 pounds. The number of bones, 200. The skeleton measures one inch less than the height
                            of the living man. The average weight of the brain of a man is 3% pounds ; of a woman, 2
                            pounds 11 ounces. The brain of a man exceeds twice that of any other animal. The average
                            height of an Englishman is 5 feet 9 inches ; of a Frenchman, 5 feet 4 inches, and of a
                            Belgian, 5 feet 6f inches. The average weight of an Englishman is 150 pounds ; of a
                            Frenchman, 136 pounds, and of a Belgian, 140 pounds. The average number of teeth is 31. A
                            man breathes about 20 times in a minute, or 1,200 times in an hour. A man breathes about
                            eighteen pints of air in a minute, or upwards of seven hogsheads in a day. A man gives about
                            4.08 per cent carbonic gas of the air he respires; respires 10,666 cubic feet of carbonic
                            acid gas in 24 hours ; consumes 10,667 cubic feet of oxygen in 24 hours, equal to 125 cubic
                            inches of common air. A man annually contributes to vegetation 124 pounds of carbon. The
                            average of the pulse in infancy is 120 per minute; in manhood, 80 ; at sixty years, 60. The
                            pulse of females is more frequent than that of males. The weight of the circulating blood is
                            about 28 pounds. The heart beats 75 times in a minute ; sends nearly 10 pounds of blood
                            through the veins and arteries each beat ; makes four beats while we breathe once. 540
                            pounds, orl hogshead 11-4 pints, of blood pass through the heart in one hour. 12,000 pounds,
                            or 24 hogsheads 4 gallons, or 10,782 1-2 pints, pass through the heart in 24 hours. 1,000
                            ounces of blood pass through the kidneys in one hour. 174,000,000 holes or cells are in the
                            lungs, which would cover a surface thirty times greater than the human body.—Journal of
                            Health.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Keeping the head clean" TEIform="index"/>KEEPING THE HEAD CLEAN</head><p TEIform="p">A distinguished physician, who had spent much time at quarantine, said that a person whose
                            head was thoroughly washed every day, rarely took contagious disease ; but where the hair
                            was allowed to become dirty and matted, it was hardly possible to escape infection. Many
                            persons find speedy relief for nervous headache by washing the hair thoroughly in warm
                            water. I have known severe cases almost wholly cured in ten minutes by this simple remedy. A
                            friend finds it the greatest relief in cases of " rare cold," the cold symptoms entirely
                            leaving the eyes and nose after one thorough washing of the hair. The head should be
                            thoroughly dried afterward, and not exposed to draughts of air for a little while.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Isms" TEIform="index"/>"I S M S"</head><p TEIform="p">Isms, like arsenic, are good in their place, but an " ism "is as poor a substitute for
                            religion as arsenic is for bread. We have nothing to say against a man's showing a strong
                            love for the church of his choice ; we have no fault to find if he regularly attends his own
                            church and is tremendously energetic in his efforts to increase her efficiency, <pb n="143" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 143 yet we would rather a man would not work for his
                            church or for the church, but for a church of Christ. Here is a distinction that ought not
                            to be overlooked. There is a difference between religious and selfish, or sectarian zeal.
                            Many an earnest worker for his church has very little leve for the Master's cause or for the
                            souls of men. The most charitable words that can be spoken to religious bigots are those
                            which Christ addressed to his disciples when they desired to call down fire from heaven and
                            burn up the inhospitable Samaritans : " Ye know not what manner of spirit ye are of."
                            Christ's love reached out to the whole world. His religion was for all nations and classes.
                            He preached no " ism," but the universal fatherhood of God to man and sonhood of man to God.
                            He called all Christians " brethren of one master." Any spirit not in harmony with the
                            spirit of Christ's teachings, can not be of God, and such a spirit will be sure to bear
                            bitter fruit.—Church Mirror,</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Way to health" TEIform="index"/>THE WAY TO HEALTH</head><p TEIform="p">The only true way to health is that which common sense dictates to man. Live within the
                            bounds of reason. Eat moderately, drink temperately, sleep regularly, avoid excess in
                            anything, and preserve a conscience " void of offense." Some men eat themselves to death,
                            some drink themselves to death, some wear out their lives by indolence, and some by
                            over-exertion ; others are killed by the doctors, while not a few sink into the grave under
                            the effects of vicious and beastly practices. All the medicines in creation are not worth a
                            farthing to a man who is constantly and habitually violating the laws of his own nature. All
                            the medical science in the world cannot save him from a preihatui'e grave. With a suicidal
                            course of conduct, he is planting the seed of decay in his own constitution, and
                            accelerating the destruction of his own life.—Scientific American.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I look upon indolence as a sort of suicide..." TEIform="index"/>I look upon indolence as a sort of suicide...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">I look upon indolence as a sort of suicide, for the man is effectually destroyed, though the
                            appetite of the brute may survive.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Chesterfield" TEIform="persName"/>Chesterfield</byline></div2><div2 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A hog, an abomination to a Mohammedan, walked into the open door of a mosque one day..." TEIform="index"/>A hog, an abomination to a Mohammedan, walked into the open door of a mosque one day...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A hog, an abomination to a Mohammedan, walked into the open door of a mosque one day, and ran
                            all about the building before he could be driven out. The temple was horribly defiled to the
                            minds of the faithful. What could be done 1 The priest explained that the mosque was so holy
                            that the hog became a lamb all the time he was in, but a hog again when he went out. This
                            theory satisfied all. Those priests are about as ingenious as some of our modern preachers,
                            who think the lottery business is all right in a church house, but a terrible sin in any
                            other house.</p></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good advice is given Congress by the Philadelphia Times..." TEIform="index"/>Good advice is given Congress by the Philadelphia Times...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Good advice is given Congress by the Philadelphia Times, which says the members had better
                            pray during the session and thus save the country much trouble. Most of them probably know
                            as little of prayer as of national matters, and it would be necessary to appoint a clergyman
                            speaker to keep them in order. It is said that Ben Hill bet Alexander Stephens five dollars
                            the latter could not say the Lord's prayer. When Stephens took the bet and began, " Now I
                            lay me down to sleep," Hill said, "Here's your money Stephens, I've lost.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="All dead" TEIform="index"/>All Dead</head><p TEIform="p">.—Have you ever read '' The Ancient Mariner !" I dare say you thought it one of the strangest
                            imaginations ever put together. Dead men pulling the rope, dead men steering. But do you
                            know I have lived to see that time, to have seen it done ? I have gone in to churches, and
                            have seen a dead man in the pulpit, a dead man as deacon, a dead man handling the plate, and
                            dead men sitting to hear.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Suggestively true" TEIform="index"/>Suggestively True</head><p TEIform="p">. — A Northern minister was introduced to a colored minister, and inquired after his work.- "
                            I preach, sah, on Colonel Gordon's plantation." " How many colored people have you there V"
                            "Well, sah, 'bout a hundred and seventyfive." " And how many have you in church ?" " Dat
                            'pends, sah, altogether on de time ob year. In de vival time dey's all members; in de
                            backsliden times, dere's nobody members but Uncle Billy and old Aunt Katy."</p></div2><pb n="144" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gentle deeds" TEIform="index"/>GENTLE DEEDS</head><p TEIform="p">Words Mt. Lebanon,N. Y. Music Selected. 1. Gentle deeds are ever forming 2. It is ours to be
                            progressing, 3. O, it is a blessed haven, Verdant spots within each heart; And to toil with
                            ardent thought, Where no blighted powers remain; -#- ¦#-¦$*¦• Whence shall spring the plants
                            of virtue, Flow'rs that incense sweet impart; That our lives may merit blessing, And with
                            holiness be fraught. Where unholy strife is banished, And pure love our souls enchain. Such
                            shall waken thot's most holy; Morn shall hope with new desires; Here in union we are leaving
                            Bring to life some germ of love; Evening shall their strength increase; All the glit'ring
                            dust of earth; Cause aspirings true and lasting, While the angels find our spirits Seeking
                            only the imniortal, For the powers that lift above. Resting in the realms of peace. Which
                            will give us angel birth. </p></div2><pb id="p29" TEIform="pb"/><!--                     <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>