<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2909" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">20</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">East Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">29</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">9</biblScope><date value="18990901" TEIform="date">September 1899</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">129-144</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="29" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="9" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
THE
MANIFESTO
Price, 50 cts.
Sketches of Shakers and Shakerism. A synopsis of the United Society of Believers in Christ's Second
Appearing. Illustrated. By Giles
B. Avert.    Price 15 cts.
BRIEF EXPOSITION
or the
Principles and Regulations
of the
SOCIETY   OF  BELIEVERS.
Price, 10 cts.
THE ALTRUIST.
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is publisht by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all their
property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. It now has 5,000
acres of land in Southeast Missouri on
which it offers a home and employment
for life to all acceptable persons who may
wish to join it.            50  cents a year;
specimen copy free.    Address A. Longley, 2819 Olive St. St. Louis, Mo.
SEPTEMBER,    1899.
WONDERFUL strange REVELATIONS,
EXPLAINING
DANIEL'S & STJOHN'S
PROPHECIES.
48 page pamphlet.    Price 10 cts.
13 for $1.00.
Address,   H. B. Beak, Preston, Ohio.
A SUMMARY VIEW
OF THE
MILLENNIAL,   CHURCH,
OB
"United   Society   of  Believers"
It treats of the Bise and Progress of the
Society, together with the general Principles of the Faith and Testimony.
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
Prank Leslie's Popular Monthly for
August is a grand Midsummer Art and Fiction Number.   It is brilliant and entertaining
in its literary contents, and sumptuous pictorially, as may be judged from the fact that
among its writers are included; W. D. Howells, Ruth McEnery Stuart, Joel Chandler
Harris, Egerton Castle, Van Tassel Sutphen,
Edgar Fawcett, Etta W. Pierce, C. F. Carter,
Theodosia Pickering Garrison, Perriton Maxwell, Larkin G. Mead, Eben E. Rexford and
R. K. Munkittrick; these illustrated by such
well known artists as Albert B. Wenzell,
Howard Chandler Christy, F. Luis Mora, W.
Granville Smith, F. Hopkinson Smith, Hugh
M. Eaton, Clifford Carleton, Charles Grunwald, H. C. Edwards, Frank Adams and Geo.
R. Brill.   Moreover, the single article upon
Weddings in Art is illustrated with sixteen
beautiful reproductions of paintings by celebrated European and American masters, including Teniers, Erdmann, Vautier, Rief sthal,
Hovenden, Moran, Turner, Leighton, Mosler
and Luke Fildes.   William Dean Howells
gives, in quaint and delightful verse, the gastronomical observations of one of our fellowcountrymen at Carlsband, who declaims,
"Breakfast is my best meal!"   Joel Chandler
Harris contributes one of his inimitable Minervy Ann stories; while Ruth McEnery Stuart's
Queen o' Sheba's Triumph, is destined to rank
among her masterpieces.   Van Tassel Sutphen shows, in a wonderful imaginative work
of fiction, entitled The Greatest Thing in the
World; how this country is rapidly becoming
golflcized.   Edgar Fawcett spins a weird yarn.'
The Lid of the Chest.   Etta W. Pierce's Miss
Angel is more cheerful.   Larkin G. Mead
writes a crisp little newspaper storyette,
called Human Interest.   A Day of the President's Life; by Mrs. John A. Logan, is no fiction, but highly interesting actuality.   The
midsummer cover, in colors, is by Wenzell.
This number will surely rank "Frank Leslie's" as the monarch of the 10 cent magazines.
British Honduras was originally a portion
of Guatemala.   In the days of piracy in the
Caribbean Sea, English pirates used to run into the harbor of Balize for safety.   They soon
founded a small settlement there, without
any right or warrant.   The few natives were
either annihilated or driven away.   Other
English and Scotch adventurers soon joined
the pirates and British commanders either
connived at or aided them in their opposition
first to Spain and then to the Republic of
Guatemala.   For two centuries England tried
every means diplomatic and military to secure a legal status for Balize.   At first she
was satisfied at obtaining the right of protection for so-called British subjects, in reality
pirates.   She always had cunning enough to
insert the deceptive clause "Saving the authority of Spain over the country."   This
claim grew stronger till in 1862, during the
War of the Rebellion, when England, took advantage of our troubled state of affairs and
no longer feared the waning power of Spain,
declared Honduras a free British colony.   The
way for this steal had been prepared by Mr.
Clayton, the American commissioner for the
Clayton-Bulwer Treaty, in which, among other things, the concession of a participation in
the Nicaraugua Canal was granted to England
and also the promise of the United States not
to include British Honduras in any farther
negotiations in regard to the Central American Republics.   Never did man yield more
easily what every true American, who loved
the integrity of the Continent, should have
refused.   Where was the Monroe Doctrine at
this time?   Where the readiness to repel all
foreign pretentions which is so pronounced
in our own day?Donahoe's for August.
The Corruptions of the New Testament by
H. L. Hastings.   This little pamphlet of ninety-four pages is one among the many books
that should be read for the information it
contains.   Bible readers will accept it with
pleasure.   It was written with careful thought
and in language that bears so uncertain deflinition.   It is also from the pen of one whose
name is so familiarly known in the literature
of good books, that we accept it without question.   We follow the author; "Everything
which passes through human hands is liable
to be altered, corrupted and vitiated, and sacred books form no exception to this rule.
The integrity of a book may be impaired every time it is copied.   In copying any writing
bad men might make alterations, careless
men might make mistakes, and good men
might seek to change and improve the things
which they were copying, and so, in one way
or another, the integrity of the document
might be seriously impaired.   This no intelligent person can deny."   Pub. by H. L. Hastings, 47 Cornhill, Boston, Mass.
The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy for July.
Dr. Gifford has an article on the "Science of
Life," which renders valuable information
for those who read to be better informed.
Practical instructions on the seience of life
that all may read and be able to understand
becomes a treasure of inestimable value.
Home Breweries touches a tender spot in the
minds of all temperance people.   Many a
hard word has been thrown at Deacon Gile's
distillery by the would be zealous lecturer and
yet he may have at the same time been innocently and ignorantly generating alchohol in
his own home.   Pub. by Dr. T. V. Gifford &
Co., Kokomo, Ind.
Are Protestants, Catholics? by Rev. R.
O. Kennedy.   This is a small pamphlet of
some twenty-two pages and written very
pleasantly in the interest of those who would
be saved.   Pub. at Notre Dame, Ind. Price 5
cents.--><pb n="129" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Search the scriptures--Jno. v., 39" TEIform="index"/>SEARCH THE SCRIPTURES-Jno. v., 39.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>By Elder Henry C. Blinn.</byline><p TEIform="p">THE searching of the Scriptures is always new and interesting. It is like the storehouse of
                            precious treasures,the eye never tires with seeing, nor the ear with hearing. Those who have
                            not grown to appreciate the study of the wonderful Book, will be more or less like those,
                            who having eyes, see not-the many beautiful things which God places before them. We should
                            study the Scriptures that we may be the better able to understand what the best inspiration
                            of all ages has instructed men to do in the work of practical righteousness. It is the duty
                            of a Christian to learn. It is also the duty of those who stand independent of the churches,
                            and of their multiplied theologies, to learn how they may become better men and women. When
                            St. Paul advised his brethren concerning the Sabbath day, and closed his remarks so
                            liberally by saying, "Let every man be fully persuaded in his own mind," and whether he keep
                            Friday, Saturday or Sunday as a day of religious devotion, let him keep the day to the glory
                            of God. So in reference to the study of the Scriptures. Let every man be fully persuaded in
                            his own mind that he understands them and obeys them with a good and honest heart. The
                            Christian church in its most extended sense is comparatively a limited order, and largely
                            amalgamated with that quality which we are pleased to denominate the spirit of the world. It
                            is greatly to our advantage and to the advantage of every progressive miud that the
                            influence of disintegration has <pb n="130" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 130 ' THE MANIFESTO. wrought so
                            effectually. It brought light into many dark places, and allowed an independence of thought
                            which must be exercised by all rational beings. When there is life, there must be more or
                            less growth of mind. If with this comes the practical righteousness which was taught by the
                            mission of the Christ, it will largely assist in making the kingdoms of this world, the
                            kingdoms of our Lord. The Reformation allowed men to think and act, as they never thought
                            and acted before, and this reformation still goes on dividing and subdividing the churches
                            and scattering the endless systems of theology to the four winds of heaven. Man has now but
                            little need of them. So also the war of the Revolution, while it brought to us, on every
                            hand, the painful record of sorrow, it also brought to us the independence of the country,
                            the independence of thought and measurably that freedom of soul with which God loves to
                            bless his children. Our government recognizes no church, but gave to all the one great
                            blessing of religious liberty. From this date, in the United States, a man for the first
                            time, in the world's history, was permitted to think for himself and to choose the road by
                            which he through anticipation, might reach the city of the New Jerusalem. Do you suppose
                            that a less number reach the kingdom of God, to-day in their freedom of thought and action,
                            in their denunciations of churchal dogmas and soulless theological traditions, than were
                            privileged to pass through the celestial gate in the days of Coustantine ? God's light comes
                            for the purpose of making men better, and it comes through the Godlike intelligence which
                            rules the minds of men and women. To say that St. Paul was very shrew'd and cautious and had
                            a great point to gain, when on his mission to the church at Jerusalem, does not speak very
                            highly for the plenary inspiration of the Scriptures. St. Paul was not Jesus and therefore
                            is not our especial guide. As we search the Scriptures for a closer walk with God, wre are
                            especially drawn to the sayings of Jesus, aud these are used wTith an emphasis w^hich is
                            unmistakable, because we have chosen to be as he was, separated from the world. Jesus gives
                            us to understand that he was not of that order and if any man would become his disciple he
                            must deny himself and take up his cross and follow himaway from the world. The Revelator
                            writes that we must be harvested from the vine of the earth, and this most assuredly
                            separates us from the world and from all the relations which grow out of that order. If the
                            mission of Jesus was for the introduction of a new and spiritual life, as all Christians
                            admit, then as certainly it forewarns us of the decline and death of the state in which we
                            had formerly lived, and brings us into a resurrection order where all things are to become
                            new. Instead of wars which have been the delight of man since the daj7s of Cain, we are to
                            have peace. Instead of evil imaginations and unrighteousness as in the days before the flood
                                <pb n="131" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 131 we are commanded to purify the heart and to be
                            crucified to the elements of the world. Whosoever believes and lives in the resurrection
                            testimony of the Lord Jesus Christ can never die, for his work is eternal life. So different
                            is this from the children of this world, who follow the pleasures jf time, that St. Paul
                            tells us, they are dead, dead in their trespasses against light, even while their bodies are
                            alive. The apostle's advice to try the spirits, means as well to prove the lives of
                            religionists by the doctrines which they preach. Advocates of peace principles are crying
                            out against the Avarlike spirit of the age and then work with a corresponding zeal to
                            inflame the passions of man. to rush to the battle field, and destroy the lives of each
                            other. The Christian prays as earnestly to God for victory over his enemies, as he prays for
                            bread in time of famine. To denounce war as sin and then pray for victory to pass from city
                            to city is praying that sin may abound. This knowledge comes through God's light to man and
                            such a light as John Calvin, Martin Luther, and Roger Williams never saw. It is the pleasure
                            and indeed, the duty of the Shaker Church, so far as they have learned the operation of the
                            spirit of truth, to zealously exalt the Lord their God. This is manifested by accepting the
                            revelation of light which leads us from ignorance and from selfishness to the blessing of an
                            honorable life and of universal love. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="He passed by on the other side" TEIform="index"/>"HE PASSED BY ON THE OTHER SIDE."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wilson, Sarah F." TEIform="persName"/>Bead before the Church at Northfield, N. H., Sunday,
                            June 4, 1S99. By Sarah F. Wilson.</byline><p TEIform="p">TTTE have often read the touching narrative of the man who fell among VV thieves and was
                            severely wounded while on his journey from Jerusalem to Jericho; of the Priest and Levite
                            who passed that way, and seeing his need}' condition very cautiously "passed by on the other
                            side." Next came the good Samaritan, who tenderly bent over the injured man, providing most
                            generously for his needs. We may be more familiar with the incidents of the parable than
                            with the Priest and Levite conditions in our own lives, as well as the good Samaritan
                            qualities. Let us learn which of the illustrations will most closely fit our conduct. The
                            Priest and Levite represented special classes serving as ministers to the people, held in
                            their estimation nearer to God than any other order. That they had been the chosen
                            instruments from the early history of God's people, seemed to have no weight with them at
                            the critical moment when a practical service was needed; there was no ritual or ceremonial
                            ob- <pb n="132" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 132 THE MANIFESTO servance that required the Piiest or Levite to
                            pause and care for the wounded and dying man. They were, perhaps, hastening to Jerusalem to
                            offer sacrifice unto God in the Temple. Sacrifice in the Temple! There are temples of God's
                            construction, whose temples we are; yea, the temples of our bodies which should be so fully
                            dedicated to his service that all our faculties will be employed in benefactions toward our
                            fellow-man. In this service we recognize, not only the Fatherhood above us, but the
                            brotherhood arouud us. It is not our province, however, to condemn the Priest and Levite of
                            the past; their ears had never heard the blessed sound of the Christ message, "Inasmuch as
                            ye have done it unto one of the least of these, my brethren, ye have done it unto me,"
                            neither had they learned the truth, "If ye love not your brother whom ye have seen, how can
                            ye love God, whom ye have not seen?" Their example is quite unlike that of some of our
                            devoted ministers and missionaries of to-day. The Rev. Charles Sheldon gives an ideal
                            picture in one of his books, (but one that we hope may be verified) of a minister of the
                            gospel, living in an aristocratic part of the city, moving from his gorgeously fitted parish
                            in a wealthy locality, to dwell in a humbler position nearer the more needy population,
                            wiiose homes were in the tenement houses, that he might work among the non-church-going
                            classes. What was the result of* this step? He was dismissed from the Church by the vote of
                            its wealthy members ! Had he "passed by on the other side," hardening his heart to the
                            crying needs of the common people, what would have been his reward? An extended popularity
                            and support in a luxurious parish while ministering to a class of people upon whom Jesus
                            Christ would have pronounced the sentence, "Woe unto you that are rich, for ye have received
                            your consolation." He would have missed that sweet reward from the Father which came to him
                            in the assurance that he was reaching and saving those who most felt the need of a good
                            Physician. Thus, to pass on the side where there is more regard for popularity than right
                            principle is always taking the unchristian side, whether in Church work, in business, or in
                            political life. The question arises,Why do we so often "pass by on the other side?" Is it
                            not to avoid the self-sacrifice that is required should we press unflinchingly forward in
                            the path of duty ? But rendering the service of our lives merely from a sense of duty is
                            synonomous to morality, alone. Did the good Samaritan act merely from a sense of duty or for
                            human approval? The sympathy and love of his heart was touched and moved in compassion and
                            piactical helpfulness. No other element than the true love of God can be applied to his
                            far-reaching kindness. A life prompted merely by even the honorable obligation of
                            faithfulness in duty will never constitute us the true disciples of Jesus Christ. "Duty is
                            morality but Love is religion." The Samaritan, although from an idolatrous nation had more
                            of the gospel of love in his soul, than could be found in all the documents of the law. <pb n="133" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 133 Was Jesus Christ ever known to "pass by on the
                            olher side" when the lame, the halt, the blind, or even the leper sought his aid? The pages
                            of sacred history are not once stained with such a betrayal of selfishness. Thus we have a
                            perfect example, as a living reality to follow ; not an ideal picture, an artistic sketch,
                            or a work of the imagination. Do we "pass by on the other side" only when in connection with
                            others? Ah, nay; we have an inner life. A new connection dawns upon our thought. Shall we
                            obey it? That obrdience involves the sacrifice of some idol we have long cherished ; some
                            mammon god we have worshiped. We can not sacrifice it, we argue, it would be hardly
                            reasonable. Oh this harmful compromise ! It leads us to "pass by on the other bide." What
                            would we not gain by obedience to that conviction. "-Nearer my God to Thee, e'en though it
                            be a cross that ruiseth me." A nearness to God we should gain by bearing that cross, but
                            compromise with conscience, the voice of God, leads to the other side. Again, how many
                            opportunities we pass by, conscious of the pressing need of that very work being
                            accomplished, yet we deceive and persuade ourselves that we are not qualified for that
                            particular mission, thus we pass by on the other side. How much talent we find reserved for
                            personal, selfish enjoyment which, if laid out broadly either in home life or in community
                            work would better, not only the conditions around us, but would widen and brighten the
                            horizon of our own lives ! The opening for service comes to us all in different ways, not
                            only according to our various conceptions of right, and willingness of heart, bit kindly
                            adapted to our different stations in life. At some time in our lives, we may, in our
                            Christian zeal, long to do some more important work for Christ than that which has engaged
                            our hands aud heart. They are rather commonplace needs, we think, and we have met them so
                            frequently that our minds have become hardened to their existence, therefore we look beyond
                            for our Christian work. If the beyond should come to us, it would find us unfitted for the
                            work, not having grown the ability for greater things, by faithfulness in the grains of
                            life,the very service we have overlooked. There is one great reason why so many pass by on
                            the side other than that of the immediate call of the spirit. There is a plank of excuse
                            put? down, and it bears us safely over, but we find ourselves on unhallowed ground. Is this
                            not always a plank of selfish interest? The difficulties experienced by the rich young
                            Ruler, is the same to-day. An excuse was in his heart if not on his lips before the great
                            sacrifice to be made of all his wealth; hence, with all his goodness under the law, like the
                            Priest and Levite, he passed by on the other side of the direct and unmistakable call of the
                            Christ. Spiritual aspiration dies, aud is often buried under the superabundance of wealth.
                            The luxurious life, the selfish pleasure-seeking life can have no part in the Christ life.
                            The good Samaritan is much needed in the earth today, represented by Christian men and women
                            who will rescue those who are <pb n="134" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 134 THE MANIFESTO. falling among
                            thieves. Aye ! many of the pure and innocent are daily falling among thieves,who rob them of
                            honor and virtue leaving them homeless, heartless, courageless, before the struggle of life.
                            May the authority of Christ become so potent in our country that these moral thieves and
                            robbers may be arrested before the evil is perpetrated, and thus not only morality but true,
                            royal and loyal Christianity be preserved in our hearts, our homes, and in our community at
                            large. Let us no longer pass by on the other side of the field of "present opportunity" that
                            opens so liberally before us in service for the Master, but with the Quaker poet let us
                            remember that we "may not pass this way again; therefore if there is any "good thing I may
                            do, let me do it Now." East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Farewell to elder Benjamin H. Smith" TEIform="index"/>A Farewell to Elder BENJAMIN H.
                            SMITH.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wilson, Josephine E." TEIform="persName"/>By Josephine E. Wilson.</byline><p TEIform="p">HOW reluctantly the word of parting is framed by the lips even to dear ones who are about to
                            leave us for a few weeks or months, only, of absence. The hope of reunion remains with us,
                            lightens our daily task, and brightens the darkest hour of life. "They will return !" Even
                            after years of separation, we speak happily of the "coming home." But ah! how different
                            "when the last farewelHs spoken; severed the last, tender tie," then the law is irrevocable;
                            the}7 have crossed the bourne whence no traveler ever returns. Gradually, day by day, the
                            verity grows upon us. We find ourselves unconsciously planning for "when they return." We
                            knew so well the little human things which formed a part of the earth life! We knew so well
                            the richness of their experience, and unwittingly we say, "when they return" all this will
                            be renewed. It takes time, to realize that the voice of a loved one is forever hushed to the
                            household, that "Nevermore" on this side shall we hear the step or meet the glance always so
                            welcome; but all this comes,ah, but too surely. Elder Benjamin has joined the invisible
                            "brotherhood of souls." "His reward is with him and his works do follow him." The memory of
                            these loving works will ever follow us, for who was so kind to respond to the many calls of
                            his large "household of Faith?" Who so conscientious that all his handiwork should keep
                            close to the perfect pattern of the Master Workman, who drew his affections in early days.
                            "Elder Benjamin is a good man." These simple words fell as a benediction from the lips of
                            our sainted mother, Eldress Dorothy, during one of her last conscious moments. It is
                            pleasant at this parting hour to repeat them, though in her memory they were enshrined in an
                            acquaintance of a life-time. During the last months of feebleness it has been ours to
                            minister, rather than to be ministered unto, and as <pb n="135" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 135
                            we realize, to-day, that the round of life and daily service has really closed for the
                            present, the "Augel of the Heart" whispers, "We know not when the dear ones will leave us.
                            Let each day, then, bear the fulness of Christian service, that the sunset of life may fade
                            upon no regrets." The good father has been gathered to "his own" among the "conquerors of
                            Time." They draw our hearts after them into the "Beyond," but our footsteps linger still
                            longer upon the strands of earth, while memory holds sacred the good life, the full measure,
                            the kind brotherhood, the useful manhood that has so gently been drawn away from us into the
                            holier sphere. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Divine overshadowing" TEIform="index"/>THE DIVINE OVERSHADOWING.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="DeGraw, Hamilton" TEIform="persName"/>By Hamilton DeGraw.</byline><p TEIform="p">IN all the systems of life that have in any measure evoluted out of the gross materialism
                            which was the result or reflection of man's unspiritualized condition as he existed in the
                            ages before the quickening of the spiritual forces, which even then, in that lowly estate,
                            existed in embryo ready for the breath of life which, when breathed into his spirit, made
                            him a living soul. In all those methods of expressing life there runs like threads of gold
                            through every fibre of human existence the recognition of a power not foreign to the human
                            finite existence. It is of a superiority far trauscending the human, and at times
                            manifesting itself in a way that to his undeveloped soul is classified as marvelous. While
                            not comprehending the law through which those forces are being made manifest, it has
                            appeared at times as if they had been set aside or revoked so as to exhibit to his unfolded
                            mind that which seems a miracle. This being the result of his ignorance, will be remedied
                            through the expansion of the soul, and knowledge of the fact that miracles do not exist;
                            that whatever transpires in the material or spiritual realm is guided by a law that is
                            immutable. Tracing human life through the ramifications of its complex existence, back to
                            the dawn of human history, and following it even into the realms which eventually merge
                            themselves into the prehistoric, this one supreme, central idea of universal acceptance,a
                            belief in a divine, overshadowing Presence, proves that it is the normal condition of the
                            soul to recognize that there exists a superhuman power; and a rejection by individual
                            entities of that fact is proof that such human minds are not in accord with the truth. A
                            reverence for an intelligent acceptance of the truth of the existence of that infinite
                            Presence, when it is based upon the evidence given through the highest medium for
                            transmitting ideas,the intuitive faculty, whose perceptions of and decisions in regard to
                            the right or wrong of a theory are not based upon the intellect alone, but when under the
                            control of the spiritual <pb n="136" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 136 THE MANIFESTO. faculties can be used as
                            a powerful auxiliary for good, and when thus controlled can be relied upon, for from their
                            position in the divine plan they are superior to all others; it biing intended to have them
                            more in harmony by recognizing all others as secondary conditions, controlled by the
                            ever-present spirit. An unquestioning, unreasoning compliance with the fossilized dogmas of
                            sectarianism, is not being spiritually-minded. Their paths do not run parallel nor converge.
                            The more enlightened the soul becomes by a study and obedience to those laws which in their
                            operation lead "from nature up to nature's God," the stronger the internal evidence is that
                            to be spirituallyminded is life, joy and peace. Those external symbols, in the form of
                            idols, intended to represent the human or animal were the lowest forms through which thi
                            idea of infinity was represented. Outward symbol was intended to convey a manifestation of
                            the divine spirit. That the conditions of human development made such illustrations
                            necessary is admissible, and as they fulfilled their purpose, like a garment outgrown and
                            worn they were rejected. Sometimes the soul through the inspiration of its higher
                            consciousness turns iconoclast, breaking the idols that it formerly worshiped, thus clearing
                            the way for a new and higher ideal. We can at times, with beneficial results, smite with a
                            strong hand and indomitable will those idolatrous forms that have before our soul's vision
                            tried to counterfeit the divine presence; if not in the form of inanimate matter, then the
                            more condemnable when represented by ideals that have been instrumental in eclipsing our
                            vision, causing us to be unconscious of that spiritual power which is omnipotent and ever
                            present to the soul that is prepared for its reception. Dr. Livingston stated that the
                            lowest types of savage life that he met in his travels, recognized the fact of a superhuman
                            power, and a belief in the soul's immortality which has withstood the shock that has
                            destroyed nations and races, and which at the present time is extending its benediction over
                            the earth as never before known. It is the supreme power that has kept human life moving
                            steadily onward and must be admitted by every one who is capable of intelligently studying
                            the causes which have brought life up to its present standard. This consciousness of the
                            divine presence, has been the inspiration that enabled those heroic souls who were the
                            witnesses of the truth and commissioners of an advanced light to the world, to maintain
                            their integrity in the face of an demoniac in its ferocity. Savanarola, when about to suffer
                            martyrdom at the stake was accosted by the bishop with, "I expel you from the church
                            militant and from the church triumphant." Savanarola replied, "Not from the church
                            triumphant, that is beyond your power." A conscious recognition of the divine Presence
                            empowered the possessor with a courage that is invincible when brought in contact with those
                            powers which are seeking to suppress an open expression of the truth. In the hum- <pb n="137" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 137 ble walks of life, among those on whose brow fame
                            has never placed her laurel wreath, are souls who are living in the conscious presence of
                            that everlasting life. They have given all for the advancement of the truth and are ready to
                            suffer that its principles may be triumphant and human life exalted, moved forward one step
                            farther toward its great and mighty destiny. We can not accept the views advanced by certain
                            so-called reformers, that the race is becoming more materialistic and the moral tone of
                            human society is on the descending scale. Such souls must be living in the lower realms of
                            their being. Such views are too horrible to contemplate, and we turn from them to view
                            life's brighter side. Shakers, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Finish thy work" TEIform="index"/>FINISH THY WORK.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> Finish thy work; the time is short; The sun is in the West; The night is coming
                                    downtill then Think not of rest. Finish thy work ; then welcome rest; Till then,
                                    rest never; The rest prepared for thee by God, Is rest forever. Finish thy work ;
                                    then wipe thy brow ; Ungird thee from thy toil; Take breath, and from each weary
                                    limb Shake off the soil. Finish thy work; then sit thee down On some celestial hill,
                                    And of its strength reviving air Take thou thy fill. Finish thy work ; then go in
                                    peace ; Life's battle fought and won. Hear from the throne the Master's voice; "Well
                                    done! Well done!" Finish thy work; then take thy harp, Give praise to God above ;
                                    Sing a new song of mighty joy And endless love. Give thanks to him who holds thee
                                    up, In all thy path below; Who holds thee faithful unto death, And crowns thee now !</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="British Friend" TEIform="index"/>British Friend.</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="138" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mother Ann Lee" TEIform="index"/>MOTHER ANN LEE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="King, Emma B." TEIform="persName"/>By Emma B. King.</byline><p TEIform="p">ANN LEE was born February 29, 1736, in Manchester, England. She accepted the testimony of
                            James and Jane Wardley, in 1758 and after suffering persecutions and imprisonment she
                            embarked for America with eight of her followers, and arrived at New York on the 6th of
                            August. Why do we commemorate this day? It is one hundred and twenty years, since Mother
                            Ann, whom we acknowledge as the founder of our Church landed on the American shores. We
                            celebrate the anniversary as a pleasant opportunity to renew our vows of consecration to the
                            glorious cause which she espoused. We exalt the integrity of purpose which fitted her as a
                            pure agent to disseminate light and truth to the world, and to reveal a way of salvation to
                            all souls. Those who associate as Brethren and Sisters in the Virgin Order,the fruit of the
                            revelation of God, through our Mother Ann, have a debt of gratitude, fur sacred protection,
                            which others may not comprehend. Its blessings and beauty open anew to our minds, as we
                            realize that one baptism, one cross and one sacrifice enable "whosoever will" to find a
                            spiritual home for both soul and body, under the parental guidance of God's love to mankind.
                            We have unlimited confidence in the Christ spirit that spoke through Jesus, which gave to
                            the world so much of truth as it was prepared to receive, and which was renewed and
                            parfected through Mother Ann. It is only for this sacred feature of the gospel mission, that
                            the landing of Mother Ann on the shores of America would be an event of moment to us, more
                            than the landing of other people, either before or since. The spirit that breathed into her
                            soul, was a purely, unselfish mission, and to this she remained faithful. We rejoice that
                            the testimony of Mother Ann was preached in a Free Land and that this church of Christ was
                            established upon principles which are life unto life to those who obey them. The crowning
                            feature of the life of Mother Ann was her loyalty to principle. She suffered severe
                            persecution at the hands of both men and women, whose favor she might have sought. Although
                            we can not claim great experience in walking by the cross, even though surrounded by the
                            angels of Grod, yet we honor and seek that birth of the spirit which through obedience may
                            be ours and which was possessed by Mother Ann. She flinched not, but published the truth in
                            its fullness, even in the midst of persecutions. Our Mother's mission was to make it
                            possible to build and maintain homes on a spiritual communal basis, and many happy companies
                            of Brethren and Sisters, are prospering in the union and blessing which these homes have
                            afforded. <pb n="139" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 139 We have a peaceful, happy home to-day,It
                            affords us the comforts of life, with temporal, moral and spiritual protection. This comes
                            through the faithfulness of our gospel parents, in the seen and unseen world. But best of
                            all, for which we are now giving thanks, is the knowledge of the Christ mission of Mother
                            Ann, which has opened its arms as a loving father and mother, to this little band of
                            brothers and sisters, as we stand in gospel union, and with the full assurance that we may
                            win and wear a full crown. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Love of christ" TEIform="index"/>THE LOVE OF CHRIST.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Phelps, Lillian" TEIform="persName"/>By Lillian Phelps.</byline><p TEIform="p">IT would be impossible to picture to the mind, Jesus, without the attribute of love. Love
                            shone like a bright star, through the truths that he uttered and in the pai ables he gave
                            for instruction in his doctrine. In many instances wherein he sought to touch the hearts of
                            the poor sinful multitude which crowded about him, attracted by the love and forgiveness
                            which he bestowed alike on all, we tind the Pharisee, ready to accuse and condemn. In the
                            story of the woman, known to be a sinner, who came and anointed the feet of Jesus with
                            precious ointment, (Luke vii., 3650.) we read how the Pharisees rose in self-righteousness,
                            and mindful only that she was a sinner, wondered that Jesus could not discern that sbe was
                            unholy. Jesus, however, in his great love and tender mercy, saw beneath all this the
                            sincerity which prompted the lowly service, and sent her away with the happy assurance, "Thy
                            sins are forgiven." Can not we, as followers of the divine Pattern, draw a valuable lesson
                            from this little instance? How often in daily life, we can discourage a brother or sibter by
                            refusing to recognize a good effort, rather magnifying the mistakes and failures. Oh the
                            accusing spirit of the Pharisee! how little it knows of the love of Christ! We are chosen to
                            become ministers of good to each other, Saviors to seek out the undeveloped germ of the
                            divine in the worlds around us, and encourage and strengthen by sympathy and love, until it
                            becomes the tree bearing fruit unto God. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A good life is the best philosophy..." TEIform="index"/>A good life is the best philosophy...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A good life is the best philosophy ; a clear conscLnce the best law; honesty the best policy;
                            temperance the best medicine. One may gather a harvest of knowledge by reading, but
                            thougntthought is the winnowing machine. No man is good enough to govern another unless he
                            has first governed himself.</p></div2><pb n="140" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. SEPTEMBER, 1899. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is publisht by the
                            "United Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued
                            regularly by the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the
                            religious views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. Address all
                            communications to Henry C. Blinx, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. One copy one year,
                            postage paid. .50 A cross in the margin will show that your subscription has closed.
                            'Remittances for subscription by Money Order should be on the Post Office at Concord, N. H.
                            NOTICE. Our little Magazine which at the present time is known as "The Manifesto," issued
                            its first number in January, 1871, at Watervliet, N. Y. At that time it bore the very
                            pleasant but modest title, "The Shaker." It was the messenger of "good news," and in its
                            advocacy of the testimony of the Christ, gave no uncertain sound. Its publication has been
                            sustained by the liberal contributions of the several Shaker Communities, as they have
                            manifested a deep interest in its success as a medium for good to its own members, and no
                            less to those who were not residents of the Community. Possibly it may be after a term of
                            some thirty years, "The Manifesto" has accomplished all the good it can for the present, and
                            may now go into retirement, till another wave of enthusiasm calls it again into action. To
                            all who have ministered to the success of the little paper, as writers or readers, or to its
                            circulation, we extend our kindest thanks. Times have changed. Money "is scarce and the
                            several Societies have' suffered with the laboring classes in the common distress. It is now
                            proposed that the December number of "The Manifesto" for 1899, shall be the closing of the
                            publication. The Directors.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">July. Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. Thermometer. Rain. 1898. 75.3 2.125 in 1899.
                                72.42 7. " Highest Temp, during this mo. 92 above 0. Lowest " " " " 50 " Xumber of rainy
                                days " " 9 " clear " " " 9 " cloudy " " " 13 July, 189:). July has been quite a hurried
                                month. It has given us seven inches of rain which is more than the three preceding
                                months combined gave us. July gave vegetation a verdant coloring, which gives the
                                landscape almost a vernal bloom. Notwithstanding the scanty showers of April, May and
                                June, their total supply of rain was only six and one fourth inches, yet garden and farm
                                crops showed^very limited signs of drought. The garden has given TERMS. <pb n="141" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 141 a bountiful supply of wholesome vegetables; the farm
                                furnishes us with excellent new potatoes; the orchard gives us an ample supply of ripe
                                apples; the nursery and berry bushes afford us a variety of small fruits. There is no
                                danger at present of our perishing with hunger. There has been a decided improvement
                                made on our village street; more yet remains to be done. The road-bed is coated with
                                gravel from the cross walk,(running from our dwelling to the infirmary,) and north to
                                the junction of the two roads; the west wall of the blacksmith pond dam has been
                                repaired; a substantial railing has been built ou each side of the dam and the road has
                                been gravelled, which is an improvement. The N. Y. State Koad is at the point of
                                completion. The Mass, end is being worked. Our Ministry are at Hancock. It is a time of
                                usual health in the Community. Calvin 0. -Reed. South Family. July, 1899. Home Notes and
                                bird notes How do they agree? Bird notes are merry notes So should Home Notes be. Bird
                                notes are musical Full of light and life Cheering ev'ry hearer Like the harp and fife,
                                Manifesto Home Notes From the writers' thought, Can impart the mu-sic Which the birds
                                have tnnght. When July laid its burdens down August rose up to the rescue; should we not
                                as ready be to lend a helping hand in bearing the burdens of life? Ofttimes they are
                                many and heavy for the willing few. Eldress Miriam Offord of Enfield; Conn, honored us
                                with a visit. We were spiritually benefited by her presence and were thankful for her
                                coming. She's just "what God requires of her A messenger of love A minister of light and
                                peace Her works they surely prove." Saturday the 29th ult. we were favored with a call
                                from our worthy friends Mr. and Mrs. Brannen of Denver, Col. Hope their next journey
                                east will be of greater length but remembering "short visits make long friends" we will
                                not regret brevity. By kind invitation of our North family friends a happy band from
                                here entered the land of Canaan, Thursday the 3rd inst. and devoted the day to
                                blackberry pick- j ing. We found a rich harvest of that I most healthful fruit. Milk and
                                honey we found flowing Through the berries black there growing Though the thorns were
                                strong and great, Yet we met with kindly fate. Many thanks to northern friends All the
                                south to them extends. Genevieve DeGraw. North Family. August, 1899. Beautiful days and
                                bountiful harvests of berries are ours. To be sure aching backs and scratched hands must
                                be taken with the blue sky and deluges of sunshine but if we had no stubborn discomforts
                                to beat our wings against how could we _0 know that we had wings? The tide of summer
                                travel casts now and then au ebbing wave upon our lawn and some of the salt and some of
                                the silliness too of the great world ocean linger for awhile in the atmosphere about us;
                                one to be used as a needed tonic and the other as an equally needed warning. The making
                                of the State road promises to be no slight task. After the hard labors of the day, you
                                may see squads of dusky-faced Italians on their errands of business or of pleasure. Poor
                                exiles! How little they thought when playing among the olives and vines of their sunny
                                land, a day would come when they would be laying roads among the hills of far away
                                America. Are they homesick? Their swathy faces tell no tales. Does not God intend for us
                                to have a kindly interest in the stranger at our gates? stranger to us but not to God.
                                Are not we too busy or too indifferent? <pb n="142" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 142 THE MANIFESTO. It is
                                Sunday to-day. One of those perfect days that Beecher calls a "flower dropped over the
                                walls of Paradise." As usual we shall attend service at the Church family. Elder Levi,
                                busy, burdened Elder Levi, has just come down the walk with a Sabbath peace on his face
                                and the sound of his springy step, for lie keeps a little chapel of fadeless springtime
                                within the hoary cathedral walls of old Time's building, and the twitter of the birds
                                are all that break the silence. Such perfect peace! And among the islands of the Pacific
                                are our brothers at war. Life is indeed a hard nut but there is a rich, sweet kernel
                                within, and it takes many blows from God's hand to bring it forth. If we, like peevish
                                children, push His hand aside and insist upon breaking the shell ourselves, we shall get
                                the kernel all the same but not without much selfbruising. Our nation is just now
                                learning this lesson. Think of the conference at the Hague! These are mad times, but
                                also glad times, and best of all God's times. Will not this be one of the memorable
                                summons of historf ? Is there not something gravely significant in the representatives
                                of the old world of Europe and of older Asia suspending their deliberations at the Hague
                                to celebrate our Independence Day? Do we realize what is being done in little Holland
                                just now? To use Stead's words, "A company of men is busy creating at the close of
                                nineteen hundred years of nominal Christianity a court which will give the nations a
                                chance to carry their disputes to some other judgment seat than that of war." How all
                                our petty cares and toils, our bread and butter strivings sink into nothing in this
                                broad white light of promise. G. Ada Drown.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">July, 1899. As we note the shortening of the days observable in the rising and setting of
                                the sun, we are reminded of the words of that old hymn commencing, "Our days are gliding
                                swiftly by," and if we could we would not detain them. The present is constantly
                                becoming history, as it is recorded in the annals of the past, and the prophetic future
                                is becoming the living present. The pleasure of anticipation in looking forward gives
                                the inspiration to every healthy mind to struggle for the best and make the futnre
                                superior to the present. During the month of July we were favored in a manner that
                                seldom falls to our lot. Our Beloved Elder Ira Lawson spent Sunday the 23rd ult. with
                                us, and although the visit was of short duration when counted by hours, yet the blessing
                                that came to us while in spiritual communion with him could not be measured by an
                                earthly standard. We also had a pleasant visit from Sister Sarah Cutler of Mt. Lebanon.
                                In reply to the question of Elder Oliver C. Hampton as to what will destroy the
                                Curculic? we would state that our experience has been that the most effectual means to
                                prevent its ravages is as soon as the fruit is past the blossom, to catch them by
                                spreading a piece of cotton sheeting six or eight feet square, under the limbs and by a
                                sudden jar on the limb they will fall and can be caught; and by burning them and all of
                                the defective fruit that falls. The best time is in the morning while the insects are
                                dormant. We have seen plum and apricot trees where this system was followed three or
                                four times in a week, or better, every morning, to yield bountiful crops of fruit while
                                those that were neglected yielded none of any value. Hamilton DeGro.w.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>West Pittsfield, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">August, 1899. When last we visited the Home Circle, we were predicting fruitless
                                harvests, and lamenting the dryness of the earth, because of the scarcity of the rain.
                                But should we not make known the sequel <pb n="143" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> TJ IE MANIFES TO. 143 and
                                as readily appraise the blessings as murmur at the ills of life? The rain came. In
                                copious showers, in lengthy "drizzles," in light mists; but interspersed with rays of
                                sunlight, so that now earth is smiliug in freshness and beauty. It is now a beautiful
                                morning. The green-covered earth is sparkling with millions of sunbeams, and the trees
                                stand arrayed in treasures of bright crimson and gold. On such mornings as this one
                                realizes more fully the significance of the words said to have been uttered in the last
                                family prayer given by the author, Eugene Field. "Let us bring morning hearts to
                                Christ.'' Not hearts only weary as at close of day, seeking rest; but hearts filled with
                                praise, and bright with purpose, strong in an endeavor to do our best. Why has August
                                been so neglected by poet or singer we wonder. They tell of "June's Roses," of "Golden
                                October," etc., but August is only noted for her sultry days, andvisiting flies. But who
                                like August of all the months, fills in each detail of the rude sketch prepared for her
                                by her preceding sisters. She rounds the apples and tinges them with sunlight hues; she
                                bronzes the pears, and busily stores away sunbeams in fruit and vegetable; she touches
                                each tree and flower with fuller, deeper beauty;and then October comes along, and with a
                                dash of color here and there, and a grand final swing of the brush; completes the
                                picture;and receives the glory. We were disappointed,very pleasantly, as to the hay
                                harvest, and reports are now issued of a plentiful supply. Pears are exceedingly
                                abundant and apples, all that we shall need. An advance regiment of tomatoes have
                                arrived from the fort across the way, with tidings of a well conditioned army soon to
                                arrive. Those who survive the present season will be quartered with us for the winter, I
                                presume. Upon our mountain-side a city has lately been building; its cottages are
                                exceedingly light and airy, with no superabundance to intercede with nature's way. Its
                                inhabitants are natives of Italy's fair clime, and they are hewers and drawers of stone
                                and earth building another mile of state road on the Massachusetts line, to meet that of
                                New York, for the "Old Bay State," wishes to meet on an equal footing, always. We have
                                enjoyed the pleasant society, and kindly influence of our editor for several weeks, and
                                now that he has returned to his old home, miss him very much. But there would be no
                                welcomes, unless a farewell preceded, so we shall hope~and trust, that the future may
                                again see him at Berkshire. Fidelia Estabroolc.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">July, 1899. The Shaker Church was established one hundred and twenty-five years ago. The
                                landing of eight persecuted souls in New York, Aug. 6, 1774, opened the history of our
                                church work on this continent. It has long been our custom to commemorate this important
                                event, and the current month brought no exception. The Sixth occurring on Sunday, the
                                anniversary exercises were presented to the society between the hours of 1-30 and 3-30
                                p. m. in our Old South Church. Each number on the well-arranged programme was especially
                                appropriate to the occasion, the following giving particular pleasure:__ In our Home of
                                Many Mansions. Chorus. A Historical Summary of the Church. Why Do we Commemorate this
                                Day? Our Mother's Way. Trio. The World's Good Women. Our Mother. Acrostic. A Bouquet of
                                Flowers. Little Girls. Art thou Watching over me My Mother? Quartette. Choice Gems from
                                our First Elders. Thy Kingdom Come. Children. What will Bring the Heavens Nearer?
                                Chorus. <pb n="144" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 144 THE MANIFESTO. Links in Mother's Golden Chain. Youth.
                                Mother's Crown. Little Boys. Our Mother Ann of To-day. Our Mothers Last Hymn. While
                                blessings rich and many are ours to-day, may we ever hold'in.sacred memory the names and
                                testimony of those pioneer spirits, who suffered that our communal Christ homes might be
                                established in this land of freedom. Temporal prosperity is still vouchsafed to us.
                                Beloved Elder Henry has been heartily welcomed home. No good friend or friends
                                accompanied him from that lovely hospitable home at West Pittsfield, however. This would
                                have been a pleasant sequel to a pleasant stoi'y. Haying has closed at this date. Jessie
                                Evans.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Alfred, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Alfred., Me.</head><p TEIform="p">August, 1899. During the past month, thunder showers have been of frequent occurrence. On
                                July 21, we had a very severe one from seven o'clock p. m. when the storm broke until
                                after midnight it was a continual roar of thunder and the lightning flashed all over the
                                sky, it seemed like too armies met in battle. We are thankful to say that we did not
                                suffer any from it, altho rumors of disaster came from all around us. Hay*is harvested
                                and we .find we shall have a plentiful supply with what was left over from last year's
                                store The Sisters are busy getting basket work ready for sale. At present Elder Henry
                                Green is in the White mountains trying to exchange some of it for the almighty dollars
                                which we need for the comforts of life. We are having very cool weather, the evenings
                                are quite chilly, if it continues to grow cooler we shall expect an early visit from
                                Jack Frost. We look forward each month with pleasure for The Manifesto, for it is full
                                of good things. It is one of the links that bind our homes together, for through its
                                columns we hear from our gospel friends afar. Eva M. Libbey.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">July, 1899. Nearly four'months have had their time since six of us were transferred from
                                the Church order to this family, and our time has been fully occupied with the duties
                                incident to the prevailing conditions, thus debarring us from some of the pleasantries
                                and duties pen and mind has enjoyed. With the abundance of fruits and grains, coupled
                                with the remembrance of the many joys that are ours as we live in nearness of thought to
                                the Christ spirit, we rejoice and "Our heart's breathe the old refrain, Thy will be
                                done." Not according to any world levelling process, nor by any pagan conception of
                                life, impeding expansion of individual and society life toward a higher degree of
                                existence, but by the power of mind that will expand in duties and uprightness of
                                spirit, valuing principle above human favor or material gift. It may not be essential
                                that we echo end reecho the same remarks the founders of our societies heralded, but it
                                is necessary that we give full consecrated lives to the principles that bind us
                                together. "Our fathers to their graves liave gone; Their strife is past, their triumph
                                won, But sterner trials wait the race Which rises in their honored place." A careful
                                inspection of our true condition will apprise us of the fact that "hands to work and
                                hearts to God" is the imperative law of to-day that we may remain able to hold fast that
                                which is good. Our Church family have shone with new lustre; three buildings revealing
                                very artistic dressing. With our kindred there we gather each Sabbath and exchange gifts
                                of the spirit. With us change from family to family can not mar the ties of affection or
                                withhold the aid each one is capable of giving. New voices may sound the gospel news and
                                different themes inspire the lips; but never can new friends or modes of life take the
                                place of old ones bearing the seal of Christly approval. George H. Baxter.</p></div3><pb n="" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Union Village, Ohio" TEIform="index"/> Union Village, O.</head><p TEIform="p">August, 1899. We have very good roads around our Village, and our Supervisor, Bro. J. H.
                                Fennessey, has very thoroughly gravelled them this summer as well as made many other
                                improvements over our farms and premises; being our farm deacon as well as one of the
                                Trustees. During the last eighteen months he has built many new fences, and cleared many
                                places of rubbish, such as weeds, briars, fence-rails sticks and stones,so that as I
                                pass around the premises, I see many places altogether improved. I call this one of the
                                emphatic ways of keeping the Gospel. For all this is in perfect accordance with our
                                blessed Mother's testimony and teaching. Last Sabbath, I read a discourse in our morning
                                meeting, from the writings of Thomas A.Kempis, on "The joy of a good Conscience," and I
                                think if we all would see to it that we keep that richest of pearls pure and unsoiled,
                                we will enjoy even our temporal blessings in far more perfection and peace. It is said
                                that temporal and spiritual go together, and this is truenevertheless, the former must
                                move, live, and have its being and actually emanate from the latter. Our yards are full
                                of flowers, which give out their fragrance and beauty on every hand, and point to the
                                Great Architect, whose wisdom and love, truth and goodness purity and peace, mercy and
                                forgiveness, are deep and substantial, not only, but sublime and ornamental. But we are
                                too far from any profitable market to make merchandise of our flowers, as they do at
                                Alfred, Me., and as for Lebanon our county seat, one dandelion posy would glut the
                                market there. So we must be contented with looking at them, which indeed is a great
                                comfortfor "a thing of beauty is a joy forever." We are enjoying excellent health, and
                                there is not a healthier location on earth than Union Village, Warren Co., O. Some 30
                                acres of our wheat yielded 29 bu. to the acre (amounting to 8*70 bus.) We have about
                                6500 bushels of wheat this season but some of it was somewhat damaged by sprouting in
                                the shock. However, we will not complain about that seeing we have been so abundantly
                                blessed in. our basket and store the present season. Some of our oats yielded 50 bus. to
                                the acre. We also have barley and rye and an excellent crop of potatoes. What we should
                                like would be for some of our good Brethren and Sisters from the Eastern Country to come
                                out here and settle right down on our vacated premises, and enjoy the comfort and
                                blessing of the same. They would find such a good place to make a living out of the soil
                                and an abundant welcome from the Society here. I wish The Manifesto prosperity and
                                success and also all its editors and publishers. O. C. Hampton.</p></div3></div2><!--
What has been done of late in the educational world in the way of advance, and "what
lines the immediate future advance is to take
are two cognate and related subjects treated
in the Educational Number of The Outlook
(August Magazine Number,) by two of the
foremost educators and writers on educational topicsProfessor Nicholas Murray Butler
of Columbia, and President G. Stanley Hall of
Clark University.   The two articles form a
memorable and unusual contribution to the
literature of American education.   ($3 a year.
The Outlook Co., New York.)
Hamlin Garland, Anthony Hope, John Kendrick Bangs, Harold Richard Vynne, Anna
Robeson "Brown, "Josiah Allen's Wife," Clara
Morris, Kate Whiting Patch and Anna Farquhar are among the half-score of writers of
fiction who contribute stories to the August
Ladies' Home Journal.   The Midsummer Fiction Number of the Journal is in many respects a notable magazine.     It has brought
together in a single issue some of the most
popular story writers, and the most capable
black-and-white artists to illustiate their
work.   Fiction, of course, predominates, but
there is an abundance of timely, practical articles especially appealing to home and family interests and tending to lighten and brighten women's work.   The Reverend Newell
Dwight Hillis, D. D., has an interesting arti-
<pb n="" id="p20"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
cle in this issue on The Diffusion of Happiness Through Conversation; the third of his
Secrets of a Happy Life series, and Mrs. Burton Kingsland and Emily D. Striebert write
of With the Children on Sunday; their diversions and instruction; What Can be Done
With an Old Farmhouse pictures how an old
building may be artistically remodeled at
small cost.   On two other pictorial pages are
shown the most cozy and attractive Houses
in Woods, Valleys and Mountains: and The
Sweetest of Summer Charities pictures the
work of the flower missions in several cities.
The latest feminine fancies in dress are set
forth in The Gossip of a New York Girl; and
Emily Wight writes of the Newest Styles in
Hairdressing and Laces for Dress Trimmings.
Mrs S. T. Rorer's cooking lesson is on Cold
Dishes for Hot Weather; and Mr. and Mrs.
Edward B. Warman's health talks are on
timely themes.   For the boys Dan Beard explains how to make A Back-Yard Fish Pond.
The editorial departments are more interesting than usual, and touch upon every phase
of home life.   By The Curtis Publishing Company, Philadelphia.   One dollar per year; ten
cents per copy.
Mission op the Shakers by A. G. Hollister.
A little pamphlet of thirty pages.    It informs
us that "the object of a Shaker life is purely
religious and spiritual."   It is self-conquest;
salvation from all wrong doing, from selfishness to be utterly rid of the carnal life and
will, through a perfect moral intellectual and
spiritual obedience to the commandments of
God.   Pub. by A. G. Hollister, Mt. Lebanon,
N. Y.
The Cosmopolitan Magazine is seeking a
reliable agent in every County.   Persons hav
ing a little leisure will find it worth while to
communicate with the Manager.   Address
Cosmopolitan Magazine, Irvington, N. Y.
"GENTLE   MANNERS."
A Guide to Good Morals.
Published   at   East   Canterbury,   N.   H.
"Nothing on earth is more beloved and
honored in the world's great heart, than a
noble youth, whose aims are high, and
whose life is a moral essay."
Gilt edged20 cts., postage 4 cts.
Boards, 16 cts. postage 4 cts.
Paper, 10 cts. postage 2 cts.
AddressH. C. Blinn.
East Canterbury, N. H.
50   YEARS'
EXPERIENCE
Trade Marks
Designs
Copyrights &c.
Anyone sending a sketch and description may
quickly ascertain our opinion free whether an
invention is probably patentable. Communications strictly confidential. Handbook on Patents
sent free. Oldest agency for securing patents.
Patents taken through Munn & Co. receive
special notice, without charge, in the
Scientific American.
A handsomely illustrated weekly. Largest circulation of any scientific journal. Terms, $3 a
year; four months, $1.  Sold by all newsdealers.
361 Broadway, I
"Branch Office,"625 F St., Washington, D. <
TJIT5 T7TT * advanced thought peoplesam XwiallJple copy of the most original and
practical occult journal of the age.
The exponent of West Gate Philosophy.
A. new occult system.An unlimited field of labor open to teachers, lecturers
and healers.   Address,
The ORACLE, Sta. A.     Boston, Mass.
HAVE YOU "'COMMON SENSE?"
If not, send at once for a free copy of this
liberal-minded  advocate of advanced
thought, which brings health and
success.    Address
"Common Sense," M. O. 55 State St.
Chicago, 111.
AUTHORISED   RULES
OF
THE   SHAKER   COMMUNITY.
The religious basis of the Order must
be a foundation resting on the principle of
righteousness, which principle is God.
This should rule the life of the individual for the protection of his own soul, for
the peace of the family and as an evidence
of his upright standing before the world.
Price, 10 cts.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>