<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm1901" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">28</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">19</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">1</biblScope><date value="18890101" TEIform="date">January 1889</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">1-24</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="19" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="1" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                    <pb n="t.p." id="p1"/>
                    <p>JANUARY. THE MANIFESTO Published by the United Societies, Vol. XIX. "For what is a man profited, if he shall gain the
                        whole world, and lose his own soul? or what shall a man give in exchange for his soul."—Matt. XVI., 26. Canterbury,
                       N. H., 1889.</p>
                    --><!--
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="none">
                        <p>CONTENTS. Page. Shaker Church Covenant, 3 Earthly Riches, 12 Letter—L. M. Pomeroy, \3 F. W. Evans, Rambling
                            Thoughts, 14 Bible Study, 15 Welcome, New Year, 18 Vegetarianism, 19 What an appetite, 21 Dec. 31st, " Coming
                            Millennium, , " Letter—Daniel Orcutt, 22 The Brooklet, - " Prisoner's Study, Tyndal's Testament, 23 Seeds of
                            Good and 111, " Books & Papers, 24 Everyday Work, Deaths, .... -</p>
                    </div2>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                --><pb n="1" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">MANIFESTO Published by the United Societies. VOL. XIX. For what is a man profited, if he
                            shall gain the whole world, and lose his own soul? or what shall a man give in exchange for
                            his soul."—Matt. XVI., 26. Shaker Village, N. H., 1889. THE</p></div2><pb n="2" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/><pb n="3" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker church covenant" TEIform="index"/>SHAKER CHURCH COVENANT</head><p TEIform="p">PREAMBLE. We, the Brethren and Sisters of the United Society of Believers (called Shakers,)
                            residing in the county of____—, and State of--------, being connected together as a
                            religious and social community, distinguished by the name and title of the Church of the
                            United Society, in the town of--------, which for many years has been established and in
                            successful operation, under the charge of the Ministry and Eldership thereof, and, feeling
                            the importance not only of renewing and confirming our spiritual covenant with God and each
                            oilier, but also of renewing and improving our social compact, and amending the written form
                            thereof, do make, ordain, and declare the following articles of agreement as a summary of
                            the principles, rules and regulations established in the Church of the said United Society,
                            which are to be kept and maintained by us, both in our collective and individual capacities,
                            as a covenant or constitution, which shall stand as a lawful testimony of our religious and
                            social compact, before all men, and in all cases of question and law relating to the
                            possession and improvement of our united and consecrated interest, property, and estate :
                            ARTICLE I. Of the Gospel Ministry. Section 1. Their origin, call and institution : We
                            solemnly declare to each other and to all whom it may concern, that we have received, and do
                            hereby acknowledge as the foundation of our faith, order and government, the testimony or
                            Gospel of Christ, in his first and second appearing, and we do hereby solemnly agree to
                            support and maintain the true primitive faith and Christian principles, the morals, rules
                            and manners pertaining to the said Gospel, as ministered by the founders of this Society,
                            and kept and conveyed through a regular order of ministration, down to the present day. And,
                            although, as a religious society, <pb n="4" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. we are variously
                            associated, with respect to the local situations of our respective communities, yet we are
                            known and distinguished as a peculiar people, and consider and acknowledge ourselves as
                            members of one general community, possessing one faith, and subject to one united, parental
                            and ministerial administration, which has been regularly supported from the first foundation
                            pillars of the Institution, and which continues to operate for the support, protection and
                            strength of every part of said community. Section 2. Their order and office : We further
                            acknowledge and declare that for the purpose of promoting and maintaining union, order and
                            harmony throughout the various branches of this community, the primary administration of
                            parental authority has been settled in the first established Ministry at New Lebanon, N. Y.,
                            there to rest and remain as the center of union to all who are in Gospel relation and
                            communion with the Society. The established order of this Ministry includes four persons ;
                            two of each sex. Section 3. Perpetuity of their office and how supplied : We further
                            acknowledge and declare that the said primary administration of parental authority has been
                            and is perpetuated as follows : Namely, that the first in that office and calling possesses
                            the right given by the sanction of divine authority, through the first founders of this
                            Society, to prescribe or direct any regulation or appointment which they may judge most
                            proper and necessary respecting the Ministry or any other important matter which may concern
                            the welfare of the Church, subsequent to their decease. But in case no such regulation or
                            appointment be so pre- scribed or directed, then the right to direct and authorize such
                            regulation and appointment devolves upon the surviving members of the Ministry, in council
                            with the Elders of the Church, or others, as the nature of the case in their judgment may
                            require. Such appoint- ments being officially communicated to all concerned, and receiving
                            the general approbation of the Church, are confirmed and supported in the Society. This is
                            agreeable to the example recorded in the Scriptures, and continued by the founders of this
                            Society, and is the order and manner which has been regularly practiced, acknowledged, and
                            maintained in the Community from the beginning. Section 4. Of the Ministerial office in the
                            several societies or communities : We further acknowledge and declare, covenant and agree
                            that the Ministerial cffice and authority in any Society or Community of our faith, which
                            has emanated, or which may emanate, in a regular line cf order from the center of union
                            aforesaid, is, and shall be acknowledged, owned and respected, as the spiritual and primary
                            authority of such Society or Community, in all matters pertaining to the Ministerial office.
                            And in case of the decease or removal of any individual of said Ministry, in any such
                            Society, his or her lot and place shall be filled by agreement of the surviving Ministers,
                            in council with the Elders and others, as the nature of the case may require, together with
                            the 4 <pb n="5" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. knowledge and approbation of the primary
                            Ministerial authority at New Lebanon, N. Y., aforesaid, to which they are responsible.
                            Section 5. Powers and duties of the Ministry: The Ministry being appointed and established
                            as aforesaid are vested with the primary authority of the Church and its various branches.
                            Hence, it becomes their special duty to guide and superintend the spiritual concerns of the
                            Society as a body of people under their care and government, and in connection with the
                            Elders in their respective families and departments, who shall act in union with them, to
                            give and establish such orders, rules and regulations as may be found necessary for the
                            government and protection of the Church and Society within the limits of their jurisdiction,
                            and also to counsel, advise and judge in all matters of importance, whether spiritual or
                            temporal. The said Ministry are also invested with authority in connection with the Elders
                            as aforesaid, to nominate and appoint to office Ministers, Elders, Deacons, and Trustees,
                            and to assign offices of care and trust to such brethren and sisters as they, the said
                            Ministers and Elders, shall judge to be best qualified for the several offices to which they
                            may be appointed ; and we do hereby covenant and agree that such nominations and
                            appointments being made and officially communicated to those concerned, and receiving the
                            general approbation of the Church, or of the families concerned, shall thenceforth be
                            confirmed and supported, until altered or revoked by the authority aforesaid. ARTICLE II.
                            Institution of the Church. Section 1. The object and design of Church relation : We further
                            acknowledge and declare that the great object, purpose and design of our uniting ourselves
                            together as a church or body of people, in social and religious compact, is faithfully and
                            honestly to occupy, improve and diffuse the various gifts and talents, both of a spiritual
                            and ^temporal nature, with which Divine wisdom has blest us, for the service of God, for the
                            honor of the Gospel, and for the mutual protection, support, comfort and happiness of each
                            other as brethren and sisters in the Gospel, aod for such other pious and charitable
                            purposes as the Gospel may require. Section 2. Who are not admissible into Church relation:
                            As the unity, stability and purity of the Church essentially depend on the character and
                            qualifications of its members, and as it is a matter of importance that it should not be
                            encumbered with persons who are under any involvement or incapacity, natural or moral:
                            Therefore, no member of any company or association in business or civil concern, no
                            co-partner in trade, no person under any legal embarrassment or obligations of service, no
                            minor, no slave or bond servant, no insane person, no profane person, nor any person who
                            lives in the willful violation of the known and acknowledged principles of moral conduct,
                            shall be deemed qualified for admission 5 <pb n="6" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. into the
                            covenant relation and communion of the Church. Section 3. Preparation for admission into
                            Church relation : In order that believers may be prepared for entering into the sacred
                            privilege of Church relation, it is of primary importance that sufficient opportunity and
                            privilege should be afforded under the Ministry of the Gospel, for them to acquire suitable
                            instruction in the genuine principles of righteousness, honesty, justice and true holiness,
                            and also that they should prove their faith and Christian morality by their practical
                            obedience to the precepts of the Gospel according to their instructions. It is also
                            indispensably necessary for them to receive the one uniting spirit of Christ, and to become
                            so far of one heart and one mind, that they are willing to sacrifice all other relations for
                            this sacred one. Another essential step, is to settle all just and equitable claims of
                            creditors and filial heirs, so that whatever property they may possess, shall be justly
                            their own. When this is done, and they feel themselves sufficiently prepared to make a
                            deliberate and final choice, to devote themselves, with all they possess, wholly to the
                            service of God, without reserve, and it shall be deemed proper by the leading authority of
                            the Church, after examination and due consideration, to allow them to associate together in
                            the capacity of a Church, or a branch thereof in Gospel order, they may then consecrate
                            themselves and all they possess to the service of God forever, and confirm the same by
                            signing and sealing a written covenant predicated upon the principles herein contained, and
                            fulfilling on their part, all its obligations. Section 4. Admission of new members : As the
                            door must be kept open for the admission of new members into the Church, when duly prepared,
                            it is agreed that each and every person who shall at any time after the date and execution
                            of the Church Covenant, in any branch of the Community, be admitted into the Church as a
                            member thereof, shall previously have a fair opportunity to obtain a full, clear and
                            explicit understanding of the object and design of the Church Covenant, and of the
                            obligations it enjoins upon the members. For this purpose, he or she shall, in the presence
                            of two of the deacons or acting trustees of the Church, read, or hear the same distinctly
                            read, so as to be able freely to acknowledge his or her full approbation and acceptance
                            thereof, in all its parts. Then he, she or they (as the case may be,) shall be at liberty to
                            sign the same; and having signed and sealed it, and being subject to all the obligations
                            required of the original signers shall thenceforth be entitled to all the benefits and
                            privileges thereunto appertaining; and the signature or signatures thus added shall be
                            certified by the said deacons or trustees, together with the date thereof. Section 5.
                            Concerning youth and children : Youth and children, being minors, cannot be received as
                            members of the Church possessing a concentrated interest in a united capacity, yet it is
                            agreed that they may be received under the immediate care and government of the Church, at
                            the desire or consent of such person or persons as have a lawful right 6 <pb n="7" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/>
                            THE MANIFESTO. to or control of such minors, together with their own desire or consent. But
                            no minor under the care of" the Church can be employed therein for wages of any kind.
                            ARTICLE III. Of the Trusteeship. Section 1. Appointment, qualifications and powers of
                            Trustees : It has been found necessary for the establishment of order in the Society m its
                            various branches, that superintending Deacons and Deaconesses should be appointed and
                            authorized to act as Trustees or agents of the temporalities of the Church. They must be
                            recommended by honesty and integrity, their fidelity in trust and their capacity for the
                            transaction of business; of these qualifications the Ministry and Elders must be the judges.
                            The official Trustees of the Church are generally known among us by the title of Office
                            Deacons, of which there must be two or more; and being appointed by the authority afore-
                            said, they are invested with power to take the general charge and oversight of all the
                            property, estate and interest, dedicated, devoted, consecrated and given up for the benefit
                            of the Church ; to hold in trust the fee of all the lands belonging to the Church ; also all
                            gifts, grants and donations which have been, or may hereafter be dedicated, devoted,
                            consecrated and given up as aforesaid ; and the said property, estate, interest, gifts,
                            grants and donations shall constitute the united and consecrated interest of the Church, and
                            shall be held in trust by the said Deacons, as acting Trustees, in their official capacity,
                            and by their successors in said office and trust forSection 2. Duties of the Trustees : It
                            is and shall be the duty of the said Deacons or acting Trustees to improve, use and
                            appropriate the said united interest for the benefit of the church in all its departments ;
                            and for such other religious and charitable purposes as the Gospel may require ; and also to
                            make all just and equitable defense in law for the protection and security of the
                            consecrated and united interest, rights and privileges of the Church and Society, jointly
                            and severally as an associated community, as far as circumstances and the nature of the case
                            may require; Provided, nevertheless, that all the transactions of the said Deacons or acting
                            Trustees, in the use, management, protection, defense and disposal of the aforesaid
                            interest, shall be for the benefit and privilege m,d in behalf of the Church or Society as
                            aforesaid; and not for any private interest, object or purpose whatever. Section 3. Trustees
                            to give information and be responsible to the Ministry and Elders: It shall also be the duty
                            of the Trustees to give information to the Ministry and Elders of the church of the general
                            state of the temporal concerns of the church and society committed to their charge ; and
                            also to report to the said authority all losses sustained in the united interest thereof,
                            which shall come under their cognizance. And no disposal of any real estate of the Church,
                            nor any important contract shall be con7 ever. <pb n="8" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. sidered
                            valid without the previous approbation of the authority aforesaid, to whom the said Deacons
                            and Trustees are and shall, at all times, be held responsible in all their transactions.
                            Section 4. Books of account and record to be kept: It shall also be the duty of the Deacons
                            or acting Trustees to keep or cause to be kept, regular books of account, in which shall be
                            entered the debt and credit accounts of all mercantile operations and business transactions
                            between the Church and others ; all receipts and expenditures, bonds, notes and bills of
                            account, and all other matters that concern the united interest of the church ; and also a
                            book or books of records, in which shall be recorded a true and correct copy of this
                            Covenant; also all appointments, removals and changes in office of Ministry, Elders, Deacons
                            and Trustees ; all admissions, removals, departure and decease of members, together with all
                            other matters and trans- actions of a public nature which are necessary to be recorded for
                            the benefit of the Church, and for the preservation and security of the documents, papers
                            and written instruments pertaining to the united interest and concerns of the church,
                            committed to their charge. And the said record shall be annually inspected by the leading
                            authority of the church, who, together with the Trustees, shall be the official auditors of
                            the same ; and the signature of one or more of said auditors, with the date of inspection
                            and approval shall be deemed sufficient authority for the correctness and validity of the
                            facts and matters so recorded. Section 5. Trustees to execute a declara'ion of trust: For
                            the better security of the united and consecrated interest of the Church to the proper uses
                            and purposes stipulated in this covenant, it shall be the duty of the Trustee or Trustees,
                            who may be vested with the lawful title or claim to the real estate of the Church, to make
                            and execute a declaration of trust, in due form of law, embracing all and singular the
                            lands, tenements and hereditaments, with every matter of interest pertaining to the Church
                            which at the time being may be vested in him or them, or that may in future come under his
                            or their charge of office, during his or their said Trusteeship. The said declaration shall
                            state expressly that the said Trustee or Trustees hold all such lands, tenements or
                            hereditaments, and all the personal property of every description belonging to the Church or
                            Society, in trust for the uses and purposes expressed in and subject to the rules,
                            conditions and regulations prescribed by the covenant and constitution of the said Church or
                            Society, or any amendments thereto which shall hereafter be adopted by the general
                            approbation of the Church, and in conformity with the primitive faith and acknowledged
                            principles of the Society. And the said declaration shall be in writing, duly executed under
                            his or their hands and seals, and shall be recorded in the Book of Records provided for in
                            the preceding section. Section 6. Vacancies in certain cases ; how supplied : We further
                            covenant and agree that in case it should at any time happen, in 8 <pb n="9" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. the course of Divine Providence, that the office of Trustees should become wholly
                            vacant, by the death or defection of all the Trustees in whom may be vested the fee of the
                            lands or real estate belonging to said Church or Society, then, and in that case, one or
                            more successors shall be appointed by the constitutional authority recognized in this
                            Covenant, according to the rules and regulations prescribed by the same. And the said
                            appointment, being duly recorded in the Book of Records, provided for in this article, shall
                            be deemed, and is hereby declared to vest in such successor or successors, all the rights,
                            interest and authority of their predecessors, in respect to all such lands, property or
                            estate belonging to the Church or Society as aforesaid. ARTICLE IV. Of the Eldership.
                            Section 1. Choice and appointment of Elders : The united interests and objects of believers
                            established in Gospel order, require that Elders should be chosen and appointed for the
                            spiritual protection of families, whose business it is to take the lead in their several
                            departments in the care and government of the concerns of the Church and of the different
                            families established in and pertaining to the Society. Their number and order should
                            correspond with that of the Min- istry. They are required to be persons of good
                            understanding, of approved faithfulness and integrity, and gifted in spiritual
                            administration. They must be selected and appointed by the Ministry, who are to judge of
                            their qualifications. Section 2. Duties of the Elders : As faithful watchmen upon the walls
                            of Zion, it becomes the duty of the Elders to watch over their respective families; to
                            instruct the members in their respective duties ; to counsel, encourage, admonish, exhort
                            and reprove as occasion may require; to lead the worship ; to be examples to the members, of
                            obedience to the principles and orders of the Gospel, and to see that the orders, rules and
                            regulations pertaining to their respective families or departments are properly kept.
                            ARTICLE V. Of Family Deacons and Deaconesses. Section 1. Their qualifications and
                            appointments : The office of family Deacons and Deaconesses has long been established in the
                            Church, and is essentially necessary for the care, management and direction of the domestic
                            concerns in each family, order or branch of the Church. They are required to be persons of
                            correct and well-grounded faith in the established principles of the Gospel, faithful in
                            duty, closely united to their Elders, and of sufficient capacity in business. Of their
                            qualifications, the Ministry and Elders by whom they are chosen and appointed must be the
                            judges. Their number in each family is generally two of each sex, but may be more or less,
                            according to the size of the family and the extent of their various duties. 9 <pb n="10" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. Section 2. Their duties and obligations : The Deacons and
                            Deaconesses of families are intrusted with the care and oversight of the domestic concerns
                            of their respective families. It is their duty to make proper arrangements in business ; to
                            maintain good order ; watch over, counsel and direct the members in their various
                            occupations, as occasion may require ; to make application to the office Deacons or Trustees
                            for whatever supplies are needed in the several departments of the family; to maintain
                            union, harmony and good understanding with the said office Deacons ; and to report to their
                            Elders, the state of matters which fall under their cognizance and observation. But their
                            power is restricted to the domestic concerns of their respective families and departments,
                            and does not extend to any immediate or direct correspondence with those without the
                            boundaries of the Church. They have no immediate concern with trade and commerce, therefore
                            it is not their business to buy and sell, nor in any way to dispose of the property under
                            their care, except with the counsel and approbation of the Trustees. ARTICLE VI. Privileges
                            and Obligations of Members. Section 1. Benefits and privileges of members in church relation
                            : The united interest of the Church having been formed and established by the free-will
                            offerings and pious donations of the members respectively, from the commencement of the
                            institution for the object and purposes already stated, it canuot be considered either as a
                            joint tenancy or a tenancy in common, but as a consecrated whole, designed for and devoted
                            to the uses and purposes of the Gospel forever, agreeable to the established principles of
                            the Church : Therefore it shall be held, possessed and enjoyed by the Church, in their
                            united capacity, as a sacred and covenant right: That is to say, all and every member
                            thereof, while standing in Gospel union and maintaining the principles of this Covenant,
                            shall enjoy equal rights, benefits and privileges, in the use of all things pertaining to
                            the Church, according to their several needs and circumstances; and no difference shall be
                            made on account of what any one has contributed and devoted, or may hereafter contribute and
                            devote to the support and benefit of the institution. Section 2. Proviso : It is
                            nevertheless stipulated and agreed that the benefits, privileges and enjoyments secured by
                            this Covenant to the members of the Church, shall not be considered as extendiog to any
                            person who shall refuse to comply with the conditions of this association ; or who shall
                            refuse to submit to the admonition and discipline of the constituted authority of the Church
                            ; or who shall willfully depart from the principles and practice of those religious and
                            moral obligations which have been established in the Church, agreeable to the primitive
                            faith and distinguished principles of this institution ; of which refusal or noncompliance
                            the leading authority acknowledged in the first article of this Covenant shall be the proper
                            and constitutional judges. 10 <pb n="11" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 11 Section 3. Obligation
                            of the members : As subordination and obedience is the life and soul of every well-regulated
                            community, so our strength and protection, our happiness and prosperity, in our capacity of
                            Church members, must depend on our faithful obedience to the rules and orders established in
                            the Church, and to the instruction, counsel and advice of its leaders. Therefore, we do
                            hereby covenant and agree that we will receive and acknowledge, as our Elders in the Gospel,
                            those members in the Church who are or may be chosen and appointed for the time being to
                            that office and calling by the authority aforesaid ; and also that we will, as faithful
                            brethren and sisters in Christ, conform and subject ourselves to the known and established
                            faith and principles of our community, and to the counsels and directions of the Elders, who
                            shall act in union, as aforesaid, end also to all the orders, rules and regulations which
                            are or may be given and established in the Church, according to the principles and by the
                            authority aforesaid. Section 4. Duties of the members : The faithful improvement of our time
                            and talents in doing good, is a duty which God requires of man, as a rational, social and
                            accountable being, and this duty is indispensable in the members of the Church of Christ.
                            Therefore, it is and shall be required of all and every member of this institution, unitedly
                            and individually, to occupy and improve their time and talents to support and maintain the
                            interest of the Society, to promote the objects of this Covenant, and discharge their duty
                            to God and each other according to their several abilities and callings, as mem- bers in
                            union with one common lead; so that the various gifts and talents of all may be improved for
                            the mutual benefit of each other and all concerned. Section 5. As we esteem the mutual
                            possession and enjoyment of the consecrated interest and privileges of the Church a valuable
                            consideration, fully adequate to any amount of personal interest, labor or service, devoted
                            or consecrated by any individual; we, therefore, covenant and agree, in conformity with an
                            established and well-known principle of the Church, that no person whatever under its care
                            and protection, can be employed for wages of any kind, on his or her individual account, and
                            that no ground is or can be afforded for the recovery of any property or service devoted or
                            consecrated as aforesaid ; and it is also agreed that in case of the removal of any member
                            or members from one family, society or branch of the Church to another, his, her or their
                            previous signature ©r signatures to the Church or Family Covenant from whence such member or
                            members shall have removed, shall forever bar all claims which are incompatible with the
                            true intent and meaning of this Covenant, in the same manner as if such removal had not
                            taken place. Yet all who shall so remove, in union with the authority aforesaid, shall be
                            entitled to all the benefits and privileges of the Order in which they shall then be placed,
                            so long as they shall conform to the rules and regulations of the same. <pb n="12" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 12 THE MANIFESTO. ARTICLE VII. Dedication and Release. Section 1. Dedication and
                            consecration of persons, property and service : According to the faith of the Gospel which
                            we have received and agreeable to the uniform practice of the Church of Christ from its
                            first establishment in this Society, we covenant and agree to dedicate, davote, consecrate
                            and give up, and by this Covenant we do solemnly and conscientiously dedicate, devote,
                            consecrate and give up ourselves and services together with all our temporal interest to the
                            service of God and the support and benefit of the Church of this community, and to such
                            other pious and charitable purposes as the Gospel may require, to be under the care and
                            direction of such Elders, Deacons, and Trustees as are or may be appointed and established
                            in the Church by the authority aforesaid. Section 2. Dedication and release of private
                            claim: Whereas, in pursuance of the requirement of the Gospel, and in the full exercise of
                            our faith, reason and understanding, we have freely and voluntarily sacrificed all
                            self-interest, and consecrated and devoted our persons, services and property, as aforesaid,
                            to the pious and benevolent purposes of the Gospel: Therefore, we do hereby solemnly and
                            conscientiously, unitedly and individually for ourselves and our heirs, release and quit
                            claim to the Deacons, or acting Trustees of the Church for the time being, for the uses and
                            purposes aforesaid, all our private personal right, title, interest, claim and demand of, in
                            and to the estate, interest, property, and appurtenances so consecrated, devoted and given
                            up ; and we hereby jointly and severally promise and declare in the presence of God, and
                            before these witnesses that we will never hereafter, neither directly nor indirectly, under
                            any circumstances whatever, contrary to the stipulations of this Covenant, make nor require
                            any account of any interest, property, labor or service, nor any division thereof which is,
                            has been, or may be devoted by us. or any of us to the uses and purposes aforesaid, nor
                            bring any charge of debt or damage, or hold any claim, nor demand whatever against the said
                            Deacons or Trustees, nor against the Church or Society, nor against any member thereof, on
                            account of any property or service given, rendered, devoted or consecrated to the aforesaid
                            sacred and charitable purposes. In confirmation of all the aforesaid statements, covenants,
                            promises, and articles of agreement, we have hereunto subscribed our names and affixed our
                            seals, commencing on this---------day of --------in the year of our Lord one thousand eight
                            hundred and---------.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Earthly riches" TEIform="index"/>EARTHLY RICHES</head><p TEIform="p">Who envies those who have the burden Of riches in this life? With them the toil and care are
                            equal And great the daily strife. They're servants in their Father's keeping, Eesponsible,
                            yet frail, And anxious ever, waking, sleeping, For duties that assail. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W.</byline></div2><pb n="13" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Westfield, Massachusetts, November 1888" TEIform="index"/>Westfield, Mass, Nov. 1888</head><p TEIform="p">Elder Evans :—I read a communication in the "Springfield Union" written by you about
                                spiritualism. I cannot see how the Fox girls have exposed it. I certainly know they did
                                not produce the raps with their toes. It is impossible for any one to produce raps so,
                                or—as it is thought by many— to converse with our departed friends. No oue ever did, or
                                ever can converse with their friends after death. I plainly say it is impossible. I have
                                been a medium myself, and I know something about spiritualism. I have been a writ- ing,
                                tipping, test and speaking medium. I think it is high time it was exposed. I know just
                                how it is done, and I want the world to know too. I would like to see you, and talk with
                                you on spiritualism, and give you nay experience. I am no medium now, nor ever will be
                                again. I shall ever fight against spiritualism. Oh how deceitful! Scripture says, "Try
                                the spirits, and see whether they are of God." I have tried it, and say, No, no ; never.
                                I am always glad to see people against it, and I am always ready to help them. I have
                                got enough of it. There is no religion in it; no good in it. It is just what our Savior
                                said would be before his coming again. I for one, long for his appearing. I never can
                                believe in spiritualism again. I never have heard from my friends since they have been
                                laid away in the cold and silent grave ; I know they will rest until the resurrection.
                                My mother used to speak of the Shakers at New Lebanon : she has visited there with them
                                ; she always thought a great deal of them. I can talk about spiritualism better than I
                                can write : it would take me quite a while to write my experience. Oh how deceitful,
                                deceitful! It is nothing but the enemy. No spirit friend will ever deceive ; never. I
                                can face any medium and tell them spiritualism is a fraud. It is a power that produces
                                raps, tipping tables, writing and test-giving; it is all done by power unseen. "Woe to
                                the inhabitants of the earth and of the sea ! for the dev- il is come down unto you,
                                having great wrath, because he knotveth that he hath but a short time." (Rev. xii., 12.)
                                I would like to hear from you, and I would like to give you my experience. Yours for
                                truth, P. S. We are commanded to let our light shine. I will come to your place if you
                                wish and the Lord be willing. I shall forever turn traitor to spiritualism ; there is no
                                religion in it: the so-called spirit hates all good. I see by the 'Union' that you had a
                                communication sent you from Spring field ; was it in favor of spiritualism, if I may be
                                so bold as to ask? Please let me know if you wish me to come. I am against spiritualism
                                : I hate the name of it—the liar !</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pomeroy, L. M." TEIform="persName"/>Mrs. L. M. Pomeroy</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reply" TEIform="index"/>REPLY</head><p TEIform="p">Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., Nov. 1888. Mrs. L. M. Pomeroy. Respected Friend :—Your letter of the
                                oth. inst. received. I have not seen the "Springfield Union" containing my article yet;
                                it will come soon. <pb n="14" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 14 THE MANIFESTO. So, you put yourself in the
                                same class with Margaret and Katie Fox. They are mediums. You have been "a medium for
                                writing, tipping, test and speaking medium, &amp;c." You ''know just how it is
                                done." Margaret and Kate were mediums ; and now they say that they have been acting as
                                frauds, all these years. You do the same ; and then expect the world to believe you.
                                Yet, you look for the Savior ; expect the bodily resurrection ; and affirm that the dead
                                cannot return until their bodies rise ; that none have ever returned ; you are positive
                                about it, &amp;c. You forget that Moses and Elias, and Samuel, returned and talked
                                with Jesus and Saul; and many other Scripture statements. Do you not think that yourself
                                and the Fox women are very wicked women, and that no person should believe a word that
                                any of you may utter ? Then you contradict yourself, and affirm your belief in
                                Spiritualism, saying, "It is a power that produces raps, tipping tables, writing, and
                                test-giving ; it is all done by power unseen." "For the devil has come down unto you,
                                having great wrath, because he knoweth his time is short."—Thus you admit yourself to
                                have been a medium for the devil to use in misleading humanity. Do not wish you to come
                                here—better repent. Respectfully,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rambling thoughts" TEIform="index"/>RAMBLING THOUGHTS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName"/>Abraham Perkins</byline><p TEIform="p">Happiness is the pursuit of all men. How singularly strange the course of many to find it!
                            Unto this most valuable and inestimable prize, heaven opens the door. There only is to be
                            found genuine peace and durable comfort. He who appeals to the natural instincts of his own
                            unregenerated heart for happiness is sure to fail in the enterprise ; while he, who in his
                            life is governed by the revelation of light and truth unto him manifested, putting his trust
                            in God, is equally sure of success. No honest individual will be left in darkness. Though
                            the struggle be long and the conflict severe, in his research for happiness supreme, a wise
                            provision is made to accomplish the object sought; ultimately, man will be led to the
                            knowledge of all truth. As true as there is a God, so sure is he to fulfill all his promises
                            to man ; for he hath declared, that whosoever seeks him shall find him. Therefrom we are to
                            learn, that such receive the baptism of the spirit of God and come into possession of the
                            elements of eternal life. Such have found the Comforter, a balm for every wound and woe. He
                            who fosters the spirit which courts mortal frailties, who dwells upon human weaknesses,
                            whose strong sympathies are with the weak and faulty, is exposed to become blind to truth
                            and a subject to the same spirit. Thus the miud becomes shrouded in darkness, the soul is
                            led irresistibly into error and the affections are alienated ; all of which combined,
                            culminate in ruin. The wise will beware of sympathizing with the murmurer, fault finder and
                            complainer, and will shun the idler, the gossiper and the traducer of character. Their
                            friendship is as deadly as the poison of asps or as microbes which cause the immense suf-
                            fering and mortality to so many of our race. ( Enfield, N. H. *</p></div2><pb n="15" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bible study" TEIform="index"/>BIBLE STUDY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, A. G." TEIform="persName"/>A. G. HOLLISTER</byline><p TEIform="p">The Bible is regarded by nearly all Protestant denominations, as the Word of God, and by many
                            of their teachers, as an infallible standard and test for all revealed truth. By revealed
                            truth, is here meant religious truth made known by Divine inspiration and spiritual wor-
                            ship. Believers in Christ's second appearing distinguish between the Word of God, which is
                            life-giving or "living and powerful, sharper than a two-edged sword," and the Bible, which
                            is a man made record of portions of the Word, uttered from two to six thousand years ago.
                            The living Word proceeds now in the forming work of a new Creation, which springs upon the
                            decay of the old, and absorbs its vital forces as the germ of a sprouting seed absorbs the
                            vitality of its environing mass, and leaves the lifeless shell to decompose in the earth. As
                            the word of God to Adam was not sufficient direction for Noah—nor the word to Noah
                            sufficient for Abraham—so the word to Abraham was not sufficient for Moses, nor for Elijah,
                            Jeremiah and Daniel. And as the Word received by all these together was not sufficient to
                            direct Jesus Christ in his work, but each messenger of a dispensation required a special
                            Word to qualify him for the work to which he was called, so also was there a special Word
                            not recorded in the Bible, given to our Mother, to enable her to perform the increasing work
                            which God required in her day and time. And there must always be a living Word of God in his
                            church, for present Divine direction, so long as God has a covenant people on Earth. There
                            is no contradiction in the living Word, however numerous its messengers, and this is one of
                            the criterions whereby it is known to be true, coming as it does through different
                            witnesses. Neither has that Word ever set limits to the future increase of its utterance and
                            operations among the children of God. Though at times inoperative, or unperceived for a
                            season, it has ever been renewed with increasing power. This admitted, some have claimed
                            that the present Word of God is sufficient, and those guided thereby have no need to know
                            the past. Others rely wholly upon the ancient record, to the exclusion of the life-giving
                            present, assuming that the former is sufficient for all time. It would be just as reasonable
                            to conclude that the sunshine of two thousand years ago, gave sufficient light and heat for
                            all time, and that consequently there is no further need for the sun to shine. But both
                            assumptions are partial and one-sided. Both set up arbitrary limits to understanding. Both
                            admit portions of the truth, and reject its complementary equivalents necessary to complete
                            knowledge. Hence either method pursued alone does not lead to satisfactory results. They
                            need combining, as really as do the primary colors of light, to make a perfect whole, with
                            which to detect error and avoid mistakes. Whatever may be the Word uttered, knowledge
                            thereof is graded to the understanding of the party receiving it. Understanding is a product
                            of instruction and experience. The less experience and less instruction, other things being
                            equal, the less power of comprehension. . Those races of the earth who have <pb n="16" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> THF MANIFESTO. 15 BIBLE STUDY. A. G. HOLLISTER. The Bible is regarded by
                            nearly all Protestant denominations, as the Word of God, and by many of their teachers, as
                            an infallible standard and test for all revealed truth. By revealed truth, is here meant
                            religious truth made known by Divine inspiration and spiritual worship. Believers in
                            Christ's second appearing distinguish between the Word of God, which is life-giving or
                            "living and powerful, sharper than a two-edged sword," and the Bible, which is a man made
                            record of portions of the Word, uttered from two to six thousand years ago. The living Word
                            proceeds now in the forming work of a new Creation, which springs upon the decay of the old,
                            and absorbs its vital forces as the germ of a sprouting seed absorbs the vitality of its
                            environing mass, and leaves the lifeless shell to decompose in the earth. As the word of God
                            to Adam was not sufficient direction for Noah—nor the word to Noah sufficient for Abraham—so
                            the word to Abraham was not sufficient for Moses, nor for Elijah, Jeremiah and Daniel. And
                            as the Word received by all these together was not sufficient to direct Jesus Christ in his
                            work, but each messenger of a dispensation required a special Word to qualify him for the
                            work to which he was called, so also was there a special Word not recorded in the Bible,
                            given to our Mother, to enable her to perform the increasing work which God required in her
                            day and time. And there must always be a living Word of God in his church, for present
                            Divine direction, so long as God has a covenant people on Earth. There is no contradiction
                            in the living Word, however numerous its messengers, and this is one of the criterions
                            whereby it is known to be true, coming as it does through different witnesses. Neither has
                            that Word ever set limits to the future increase of its utterance and operations among the
                            children of God. Though at times inoperative, or unperceived for a season, it has ever been
                            renewed with increasing power. This admitted, some have claimed that the present Word of God
                            is sufficient, and those guided thereby have no need to know the past. Others rely wholly
                            upon the ancient record, to the exclusion of the life-giving present, assuming that the
                            former is sufficient for all time. It would be just as reasonable to conclude that the
                            sunshine of two thousand years ago, gave sufficient light and heat for all time, and that
                            consequently there is no further need for the sun to shine. But both assumptions are partial
                            and one-sided. Both set up arbitrary limits to understanding. Both admit portions of the
                            truth, and reject its complementary equivalents necessary to complete knowledge. Hence
                            either method pursued alone does not lead to satisfactory results. They need com- bining, as
                            really as do the primary colors of light, to make a perfect whole, with which to detect
                            error and avoid mistakes. Whatever may be the Word uttered, knowledge thereof is graded to
                            the understanding of the party receiving it. Understanding is a product of instruction and
                            experience. The less experience and less instruction, other things being equal, the less
                            power of comprehension. . Those races of the earth who have <pb n="17" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. the discriminating faculty which the Creator gave them, have separated between
                            wheat and cheat, and found by practicing the restraints commanded, that error is condemned
                            and truth sustained. For be it understood, that the Bible has no light in itself, but like a
                            mirror, reflects back into the mind, the light of the intelligence shed upon it, sometimes
                            with added intensity. Should we have Bible Classes for acquiring a knowledge of Scripture,
                            and of the Faith of Believers in Christ's Second Appearing, as illustrated and confirmed
                            thereby? It seems to the writer that if properly organized and conducted, no literary study
                            can be more profitable, for its illuminating effects, the growth of spiritual understanding,
                            and for the increase, spread, and building up of our most precious faith. Precious indeed
                            because it saves the obedient from sin, and from the doleful consequences thereof. Doubly
                            precious because scarce, which caused Jesus to ask "When the Son of man cometh, will he find
                            faith on the earth?" As no one mind possesses all knowledge nor all wisdom, unless it be the
                            mind that was in Jesus Christ and our first gospel Parents, it would seem best to be guided
                            in our interpretations by the concurring testimony, so far as it can be ascertained, of the
                            true witnesses of Christ, who have lived his life by following his example of virgin purity.
                            I mean the Apostles both of his first and second appearing. For manners and customs of
                            people in Bible lands, and for critical meanings of original words, we will have to rely
                            upon scholars who have made such matters their study. Focusing the attention of many minds
                            on the subject in connection with the in- creasing development of God's spiritual work in
                            late years will afford greater light for the elucidation of many topics, and for clearer
                            interpretations of some matters heretofore obscure. Perhaps improvements may be made upon
                            explanations formerly given, but all harmo- nizing with each other, and with the united
                            testimony of previous witnesses. Because as truth is a unit, and cannot conflict with
                            itself, all contradiction partakes of faLehood, and is ruled out by the laws of evidence.
                            But since truth has many various aspects when seen from different standpoints,
                            interpretations also may be various without conflicting. An original, unsupported witness or
                            testimony, has little or no weight. But when one witness or truth confirms another, both are
                            strengthened thereby, and the greater the number of reliable witnesses or truths, affirming
                            a position or fact, the more firmly said position or fact is established in our confidence.
                            The word of God is truth, and as every truth is in substantial agreement with every other
                            truth on the same plane, it is written that k'by the mouth of two or three witnesses shall
                            every word be established." If we reject the ancient record of the true abiding Word of God,
                            because of a present living Word which is most necessary for us, we reject a valuable and
                            important witness, and weaken our own testimony by so much. No one need believe these
                            positions unless they are true in fact and seeming. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="He who hath truth on the tongue replies readily" TEIform="index"/>
                            He who hath truth on the tongue replies readily
                        </head><p TEIform="p">He who hath truth on the tongue replies readily.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ill-will, like the blighting frost, destroys life's sweetest blossoms" TEIform="index"/>
                            Ill-will, like the blighting frost, destroys life's sweetest blossoms
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Ill-will, like the blighting frost, destroys life's sweetest blossoms.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. A.</byline></div2><pb n="18" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Manifesto, January, 1889. Office of Publication" TEIform="index"/>THE MANIFESTO. JANUARY,
                            1889. Office of Publication</head><p TEIform="p">The Manifesto is published on the first of each month, at Shaker Village, Mer. Co., N. H. All
                            articles for publication should be addressed to Henry CBonn, and all letters on financial
                            business to A. Y. Cochran. One copy per year, postage paid, " six months, " Send for
                            specimen copy, free. .75 .40</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editoria[l]</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Welcome, new year" TEIform="index"/>WELCOME, NEW YEAR</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Passing along from month to month and from year to year with the testimony of the cross
                                of Christ, which we have made to be our testimony, we have now reached the initial
                                number of the nineteenth volume of The Manifesto. Even this willing perseverance in a
                                good work, this faithful continuance in a Christian duty that we owe to God and man, is
                                sufficient cause'for great thankfulness. All the crosses and trials that we have passed
                                through, and all the anxieties and even vexations that have at times filled our minds
                                should now vanish like the mist before the morning sun. A new year has come to greet us,
                                a series of twelve months are preparing to bear us company on our pilgrimage to the Holy
                                City. With the introduction of a New Year so auspicious, so effulgent with light from
                                God, so anticipatory of righteousness and peace, our hearts cannot fail to rejoice. If
                                led by the spirit of God, and thereby becoming the sons and daughters of God, our
                                mission before the children of this world, although manifested in a still, small voice,
                                cannot fail to exert an influence for good and inspire souls to look forward to a better
                                and to a brighter day. Our mission inasmuch as it harmonizes with that of the apostolic
                                church, should be aggressive against that which is wrong, must fight the good fight of
                                faith and overcome all the powers of darkness. Through the manifestation of this spirit
                                which crucifies the elements of a worldly life, we may rest assured that its influence
                                will carry God's precious goodness wherever it may chance to fall. We need have no doubt
                                of our success, if our hearts are pure, as that insures us an entrance into the Kingdom
                                of our Heavenly Father. Those who have written in the past, will not fail to write again
                                and again, as growth in the mind by cultivation, is as valuable in this department, as
                                growth and value can be in any other. Those who have not written or who have been
                                parsimonious, will study with profit this brief but valuable lesson. "Like begets like."
                                An active interest in the cultivation of that wThich is good and profitable, will
                                stimulate a greater and greater zeal in the same work, till it culminates in an interest
                                for God that can never grow dim. Whoever writes in the fulness of the light which God
                                gives them, and in prayer for the peace and prosperity of others cannot fail to
                                accomplish a <pb n="19" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE .MANIFESTO. 19 good work for themselves and a
                                corresponding one for their readers. It does not need an elaborate discourse on
                                speculative theology nor a lengthy dissertation on prophecies and mira- cles to direct a
                                fellow pilgrim on the way to the cross or to give him an introduction to Evangelist or
                                to any other of the heavenly guides. The simple story of right over wrong has nothing
                                mysterious, requires no commentary, not even a biblical Diction- ary. It enters at once
                                upon an assurance which cannot fail. "Blessed are the poor in spirit for theirs is the
                                Kingdom of Heaven." Any wayfaring man can easily comprehend a message so concise and so
                                in sympathy with the human heart. In this number we have published the Covenant of the
                                Church. A document of great importance to the Community and about which many who are not
                                intimately acquainted with the Society, have had much to say. To give the work a careful
                                perusal will be time well spent, as this is an essential part of the foundation of
                                Community life, and upon which every one must build to become successful. The first
                                Covenant for the Society was written in the year 1796. Since that date several articles
                                have been added till in 1832 the present form was written and signed by the then adult
                                members, and then by all accessions of members since that time. Probationary or
                                Novitiate members on entering the Society are expected to sign The Articles of
                                Agreement, which stipulates briefly what the Society will do, and also what the new
                                member agrees to do. Too much care cannot be exercised in holding this covenant and
                                these articles of agreement in their respective places and in seeing that the names of
                                all who have reached the age of majority are clearly entered, in the presence of
                                witnesses, to the one that is deemed expedient.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vegetarianism" TEIform="index"/>VEGETARIANISM</head><p TEIform="p">An antiquarian is not one whu eats antiquities, neither is a vegetarian one who eats only
                                vegetables, although Webster's definition conveys this meaning: "Vegetarian: One who
                                holds that vegetables constitute the only proper food for man, and who Jives solely upon
                                them." The definition given by the Vegetarian Society is as follows : "A vegetarian diet
                                consists of the products of the vegetable kingdom—chiefly grains, pulse, fruits, and
                                nuts—with or without the addition of eggs, milk and its products, as cheese and butter
                                to the exclusion of the flesh of animals (fish^ flesh and fowl,) and its products, as
                                fat, dripping, lard, suet, etc." The definition given in The Imperial Dictionary of the
                                English Language, by John Ogilvie, London, corresponds with the latter definition.
                                "Vegetarian : One who abstains from animal food and lives exclusively on vegetables,
                                eggs, milk, etc. Strict vegetarians eat vegetables and farinaceous food only, and will
                                not eat butter, eggs, or even milk." According to Prof! Mayor, of Cambridge, England,
                                vegetable and vegetarian are not synonymous, the latter being a newly-coined word, which
                                has the meaning given in the last two explanations. Assuming the latter definition, let
                                us glance at the opinions of a few of the World's greatest thinkers, concerning a
                                Vegetarian Diet. Baron Cuvier says: "The natural food of man, judging from his
                                structure, appears to consist principally of the fruits, roots, and other succulent
                                parts of vegetables."-^Animal Kingdom, p. 46. Prof. Lawrence en- <pb n="20" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/>
                                20 THE MANIFESTO. larges on this idea as follows : "The teeth of man have not the
                                slightest resemblance to those of the carnivorous animals, except that their enamel is
                                confined to the external surface. He possesses, indeed, teeth called'canine,' but they
                                do not exceed the level of the others, and are obviously unsuited to the purposes which
                                the corresponding teeth execute in carnivorous animals. * * * Whether we consider the
                                teeth and jaws, or the immediate instruments of digestion, the human structure closely
                                resembles that of the simicB; all of which, in their natural state, are completely
                                herbivorous."—Lectures on Physiology, pp. 189-191. Linnaeus confirms their decision in
                                the words : "This species of food (fruit) is that which is most suitable to man, which
                                is evinced by the series of quadrupeds, analogy, wild men, apes, the structure of the
                                mouth, of the stomach and the hands."—Linncci Amcemtates Academical, vol. x, p. 8. As to
                                the possibility of fully supporting human life by a Vegetarian Diet, Sir Henry Thompson
                                writes: "The vegetable eater, pure and simple, can extract from his food all the
                                principles necessary for the growth and support of the body, as well as for the
                                production of heat and force."—Food and Feeding, p. 11. To the same question Liebig
                                answers moie minutely : "Grain and other nutritious vegetables yield us, not only in
                                starch, sugar, and gum, the carbon which protects our organs from the action of oxygen,
                                and produces in the organism the heat which is essential to life, but also in the form
                                of vegetable fibrine, albumen, and caseine, the elements of our blood from which the
                                other parts of our body are developed. * * Vegetable fibrine and animal Sbrine,
                                vegetable albumen and animal albumen, hardly differ, even in form; * * and when they are
                                present the graminivorous animal obtains in its food the very same principles, on the
                                presence of which the nutrition of the car- nivora entirely depends." In addition to the
                                arguments set forth by the preceding writers, we must remember that, under the most
                                favorable circumstances the flesh of animals can never be free from impurities. The
                                process of waste and repair is constantly going on in the living body, and hence there
                                is always present in the sys- tem a certain amount of broken-down cell tissue, which is
                                on its way to the excretory outlets of the system. If this process is suddenly stopped
                                by killing the animal, this effete matter, together with the impure venous blood which
                                is in the capillaries (a large proportion) remains in the flesh, rendering it impure and
                                unhealthy. If in addition, the animals are actually diseased, as good authorities say 80
                                per cent, are, caused by immature breeding and putting them in an unnatural condition by
                                fattening and shipping in crowded freight cars, flesh-eating becomes actually dangerous.
                                It is now well known that not only the different parasitic diseases may be communicated
                                to man, but pleuropneumonia, erysipelas, swine typhoid, cattleplague, and foot-and-mouth
                                disease, aie also transmissible to man. With the Biblical student the following
                                Scripture verse has great weight, no mention whatever being made of flesh foods:
                                "Behold, I have given you every herb bearing seed which is upon the face of all the
                                earth, and every tree in which is the fruit of a tree yielding seed; to you it shall be
                                for meat."—Gen. i., 29. The attention of those who long and sigh for beauty, which " * *
                                * * gives The features perfectness, and to the form Its delicate proportions," is
                                directed to the statement of Adam Smith in his Wealth of Nations, that the most beau-
                                tiful women in the British dominions are found among the lower ranks of the people of
                                Ireland, who are generally fed with potatoes. Also, to the Scriptural fact that Dan- iel
                                and his companions, who ate grain and pulse, were "fairer and fatter in flesh than all
                                the children which did eat the portions of the king's meat."—Dan. i., 15. Those who live
                                on a Vegetarian Diet are, as a rule, heavier, stronger in muscle, and capable of greater
                                endurance than those who live on a mixed diet. Prof. Forbes, from experiments on
                                "flesh-eating Englishmen, porridge-eating Scotchmen, and potato-andbread-eating
                                Irishmen" proved that the Scotchmen and Irishmen were superior in height, weight and
                                strength to the Englishmen. "The Laplanders, living on flesh, are <pb n="21" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/>
                                THE MANIFESTO. 21 a diminutive race, while the Finns, who in. habit the same climate and
                                live chiefly on the products of the soil, are as fine a race as the Swedes and
                                Norwegians. The difference," says Dr. Lamb, "must be attributed mainly or entirely to
                                diet." Although at present we may or may not eat flesh as we choose, the time will come
                                when all must be vegetarians. Already flesh is ten to twenty times more expensive than
                                wheat, oatmeal, peas, lentils, etc., considering the amount of solid substsnce in each,
                                and the price of the former is gradually increasing. Land which is cultivated for
                                grains, fruits, and vegetables, provides employment for several times as many men as
                                that which is used for raising stocj;; and, as the population gradually becomes more
                                dense stock-raising for food purposes will decline more and more, and finally become a
                                thing of the past.—Student Life.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What an appetite" TEIform="index"/>WHAT AN APPETITE</head><p TEIform="p">There is no accounting for tastes. No person with a natural appetite can tell why another
                                likes food which is rank, or partially decayed, nor can bees tell why, when they are
                                sipping nectar from the flowers, buzzards should be flying overhead looking out for of-
                                fal and carrion. These are simply matters of taste and nature. So there are men who are
                                inclined to smut and filth and scandal, and who smile and smirk and grin and gloat over
                                vice and vileness, and who continually pry and peddle in this line. One can hardly be in
                                their company for an hour without listening to smutty talk, questionable stories, and
                                scandalous reports. They gather such things from all quarters. What they cannot gather
                                they invent. What they hear from others they embellish, and what they have gathered,
                                invented, and embellished, they peddle. There are men who profess to be ministers of the
                                gospel who need a conversion that shall give them clean hearts and clean tongues, for so
                                long as men lack that purity of heart which God bestows by the power of the Holy Spirit
                                so long will the results of early education, vile surroundings, bad training, exhibit
                                themselves ; until they are thoroughly and soundly saved, we shall find such persons,
                                whatever their professions or positions may be, returning to the blackguardism of their
                                early days like the dog to his vomit, and the sow that was washed to her wallowing in
                                the mire. — Good Way.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Monday, December 31, 1888" TEIform="index"/>MONDAY, DEC. 31, 1888</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>Mary Whitcher</byline><p TEIform="p">And lo ! the year has ended ! And I am left to ask How have my labors tended And how
                            performed my task? Have I been truly faithful To do the little good, And ever anxious,
                            prayerful For more, whene'er I could Perform a further labor For Zion and Her cause, With
                            care for sister, brother, And for Her sacred laws. Doth injury to self-hood Affect mj7
                            feelings more Than to the cause of Zion And those who've gone before? Let this reflection
                            prompt me To greater zeal and care For Zion and Her int'rests While self doth disappear. Let
                            me renew my patience My love for all that's true, My thankfulness and earnestness Dear
                            Sisters, 'long with you. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Coming millennium" TEIform="index"/>COMING MILLENNIUM</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dibble, Chancy" TEIform="persName"/>Chancy Dibble</byline><p TEIform="p">"Come, Lord, in thy own time and pleasure. Send by whom thou wilt. May the King of Glory
                            descend, seated upon his Throne. May thine elect be caught up, and unbelievers peri-h be-
                            neath thy feet." Similar to this are the prayers offered up from many a pulpit for ages.
                            Dees any sensible Christian <pb n="22" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 22 THE MANIFESTO. in these 1hvs suppose
                            that Christ is coming to save a few and sink sinners to perdition? Does the kind Father
                            propose to usber in the reign of happiness over the endless miseiy of a large portion of his
                            intelligences? Rather has not C-Jod designed from the beginning to purge out the evil from
                            every human heart and thereby unite all as one family. Thus are our prayers answered ; "Thy
                            Kingdom Come, Thy will be done on Earth." Watervliet, N. Y..</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>Juvenile</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, Connecticut, January 1889" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, Conn., Jan. 1889</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Children :—-A Happy New Year. We wish you this, but wishes alone can do very little
                                toward securing to you the greatest blessing—real happiness, which is the reward for
                                individual effort. The happiest persons are not those who have the most done for them,
                                but those who do the most for others. Happy are those who make others happy. Be true and
                                virtuous. Virtue alone is happiness, happiness is heaven. "So happy and free, so happy
                                and free The followers of Jesus forever will be." Would you be virtuous? Look to the
                                virtuous and follow the virtuous. Virtuous lives bring blessings to those who live them,
                                and blessings to those who follow them. The beginning of the New Year is the time for
                                correcting the mistakes of the past, and the earnest resolve to avoid them in future.
                                Good resolves even give hope and encouragement, and happiness comes as you keep these
                                resolves. In a sincere resolution to win, there is a promise of winning. Perse" viT.inco
                                overcomes obstacles. Bear this in mind, and by doing your whole duty, enjoy a whole year
                                of unbroken happiness. The heavenly prize is within your reach, and it is worthy of your
                                greatest effort. Wrestle for it. Subdue your inborn selfishness. Help each other in all
                                good work. Love good, for the sake of pure goodness, and shun evil, because evil is sin.
                                Brighten your records with purity and truth. Build up good characters. Reform your
                                little selves, and you have begun to reform the world. Avoid deceit. "Be what you seem,
                                and seem what you should be, children of truth, from all dishonor free." Your Brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt</byline></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Brooklet" TEIform="index"/>THE BROOKLET</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Rullhousen, May" TEIform="persName"/>May Rullhausen</byline><p TEIform="p">Down from the heights of the mountain, Flowing without delay, Cometh the beautiful
                                brooklet, Day after day. Over the stones and the pebbles, Over the green soft moss,
                                Still in its curious winding, It keepeth its course. Under the cloud and the sunlight,
                                Under,the tall stately trees, Out in the clear air of heaven, 'Tis free as the breeze.
                                Passing through vales and through meadows, Rippling along with delight, Singing a song
                                full of music, Even at night. Dashing o'er rocks, full and bounding, Heaving and foaming
                                along, Evening and night, day and morning, Happy and strong. And where, O where art thou
                                going?— "On to the beautiful sea, Where I'll mingle my sparkling waters Lost ever to
                                thee." —Age 14 years. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prisoner's study" TEIform="index"/>A PRISONER'S STUDY</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A prisoner condemned to confinement for life, after a careful study of the
                                        Scriptures, found them to contain 3,586,489 letters. 773,692 words, 31,173
                                        verses, 1,183 chapters, and 66 books. The word "and" occurs 46,277 times; the
                                        word Lord 1.855 times : the word reverend <pb n="23" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO.
                                        23 only once, which is in the 9th verse of 111th Psalm. The middle is the 8th
                                        verse of the 118th Psalm. The 21st verse of the Gth chapter of Ezra contains all
                                        the letters of the alphabet with the exception of the letter J. The finest
                                        chapter to read is the 26th chapter of Acts of the Apostles ; the 19th chapter
                                        II Kings, and the 32d of Isaiah, are alike. The longest verse is the 9th verse
                                        in the eighth chapter of Esther. The shortest is the 35th of the 11th chapter of
                                        St. John. The 8th, 15th, 21st, and 31st verses of the 107th Psalm are the same.
                                        All the verses of the 136th Psalm end alike. There are no words or names of more
                                        than six syllables. The 117th Psalm is the middle and shortest chapter in the
                                        Bible. It must have taken him many years of patient, careful study to gather all
                                        these facts. We hope in such close perusal the Spirit revealed a deeper lesson
                                        to his heart and made him fully acquainted with its precious precepts. M. J. S.
                                        in the </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Christian union" TEIform="index"/>Christian Union</bibl></cit></p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="S., M. J." TEIform="persName"/></byline></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="St. Matthew XIII, from Tyndal's testament" TEIform="index"/>ST. MATT. XIII., EROM
                                TYNDAL'S TESTAMENT</head><p TEIform="p">The same daye wentt Jesus out of the housse, and satt by the see syde, and moche people
                                resorted unto him, so gretly that he wet and sat in a shyppe, and all the people stode
                                on the shoore. And he spake many thyngs to them in similituds, sayinge : behold the
                                sower went forth to sowe, and as he sowed, some fell by the wayes syde, and the fowlls
                                ca, and devoured it uppe. Some fell on stony grounde where it had nott moche erth, and a
                                non it spronge uppe, because it had no depth of erth • and when the son was uppe, hit
                                cauth heet, and for lak of rotynge wyd dred awaye. Some fell amonge thornes, and the
                                thornes arose, and chooked it. Parte fell in goode grounde, and broght forth good frute
                                : some an hundred fold, some fifty fold, some thyrty folde. Whosoever hath eares to
                                heare, let him heare. And hys disciples cam, and sayde to him : Why speakest thou to
                                them in parables : he answered and saide unto them : Hit is geven onto you to knowe the
                                secretts of the Kyngdome of he ven, but to them it is nott geven, for whosomever hath,
                                to him shall hit be gevne : and he shall have aboundance : But whosoevrr hath not: from
                                him shalbe takyn awaye eve that same that he hath.—Selected</p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Seeds of good and ill" TEIform="index"/>SEEDS 0F GOOD AND ILL
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">We are sowing, daily sowing, Countless seeds of good
                                        and ill, Scattered on the level low land, Cast upon the windy hill, Seeds that
                                        sink in rich, brown furrows, Soft with heaven's gracious rain. Seeds that rest
                                        upon the surface Of the dry, unyielding plain. Seeds that fall amid the
                                        stillness Of the lonely mountain glen, Seeds cast out in crowded places, Trodden
                                        under foot of men. Seeds by idle hearts forgotten, Flung at random in the air,
                                        Seeds by faithful souls remembered, Sown in tears and love and prayer. Seeds
                                        that lie unchanged, unquickened, Lifeless on the teeming mould Seeds that live
                                        and grow and flourish When the sower's hand is cold, By a whisper sow we
                                        blessing, By a breath we scatter strife, In our words and looks and actions Like
                                        the seeds of death and life. Thou who knowest all our weakness, Leave us not to
                                        sow alone, But Thine angels guard the furrows Where the precious grain is sown,
                                        Till the fields are crowned with glory, Filled with mellow ripened ears, Filled
                                        with fruit of life eternal From the seed we sow in tears. Check the forward
                                        thoughts and passion, Stay the hasty heedless hands, Lest the germ of sin and
                                        sorrow, Mar our fair and pleasant lands. Father, help each weak endeavor, Make
                                        each feeble effort blest, Till Thine harvest shall be garnered, And we enter
                                        into rest.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Catholic" TEIform="index"/>The Catholic.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><pb n="24" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Autobiography of a Shaker" TEIform="index"/>Autobiography of a Shaker
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>Elder F.W. Evans</byline><p TEIform="p">Autobiography of a Shaker (Elder, V. W. Evans.) A new and enlarged Edition with portrait.
                                This work has recently been published in Glasgow, Scotland, and contains some one
                                hundred and seventy pages. In an appendix to this new edition will be found, articles on
                                Shaker Communism, Shakerism in London, Enjr.. Shakers as Farmers, etc., etc. Elder
                                Frederic lias brought together in this work, many very interesting subjects, upon which
                                one may dwell with increasing pleasure and profit. Price $1.50. Address F.W. Evans, Mt.
                                Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>
                                The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health. Dei;. Contents: Wni.
                                E.Gladstone; Notable People; Adaptation: Dessie W. Fitzgerald; Getting Rested;
                                Vivativeness ; How to make Home Happy ; The Aryans; Southern California as a Health
                                Resort; View of the Shady Side of Civilization; Catarrh ; Sanitary Reform; Child
                                Culture; etc., etc. Fowler and Wells Co., 775 Broadway, N. Y. $1.50 per year. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/>Hall's
                                Journal of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Hall's
                                Journal of Health. Dec. Contents : Mind Cure Matter; Magnetic Hygiene ; What to Eat; The
                                Onion ; Good Living and the Brain; Plantains and Bananas ; Salt as a Medicine; Anecdote
                                of H. W. Beecher; A Good Work; Cuba's two Meals a Day ; Psychometric Power; Calisthenic
                                Exercises for Girls ; A Soldier Somnambulist; Treatment of Ingrowing Nail; etc., etc.
                                Office 206 Broadway, N. Y. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bible and land" TEIform="index"/>The Bible and Land
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Converse, James B." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The Bible and Land.—By Jambs B. Converse.—16 mo.—size 5x7
                                inches. 251 pp.—Neatly bound in cloth—Price $1.00 postpaid.—Published and for sale by
                                Rev. James B. Converse, MorRISTOWN, TENN. The table of contents of this "eminently
                                timely" book is as follows :. Chapter 1, The Creator's Title to Land; ch. 2, The
                                Problem: ch. 3, The Causes of Poverty; ch. 4, Land Values ; ch. 5, Grounds of Ownership;
                                ch. 6, The Terms of the Original Grant; ch. 7, Biblical Land Grants; ch. 8, The Land
                                Law? of Moses ; ch. 9, The Law of the Tithe ; ch. 19, The Prophets and Land; ch. 11, The
                                Bible and Liberty; ch. 12, God's Government and God's Land; ch. 13., The Future of Earth
                                ; Appendix of Proof Texts. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Convenient calendar and stand" TEIform="index"/>A Convenient Calender and Stand
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A Convenient Calender and Stand. The most convenient,
                                valuable, and novel business, table, or desk calendar for 1889, is the Columbia Bicycle
                                Calendar and Stand issued by the Pope Mfg. Co., of Boston, Mass. The calendar proper is
                                in the form of a pad of 365 leaves, one for each day. The leaves are 5%x2% inches, a
                                portion of each is left blank for memoranda, and as the leaves are sewed at the ends,
                                any entire leaf, as well as the memorandum blank, can be exposed whenever desired. The
                                pad rests upon a portable stand, and when placed upon the desk or writing table the
                                entire surface of the date leaf is brought directly before the eye, furnishing date and
                                memoranda impossible to be overlooked. The upper portion of the stand is made of pressed
                                pulp, with "Columbia" in raised letters at the top, the whole handsomely gilded, and
                                practically indestructible. Although this is the fourth year of the Columbia calendar,
                                the quotations are fresh and new, and are interesting and instructive to the public as
                                well as to the cycler. A departure is made this year, in that a portion of the
                                quotations pertain to typewriting and stenography, with occasional reference to the new
                                Becker typewriter made by the Pope Mfg. Co. The reading matter in no way interferes with
                                the calendar, and the information contained on the leaves would, if placed in book type,
                                make a fair sized volume.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Randolph, John W." TEIform="index"/>John W. Randolph
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Randolph, John W." TEIform="persName">John W. Randolph</persName>, at Watervliet, N. Y.,
                                Nov. 8, 1888. Age 75 yrs.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Webb, Rachel" TEIform="index"/>Rachel Webb
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Webb, Rachel" TEIform="persName">Rachel Webb</persName>, at Watervliet, N. Y., Dec. 6, 1888.
                                Age 64 yrs. and 3 mo.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prentiss, Sylvester" TEIform="index"/>Sylvester Prentiss
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Prentiss, Sylvester" TEIform="persName">Sylvester Prentiss</persName>, at Watervliet, N. Y.,
                                Nov. 22, 1888. Age 82 yrs, 2 mo. and 28 days. He had lived in the Community sixty years.
                                Brother Sylvester was a peacemaker, and loved by all for his kindness and unswerving
                                integrity to the Cause. His noble example was a safe pattern for all to follow and he
                                will be held in loving remembrance by his many gospel friends. J. B.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pretch, Charles" TEIform="index"/>Charles Pretch
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Pretch, Charles" TEIform="persName">Charles Pretch</persName>, at Watervliet, N. Y. Nov. 24,
                                1888. Age 72 yrs. and 11 mo.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Buxton, Josiah" TEIform="index"/>Josiah Buxton
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Buxton, Josiah" TEIform="persName">Josiah Buxton</persName>, at Center Family, Union
                                Village, Ohio. Dec 12, 1888. Age 58 yrs. 6 mo. and 6 days.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Advertisements" TEIform="index"/>[Advertisements]</head><p TEIform="p">[Advertisements deleted.]</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>