<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0712" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shakers, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">7</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">12</biblScope><date value="18771201" TEIform="date">December 1877</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">89-96</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="7" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="89" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="12" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--THE SHAKER. OFFICIAL MONTHLY.—PUBLISHED By THE UNITED SOCIETIES. " Ha $reiul\ the kingdom of §»od!" JP# testimony of
                        eternal t\uth. Vol. VII. G. A. LOMAS, Editok, 1 Shakers, N. Y. DECEMBER, 1877. N. A. BRIGGS, PlJBLISHEK, Shaker
                        Village, N. H. ~No. 12.--><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What lack I yet?" TEIform="index"/>"WHAT LACK I YET?"</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, James G." TEIform="persName"/>JAMES G. RUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p">Good master, what would'st thou have me to do, That I may have eternal life in thee? I seek a
                            part within thy kingdom new; What further sacrifice remains for me ? The things that thou
                            hast mentioned—all h ;\e 1 Most sacredly observed, and ever set My heart intent on
                            godliness, whereby I would in truth be free: what lack I yet? Loved one—the goodly master
                            now responds— If perfect thou would'st toe, go sell thine all, And give unto the poor,
                            release their bonds, Then come and follow me. Most blessed call! And yet behold the
                            sorrowful effect! The sacrifice too great, for great indeed Were earth's possessions, thus
                            to resurrect And unto God the miser'd soul to lead. Away the anxious face with sorrow turns,
                            With feelings of dismay and deep regret, Though for eternal life the spirit yearns— Comes
                            forth in words of grief—much lack I yet! Ah, is the sacrifice too great to make ? A life of
                            woridliness to lay- aside? The Christian pathway cheerfully to take ? And in the loving
                            grace of God abide ? Thou surely shalt have treasures stored in heaven, If cheerfully the
                            price thou'lt fully pay, If unto God thy time and strength be given, To walk with care the
                            self-denjing way, Though worldly riches be the selfish part, That calls for sacrifice,
                            though great or small, Or be the idol sinfumess of heart, That seeks indulgence, allied to
                            the fall; Whatever be the part for sacrifice, If God's pure love is all in all to thee, From
                            worldly loves and pleasures thou may'st rise, And in my kingdom have a part with me.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes by the way, no. 12" TEIform="index"/>NOTES BY THE WAY.—No. 12</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/>H. C. BLINN</byline><p TEIform="p">I could probably have no better subject for my closing "notes" in our little missionary of
                            "Good News," than that which has for some time past had a growing interest in our mountain
                            home. As strange as it may seem, it is nevertheless true, that a revival of the temperance
                            question, as belonging expressly to our order, has been occupying the minds of both old and
                            young. Quite a number from our family attended the State Temperance Convention, and heard
                            many earnest and faithful advocates for the cause. We also heard, and some of us for the
                            first time, the recital of those wrongs and sufferings which arise from the use of alcoholic
                            drinks. While we listened, we pitied, as we knew many were asking others to do what they
                            were unable to accomplish themselves. We knew, also, that we already belonged to an order
                            that sought earnestly to cultivate the principles of temperance through the blessings of the
                            cross of Christ. Privileged, as we are, to live among the "sober, righteous and godly in
                            this present world," many who are young had not the least idea of the sorrow and shame
                            intemperance was bringing to the thousands of young men and women. The sad confession which
                            some made of their first steps in wrong by drinking beer or cider, and from this going on
                            and on with alcoholic drinks till they finally ended as confirmed drunkards, has awakened a
                            thought in many young minds of the danger there is, not only in the drinking of beer and
                            cider, but in a habit only a fraction less reprehensible, and that is, the chewing and
                            smoking of tobacco. Better never begin. It has been said that "the error of a moment is
                            often the sorrow of a life ;" and perhaps this is never more fully realized than in the
                            cases of those who, from lack of moral courage, yield themselves a prey to the irreligious
                            or unprincipled. Intemperance has really become a burden in the land. The inordinate desire
                            which many have for external appearances, as the furnishing of their residences, their
                            articles of apparel, the expense of their table, the cigars to be smoked, the liquor to be
                            drank, obliges them to spend large sums of money belonging to themselves 6r others. All the
                            injury to others, and the ruin to themselves, arising from this intemperate course, is now
                            termed "Liabilities." The word embodies every form of dissipation. But I must bear in mind
                            the P2ditor's advice, and not be too lengthy.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Duplicity" TEIform="index"/>DUPLICITY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ervin, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>ANNA ERVIN</byline><p TEIform="p">]A distinguished divine inquires: "Who is the prophet that shall uncover the abysses of our
                            acted lies?" Were this ever true of those who profess to be Christians? When is the rugged,
                            truthspeaking, Christian time coming? are queries of no trifling moment; when all shall be
                            what they seem, and cease to seem what they are not. Have you ever socially trusted another
                            from appearances implicitly, and afterwards been rejected for no good and sufficient reason?
                            How liable are such lessons of experience to make us doubtful of human fidelity. A friend,
                            in whose presence we may not think aloud, should be regarded as an acquaintance, but never
                            trusted as a true friend. Let all earnestly strive to make this life as productive of good
                            as it shall be when duplicity, dissembling and hypocrisy are only known as things thai were,
                            and are not.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Glories of Mt. Lebanon" TEIform="index"/>GLORIES OF MT. LEBANON</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p">____ i For sixty and nine years I have lived, 1 moved and had my being in this mundane
                            sphere. During all that time, I have not seen so perfect a year for weather as 1877 has thus
                            far proved to be. Lights and shades, heat and cold, rain and drouth have alternated each
                            other, keeping our hopes and fears all the time in action. Yet no harm has befallen us.
                            Neither flood nor rain, frost nor blight, hail storm nor heat has harmed us in the holy
                            mountain. Is our climate improving? progressing? or to what shall we attribute a constant
                            succession of enjoyable days and nights, without a drawback ? I am an unfailing" friend of
                            the weather ; never fail to be inwardly thankful for its abundance : never grumble at it,
                            nor call it wicked names ; do not complain when it is hot nor cold, nor, under any
                            circumstances, do I utter disrespectful phrases about it; when it is a pleasant day, never
                            call it "a weather breeder !" nor forget the good of to-day in dark forebodings of
                            to-morrow. In fact, I enjoy the weather, more especially Attierican zveather, in our
                            temperate zone—cannot imagine anything more perfect than the weather that we have been
                            blessed with in 1877 ! It has been a continual feast of good things, filling our hearts with
                            gratitude and praise, as water flowing from a fountain. All the elements seem tuned to
                            harmony— full of blessing. To be in unison with God, with the people of God, with all the
                            visible heavens and earth, is happiness—is life to a devotional, worshipful spirit. Were I a
                            poet, I would sing the perfection of Mt. Lebanon weather, as against all the earth.
                            Mosquitoes cannot live in it—flies are simply harmless scavengers—snakes are a pleasant curi
                            osity—centipedes and gallinippers as rare as wolves, bears, panthers or tigers. The absent
                            evils, that we know only by name, are replaced with pure mountain springs of water, so good
                            that no excuse remains to us, as is so common to the west and south, to put into our drink
                            some foreign substance. Temperance is our normal condition. The air we breathe into our
                            lungs is pure as the love that fills our hearts. Whether it be England or Scotland, France
                            or Italy, California or Texas, Louisiana or Kentucky, or even Maine or New Hampshire, we can
                            still see some infliction to which we are not subject,—something undesirable, that we have
                            not. Is it not good to be so fully established in our own minds, and to realize that
                            whatever good we do thus possess, it is not at the expense of our neighbors? None are the
                            poorer for it, nor the sufferers by it.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Not by observation" TEIform="index"/>NOT BY OBSERVATION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hastings, Marcia" TEIform="persName"/>MARCIA HASTINGS</byline><p TEIform="p">"The kingdom of God cometh not by observation." By observation, we lave found this to be
                            true. Persons do lot receive the baptism of the holy spirit immediately and exclusively
                            through the intellect It reaches first n its validity the soul, and there begins ts
                            operation. The intellect may and should be a power to weigh the consistency of all tenets of
                            religion which the spirit accepts; but seldom, if ever, does it supersede the soul's feeling
                            ; the nonreasoning, absorbent, faculty of intuition. Reason may sit as judge to determine
                            the efficacy of bias in conscience ; regulate the enthusiasm that commonly attends newly
                            received truths, and help to sift the manifestation thereof. But whoever depends on
                            intellect alone for conviction and conversion, will wait long before the illumination
                            manifests itself to effect the new birth. When the testimony of cleansing truth shall reach
                            a sincere seeker after righteousness—a soul sick of sin and weary of the dominance of animal
                            appetites—groping in human blindness, and intently desiring emancipation, then that soul
                            will hardly stop for logic or nice points in argument; yet may profitablv obey the
                            injunction to "try the spirit," and the witness will appear ; will be unmistakably felt,
                            that the kingdom of God is within reach. "If ye do the works, then shall ye know of the
                            doctrine ; " and if ye will accept the testimony of those who confidently report from
                            experience, this rich knowledge, and confirmation, happy will ye be in finding yourselves in
                            a way to possess the pearl of great price, the inheritance of righteousness, "the kingdom of
                            God which cometh not by observation." Canterbury, N. H. </p><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bashfullness is more connected with good sense..." TEIform="index"/>Bashfullness is more connected with good sense...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Bashfulness is more frequently connected with good sense, than we find assurance; and
                                impudence, on the other hand, is often themere effect of downright stupidity.</p></div3></div2><pb n="90" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Is this Christ our exampler?" TEIform="index"/>IS THIS CHRIST OUR EXAMPLER?</head><byline TEIform="byline">SERMON BY <persName reg="Ballou, Adin" TEIform="persName"/>ADIN BALLOU</byline><p TEIform="p">* * * "But I am asked, what is there in Christ or his religion so very important and
                            indispensable to human happiness? I answer, A true and perfect righteousness—Godward,
                            manward, soulward, earthward and heavenward. He was righteous in all these directions,
                            righteous in his ruling motives, his principles, his spirit, his conduct and his character.
                            Every human being must become righteous in all these respects, or be unhappy to the extent
                            he falls short of the pattern. Christ's religion governs man internally. It presides in a
                            region which no human law, power, or system of arrangement, can reach. It deals with the
                            inmost springs of human thought, desire, feeling and action—with the loves, affections,
                            passions and sentimental emotions from which issue forth all the external manifestations of
                            life. Its business is to purify, regulate and reduce to true order the heart, its will, its
                            motives and ruling principles— in a word, to render the soul internally wise and good, and
                            so the outward life. Thus it promotes and insures, what nothing else without it can—absolute
                            happiness. Why are we miserable ? Because some law of divine order has been transgressed by
                            ourselves or others. But why have we, or others, transgressed? Because some motive,
                            affection or thought inside our souls is out of order. All external sins are germinated
                            within. This is Christ's doctrine, and it is the immutable truth. Therefore his religion
                            begins at the beginning, and insists on making clean the inside, that the outside may be
                            clean also. If I analyze the internal, when I have sinned and been rendered unhappy, I find
                            one or more of the following specified evils in me : 1. Carelessness, indifference,
                            irreverence toward he Divine and spiritual—prayerlessness, unwatchfulness, ingratitude,
                            distrust of Providence. 2. Pride, self-will, rebellion against God's law and order, and a
                            disposition to self-indulgence, regardless of the wholesome cross—with a propensity to
                            ignore or disregard the rights, feelings, wants and co-equal welfare of others. 3. A
                            disposition to set up and promote my own good, regardless of the supreme, universal good,
                            and the perfect law of eternal rectitude, so as to care less for absolute right, and for the
                            happiness of others, than my own will. 4. The continued indulgence of some desire, passion
                            or lust, which I know to be wrong, and which I abhor, but which I have not yet the virtue to
                            subdue. 5. Fretfulness, resentment or revenge, on account of some wrong done me, whereby I
                            am inclined to return evil for evil, and not to love my enemy with that pure love which
                            seeks nothing but his highest good— also impatience, in some form, with what is offensive or
                            disagreeable to me. These and kindred ones I believe to be the internal springs of sin and
                            misery in all mankind. Jesus completely overcame them all. He recognized, reverenced, loved,
                            obeyed and trusted in the Father with his whole heart. He was habitually prayerful,
                            watchful, spiritually minded and conscientiously scrupulous to do the Divine will—to execute
                            and discharge all his personal responsibilities. He teaches his disciples to follow him, and
                            do likewise, promising to help them effectually in all their struggles and weaknesses. He
                            was not proud, self-willed nor rebellious against divine law, but humble, meek, lowly,
                            self-denying for righteousness' sake; tender-hearted towards all, and ever regardful of
                            their welfarefull of self-sacrifice in doing good to their bodies and spirits. He went
                            always for truth, for divine principles, for the universal good, and the eternal^ right,
                            even to the laying down of his life, rather than prefer himself, or any selfish advantage.
                            He loved absolute righteousness perfectly. He teaches his disciples to take up the cross
                            daily, to deny themselves for principle's sake, and to follow him as the Lamb of God, if
                            need be unto death—assuring them of eternal life and final triumph. He had the desires and
                            passions common to human nature, but he subordinated them all to divine order, in spite of
                            the most seductive and urgent temptations, till it became his meat and drink to do right;
                            though in so doing he deprived himself of many gratifications naturally dear to human
                            nature, to secure a permanent home wherein to lay his head; voluntarily making himself a
                            victim of persecution, and poor, that mankind through his poverty and sufferings might be
                            made rich unto eternal life. O, how unselfish! Moreover, while he was so pure, so
                            self-sacrificing, so devoted to uncompromising truth and righteousness, lie was as harmless
                            as he was holy. He indulged in no resentment, nor moroseness, nor revenge against his
                            persecutors. He loved them still, and wept for them, even when he rebuked their wickedness
                            most severely. He forgave their trespasses until seventy times seven. He returned not evil
                            for evil unto his bitterest foe. He was the unchangeable friend of his worst enemies, and
                            his glorious soul went out from the agonies of the cross, into paradise | with prayer for
                            his murderers, saying, "Father, forgive them, for they know not what they do." Now where is
                            the candid soul that is not prompted to exclaim with the centurion, "Tiuly, this man was the
                            Son of God!" I am well aware that those who claim to have out- rown Jesus will demur to all
                            this. They profess to nd defects in his character which unfit him to be the eligious master
                            and moral model of mankind. Such ontend that they reject his personal authority
                            concientiously, on account of those defects. But I have arefully examined all their
                            criticisms without findag a single allegation well ftranded. In every case, o is
                            misrepresented, or an unwarrantable inference s drawn, or the so-called defect is a real
                            excellence.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Write for humanity's good" TEIform="index"/>WRITE FOR HUMANITY'S GOOD</head><p TEIform="p">Beloved Editor:—I fully recognize the fact that a person may be educated in ideas, but not in
                            letters; and that you desire to have nothing kept back that may be of real benefit to
                            mankind, from the author's consciousness of his inability to present it in a fitting
                            external dress. You are amply paid for deciphering illegible manuscripts, and reducing them
                            to form, when, as the result of your labors, you find yourself in possession of a prize.
                            Nevertheless, I cannot be the worse, and may be the better, for a few hints to guide others
                            in writing for The Shaker : 1. Not to attempt writing for the benefit of humanity, unless
                            there is something important welling up in my heart—not my head—and struggling to get out.
                            Until this is the case, whatever I may think, there will be no message to deliver. 2. Be
                            sparing of points. Punctuate no further than is necessary to be understood, and leave the
                            rest to the printer. Dots and dashes, which many writers throw between* words wherever they
                            suspect a pause may be needed, are a crying vexation and a nuisance to editor, type-setter
                            and proof-reader. 3. Pack the thoughts. An important communication need not necessarily be
                            long; frequently the ideas of a whole column of a newspaper might be compressed into two
                            inches of space, with advantage to both reader and author. An idea is weakened by being
                            crowded with words. A tremendous thought may be packed into a small compass, made as solid
                            as a cannon ball, and like the projectile, cut all down before it. Short articles are
                            generally more effective, find more readers, and are more widely copied, than long ones.
                            Pack the thoughts closely, and though the article may be brief, it will have weight, and
                            will be more likely to make an impression. Use black ink. Yours, truly, Note by the
                            editor.—Our thanks are due to Bro. Orcutt for these timely hints. In our new volume, ive
                            can?iot use long articles. Contributors must "pack their thoughts;" or, if we use their
                            contributions, we must shorten them by erasion or division. Memento.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian light" TEIform="index"/>CHRISTIAN LIGHT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Witham, Maria" TEIform="persName"/>MARIA WITHAM</byline><p TEIform="p">There is a light which beams from heaven, On life's short, evil day; It cheers the pathway of
                            the just, And guides us on our way. How it illuminates the soul With joy, and peace, and
                            love! Disperses every glooin3r doubt, Dire3ts our thoughts above! And who enjoys this
                            glorious boon Which shineth from on high? The christia:i soldier of the cross, Who does not
                            fear to die.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The definition of the Religious Communities give by the Boston Commonwealth..." TEIform="index"/>The definition of the Religious Communities give by the Boston Commonwealth...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The definition of the Religious Communities give ;- by the Boston Commonwealth deserves
                            frequent rep e tition. It is the best we have come across: "¦The are churches which clothe
                            their members in a materia as well as a spiritual sense." Give a better one if yo ;-
                        can.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker home" TEIform="index"/>A SHAKER HOME</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stickney, A. C." TEIform="persName"/>A. C. STICKNEY</byline><p TEIform="p">O the blessing of a home where old and young j st dwell kindly; a] he young unawed, the old
                            unchilled, in unreserved communion." —Martin F. Tupper. p] Thus the poet sings, and this,
                            perchance, w was the ideal picture, at which our friend sc vas looking, when contemplating
                            the kind of home best suited for her dear niece. We ive below a few extracts from a letter
                            adressed to the latter, by her aunt, who had hosen a home for her among the Shakers. "My
                            dear Niece: I received your last letter with reat pleasure. Am glad that you like the place
                            and eople; hope you will like both more and more, unll you feel settled for life. I say
                            this, believing your oul will be cared for as well as your body. Remember, dear one, you
                            have a soul to save, and God even, cannot save it for you, unless you repent f your sins and
                            consecrate your life to Him. He reuires that you give your heart to Him, though it lay be a
                            small and poor gift. You are now away rom the allurements of the world, in just the place o
                            serve God with your whole heart. O give him our heart, and learn to love your Savioi\ I
                            suppose, to-day, that you are dressed like a real haker, and I have been praying that when
                            you put n your Shaker dress, God will clothe your heart nth. its righteousness." And so He
                            will clothe all hearts, that, ere hey assume the Shaker dress, will strive to earn this
                            righteousness, by cleansing the ame through confession and repentance for ?ast sins. Verily,
                            "God helps those who lelp themselves."</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nothing is lost" TEIform="index"/>NOTHING IS LOST</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Devyr, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/>CECELIA DEVYR</byline><p TEIform="p">Scatter bright jewels like hail on the mountain, Like rain that falls fast on the valley
                            below, Though like the snow that dissolves in the fountain, They pass from your vision,
                            still, still let them go. Nothing is lost in the outward creation, Change is the law that to
                            nature is given, Nothing shall fail in the work of salvation, Progress shall bring us the
                            kingdom of heavers. We may be up and awake in the morning, Doing the work that is needful at
                            home, Or we may sleep through the light that is dawning, Yet unimpeded its glory will come.
                            Who would awake to the light that is blinding? Who would be called to the sluggard's reward?
                            Who would be sowing in season of binding? Who would be dead in the day of the Lord? Surely
                            not those who are called by the spirit, Heavenly treasures on earth to obtain, Those who the
                            life everlasting inherit, By faith that will cleanse them from every stain.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbath of rest" TEIform="index"/>Sabbath of rest
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Niles, Marston" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">THE SABBATH OF REST. The benefit of a day of rest, in a religious point of view,
                                    lies in this : The suspension of a man's business for a day is a suspension, more or
                                    less, of his temptations to dishonesty on that day. That makes Sunday to some
                                    extent, a spiritual Sabbath for him. Temptations are removable in two ways: one,
                                    through removal ol evil desire; the other, through removal of possible opportunity
                                    for the gratification of desire. The former process is permanent and brings an
                                    eternal Sabbath. The latter is temporary, and comes to an end whenever temptation
                                    recurs. Thus it is that labor of the body comes to correspond to labor of the soul,
                                    and the body's struggle foexistence to the soul's struggle, and the repose of the
                                    one to the repose of the other. Sunday may be called with justice a sort of truce
                                    day. Not in a bad sense : it does not suggest a compromise with the enemy; but it
                                    does suggest that the enemy has vanished for the time. One may wish and think and do
                                    the ba on Sunday as easily as on any other day. But on the whole and generally, he
                                    has then far less temptation. We must except always those whose consciences are
                                    mainly formed by customs and human opinions, and who get but little from the Word of
                                    God direct. It is possible that these—indeed they themselves assert itfind on Sunday
                                    more temptation than in all the week besides. Sunday is a day for good resolutions.
                                    Without irony and in all seriousness, there is nothing so restful as to resolve. In
                                    resolves, the ideal has full play: resolution is the Christian's fairy-land. All
                                    this is well. What is not well is to mistake the Sunday mood lor the eternal
                                    Sabbath. That Sabbath is the practical fulfillment of the ideal: it is resolution
                                    accomplished in life : it is the imaginary reproduced in the real, and* the entrance
                                    into that Sabbath is through the six week-days only. It is sometimes said that
                                    Sunday's chief use is in religious instruction. This use is very great at the
                                    present time, and with our present habits. But the need of a rest-day for the soul's
                                    behoof is one which will exist as long as the human race, or as long as man's only
                                    road to spiritual victory lies through spiritual combat. The time may come when
                                    religious instruction will be imparted as much on one day as another; but the time
                                    can never come when all respite from temptation can be dispensed with. What will
                                    give Sunday in the New Age this value, which it has never generally before been felt
                                    to possess, is r. growing perception that the battle-field between hell and heaven
                                    is not mainly in the closet nor le church-pew, but in the shop, in the garden, in
                                    the ank and at the bar. Six days of the body's hard ork make the seventh really
                                    restful: and this is just s true of the soul. No labor, no rest: that rule is in le
                                    nature of all things. Marston Niles in the N. J. Messenger.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New Jersey messenger" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mystery of punctuation" TEIform="index"/>THE MYSTERY OF PUNCTUATION</head><p TEIform="p">The art of punctuation is really one of the implest of the accidents of literature ; yet ;o
                            most people it seems an impenetrable mystery. Many writers of high reputation make the
                            wildest work in attempting to nunctuate their own manuscript. Indeed, nost of the
                            punctuation in books is that of tie proof-reader, not that of the author. ^his, however, is
                            not wonderful; for if the secrets of the proof-reader's den were revealed, the reading
                            public would be astonished to learn that that useful but invisible functionary often
                            supplies for writers of reputation not only all the punctuation but aho a great deal of the
                            spelling and correct English. It is popularly supposed that all printers are accomplished
                            punctuators ; but in truth they are not. The best of them will punctuate ordinary narrative
                            tolerably well; but if anything more elaborate is left to their mercies, they are apt to
                            make strange work of it. A good proof-reader can of course punctuate when he understands the
                            sense; but frequently the meaning is equivocal until the proper points are supplied, and he
                            can only guess at the author's intention. Every one who writes for other eyes than his own,
                            though nothing but occasional letters, should punctuate systematically. The great obstacle
                            to this is the assumption that there is something very mysterious and abstruse in the proper
                            distribution of those troublesome little dots and scratches. The best general rule for
                            punctuation is this : Read your article or letter aloud, making your inflections conform as
                            accurately as possible to the sense you wish to convey; and wherever you make a pause mark a
                            corresponding one in the manuscript. Do not mark one where you do not make one in reading.
                            Nearly all manuscript, and a good deal of printed matter, is punctuated too much. If you can
                            use periods and commas correctly—which, easy as it seems, is rarely done—you will get along
                            very well with any simple composition. Semicolons and dashes belong rather to the elegancies
                            of punctuation. Three fourths of all the semicolons that ought to be used are required
                            before clauses beginning with "for" or "but," assigning a reason for, or noting an exception
                            to, the statement that immediately precedes. Dashes, which many -writers scatter about in
                            such reckless profusion, should be used very sparingly. They generally indicate that the
                            sense which is interrupted by some necessary intervening explanation, is resumed farther
                            along. When several enumerated particulars, taken together, are in apposition with a single
                            word or clause that precedes or follows, they should be separated from it with a dash. These
                            two cases cover almost entirely the proper use of that punctuation mark with whose wholesale
                            abuse manuscripts are so generally disfigured. When you are in doubt as to the necessity of
                            a point, by all means omit it. Other things being equal, that is best English which requires
                            least punctuation.</p></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lawyers and doctors" TEIform="index"/>LAWYERS AND DOCTORS</head><p TEIform="p">A litigation once arose in- the university of Cambridge, whether doctors in law or doctors in
                            medicine should hold precedence. The chancelor asked whether the thief or the hangman
                            preceded at the execution, and on being told that the thief usually took the lead, "Well
                            then" "let the doctors of the law have the precedence, and let the doctors in medicine be
                            next in rank."</p></div2><pb n="91" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vulgar talk" TEIform="index"/>VULGAR TALK</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The hopeful student who translated these words of Horace, "I hate protaneness and
                                    vulgarity," was better posted in ethics than in parsing Latin: for, if he expressed
                                    his real sentiment, he (and a great many of him) is badly needed now. The amount of
                                    vulgar speech that is to be heard among certain classes of our people is astonishing
                                    and humiliating. We do not affirm, we do not believe that the evil is increasing and
                                    is greater than in former times ; for one cannot do much looking into the past
                                    without coming upon this foulness in prodigious abundance. But, letting alone
                                    anjsuch comparison, the mischief is a great one now; greater, doubtless, than most
                                    of our readers are aware of. This their ignorance is fortunate and wholesome. It is
                                    a restriction upon the plague to keep away from it, and not to know thus what it is.
                                    The places and the men infected are not safe for resort or companionship. To hold
                                    deliberately aloof from them, besides protecting ourselves, may be also one of the
                                    most effective means of putting reproof upon the evil where it exists in others.
                                    Occasions will arise, however, upon which a man, in spite of his wishes, will learn
                                    something as to this abomination. He must take care at such times not only that he
                                    is in no wise pleased with what he hears, but also that he does not seem to be. The
                                    admixture, often made, of wit with vulgarity may place one at some disadvantage in
                                    this respect, by its provocation to laughter; and there are difficulties here, as
                                    everywhere, in drawing the lines of absolute propriety. But, practically and in
                                    general, it is not difficult to tell when the point of a story or a remark lies in
                                    what is vulgar in it; and in all such cases the treatment is not doubtful. These
                                    admixtures, too, are not to be encouraged; and there is wit enough in the world that
                                    is not low; or there may be, and we may help, if we please, to make more. Christian
                                    men need not be falsely delicate and squeamish ; but they ought to be and must be
                                    pure and decent and decorous, and, even if they are cast into low company, they
                                    should be able to show in face and bearing that they have not left their honor and
                                    decency behind them. We will only add that persons prominent in professional or
                                    public life may sometimes constitute very low company, and that in these cases there
                                    is at least as much need as in any other that one should take care of his manliness
                                    and self-respect.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Congregationalist" TEIform="index"/>Congregationalist</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religion or legislation wanted" TEIform="index"/> Religion or legislation wanted</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The plain, unvarnished tale supplied by our special correspondent now among the
                                    Pennsylvania miners cannot be read with indifference by any just or humane man. We
                                    speak of "hard times" when it becomes necessary to forego some luxury, to deny
                                    ourselves some familiar pleasure, and to reduce our general standard of expenditure.
                                    We complain when pinched to keep up appearances, and repine at the hardship which
                                    invades our comfort. In and around the coal fields of an adjoining state, however,
                                    are tens of thousands of working men who, with their families, are on the verge of
                                    starvation. A large proportion are unemployed; those that have ivork are paid so
                                    scantily that what they earn barely keeps soul and body together. The picture of
                                    squalor and wretchedness, of hunger and nakedness, is shocking enough to touch the
                                    hardest heart. It is made more painful by the fact that some of the companies add to
                                    the miseries of their people by the enforcement of the truck system. There may be
                                    reasons for suspending work in some cases, and for reducing wages in others, but the
                                    greed which prompts employers of labor to squeeze out of it the beggarly pittance
                                    through the agency of store pay admits of no excuse- It is an infamy which the law
                                    in other countries has suppressed.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New York times" TEIform="index"/>New York Times.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Here is religion" TEIform="index"/> Here is religion.</head><p TEIform="p">Mysterious is a wornn's way. Several weeks ago, a lady, with bright face and pleasing manner,
                            elegantly ressed, arrived in Columbus, O., and after breakfasting at a hotel, went to a
                            station louse to apply for a lodging. She was given cell on the first floor, with the
                            privilege of the prison, and she immediately began to brighten the lives of the poor
                            prisoners. She made a decisive onslaught on the cockroaches and on the bed-bugs by scrubbing
                            her cell again and again. When the wood work was as neat as soap and water could make it,
                            she hung some pictures on the walls, and every day she has a bouquet of fresh flowers. She
                            has books in her cell, and sometimes she takes a short walk, but whenever there is anything"
                            to be done for any prisoner, she is ready to do it. When a drunken woman is brought in and
                            laid on the floor, the strange lady busies herself during the night in bathing the poor
                            creature's head, rubbing her hands and feet, and bringing her to her better self. The
                            expense to the city of keeping this ministering angel in its prison fs not great: She lives
                            on bread and water. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let us consider" TEIform="index"/>LET US CONSIDER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Neal, Sarah A." TEIform="persName"/>SARAH A. NEAL</byline><p TEIform="p">Our earthly summer is past, and our material harvest ended. Providence las blest us with an
                            abundant growth &gt;f those substances which we have argely garnered for the sustenance
                            of our physical beings. Bv exertion, we lave saved much of earthly treasures, and,
                            comparatively speaking, perhaps ost little ; for all which we have cause o feel truly
                            thankful. But in what ratio does our spiritual harvest agree with our material? During the
                            past seedime and harvest, how ardent have been our exertions to sow the seeds of truth, that
                            we might realize their grow7th, and harvest the effects thereof? And how great is the
                            realization within our own souls, that we have been saved from worldly sins, that have
                            afflicted humanity from earliest recollections, and have lost to the various consequences of
                            these sins! Let us consider. Creation is now preparing to enter a season, when its entire
                            forces need to x-est on its basic germ, to sustain vitality through a chilling test,
                            preparatory to the evolution of a new seed-time and harvest. In this season, life's
                            foundational principles are strengthened by the return forces, and held in readiness to
                            perform new service at the dawn of a new seed-time And surely, this season comes to
                            intellectual creation with no less meaning than a time for meditation and reflec tion. A
                            time for mental exercise, anc deep soul-labor, through which human ity should become better
                            conditioned to evolve the principles of the new life first made manifest by Jesus, the
                            Christ Earth rolls her rapid seasons round they come aad they retire ; and eacl successive
                            year brings with it a new seed-time that* leads to a future harvest and so are new
                            opportunities yearl} coming to those of us who are toiling ii spiritual fields, to sow anew
                            the seed of divine faith ; and to cultivate wit! care, that their growth may be even un to
                            perfection and our harvest abountifu yield ! Let us consider, while the earth-win ter lasts,
                            that it is ours, as with all creation, to prepare for the coming of a new seed time, and be
                            ready at its dawn to nter our spiritual fields, with a zeal ruly becoming Christian workers
                            ; that we may realize, as the season rolls on, superior growth of virtue, that shall uetoken
                            the golden harvest. But now s our time to prepare for more active ervice ; for deeper
                            consecration ; and "or a fuller sacrifice of our entire beings o the cause of truth ; and
                            may we be wise and well consider our day. Shakers, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Time as a weaver" TEIform="index"/>TIME AS A WEAVER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>MARTHA J. ANDERSON</byline><p TEIform="p">How swift the shuttle flies that iveaves thy shroud!" —Young. Time with a swift momentum
                            flies, As through life's web his shuttle flies; Twining the fiberd that fate has spun, All
                            through the years since life begun; Threading the woof of hours and days, Drawn through our
                            devious winding ways; Gathering the tangled ends of time, Weaving them all in rhythmic
                            chime; Bending the broken ends of thought, Each by his skillful fingers caught. Soon shall
                            thy garment woven be, Ere thou sbalt enter Eternity. But, O thou mortal! be not proud, Time
                            with his shuttle weaves thy shroud. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pray without ceasing" TEIform="index"/>PRAY WITHOUT CEASING</head><p TEIform="p">As a number of Ministers were assembled to disuss different questions, among others it was
                            asked low the command "Pray without ceasing," could be omplied with. Various suppositions
                            were stated, nd at length one of the number was appointed to vrite upon the subject and read
                            it at their next meetng; which being overheard by a sensible little girl, he exclaimed!
                            "What, a whole month wanted to explain the meaning of that text! It is one of the easist and
                            best texts in the Bible." "Well," said an aged divine, "Mary, what can you say about it? Can
                            you pray all the time?" "O, yes sir." "What, when you have so nmeh to do!" "Why, sir, the
                            more I have to lo the more I can pray." "Indeed! Mary, let us snow how it is, for most
                            people think otherwise." 'Well, when I first open my eyes in the morning, ] pray, Lord open
                            the eyes of my understanding to behold wondrous things out of thy law. And when I am
                            washing, I pray that I may be washed, sanctified and justified in the name of the Lord. And
                            while dressing, I pray to be clothed with humility. And as I begin my work I pray for
                            strength equal to my day, and when I kindle the fire I pray that the love of God may burn in
                            my heart. While I sweep the house I pray that my heart may be cleansed from all impurity.
                            And while partaking of breakfast, I desire to be fed with the hidden manna and sincere milk
                            of the word. And when with the children I look up to God as my Father and pray for the
                            spirit of adoption, that I may be his child; and all day, every thing I do furnishes
                            something for prayer."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Selected" TEIform="persName"/>Selected</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker remedy" TEIform="index"/>THE SHAKER REMEDY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="American socialist" TEIform="persName"/>AM. SOCIALIST </byline><p TEIform="p">One of the editors of the Albany Morning Express, has visited Mt. Lebanon and held
                            conferences with Elder Frederick W. Evans. When the editor asked the Elder to propose a
                            remedy for the political disease "which threatens the very life of the nation," the latter
                            said : "In all seriousness, I ask you to look at the material laws and lives of Shakerdom.
                            Here is a village of several hundred people. For fifty or a hundred years wre have lived
                            here, prosperous, contented, happy. We have tilled the land, and year after year put back
                            upon it that which necessity and comfort did not require. Now it blooms like the fairest
                            garden During all these years of our existence, we hav never spent a penny for police, for
                            lawyers, fo judges, for poorhouses, for penal institutions, or any of the other
                            'improvements' of the outside world We have our quarrels, our differences, our ambi tions,
                            like other men, but we settle them in a loving brotherly manner, by gentle arbitration, by
                            cruci fixion of the spirit and unselfishness. Therefore, w find police, courts of law, and
                            jails, not only useless but degrading. We never have used them, and wit God's help, never
                            shall. But we claim to be no be ter than other men or women. Not a bit. We ar just the same
                            as^ny other six hundred you will fine in any part of the country. What we claim is, tha our
                            system is better; and it is that which gives u content, prosperity, happiness. If, then,
                            this villag of six hundred can exist for a century in peace anc plenty, why can not any
                            other village of six hundrec any town of six thousand, any city of six hundrec thousand? We
                            have demonstrated it to be possible, and what are we better than any other men?"</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Indians learning the arts of peace" TEIform="index"/>INDIANS LEARNING THE ARTS OF PEACE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="McClellan, [Gen.]" TEIform="persName"/>GEN, McCLELLAN IN N. Y. WORLD</byline><p TEIform="p">IN N. Y. WORLD. Speaking of the peaceful methods of dealing with ndians, have you heard of
                            the success of the little •aining school at St. Augustine, Fla.? About forty r fifty.of the
                            worst cases for such treatment—Camanches, Apaches, and other southern Indians—were wrought
                            as prisoners to St. Augustine, and have nice been drilled by military rule and square. The
                            )risoners were treated kindly but with unmistakable rnmess and decision. I understand that
                            they contitute now a well-ordered little colony in the garrion town. They have been taught
                            to build little cotages, to cultivate the ground and to live at peace vith one another. They
                            have a printing press mong them and all attend school. Some have hown a taste for the simple
                            manufactures and arts, nd all are employed in some useful and profitable lanner. If these
                            most unpromising cases, at first ook, could be so trained, I think that there is reason o
                            believe that the condition of other hostile Indians ould be as readily changed for the
                            better if they ould once be brought under strict military superision.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>SUPERIOR REFLECTIONS</head><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Interior says that 'bigotry' means holding view..." TEIform="index"/>Interior says that 'bigotry' means holding view...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> The Interior says that "bigotry" means lolding the views of those who are a shade nore
                                conservative than ourselves. Nonsense. ?here are hundreds and thousands in all
                                denominations, from the loosest to the strictest, vho are not bigots in any sense.
                                Bigotry is ;he lack of Christian charity toward those who differ from us in matters of
                                religious beief. </p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Time is short" TEIform="index"/>THE TIME IS SHORT</head><p TEIform="p">The time is short; the more the reason,then, For filling it as full as it can hold With
                                thrills of beauty, yearnings for the truth, And joys of love and labor manifold. Then
                                should it chance, as we would fain believe, Life's glory waits us in some other sphere,
                                Its first great joy shall be we did not miss God's meaning in the glory that is
                            here.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Honey from the scriptures" TEIform="index"/>Honey from the Scriptures</head><p TEIform="p">Do not think it enough if you learn to spell and read, and to say the words of the
                                Scriptures, but seek to learn the truth of the Scriptures. Do is the bees do. A bee,
                                when it sees a flower, does not fly round and round it, and then fly off" again, like
                                foolish, idle butterflies. It settles on a flower and sucks the honey out of t. You
                                should do as the bees do ; you should settle your thoughts on what you read, and :ry to
                                suck the honey out of it. Almost every verse in the New Testament has its honey. Almost
                                every verse contains a spiritual truth, fit to nourish some soul or other. </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="That may be right which is not pleasant..." TEIform="index"/>That may be right which is not pleasant...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">That may be right which is not pleasant, and pleasant which is not right; but Christ's
                                religion is both.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Henry, Matthew" TEIform="persName"/>Matthew Henry</byline></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sun colors the sky most deeply and diffusely..." TEIform="index"/>Sun colors the sky most deeply and diffusely...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The sun colors the sky most deeply and diffusely when he hath sunk below the horizon ;
                                and they who never said, "How beneficently he shines;" say at last, "Howbrightly he
                                set!"</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Landor" TEIform="persName"/>Landor</byline>Landor
                        </div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ministering" TEIform="index"/>Ministering
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stone, A. L." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Pure religion and undefiled is "ministering"—not that other thing, "being ministered
                                unto." It is handing over the morning paper to another for first perusal. It is vacating
                                a pleasant seat by the fire for one who comes in chilled. It is giving up the most
                                restful armchair or sofa, for one who is weary. It is moving up in a pew to let a
                                new-comer sit down by the entrance. It is rising from your place to lower a curtain or
                                close a blind when the sun's ray streams in too brightly upon some face in the circle.
                                It is giving your own time and convenience every time, for the comfort and convenience
                                of another. This is at once true courtesy and genuine Christianity. If we mean to copy
                                the spirit of the Savior, we must be ready in every hour of the day, to give up being
                                waited upon, and to practice this self-sacrificing beneficent and "ministering"
                                graciousness of spirit and coniduct. Rev. A. L. Stone, in Pacific Methodist </p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Look pleasant, be pleasant" TEIform="index"/>Look pleasant, be pleasant</head><p TEIform="p">If people will only notice, they will be amazed to find how much a really enjoj'able
                                evening owes to smiles. But very few consider what an important symbol of fine intellect
                                and of fine feeling they are. Yet all smiles, after childhood, are things of education.
                                Savages do not smile; coarse, brutal, cruel men may laugh, but they seldom smile. It is
                                painful to reflect how seldom the poor smile. The affluence, the benediction, the
                                radiance, which "fill the silence like a speech"—the smile of a full, appreciative
                                heart. The face grows finer as it listens, and then breaks into sunshine instead of
                                words, has a subtle, charming influence universally felt, though seldom understood or
                                acknowledged. Lord Bacon tells of a nobleman whom he knew; a man who gave lordly
                                entertainments, but always suffered some sarcastic personality to "mar a good dinner,"
                                adding, "Discretion of speech is more than eloquence, and to speak agreeably to him with
                                whom we deal is more than to speak in good words; for he that hath a satirical vein,
                                making others afraid of his wit, hath need to be afraid of others memory."</p></div3></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE SHAKER. Monthly—60 cents per annum. A DUAL ADVOCATE OF CHRIST PRINCIPLES</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Impelling motive" TEIform="index"/>THE IMPELLING MOTIVE</head><p TEIform="p">We would call to mind the object for which The Shaker is published anc continued, at an
                            expense much greater than the income derived. Surely it is for no one's pastime ; nor for
                            competition in excellence of anything, except the exposition of a most excellent faith. Our
                            faith is a singular one—singular, because so few are willing to practice real, unmixed
                            Christianity. Every device that can be offered to excuse individuals from looking the
                            demands of genuine Christianity in the face, are being resorted to by the multitude, and
                            consequently there is but little salvation from sin, active among the people. Heal,
                            Christian life, will save sotds from their sins now. We feel it a duty to make known this
                            truth ; and would preach through The Shaker, plain, unvarnished, pertinently Christian
                            testimony, however unpalatable to ourselves or others. Before us all stands the life of
                            Jesus, the Christ. In that life is Christianity alone represented—therein alone, is the true
                            Christian religion. It matters not to us, nor to others, what this one or that one preached
                            or meant by the preaching, Paul not excepted, but what was the life of Jesus, and his
                            immediate disciples, as Christians? Herein is the security of salvation ; herein alone is
                            all the religion worth having. For this alone The Shaker contends single handed ; while its
                            hundreds of religious contemporaries ai*e preaching a Christianity not found in the life of
                            Christ, but in the very opposite of Christ's life ! Shall we be sustained ia preaching
                            genuine Christianity? Who will send us the needed encouragement to sustain The Shaker, in
                            its unrelenting, determined assaults upon the principalities of evil, the world, the flesh,
                            and every unchristian practice—the devils among the people ! We love our fellowmen, and our
                            object only is, their salvation from the evils and the good which are not of
                            Christ—unpracticed by the beautiful Jesus ! Who will lend to the Lord, by aiding the
                            circulation of The Shaker?</p></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Close of vol. 7—our vol. 8" TEIform="index"/>CLOSE OF VOL. 7.—OUR VOL. 8</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">In closing, with this number, Vol. 7 of The Shaker, we want to add " God speed" to the
                            thousands of readers who olessed our labors, and comforted our spirit, by their active
                            prayers and contributions. If any have aught but blessing and encouragement for the
                            circulation of God's Word and Shaker testimony by The Shaker—and there may be such—we have
                            only kindness in our hearts for them ; they know not what they do ; they cannot, at the
                            proper time, refuse their reward. We have given to it our best life and endeavors, however
                            imperfect these have been. We feel satisfied with the comfortable reward of this
                            consciousness : and the best of courage for the work of the future. We are unsalaried, but
                            feel well paid. We beg, however, for the immediate settlement of past subscriptions, and
                            instant renewal, with an increase. Give the cause a dime, a day, or a dollar! Take notice :
                            We mean to pleasantly surprise all who subscribe for Vol. 8, by additional improvements and
                            attractions. The testimony will be the same ; but there will be a change of form, more
                            space, more departments, more desirable information, more of everything that is good. Times
                            s.re improving financially ; do not fail to devote sixty cents for Vol. S of The Shaker.
                            Show the first illustrated number to your neighbors and friends. Send us an advertisement,
                            no matter how small nor for how short a period. We will make yearly visitsyr to every one
                            sending us an advertisement. So confident are we of being called to the good work of
                            circulating The Shaker, that we believe every subscriber will feel especial blessings from
                            the heavens for their interests in its behalf. Remember, the music alone will be worth more
                            than the subscription price !</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>EDITORIAL NOTES</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How nearly Christian?" TEIform="index"/>HOW NEARLY CHRISTIAN?</head><p TEIform="p">The Supreme Court of Pennsylvania declares that "Christianity is part ol the common law
                                of the State; and waiving all question of hereafter, it is the purest system of
                                morality, the foremost auxiliary, and only stable support of all human laws?" We suppose
                                nearly or quite every State in the Union makes a similar claim. But wherein can we see
                                any Christianity operative in the laws of any State ? Is it not an eye for an eye, life
                                for a life, and such like dealings, after the manner of Judaism. Wherein does any
                                State*bring riches and poverty upon a level, after the chris tian pattern ? or even does
                                half as well in this as Judaism did ? Wherein does | any State oppose war or warlike
                                preparations, as taught by Christianity ? Does any State encourage the growth of virgin
                                purity, as did the friends of Christianity? True, almost or quite every State permits
                                these principles to be observed by those who would be Christians ; but the States are in
                                no particulars Christian in administration of their laws ; nor in the particular
                                encouragement of Christian principles. If any State should begin to be as equitable and
                                just in its administration as Judaism of old was, people would think the Millennium come
                                ! We urge the trial of it. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The editor of Sunday School Times..." TEIform="index"/>The editor of Sunday School Times...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The editor of Sunday School Times, in an article on Brigham Young, says: " It is possible for
                            a man to be sincere, and as far from right. There is hardly any limit to the wild fanaticism
                            of a deluded, religious enthusiast." Then he goes on to name, as such, several of the most
                            prominent reformers, beginning with Mohammed, ending with John H. Noyes, and including Ann
                            Lee ! We looked in vain for the name of that distinguished religious enthusiast, Jesus of
                            Nazareth! but it was not there. Again, we must assert: Ann Lee's zeal,wild, fanatical,
                            deluded, religious and enthusiastic as it may have been, never exceeded the same
                            characteristics in Jesus; lor ever aimed at any purer life, through any more self-denials,
                            than were practiced by Jesus. We would ask Editor Trumbull, wherein did Ann Lee's testimony
                            differ from that of Jesus? Wherein, her Christian life? Wherein, the testimony she has left
                            for her children, or their lives when obedient to it? Wherein do the lives of true Shakers
                            differ from the lives of those composing that model church—the Pentecostal ? Until the
                            differences are declared, we ask the consideration of all men* whether, because we are good
                            enough to follow Jesus and his immediate disciples so literally, we should be maligned and
                            ridiculed? And what a testimony the living Shaker is to the whole unchristian world !</p></div2><div2 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Common Sense, a spicy monthly, printed at St. Louis..." TEIform="index"/>The Common Sense, a spicy monthly, printed at St. Louis...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The Common Sense, a spicy monthly, printed at St. Louis, gives up in despair when thinking
                            how very differently professedly Christian sects believe. " The Shaker Christians refuse to
                            propagate, while the Mormon and worldly Christians cannot propagate too much." It was Henry
                            C. Wright who spoke in New Haven: "I cannot see how any believer in the Old Testament can
                            come to any other conclusion than that of the Mormons; nor do I see how it is possible for
                            any believer in the New Testament to arrive at any other conclusion than that of the Shakers
                            ! Jesus and Paul taught and practiced celibacy. Were Paul living to-day, in my opinion,
                            judging from his writings, he would be a thorough-going, first-class Shaker ! " Our opinion
                            of Christians is, they are such as follow Jesus and his immediate disciples in life—not
                            merely in admiration. If Mormons, worldly people, or Shakers, take pattern of Jesus, then
                            are they Christians, not otherwise. The Old Testament treats particularly of the old
                            man—Adam and his descendants. The New Testament as particularly rises up to the new
                            man—Jesus, the Christ—and "old things are done away, all things become new," like unto
                            Jesus. No man nor woman can, at one and the same time, worship the God of the Old Testament
                            and the God of the New. One teaches human propagation ; private, personal interests ;
                            retaliations and wars ; politics, etc. The other teaches Celibacy; universal
                            brotherhood—community of goods—Peace ; non-resistance ; and separation from the world. Which
                            of these two classes is Christian? " Choose ye, which ye will serve ; for ye are the servant
                            of him to whom ye yield yourselves servants to obey."</p></div2><div2 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Some one, zealous in behalf of Shaker principles..." TEIform="index"/>Some one, zealous in behalf of Shaker principles...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Some one, zealous in behalf of Shaker principles, has been "contending for the faith," by
                            writing letters to the Voice of the Angels, a Spiritual paper, published in Boston. Just how
                            successful their logic was, we do not know ; but extracts in type speak very favorable, and
                            perhaps the weakest portions were printed. But we must condemn the silly practice of sending
                            anonymous communications. We have no means of knowing who wrote these letters, as care was
                            taken to leave off' even the postal address! We esteem honor and propriety so highly among
                            the brethren, that we are ashamed to own that they were indited in any of the Societies. We
                            prefer to believe they were the work of an ex-Shaker. But, whoever it was, let your light
                            shine over your own name. Do not engage in the disreputable practice of being ashamed of
                            seeing your name attached to any defence of Christ and his words.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We hope, that in every issue of The Shaker..." TEIform="index"/>We hope, that in every issue of The Shaker...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> We hope, that in every issue of The Shaker, there will appear evidences of what is true
                            Shaker belief; so that none, getting hold of a stray copy, but may therein find something
                            that will teach "What any must do to be a Shaker." A virgin celibacy : It is the life for
                            Christians—the life of the heavens. Communion of interests : None rich ; none poor ; the
                            whole comfortable. Bless, and curse not." " Resist not evil." Separation from the world :
                            From its loves, lusts ; from its bad and its good. Follow Jesus, the Christ, in our daily
                            life. Natural inclinations prompt us otherwise ; make us believe it impossible, unnecessary.
                            But the " follow me" of Jesus means a life like his, —very unlike the ones our natural
                            inclinations select—very unlike the life of the world.</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">NOTICE. Any parties desiring fuller information of "The Shakers," "Shakerism," "Ann Lee and
                            her people," shaker communism and Life," or on any points not fully understood, may be
                            accommodated by a lecturer, (where expenses in transitu will be offered and paid,) on
                            application at this office. If inconsistent to comply ourself, we will secure better
                            speakers, singers, etc.</p></div2><pb n="93" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Speak the truth" TEIform="index"/>SPEAK THE TRUTH</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Edith" TEIform="persName"/>EDITH</byline><p TEIform="p">I trust that many of us have proved from experience the truth of the maxim, " Honesty is the
                            best policy;" and have also learned that it is the safest principle upon which to found an
                            honorable character for life. My little friends, are we not aware that one of the greatest
                            causes for so much sorrow and failure in this w-orld, is dishonesty? Perhaps the first error
                            in a person's life, was the false, statement of some simple anecdote in childhood, which
                            carelessly passed over without correction, led to greater untruths; and so by one step and
                            another, he became habitually deceitful and dishonest. Little children, will you take this
                            friendly warning —Never lie down to rest at night with the slightest misstatement
                            unconfessed. If you have been careless, repent before it is too late; begin now to be
                            honest. If we continue to live dishonestly we shall lose the blessing of God, the confidence
                            of our friends, forget to pray, and finally drift away from the good and pure. Let us be
                            wise, shun the first temptation, and thus save ourselves years of sorrow and regret.
                            Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>BOOK TABLE</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="People" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Country gentleman" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christianity and infidelity: a discussion" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Radical review" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">We would call especial attention to The People, a weekly paper, published by Chas. C.
                                Pearson of Concord, N. H. It is an excellent family paper; brim full of news;
                                enterprising in its every department, even in its politics! Our relations with the firm
                                and The People, have been of a very pleasant character, and we only do duty when we make
                                known to our readers, that as a New Hampshire paper, it is unexcelled. The best farm,
                                stock and garden paper in our country, or in any other as far as we know, is The Country
                                Gentleman, published by Luther Tucker f Son, Albany, N. Y. With the farmers who are
                                successful in business, it is as readily and commonly found as is their Bible, and what
                                the Bible should be to the morals of the community at large, such is the Country
                                Gentleman to the farm and garden. We will send it and The Shaker for its subscription
                                price, $¦2.50. Send us your orders. Christianity and Infidelity': A Discussion. Herein
                                are the pro and con of Christianity pretty fully ventilated. The weakness of the
                                affirmative side, is certainly manifested, because of its being an argument for a
                                Christianity, not radical and true, but manmade. Half-way work in regard to
                                Christianity, or arguments in its behalf, leave pregnable the positions of any advocate,
                                to the javelins of the most radical infidel. Pure Christianity is an impregnable
                                position. Those who are fond of such arguments, send to D. M. Bennett, 141 Eighth
                                street, New York. " The Radical Review." for November contains many very interesting
                                articles upon radically humane subjects. Prominent among many others are " So Railway
                                kings itch for an Empire, do they?" and " The Spirit that was of Jesus." Whoever is in
                                earnest, as a worker for human weal, will do well to secure a copy of this Review, and
                                they will then feel fully equipped. Send to Benjamin R. Tucker, New Bedford, Mass.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Not if it was my boy!" TEIform="index"/>"NOT IF IT WAS MY BOY!"</head><p TEIform="p">Some years ago the late Horace Mann, the eminent educator, delivered an address at the
                            opening of some reformatory institution for boys, during which he remarked that if only one
                            boy was saved from ruin, it would pay for all the cost, and care, and labor of establishing
                            such an institution as that. After the exercises had closed, in private conversation, a
                            gentleman rallied Mr. Mann upon his statement, and said to him: " Did you not color that a
                            little, when you said that all that expense and labor would be repaid if it only saved one
                            boy f" " Not if it was MY boy," was the solemn and convincing reply. Ah! there is a
                            wonderful value about "My boy." Other boys may be rude and rough; other boys may be reckless
                            and wild; other boys may seem to require more pains and labor than they ever will repay;
                            other boys may be left to drift uncared for to the ruin which is so near at hand; but "My
                            boy,"—it were worth the toil of a lifetime and the lavish wealth of a world to save Mm from
                            temporal and eternal ruin. We would go the world around to save him from peril, and would
                            bless every hand that was stretched out to give him help or welcome. And yet every poor,
                            wandering, outcast, homeless man, is one whom some fond mother called, " My Boy." Every lost
                            woman, sunken in the depths of sin, was somebody's daughter, in her days of childish
                            innocence. To-day somebody's son is a hungry outcast, pressed to the very verge of crime and
                            sin. To-day some body's daughter is a weary, helpless wanderer, driven by necessity into the
                            paths that lead to death. Shall we shrink from labor, shall we hesitate at cost when the
                            work before us is the salvation of a soul t Not if it is "My Boy;" not if we have the love o
                            Him who gave His life to save the lost. —The Common People.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Crooked sticks" TEIform="index"/>CROOKED STICKS</head><p TEIform="p">One crooked stick in a pile of wood is sufficient to isturb the whole heap, and if two or
                            three such ticks are placed together you cannot make them lie : °^ ley will tumble down.
                            Nothing can be more trying a o the woodman or the housewife than these crooked n ;icks. Who
                            can abide them? There are some individuals in society who are al" ways finding fault with
                            everything which they do not " originate themselves. They cannot get on bar- w moniously and
                            help forward any good cause, because w something goes wrong. Unless they can manage
                            everything in their own way, they will do nothing but to be perpetually grumbling. They are
                            uncom- " fortable brethren—you cannot work with them,— n crooked sticks—you can harmonize
                            them in nothing, r; Such individuals have a mortal disease, of a very a troublesome if not
                            dangerous character. It is difficult to trace its origin, but we suppose the moral system to
                            be affected more or less with the virulent hu- a niors of selfishness, jealousy,
                            self-conceit, pride of tl opinion and ill nature. We know not exactly what c to call it, but
                            suppose the grumbling hypochrondriasis may not be amiss. We venture to prescribe a remedy:
                            Take of Humility, 3 grains, e Forbearance, h ounce, Charity, 3 scruples, ¦ Brotherly love, 2
                            drachms, Patience, 3 ounces : ]_, Mix in 3 gills of the milk of human kindness. To be kept
                            on hand, and taken whenever the grumbling symptoms appear. If the paroxysms continue,
                            increase the strength of the prescription by a little self-knowledge.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nothing to do" TEIform="index"/>Nothing to do
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">NOTHING TO DO"Nothing to do!" in this world, of ours, Where weeds spring up with
                                    fairest flowers, a Where smiles have only a fitful play, Where hearts are breaking
                                    every day! 1 "Nothing to do!" thou Christian soul, Wrapping thee round in thy
                                    selfish stole; £ Off with the garments of sloth and sin, Christ thy Lord hath a
                                    kingdom to win. v "Nothing to do!" There are prayers to lay On the altar of incense,
                                    day by day; c There are foes to meet within and without, There is error to conquer,
                                    strong and stout. ^ "Nothing to do!" There are minds to teach The simplest form of
                                    Christian speech; C There are hearts to lure with loving wile, From the grimmest
                                    haunts of Sin's defile. "Nothing to do!" There are lambs to feed, The precious hope
                                    of the Church's need; Strength to be borne to the weak and faint, i Vigils to keep
                                    with the doubting saint. "Nothing to do!" And thy Savior said, j "Follow thou Me, in
                                    the path I tread." Lord, lend Thy help the journey through, i Lest faint, we cry,
                                    "So much to do."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Nation" TEIform="index"/>The Nation.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Useless expenses" TEIform="index"/>Useless expenses
                        </head><p TEIform="p">USELESS EXPENSES. 1 The Louisville Courier-Journal propounds the fol- { lowing: "Why should
                            this government, in times of profound peace, maintain a general and a lieutenantgeneral and
                            their glittering establishments, at a cost ' of perhaps $75,000 a year, when a
                            major-general, * with his glittering establishment, at a cost, say of 1 $10,000 a year,
                            would do just as well? But if you go ( on hunting up such conundrums as this, you will rob ,
                            the government of the luxury of uselessly squandering at least $50,000,000 per annum. </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Why the rich are miserable" TEIform="index"/>Why the rich are miserable
                        </head><p TEIform="p">WHY THE RICH ARE MISERABLE. 1 In his speech at the recent award of the Montyon ' prize for
                            virtue, M. Alexander Dumas discussed the : reason why rich people are miserable, and came to
                            i the conclusion that it is because they do not sufficiently devote their wealth to making
                            others happy. One of the passages runs thus: "The kingdom she has long inhabited is no
                            longer of this world; it knows no limits or frontiers, no foreigners or enemies, no victors
                            or vanquished; all who inhabit it are the children of one father, whose name is
                        Charity."</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Poetry" TEIform="index"/>POETRY. </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> We have been extremely sorry to learn from our experience as an editor that a
                                    very common folly, and one of the most unaccountable, is the desire among a great
                                    many people to write poetry. There are many things of literary excellence that
                                    poetry may lack; it may be defective in grammar, coined and curious words may be
                                    forgiven, fantastic and difficult antitheses and illustrations maybe allowed; but
                                    there must be genius. It has been our fate to bo tormented by correspondents who
                                    have all these things that may be forgiven, and more, too, they lack genius, which
                                    cannot be forgiven. As a rule these correspondents mistake a fit of sentimentalism
                                    for the divine afflatus; they are a good, solid, commonsense people with a little
                                    bit of "inner consciousness," which while it does not amouut to a poetic frenzy yet
                                    gives them a trouble which can only be assuaged by spoiling good white paper and
                                    worrying the Editor. If this be a relief, we will stand it. But they must not be
                                    angry if we do not allow them to parade their folly before a less gentle critic—the
                                    public. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Pacific Methodist" TEIform="index"/>—Pacific Methodist.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Never make a promise..." TEIform="index"/>Never make a promise...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Never make a promise when the power of performing that promise depends on another.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>LIVE-STOCK ITEMS</head><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mistakes in managing horses..." TEIform="index"/>Mistakes in managing horses...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Mistakes in managing horses, even when fan apparently trivial nature, are often the ause
                                of much needless suffering and permanent injury. Of these a fewr that are common ust
                                about this time are : bathing the feet of iorses to cool them off when heated by hard
                                work; watering them immediately after meals when about to start on a journey, instead of
                                vaiting a while, or letting them drink before eeding; giving them, through mistaken
                                kindness, an extra feed before driving them at a apid pace, and so forcing them to
                                travel on an overloaded stomach; starting to fair or market at a swinging trot, while
                                the animals are fresh and full of feed, instead of letting ;hem settle slowly down to
                                their work; and cruelly omitting to cover them when heated after a rapid drive, and so
                                exposing them to much suffering while the reckless driver is enjoying himself.—Rural, N.
                                Y. </p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The advantage of kindness to cow..." TEIform="index"/>The advantage of kindness to cow...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The advantage of kindness to cows has Keen frequently insisted on in these pages, and is
                                well illustrated by the following anecdote : A man had a fine cow that, week after week,
                                was milked alternately by a couple of hired men. He observed that the amount of butter
                                he carried weighed about a pound more each alternate week. He watched the men, and tried
                                the cow after they had finished milking; but always found that no milk had been left in
                                the teats. Finally he asked the Scotch girl who took care of the milk, if she could
                                account for the difference. "Why, yes,' said she. " When Jim milks, he says to the old
                                cow : ' So ; my pretty muley ; so !' Bu when Sam milks, he hits her on the hip with the
                                edge of the pail, and says : ' H'ist, you old brute !' " </p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Oats for horses should be bruised..." TEIform="index"/>Oats for horses should be bruised...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Oats for horses should be bruised or crushed in a mill before being fed, for by thii
                                means their nutritive properties are renderec far more available. When there are no
                                facili ties for crushing, pour hot water on them and let them soak for a few hours. </p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The qualities of hay are pithily stated..." TEIform="index"/>The qualities of hay are pithily stated...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The qualities of hay are pithily stated in the old saying: " timothy for muscle; clover
                                for milk; corn for fat." Hence timothy is the hay for horses and young stock; and clover
                                for milch cows. People are generally too reckless in feeding cattle promiscuously with
                                whatever they have to give them, without taking much pains to make a proper selection.
                            </p></div3><div3 type="The communications fo farmers..." org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The communications of farmers are always the most valuable matter in any
                                        paper; they deal with practical details, familiar to the man who comes face to
                                        face with difficulties and overcomes them. The editor can select such items of
                                        news or general interest as he thinks will be interesting and useful; but to
                                        build up a truly useful and practical paper, must rely very largely upon the
                                        assistance of practical men.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Massachusetts, Ploughman" TEIform="index"/>—Mass. Ploughman.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Duty" TEIform="index"/>DUTY</head><p TEIform="p">The path of duty is the way to glory; He that walks it, only thirsting For the right, learns
                            to deaden Love of self, before his journey closes He shall find the stubborn thistle
                            bursting Into glossy purples, which outredden All voluptuous garden roses, The path of Duty
                            is the way to glory; He that ever following her commands, On with toil of heart and knees
                            and hands, Thro' the long gorge to the far light has wo His path upward, and prevailed,
                            Shall find the toppling crags of Duty scalec Are close upon the shining table lands, To
                            which our God Himself is moon and sun</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Tennyson" TEIform="persName"/>Tennyson</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We must not be in a hurry..." TEIform="index"/>We must not be in a hurry...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">We must not be in a hurry, when a ma falls, to say: "That man is a co" upt ole
                        hypocrite."</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="There are a great many things which men register..." TEIform="index"/>There are a great many things which men register...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">There are a great many thinv which me register in their journals as th • work of th ¦ devil,
                            that are nothing but th" work of a dis ordered stomach.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ollapodrida" TEIform="index"/>OLLAPODRIDA</head><p TEIform="p">An unpleasant sort of arithmetic—Division mong families. It makes a great difference whether
                            glasses re used over or under the nose. The height of impudence—taking refuge rom the rain
                            in an umbrella shop. Ignorance has no light; error follows a alse one. He is the greatest
                            who chooses to do right t all times. He who lives to no purpose lives to a bad purpose.
                            Severity breeds fear, but roughness engenders hate. We may be as good as we please, if wre
                            please to be good. Whoever conquers indolence can conquer most things. Pleasures come like
                            oxen, and go away like post-horses. Reprove thy friend privately, commend him publicly.
                            Vanity is a strong drink that makes all virtues stagger. He that despiseth small things
                            shall fall little by little. Never apologize for a long letter; you only add to its length.
                            Those who know the least of others think the most of themselves. Men sometimes think they
                            hate flattery; but they only hate the manner of it. Never speak evil of any one. Be
                            charitable in thought, and give even the worst people the benefit of a doubt. The
                            cultivation of the heart should be like that of the garden, where we prune and weed before
                            we begin to plant. To neglect at any time preparations for death, is to sleep on our post at
                            a siege; but to omit it in old age is to sleep at an attack. Dupes, indeed, are many; but of
                            all dupes, there is none so fatally situated as he who lives in undue terror of being duped.
                            It is better to need relief than to want the heart to give it. He that finds a thing, steals
                            it if he endeavors not to restore it. If the gossip is not in her own house, she is in
                            somebody's else. To be at once in any great degree loved and praised is truly rare.
                            Greatness may build the tomb, but goodness must make the epitaph. Everywhere endeavor to be
                            useful, and everywhere you will be at home. There is a certain decorum even in grief; for
                            excess of sorrow is as foolish as profuse laughter. It is good to respect ancient
                            foundations, but we are not, on that account, to neglect founding something in our turn.
                            Vanity, like laudanum, and other poisonous medicine, is beneficial in small, though
                            injurious in large quantities. Very few in the world have their passions adequately occupied
                            ; almost everybody has it in them to be better than they are. In this world there is one
                            thing godlike— the essence of all that ever was or ever will be godlike in this world—the
                            veneration of human worth by the hearts of men. To be in company with those we love,
                            satisfies us; it does not signify whether we speak to them or not, whether we think on them
                            or indifferent things; to be near them is all. The King of Austria has 187 diamonds, yet he
                            can't make a wrood-box, put up stovepipes, nor paint the kitchen floor. Josh Billings says:
                            "Success don't konsist in never making blunders, but never making the same one the seckond
                            time." <pb n="94" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. A Yankee humorist, who had a hard time of it, says :
                            "When a man begins to go down hill, he finds everything greased for the occasion." Our most
                            indifferent actions have the impress of individuality; we may convey an impression not to be
                            effaced for years, by an unconsidered word or gesture. Revenge is a momentary triumph, of
                            which the satisfaction dies at once, and is succeeded bv remorse; whereas forgiveness, which
                            is the noblest of all revenge, entails a perpetual pleasure. The world never keeps faith
                            with the heart that trusts it. Its promises of happiness are perpetually broken. Take it for
                            what it is worth, and set your affections on what is worth more. A Japanese student, newly
                            arrived in this country, thought we were all doctors, because everybody took his hand and
                            asked after his health. John Ruskin says the art of making yourself rich in the ordinary
                            mercantile economists' sense, is equally and necessarily the art of keeping your neighbors
                            poor. A French statistician places the number of human beings who have been killed or lost
                            their lives by camp diseases, in connection with the wars of the nineteenth century, at two
                            hundred millions. This is nearly five times as large as the entire population of the United
                            States. Christians are like the several flowers in a garden, that have each of them the dew
                            of heaven, which, being shaken with the wind, they let fall at each other's roots, whereby
                            they are jointly nourished, and become nourishers of each other. We ought to think much more
                            of walking in the right path, than of reaching our end. We should desiie virtue more than
                            success. If by one wrong deed we could accomplish the liberation of millions, and in no
                            other way, we ought to feel that this good, for which, perhaps, we had prayed with an agony
                            of desire, was denied us by God, Avas reserved for other times and other hands.— Channing:
                            There are a million natural laws of which we know nothing. We are gradually learning them as
                            we find out where beans are in the dark—by feeling a thumb, by discovering that there is
                            something in the way When you get an apple that is half rotten, the other half being as good
                            as though the whole were sound, then you can get a Christian that is rotten on one side, who
                            is as good on the other side as if both sides were good. I have seen persons so violently
                            indignant at missteps in others, that I suspected all the virtue they had was at the window.
                            He was as tender as a woman—or rather, I should have said, he lacked the toughness of a
                            woman; for, slender and shrinking as women are, when troubles come they are almost the only
                            persons who are tough of heart. They are tender of skin, but inside they are strong as iron.
                            Do you know that the way for men to build themselves up is to be ground to powder? It is
                            likewise to be remembered that no man has a right to prophecy good as a consequence of
                            deception. Love sits as God's vicegegent in the soul, and I will not fight with my brethren.
                            It is a man dying with his harness on that angels love to take.—</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Beecher" TEIform="persName"/>Beecher.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Tribune says..." TEIform="index"/>The Tribune says...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Tribune" TEIform="index"/> The Tribune says,</bibl><quote TEIform="quote"> "An Amherst Granger offered a young lady a bushel of potatoes if she would wheel
                                    them through the village at the hour when the students were loafing. She came to
                                    time, wheeled the potatoes home, and asked the Granger to let her know when he had
                                    more to dispose of in that way." Good for her! We have no doubt that she is a plucky
                                    young lady, and not less a lady on account of her pluck.</quote></cit></p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spirit materializations" TEIform="index"/>SPIRIT MATERIALIZATIONS</head><p TEIform="p"> CANAAN, N. Y., Dec. 4. , Dear Shaker: - Business having' called me, in company with two
                                Sisters, to Utica, N. Y., and remaining three days, we attended three materialization
                                seances of the Eddy mediums, who were stopping there. As the public mind is in a state
                                of agitation on the subject, I will simply state a few facts which came under our
                                observations. Seance No. I-composed of fourteen persons, occupied ninety minutes.
                                Fifteen spirit forms appeared, including three former members of our Society. One,
                                whose obituary appeared in the June SHAKER, 1877, being short in stature and much
                                deformed, with peculiarities known only to friends, seemed a perfect test of identity
                                , especially when she told her name. Seance No.2-composed of eighteen. persons.
                                Twenty-two forms appeared, among- whom were little children, gigantic Indians, and a
                                number of our Brethren and Sisters. Some of the latter spoke to us, sending messages to
                                Brethren and Sisters at home, calling us by name and giving their names. Others came
                                across the room, shaking hands with us and others present. Things comical, serious,
                                pleasant and, igrave were curiously blended. They: sang, joked, played musical
                                instruments, when there were none in the cabinet" laughed, and gave good advice to all
                                present. In both of these seances, there came a spirit who spoke audibly and seemed sad
                                and distressed in mind. He want- : ed to say something privately, but could: not, on
                                account of those present I Seance NO.3-held for us in particu- , lar, in the day-time .•
                                Only two other: persons were present, making five in 1 all. The spirit aforesaid came
                                early in I the sitting, and begged the forgiveness, of one of our company, (to whom he l
                                had formerly held intimate relation,) , for grievous wrongs j and in such a 1 spirit of
                                deep contrition that the scene ( was truly affecting. The spirit de- ( clared his
                                inability to progress, or be re-f leased, until he heard, orally, the words ( of
                                forgiveness. f Children, two years of age and up- ] ward j Shaker spirits, in their
                                peculiar 1 costumes j Indians, in their dress; spir- t its with bouquets of flowers in
                                their I hands and wreaths of flowers upon their r heads, which they removed for our ex-
                                s amination j spirits with long, trailing t hair, divers peculiarities of form, dress, t
                                name and mien, helped to make up an I unmistakable manifestation of spirit r identity,
                                in "FORM MATERIALIZATION." c </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Smith, Thomas" TEIform="persName"/>THOMAS SMITH. </byline></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Any person gifted with ordinary common sense can perceive..." TEIform="index"/>Any person gifted with ordinary common sense can perceive...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Any person gifted with ordinary common sense can perceive that life is short, that time
                            flies, that we ought to make good use of the present; but it needs the union of much
                            experience with the most consummate wisdom to know exactly what ought to be done and what
                            ought to be left undone, the latter being frequently by far the more important of the two.
                        </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Was it a dream?" TEIform="index"/>WAS IT A DREAM?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Adler, Wm." TEIform="persName"/>WM. ADLER</byline><p TEIform="p">About a year since, while a resident g of Harvard, Mass., I experienced a very ;. remarkable
                            dream. I seemed to be g walking beside the bank of a beautiful i- river, in an exceedingly
                            straight and i, narrow, but well-worn path. Feeling ,- unusually calm and happy, I prolonged
                            e the walk, admiring, meantime, the s lovely scenery around, when suddenly my attention was
                            arrested by a large 1 number of snakes, which darted across '- my pathway, to my great
                            discomfort ; and alarm. These disagreeable rep- tiles were of every variety of form and ~
                            size. Anon, some glided into the water 1 near, while others came out, and some - of the most
                            hideous of these confronted - me, and darted toward me their forked 1 tongues. Here, then,
                            was a dilemma, from which I saw no means of escape. ~ To proceed farther was impossible, ,
                            though I was very anxious to do so ; - and to go back was equally difficult. r At my right,
                            still sparkled the beautiful ~ river j at my left, a dense forest stood. ) What could I do?
                            Absolutely nothing, ~ but stand still, terrified and bewildered, • unable to move in any
                            direction. At ~ this point, the dream abruptly closed, and I was left to ponder upon its
                            singular character. T However, some six months later, the • same dream recurred again,
                            and with ~. it came what I am inclined to consider an interpretation. For, beside the view
                            of the straight and narrow path, I saw, ~ at the end of the same, a most beautiful I land;
                            and while contemplating this new • feature of the scene, I distinctlv heard I a sweet voice
                            say," Willial~, take courage j turn not back-neither to the right nor left-but press
                            steadily on, : and you shall dwell with me in the l bright and' beautiful land which you l
                            now behold." The glorious scene again ; vanished from my view, and I resolved ~ anew to
                            press onward toward perfection. Perhaps I should remark, just here, l that previous to the
                            repetition of the ~ dream, I was becoming somewhat dis- couraged in my attempts to be a
                            real, self-denying Shaker, or christian-synonymous terms-and consequently feeling my way
                            hedged up, decided that I would leave the Shaker church and return to the life of the world.
                            But by the recurrence of the dream, I was made to realize that the disagreeable reptiles
                            only represented how loath-] some are the passions and appetites .of . the careial mind to
                            Him who has risen triumphant over selfishness and sin, and ] I took heart again and
                            recommenced l my journey. Permit me to say, therefore, in con- l elusion, to all my Brethren
                            and' Sisters, ~ who have commence-C!• to travel in this 1 narrow path: Do not mind
                            obstacles, t nor for a moment think of turning back. Let us press steadily on till we reach
                            that bright and beautiful land ; or, more i practically speaking, till we gain that i
                            enviable position for which we should ~ RoH ~spir~l namely: perfection in purity.•t </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pentateuch" TEIform="index"/>THE PENTATEUCH</head><p TEIform="p">The first five books of the Bible are called by this name. It was derived from the Greek
                            words, "penta," meaning five, and "teuchos," a volume, that is, a five-fold volume.
                            Universal and ancient tradition declares this work to have been written by Moses. It was the
                            general custom with the Hebrews to designate any portion of the sacred literature by the
                            first words in them. The first word in Genesis, in Hebrew, is "Bereshith," translated, "In
                            the beginning." The first book in the Hebrew Bible has no title. The word "Genesis" was
                            prefixed by those who translated it into Greek. This book contains an account of the
                            creation of the world, and of man, the history of the deluge, and the patriarchs to the
                            death of Joseph, and includes a period of 2135 years. Exodus is so called because it
                            contains an account of the departure of the children of Israel from the land of the
                            Egyptians, to the land of promise ; the term is taken from the Greek word exodos, signifying
                            an exit. The Hebrews call this book Veele Semos/i, the words with which it commences,
                            meaning these are the names. Its history includes a period of 145 years: from the death of
                            Joseph to the erection of the tabernacle in the wilderness. The slavery of the Israelites
                            described in the first chapters, is supposed to have continued 90 years. Leviticus treats of
                            the offices, rites and ceremonies of the priests and Levites under the Jewish law. The
                            Hebrew term is Vl-ylkra, "and The (the Lord) called," with which words it commences. Numbers
                            begins and concludes with the numbering of the people. The word Numbers is derived from the
                            Greek of the Septuagint, Aplomol. Its Latin rendering in the Vulgate is Numeric from which
                            the English is derived. The history in'this portion of the Pentateuch extends over about 39
                            years. In the first nine chapters various orders of people are described, and several laws
                            are given or repeated. From the tenth to the thirty-third, the marches and history of the
                            Hebrews are related. Deuteronomy signifies a second law. This book comprises a series of
                            addresses delivered to the assembled Israelites by Moses, when he knew that he must shortly
                            leave them, and they were upon the eve of departure for the promised land. It contains his
                            appointmi 11; of Joshua to succeed him ; h. be no doubt about the .." this book, from the
                            fact &gt; : being described there. ably add \ : y Ezra, also, his .'. - I There
                            authenticity •;. of Moses' det in, as it was j. the transcriber. Canterbury.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Short sermon" TEIform="index"/>Short sermon
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Short sermon.—Who is blind? He who is bent on doing what he should not. Who is
                                    deaf ? He who does not listen to what is beneficial. Who is dumb? He who does not
                                    know how to say kind things at the proper time,—</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Ancient Hindoo writing" TEIform="index"/>Ancient Hindoo Writing.</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="95" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>THE CHILDREN'S GROTTO</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My dear Children: I have a few good words to say to you..." TEIform="index"/>My dear Children: I have a few good words to say to you...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">My dear Children : I have a few good words to say to you, in this, the last paper of the
                                year 1877. When next we meet for counsel, it will be under vei-3' improved conditions. I
                                want to suggest to each of you, the good idea of saving a copy of every number of The
                                Shakee, keeping it nice, untorn, unsoiled in all its parts; and at the end of the year,
                                binding, or having them bound for you, making you a very valuable book. I am aware you
                                love the music; that you sometimes have cut the music out to put into other books; nor
                                you alone—some " children of larger growth"—men and women have done this—but there will
                                be 110 inconvenience of form, hereafter to be contended with. I would have you, dear
                                children, study the beautiful in all around you—the beautiful in language, form,
                                behavior: and to be most agreeable to those you know or believe to be better than you
                                are. Remember to love the good in every one; for by truly loving this good, we will
                                surely grow and become like unto that which we love. Who say they love Jesus, a:;d do
                                not grow more and more like him, are mistaken, in that they think they love him.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/>—Editor.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My dear young friends:" TEIform="index"/>My dear young Friends :</head><p TEIform="p">In our little messenger, " The Shakes," I have noticed with pleasure the" Children's
                                Grotto;" in which you have been occasionally addressed by some kind friend, who has
                                endeavored to impart something useful for you to learn and practice. I say kind friend,
                                because he would not have noticed you thus, were it not that he loved you, and wished to
                                make you wiser, better and more happy. It has been very truly remarked, that " To be
                                good is to be happy;" because to enjoy abiding happiness we must become virtuous. You
                                see, there are different degrees of goodness, as good, better, BEST. Strive to attain
                                the highest degree. Some of you may ask : " What shall I do to attain it?" I answer, you
                                must simply do right in all things; and to do right is to do as well as one knows. As
                                you increase in knowledge, so you may grow in goodness. All children have not the same
                                opportunities to receive instruction. Some have more, some less. To become good, dear
                                young friends, you must ue truthful, honest, obedient, peaceable, kind and dutiful. Some
                                children incline to become mischievous, and take pleasure in doing naughty tricks. Some
                                learn to curse and swear, lie, steal and fight. Those are very wrong; degrading to your
                                nature! If you do wrong, and are sensible of it, you should confess it to your parents
                                or eiders, and strive in future to do better. You don't want—not one of you—to grow up
                                to be like an ugly Thistle, piercing everybody's heart or fingers! You must aspire, dear
                                children, to become intelligent, respectful and obliging; then you will rise in the
                                estimation of all good, honest people. I don't know of any harm in children being
                                playsome—full of frolic and life, at proper seasons; but you need not be tumultuous,
                                malicious nor quarrelsome at any time. The little lambs of the fields, play and gambol
                                in the green pastures. Did you never notice how they skip about, and run from hill to
                                dale, and from hill to hill? I presume, you have. How very harmless they appear! I don't
                                think you ever saw two lambkins tight. I never did, and I am now more than " Three score
                                and ten" years old. Then why should children contend, and strive to hurt each other? I
                                well remember, when I was a small boy, living in my father's family, that when lie was
                                about to slay a calf or lambkin, to obtain fresh meat, I would try to be present. When
                                taking out the tongue of the innocent creature, my father used to call to me, saying,
                                "Here, my child, is a tongue thai never told a Ue." This would immediately set me to
                                thinking, if mine was as innocent of that fault, as many others. Now, if you wish to
                                have people love you, and speak well of you, you must be good children. You can be so,
                                if you will. " Where there is a will, there is a wray." Your friends are all looking
                                forward with anxious expectations to see what you will grow up to be, whether virtuous
                                youth, honest, upright men and women—brothers and sisters in Christ—or otherwise. Oh!
                                how it makes their hearts ache to see you pursue a wrong course! Yea, it causes even the
                                angels to weep! For all that love you, desire your prosperity. And now, my children
                                dear, I'll stop my musings here; Wipe from my eyes, a tear, And pray for you. In heaven
                                I hope to meet You all in union sweet; Walk there the golden street In friendship true.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Buckingham, D. A." TEIform="persName"/>D. A. Buckingham. Shakers, N. Y.</byline></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Advice to boys" TEIform="index"/>Advice to boys
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">ADVICE TO BOYS. Whatever you are, be brave, boys! The liar's a coward and
                                        slave, boys; Though clever at ruses And sharp at excuses, He's a sneaking and
                                        pitiful knave, boys! Whatever you are, be frank, boys! "Pis better than money
                                        and rank, boys; Still cleave to the right, Be lovers of light, Be open,
                                        aboveboard, and frank, boy*! Whatever you are, be kind, boys! Be gentle in
                                        manners and mind, boys; The man gentle in mien, Words, and temper, I ween, Is
                                        the gentleman truly refined, boys! But, whatever you are, be true, "boys! Be
                                        visible through and through, boys; Leave toothers the shamming, The "greening"
                                        and "cramming," In fun and in earnest, be true, boys!</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Leisure hour" TEIform="index"/>Leisure Hour.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Boys' rights" TEIform="index"/>BOYS' RIGHTS</head><p TEIform="p">I wonder now if any one In this broad land has heard, In favor of down-trodden boys One
                                solitary wore ? We hear enough of 'women's rights,' And 'rights of working men,' Of
                                'equal rights,' and 'nation's rights,' But pray just tell us when Boys' rights were ever
                                spoken of? Why we've become so used To being snubbed by every one, And slighted and
                                abused, That when one is polite to us, We open wide our eyes, And stretch them in
                                astonishment To nearly twice their size! Boys seldom dare to ask their Mends To venture
                                ia the house! It don't come natural at all To creep round like a mouse. And if we should
                                forget ourselves And make a little noise! Then ma or auntie sure would say, 'Oh, my!
                                those dreadful boys.' The girls bang on the piano, In peace, but if the boys Attempt a
                                tune with fife and drum, It's 'Stop that horrid noise!' 'That horrid noise!' just think
                                of it; When sister never fails To make a noise three times as bad With everlasting
                                'scales.' Insulted thus, we lose no time In beating a retreat; So off we go to romp and
                                tear, And scamper in the street. No wonder that so many boys Such wicked men become,
                                'Twere better far to let them have Their games and play at home. Perhaps that text the
                                teacher quotes Sometimes—'Train up a child'— Means only train the girls, And let the
                                boys run wild. But patience, and the time shall come When we will all be men, And when
                                it does, I rather think Wrongs will be made light then. </p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rules for general deportment of the young" TEIform="index"/>RULES FOR GENERAL DEPORTMENT
                                OF THE YOUNG</head><p TEIform="p">" "Be kindly affeetioned one toward another." Always give place to age. It should command
                                respect at home and abroad. Use no language in conversation that yon would be unwilling
                                to have reported before your friends. Always consider yourself in company that you may
                                have but one set of manners to cultivate, and those should be, true politeness.
                                Affectation arises from vanity, and should have no place in the deportment of those who
                                wish to become honorable members of society. Cultivation of the mind is as essential as
                                food for the body. Ignorance and sin are closely conjoined. Be as careful in your
                                selection for reading as in the food you eat. Study to become a blessing to society. Be
                                industrious. Be frugal. Be honest in all your dealings. Be neat. If you would be pure,
                                first be chaste. As the character of every individual will be estimated by an observance
                                of the daily life, rather than by the protestations of innocence, you should always
                                walls circumspectly. A modest reserve in the company of either sex, will always command
                                the respect of the virtuous. Accept with this, my young friends, the prayerful interest
                                of your brother, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/>H. C. Blinn</byline></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Anger" TEIform="index"/>Anger
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Anger.—Children, be careful that this enemy of your peace does not become master of you.
                                If so, it will govern you with a rod of iron, and drive out of your heart all the
                                peaceful and happy inmates, as love, meekness, kindness, forbearar.ee, mercy and
                                forgiveness. Watch this enemy, and give it a blow while 3roung, that will stop its
                                growth. Never suffer it to triumph over you, and it will do you no harm.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rev. W. H. H. Murray says..." TEIform="index"/>Rev. W. H. H. Murray says...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Rev. W. H. H. Murray says that the religion of the future will be a Christianity that shall
                            help the poor, etc., and that the theologians on Andover Hill will be taught how to minister
                            to sick people in city tenementhouses; and the New England churches will learn that
                            Christianity is not theology; not thinking and believing, but being and doing good.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Form materialization" TEIform="index"/>FORM MATERIALIZATION</head><p TEIform="p">[The following is a recent editorial in the Banner of Light. We have expressed our personal
                            confidence in spirit materializations. We deem them, however, nonessentials to salvation.
                            Others among the Shakers, deem them among the highest of providences; while others again do
                            not believe in them at all or consider them fraudulent and impossible. We print a letter,
                            elsewhere, received from a believing company.—Ed.] The frequent and sickening exposures
                            attending this phase of spirit phenomena, are quite naturally staggering the faith of
                            thousands of Spiritualists in the probability of such materialization in the past, or its
                            possibility in the future. Even now there are old " dyed in the wool" Spiritualists, whose
                            belief is anchored to a knowledge extending over a quarter of a century, who not only
                            question the fact of spirit forms ever being materialized at any of our seances, but who are
                            debating whether it is not a sacred duty they owe the cause and humanity, to organize
                            combinations to travel the country and, as Spiritualists, expose the fallaciousness of the
                            claim of form materialization. No phase of the phenomena has ever created a tithe of the bad
                            blood and bickering among Spiritualists, as has this; needlessly so, we think. The
                            difficulties have arisen rather through the ignorance of investigators and the dogmatic
                            proclivities of a few self-appointed exponents. It seems to us, that when ali the rubbish
                            which environs the subject is removed by calm, careful, patient students, who are seeking
                            for the truth and not to substantiate some pet theory of their own, which is often born of
                            generations of narrow creedal training; when these investigators shall be composed of men
                            possessing the zeal, persistency and devotion of some of the present champions of this
                            phase, without their blind narrowness and want of capacity to comprehend the subject in its
                            scientific aspects; when they shall bring to the subject abilities capable of mastering its
                            subtle laws; in a word, when the investigation shall be pursued by strictly scientific
                            processes, then we shall come to a better understanding of the matter; and by scientific
                            processes, we do not wish to be understood as declaring that any written code of rules must
                            be followed; in the very nature of the case, many of the laws governing the action of the
                            student can only be learned by actual observation, and afterwards intelligently applied. The
                            words science and scientific, have come to be looked upon by many Spiritualists with
                            suspicion. They personify them in the persons of Carpenter, Lankester, and others, and feel
                            that they do not wish to cultivate such narrow acquaintances; rather let us look to the
                            fountain head for their true significance. There we find that science means truth
                            ascertained; that which is known; knowledge; penetrating and comprehensive information, and
                            the like. All of our readers will readily agree, we presume, that only by the application of
                            science as thus interpreted, can we arrive at any satisfactory elucidation of this phase of
                            spirit phenomena, or any other, for that matter. From our standpoint, we cannot see how a
                            Spiritualist can doubt the possibility of form materialization or scout sonic of the
                            evidences that such materialization is already an accomplished fact. We, all of us, know of
                            our own knowledge that spirits possess the power to communicate with us, and under proper
                            conditions to do many things which are probably as difficult to accomplish as to materialize
                            a form, and would be so acknowledged by us could we fully understand the process in each
                            case. Why should form materialization be considered so remarkable? It is really only a
                            mechanical process. Let the investigator be fully imbued with the knowledge that the form
                            standing before him is not the actual identical spirit body of his friend put through some
                            inexplicable process which renders it visible; let him realize still further that the
                            materialized form shown, never belonged to that spirit, and consists only of chemical,
                            electric and magnetic elements gathered from the atmosphere, the medium and the
                            investigator; let him comprehend all this, and the mystery disappears to a great extent.
                            There is another feature of form materialization, a logical deduction from what has already
                            been stated, and which we also state upon the authority of a spirit, which is that the
                            spirit upon entering the materialized form, experiences the same sensations that mortals
                            sometimes do on entering a strange house, or as one spirit graphically expressed it, " we
                            feel as strange as you would if you had borrowed a suit of clothes that didn't fit very
                            well, to go to church in." The wonderful fascination of-this phenomenon springs from the
                            heart rather than the intellect of the investigator; all the pent-up affections of a
                            sorrowing soul cry out for contact with the dear one, the cords of tenderness are strained
                            to the utmost tension with the thought that the loved form may appear, may be seen and
                            caressed, even though it be ever so lightly, or the vision ever so fleeting. When the
                            investigator can comprehend that in caressing this form, he does not actually touch the
                            loved spirit, nor come any closer, if indeed so close, as when said spirit is controlling a
                            medium in the flesh, then will the fascination flowing from the heart and the sacred
                            recollections of the past, vanish, it seems to us, to a great extent, if not entirely; and
                            the pursuit of this phase will be, among intelligent people at least, from a purely
                            intellectual standpoint.</p></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Czar of Russia thinks that Turkey..." TEIform="index"/>The Czar of Russia thinks that Turkey...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The Czar of Russia thinks that Turkey hasn't had enough dressing.</p></div2><div2 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Elements of food lost in cooking" TEIform="index"/>ELEMENTS OF FOOD LOST IN COOKING</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Food must contain three classes of elements—those vhich will feed the brain and
                                    nerves, those which feed muscles and tissues, and those which furnish heat and fat.
                                    These elements may be found combined so as to be soluble in water, cold or hot, or
                                    both, and therefore if cooked in water, are lost. The musclefeeding elements of all
                                    meats and fish consist in fibrin and albumen and in the flesh of all young animals,
                                    as veal and lamb, and in all kinds of fish albumen predominates. Albumen is soluble
                                    in cold water, but coagulates and becomes solid in hot water. For example, the white
                                    of an egg, which is albumen, may be dissolved and lost in cold water, but on being
                                    dropped into hot water immediately coagulates and becomes insoluble. All meats,
                                    therefore, lose a portion of their nutrition, and some a very large portion, by
                                    being soaked in water, or by being put into cold water to boil, and it boiled at
                                    all, should be put into boiling water, unless the water in which they are boiled is
                                    to be saved as soup. In that case, the flavor and nutritive properties of the soap
                                    are much better by being first soaked in cold water and boiled in the same water.
                                    Besides albumen, other valuable elements are lost in water, whether hot or cold, as
                                    is shown by chemical analysis. If the flesh of animals or fish be cut up fine, and
                                    washed and filtered, the water is found to contain not only the albumen, but the
                                    osmazome which gives the flavor, the phosphates which feed the brains and the
                                    nerves, and all soluble salts of the blood, while there remains nothing nutritious
                                    but fibrin and the insoluble salts, which constitute the basis of bones. By boiling,
                                    instead of roasting or frying meats or fish, we lose therefore that which gives them
                                    relish, much of the true nourishment, and some other valuable elements. On the other
                                    hand, by soaking in cold water, and boiling gradually, and retaining the liquid, we
                                    get all the valuable properties of meat. The liquid contains all the soluble
                                    properties, and indeed all the important properties necessary for sickly or
                                    sedentary persons; and the solids contain the fibrin and lime which are wanted for
                                    muscular power and strength of sinew and bone. Another practical error in regard to
                                    soups, relates to the nutrition in the gelatinous portions of soup obtained from the
                                    cartilages and tendons of the joints of meat, which are usually selected under the
                                    impression that the more gelatinous the more nutritious the soup, whereas it is
                                    found to be true that gelatine is in no sense nutritious. Its only iise in the
                                    living system seems to be mechanical, forming protection to the joints as a kind of
                                    cushion, and attaching the muscles to the bones, and as food, answering as waste
                                    material to keep the bowels in action. This is true of all animal jellies, as calf's
                                    foot, isinglass, etc.—</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Philosophy of eating" TEIform="index"/>Philosophy of Eating.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARIES</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bangs, Josiah" TEIform="index"/>Josiah Bangs
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Alfred, Me., <persName reg="Bangs, Josiah" TEIform="persName">Josiah Bangs</persName>, aged 84 years, 7
                                mos., on October 20th, 1877, and blessed is the memorv of such!</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lewis, Sarah Ann" TEIform="index"/>Sarah Ann Lewis
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., Oct, 19, 1877. <persName reg="Lewis, Sarah Ann" TEIform="persName">SARAH Ann
                                Lewis</persName>, aged 64 years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bryant, Hannah" TEIform="index"/>Hannah Bryant
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Canaan, N. Y., Oct. 10,1877, <persName reg="Bryant, Hannah" TEIform="persName">Hannah Bryant</persName>
                                aged 92 years. [ Besides being a beautiful mother in Israel, she was physically noted
                                for never having taken an emetic, nor the loss of tooth!—[Editor.]</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beers, Polly" TEIform="index"/>Polly Beers
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Hancock Church Family, Oct. 19,1S77, <persName reg="Beers, Polly" TEIform="persName">Polly
                                Beers</persName>, aged 73.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sanders, Celia" TEIform="index"/>Celia Sanders
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The two following notices shoul have been sent us sooner. Will our friend make it
                                convenient to do better in future ? At West Gloucester, Me., <persName reg="Sanders, Celia" TEIform="persName">Celia Sandeks</persName>, aged 07 years, on Aug. 19, 1877.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Stebbins, Persis" TEIform="index"/>Persis Stebbins
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Enfield, Conn., <persName reg="Stebbins, Persis" TEIform="persName">Peesis Stebbins</persName>, aged 83
                                years, on Aug. 23, 1S77. A. believer for sixty-four "years!</p></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="During a recent thunderstorm..." TEIform="index"/>During a recent thunderstorm...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">During a recent thunder-storm near Memphis, Tenn., a negro was severely kicked by a vicious
                            mule, and just as he was picking himself up, a stroke of lightning hit the mule and killed
                            him dead on the spot. "Well, dar!" exclaimed the negro, "ef dis chile hain't got powerful
                            friends to 'venge his insults, den dere's no use tryin to hab faith in anything! "</p></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Typographical errors" TEIform="index"/>Typographical errors.</head><p TEIform="p">—In a recent number of the English Workman, Richard A. Proctor bewails some of his
                            typographical misfortunes. One journal speaking of his charts of 22,434 fixed stars, made it
                            " chart of 2,2235 stars.'' This mishap he forgives in consideration of the dullness of a
                            compositor's life; but the following he thinks a severe test of any one's good nature. He
                            wrote of the solar spectra, " lines, stripes, and bands of the violet end of the spectra,"
                            which appeared when printed as " lines, stripes, and bonds for the violent kind of
                            spectres."</p></div2><div2 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Horse doctors, according to their own reports, are increasing and doing splendidly..." TEIform="index"/>Horse doctors, according to their own reports, are increasing and doing splendidly...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Horse doctors, according to their own reports, are increasing and doing
                                    splendidly. But how about the horses?</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New York herald" TEIform="index"/>N. Y. Herald.</bibl></cit> What does it matter about the horses so long as the doctors thrive?</p></div2><pb n="96" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Heavenly home" TEIform="index"/>HEAVENLY HOME</head><p TEIform="p">Canterbury, N. H. I covet not earth's treasures, They fail before my sight; I would renew my
                            spirit Unto the Virgin life. To obtain a home in heaven Is worth the strife Of forsaking the
                            earthly, To live the angel life.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Battle of life" TEIform="index"/>THE "BATTLE OF LIFE."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Newton, Agnes E." TEIform="persName"/>AGNES E. NEWTON</byline><p TEIform="p">The battle of life is not encountered upon a field, where human beings controlled by thirst
                            for power and fame meet, and fall in deadly conflict. It takes place within the human soul ;
                            no one can escape it—all to a greater or less extent, must participate therein. Our Savior
                            ably illustrated this when he said : "A man's foes shall be they of his own household."
                            Truly these are) sufficient in might and strength to constitute a battle, requiring the
                            utmost courage to engage. Strong as are the enemies which beset the Christian's path, if
                            clad in truth's bright armor, the battle of life, to him, will be a success ; the laurels of
                            victory not imaginary attainments, but present realities. How insignificantly slight will
                            seem the battle, when the glorious end is achieved, and the Savior's words are the
                            Christian's to repeat: "I have overcome the world." O, that all could be wise, old and
                            young, especially we who are just entering life's battle field, and choose for our armor the
                            one thing needful, the active principle of truth. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Purity" TEIform="index"/>PURITY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Clapp, L." TEIform="persName"/>L. CLAPP</byline><p TEIform="p">'' Pure as the crystal waters, White as snow my soul shall be; When the struggle is
                            completed, And from earthly troubles free." This was the aspiration and happy thought that
                            filled my mind while in sacred worship this morning; a cherished hope of freedom and
                            releasement from sin ; a triumph over the earthly inheritance ; with a robe made beautiful
                            and pure by an upright life, of honest endeavor to do my Christian duty before God. O,
                            Purity ! in the depths of my soul thou hast an abode, the germ of a spiritual life imbedded
                            in the heart's deep soil; beneath the light and brightness of heavenly beauty, mayst thou
                            blossom as the beautiful rose of Sharon. As a star in the firmament, ever constant and
                            enduring in its course, so would I have purity the all-controlling power of my life. I would
                            be ever aspiring, through the sunshine and storm, up, up to the heights of virgin excellence
                            ; to an atmosphere where the spiritual element matures into the loveliness of the angel
                            life. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Physical resurrection" TEIform="index"/>THE PHYSICAL RESURRECTION</head><p TEIform="p">You may see, kind friends, that the world of mind is moving correctly, and pretty fast too.
                            We clip from the Albany Express', and expect to hear oi many similar departures from error
                            unto reason : "This was the subject of a sermon preached last Sunday evening by Rev. Mr.
                            Morse, pastor of the Tabernacle Baptist Church. The purpose of the discourse was to show
                            that there is no resurrection of the natural body, or the body that is put into the grave.
                            The positions taken were sustained by appeals to reason and scripture. The discussion of the
                            same subject will be continued to-morrow evening."</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is one of the striking facts of Christian experience, that sometimes the purest joys..." TEIform="index"/>It is one of the striking facts of Christian experience, that sometimes the purest joys...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">It is one of the striking facts of Christian experience, that sometimes the purest joys, like
                            jewels in the mine, are to be found where all to the outward eye seems dark and forbidding.
                            This is one of the wonders of divine grace. There is a "good," independent of outward
                            conditions—a good which "moth and rust cannot corrupt," which bereavement and affliction
                            cannot quite rend away. The soul holds it by a grasp that the fear of death cannot dissolve
                            and by a title that no human decision can set aside. And it fills the soul; it satisfies the
                            cravings of its immortal nature; it endures the test when all things else, —the prizes of
                            effort, the triumphs of genius, the successes of enterprise,—mock the soul's cheated
                            anticipations. To the very last, its value is undiminished and its luster is un dimmd. It is
                            a pearl of great price; it is the good part that can never be taken away.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Trouble" TEIform="index"/>Trouble.</head><p TEIform="p">In ninety-nine cases out of a hundred, mankind make their own troubles jit is not in the
                            nature of things that it shoulc jbe otherwise. And yet we might be the mos happy people that
                            the sun shines on, ifw pleased. Life would run smoothly in th "•rooves if we would only let
                            it; but we are e not content to do so—in fact, contented Avith 1 nothing! From the cradle to
                            the tomb we c re continually fretting about something, v We are living at altogether too
                            fast and too ^ eckless a rate. We innate the balloon beyond its capacity to bear, and then
                            wonder hat it collapses, and we get a fall. Contentnent—to let things take their course—is a
                            ondition we have yet to learn. But how an we expect to be free from the trouble, so ong as
                            we are seeking for it! We are much ike the son of the Emerald Isle, who was ' niver at peace
                            widout he was at war wid omebody." We constantly make trouble— get into hot water—and then
                            grumble. But he world wags on just the same, and will unto the end, although we hasten our
                            end by constant restlessness.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Trouble" TEIform="index"/>Trouble.</head><p TEIform="p">There is a structure which everybody is Duilding, young and old, each one for himself. It is
                            called character; and in it every act of life is a stone. If day by day we are careful to
                            build our lives with pure, noble , and upright deeds, at the end will stand a fair temple,
                            honored by God and man. But as one leak will sink a ship and one flaw break a chain, so one
                            mean, dishonorable, untruthful act or word will forever leave its impress, and work its
                            influence, on our characters. 1 Then let the several deeds unite to form a day, and one by
                            one the days grow into noble i years; and the years, as they slowly pass, i will raise at
                            last a beautiful edifice, enduring forever to our praise.</p></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Printing and journalism in China" TEIform="index"/>Printing and journalism in China</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A , Chinese printing office is a greater curiosity , than one would think. The
                                    alphabet num- , bers way into the thousands, and a cap and lower case goes all the
                                    way round the inside ¦ of a two-story building, and half way up the roof. It takes
                                    an apprentice twenty years to learn the case, and then he has to use a step ladder
                                    to get at the higher branches. A case was pied once in Canton, and it took five days
                                    to remove the type from the body of the foreman. They punctuate wherever they can
                                    drop a dot, without regard to the prospective. When the editor coins a word, the
                                    printer whittles out a new character with his jackknife. The journeymen set type by
                                    the square foot, and never belong to a union. They do their press work by hand, and
                                    use boxing gloves to ink the type. They have one paper in the empire a thousand
                                    years old, and the bound volumes half fill a pagoda. It is rumored that Bennett has
                                    started to edit that venerable paper. The editor's head is responsible for all items
                                    published in the paper, and is taken off whenever an article of news is published.
                                    Not an editor has been beheaded in China for the last five hundred years. The
                                    Chinese have just invented a twenty-five cylinder press for printing tea chests,
                                    with which they are able to print one a week.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="San Francisco monitor" TEIform="index"/>San Francisco Monitor</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dressing with plainness" TEIform="index"/>Dressing with plainness</head><p TEIform="p">It would lessen the burdens of many who find it hard to maintain their place in society. It
                            would lessen the force of the temptations which often lead men to barter honor and honesty
                            for display. If there was less strife in dress at church, people in moderate circumstances
                            would be more inclined to attend. Universal moderation in dress at church would improve the
                            worship, by the removal of many wandering thoughts. It would enable all classes of people to
                            attend church better in unfavorable weather. It would lessen, on the part of the rich, the
                            temptation to vanity. It would lessen, on the part of the poor, the temptation to be envious
                            and malicious. It would save valuable time on the Sabbath. It would relieve our means from a
                            serious pressure, and thus enable us to do more for good enterprises.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beautiful thought" TEIform="index"/>A beautiful thought</head><p TEIform="p">God knows what keys in the human soul to touch, in order to draw out its sweeter and more
                            perfect harmonies. They may be the minor strains of sadness and sorrow ; they may be the
                            loftier notes of joy and gladness. God knows where the melodies of our nature are, and what
                            discipline wrill bring them forth. Some with plaintive tongues must walk in lowly vales of
                            life's weary way ; others, in loftier hymns, sing of nothing but joy, as they tread the
                            mountain tops of life; but they all unite without discord or jar, as the ascending anthem of
                            loving and believing hearts finds its way into the chorus of the redeemed heaven.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hold on boys" TEIform="index"/> Hold on, boys.</head><p TEIform="p">—-Hold on to your tongue when you are just ready to swear, lie, or speak harshly, or use an
                            improper word. Hold on to your foot when you are on the point of kicking, running off from
                            study, or pursuing the path of error, shame or crime. Hold on to your temper when you are
                            angry, excited or imposed upon, or others are angry with you. Hold on to your heart when
                            evil associates seek your company, and invite you to join in their mirth, games and revelry.
                            Hold on to your good name at all times, for it is of more value than gold, high places, or
                            fashionable attire. Hold on to truth, for it will sei-ve you well, and do you through
                            eternity. Hold on to virtue, for it is above all price to you, in all times and in all
                            places. Hold on to your good character, for it is, and ever will be, your best wealth.</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>