<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm0903" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title><editor role="editor" TEIform="editor"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/></editor></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">9</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">3</biblScope><date value="18790301" TEIform="date">March 1879</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">49-72</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="9" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="3" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                                     <pb id="p1"/>
<p> Vol. IX. No. 3. MARCH, 1879. 60 Cents Per Annum, MANIFESTO. (OFFICIAL MONTHLY.) G. A. LOMAS, Editoe. Published by
                        the United Societies. OUR HOME AT HARVARD, MASS. "And they shall turn to you for a testimony:" "Go preach the
                        Kingdom of God!" ADDKESS ALL COMMUNICATIONS TO " The Shaker Manifesto, Shakers, N.D." G. B. AVERY, PUBLISHER. 1879.</p>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <pb id="p2"/>
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[ads deleted]</p>
                        </div2>
                    --><pb n="49" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Interior life" TEIform="index"/>INTERIOR LIFE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Devyr, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/>CECELIA DEVYR</byline><p TEIform="p">Seek not within the darkness of the earth. Thy friends nor flowers ; For lo ! their spirits
                            have a radiant birth Through death's dim hours. Ask for the myst'ry hidden in the light, For
                            eyes are blind ; Seek for the veil that screens all mortal sight. And heaven thou'lt find.
                            'Tis but the olden root the sod conceals, The flowers are new; A re-creative power, the
                            spring reveals Through heat and dew. The simplest blossom of the mountain-pass, A marvel
                            seems; When 'neath the magic of wondrous glass Its beauty beams. And yet within this
                            revelation, hides A marvel still— A life—a presence calmly there abides, That makes us
                            thrill. Only the eye clairvoyant can behold The spirit flower; Gath'ring its robes of purple
                            pearl and gold, In dying hour. And yet, the eye clairvoyant like the lens, A limit finds;
                            The infinite creation, so transcends Our girded minds. The sun that gives to us this fertile
                            ball, Has jealous light, That shuts out with a golden roof and wall, The stars of night. And
                            thus the life external wraps the soul In fervid beams; Conceals the glories that around it
                            roll, Beyond its dreams. Yet still, we wonder that we know in part, And only so ; And mourn
                            to think, the garden of the heart In growth is slow. But death will make the spirit powers
                            complete ; And angels bring Blest words, wherein life's holy meanings meet ; Wake, it is
                            Spring. Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Party" TEIform="index"/>PARTY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, Elijah" TEIform="persName"/>ELIJAH MYRICK</byline><p TEIform="p">" One faith, one Lord, and one baptism " admits of no party in the Christ family. Party is
                            the bane of communal and social life. It is alienation of individuals first; and too often
                            augments into strong parties, which, led on by a blind prejudice, disturbs the peace, and
                            impedes the progress of society. Said Franklin : " Now that we have declared our
                            independence, if we don't hang together we shall each hang apart"—be hung by our enemies, is
                            the inference. A party spirit—"a house divided against itself "—is an element of weakness,
                            which, if persisted in, is sure ruin. The oneness of interest, love and affection manifested
                            in a true, parental government, is a type of the heavenly. It is not republican—" The
                            greatest good to the greatest number." It seeks the greatest good to all. Without this
                            central idea, this oneness of interest and unselfish love, there will always be parties and
                            divisions, followed by clamoring for position, for self, or party friends, and ten- acity
                            for office and authority for selfish ends. Those time-honored individuals who<pb n="50" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 50 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. have advanced the world, lived and moved above all
                            party interests. They were as true as the needle to the pole to their convictions of right.
                            Conscious of their rectitude, and the purity of their motives, they feared not the verdict
                            of the world " when truth should come uppermost and justice should be done." While to the
                            partisan—he who has bartered his manhood for fleeting popularity—the balance of justice is
                            ever a terror. There is no stability, hence no safety in party. To-day adored, to-morrow
                            abhorred—the sport of the ever-changing winds of a time-serving party. The confiding friends
                            of to-day may be your open enemies to-morrow, and wound the deeper for the confidence you
                            gave them. Never yield selfhood a servant to party. But, " Stand upright, and them standest
                            forever. Live by the truth, 'twill forsake thee never. Though days of thy triumph tarry."
                            Position is not proof against party prejudice. When it usurps magnanimity, the more
                            deplorable the consequences. Favoritism, except for true merit, is a sure cause of jealousy,
                            envy, and hence, of party. Let Jacob's experiment with Joseph be an instructive lesson—a
                            warning. Garments made of the Christian virtue, sewed with the silken thread of Charity for
                            those most in need, will do the best service. Would we be allied to those great souls who
                            were careful of God's honor, and careless of men's applause, our singleness of purpose, and
                            integrity, must be wound up to that degree of intensity that it will never run down nor be
                            dwarfed into a partisan. We must be strong with divine strength ; wise with that wisdom
                            which cometh from above ; loving with the love of Christ ; men of God. " God give us
                            men,a,time like this demands, Strong minds, great hearts, true faith, and ready hands. Men,
                            whom the lusts of office do not kill, Men, whom the spoils of office cannot buy; Men who
                            have opinions, and a will; Men who have honor—men who will not lie; Men who can stand before
                            a demagogue, And face his treacherous flatterings without winking, Tall men, sun-crowned,
                            who live above the fog. In public duty, and in private thinking. For while the rabble with
                            their thumbworn creeds, Their large professions, and their little deeds, Mingle in selfish
                            strife, lol goodness weeps, Wrong rules the land, and waiting justice sleeps " Harvard,
                            Mass. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Principles" TEIform="index"/>PRINCIPLES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName"/>WM. H. BUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p">The love of truth is natural to the human mind. But this statement seems to be contradicted
                            by all experience. Man has all along accepted fancy instead of fact, the absurd in place of
                            the consistent, and clung to error as though his eternal welfare depended upon it. This only
                            proves that in hie original condition he was incapable of ascertaining all truth at once.
                            Eyes had he in the beginning, but capable of seeing above, him only the blue canopy studded
                            with unnumbered gems. That was truth to him to a certain extent. He rejoiced in it, for he
                            beheld there beauty, sublim-<pb n="51" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 51 ity and glory. But
                            is it to him now "little joy To know lie's farther off from heaven Than when he was a boy ?
                            " The old heaven of his original fancy has disappeared forever, but behold the infinitude of
                            glories that have succeeded! The gods and goddesses that once peopled fountain and river,
                            mountain and forest, have fled, but the sources of inspiration for the poet are more
                            abundant now than ever before. Theologians have laid great stress upon the necessity of a
                            divine revelation, and, if we can rely upon their statements, we have it in the form of
                            books called the Bible, the Koran, the Shasta, and the like. But the Book, even to the most
                            orthodox of them, is not sufficient in itself. Its literal sense does not content them,
                            hence they must allegorize and spiritualize in order to satisfy the demands of unfolding
                            reason, even where religious truth alone is concerned. Jesus was not satisfied with the
                            Bible of his own people, and therefore appealed to the revelation of God in his own soul as
                            something of higher authority than the ancients had taught. The scientist is not content
                            with old theories of science; continued investigations and discoveries demand new theories.
                            The future will doubtless call for still newer ones. As well undertake to confine the
                            Infinite Life within the compass of a human body, as to limit divine principles to any or
                            all of the books that have ever been or shall be composed by human minds. Dissatisfaction
                            with the enunciations and theories of any one age is not inconsistent with the statement
                            that man is a Lover of truth. He may cling to the past because his feet are not well planted
                            upon the eternal foundations. He may be fearful lest the billows continually swelling and
                            rolling on the ocean of life should forever engulf him and his hopes. He may cherish the
                            truth which he holds with ardent affection, yet not with the confidence which truth demands
                            of him. His timid utterance is: " If the foundations be destroyed what can the righteous do
                            ?" whereas he should be able exultingly to exclaim: " We will not fear though the earth be
                            removed." The present is an age of investigation. It is right that it should be so. All are
                            interested in the discovery of truth, whether called scientific or religious, for all may be
                            alike benefited by it. It is said that some have been rendered skeptical thereby. If their
                            skepticism consists in the rejection of superstitions, whether1 old or new, so much the
                            better. These have never helped the world. " The truth shall make you free." If it is said
                            that scientific investigations tend to make men atheistic and materialistic, this may fairly
                            and squarely be denied. If some, called scientists, are materialists, yet thousands of
                            others are not so. Let all truths be thoroughly and candidly examined; they contain the
                            principles of life both present and future. " Life and immortality were brought to light" by
                            Jesus. Every other one may do the same, for himself at least, if not for thousands of others
                            now sitting in the darkness of doubt respecting the immortal existence. Groveland, N. Y.</p></div2><pb n="52" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Omnipresence" TEIform="index"/>OMNIPRESENCE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName">ANTOINETTE DOOLITTLE</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">When God created man and woman and endowed them with reason and intelligence, those powers
                            were given to be used. It was not the design of the Creator that man should fold his hands
                            and close his eyes, and accept every thing as true, without investigation, and merely say "
                            God works in a mysterious way His wonders to perform " ; neither can he. When he or she
                            reads or hears that God is omnipresent, fills immensity, and that "not a sparrow falls to
                            the ground without His knowledge, they intuitively ask, if this be true, how, and why? Men
                            and women are God-created diadems of beauty and strength in the hands of their Creator.
                            True, when in a fractional condition, individualized, we are atoms, like sands upon the
                            sea-shore; but when aggregated, and added to the vast multitude of intelligences, we rise in
                            the likeness, and reflect the image of the great LifeGiver and Preserver ; and we learn to
                            think and reason, as God thinks and reasons. He would reason with man through the medium of
                            all his works, and give lessons from the lower to the higher, as well as to point to the
                            higher for the attainment of greater perfection in goodness and knowledge. God is in the
                            lowest strata of the earth, as well as upon its surface, to vivify and quicken vegetable
                            life. Trees, plants and flowers, in their proper season, chant the praises of the Productive
                            powers, and wave their branches in token of gratitude for fostering care. All of God's works
                            are in harmony. There is order in the heavens and order on the earth. The lower forms of
                            creation are to a large degree governed by compulsive force; while the higher, and more
                            sublimated, are governed by inductive law, to a great extent. And man and woman, by reason
                            of their power of susceptibility and capability to act, become their own agents, in a large
                            measure,as regards the power of choice. How careful should we be in the exercise of this
                            power, ever remembering that the greatest talent that any mortal possesses is an endowment,
                            dispensed to be unselfishly used, and added to the sum of cumulative knowl- edge. If we toil
                            diligently and improve faithfully the talent given to us, and give liberally to others of
                            the product of our labors, by this means we can bless humanity and carry the fruitage of a
                            rich harvest to our own garners. By such agencies, have the purest and best thoughts that
                            God has given to prophets, martyrs, and saints of old been borne to us on the wings of the
                            spiritual winds along the highway of truth, down through the ages. Who maketh one man or
                            woman to differ from another ? God is the Giver, we the receivers. Then why should we boast
                            ? There are diversity of gifts, but one source. To one is given the ability to study
                            astronomical figures ; to search the stellar regions; to mark the course and find the home
                            of the fixed planets. Another turns his attention to geology, and enters into rapport with
                            the mineral department, and studies to comprehend the foundation of the material world, the
                            frame-work of such a grand and noble structure; and<pb n="53" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. 53 from the strata of rocks to read history more correctly than has been
                            transmitted to present generations by the written pages of the past. There are many fields
                            of labor, and different departments, but they are all God's fields, and His workshops. Man
                            and woman are his mediumistic instruments; through them He works, by them He perfects His
                            plans. The exterior, material, being only an outward expression of the interior and
                            spiritual; every step taken to progress and perfect the natural is a co-opera- tive adjunct
                            to help roll forward the spiritual work of uplifting humanity to more refined' and
                            sublimated conditions, preparing them to enter into harmonious relation and action with
                            angelic beings in the inner sphere of light and love, where with them they may continue in
                            the path of endless progression on and still on unto higher and broader fields, nearer the
                            throne of the Eternal Father and Mother. Thus we reason that God's universe, taken as a
                            whole, is a unitary compact. He is found in all His works, and thus fills immensity. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="No time for hating" TEIform="index"/>NO TIME FOR HATING</head><p TEIform="p">Begone with feud ! away with strife ; Our human hearts unmating ; Let us be friends again!
                            This life Is all too short for hating ; So dull the day, so dim the way, So rough the road
                            we're faring— Far better weal with faithful friend, Than stalk along uncaring. The barren
                            fig, the withered vine, Are types of selfish living ; But souls that give, like thine and
                            mine, Renew their life by living. While cypress waves o'er early graves, On all the ways
                            we're going, Far better plant where seed is scant, Than tread on fruit that's growing. Away
                            with scorn! Since die we must— And rest on one low pillow ; There are no rivals in the dust—
                            No foes beneath the willow. So dry the bowers, so few the flowers, Our earthly way
                            discloses, Far better stoop where daisies droop, Than tramp o'er broken roses ! Of what are
                            all the joys we hold, Compared to joys above us, And what are rank, and power, and gold,
                            Compared to hearts that love us 1 So fleet our years, so full of tears, So closely death is
                            waiting, God give us peace for loving grace But leave no time for hating. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Man, a symbol of what society ought to be" TEIform="index"/>MAN, A SYMBOL OF WHAT SOCIETY
                            OUGHT TO BE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Frazer, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL FRAZER</byline><p TEIform="p">He is a world in miniature; and when standing in the light and life of hygienic law,
                            symbolizes what society can attain to. All the internal functions of his body co-operate for
                            the general good, automatically manifesting a vital community of interests. That the
                            integrity of this little world should be preserved intact, telegraphic lines from a central
                            sensorium radiate to, and spread themselves over the confines of his body; so that the
                            slightest harmful touch is speedily recorded, and prompt assistance is in stantly at hand.
                            We boast of our civilization and attainments, and point to our telegraphic feats with
                            complacency ; but far away in the dark oblivion, of which historic time is but a point, all
                            animals were supplied each with atelegraphic apparatus, beneficently guarding its whole
                            vital domain. No member so insignificant as even to be liable to neglect, while the inner
                            machinery of life distributed the vital fluid with Pentecostal equality; teaching, that even
                            as we are cared for, so should society be constituted and cared for. In the body physical,
                            if one member suffers, so also do the others. In the body moral when the general happiness
                            is impaired, everymember is involved. In the present form of social life, when the markets
                            of the world are overstocked with goods, and their values suddenly changed, commercial
                            distress, distrust and panics arise, crowding the labor<pb n="54" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 54 THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. market with the unemployed. Then landless men and women find that themselves are
                            like the goods they have made, commodities. Violations of social laws are at all times full
                            of danger. Absolute slavery " is the sum of all villainies," inasmuch as it made men and
                            women commodities. The degradation of the slave degraded also the owner and his family; and
                            retributively he becomes a slave to the enslaved. And so of every wrong to the smallest jot.
                            " Whatever measure ye mete unto men, will be measured to you again," is one of the ever
                            active laws, inherent in the Moral Universe. In the World Social, the measure of the
                            happiness of the millions is the happiness of the unit. Where men and women are commodities
                            absolute or circumstantial, there ever will be a feeling of unrest; an uneasiness, " a
                            fearful looking for judgment." The wrongs of Ireland created Fenianism. and a few
                            skirmishing Irishmen were able to shake the British empire, and put the peace of Europe in
                            jeopardy. Had the people of Ireland been owners of the soil, Fenianism would have been an
                            impossibility. But the millions, being landless, are forced to offer themselves as
                            commodities in many markets. To-day the great Eepublic is in peril! Why ? because within her
                            borders millions of men and women are also commodities ! The whole fabric of social life,
                            law and government, in what is called Christendom, rests on a bed of moral nitro-glycerine.
                            Would we tolerate for an instant a dangerous explosive in the basement of our homes knowing
                            that a slight jar would involve life and property in wreck and ruin ? " The Peculiar
                            Institution, the sum of all villainies," which but lately existed at the South, although
                            having its foundations wide as an empire, and rooted in the interests and affections of the
                            ruling classes, came suddenly to an end, and passed away in blood, fire andsconvulsions—
                            vanished in one awful explosion. The moral providences in human experi- ence point but in
                            one direction : if you will be happy, make those around you so. Have you a farm ? help your
                            neighbor to one ; love him in this thing as you do yourself. Have you a house ? help him to
                            a shelter. Do not make use of his poverty to make a wagesslave of him ; nor of his
                            necessities to tax him with interest for money lent, but rather let his deeds stir up your
                            benevolence. Have we not at the North something akin to " the sum of all villainies ? " To
                            make a, man a commodity is that sum ! Have we made use of the public lands that men should
                            not be so ? and thereby given peace and joy to the millions and stability to the republic ?
                            Again, has legislative power been uniformly rendered in this direction ? or has not the
                            contrary been the more common result ? Instead of to every man his portion, have not these
                            lands gone largely to fill the maws of individuals and corporate greed ? Do not the landless
                            to-day crowd the labor market, and in the midst of an overflow of food and clothing suffer
                            penury ? The more prosperity the slave of the South created, the more he was worth as a
                            commodity. Not so the wages-slave at the North; the more he gluts the market with goods and
                            the labor market with his person, the less he is worth f Why should a man, my equal,' work
                            for me and not for himself ? Why should I be able to enter the labor market and take my
                            choice of a thousand men, and from each, gain twenty-five cents per day — two hun- dred and
                            fifty dollars — while my thousand neighbors get but one dollar and a quarter t Not satisfied
                            with two hundred and fifty dollars a day, I increase my works and my income ; live like a
                            prince ; have pleasant surroundings and all the appliances of taste, art, means, and
                            opportunities of culture j while my thousand neighbors have not! Also, having means, power,
                            and the disposition to corrupt, I turn the current of legislation in the direction of my
                            individual or corporate interests. Why should I or others be able to monopolize any of the
                            necessaries of life, and change their value to suit our interests, causing even the needy to
                            pay tribute to us ? Why should bond and mortgage holders and money-lenders eat bread without
                            labor ? Suppose one-third of the population were such, would not the twothirds have to
                            support themselves and families, and the others also ?<pb n="55" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. ao The morality of Jewish legislation of more than three thousand years ago was :
                            "If thy brother be fallen into, r'ecay with thee, then ye shall relieve him ; yea, though he
                            be a stranger or a sojourner — a trampthat he may live with thee. Thou shalt not give him
                            thy money upon usury, nor thy victuals for increase; but Fear thy God, that thy brother may
                            live with thee." Lev. 25.35. The morality of Jesus was: "lend, hoping for nothing again."
                            How shall the morality of our day be designated ? There are three kinds : The first is
                            loving the neighbor as you do self. The second, loving others at the expense of self. The
                            third, loving self at the expense of the neighbor. The first is the morality of just men ;
                            the second, of God-like men ; the third, of Satanic men. Is not the main current of the
                            morality of these times of the latter stamp? Is not the prominent feature of our
                            civilization to grab and get from the neighbor — to get something for nothing ? To have
                            wagesslaves work for us, do our drudgery, fight battles, and pay the expenses of wicked
                            wars? This manner of going with a few charitable, beggarly institutions, some sporadic acts
                            of individual beneficence, some scientific progress, considerable theology and literature ;
                            many criminals, and a hunt after the North Pole seems about the sum total of modern
                            civilization. Young men and women of all the States, may I ask you to labor for a spirit of
                            inspiration, to live out and bring to the front a higher social life ? Without inspiration,
                            no important work can be begun. To be inspired to fulfill the desires of our lower
                            selfhoods, is animal; but to be inspired to do good to others, is divine inspiration. With
                            this, it is for you to inaugurate a higher civilization. To establish a foundation, on which
                            the hopes of millions, and the high ideals of what society ought to be may be realized. No
                            doubt the lower instincts and interests of many will stand in the way; but there is no need
                            of violence, no need of a war of classes; work cordially with all. Let your aim be, the
                            elevation of humanity. Take command of public sentiment, and, National and State legislation
                            through the ballot, and cause its current to run in the channel of justice and beneficence.
                            A just apportionment of land, limited in amount, is the first necessity. Not only should
                            there be free access to land, but we should care for one another in this .thing ; have an
                            anxiety that all be provided for. The second is, that the portion allotted shall be an
                            inalienable homestead ; not subject to debt, sale, nor mortgage, etc., but may be exchanged.
                            The natural wants of men are alike. To deprive any person of the means to supply them, is
                            treason ; causing a man " To beg a fellow worm To give him leave to toil." A. community
                            having land and other property in common fulfills the symbol; no member with us being left
                            uncared for; while the laboring populations of Christendom are cut off from the land, and
                            form the accumulated property they have created. Having called upon the youth of these
                            States to labor for a spirit of inspiration, to live out and inaugurate a higher social life
                            than now prevails with them, I turn to you, young brethren and sisters in Shakerdom—to those
                            in whom truth becomes goodness—to labor also for a spirit of inspiration—a baptismal
                            earnestness, so that you can bear down oh your individual, animal self-hoods. From the lower
                            emotions of human self-hoods flow the awful manifestations of evil as above shadowed forth.
                            We inherit the good fruits of those who have gone before us, who conquered, and in purity
                            lived as angels do, and brought forth a form of social life as angels have. The time has
                            fully come to move forward to make a new growth; the fathers and mothers of our Order, in
                            bearing a full cross against the lusts of generation, have freed us from the moral maladies
                            of the world. Instead of being " commodities," or exposed to be so, we are, to-day, of more
                            value to one another than fine gold. The time has now come to bear down on another
                            department of animal emotions—the lusts of eating ; in yielding obedience to the
                            commandments of God—to hygienic law, according to if needs be create it. Take command of |
                            the order of a virgin life, which involves no<pb n="56" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 56 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO.
                            cruelty to animals, " our bread and our water will be blest, and sickness be taken away."
                            The fruit of this new growth will gladden every heart; and those without, whom the Father is
                            raising up to keep his " command- ments," will turn to you with : " Your God shall be my
                            God, and your people mine." Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What shall I do to be a shaker?" TEIform="index"/>WHAT SHALL I DO TO BE A SHAKER?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cumings, Henry" TEIform="persName"/>HENRY CUMINGS</byline><p TEIform="p">This question has been asked and answered so many times, that another attempt to answer it
                            might seem quite superfluous, except for its constant recurrence, and the demand for an
                            answer which we so often meet. On our part, the question naturally arises : What-induces you
                            to try to be a Shaker? The reason assigned will vary somewhat according to the circumstances
                            of the candidate for admission, as will be seen by the following answers, which are actual
                            experiences, drawn from real life: Answer 1st. " Times are hard, business dull; I cannot get
                            work that pays, and thought I might as well join the Shakers." Answer 2d. " Having lost my
                            wife, and being left with three or four small children and no home in which to give them
                            proper care, I thought it would be a good plan to come to the Shakers, as this would give me
                            and my children a comfortable home." Answer 3d. " My health is not very good ; I am not
                            sick, but I am not strong and rugged ; I had heard that the Shakers were a good kind people,
                            and as I am getting along in years, losing somewhat the relish for worldly pleas- ures and
                            pursuits, and withal, growing tired of the cares and burdens of life, I have come to you to
                            spend the rest of my days." Answer 4th. " I had acquired a good property, but the crisis
                            came, and I indorsed notes for my brotherin-law, and he failed, and ruined me ; I have lost
                            all hope, courage and ambition to try to be any thing in the world, and have come to the
                            Shakers." Answer 5th. " I have met with a severe disappointment in an affair of the heart,
                            and I do not care whether I live or die ; the world is utterly selfish and terribly
                            deceitful, and I wish to get, as it were, out of the world, and have come to you." Answer
                            6th. " I have lived fast, and my appetites and passions have acquired that power over me,
                            that notwithstanding the many resolves which I have made to do better, I find myself unable
                            to correct the evil, habits of the past, especially as I am constantly meeting my former
                            associates and companions ; I have heard that, the Shakers are very temperate, and I have
                            come to you for protection from evil influences and temptations. Can you, and will you aid
                            me?" Answer 7th. "I have been deceived by one whom 1 thought a friend ; am in great trouble,
                            and wish to hide my sin and shame." Answer 8th. " My husband has deserted me, leaving
                            dependent on my care, three small children, one a babe; I cannot support them myself, and
                            heard that the Shakers were always glad to take children to educate, with a view to their
                            becoming members of their Society ; I have come to you for help." Answer 9th. '' I am a
                            spiritualist ; have heard that the Shakers believed in spiritualism, and have had mani-
                            festations among them ; I have come, wishing to share in the good, harmonious influences
                            which prevail with you, thereby avoiding the low, inharmonious, undeveloped conditions that
                            I'find in the world; seeking to get good, and to do good by my association with you, by
                            bringing the gifts which I claim to possess, to you." Answer 10th. " I have come to you for
                            salvation from sin; I have sought elsewhere, and do not find the power that can save me from
                            the sins of a worldly, selfish, carnal life ; can you show me the way of salvation, and help
                            me to walk in it ? What shall 1 do to be saved ? " As we proceed to answer each of these
                            applicants, perhaps the whole may furnish an answer to the question. " What shall 1 do to be
                            a Shaker? " To Answers 1, 2, 3 and 4, we should say, That as our Societies are not simply
                            Charitable Institutions for the relief of the needy, or asylums for those in trouble, their
                            primary object and purpose being to build up a spiritual life and character, we do not wish
                            to fill our families with persons who will be member?<pb n="57" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. 57 only in name, and not really in sympathy with the spirit of the Institution ;
                            yet. we are willing to give any candid inquirer a chance to know for themselves of the prin-
                            ciples and orders of the Institution. From those thus admitted on trial, we expect a
                            compliance with, and conformity to, the orders and rules necessary for the maintenance of
                            the principles upon which the Institution is based. " Oh, yes," says the candidate, " we
                            admire your order and neatness, and think we shall be able to meet al] your requirements ;
                            but what are the main principles holding you together as a society? " Certainly, we would
                            endeavor to state briefly the principles by which we aim to live. First, Community of
                            Property; no mine nor thine exclusively, but all living and sharing together, according to
                            their needs. All are required to give time and service in some useful hand labor, and you
                            must not be too particular as to what manner of employment you engage in, as our quiet
                            country homes do not furnish a great variety of pursuits. We have no lawyers, nor doctors,
                            nor ministers, nor clerks, on big salaries ; in fact none of the ornamental professions, in
                            which so many try to find a place of big pay, and little work. "Certainly, only tell me what
                            to do, and how, and I will do what I can. I suppose you do not make very long days for work;
                            I have been used to regular habits in this respect, making it a rule to begin as late in the
                            morning, and quit as early at night as I could, and not lose my place, or get my pay
                            docked." We expect all to be industrious, improving the time to the best advantage, to do
                            all the good they can. Instead of every one for himself, it is each for all, and all for
                            each. Another, and very important principle is the honest confession of all known sin to
                            God, before Elders or ministers, appointed as His witnesses. "Well, I had not thought much
                            of that, and it sounds very much like the Catholic practice, but I am willing to do even
                            that. I don't suppose you require one to go much into particulars ; modesty would forbid
                            that; but I am very willing to confess that 1 have been a sinner." Another very important
                            point is the virgin life principle; purity and chastity in all things ; in thought, word and
                            deed. "Ah, yes, that we admire." Another principle is Peace. Our Saviour's mission was
                            heralded as the reign of peace on earth, and good will to man ; therefore, as Christians,
                            seeking to follow Christ, we should forego all worldly strife, and aim to live peaceably
                            with all " Yes, certainly, I am for peace ; if others treat me well and mind their own
                            business, I will do the same ; but if they don't, why I am able to take care and defend
                            myself." Thus it usually is with this class of applicants. Being without any fixed religious
                            principles or convictions, they will profess a willingness to accept all that may be
                            presented to them, in theory, that their earthly wants may thus be met, and when such are
                            admitted among us on trial, both they and we find that they are not quite so ready to accept
                            the principles of a Shaker life, practically, as they thought. The idea of living
                            unselfishly for the good of others is entirely beyond their comprehension ; and they are
                            generally selfish, exacting, disagreeable, and quarrelsome members, till they conclude to
                            withdraw, or until they become unbearable and are dismissed. To answers 5 and 6, most of the
                            foregoing will apply. Occasionally one of these has been humbled enough to be glad to know
                            of a better way, and by giving themselves to learn, finally gain a spirit of real, true
                            conviction. Such may succeed, and become good, substantial members of Society, as perhaps
                            they only needed a kind word and helping hand, to aid them in their resolution, to turn away
                            from evil courses. To answers 7 and 8, we should say, that our Societies are not to be
                            regarded as Magdalen Asylums, or Orphans' Homes, and unless there is evidence to convince us
                            that something more than home and shelter are wanted, we should kindly refer such ap-
                            plicants to institutions providing for such cases. To answer 9, we would say : We do believe
                            in modern spiritualism as a science. We know there is much truth in its teachings,
                            notwithstanding much that is false and erroneous has found a sanction under its name. We
                            have had large experience in dealing with spiritual manifestations, and have learned to be
                            cautious as to what we accept and sanction. Because a statement or proposition claims, to be
                            a manifestation<pb n="58" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 58 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. from the other world, reasons
                            not to us that we should accept it as true, nor that we should even tolerate it, if
                            otherwise objectionable. And in a Shaker family, where there is a larger and closer
                            association of individuals than in ordinary life, these gifts and manifestations mast be
                            subject to the advice and counsel of the leading authority of the Society, or you would have
                            small reason to seek among us the harmonious conditions you so much desire to enjoy. To an
                            applicant like No. 10 we say ; Come, and try this way for yourself. We will teach you the
                            principles, which, if adopted and Jived, will yield salvation from sin. We will give you all
                            the aid in our power, both by precept and example, in your efforts to turn from the evils of
                            a sinful, worldly life. This is really the spirit and intent of our institutions ; to aid
                            those who are conscious of the need of a purer and better life; those who are seeking a
                            power and strength to aid them in their struggles against the selfishness and worldliness of
                            their own lives. For this the worthy founders of our Societies toiled, giving themselves and
                            all they possessed in the spirit of consecration, to establish these earthly homes, where,
                            by the power and strength of association, it is possible to attain to that victory over sin,
                            which a life of true self-denial will bring to every one. You ask; " What shall I do to be
                            saved ? " We answer, Honestly confess your sins; settle all honest debts ; make restitution
                            if you have wronged any one; strive to live peaceably with all ; be pure, in deed, word and
                            thought, and finally consecrate your life, in all sincerity, to live un- selfishly for the
                            good of those around you. This we know to be a work of growth, but by constant and
                            persistent efforts to live by the principles of truth and goodness in all things, you will
                            come to realize what you are now seeking to find, salvation from sin. Thus will your life be
                            of use, and you will have reason to feel in the language of another, " I am not ashamed of
                            the gospel of Christ, for I know it is the power of God unto salvation." This being fully
                            attained, will bring you to realize the ideal of a true Shaker life — the kingdom of heaven
                            HEBE ON EARTH. Enfield, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lex talionis" TEIform="index"/>LEX TALIONIS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prentiss, Oliver" TEIform="persName"/>OLIVER PRENTISS</byline><p TEIform="p">The Lex Talionis of Moses : " Eye for eye, tooth for tooth," etc. Exodus 21, 24, and
                            Leviticus 24: 20. Of Solomon: "Heap coals of fire on his head." Proverbs 25: 21, 22. Of
                            Jesus : "Turn the other cheek." Matthew 5: 39, and Luke 6: 29. Some difference in the codes,
                            corresponding with difference in material of which human society has been, is and is to be
                            constructed. The Code Moses was for raw material, preliminary to the formation of a social
                            structure. The Code Solomon came when that social structure was at its zenith, its
                            culminating point. The Code Jesus was, and to some extent still is, prophetic—prophetic of
                            Community, wherein all passions and appetites are held in strict subordination to our
                            highest perceptions of the purity of the Angels of God, in the more advanced Heavens. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beds" TEIform="index"/>BEDS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p">Is it not a significant fact that one of the lowest in the animal kingdom has this one good
                            trait. When rising in the morning its first act is to stir up and ventilate, as best it
                            knows how, the bed upon which it reposed ? Is it gratitude for the night's lodging,
                            scientifically expressed, to thus commence the new-born day by observing one of nature's
                            laws, promotive of life and health ?<pb n="59" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 59 Go to the
                            Ant thou sluggard, to learn activity; go to the Stork to learn lilial affections; to the
                            Bee, and be industrious; observe the Swine, and leave not in the morning thy couchuntil, as
                            some of our societies now practice, you have hung up all the bed-clothes and some of the
                            bedding. So shall ye leave the imperfect behind and press on to sanitary perfection. So long
                            as necessity compels to combine the sitting-room and bed-room in one, let the rights of each
                            be regarded. In the forenoon, be it a ventilating bed-room ; in the afternoon, let it be a
                            retiring room. Is a whitewashed sepulcher any more objectionable than a nice-looking
                            sitting-room, made out of an unventilated bed-room ? In every good word and work, the
                            righteousness of Christians should exceed that of the outside world. The preacher's lips
                            should reveal the knowledge that forestalls sickness and premature death, as the result of
                            physical unrighteousness.</p></div2><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ann Lee: her work, her people, and their critics, eleventh paper" TEIform="index"/> [See
                            January Number for Tenth Paper.] ANN LEE. HER WORK, HER PEOPLE, AND THEIR CRITICS. Eleventh
                            Paper</head><p TEIform="p">James Whittaker was born February 28, 1751, in Oldham, England. His mother's maiden name was
                            Ann Lee. Both the parents of James were converts to the teachings of James and Jane Wardley,
                            and by his early accompanying them to their meetings, he grew up in the faith they taught,
                            and became the most valued coadjutor of Mother Ann, in all her labors in the establishment
                            of her faith in England and America. With a most loving, lovable and sympathetic
                            disposition, he entered readily into all the physical sufferings of the founders, bearing
                            his full share, while none knew of more exceedingly spiritual exaltations in seasons of
                            gospel refreshment. Whether we shall attribute the fact to the deep good sense of his
                            progenitors, or credit him with herculean self-government, he was, nevertheless, one of the
                            most pure-minded men that has ever walked the earth! His freedom from even immodest
                            expressions evidenced to his associates that his heart was very pure, while all through the
                            years of his martyrdom for the cause, we have no inkling that he ever vented a retaliatory
                            feeling. When he was whipped in the vicinity of Harvard and Shirley, Mass., until his back
                            was jellied, and his tattered shirt so mingled with the coagulations of flesh and blood as
                            to be with difficulty separated he repeated the prayer of Jesus on Calvary for his enemies:
                            " Father, forgive them, for they know not what they do ! " We are not over-much given to
                            superstition, but we do not wonder that the apple-tree to which he was tied while being
                            lashed, though then in a flourishing condition, soon after dwindled and died, while its dead
                            trunk stood for years as a memento both of Puritan perse- cution and Shaker martyrdom. He
                            was early titled one of the fathers of the Church, and well worthy did he wear the title. He
                            was gifted with great eloquence in speech, and would hold immense congregations spell-bound
                            for an hour by the delivery of the testimony¦—a testimony, too, that was in no respect, save
                            in chaste ness of language, calculated to please the worldly bearings or hearing of his
                            auditors. He was, like Father William, clairvoyant seeing visions of unusual splendor, and
                            so in sympathy with the heavens as to be the mediator of the most angelic impressions to
                            those with whom he associated. In ministrations of comfort and cheer to the afflicted, he
                            had no equal in mildness and philanthropy. In the annunciation of the unpalatable truths of
                            the gospel, none were more undaunted, firm, nor inflexible in the duty Many anecdotes are
                            told of his wisdom, as exercised under trying circumstances, and these invariably mark him
                            as an extraordinary man. He was also very wise as a counselor, as we will show, in the
                            future, by quotations from his preserved admonitions and encouraging counsels. He sue-<pb n="60" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 60 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. ceeded Mother Ann in the leadership of the
                            people, and had to meet with and reconcile the sorrows,unreconciliations and discouragements
                            of the people, many of whom, having clung to her personality instead of her principles, felt
                            the sufferings of an irreparable loss in her death.Father James was very successful in his
                            leadership, but so great sufferings had he endured that he showed early signs of a general
                            collapse of his physical powers. He resigned his position, selecting as his successor,
                            Joseph Meacham, a convert from the Baptist ministry, which choice proved in every way a most
                            wise one. After his resignation he retired from Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., and went to Enfield, now
                            Shaker Station, Conn., where in a few months he died, full of sufferings in body, but in a
                            most beautiful serenity of mind. He died July 20, 1787, less than 37 years of age ! But his
                            name lingers in the hearts of our people as a reminder of one who was a synonym of purity,
                            peace, earnest, zealous and uncom- promising for the right. </p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Eternity of shaker principles" TEIform="index"/>THE ETERNITY OF SHAKER PRINCIPLES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">There always has been a firm belief, and there still exists a dominant feeling on the
                                part of the people called Shakers, that their system of life, and its introduction to
                                the world first, by Jesus, the Christ, and the members of the Pentecostal Church; and
                                secondly, through the mediumship of Ann Lee, were the direct conceptions and
                                elaborations of a Merciful, xllmighty God. That Shaker principles will remain intact, in
                                perpetuity, there are thousands of earnest believers, with almost as many vigorous and
                                determined wills, that they shall be so, as far as human, personal efforts can aid, and
                                decide for the cause. It is our firm belief that God having builded,the " kingdom is
                                established that shall never be destroyed," and that this kingdom is the Cause of
                                Christ, as represented by fundamental, Shaker principles. That these principles are, and
                                may become insufficiently operative among their professed Believers, to fully display to
                                the world the perfect fruits of the Christ life and of heavenly communism, may be true.
                                That the system may seem to suffer, as judged by human wisdom, through the defections of
                                trusted agents, by an unprincipled misuse of confidence and power, also may be true.
                                Depletions may ensue, caused by the indifference or inaction of the general household,
                                for want of that preservative element, the life-blood of the unselfish Christ. Apathy
                                may lay hard hold on the people, and a lukewarmness, worthy only to be "speivedout" find
                                a too general representation among our people; but there stand the irrevocable and
                                immovable principles, which shall eternally find representatives with more or less
                                emphatical zeal. We never yet anticipated that our system of life would become
                                universally popular and acceptable in this world; nor be espoused by even a majority;
                                but rather have ever presented that but " a few among many " would find it convenient or
                                conscientiously necessary to live a Shaker life. We are, nevertheless, positive in the
                                belief and teaching, that genuine Shaker life is the best preparation for the life to
                                come; and is withal, very endurable, and comfortable in this tvorld, to the faithful
                                Believer. All who live on the earth are but a small handful to those who have passed "
                                over the river of death;" and accepting the orthodox gditaiat<pb n="61" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                                SHAKER MANIFESTO. 61 view of popular churches, concerning post-mortem conditions, as
                                correct, there are billions more Shakers there, than Shakerism has opponents or
                                indifferent admirers here. For those who already in this life become ripe for the
                                harvest of which Christ's life was, and is, the husbandman; for these who, sick of both
                                the good and bad of a worldly life, and ardently anxious to live a new life, be reaped
                                from the earth and born anew — Shakerism offers not only a merciful asylum, but a
                                boundless aid to the successful accomplishment of a new creation. Our Virgin Celibacy —
                                rejected by the masses, and spurned by the majority now —will be a very respectable and
                                desirable condition, by all who will be privileged to walk the streets of the New
                                Jerusalem. These will be "they who have come up out of great tribulation; " are not
                                defiled with human lusts; having " washed their robes " making them clean, by living the
                                life of Christ, which is the blood of the Lamb." In this virgin respect, all who march
                                those " golden streets " will be Shakers, made so here, or hereafter. Our Communal
                                Interests are only fruits of a Christian, virgin celibacy; selfishness in lesser things
                                finds its death-blow by "laying the axe at the root" of human, selfish depravity. Not
                                one supposes that in the heavenly relations of individuals, here nor hereafter, the
                                selfishness of the individual will prevail, but a glorious consummation of the contrary.
                                Again, in heaven there will be a spiritual community of sons and daughters of God, and
                                will this not resemble genuine Shakerism ? And is it not best to go into training here
                                for an eligibility to the mansions of those peculiarly blest ? " Peace on earth, and
                                good will " are the constituents of another fundamental, Shaker principle ; and this is
                                as eternal as God. Only those calloused by long-continued, worldly lusts, refuse to
                                believe that war and dissensions are ungodly, unmanly, inhuman ; and that these are
                                unheavenly practices, which will some day be eliminated from God's creature, man, and he
                                will love peace in heaven. Separation prom the world, its good and its bad, is
                                emblematical of the eternal heavens. Where there is neither rust nor thief, there will
                                be a treasure so separate from the world, that as it never gave it, so will it also be
                                unable to take it away. Let there be no despairing; the principles of Shakerism are
                                eternal, and so surely as they are in exercise by the assembly of the heavens, just as
                                assuredly will there be a reflection of that heavenly life on earth, while God exists,
                                be it called Shakerism, or by some other name.</p></div3><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>NOTES</head><div4 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our number for March" TEIform="index"/>OUR NUMBER FOR MARCH</head><p TEIform="p">We feel warranted in saying that the present number of The Manifesto will be found an
                                    interesting and valuable one. We think this, because several of the papers contained
                                    herein, treat upon subjects which many are very desirous of knowing concerning us.
                                    The articles of " Party," and " Principles," treat very lucidly of our ideas upon
                                    those subjects. " What shall I do to be a Shaker ? " gives interesting features of a
                                    certain class of correspondence very frequently met with. Daniel Fraser's article is
                                    a(revolutionary one ; but is nevertheless a peaceful solution of many knotty,
                                    socialistic problems. " Children among the Shakers "<pb n="62" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 62 THE
                                    SHAKER MANIFESTO. ought to have been known of long ago ; so, also, with the
                                    important subject of "Beds." " Omnipresence " gives a grand hope of God in this
                                    world ; while " Interior Life " gives assurance, in most excellent language, that
                                    there is no death. "Lex Talionis," while characteristic of the writer, is
                                    practically true of human progress from brute force to angel dealings. Our long
                                    quotation upon " War or Arbitration ? " will be gratifying, and meet an urgent
                                    demand of our honored publisher, who has feared we were not doing our whole duty on
                                    this subject. The children will find in their " Grotto " a kindly feeding of lambs
                                    by their dear friend, Amelia J. Calver; while every one will rejoice in " The New
                                    Song." We hope with this goodly array of food, contributors will bear with us, in
                                    our crowded condition. Articles will appear from other pens as soon as con-
                                sistent.</p></div4><div4 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christ's second coming" TEIform="index"/>Christ's Second Coming</head><p TEIform="p">There appeared, recently, in the Sedalia (Mo.) Bazoo, a long article upon this
                                    subject, written by a lady named Clark, and which is, undoubtedly, a review of Elder
                                    Eads' " Types of Christ." It is an excellent paper, filled with the most advanced
                                    views upon the subject, and a very favorable, yet critical, indorsement of Shaker
                                    views as put forth in Elder Eads' pamphlet. It would occupy several pages of The
                                    Manifesto, or we would reproduce it; but do not feel warranted in so doing while so
                                    much matter crowds our " pigeon holes." </p></div4><div4 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Celibacy, chastity, sacraments" TEIform="index"/>Celibacy—Chastity—Sacraments</head><p TEIform="p">It should be known, that Shaker principles demand of their adherents, not only a
                                    virgin celibacy in life, but a chastity of thought and behavior, that makes rigid
                                    watchfulness and self-denial ever active among them. No half-way working—living in
                                    alternate purity and corruption—will ever answer, and who should attempt so to live,
                                    would be in hell among the Shakers. The chastest virgin celibacy is our first
                                    sacrament —no dabbling with the flesh. "Entire consecration of self,'' in communal
                                    relations, is another sacrament. Peace, with all the additions which that word
                                    means, and whatever eradication is necessary thereunto, is another. flighting of our
                                    wrongs, and living as brethren and sisters in Christ should live, separate from the
                                    world, rounds up the sum of our faith. Amid this public confession of faith, we
                                    would ask of our Roman Catholic priesthood, who are sworn to celibacy, whether they
                                    are also sworn to virgin chastity ?</p></div4><div4 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Accommodation of $10,000,000" TEIform="index"/>Accommodation of $10,000,000</head><p TEIform="p">Secretary of the Treasury, Sherman, has concluded to issue ten millions of fractional
                                    currency for the convenience of those needing fractions of a dollar to send by mail,
                                    and for change. We congratulate ourselves somewhat upon having our wishes, as
                                    expressed in February No., complied with so readily.</p></div4><div4 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God help the Indian" TEIform="index"/>God help the Indian</head><p TEIform="p">We feel an assurgiice, that in so flagrant a proposition, as that to transfer " Poor
                                    Lo " and Indian Bureau, to the untender mercies of the War Department, there will be
                                    a godly interposition and interference. Bad as the Indians are used by dishonest
                                    subordinates of the Interior, they would fare worse under Gen. Sherman's rule. In
                                    lieu of such a change, we offer an amendment to the Constitution, to abolish the War
                                    Department, and substitute a Bureau of Arbitration, to be presided over by an
                                    unwarlike individual as Secretary. And it will come to this yet. We hope, at least,
                                    the Cheyenne massacre will prove a blessing in disguise for the Indian.</p></div4><div4 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Trampism" TEIform="index"/>Trampism</head><p TEIform="p">—The legislation of New Hampshire has practically abolished "the tramp " from that
                                    State. Amid the terrors now so prevalent in this and other States, accumulated and
                                    accumulating by these pestiferous walkers, wise and determined legislation must be
                                    enacted, that life and property be made secure. We opine New Hampshire laws are not
                                    sufficiently merciful to the tramp; but these are infinitely better than lawless
                                    trampism, with the nightly dread of robbery, arson and assassination. </p></div4><div4 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="War or arbitration?" TEIform="index"/>WAR OR ARBITRATION?</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">It should be particularly remembered that recent wars prove the fallacy
                                            of the com- mon argument that large standing armies<pb n="63" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                                            SHAKER MANIFESTO. 63 are necessary to preserve the peace of the world.
                                            Throughout the past quarter of a century, gigantic standing armies have been
                                            maintained, and how far they have been effectual to preserve peace is
                                            indicated by the following summary of losses from war in 25 years (1853-78)
                                            :— Killed in battle, or died of wounds and disease. Crimean
                                            War............... 750,000 Italian War, 1850........... 45,000 War of
                                            Schleswig-Holstein.. 3,000 American Civil War—North, 280,000 « —South,
                                            520,000 War between Prussia, Austria and Italy in 18(36.......... 45,000
                                            Expeditions to Mexico, Cochin China, Morocco, Paraguay,
                                            etc....................... 65,000 Franco-German War of 1870 and 1871—
                                            France................. 155,000 Germany................ 60,000 Turkish
                                            Massacres of Christians in Bulgaria, Armenia, etc., 1876-77..............
                                            25,000 Russian and Turkish War of 1877..................... 600,000
                                            Total............... 2,548,000 These tables are carefully compiled from the
                                            official statistics of the various nations concerned, «,nd include, in
                                            addition to the troops slain, a portion of the deaths occasioned by the
                                            ravages of the wars amongst the civil population. If the execution of two or
                                            three criminals justly excites horror, what should be the feeling produced
                                            by the contemplation of such an awful sacrifice of human life in millions
                                            upon millions, and often amid circumstances of unimaginable horror! Dr.
                                            Russell, the Times' correspondent, wrote from the battle-field of Sedan : "
                                            Let your readers fancy masses of colored rags glued together with blood and
                                            brains, and pinned into strange shapes by fragments of bones. Let them
                                            conceive men's bodies without heads, legs without bodies, heaps of human
                                            entrails attached to red and blue cloth, and disembowelled corpses in uni-
                                            form, bodies lying about in all attitudes with skulls shattered, faces blown
                                            off, hips smashed, bones, flesh, with gay clothing all pounded together as
                                            if brayed in a mortar, extending for miles, not very thick in any one place,
                                            but recurring perpetually for weary hours, and then they cannot, with the
                                            most vivid imagination, come up to the sickening reality of that butchery.
                                            No nightmare could be so frightful! " Charles Dickens, in All The Year
                                            lloiind, says : " We talk exultingly and with a certain fire of ' a
                                            magnificent charge !' of ' a splendid charge ! ' yet very few will think of
                                            the hideous particulars these two airy words stand for. The ' splendid
                                            charge ' is a headlong rush of men on strong horses, urged to their fullest
                                            speed, riding down and overwhelming an opposing mass of men on foot. The
                                            reader's mind goes no further ; being content with the information that the
                                            enemy's line was ' broken' and 'gave way.' It does not fill in the picture.
                                            When the ' splendid charge ' has done its work and passed by, there will be
                                            found a sight very much like the scene of a frightful railway accident.
                                            There will be the full complement of backs broken in two; of arms twisted
                                            wholly off; of men impaled upon their own bayonets; of legs smashed up like
                                            bits of firewood; of heads sliced open like apples; of other heads crunched
                                            into soft jelly by iron hoofs of horses ; of faces trampled out of all
                                            likeness to any thing human. This is what skulks behind a ' splendid
                                            charge!' This is what follows, as a matter of course, when 'our fellows rode
                                            at them in style' and ' cut them up famously.' " The Daily News' special
                                            correspondent writes: " The number of children killed in these massacres is
                                            something enormous. They were often spitted on bayonets, and we have several
                                            stories from eye-witnesses who saw little babes carried about the streets,
                                            both here and at Olluk-kui, on the points of bayonets. Before many of the
                                            doorways women were walking up and down wailing their funeral chant. One of
                                            them caught me by the arm and led me inside of the walls, and there in one
                                            corner, half-covered with stones and mortar, were the remains of another
                                            young girl, with her<pb n="64" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 64 THE SHAKEK MANIFESTO. long hair
                                            flowing wildly about among the stones and dust. And the mother fairly
                                            shrieked with agony, and beat her head madly against the wall. I could only
                                            turn round and walk out, sick at heart, leaving her alone with her skeleton.
                                            A few steps further on sat a woman on a doorstep, rocking herself to and
                                            fro, and uttering moans heartrending beyond any thing I could have imagined.
                                            Her head was buried in her hands, while her fingers were unconsciously
                                            twisting and tearing her hair as she gazed into her lap, where lay three
                                            little skulls with the hair still clinging to them." The following is a
                                            tabular statement of the cost of recent wars :— Crimean War...........
                                            £340,000,000 Italian War of 1859..... 60,000,000 American Civil War— The
                                            North.......... 940,000,000 The South.......... 460,000,000
                                            Schleswig-Holstein War. 7,000,000 Austrian and Prussian War,
                                            1866............ 66,000,000 Expeditions to Mexico, Morocco, Paraguay, etc.
                                            (say only)............. 40,000,000 Franco-Prussian War___ 500,000,000
                                            Eussian and Turkish War, 1877.................. 250,000,000
                                            Total...........£2,663,000,000 This would allow £2 10s. for every man, woman
                                            and child on the habitable globe. It would afford a present of £110 to every
                                            person in England and Wales. It would erect and furnish 2250 such
                                            institutions as the beautiful Crystal Palace near London. It would make two
                                            railways all round the world at more than £50,000 per mile each. It would
                                            thickly dot colleges, schools, and hospitals over all Europe. It would
                                            provide for every adult male in Europe (about 50 millions) a freehold farm
                                            of 120 acres in the United States of America. A northern manufacturer
                                            remarks that in Great Britain, even in time of peace,'' the actual workers
                                            of the kingdom work every day of the year to pay the interest of the
                                            National Debt twenty-six minutes ; for the maintenance of our armaments,
                                            twentyeight minutes a day ; for the cost of collect- ing the taxes, five
                                            minutes a day; for the relief of the poor, nine minutes a day ; for local
                                            taxes, nine minutes a day ; for the cost of civil government, twelve minutes
                                            a day. Is not a diminution of these terrible evils practicable ? Is there no
                                            way of checking this suicidal insanity on the part of the nations, or of the
                                            governments ? Cannot the human reason be brought to bear on this system of
                                            mutual ruin ? Yes, we think it can. 1. Let there be established a
                                            permanentlyorganized system of international arbitration, by which disputes
                                            arising between nations may be settled without appealing to arms. 2. A
                                            permanent high court of nations should be constituted as an advisory
                                            tribunal for Christendom. 3. Let the Great Powers come to an agreement for a
                                            mutual and simultaneous reduction of armaments. These, so far from being the
                                            dreams of utopian and impracticable men, have been approved and recommended
                                            by many of the foremost statesmen of the world. The force of its decisions
                                            would be mainly or wholly that of moral power. It is not to be assumed that
                                            this power would absolutely render wars impossible, or succeed in
                                            reconciling all cases of international dispute. But it would go very far in
                                            that direction. It would be an infinite gain over the existing system of
                                            brute force. In 1861 the Federal Government, acting oh a sudden impulse,
                                            transgressed the law of nations by forcibly taking the two Confederate
                                            Ambassadors, Messrs. Slidell and Mason, from a British mail-steamer—the
                                            Trent. Almost immediately and spontaneously the chief courts of Europe
                                            communicated to the Washington Government their verdict that this act was
                                            contrary to international equity. And this simple " collective opinion,"
                                            definitely and unitedly expressed, greatly influenced the Federal
                                            authorities in arriving at their conclusion to surrender the two captives.
                                            In like manner, it may be confidently expected, a systematic utterance of
                                            the-) col- lective opinion of the family of nations, or<pb n="65" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/>
                                            THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 65 of the chief of them, especially when given forth
                                            by a representative body of their best jurists or most intelligent men,
                                            would largely restrain war.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="National Secular Almanack" TEIform="index"/>—National Secular
                                        Almanack.</bibl></cit></p></div4></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Children among the shakers" TEIform="index"/>CHILDREN AMONG THE SHAKERS</head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, February 4, 1879" TEIform="index"/>New York, Feb. 4, 1879. </dateline><p TEIform="p">Elder Frederick W. Evans : Your letter received. Grlad to hear you are all well. I do not
                                like the letters that my boy writes. He does not understand what he is writing about. He
                                writes what you dictate. You have no right to influence those boys in trying to make
                                Shakers and Spiritualists of them, nor give them the im- pression that they ought to
                                spend their lives with you. You are not acting the part of a friend to me when you do
                                these thing's. The Bible says, " Thou shalt not covet thy neighbor's son, nor his
                                daughter, nor any thing that is his." These boys are only loaned to you for a time, and
                                while with you I want them to be respectful, obedient and industrious. I want the boys
                                to come out into the world, when of age, and have a chance to judge for themselves
                                whether they want to be Shakers or not. Do you think for one single moment, Elder
                                Frederick, that after I have suffered almost death to bring those children into the
                                world, I will look on quietly and see you take possession of them, body and soul ? No !
                                Why, they are my own life. You talk about love. What can you possibly know about love?
                                There is no one on the face of this earth knows the meaning of that word but a parent. I
                                do not believe in Spiritualism, nor Shakerism. You should all marry and have lots of
                                children. I hope you will not be offended at what I say. I would not be disrespectful to
                                you for the world. I only want you to know what I think. Respectfully yours,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="G., L." TEIform="persName"/>L-----G-----</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Esteemed Friend : Your letter of 4th is received..." TEIform="index"/>Esteemed Friend : Your letter of 4th is received...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Mount Lebanon, February 10, 1879" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, Feb. 10, 1879</dateline><p TEIform="p">Esteemed Friend : Your letter of 4th is received. It is a declaration of war. You want to
                                eat your cake and give it away too. Can you do it ? What are you thinking about ? I was
                                as plain with you and your husband as I know how to be, when I took the boys. All our
                                publications are plain as they can be on the subject of children, the terms, etc. So
                                also is the indenture. If we would take children merely to board and school them at a
                                stipulated price, we could have any number that we could take care of. We do no such
                                thing. Our leading motive is to make Christians of all whom we take into the Society. We
                                act as servants of God and humanity in this respect— conscientiously, religiously. You
                                knew that, when you proposed for us to take your sons, and when you visited us, you knew
                                it. We do " covet " all souls to God, whether old or young. The guardianship of those
                                children is transferred to me, until they are of age. They are part and parcel of our
                                family. What do you suppose we took them for ? To feed, clothe and school, without
                                compensation? And then, as they become old enough to begin to be of some profit, after
                                years of expense, care and trouble, you want to hold them under your influence entirely.
                                If you thus felt, and were determined so to act, you ought to have kept the boys under
                                your own supervision and guardianship. Not make a pretense of transferring this, when
                                all you wanted to transfer was the burthen of their support and care, and to have
                                strangers give them a training and discipline, that in the disunited condition of your
                                own household, you said you could not oestow upon them. When the boys are of age, they
                                have the same legal rights to choose for themselves that you and I had. That liberty we
                                possessed and have exercised independent of our mothers. That liberty Jesus possessed,
                                when his mother chided him for running away and causing his father and mother several
                                days' search and anxiety "Wist ye not that I must be about my Father's business ? " That
                                was the sword of which the prophet said in the temple : " A sword shall pass through
                                thine own bowels also "—thine affections. Then you speak of love—think'I do not know
                                what it is, etc. Jesus needed not that anyone should testify to him of man or woman ;
                                for he knew what<pb n="66" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 66 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. was in man and woman. And
                                may it not be thus with a Shaker? That which human beings know naturally as brute
                                beasts, in those things they corrupt themselves. Natural affection is of God, and is
                                common to the whole animal kingdom. Oftener is it, that the human is without natural
                                affection, than that the inferior creatures are without it. In its present form, as in
                                the Virgin Mary, it is but the shadow of the love of our Eternal Mother in the heavens,
                                and of the love that exists in the Resurrection Order. The natural is first, and the
                                natural has to be forsaken and die, to make room for the spiritual. " Except a man
                                forsake father, mother, brother, sister," in nature, he cannot become possessed of the
                                love that prevails in the Household of Faith. " By this shall all men know that ye are
                                my disciples, if ye have love one for another." Is there, then, no love but natural
                                mother's love i.'You may know no other. And so you think we " should marry and haoe lots
                                of children !" and then we should be better men and women, forsooth. And when toe
                                quarreled and divorced, and the lots of children run loose and wild, where and who would
                                he the Shakers to take care of them ? I am not offended at all. You speak as a foolish
                                woman speaketh. By and by you will see it so and be ashamed of it. You refer to
                                amusements : Innocence is a state of perpetual amusement. We aim to preserve children in
                                innocence ; to teach them pure morality, industry, economy, prudence and justice. And
                                when we can preserve them from a selfish mother's love and other worldly influences, we
                                have bat little trouble in keeping them contented and happy. Respectfully,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A man will be already in no mean Paradise..." TEIform="index"/>A man will be already in no mean Paradise...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A man will be already in no mean Paradise if at the hour of sunset a good hope can fall upon
                            him, like harmonies of music, that the earth shall still be fair, and the happiness of every
                            feeling creature still re ceives a constant augmentation, and each good cause yet find
                            worthy defenders, when the memory of his own poor name and personality has long been blotted
                            out of the brief recollection of man forever.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>The Children's Grotto</head><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fun and noise sometimes proper" TEIform="index"/>Fun and Noise Sometimes Proper</head><p TEIform="p">— My Dear Children :—I have been persuaded for years that there is a hilarity in the com-
                                position of young people while they are growing, which aches to come out; and that if it
                                does not get vent in the proper place, it will bring distress on older and more sedate
                                people at an improper time. I think you have a right to be noisy at times and in proper
                                places ; but accept a hint from me; and out of respect for your superiors and seniors,
                                try and have the overflow of youthful glee and noise take place where it will not
                                disturb the older people, and be sure to refrain from being ill-mannerly in places
                                sacred to quiet and religious purposes. We older people are too apt to forget we once
                                were young and noisy, and needed a great de"al of forbearance ; but when we think of it,
                                we will know it was so. But you can do a great deal to make older people better pleased
                                with you, than making the earth quake with a racket of noise too much of the time. Not
                                long ago there was a prediction that a certain city would be visited by an earthquake,
                                so some careful parents sent their boys a long distance into the country to visit some
                                friends ; but some things happened shortly after, and you can imagine what they were,
                                which caused the country friends to write : " Send us on the earthqaake, but come and
                                take your boys home ! " An earthquake rather than noisy boys ! </p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Like those we love" TEIform="index"/>Like Those we Love</head><p TEIform="p">—If I should set you to watch for any thing in which you had a special interest, you
                                would see the desired object sooner than older people. Now I want all of my little boys
                                and girls to spy out a great truth; a fact, which you may sooner be able to realize
                                true, than some who are much older than you are. Watch yourselves and companions, and
                                those who are older/too, and learn how true it is that we all strive to be like that
                                which we truly love ! We pattern those persons whom we love, even without thinking about
                                doing so. We imitate the words, the ways and actions of those whom we truly admire. In
                                Africa, where<pb n="67" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. civilization is yet unknown,
                                some tribes of the people own herds of cattle, which they think more of than they do of
                                themselves or their children ! They give these cattle better shelter from the sun and
                                storms than they have themselves ! More than this ; so much do they admire these cattle,
                                that they try to appear like them; and for this purpose knock out their upper frqnt
                                teeth, because the cattle have none ! So Dr. Livingstone writes. This central truth has
                                a very religious side to it. We prefer to be Christians, and Christian children, and to
                                love Jesus, the Christ, best — is it not so ? Now, observe again, my dear children,
                                those are the best Christians, and those love Jesus best, who try to live as He lived,
                                and to become just like Him, When we say we love Jesus, and love to be good Christians,
                                and yet take no pains to be good as He teas good, to be pure, as He was pure, to forsake
                                the bad and even things not so bad which He forsook, we do not tell the truth. If we
                                really love goodness and purity, we will try ever so hard to be pure and good, and in
                                that degree we love the beautiful and pure Jesus, we will live just like Him, as nearly
                                as we, with the help of good angels, are able to live. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Useful thumb" TEIform="index"/>Useful thumb
                            </head><p TEIform="p">We clip from the N. J. Messenger the following about the Useful Thumb : <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Do you know how tisef ul your thumb is to you? If you do not, suppose you
                                        bind it up a while, and see how helpless your four fingers will be alone. We say
                                        when we are particularly clumsy, that our " fingers are all thumbs," which is a
                                        slander on the hardest worked, most useful one of the five. The thumb is also a
                                        sign of intelligence; an idiot's thumb is said to be almost useless, and is
                                        always shut inside of the fingers, while the same member belonging to others is
                                        always shut outside. He who cheerfully takes advice may be greater than he who
                                        gives it. " In this life," says a spirit, " I am not advanced as I might have
                                        been if I had cultivated the art of peace instead of the art of war."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New Jersey messenger" TEIform="index"/>New Jersey messengeR
                                    </bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>Home Topics</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Medical Record describes a new cure for consumption..." TEIform="index"/>The Medical Record describes a new cure for consumption...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">THE Medical Record describes a new cure for consumption. The points are, first, to clear
                                the lungs by deep, forcible breathing;, second, to establish perfect digestion, by
                                eating good, well-cooked food ; third, to promote a healing of the tubercles by eating
                                salts of lime ; fourth, to take plenty of out-door exercise and sleep in apartments with
                                the windows open, summer and winter.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In damp closets, strong rooms, safes, and other places..." TEIform="index"/>In damp closets, strong rooms, safes, and other places...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> In damp closets, strong rooms, safes and other places where mildew is dreaded, a trayful
                                of quick lime placed there will prevent it.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mucilage" TEIform="index"/>Mucilage
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Mucilage.—A very clear and transparent mucilage of great tenacity may be made by mixing
                                rice flour with cold water, and letting it gently simmer over the fire.</p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A correspondent asks how to keep fresh meat..." TEIform="index"/>A correspondent asks how to keep fresh meat...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> A correspondent asks how to keep fresh meat from tainting. Pour a little good vinegar
                                into a spoon, dip a finger into it, and pass it over the entire surface of the raw
                            meat.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bits of soap" TEIform="index"/>Bits of soap
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Bits of soap.—Instead of throwing away the pieces of soap which become too small for
                                convenient handling, make a square flannel bag of suitable size ; leave one end partly
                                open, and put in the pieces as they collect; when it is full, baste.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cement for joining metals with nonmetallic substances" TEIform="index"/>Cement for joining metals with nonmetallic substances
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Cement for joining mentals with nonmetallic substances.—To obtain a cement suitable for
                                joining metals and nonmetallic substances, mix liquid glue with a sufficient quantity of
                                wood-ashes to form a thick mass. The ashes should be added in small quantities to the
                                glue while boiling, and constantly stirred. A sort of mastic is thus obtained, which,
                                applied hot to the two surfaces that are to be joined, makes them adhere firmly
                                together. A similar substance may be prepared by dissolving in boiling water 2J lbs. of
                                glue and two ozs. of gum ammoniac, adding in small quantities about 2 ozs. of sulphuric
                                acid.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Housekeeping hints" TEIform="index"/>Housekeeping hints
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> Housekeeping hints.—Soaking salt fish in sour milk will freshen them
                                        speedily. Salt curdles new milk ; hence, in preparing milk porridge, gravies,
                                        etc., the salt should 7(&gt;<pb n="68" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 68 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO.
                                        not be added until the dish is prepared. That clear, boiling water will remove
                                        tea stains and many fruit stains. Pour the water through the stain, and thus
                                        prevent it from spreading over the fabric. The ripe tomato will remove ink and
                                        other stains from white cloth; also from the hands. That a teaspoonful of
                                        turpentine boiled with your white clothes will aid the whitening process. That
                                        boiled starch is much improved by the addition of a little sperm, or a little
                                        salt, or both, or a little gumarabic dissolved. That beeswax and salt will make
                                        your flatirons as clean and smooth as glass. Tie a lump of wax in a rag, and
                                        keep for that purpose. When the irons are hot rub them first with the wax rag,
                                        then scour with a paper or cloth sprinkled with salt. That kerosene will soften
                                        boots or shoes which have been hardened by water, and render them as pliable as
                                        new. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Montreal star" TEIform="index"/>Montreal Star.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>THOUGHTS FOR TO-DAY</head><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="No matter how pious men are..." TEIform="index"/>No matter how pious men are...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">No matter how pious men are, the moment they place policy before principle, they become
                                incapable of doing right, and are transformed into the most odious tools of despotism.
                            </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A man may be in heaven..." TEIform="index"/>A man may be in heaven...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A man may be in heaven long before he goes there; and a man may be perfectly sure that
                                there is a hell here, even when he is doubtful about the one hereafter. </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Darkest hour" TEIform="index"/>Darkest hour
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Darkest Hour.—Horace Greeley never said a more truthful thing than when he declared "
                                that the darkest hour in the history of any young man is when he sits down to study how
                                to get money without honestly earning it." </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="He who can only be serious..." TEIform="index"/>He who can only be serious...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">He who can only be serious, and he who can only be merry, is but half a man. Both halves
                                must be developed to form a real specimen. </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God does not pay off every Saturday night..." TEIform="index"/>God does not pay off every Saturday night...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">God does not pay off every Saturday night; but he is sure to " settle in full" some day.
                            </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="When a person dies..." TEIform="index"/>When a person dies...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> When a person dies, we never regret our tenderness toward him ; but we often do our lack
                                of it. </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The devil works on mortals..." TEIform="index"/>The devil works on mortals...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The devil works on mortals through their selfishness. When they talk about the duty
                                everybody owes to " number one," he chuck- les, and says, " I've got another
                                missionary." </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Many a man thinks that it is his goodness..." TEIform="index"/>Many a man thinks that it is his goodness...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Many a man thinks that it is his goodness that keeps him from crime, when it is only his
                                full stomach. On half allowance, he would be as ugly and knavish as anybody. Don't
                                mistake potatoes for principles. </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To pretend to be better than we are..." TEIform="index"/>To pretend to be better than we are...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> To pretend to be better than we are, is hypocrisy ; to pretend to be greater than we
                                are, is vanity and folly; to pretend to be worse than we really are, is the silliest
                                pretense of all. </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="There is more of the Christly spirit..." TEIform="index"/>There is more of the Christly spirit...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">There is more of the Christly spirit in carrying a basket of provisions to some hungry
                                and destitute family in your neighborhood than in praying for them, and then waiting for
                                some one else to go to their relief. </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our thoughts are the parents of our words..." TEIform="index"/>Our thoughts are the parents of our words...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Our thoughts are the parents of our words, and our words are soon crystallized into
                                deeds. Therefore our deeds are as our thoughts, as certainly as the sapling only
                                produces the tree, " each after its kind." He who talks vice will become vicious, so far
                                as his courage will permit. He who loves impure thoughts will naturally illustrate these
                                thoughts in daily life, while he whose heart-tablet is free from the impress of unholy
                                thoughts and vicious desires will naturally be kept from the outcropping of sins. </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christ-life pattern" TEIform="index"/>Christ-life pattern
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Cubist-Life Pattern.—The Christian religion, as much as it has hitherto done for the
                                world, is yet only beginning to be a power in the world. The nineteen centuries of its
                                existence have been but the dawn of a new day. A higher and truer Christianity is to
                                come Men have been preaching a crucified Christ—they have shown forth his death. The
                                risen and living Christ is to be preached to the Church of the future. The presence of
                                the living Christ is what we all need. We need to 7iave Him walk with us and work in us
                                and among us. He can do His mighty works for us and in us only through His spiritual and
                                divine presence. If we have not His divine presence we are without God in the world.—Dr.
                                S. F. Dike.</p></div3></div2><pb n="69" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Missionary items" TEIform="index"/>MISSIONARY ITEMS</head><p TEIform="p">The Seventh-Day Adventists — a body which numbers only about 20,000—propose to raise $100,000
                            in two years for missionary work in Great Britain. There is said to be a religious sect in
                            Russia called the " Helpers." They avoid lying, stealing and getting in debt. An organiza-
                            tion of that kind might accomplish good in this country. Let us graft thereon our re-
                            ligion, if not there already. Let people make what excuses they will, one fact is assured,
                            and can be proven to any by a little observation, that whoso makes objection, excuses,
                            trouble or refusals to the paying of a small tax for the spread of the faith he professes to
                            believe to be most righteous, will invariably be found spending the amount of such tax,
                            multiplied many times, in worldly or beastly habits of selfish indulgencies. </p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Book Table</head><p TEIform="p">"Coronation hymns and songs " has been sent us by the publishers, A. S. Barnes &amp; Co.,
                            New York. It is a pretty book,very chubby in appearance, as if fat with the choice collec-
                            tion of good music and much fine sentiment within. It is much fuller of musical selections
                            than the numerous books of its kind lately issued, and we note a considerable prominence of
                            new hymns aud songs. The composition and compilation are the work of Dr. Deems and Theo. E.
                            Perkins. While we do not agree with those sentiments of the vicarious sufferings and
                            atonement, so popular in books like these, we live in hopes, that by the repetition of such
                            words as " blood," " death," " died for me," etc., the life of Christ as an example may yet
                            shine through the first; departure from evil, death to the world, may be significant of the
                            second, and that "Tie lived for me " as a pattern, may revolve from the third. Price, 35
                            cents. The Shaker Manifesto for 1878.— A few complete volumes of this year may still be
                            obtained, though only a few. The binding of the twelve numbers makes a book of 313 pages,
                            containing eleven pieces of music, and a host of information and interesting reading,
                            relative to Shaker biography, customs, theology and record. We will send, unbound, for 60
                            cents; bound, for $1.50. Address, Shaker Manifesto, Shakers, N. Y. The Shaker Child's
                            Prayer. — Sent, postpaid, for five cents, currency. It is a short, easily-learned poem,
                            non-sectarian and universally practicable. Address, Shaker Manifesto, Shakers, N. Y. A
                            Movable Planisphere of the Heavens at Every Minute : By Henry Whitall, of Camden, N. J. Such
                            is the title of a set of machinery, and arrangement of the planetary system, that with this
                            set of two spheres more can be accomplished in the study of astronomy in two weeks than
                            could possibly be learned in twelve months, even with such valuable treatises as Burritt's,
                            Mitchell's, or any other that we know of. Any problem of the heavens, the position of stars
                            every evening of the year, every movement of the moon, planets, etc., and a hundred ideas
                            very useful to know, are here actually shown to you by the movable planisphere. It is more
                            to astronomy than a map in geography. Prof. Metcalf says of it: "I can teach with the set
                            more of the Starry Heavens in one day than I can in a year from any other celestial atlas,
                            map or globe I have ever seen." The price of the set is $4.00. ' Apply at this office. </p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notice" TEIform="index"/>NOTICE</head><p TEIform="p">To the liberally inclined : In consideration of the Editor's office being without
                            compensation of any kind, we would kindly invite the offerings of those having to spare, to
                            be sent thereto, to defray necessary expenses, and to furnish needed conveniences. We are in
                            hopes to be able to meet expenses of The Manifesto ; but every dollar, at present rates,
                            will be required for this purpose. Those expecting or requiring answers to correspondence,
                            will inclose stamps.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Publisher" TEIform="persName"/>The Publisher</byline></div2><pb n="70" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New song" TEIform="index"/>A NEW SONG</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, James G." TEIform="persName"/>James G. Russell</byline><p TEIform="p">Enfield, N. H. 1. Let us sing unto the Lord— To the Lord a new song. 2. We will come into His
                            courts, To His courts of pure love. 3. Let us walk within the light, In the light of the
                            day. Sound His praises abroad, In music most sweet. "We will And His praises sound forth,
                            With gladness and zeal. While the We will banish the night, While journeying on, To the<pb n="71" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 71 sing of His love, As we journey along, "While
                            angelic music resounds Thro' the heavens above, Whose arches rebright spirit realms. The
                            abode of the Free, Where union ceCHORUS. Allegro. choirs, The chorus repeat. turn Each
                            echoing peal, ments The Faithful in one. The Lord He is God, His goodness supreme, His arm
                            will uphold, And His love will redeem,<pb n="72" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/> His arm will up hold, And His
                            love will redeem</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Feed my lambs [Children's supplement]" TEIform="index"/>[Children's Supplement.] "FEED MY
                            LAMBS."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Calver, Amelia J." TEIform="persName"/>AMELIA J. CALVER</byline><p TEIform="p">" O, Simon, Simon, lovest thou ? " Our Lord and Savior saitb, When rising from his sepulchre
                            He triumphed over death. " Thou knowest that I love Thee all," Was Peter's fond reply. And
                            sweeter than a seraph's tone, Was heard our Savior's cry : " Feed my Lambs." Thrice was this
                            loving question asked, And thrice the injunction given ; And sealing thus his parting word,
                            Returned again to heaven. But all along the vale of time, His silvery tones are heard, And
                            every Savior of the race, Repeats His parting word, "Feed my Lambs." Yea, feed my lambs, my
                            little lambs, Who're called to fields of grace ; For straight and narrow is the path And
                            limited the space, Until they learn that paths of peace Are paths of pleasantness ; And good
                            is added to the soul, With Heaven's righteousness. " Feed my Lambs." Feed them with precepts
                            rich with truth, Examples wise and good ; And never let them seek in vain The spirit's daily
                            food. For as you nurture, thus will grow The tender, youthful mind, While innocence and
                            purity Will seek for food refined. •'' Feed my Lam, bs." And when they're strengthened in
                            the Lord, By culture you have given, They will arise and call you blest, And sing your
                            praise in heaven. And when you see them pure and white Amid the angel throng, You'll bless
                            the day that duty called In accents sweet and strong, " Feed my Lambs." Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.
                        </p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><p TEIform="p">Received of N. A. Brig-gs, $5.04. Received of A. W. Williams, $18.80. Received of Samuel
                            Kendrick, $25.00. Received of A. J. Battles, $40.00. Received of John Vance, $30.00.
                            Received of diaries Clapp, $5.20. Received of R. M. Wagan, $15.00. </p><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>DEATHS</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Congleton, Cyrene" TEIform="index"/>Cyrene Congleton
                                </head><p TEIform="p">At Pleasant Hill, Ky., Nov. 10, 1878, <persName reg="Congleton, Cyrene" TEIform="persName">Eldress
                                        Cyrene Congleton</persName>, aged 77 years. " A bright jewel of the first
                                    water." B. B. D. </p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Burnett, Micajah" TEIform="index"/>Burnett Micajah
                                </head><p TEIform="p">Also Jan, 10, 1879, <persName reg="Burnett, Micajah" TEIform="persName">Bro. Micajah Burnett</persName>,
                                    aged 87. " A bright star taken from our firmament, to shine more brightly in a
                                    higher sphere." B. B. D. </p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Price, Maria" TEIform="index"/>Maria Price
                                </head><p TEIform="p">At South Union, Ky., Jan. 12, <persName reg="Price, Maria" TEIform="persName">Maria Price</persName>,
                                    aged 72 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gorden, Lewis" TEIform="index"/>Lewis Gorden
                                </head><p TEIform="p">At White Water Village, O., Jan. 24, <persName reg="Gorden, Lewis" TEIform="persName">Lewis
                                    Gorden</persName>, aged 77 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cram, Jane" TEIform="index"/>Jane Cram
                                </head><p TEIform="p">At Shaker Village, N. H., Dec. 16th, 1878, <persName reg="Cram, Jane" TEIform="persName">Jane
                                    Cram</persName>, aged 71 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Crooker, Sarah" TEIform="index"/>Sarah Crooker
                                </head><p TEIform="p">At Shaker Village, N. H., Jan. 8th, <persName reg="Crooker, Sarah" TEIform="persName">Sarah
                                    Crooker</persName>, aged 80 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Blanchard, Ruth" TEIform="index"/>Ruth Blanchard
                                </head><p TEIform="p">At Shaker Village, N. H., Jan. 28th, <persName reg="Blanchard, Ruth" TEIform="persName">Ruth
                                    Blanchard</persName>, aged 79 years, 6 months. </p></div4></div3></div2><!--
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p> [ads deleted] </p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>