<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1209" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">12</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">9</biblScope><date value="18820901" TEIform="date">September 1882</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">193-216</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="12" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="9" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!-- 
                        <pb n="t.p." id="p1"/>
                        <p> VOL. XII. SEPTEMBER. NO. 9 SHAKER MANIFESTO Published by the United Societies. OUR HOME AT SHIRLEY, MASS. "Blessed
                        are those that hear the word of God and keep it." SHAKER VILLAGE, N. H. 1882. </p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>
                        </head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]<pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                        --><pb n="193" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><!--
                    <div2 type="none">
                        <p> CONTENTS. Page., A Leiteb by Giles B. Avkky, America,..... Elijah Wilds, The Incoming Woman, Communal Relations,
                            No. 2, Eternal Life, Peteb Ayebs, Be Mine to Love int Truth, A Call fob Mbrjy, [dbas of Inspiration, Heboes,
                            '..... The Conscience axd Future Judi A Brave and Honest Man, Notes,...... cobbespokdekce, Deaths, Fable, 193 -
                            195 396 - 198 | I Can and I Will, 198 | Letter Box, - 203 i Books and Papers, 200 202 202 203 Good Cookies, To
                            Bepair Cracks i\ Walli Tub Sick Koom, Scalds and Burns, Sour Milk, - 205 Breathing Dirty Air, Leg Weakness,
                            Music,—"Here Am I." Page. 207 - 211 212 - 212 212 - 214 214 - 214 215 - 215 215 - 215 215 - 216 Vol. XII.
                            SEPTEMBER, 1882. ]Sro. VIII.</p>
                    </div2>
                    --><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Respected Friend :—Your kind letter of the..." TEIform="index"/>Respected Friend :—Your kind letter of the...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon, April 1882" TEIform="index"/>Mount Lebanon, N. Y. Apr. 1882</dateline><p TEIform="p">[The following Letter is a reply to an invitation from Stephen Pearl Andrews, of New York,
                            extended to Giles I}. Avery. to attend a Colloquium, in that city, "to forecast and
                            inaugurate that grand reconciliation, mutual acceptance, and harmony, which, is believed may
                            be the basis of the religion of the future."'] Mount Lebanon, N. Y. Apr. 1882 Respected
                            Friend :—Your kind letter of the 28, ult., is before us ; please excuse delay in reply, as
                            our duties, and absence from home must account for the same. We cannot fail to be interested
                            in the ''quest of truth" and "in the mutual harmony and acceptance of the religion of the
                            future." But, our personal duties are such, it does not appear, at this moment, to be
                            consistent for the writer to attend the "Colloquium" therefore beg you to accept our thanks
                            for the interest you take in our noble cause—the universal blessing of humanity ; and your
                            special respect to the Shaker Institution. In lieu of attendance to your noble, purposed
                            convention, we will present just a few leading ideas in behalf of universal human weal ;
                            leaving denominational t;issues," out in the cold. And, first, of the question which Pilate
                            put to Jesus. "What is truth ?" Jesus never answered it, except in reference to its
                            religious character. In this capacity, he said, "I am the truth," that is, my life's mission
                            ; my testimony of theory and practice ! Our answer to the question,, in its universal
                            bearing, is this, Truth, is the manifesto of those principles, that, in their application to
                            the pursuits of life, eventuate in the development, ele^ vation and perfection of humanity,
                            and culminate in the glory of God. To define truth in all its varied phases of relations to
                            science, art, conventional propriety, social, political, and religious economy, and
                            delineate it in its multiform ramifications, would require volumes, instead of sentences.
                            But to refer to religious truth, we would suggest that it is not an article made of the
                            metal of human sophisms, or philosophy and tempered in a theological bath ! It <pb n="194" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 194 SHAKER MANIFESTO. would bo falsehood to assert that there are no
                            expressions of a measure of truth in the sentimental frame work of the multiform theologies
                            which are the products of the labored speculations of the human mind ; because each one, and
                            all of them have a few golden nuggets of truth mid the vast amount of speculative debris,
                            that makes up the bulk of their denominational characteristics and differences. But, Creeds
                            which shroud faith and religion in mystery and inconsistency ; which make God a revengh.il
                            Tyrant, more cruel in his purposes than the savages of the cannibal races ; creeds which
                            despoil justice of her rewards, and give the lie to God's goodness and love ; his charity
                            and mercy make as chaff; and crown the fiat of his alleged decrees with daggers which pierce
                            the human soul with horror, and anoint the murderous wounds with despair, cannot be models
                            of Truth. lu this, we refer to what many theologians teach as the "vicarious atonement of
                            Jesus," for the sins of all who affect to believe in his divinity, and confess him to be the
                            Savior of man in sh&gt;. by, and through his sufferings for sin ! instead of a salvation
                            from sin ; which, especially, was his mission ! Much psevido Christianity teaches salvation
                            simply from the consequences of sin ! In this theology is taught, 1st. That Jesus is God.
                            2nd. That Mary was the mother of God. 3rd. That the Holy Ghost is God. That Jesus, God's son
                            is as old as his Father, and older than his mother; that these three are One and this One is
                            three! That these thi%ee are all eternal, and yet one of them is a son : and this son was
                            begotten, but not made ! Was this sophistical theology the fruit of some ancient
                            '•'Curriculum ?" In this remark we would not be understood, as treating with levity the
                            noble pursuits of truth's guest; these we revere ; but mean that we consider religious truth
                            makes an end of a sinful life, revealing sin as a violation of God's law, and a life of
                            practical obedience to the precepts of Christ, the culmination of righteousness, peace, and
                            universal unity. Now, friend Andrews, while we have the greatest respect to all efforts to
                            improve human society, when we reflect upon the world's history, and consider how many
                            "Colloquiums" have been inaugurated to invent and establish a universal religion, and how
                            fruitless have been all religions, so called, of human origin, we shrink from the effort of
                            repeating the vain endeavor. The deeliue of the influence of the Churches, and the
                            diminished power of the pulpit, is directly traceable to the want of vitality and saving
                            power in the theologies of human production, scholastically called, and studied, as
                            religion. And the deserved fact that the great mass of religions professed, do not alter and
                            improve the lives, of religious professors. Amid the storms of human ambition. pride,
                            prejudice and contention that always bear sway, to a great extent, in Colloquial
                            organizations, we confidently rely on the truth standard that Christ hath reared, with its
                            eternal increase in grace and loveliness. The great mistakes of the present churchal
                            influence, are. I. An attempt to harmonize the Church and the world ! II. An effort to
                            combine, in one churchal organization, before there is a spiritual harmony in the
                            understandings and <pb n="195" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 195 heart's emotions of the
                            different religious professors. III. A harmony of denominations,, before there is a harmony
                            and unity ot faith. IV. To convert religion into a mere theology. V. To embody, in a
                            communistic relation, soids who have not been baptized into, nor grown up unto, a union of
                            spirit. All communions formed on a mere external or material basis, for external purposes
                            only, without reference to unity of spirit, must fail, for it lacks the foundational
                            principle of success ! Thus, friend Andrews, you will observe, that the Shaker idea, is, I.
                            That religion is not theology. II. That no h"nian institution of theology that can be
                            devised, will ever, be a reliable basis for a unification of the human family in religion.
                            III. That the Truth, in religion, is already revealed, and need no colloquial tinkering to
                            render it perfect. IV. Shakers do not believe that the mere profession of faith in any
                            special theory or dogma of theological opinion, constitutes true religion. This is
                            accomplished only by living in harmony with the same principles of Truth that Jesus Christ
                            lived. What is needed for humanity's weal, is a religion and moral philosophy which will
                            inspire patriotism and hold us strenuously to tlie work of making the earth a clean,
                            orderly, and whohsmie dwelling place, for human beings. All that is good and true, in the
                            religious element of life, will work to disentaugle itself from the worldly, sensual and
                            narrow interests of the carnal life. Our religion should be utilitarian, understandable, and
                            comprehensible, freed from mysteries, whether of God, Angels, Heaven, Hell or in the social
                            relations. True religion consists, I. Of faith in God, as a Supreme being, unto whom all
                            intelligent beings are accountable for the conduct of their lives. II. Of faith in Man as a
                            Creature of God, unto whom the same regard for the good feelings of brother and sister,
                            should be exercised as unto ones-self. III. In a practical obedience to the dictates of this
                            faith, so that life's deeds will be a blessing to the doer, and work no ill to any creature
                            of God. While Shakers understand that Truth is an eternal reality, and that all phases of
                            its manifestations are necessary, and living stones in its glorious temple, they do not
                            believe that any formulated opinions of mere human conception,1 anchored at the dock of
                            Creed has chained the heavenly Argosy of Divine Truth, with all her cargo of revelations,
                            within the finite harbor of human attainments. She is out upon the boundless ocean of God's
                            wisdom and love; and, though she may often come to human port, with her cargo, will never be
                            chained to the dock of any finished Venice on a human strand. Your friend kindly,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B" TEIform="persName"/>Giles B. Avery</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="America" TEIform="index"/>AMERICA</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Devyr, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/>CECELIA DEVYR</byline><p TEIform="p">A captive on her own domain, A half bewildered, passive slave, Her song to Liberty as vain.
                            As music breathed above a grave. Taere is no time to sing, or dream, Mo moments for the
                            banquet hall: Behold the cloud ! whose lightnings' beam Is like the writing on the wall.
                            With childish pride, elate and warm, She sees the past with ruddy sky. Unconscious of the
                            fearful storm That darkly, wildly gathers nigh. <pb n="196" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 196 SHAKER MANIFESTO.
                            Her laborers in their need for bread, Implore her for the right to toil : She drops her
                            hands, she droops her head, And whispers, "This is freedom's soil." Above her breath, she
                            dare not speak, Her tyrants, awe her. with their might. She scarcely knows that she is
                            weak,— Or that the right, is right.— Whence is this power, this conquest sore? At which her
                            lips may not demur ! No hostile foot, is on her shore, No ioreign foe has conquered her, But
                            many masters, calls she lord. And many kings she must obey. Monopolists ! a selfish horde,
                            Degrade America to-day.. Prom Tallies to the mountain tops, Her heavy golden harvests stand.
                            Her soil is teeming with its crops, Yet want is seen on every hand. The factory and the
                            foundry's still, Are only making broken sounds. The work-shops long untrodden, till With
                            rankest weeds and grasses crowned And idlers, idlers every where, And tramps that no one
                            could employ, Till Satan takes them in his care And makes their wreckless hands destroy. The
                            crimson flame is in the sky, The crimson blood is on the ground, Rut crimson of a deeper dye
                            Might on the Nation's face be found. For she who saw not the distress, Nor heard the
                            pleadings of her throngs, Could call her armies to suppress The rage that swelled against
                            their wrongs. 0 had she heard them when they cried, And waked to effort for their good,
                            Prosperity would now be wide, Where desolation's terror brood. But wealth above, and mines
                            below, And commerce on the open sea, One clutching, grasping system know, One law, and that,
                            monopoly. Can God forgive a sin so great? O ye who have it in your power V You tamper with
                            the bolt of fate, If you delay a single hour. You were combined to work this woe, Combine
                            again to be its doom, The coming destiny o'er throw, And make the desert places bloom ; The
                            land shall not in bondage groan, Though you refuse to make it free, For God e'er long will
                            claim his own, And give it back to Liberty. Mount Lebanon. N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Elijah Wilds part 2" TEIform="index"/>Elijah Wilds [part 2]</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wilds, Elijah" TEIform="persName"/> ELIJAH WILDS</byline><p TEIform="p">(Continued from last number). The spirit of opposition and cruel persecution which was raised
                            against Mother and the Elders, and the patience, meekness and charity which they manifested
                            under it, was a most striking evidence of their Christ like spirit, and a powerful
                            confirmation of the divine origin and heavenly purity of that gospel which they preached. A
                            remarkable instance of this took place while they were at my house. In consequence of
                            Mother's testimony against all sin, and every kind of impurity of the flesh and spirit, and
                            the great conviction it produced among the people in this vicinity, a tumultuous mob was
                            raised, mostly from the town of Harvard, and consisting altogether of the enemies of the
                            cross. They came on Sabbath evening, June 1, 1783, about eight o'clock, and surrounded the
                            house. Some of the leaders had been captains in the militia, and still bore that title.
                            About one hundred men followed them for the evident purpose of abusing Mother Ann and the
                            Elders. They surrounded the house all night, and would suffer no one to go out, excepting
                            one woman, who had left her infant at home, unprotected. By her we sent information of these
                            proceedings to Thomas Buckmore, an officer of the town, who came in the morning with a
                            constable. When daylight appeared, the leaders of the mob called for Mother Ann and *he
                            Elders to come out to them, but they <pb n="197" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 197 did not
                            think proper to comply. By permission the leaders now entered the house, when Mother and the
                            Elders requested us to prepare some breakfast for them, and these men sat down to cat.
                            Mother then advised me to carry some food to those, who were in the door yard. All ate
                            freely ; after this the Elders went among the men and Elder James addressed them as follows
                            ;— "Why have you come here to abuse or to hurt us? What have we done? Have we injured your
                            persons or property? If we have, make us sensible of it, and we will make you restitution."
                            These words so enraged the mob, that they seized him by one arm, and the brethren by the
                            other, and held him, till he cried out. "•Lord have mercy! you will pull me to pieces ! !"
                            At this cry the hands of the mob were loosed from him. At this instant, Thomas Buckmore came
                            forward and commanded the peace, and ordered the mob to disperse. This produced, in them,
                            some fear, and after considerable parley they requested that the two Elders, William Lee and
                            James Whittaker, would go with them to Jeremiah Willard's, a man of professed faith, who
                            lived in Harvard, promising that they should not be hurt. rJthey pretended that their only
                            wish was to get them from this place, and have them leave the town. Although the Elders had
                            no confidence in their promises, vet, wishing to save Mother Ann from their cruel hands,
                            they agreed to go. Several of the brethren accompanied them, while Mother Ann was left at my
                            house. Most of the mob followed the Elders to Harvard.* *After reaching Harvard Elder James
                            Whittaker was bound to a tree and most inhumanly scourged by the mob as above narAt evening,
                            the Elders returned and were gladly received by Mother Ann and the brethren and sisters, at
                            our house. Have they abused you, James? said Mother. It was soon ascertained that his
                            wounded back was covered with blood, caused by whipping at the hands of the mob. Many places
                            from his shoulders to his waist was bruised to a jelly. "I have been abuaed, said he ; but
                            not for any wrong that I have done them ; it is for your sakes. I feel nothing against them
                            for what they have done to me, for they went ignorant, and knew not what they d:d, nor what
                            manner of spirit controlled them." Mother Ann, and all the company present, now kneeled and
                            prayed to God to jorgive their wicked persecutors. Elder James cried heartily, and said,
                            "Father, forgive them, for they know not what they do." After praying for their enemies.
                            Mother Ann and the Elders were filled with joy and thankfulness, that they were counted
                            worthy to suffer persecution for Christ's sake. As they prayed for their persecutors in the
                            spirit of love they endured their sufferings with meekness and patience, which were
                            evidences to me that they possessed a treasure above all earthly treasures, and a power
                            beyond all human power. My sincere prayer now, is that rated. Father William Lee was saved
                            from this cruelty by the Believers who received the blows that were aimed at him. One of the
                            persecutors struck Sister Lucy Frescott in the face, causing the blood to flow from the
                            wound. Lucy's former husband was present, and one of them called out,—"See what you have
                            done to that man's wife." At this the mob dispersed, and the Believers returned home. On the
                            27th, of May 1882 a lot of land inclosing the place where the tree stood was deeded to the
                            Believers; a fact that will, no doubt, give pleasure to the many who have visited the place.
                                <pb n="198" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 198 SHAKER MANIFESTO. this spirit of God may find an entrance
                            into the hears of the children of men, and lead them into the way of purity and holiness.—
                            Shirley Mass. 1826.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Incoming woman" TEIform="index"/> THE INCOMING WOMAN</head><byline TEIform="byline">OLIVE F. CHANDLER</byline><p TEIform="p">Behold in the distance, the incoming woman ! No tarnish of fashion, no sham or display; 80
                            divinely majestic, a halo precedes her, Illuming earth's pathway by night and by- day. She's
                            risen superior to sensuous desires ; A magnet of love, drawing higher mankind ; She's
                            chaste, pure and gentle, yet strong and courageous, Her sceptre is trutli and her mission
                            divine. 0 welcome with gladness, ye brave sons and noble! Her advent is seen in vast
                            beauties revealed; In tastes so artistic in paintings and flowers, She's opened new
                            fountains of art long concealed. 0 heed her all nations, and list to lier pleadings She's
                            wisdom eternal and culture divine. O trust her and garner her spirit and power, The image of
                            God doth her being enshrine. She's coming my friends, lo, her spring-time is nearing! The
                            true buds of promise are swelling to bloom; The breezes all laden with essence of healing.
                            Will bring a new era and banish the gloom, Her brothers no longer may dare to oppress her,
                            In her their true equal and helper is seen; So pure is her presence, so chastened her
                            spirit, The "kingdom" is "conic," and she reigneth its Queen. Ayer, Mass</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ark" TEIform="index"/>An Ark</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">An ark two hundred feet long is being built by an Iowa man, who believes that a
                                    second flood will take place in 1885. He intends, how-ever, to take passengers at $
                                    5000 each, and expects to make a fortune</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Plain Dealer" TEIform="index"/>Plain Dealer</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Communal relations, no. 2" TEIform="index"/> COMMUNAL RELATIONS. No, 2.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, Oliver C" TEIform="persName"/>OLIVER C. HAMPTON</byline><p TEIform="p">Tyranny is an unmitigated curse under all circumstances. It is no part of a Christian
                            government nor of a Christian spirit. Those who allow themselves to be influenced by its
                            dictates, are unfit for Directors of the affairs of a Community. They are even unfit members
                            of such Community, unless they reform. Some persons having experienced the baleful effects
                            of tyranny upon themselves, become so desperate and indignant, as to propose to throw off
                            all restraint and to become as it were, outlaws. They at least propose to strike such an
                            independent attitude as to ignore all government external to themselves. But this it seems
                            to me would strike at the very foundation of all community life, yea, and utterly annihilate
                            it. Now we are all fallible beings. We are brought into contact with earth and its
                            conditions that we may have a school of discipline. We are likewise placed in community
                            life, that we may have a chance to further and complete that discipline. As we come to be
                            d?veloped from infancy to the period of old age we gradually discover many faults, sinful
                            proclivities and idiosynci'acies disagreeable to others and tormenting to ourselves. Some of
                            these are acquired, most of them entailed, all of themhateful. We should grow out of them
                            and we must have time for it. Tyranny is one of these and they are few and far between
                            indeed, who have not one atom of it in their make up. Then there are envy, jealousy,
                            passionateucss, impatience, impurity and about a thousand more equally unbearable
                            rudimentalisms to be ^rotten clear of through <pb n="199" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 199
                            the splendid discipline of our community life. And blessed, thrice blessed is he who can
                            afford to submit to the refining ordeal. No language can do justice to the after-glory of
                            such melting of these crude elements "with fervent heat'" and their final transmutation into
                            the fine gold of resulting and eternal fruitions. No one can know these things but those who
                            have actually submitted to this salutary discipline and calmly passed into the region
                            beyond. Will any one then resort to the suicidal policy of ignoring the necessity for
                            Directors in the affairs of our community life, or refuse to be governed and externally
                            influenced by the administration thereof, because sometimes such administration may appear
                            tyrannical or possibly be so, occasionally, to some painful extent ? Organization in our
                            community implies a systematic arrangement, scientifically looking to the greatest possible
                            advantage and success from organized effortIt also keeps forever in view the sublime and
                            benevolent law of the greatest possible good to the greatest possible number. But do away
                            with authority's Directors and the obligations to yield a cheerful intelligent compliance to
                            their administration, and the whole communal structure goes to pieces under the inexorable
                            law of desintegration and repulsion. Most assuredly none of us can afford to do this; for
                            this pentecostal arrangement with all its faults is the very best system of communal life
                            ever yet evolved ; far seeing in results as the gleams of glory which passed across the
                            halcyon horoscope of the ancient seers and sages. But again, our Institution is a
                            selfmending machine, a constantly improving and progressing community; and will finally
                            eradicate all its crudities, all elements of unkindness. oppression tyranny and all the
                            rest. This is one of its crowning glories. It is the embodiment ef a great and sublime
                            concatenation of events at one end of which God and higher intelligences are at work and we
                            at the other. They are laying down the cross ties of Love and Wisdom, and we furnishing the
                            rails, ballasting and rolling stock. They impart the holy fervors of Inspiration and we the
                            crude ores to be transmuted by them into pure metal. We furnish the sorrows and sacrifice,
                            they, the forces of pure love, sympathy and encouragement to melt them down into the
                            contentment and peace which passeth all understanding." We unfortunately contribute a great
                            amount of ''dross and tin" and they, the fire to consume it. With these very considerable
                            taxes raised on what in moments of pain and despair we might be inclined to call our
                            calamities, will it not be best to bear patiently, even a little oppression, than by
                            resisting the same to rob one's self of pentecoslal blessings, and the temporal and
                            spiritual advantages of communal life, and by continuing and widening the policy of
                            resistance, to finally disintegrate and destroy the whole organic structure and annihilate
                            all the blessings of a systematic arrangement, the most perfect ever yet originated on earth
                            ? I am locking at this whole subject through the lens of experience, am not the least
                            inclined to speculate upon any communistic El Dorado, flowered over with Utopian forecasts
                            of an Elysian existence not possible to be realized on this earth, so long as man is so full
                            of evil as at present and likely to be as long as I live at least. <pb n="200" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/>
                            200 SHAKER MANIFESTO. I know what it is to be oppressed both in fact and in imagination. I
                            think I have been down to the very bottom of this Jordan and felt all its waves roll over
                            me. So that I am not without deep lasting sympathy for any and all who may now be passing
                            through that fearful river of experience. And now may thorns grow in place of roses and
                            thistles in place of wheat, if I ever knowingly exercise a spirit of tyranny and oppression
                            toward any one ; under this blessed resolution I doubt not has been one of the good fruits
                            extorted from the arid soil of these very experiences which I resolved to bear, and the
                            painful discipline by which I determined to profit. Dear reader, if you do not see the point
                            ube you a doer of the work and you shall know of the doctri :e whether it be trite or
                            whether I speak of myself" as Jesus proposes. Union Village, Ohio</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Eternal life" TEIform="index"/>ETERNAL LIFE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"> NANCY G. DANFORTH</byline><p TEIform="p"> What is it? Jt is a life which we may live through all eternity without a desire of change
                            in the order of it. We may still be progressing, traveling from one degree of perfection to
                            another ; drawing nearer ever nearer to God, the Source of all life. The Savior says, "My
                            sheep hear my voice ard they follow me, and I give unto them o'eruul life and they shall
                            never perish." Thus we find that this life which we seek is obtained by becoming a follower
                            of Christ. Being thus sheltered from the tumultuous storms of strife and ambition, which so
                            fiercely rage among the children of this world, while contending for wealth, or unmerited
                            fame, we turn the warfare within to overcome all that would render life unholy ; those
                            conditions which would make eternity unpleasant to contemplate. The strife of the true
                            disciple is to live in peace ; to speak kindly to all ; to forgive the erring, and let the
                            love of God reign supremely in the soul, governing every act of the life. Where these
                            principles are lived they will create a state so happy that we shall not wish a change ; but
                            would have it grow into more and more of heaven, even upon earth. In this way we are sowing
                            seed, the fruits of which we shall be willing to reap, and thus lay hold on Eternal Life.
                            CanterburyN. H.</p></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Peter Ayers" TEIform="index"/> PETER AYERS</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>HENRY C. BLINN</byline><p TEIform="p"> The subject of our sketch was born in Voluntown Conn. Sep. 12, 1760. He was of German
                            descent and a man of remarkable physical endurance. Lovingliberty more than he loved life,
                            he entered the army as a volunteer and had the pleasure of witnessing the surrender of Gen.
                            Burgoyne at Bemis' heights, Oct. 1(5, 1777. In the year 1854 when Peter was 94 years of age
                            he related to the writer ot this notice, the following ; "At the age of 14 years I removed
                            to the State of New York, with my parents, and remained with them till about twenty years of
                            age. In the month of May,' 1780, I heard of Mother Ann and the Elders, who then resided at
                            Niskeyuna and came to the conclusion to visit them. Previous to this I had convictions in my
                            mind re- <pb n="201" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKEE MANIFESTO. 201 specting my lost condition, and had
                            been blessed with spiritual manifestations in which were represented those whom we call the
                            people of God. The exact likeness of this vision I afterward found to be in Mother Ann and
                            her followers. At the time of my first visit to this religious order, I thought I would take
                            express pains, in regard to myself, and not be deceived by any one. My visit was one largely
                            fraught with curiosity, as I at this time supposed them to be a deluded people. In order to
                            be doubly guarded, I concluded to take some food with me, that I need not be obliged to
                            accept an invitation to eat at their table. I was very kindly received and conversed freely
                            with several of the Shakers, upon the matters of common interest, till the first half of the
                            day had nearly passed away. Being at this time in conversation with Elder John Hocknell, he
                            extended an invitation for me to dine with them, when Mother Ann immediately remarked, 'We
                            will let our brother Peter eat the food which he has brought with him, as he prefers to do
                            that, rather than to dine with us.' How Mother knew my mind in this respect, I am unable to
                            tell, as I was very careful of my words, in regard to the course I had chosen to follow.
                            They then invited me to remain with them over the Sabbath, and Elder John Hocknell said very
                            kindly and seriously, 'Young man, you ought this day to confess your sins to God, and .live
                            a new life ; I told him 'I knew it was a wicked spirit that made me commit sin, and it was
                            wrong to keep the works of darkness hid, but it was my choice to return home, as I wished to
                            labor in my mind respecting what I had seen and heard. While I was maturing this thought,
                            Mother Ann said, 'Let Peter go home to his parents, and have time to labor in his mind, and
                            then he can come again.' When Mother Ann spoke this, I thought she knew me, and could
                            discover the innermost feelings of my heart. Subsequently I visited Mother Ann and the
                            Elders, three times, before I fully concluded to abide by their counsel. It was revealed to
                            me that they ¦Acre the people of God, and I was fully persuaded that I was called to accept
                            their testimony, and to take up my cross against a sinful life. I made mention of this to
                            Father James Whittaker, and he said to me, 'It is the gift of God.' Soon after this I made a
                            confession of my life to Elder John Hocknell and also to Father William Lee. Once, I saw
                            Mother Ann and the Elders at Steventown and attended worship with them. Several persons
                            stood by the door, as spectators, and Mother, invited them to come in and take part in the
                            service. I was at meeting in Hancock Mass, at the house of Stephen Fitch. A mob gathered
                            around the bouse while Father William Lee was speaking. Several of the brethren went oiit
                            among the mob but Elder John Hocknell advised us all to return to the house. Mother Ann then
                            spoke very kindly to these persecutors but they were very unreasonable in their replies,
                            s,nd in their false accusations. It was of but little consequence to this reckless mob what
                            the words or actions were, if they could only find some pretext whereby to accuse Mother Ann
                            and her followers. They asked Father William what he had to say ; 'I am clear of your
                            charges, before God and his angels.' Mother Ann, Father William and Hannah Kendall were, <pb n="202" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 202 SHAKER MANIFESTO. however, arrested and tried and fined $6.25
                            each." Such, is the injustice of a hypocritical and sectarian jury. "At one time I was
                            engaged in the hauling of lumber to Albany. My wagon was formed of only one long board, one
                            end of which was attached to the forward axletree, and the other of the board to the rear
                            one. On my return home I overtook six sisters who had been on a visit to Niskeyuna, now
                            Watervliet. They belonged in Hancock, a. distance of 30 miles. By invitation, they accepted
                            a ride on my carriage for some ten miles, which brought us to the residence of my parents.
                            My mother accommodated them for the night, and soon after breakfast they left for their own
                            hon\es. We now learned that these sisters had only a few days previous traveled from Hancock
                            to Watervliet. on foot. About three years previous to the gathering of the church at New
                            Lebanon, N. Y. I accompanied Father Job Bishop, John Barnes and David Darrowon a journey to
                            Alfred, Gloucester, Canterbury and Enfield." (TO BE CONTINUED.)</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Be mine to love in truth" TEIform="index"/> BE MINE TO LOVE IN TRUTH.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whiteley, John" TEIform="persName"/> JOHN WHITELEY</byline><p TEIform="p">A love sincere, intense, Can never be concealed, While what is mere pretense Will clearly be
                            revealed. Be mine to love in truth, If not so much is shown—¦ The aged and the youth Reap
                            from the seed I've sown. If in humility 'twas sown And watered with my tears, The harvest
                            fully grown Will leave no place for fears. God's blessing will attend The toiler in His
                            field, And tho' life's labors end— Kind acts will increase yield. Shirley, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Call for mercy" TEIform="index"/> A CALL FOR MERCY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wythe, Eunice" TEIform="persName"/> EUNICE WYTHE.</byline><p TEIform="p"> [This poem was composed by sister Eunice while 3he was held in bondage to the relations of
                            the world.] Father of mercies hear the erieo That rend my feeble breast Redress my sorrows,
                            hear my sighs And answer my request. Kind Mother on Mount Zion's height An outcast child
                            behold Let mercy's hand unlock the gate And lead me to thy fold. I mourn and sorrow like a
                            dove Thy mercy to obtain sMy soul depends on mother's love To bring me home again. 0 God I
                            look to thee for power To cut this cruel chain If thou wilt burst the prison door I'll not
                            return again. Dear Brethren ever kind and just Where charity belongs Who are at Mother's
                            banquet blest Remember those in bonds. Dear Sisters who in love combine And f?ast at
                            Mother's board Unite your prayers to God witli mine That I may be restored. Ye pure
                            attendants of the Lamb My fervent prayer receive That T may ever bless the name That does my
                            soul relieve. Bright Angels spread your wings around And be my swift convoy To bear me safe
                            to Zion's ground The seat of peace and joy. But if 'tis best to stand the test And patiently
                            endure Lord may I have beyond the grave A refuge with the pure. Let patience stand at my
                            right hand To keep me meek and mild That I may wait a better state Completely reconciled.
                            Harvard, Mass.</p></div2><pb n="203" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ideas of inspiration" TEIform="index"/> IDEAS OF INSPIRATION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pool, Jason" TEIform="persName"/> JASON POOL</byline><p TEIform="p">The Church was established by Divine revelation, and the leaders, afterwards, were, no doubt
                            gifted with inspiration to lead the people. It is quite possible for a person to be inspired
                            and not be folly aware of it, the quantity being very small. Although the principles of the
                            gospel are'not contrary to reason, yet, human reason may not always be sufficiently
                            developed to comprehend the gospel plan, hence it was necessary to discard this lower phase,
                            when it ^ame in contact with revelation. Reason, in man, is of a progressive nature, and on
                            this account he was destined to come to a point where he could see and understand for
                            himself. When we take a survey of the great progress that has been made in the arts and
                            sciences ; and the many useful inventions that have been discovered, we are inclined to
                            believe that the capacity for comprehending the philosophy of the Christian religion is
                            pretty well developed. On the whole, mankind seem to be very much opposed to the
                            investigation of any theological subject with an unprejudiced mind especially if it should
                            result in establishing a doctrine which would come across their own natural feelings and
                            inclinations. Some are very slow to give up preconceived opinions, and unless they obtain
                            positive evidence to the contrary, will cling unyieldingly to them. On this account it is
                            highly necessary that some should be able to throw a clear light on the darkness of theory
                            and speculation. It may be necessary for some one to do for theology what Sir Isaac Newton
                            did for natural philosophy. All who believe in a kind Providence, must also believe that
                            when there is a necessity which belongs to a superior power to supply, it will eventually be
                            supplied. Implicit faith in modern revelation is becoming very weak. Transgressors will
                            commit all kinds of crime and then claim to be inspired. In view of this fact, one writer
                            well observes :—"I believe in the revelation of God : in modern as* well as in ancient
                            revelation. But it is to be considered that a revelation to me is not necessarily a
                            revelation to others. No person is under obligation to believe a thing because it has been
                            revealed to me, unless I can show him convincing evidence that such a thing has, indeed,"
                            been revealed from God. Neither am I obliged to receive a thing because another says it has
                            been revealed to him. It may be a revelation to him, but it is not therefore a revelation to
                            me : neither am I bound to believe it on his testimony. If the thing be revealed to me by
                            the Spirit, I know it to be true from the testimony of the spirit, but if it be revealed to
                            another, I cannot receive it without the proof." Hancock, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Heroes" TEIform="index"/>HEROES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sutton, Elizette" TEIform="persName"/>ELIZETTE SUTTON</byline><p TEIform="p">There is much said in this day, about heroes ; heroic deeds are performed by thousands of
                            people, who are highly applauded. Too much cannot be said in commendation of valor and
                            heroism. Very many individuals can tell of remarkable examples of courage witnessed in the
                            hour of great peril. We have read of a fire occurring in <pb n="204" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/>one of the
                            large publishing houses of New York city, where a young woman was seen in one of the upper
                            story windows, holding to the outside casement with an iron grasp, while the smoke
                            completely enshrouded her form. There she was alone in that awful moment of terror shrieking
                            for aid. She was rescued from the maddening flames, by men of courage, who braved the
                            danger, at the risk of their own lives. Was not this heroism ? Heroes will, and must have
                            their own renown, though renown does not make heroes. The lives of some persons are full of
                            similar nets. On the spur of the moment, noble deeds are often performed deserving of great
                            credit. Such characters exercise almost superhuman effort, to bring about great results. We
                            find on record, a host of adventurers who with a genuine ambition, have climbed the heights,
                            and explored the depths of science, till its voice of wisdom speaks through their living
                            senses, and develops the unknown to the people at large, so that, what was once veiled in
                            obscurity, becomes familiar even to the populace. A light flashes from electric fluid, and
                            starts the world with its bearings. A cable reaches from continent to continent which
                            carries the latest ne'ws with such rapidity that in a few moments the two worlds become
                            familiar with what is transpiring of interest to either. Wires are stretched across the
                            country, on which plays the electric current, relating facts by a simple click, click, that
                            the human voice would utter far and near. Steam operates by magical power, and forces a long
                            line of coaches through the country, crowded with travelers on every conceivable mission.
                            Schemes of persistent daring are acted by the men of our times, who are forward in hope.
                            They have come up to a height of physical and spiritual pressure, that pushes them on toward
                            the truths of science, and the might of reform in all its bearings. The world has known its
                            Newton, its Franklin, as well as the principle scientists whose intelligence has shone with
                            splendor, through the vista of ages; they have gone out of sight, but have left their light
                            to illumine present and future posterity, and to mingle with greater and more powerful
                            agencies and agents, that will yet crowd the stage of action. Research is not only a word,
                            but a practical reality ; a disenthralled active mind, embraces it tenaciously and
                            affectionately. Working heroes still walk the halls of science with ambitious feet. Hail to
                            the great Chieftain ! Washington, the anniversary of whose birth we so kindly celebrate. The
                            hero's path is not a flowery one, it is evidently strewn with thorns, his oft bleeding feet
                            and manacled hands told of severe trial, and dangerous ways to pass over, before tie shout
                            was re-echoed from shore to shore of an independent nation. He did not live to himself, but
                            unto the race and unto God ; the divinity was stirred within him, and he lighted the fires
                            of truth and justice in the hearts of the people. It still burns far and wide among the
                            heroes of our times. Well may his deeds be rehearsed and adored by the multitude of today.
                            They are emblazoned on banners that float in a free air. Too many are willing to spend their
                            lives in a passive condition, without <pb n="205" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> power to perfect or promote the
                            happiness of others by a single act of selfdenial. They think that all the sweetness of life
                            is locked up in their own selfish hearts ; their pleasures arise from narrow minds and
                            untaught lives. When will the heroes of the cross of Christ, stand in a more conspicuous
                            light in the ranks of the brave? A seed has been sown that will yet bear its fruit in that
                            direction. The spiritual horizon is brightening, and God will say again, "Let there be
                            light." People of enduring fortitude are working in fields of progress. No wider range of
                            thought has yet filled the mind in the interest of the political, or scientific world, than
                            will yet fill it in the religious world. When the battle is turned to the foes of our''own
                            household,'' and all impurity is slain by the sword of truth ; then devotion to principle,
                            to the higher laws of being, will be our crown of rejoicing. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Conscience and future judgement" TEIform="index"/>THE CONSCIENCE AND FUTURE JUDGMENT
                        </head><p TEIform="p">I sat alone with my conscience, In a place where time had
                            ceased, And we talked of my former living In the land where the years increased; And I felt
                            I should have to answer The question it put to me, And to face the answer and question
                            Throughout an eternity. The ghosts of forgotten actions Came floating before my sight, And
                            things that I thought were dead things, Were alive with a terrible might. And the vision of
                            all my past life Was an awful thing to face— Alone with my conscience sitting In that
                            silently solemn place. And I thought of a far-away warning Of a sorrow that was to be mine,
                            In a land that then was the future, But now is the present time. And I thought of my former
                            thinking Of the judgment-day to be ; But sitting alone with my conscience Seemed judgment
                            enough for me. And I wondered if there was a future To this land beyond the grave ; But no
                            one gave me an answer, And no one came to save. Then I felt that the future was present, And
                            the present would never go by, For it was but the thought of my past lite Grown into
                            eternity. Then I woke from my timely dreaming, And the vision passed away, And I knew the-
                            far-away warning Was a warning of yesterday. And I prayed that I may not forget it, In this
                            land before the grave, That I may not cry in the future, And no one come to save. And so I
                            have learnt a lesson, Which I ought to have known before, And which, though I learnt it
                            dreaming, I hope to forget no more. So I sit alone with my conscience • In the place where
                            the years increase, And I try to remember the future In the land where time will cease. And
                            I know of the future judgment, How dreadful soe'er it be, That to sit alone with my
                            conscience Will be judgment enough for me</p><byline TEIform="byline">Exchange</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Brave and honest man" TEIform="index"/>A BRAVE AND HONEST MAN Formed on the good old plan</head><p TEIform="p">A true and brave and down right honest man! He blew no trumpet in the market place, Nor in
                            the Church, with hypocritic face, Supplied with cant, the lack of Christian grace; Loathing
                            pretense, he did with cheerful will What others talked of, while their hands were still.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whittier" TEIform="persName"/>Whittier</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Act well at the moment, and you have performed a good action to all eternity" TEIform="index"/>
                            Act well at the moment, and you have performed a good action to all eternity
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Act well at the moment, and you have performed a good action to all eternity. </p></div2><pb n="206" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker manifesto. 1882. " TEIform="index"/>SHAKER MANIFESTO. 1882.</head><p TEIform="p">Office of Publication, The "Shaker Manifesto" is published at Shaker Village, Mer. Co., N.
                            II. Ail business matters connected with the financial department of the paper will be
                            directed to the Publisher of Manifesto, Shaker Village, N. H. All other communications may
                            be addressed, Editor of Manifesto, Shaker Village, N. H. One Copy per. year, Postage paid,
                            .60 " " six months, " " .35 Enclose a two cent stamp for a specimen copy. To avoid mistakes,
                            those who send money, should write the name of their Post Office, County and State. TO
                            A.DVEKO'ISBXt.S. One inch, one insertion $ 1.00 " " three " each .75 " " six " " .65 " "
                            twelve " " .50 " column ----- ----- ----- 6.00 Larger spaces, rates in same proportion.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/> NOTES</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Occasionally we have placed before us..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Occasionally we have placed before us...
                            </head><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></bibl><p TEIform="p">Occasionally we have placed before us an illustrated article referring to the cultivation
                                of the mind, which appeals so directly and so largely to our best judgment that we take
                                pleasure in making reference to it. In the American Phrenological Journal for July we
                                have the portrait of a West African boy, a King's son, at the age of 15 years, and then
                                another portrait of the same individual after a cultivation of six years by the
                                missionaries of that country. The contrast is remarkably clear and withal very
                                interesting. The change is, probably, no more than might be wrought out on the mind of a
                                white boy and for this reason it should become a valuable lesson to all who are
                                interested in the advancement of humanity. We all understand very well that a neglected
                                garden soon becomes overrun with weeds and many of the valuable plants may be wholly or
                                partially ruined, and yet this is no more apparent than it is that the neglected or
                                undisciplined mind, in a few years, become careless, coarse and sensual. On the other
                                hand the careful gardener destroys all the weeds and useless plants and makes his garden
                                a place of profit and of pleasure. Two much cannot be said in encouragement of the care
                                and culture of the mind ; to afford an education that will banish ignorance and
                                superstition. It must prove very satisfactory to know that a change can be so
                                effectually wrought, that even a few years of right doing will efface many of the marks
                                of transgression, and that by faithfully living in the works of righteousness we may be
                                redeemed from all wrong. </p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Clean hands and a pure heart..." TEIform="index"/>Clean hands and a pure heart...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Clean hands*and a pure heart must aid very largely in forming an acceptable offering.
                                Destitute of this simple preparation, all forms and ceremonies lose their vitality and
                                the service of worship becomes a representation of the letter which killeth. Whatever we
                                may be led to do, the best that we have in our possession should constitute our gift for
                                presentation before the Lord. Mutilated offerings must prove as objectionable in this
                                day, as in the early religious history of mankind. The Apostle, evidently had this
                                Si:xsri^i:]vi35nBii, <pb n="207" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 207 thought on his mind
                                when he wrote that it was a "living sacrifice, holy and acceptable" that should be
                                prepared. Anything less than this would be selfish and destroy the very object for which
                                the offering1 was made</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cleanliness comes very near..." TEIform="index"/>Cleanliness comes very near...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Cleanliness comes very near to godliness. To reach this desirable state make frequent use
                                of the bath. A variety of ways have been proved to be quite beneficial for the health,
                                such as plunge, hand, towel, sponge or shower bath. One in limited circumstances can
                                bathe effectually with one quart of water, while the more fortunate can use a more
                                liberal supply. The temperature of the water should be made agreeable to the one who
                                uses it. By some advisers, water at 75 degrees would be called cold ; others prefer a
                                lower temperature. Use a little common sense apd you will not be harmed : without this,
                                bathing, like eating and drinking may be carried to a ruinous excess. We have known
                                persons to pamgc into a bath which was at freezing point, and others to stand on the ice
                                for a shower bath. These may be heroic for cleanliness, but destructive to health. Study
                                some good work on the subject of bathing and then follow the directions for your own
                                health and for the comfort of your friends.</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Calvin G. Reed teacher. I visited this school on..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Calvin G. Reed teacher. I visited this school on...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon,  District No. 12" TEIform="index"/> Mt. Lebanon, N,Y,. Dis. No.
                                12.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Calvin G. Reed teacher. I visited this school on the 13 of Jan. I found everything in
                                perfect order, and can speak in the highest terms, both of the teacher and scholars. The
                                school-room was in perfect order, supplied with globes, charts, maps, Webster's
                                Unabridged Dictionary, and every thing that is needed for teacher and scholars. The
                                order was perfect and recitation superior to schools in Columbia County. The attendance
                                was the best in the Second Commissioner District, being 95 per. cent. The teacher's
                                success did honor to himself as a teacher, and honor to the Society. Penmanship was one
                                of the good qualities of the school, but reading was a success. The pronunciation was
                                clear and distinct. Each word was accented correctly, and the scholars understood what
                                they read. I was well pleased with the reading exercises. The interest the Shakers take
                                in education is very commendable. I regret that more of our Public Schools do not take a
                                deeper interest in our schools and bring them up to the standard of the school at Mt.
                                Lebanon. The teachers attend the Institutes and Association, and are ready to catch
                                every new idea or new method ; therefore "their teachers are well posted in all the New
                                Methods now in use. Isaac T. Haight. School Commissioner</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Haight, Isaac T." TEIform="persName"/></byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The North Family at Mt. Lebanon maintain a private school..." TEIform="index"/>
                                The North Family at Mt. Lebanon maintain a private school...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The North Family at Mt. Lebanon maintain a private school and afford their pupils the
                                best of advantages.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Friend:—Could not a company of your..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Dear Friend:—Could not a company of your...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Connecticut, Mystic, August 1, 1882" TEIform="index"/>Mystic, Ct. August 1, 1882.</dateline><p TEIform="p">F. W. Evans, Dear Friend:—Could not a company of your people attend our annual peace
                                meeting, to be held the 23rd. and 24th of August? We hold large 'meetings and need aid.
                                The meeting is to be held in the usual place on the west bank of the Mystic River. If
                                you could bring some singers too, it would help us a great deal. Please answer soon.
                                Yours, with much respect</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whipple, Fred E." TEIform="persName"/>Fred. E. Whipple, Sec.</byline></div3><pb n="208" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Friend: Your kind invitation to attend with..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Dear Friend: Your kind invitation to attend with...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon,  August 5,1882" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. August 5,
                                1882</dateline><p TEIform="p">Frederic E. Whipple, Dear Friend: Your kind invitation to attend with a company o:
                                singers your great gathering for the noble purpose of bringing War to an end, is a hand.
                                I assure you nothing would give mt more pleasure than to be in your midst anc to bring
                                with me a band of our spiritual singers. I would also dearly enjoy your singing1, and to
                                hear the eloquent utterances of your speakers, both male and female, would be a high
                                intellectual treat. Also, to meet anc greet such friends of Peace and advocates o1
                                virtue as gather around your honored President, Alfred Love and Amanda Deyo, would be
                                good for my constitution of both body and mind. The primary causes of War must be
                                fearlessly sought out. When these are found, the Mystery of Iniquity will be revealed.
                                Light makes manifest! What is it in human nature that in a straight, makes physical
                                fighters out of intellectual nonresistants? In an emergency, wherefore do even the
                                Friends, furnish their quota of soldiers? Indeed, may we not candidly ask ourselves; Why
                                it is that War has been and is, so nearly universal? Effects so wide spread, so general,
                                must have producing causes that are equally present in the hearts of human beings
                                everywhere. What are they? Can they be removed? If so, by whojn and through what agency?
                                Perhaps, when the Peace advocates adopt the Buddhist principle of "Thou shalt not kill,"
                                the axe oi reform will have been put to the root of the evil tree of War and violence.
                                Another Buddhist principle is ; Use no intoxicating beverages. How much of the warspirit
                                of the English nation, ar.d of the AngloSaxon race in general, is due to their Hullbeef
                                diet, we may come to know before we cease to grow in grace and in the knowledge of God
                                and nature. It is certain that a few flesh-eating Englishmen hold in subjection the
                                millions, of rice-eating men, women and children of India. The Americans are a
                                meat-eating people, and uatil the last quarter of a century, were eminently a
                                pork-eating people. That they are a fighting nation is not disputed; and if the Egyptian
                                Israelites had more diseases than the toothless Americans, no wonder the Lord changed
                                their diet for forty years,— medical treatment. When Temperance lecturers, first began
                                making converts, they did not preach total abstinence from beer, cider, or even wine.
                                Neither did Lincoln begin the Civil War with Slavery emancipation, but with it he ended
                                the war and slavery together. Is it not thus with Peace-advocates ? Beginning with ;
                                Thou shalt not kill human beings, nor eat them, they will end flesh-eating and War
                                together by simply saying, Thou shalt not kill. It is possible that I, with one brother,
                                may appear in your midst as spectators. I should so love to witness your proceedings.
                                But it is quite uncertain. With most fraternal greetings. Your Friend,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Manifesto ;—Your sweet, little face so..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Dear Manifesto ;—Your sweet, little face so...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Oswego, May, 1882" TEIform="index"/> Oswego, May, 1882</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Manifesto ;—Your sweet, little face so welcome to us, has been missed from our
                                fireside since the Jan. No. came to hand, and we infer that our subscription has
                                expired. Enclosed, please find am't. for one year's renewal, and consider us a life
                                subscriber. You have entwined yourself around our hearts, and become one of the
                                necessities of our earthly existence. And now a word to our dear brethren and sisters
                                greeting : As John the Baptist preceded the first advent of Christ in the person of
                                Jesus, and as the primitive Christian church gave promise, before its extinction, in the
                                sec)nd and third centuries, of its permanent foundation in the "latter days," so do you
                                as in organized body of harmonious and loving, n*actical Christians, give hope, and
                                promise, that the time is at hand, when the leaven of rue Shaker principles, will leaven
                                the whole ump of humanity. Ye are a light unto the world, therefore, "Let your light so
                                shine bebre men that they may see your good works ¦xnd glorify our Father which is in
                                heaven," and let the little Manifesto go into the hearts and homes of all God's
                                children, who are eady to receive it, with its precious fruitage of joy, and peace, and
                                purity, and "the angels bright, from their homes of light" will <pb n="209" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/>
                                SIIAKKIl MANIFESTO. 209 continue to aid you in bearing the burdens of its care and
                                sustenance. We venture to say, that there are millions of people in this broad land, who
                                have never heard of such a people as the Shakers, much less, are familiar with the
                                principles of which they are the living exponents. How truly in this case, as in :thers,
                                do the words of our dear Lord apply when he said, "The harvest truly is plenteous, but
                                the laborers are few." May our Heavenly Father bestow still more abundantly, the means
                                whereby the "Manifesto" can be sent all over this broad land, with the tidings that
                                there is a happy, Godfearing, man-loving people, living above the . law of "mine and
                                thine" in fraternal unity and love. Where there are no Prisons, Almshouses, or Insane
                                Asylums ; where there are no homicides, suicides, embezzlements, or adulteries, clearly
                                showing who are the followers ot Jesus, for he said "Ye shall know them by their
                                fruits." We would if time and space permitted, gladly enter upon the discussion of the
                                analogy between the historical events of the time of Jesus the Christ and the events of
                                these "latter days." For instance, we have our Pharisees, Christians so-called.
                                Sadducees, called materialists, Essenes, and Nazarites in the garb of the Shakers, and
                                those who have dealings with "familiar spirits," called Spiritualists. And our boasted
                                nineteenth century civilization, with its concomitants Church and State, already past
                                the zenith of their power, weak and enfeebled with the accumulated vice and crime, of
                                centuries. Is it not like the ancient Roman Empire, tottering toward its down fall in
                                fulfillment of the prediction of St. John in the Apocalypse? Do not the "signs of the
                                times," point to this approaching advent of the "True Church of the Living God," as
                                clearly as they did, at its first appearing? We have done. We have thrown out thes e few
                                thoughts feeling quite confident they will not escape the attention of the "children of
                                light," and now may the "peace of God which passeth all understanding" prevail and
                                continue at the homes of our brother and sister Shakersuntil noneshall say, "Know the
                                Lord : for they shall all kno.v me, from the least of them unto the greatest of them,
                                saith the Lord; for I will forgive their iniquity, and 1 will remember their sin no
                                more."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bailey, B. F." TEIform="persName"/>B. F. Bailey</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Very pleasantly remembered, Elder Henry : I send you..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Very pleasantly remembered, Elder Henry : I send you...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Canaan, Four Corners,  June 3, 1882" TEIform="index"/> Canaan, Four Corners, N.
                                Y. June 3, 1882.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Very pleasantly remembered, Elder Henry : I send you, according to request, an article
                                relating to life and adventures among the Indians of the Xorth West. I often go back in
                                memory to the days spent among them. I expect the memory will follow me to the end of my
                                life. Most of those have passed away with whom I spent my twelve years of early manhood;
                                those who were children then, are only left to remember, me now. I hope it is to them a
                                grateful remembrance. I know it is so to me ; for very pleasant were the days I spent
                                among them. I still cherish for them the deepest affection, and their wrongs have
                                grieved me to the heart. I hope to meet them in a world better and happier than
                                this—free from the many wrongs and miseries which they have had to oaidure from
                                merciless and rapacious white'men ; for which I consider our Government in a measure,
                                answerable. I have known butfew good Indian Agent*. The majority of them have been a
                                disgrace to the race, men who could practice, with impunity, every kind of iniquity. The
                                liquor wliich they have introduced among the Indians has slain its thousands. The
                                Indians knew nothing of "fire water" till the whites introduced it. With drunkenness,
                                came every other vice. Hear what Ke-che Be-zhe-ka (Big Buffalo.) of the Lakes, once said
                                to me on this subject;— "When the Pale Faces came across the Big Waters. {Ke-che
                                Gah*me,~) there were straight paths running through all our forests. One warrior walked
                                in them. They were very narrow. But one warrior's feet went straight forward. It did not
                                hurt them to walk in straight, narrow paths. But the Pale Face could not walk in them.
                                His toes turned out. He was trying to walk two ways at once. He could not walk straight.
                                His ways were crooked. He taught our people to drink "Fire Water." He taught them to
                                steal. He came creeping into our wigwams, at night. He crept in like a mouse, that
                                nibbles the children's corn- He had long fingers—so long that they would reach to the
                                bottom of the mo-koks (birch bark boxes.) He stole all the women's sugar out of them,
                                made of the juice of the maple-tree. And when our people told him of this, and he <pb n="210" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 210 SHAKER MANIFESTO. opened his mouth to speak, we saw that he
                                had two tongues. One tongue laid very still, the other moved very fast. The lying tongue
                                walked, ike fastest. It is like the brook that runs over the stones. None can stop its
                                babblings." We are all well and feel thankful for your pleasant visit among us. Love to
                                Eldress Joanna, and the other sisters—your associates. Yours with much love</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sproat, Granville T." TEIform="persName"/>GRANVILLE T. SPROAT</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dearly Beloved Elders ;—While sitting by my window, this fine pleasant..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Dearly Beloved Elders ;—While sitting by my window, this fine pleasant...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Massachusetts, Harvard,  1882" TEIform="index"/>Harvard, Mass. 1882</dateline><p TEIform="p">[The following beautiful letter was written by our aged mother, Eunice Bathrick of the
                                Society of Har. Yard, Mass, and addressed to the Elders of the North family at Mount
                                Lebanon. Sister Eunice lias lived with the Believers since early childhood, and has now
                                reached her eighty eighth year. ] Harvard, Mass. 1882. Dearly Beloved Elders ;—While
                                sitting by my window, this fine pleasant morning, and listening to the birds, as they
                                chant their hymns of praise to the Author of all Good, my spirit is drawn to you, my
                                precious friends, and all the dear ones in your Order, many of whom seem to be present,
                                as I take my pen, to address you. Were it not for this soul communion, my spirit would
                                hunger, and thirst more deeply; but this sustains me, and bears me up, as I journey to
                                the land beyond. I often feel the presence of loved ones, who are still in the form, and
                                take pleasure in their visits ; still I sometimes crave something more tangible ; and so
                                I inquire "How are all the good Elders,—dear Brethren and Sisters at the North Family,
                                Mount Lebanon? By letters received from Canaan by sisters M. and E. we learn of the
                                beautiful spirit manifestations with which you are blessed. We hope we may be like
                                favored, in our turn. I long to hear the voice of our spirit friends, through whomsoever
                                they may choose, as mediums to convey their messages, even if it is through little
                                children. It is true, I enjoy the presence of the dear loved ones who have long since
                                passed the river, and they comfort me, and give me strength to bear the infirmities of
                                age; but I wish for the sake of others, that we may have something more tangible,—some
                                further proof of their presence than any thing which I can convey. I earnestly pray that
                                something may take place, to draw the mind,—the attention of the young and inexperienced
                                from worldly pleasures, and all that attracts downward. If they can once gain an element
                                in spiritual things, worldly pleasures soon loose their charms, or so I found it, and I
                                think I am not an exception in this case. Never-ceasing thanks to Mother Ann's first
                                horn; for this; for had they not shown me the beauties of the more excellent way,-— and
                                heightened my aspirations to obtain a growth in the work of purification while in my
                                youth, I might have fallen, as some of my companions did in the hour of trial. But when
                                this time came, my love for the pleasures of nature was gone; and I had nothing to look
                                to, but to press ahead, and win the prize. The sooner the young can find an element in
                                the work of full consecration, the easier it will be for them through life. They never
                                can fully realize the benefit thus derived, only as they travel. I have seen those who
                                had never felt the necessity of giving1 up all, while young, when the trial of their
                                faith came upon them, later in life, their struggles would be so great, that they could
                                hardly resist them ; and some of them fell by the way. When I saw cases like these, it
                                heightened my veneration and gratitude to my early teachers, for through them, I was
                                made able to stand in the hour of trial, and temptation. All I can say in my own behalf
                                is, that I obeyed their teachings in general • but when I deviated, an awakened
                                conscience soon drove me to confession and repentance. Thanks to the Power of Good for
                                this. I feel that I am, and ever shall remain a debtor to my Heavenly Parents and the
                                guardian spirits for all I possess; and am likewise dependant on the saints in, as well
                                as out of the form for much of my support. I feel that the time is drawing near when the
                                veil will be lifted, and many who now dwell in Zion will see things in a very different
                                light from that which they now appear to them. Till this time arrives, we must continue
                                to <pb n="211" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 211 wait, hope, pray and trust; for the true
                                and honest hearted will not pray in vain. Our Heavenly Parents never turn a deaf ear to
                                their children's ciy. I hope these lines will find you, and yours» in health and
                                prosperity,—enjoying the rich bounties of heaven, which your faithful labors so truly
                                merit. And may the good spirits in your order, never leave the field, till all Zion's
                                inhabit" f ants are brought into union and harmony o sentiment; having one faith, and
                                one bap tism; the baptism of the true Christ spiritl unmixed with worldly elements. We
                                shal then be prepared for the harvest of souls. Accept love from all, as we have a great
                                store tor you, and circulate as you may feel. Devotedly Yours,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bathrick, Eunice" TEIform="persName"/>Eunice Bathrick</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beloved Sister Eunice Bathrick,— prayers and provender hinder no..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Beloved Sister Eunice Bathrick,— prayers and provender hinder no...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon, 1882" TEIform="index"/> Mount Lebanon, 1882</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Beloved Sister Eunice Bathrick,— "Prayers and provender hinder no man's journey" is a
                                Spanish proverb. I am going to prove it this morning by writing you. We are remodeling,
                                or repairing our Old Believer's dwelling house. They did well with it. We are trying to
                                do better. This is about the sixth time we have made the attempt. 1st. We put an
                                addition to the North end, in which is our beautiful Meeting Room. 2nd. We dug a cellar
                                under the North part of the house, in which we put a Boiler for heating the whole house
                                with steam. The steam also goes to and warms the Sister's Shop, some six rods away.
                                Heavy iron Radiators, weighing about (500 lbs., have done good service in warming 26
                                rooms and keeping the house from blowing over by the powerful East winds that used to
                                tumble down the mountain like a cataract of water, until arrested by the growth of the
                                Union Grove, containing some 70 varieties of trees. Now we have peace, when the East
                                wind roars only a short distance away. 3rd. We added a story to the top of the house by
                                merely raising the ridge 2, or 3 feet and putting on a flat, instead of a steep roof.
                                4th. We added to the South end of the house, rooms for the Elders and Deacons to labor
                                and lodge in. 5th. Outside, we built a Rain-water Cistern that receives the water from
                                three large and two small roofs. 6th. We are digging the whole length of the house, on
                                the East side, 10 feet wide, from 8, to 13 feet deep. This will make Coal Reservoirs,
                                one at the North and one at the South end of the house, with an Oven in the middle,
                                adding space to the Kitchen and Bakeroom. Two old single brick Chimneys we take down and
                                build one good double brick chimney in place of them— connect the fire from Boiler and
                                Oven with the new chimney at the South end, by 73 ft of 19 inch Tena Cotta Flue Pipe,
                                under ground. Why. should we be bound by matter'' In the Spirit World, the material
                                elements are more plastic than here. Progressive minds can change, model and remodel to
                                express their inward thoughts in outward things, quite easily. But dull, sleepy souls
                                can have every thing "just as it used to was"—as long as the}' please. Time, there, is
                                condition. There are souls in the spirit spheres, who remain, for age upon age, in the
                                same state— Jesus visited some of these long ago people . Then they saw a great light
                                and heard the last trump, saying "Awake, theu,that sleepeth, and arise from the dead,
                                and Christ shall give thee light." Some did awake, saw, heard and went up one degree.
                                But you, dear Mother Eunice, will never thus die.— You are Resurrected—The body clogs
                                your spirit somewhat, but just as soon as you drop it "Glory to the Righteous" will be
                                the first salutation you will recognize—Friends will flock around you like doves to the
                                windows, and after a little rest, amid much rejoicing, you will have your field of labor
                                assigned to you. Work will be given that will be worship. To do good, to less favored
                                ones, will be your meat and drink. Love from all of the North Family.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/> DEATHS</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Whitney, Abraham" TEIform="index"/>Abraham Whitney
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Whitney, Abraham" TEIform="persName">Abraham Whitney</persName>, at Shirley, Mass., Aug. 9.
                                Age 97 years, 4 months. Was a musician in the war of 1812. Had been with the Society
                                about 67 years. A very worthy brother.</p></div3></div2><pb n="212" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>JUVENILE</head><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fable: the wolf and the crane" TEIform="index"/>FABLE. The Wolf and the Crane</head><p TEIform="p">A wolf having a bone stuck in his throat, hired a crane, for a large sum, to put her head
                                into his throat and draw out the bone. When the Crane had extracted the bone, and
                                demanded the promised payment, the Wolf, grinning and grinding his teeth, exclaimed:
                                "Why, you have surely already a sufficient recompense, in having been permitted to draw
                                out your head in safety from the month and jaws of a wolf." In serving the wicked,
                                expect no reward, and be thankful if you escape injury for your pains.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Aesop" TEIform="persName"/>Aesop</byline></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I can and I will" TEIform="index"/> I CAN AND I WILL</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">I CAN AND I WILL. How many, boys there are who can, but never do, because
                                        they have no will-power, or if they have, do not use it! Before undertaking to
                                        perform any task you must carefully consider whether you can do it, and once
                                        convinced that you are able to accomplish it, then say, "I will do it," with a
                                        determination that you will never give up till it is done, and you will be
                                        successful. The difference between "Give up" and "I cant," and "I can and I
                                        will," is just the difference between victory and defeat in all the great
                                        conflicts of life. Boys, adopt your motto, "I can and I will," and victory shall
                                        be yours in all life's battles. "lean and I will" nerves the arms of the world's
                                        heroes to-day, in whatever department of labor they are engaged. "I can and I
                                        will" has fought and won all the great battles of life and of the world. I know
                                        a boy who was preparing to enter the junior class of the New York University. He
                                        was studying trigonometry, and 1 gave him three examples for his next lesson.
                                        The following day he came into ray room to demonstrate his problems. Two of them
                                        lie understood, but the third—a very difficult one— he had not performed. I said
                                        to him : -'Shall I help you?" "Mo sir," he answered, "but I can and will do it,
                                        if you will give me a little more time." 1 said : "1 will give you all the time
                                        you wish." The next day he came into my room to recite another lesson in the
                                        same study. "Well, Simon, have you worked that example?" "No, Sir," he answered,
                                        "hut I can and I will do it, if you will give me a little more time."
                                        "Certainly; yoix shall have all the time you desire." I always like those boys
                                        who are determined to do their own work, for they make our best scholars, and
                                        men, too. Again Simon entered my room, I knew he had it, for his whole face told
                                        the story of his success. Yes, he had it, notwithstanding it had cost him many
                                        hours of the severest mental labor. Not only had he solved the problem, but what
                                        was of infinitely greater importance to him, he had begun to develop
                                        mathematical powers which, under the inspiration of "I can and I will" he has
                                        continued to cultivate, until to-day he is professor of mathematics in one of
                                        our largest colleges, and one of the ablest mathematicians of his years in our
                                        country. My young friends, let your motto ever be, "if I can, I will." </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New York evangelist" TEIform="index"/>New York Evangelist</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondences" TEIform="index"/>Letter Box</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Children;—You are sowing on the field of..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Dear Children;—You are sowing on the field of...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Connecticut, Enfield, May, 1882" TEIform="index"/> Enfield, Conn. May, 1882</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Children;—Yoti are sowing on the field of life. Be sure that the sesd is good. Now
                                is the time to sow seeds of truth and virtue. Golden opportunities are often not valued
                                till they are gone. Sowing "wild oats" is a poor investment; sowing to the spirit yields
                                a good return for expenditure. You cannot sow "tares" and reap wheat. You cannot walk
                                the broad road and the narrow path at the same time. You are sowing the seeds of life
                                and happiness, or of death and misery. "You'll surely reap the harvest from the seed you
                                daily sow; you scatter thorns or roses, what you cultivate will grow." "Thorns never
                                bear figs nor thistles grapes." Each field produces a harvest of the seed sown; each act
                                of your lives is a seed sown, which will produce a crop, and the harvest will be the
                                same as was the sowing, not something else. If you sow "tares" you will reap vices. "One
                                year's weed, sevren year's seed." Let the product of your lives be such as you will be
                                proud to garner. Be pure, then each act will be a fruitful seed. Sow the seeds of truth
                                and virtue, then the blossoms will be <pb n="213" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 213 the
                                perfect ones of hope and cheerfulness, and the fruit, real happiness and joy. "If you
                                sow the seeds of sin, corruption youwilj gather in : if you to the spirit sow, life
                                eternal you will know." Think not lightly of these things. Guard well the gaps through
                                which temptation enters your souls. There is a powerful incentive to gain the
                                overcomer's regard. There is honor and eternal life before you. Your hearts are rich in
                                possibilities, but as you sow you will reap golden grain q,r anxious weeds. Your
                                brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our Dear S. ;—Your oft repeated request for..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Our Dear S. ;—Your oft repeated request for...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New Hampshire, Shaker Village" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Village, New Hampshire</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Our Dear S. ;—Your oft repeated ¦ request for a letter has not fallen upon a dull ear,
                                nor appealed to a heart unconcerned in your welfare. We never look upon you without
                                hoping and earnestly desiring that you may ever be an honor in the Virgin Church;
                                unspotted, unblemished, ever growing, and finally ripening into a glorious spiritual
                                womanhood,—a fruit which shall be acceptable to your Father and Mother in God. Your
                                earthly parents have given you in prayerful dedication upon the altar; it remains with
                                you to consummate the sacrifice. There is no power on earth able to overthrow your
                                foundation if it is fixed upon heavenly principles; if you daily commit your life to God
                                through prayer, earnest trust and simple obedience. These are the safe guards of youth;
                                the companions of middle life; and the staff of old age. Be wise in the improvement of
                                your time. Learn to accept life's trials and obligations in such a way, that they will
                                serve to refine the mind and polish the manners. In the time being, they may seem of but
                                little account ; but as the days and years pass away, you will find that interest is
                                borne to you in the degree only, that you have accumulated, grain by grain, your
                                treasure. If you improve all the little opportunities for culture, as they come to you,
                                and every day offers them, j'ou will thereby enlarge yotir capacity for doing good in
                                whatever field you may be called to labor. Every opportunity neglected is a seed sown
                                for future repentance. Let us just here transcribe a few lines# which we once came
                                across, entitled "Opportunity." "Say who art thou with more than mortal air Endowed by
                                Heaven with gifts and graces rare, Whom restless, winged feet forever onward bear? Ii.m
                                occasion—known to few, at best, And since one foot upon a wheel I rest, Constant my
                                movements are—the}7 cannot be repressed. Not the swift eagle in his swiftest flight Can
                                equal me in speed, toy wings are bright ; And man who sees them waved is dazzled by the
                                sight. Whom then so close behind thee do 1 see? Her narne is Penitence ; and Heaven's
                                decree Hath made all those her pro}-, who profit not by me. And thou, O mortal, who dost
                                vainly fly These curious questions, thou dost not descry That now thy time is lost, for
                                I am passing by ! Is not this a beautiful portrayal of the sad idea of lost
                                opportunities? A motto suspended in tlie Ironing room, which has attracted our attention
                                many times suggesting thought, reads thus; "Our life is what we make it,"—Our dear young
                                friend, may your life be made happy by cheerful obedience to divine precepts, by fixing
                                your affections upon enduring, heavenly things, rather than upon earthly objects and
                                perishable pleasures. The latter promise much, while they confer the least; the
                                indulgence only widens the distance between the soul and its eternal peace. Could we
                                picture your future as that of an earthly queen, the position would be far inferior in
                                our estimation, to that of our sweet angel sister, clad in robes of purity, and wearing
                                the coronet of virtue, this, we anticipate for our Sister. Hold on to Truth, it will
                                outride all trial; hold on to Purity, it is the gem of all gems; the pearl of great
                                price, the passport to the courts of the redeemed in Heaven, where you shall continue to
                                grow in the love and favor of the Highest Intelligence. We shall ever love and pray for
                                you. Your Sister</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Martin, E." TEIform="persName"/>E. Martin</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A young clergyman having preached for Dr. South, one day..." TEIform="index"/>
                            A young clergyman having preached for Dr. South, one day...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A young clergyman having preached for Dr. South, one day, was anxious to get a word of
                            applause for his labor of love. The grave doctor, however, did not introduce the subject,
                            and his younger brother was obliged to bait the hook for him. "I hope, sir," he said, "I did
                            not weary your people by the length of my sermon today V" "No, sir, not at all; nor by the
                            depth either." The young man was silent.</p></div2><pb n="214" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Household" TEIform="index"/>The Household
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Household is a Journal devoted to the interests of the American House-wife. Geo. E.
                                Cbowxix, Editor. BrattleboroVt. Its departments are The Veranda, Drawing Room,
                                Conservatory, Nursery, Library, Music, Dispensary, Dressing Room, Dining Room, Kitchen
                                and Parlor. Every Department is abundantly filled with interesting &amp; instructive
                                matter, and cannot be otherwise than an ever present aid to those who are so fortunate
                                as to enjoy its presence. Terms, $1.10 per. year. Single copy, 10 cents.
                                </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Universal republic of labor and learning" TEIform="index"/>Universal republic of labor
                                and learning</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prindle, George" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The Universal
                                Republic of Labor and Learning, by George Prindle. The work is addressed to those who
                                love truth, purity and pacific progress.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Quiz" TEIform="index"/>Quiz
                            </head><p TEIform="p">"Quiz," A Meekly Journal for the Family. Edited
                                by Florence I. Duncan. Devoted to Fun, Fancy, Family, Education, Progress &amp;
                                Eumanity. By Quiz Publishing Co. .1012, Walnut St. Philadelphia. $2.50 per year.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal" TEIform="index"/>Phrenological journal
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Phrenological Journal. Aug. Pub. by Fowler and Wells, 753 Broadway, N. Y. Contents. A.
                                Wilford Hall, author of the problem of human Life,—with Portrait, is conscience Innate?
                                Silk Culture and the silk worm, Illustrated. Gen. Garibaldi, with Portrait, Historical
                                Problems, Alexander H. Stevens, with Portrait, Errors in the government of children,
                                (roinginto Business, The Pulse and its significance, The gloomy Brother, Skin diseases,
                                Notes in Science and Agriculture, Poetry, Editorial. Terms $2.00 per year.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/>Hall's journal of health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Hall's
                                Journal of Health .July. Pub. by E. H. GlBBS A. M., M. D. No. 135 Eighth St., near
                                Broadway, N. Y. Contents, Pneumonia, Care of children, Health Capacity, Facts worth
                                rernemberiug, Feeding Horses, Pure water, Servant Girls, Human Health, Ventilation,
                                Insanity, A sick mind, The aim of Life, The human Teeth, Sleep, Finger nails, Remedy for
                                Cough, Throat ail etc., etc. Terms $2 a year. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Herald of health" TEIform="index"/>Herald of health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">  
                                Herald of Health. August. Pub. byM. L.
                                Holrrook M. D. 13 and 15 Laight St., N. Y. Contents. Hygienic Habits of the Hindoos,
                                Rural Wells, Deformities transmitted, Why some women are not strong, Vivisection. Our
                                exercise. Causes of Nervousness, Topics of the Month, Sanitary Charity, Shaker
                                Longevity, Anti Malarious plants, etc., etc. Studies in Hygeine 3TOB WOMEN, Medical
                                studies for women. Sanitary science in a university, Diet for Invalids, Two ways of
                                Living, etc. etc. Terms $1.00 a Year.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rip Van Winkle" TEIform="index"/>Rip Van Winkle
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> RIP VAX WINKLE AGAIN. The ever-delightful "Rip Van Winkle" is "waking up" lately in tens
                                of thousands of American homes where only his fame has heretofore entered. The Useful
                                Knowledge Publishing Company, New York, has published this and other of the famous
                                sketches of Washington Irving in an exquisite little volume, as beautiful as often finds
                                a place in the homes of ordinary mortals, and at a mere pittance in price,—15 cts. in
                                Utility binding, 25 cts. in cloth, 35 cts. in half Russia, and 40 cts. in extra cloth,
                                red line, gilt edges. These are being scattered broadcast as specimens of the quality of
                                book making and of the marvellously low prices of this new publishing company; and they
                                are winning for them the friendship of tens of thousands who delight in beautiful books
                                as well as in cheap and good literature. Enterprising booksellers will supply their
                                publications, and club agents and canvassers are wanted in eveiy county and town, to
                                whom very unusual terms and facilities are given. Catalogues with specimen pages and
                                terms will be sent upon request. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="National Associated Press" TEIform="index"/>The National Associated Press
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> The National Associated Press, to which The Boston
                                Daily Globe and Sunday Globe belong, has recently been reorganized, and has leased a
                                special wire from New York to New England of the Western Union Telegraph Company. On
                                Monday, August 14, The Boston Globe begun to receive its general news on a wire which
                                runs directly into its editorial rooms from New York, the great centre of news of all
                                kinds. Two or three papers in'the country have special wires to Washington, but we
                                believe this is the first instance in American journalism where a daily newspaper has
                                been able to secure its general news on a special wire into its editorial rooms.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>House-hold</head><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Use wire-rope for clothes-line..." TEIform="index"/>Use wire-rope for clothes-line...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Use wire-rope for clothes-line. It saves annoyance, is cheaper in the longrun, and much
                                more convenient</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good cookies" TEIform="index"/> GOOD COOKIES</head><p TEIform="p">3 cups of sugar 3 eggs 1 cup sour cream 1 teaspoonful saleratus 1 " cream tartar Flour to
                                stiffen, roll thin, or drop, bake in a hot oven</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To repair cracks in walls" TEIform="index"/> To Repair Cracks in Walls</head><p TEIform="p">—Equal parts of plaster of Paris and white sand, such as is used in most families for
                                scouring purposes, mixed with water to a paste, applied immediately and smoothed with a
                                knife or a flat piece of wood will make the broken place as good as new. The mixture
                                hardens quickly, so that it is best to prepare but a small quantity at a time.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Exchange" TEIform="persName"/>Exchange</byline></div3><pb n="215" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Breathing dirty air" TEIform="index"/> Breathing Dirty Air</head><p TEIform="p">—Think of the air of church, theater and crowded parlor. Go into such from the fresh air
                                an hour after the company has assembled. How heavy the air with personal affluvia and
                                rebreathedbreath. Pah! these delicate women have no thought of what they are doing.
                                Offer such an one a cup of ditch water; would she drink it? Would she drink it if it
                                contained even a speck? No. And yet think of it: in unventilated rooms and crowded
                                assemblies, we inhale dirty air—air which has washed out other lungs than ours, some of
                                them probably in 11 state of disease ! Such air contains personal impurities, particles
                                from the lungs, uncleanly odors. Such air drawn into sensitive lungs—lungs which are
                                only waiting to spring into inflamed conditions—creates disease. God gives us pure air.
                                Is it not a sin and a shame that we do not keep it pure?</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Osgood, Hamilton" TEIform="persName"/>Dr. Hamilton Osgood</byline></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sick room" TEIform="index"/> The sick room</head><p TEIform="p"> should be quiet, cleanly, and well aired. Label all medicines. Poison should be placed
                                above the reach of children. A good nurse has a very steady hand, a clear head, and a
                                kind heart; she is not talkative or nervous. Avoid arguments with the sick; do not tease
                                them with business ; do not sit or lean on the bed. If a friend calls on a patient their
                                stay should be very short. The practice of visiting the sick on the Sabbath is a very
                                poor one ; that day often thus becomes the most fatiguing of all of them. As a general
                                thing do not go into a sick room unless you go to help and not to talk. Do not deceive
                                the sick; deceit breeds suspicion: they will worry lest you are "keeping something from
                                them." To persuade the dying that they will recover is treason against the interests of
                                the soul. It soothes and cools a fevered patient to wash them with warm water in which
                                saleratus or soda has been dissolved.</p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A correspondent replies to an inquirer..." TEIform="index"/> A Correspondent</head><p TEIform="p">replies to an inquirer, that chestnuts properly prepared, make an unrivaled addition to
                                puddings, maccaroni, potatoes, and many other articles. In this respect they are
                                superior to the cocoanut, having a finer flavor and being more digestible. They are used
                                in the East for stuffing poultry, and are admirable for this purpose.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Scalds, and burns" TEIform="index"/> Scalds, and Burns</head><p TEIform="p">, and how to treat them. The very simple remedy which we give has been thoroughly tried
                                in our Society, for burns and scalds, both severe and light. It gives precedence, in our
                                esteem, to all other articles, for its superior curative effects, its simplicity and
                                cheapness. It would be well for every housekeeper, especially, where there are children,
                                to keep on hand a vial of this mixture for any emergency. Take any quantity of linseed
                                oil. according to the extent of surface burned, add to this, lime water, stirring all
                                the time until it changes to a whitish color and becomes about the consistency of thick
                                cream. Have also, prepared cotton-batting sufficient to cover the inflamed surface, upon
                                which spread the mixture evenly and quickly; see that every spot showing the least
                                inflaniation, is closely covered with the dressing, and there will be but little pain
                                and a speedy cure. In many cases no other dressing would be necessary. If the burn is
                                severe, it would require a longer time to heal and need a frequent application. Should
                                the cotton get dry. remove, and wet in the preparation, covering the surface again as
                                quickly as possible from the air. Continue this treatment until the inflamation has
                                subsided and no farther difficulty need be apprehended. This treatment is equally good
                                for frost bites.—Canterbury N. H. </p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fowls" TEIform="index"/> Fowls</head><p TEIform="p"> seem exceedingly grateful for the gift of cold water. They never swallow a drop of it
                                without turning up their eyes to heaven.</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sour milk" TEIform="index"/> Sour milk</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> Sour milk and butter-milk are excellent food for all kinds of poultry,
                                        especially turkeys, ducks and geese. When thickened with shorts, bran or meal,
                                        it is very nourishing diet for young fowls.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Exchange" TEIform="index"/>Exchange.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Leg weakness" TEIform="index"/> Leg weakness</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Leg weakness may be prevented or cured by giving in the feed ateaspoonfulof
                                        cayenne pepper and one of sulphate of iron (copperas) for every dozen fowls,
                                        once in two weeks, and continued until cured. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Exchange" TEIform="index"/>Exchange.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Feed your poultry" TEIform="index"/> Feed your poultry</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Feed poultry on raw onions, chopped fine, mixed with other food, about twice
                                        a week. It is better than a dozen cures for cholera. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Exchange" TEIform="index"/>Exchange.</bibl></cit></p></div3><pb n="216" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Here am I" TEIform="index"/> 'HERE AM I.'</head><p TEIform="p">Canterbury,N. H. 1. O Father, with the signet Of thy undying love, For2. Wouldst Thou
                                direct me thither O'er yon tempestuous flood, My 3. Speak, Lord, thy servant heareth,
                                And gladly will obey; Whatever seal my spirit, That I thine own may prove, faith in Thee
                                is anchored, Thou knowest my best good, e'er Thou wouldst, my Father, Make known to me,
                                I pray. Teach me to And when I Whatever know Thy voice, Though tempests may defy; hear
                                Thy call O may I e'er reply cares oppress, Whatever int'rests try, Let With I'll me be
                                clothed with grace To answer, true submissive heart My Father, trust my all with Thee
                                And answer, 'Here am. I." Here am I." Here am I."</p></div3></div2><pb id="p29" TEIform="pb"/><!-- 
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]<pb id="p30"/>
                            <pb id="p31"/>
                            <pb id="p32"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>