<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2809" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">20</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">28</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">9</biblScope><date value="18980901" TEIform="date">September 1898</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">129-144</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="28" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="9" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
THE
MANIFESTO
 1898.
A CONCISE HISTORY OF THE
SHAKERS.
Just Published.     The book is printed
A SUMMARY VIEW
OF  THE
 church,
OK
"United   Society   of  Believers"
It treats of the Rise and Progress of the
with large type  and on excellent paper.   Society,  together with the general Principles of the Faith and Testimony.
It contains  130 pages and has                                             Price   50 els.
ILL USTRA TIONS                             THE ALTRUIST^
of the Shakers and their          Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is publisht by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
The work gives quite an extended ac-   live and work together, and hold all their
property in common,  all the men   and
count of the Several SOCIETIES, their   women having equal rights in electing officers and deciding all business affairs by
organization and general management.         their majority vote.      50 cents  a year;
Price   50 cts.         specimen copy free.    Address A. Longley, 1719 Franklin Ave, St. Louis, Mo.
BRIEF EXPOSITION
OF  THE
Principles and Regulations
of the
SOCIETY   OF   BELIEVERS.
Price, 10 cts.
AND
SHAKERISM.
A synopsis of Theology of the United   Society  of   Believers  in   Christ's
Second Appearing.    Illustrated.
By Giles B. Avery.
Price,  15 cts.
SEPTEMBER,
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
A reprint from the Journal of HygeioTherapy and Anti-Vaccination is at hand, entitled Mental Influences in the Healing of the
Body.   Price 10 cts.   T. V. Gifford, M. D., M. S.
Kokomo, Ind.
In Frank Leslie's Popular Monthly for
August, the United States Army is appropriately at the front, in an admirably illustrated
article by Frederick S. Daniel.   The development of our Army from colonial times to the
present day is picturesquely traced, and
American military warfare in general is well
described.   A most fortuitous timeliness favors the fine, up-to-date portraits of Generals
Miles, Shatter, Merritt, Otis, Breckinridge,
Graham and others.   Blanca de Freyre Tibbits gives some highly interesting personal
reminiscences, with family photographs, of
Don Carlos, the chivalrous Pretender to the
throne of Spain.   A holiday in Antigua, one
of the quaintest of the British West Indian
islands, is described by Lillian D. Kelsey.
"War Envelopes," by W. G. Bowdoin, and
"Pheasant Shooting," by Howard Paul, are
among the minor articles; and Mr. Wilf. P.
Pond tells the boys, in a thoroughly practical
manner, how to build boats.   The Andrew
Jackson series draws to a close with Mary B.
Donelson Wilcox's second paper upon Rachel
Donelson Jackson; while The Jews of the
United States, by Abram S. Isaacs, is the latest of the Religious Denomination series.
The American city described and illustrated
this month is Kansas City, Mo.   Of fiction
Frank Leslie's Popular Monthly always
gives a liberal supply.   The current August
number includes, besides Frances S. Williams's serial, Marie Tremaine, complete short
stories by Gilberte Holt, F. Hinton, and
others.   The juvenile department, and J. Frederick Thome's literary chat are excellent.
Wilhelmina, who is to be crowned Queen of
the Netherlands on September 6 next, lias
personally sent to Mr. Bok, the editor of The
Ladies' Borne Journalhimself a Hollander by
birthone of her private portraits for publication in the next number of his magazine.
It is the last portrait which will be taken of
the little lady before her coronation, and will
be printed in connection with a specially prepared sketch, showing the personality of the
first Queen of Holland from every point of
view.
Mr. George Kennan's Story of the War, now
appearing in The Outlook, is constantly
growing in interest.   One of his latest letters
takes up the subject of the management of
the Florida camps and the starting of the
Shatter expedition.   Mr. Kennan treats this
important topic freely and frankly, but with
great fair-mindedness, admitting all possible
excuses, and yet pointing out many ways by
which prudence and foresight could have
avoided irritating delays.   Mr. Kennan is
now actually in Cuba, and his comments on
the Santiago campaign will be awaited eagerly.   ($3 a year.   The Outlook Co., 287 Fourth
Ave. New York.)
Ex-Senator John J. Ingalls, of Kansas,
whose fame as a brilliant writer, a man of remarkable scholarship and literary attainments, is even greater than that of the distinguished senator, announces anew book on the
subject of the American-Spanish-Cuban War.
It is entitled America's War For Humanity in
Picture and Story.   It is published by the N.
D. Thompson Publishing Co., of St. Louis, Mo.
and is an exhaustive discussion of the causes
of the war, and an equally exhaustive history
of its incidents, and a brilliant analysis of the
famous characters conducting it.   It promises
to be the one great and popular work called
forth by this wonderfully interesting national episode.   Whatever Senator Ingalls touches
he adorns; and this book shines and sparkles
in the light of his genius.   The present work
is worthy of his genius, and will be a monument to his fame.   The subject now so engrosses the popular mind as to forecast for
this book a sale that will be universal.   It
will be sold by subscription only, and the canvassing samples are now ready for agents.
We advertise it in another column.
The Scientific American for August is a
digest of naval knowledge up to date, interesting alike to the warlike and the peaceloving.   Its illustrations alone traced from
week to week are a pictorial national history
in themselves, and add to this excellent prose
articles following up the avenues of modern invention, manufactures, art and science, and
you have an idea of the worth of this indispensable journal.   Munn & Co. N. Y.$3.00 a
year.
Word and Works for Sept. contains this
significant line; "Just trust in the Lord and do
right."   Is this not an excellent rule for reestablishing peace after disagreement?   All
is successful that rests on this foundation.
This good paper is read with interest at our
Office.   $1.00 a year10 cts. single copy.
A Visit to the
of EAST CANTERBURY,   N. H.
Price,  15 cts.
Address   H. C. Blinn,
East Canterbury, N. H.
BY
LLOYD H. CHANDLER. U.S.N--><pb n="129" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Am I a christian?" TEIform="index"/>AM I A CHRISTIAN?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, Jessie" TEIform="persName"/>By Jessie Evans.</byline><p TEIform="p">TTTE live in a day of adulteration and deception. In the market that VV which is warranted to
                            be "absolutely pure" is proved to contain foreign elements, and an article whose manufacture
                            costs so much is deemed cheap at a price twice its real value. The mercantile world seems to
                            be a race for shrewd bargains, and the shrewdest are its heroes. This deceptive policy has
                            found its way into the religious world to quite as alarming an extent. What can be more
                            indiscriminate than the use of the term Christian ? Under its sanctity thousands of
                            denominations have sprung up, each claiming the nearest kinship to Christ's doctrine yet
                            each in turn dissenting from the creeds of other churches. Catholic and Protestant alike
                            hold dear the name of Christ and before the Christian altar the world nominally bows the
                            knee. We put the question here and there : Are you a Christian? and we receive either a
                            ready affirmative or at least, "I hope so." Only those who have outwardly fallen from the
                            world's approved standard of moral rectitude shrink from meeting the question. But the lower
                            tJie standard before which we answer this vital question, the better appears our personal
                            standard and the freer is the response. A deep conception of the true meaning of the word
                            Christian leads us to pause ere we reply, and where the ideal in the mind accords with the
                            true type of Christhood, our heads bow in the spirit of the publican as we murmur, "God be
                            merciful to SEPTEMBER <pb n="130" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 130 THE MANIFESTO. me a sinner." It is a strange
                            fact that those who live nearest to Christ within make the least outward show of doing so.
                            They need no badge of discipleship, their influence speaks for itself . Many, very many of
                            us make a profession of following Christ, but there conies a time to us all when a public
                            profession of faith in God feels like the shadow, and our weary souls cry for the substance
                            of religion, the real possession of comfort and peace which the world can not take away and
                            over which the sorrows of earth have no control. Our experiences of the past teach us that
                            the nominal Christianity of creed, church, and tangible charities is, was, and ever will be
                            inadequate to meet the needs of the souls of humanity and to answer its cries for permanent
                            relief. Despite our church-going and our Bible-reading, the old hunger revives tho driven
                            off for the moment, the stubborn sorrow of the heart refuses to be soothed. Jesus said,
                            "Judge not that ye be not judged," but he left no need for his disciples to be thus
                            troubled, for he significantly added, "By their fruits ye shall know them." This leaves no
                            room for doubt or mystery. Like causes produce like effects. As the Christ was and is, every
                            perfect Christian must be; and only thus is the holy comfort which sustained Jesus through
                            his earthly ministry ensured. But we are proving from day to day to ourselves and to each
                            other that we are not Christian to a degree satisfactory to the light of our day, and the
                            pure principle is forcing its way up through the surgings of our national and individual
                            life and is condemning all that "savorest not the things that be of God." We are dualhuman
                            and divine lodging for a time in the same casket. We do much to render the former prosperous
                            and comfortablebut are there not further duties devolving upon us in behalf of the latter?
                            Is our citizenship complete without reference to the "city set upon a hill?" Whether we
                            invite it or not, there comes a time to us all when the highest intelligence we are capable
                            of receiving confronts us with real home thrusts. Opposite elements can not occupy the same
                            place at the same time. Flesh and spirit do not coexist. When the Christian element enters
                            the mind, it wages war instantly with its opposites. Christ is a synonym for all that is
                            holythe anointing spirit which rested upon Jesus when he stood confest in the Jordan. This
                            spirit comes to "set a man at variance against his father, and the daughter against her
                            mother and the daughter-in-law against her mother-in-law, and a man's foes shall be they of
                            his own household." It is in the seclusion of this "household" that the question quoted is
                            most truthfully answered. He who conquers there the suggestions of the selfish will and can
                            say, as did Jesus, "I came not to do mine own will but the will of him that sent me," is a
                            Christian wherever he may be found. And when you find him, he is hedged in by no dogma, he
                            wears no particular costume, he repeats no special creedhis life is "a well of living
                            water," his influence is a perpetual <pb n="131" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 131 inspiration,
                            and his "light shines," not from conscious effort, but from the vigor of his "good works."
                            His mind has fathomed a deeper current than the transient things of earth. With a keener eye
                            than his fellows, he has caught sight of the pearls far beneath, and the floating straw upon
                            the surface is forgotten as he dives after the priceless gem. The Christian's joy is
                            attained only by conscious suffering at the seat of the selfish life, for this reason "few
                            there be that find it." Jesus showed distinctly by his teaching that all would not and could
                            not accept his peculiar mission, and for those who gave no signs of comprehending his words
                            he exprest no anxiety. "His mission was to call mankind from the rudimental to a higher
                            lifefrom the natural, carnal, selfish, partial, to the spiritual, unselfish, universal and
                            Godlike." Those who had no light beyond the rudimental, enjoyed rudimental happiness and
                            were satisfied. But here and there in Jesus's time souls were touched by the superior
                            inspiration which emanated from his mind making even the "hem of his garment" sacred; and
                            despite the parables which he employed ' 'lest hearing they might hear," a few caught the
                            hidden message and like little Samuel of old their rest of mind was forever broken. That
                            holy truth has never left the earth. From generation to generation, the seed of Christ's
                            exceeding righteousness has been preserved, not by the majority it is true; but dropt from
                            heart to heart it has found lodgment here and there, and constitutes to-day the vital hope
                            of the race. In one of the Shaker Sermons written by Elder H. L. Eads is this passage : "Who
                            can stand up with his hand on his heart and his eyes turned toward heaven, and say, 'I am a
                            Christian ?' I venture the assertion that not one can be found." It is indeed a fine point
                            to draw the line between Christ' and Antichrist. Who shall decide between the sheep and the
                            goats? But the gentle Savior gives us this comforting assurance: "He that is not against us
                            is on our part," and yet again "He that is not with me is against me." As a Church, we dare
                            not bind our thought life down to a written creed, for the infinite can not be bounded by
                            the finite. Nothing less than the spotless Christ can be accepted as pattern. We dare not
                            justify evil in any degree on the grounds that Jesus did not really mean what he preacht
                            that had he lived in our day and in our land he would have modified parts at least of the
                            inexorable testimony he proclaimedas many take liberty to do. Further than this, we dare not
                            plead our inability to follow in his steps, for the G-od of our worship is infinite mercy
                            affording "strength according to our day." As a Church we testify to the world boldly that
                            our spiritual standard is the perfect Christian ideal, as mind expands to comprehend itas
                            individuals we still wrestle with the momentous question : Am I a Christian?the emancipation
                            of our higher nature from its earthly bondage is so gradual, so slow. The human and the
                            divine continually strive together and as long as they alternate our sincerity is marredbut
                            we are pledged never to recede. <pb n="132" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 132 THE MANIFESTO. We can see nothing
                            mysterious in the career of Jesus. From childhood to manhood, his mind was the arena of
                            noble triumphs over self-interests, until that glorious spirit was fully enthroned there
                            whose presence empowered him to say, "No man cometh unto the Father but by me." The
                            experience of each of his honest disciples must ever be the same, and if the disciplinary
                            processes are borne without compromise by our weak human nature, as was the case with the
                            perfectly developt character of the Savior, who shall say that the power of full and free
                            salvation will not be ours in a degree commensurate with the strife ? East Canterbury, N.
                        H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Persecutions of the early shakers" TEIform="index"/>PERSECUTIONS OF THE EARLY SHAKERS.</head><p TEIform="p">AS Samuel Johnson, a minister of the Presbyterian Church was engaged in prayer, several
                            persons hurriedly entered the building and rudely dragged the praying brother from the
                            meeting. After a mock trial before the British Justice, he was taken to Albany and charged
                            with saying,"People can not follow Christ and live in wars and fightings." For this remark
                            he was imprisoned in the jail of the old City Hall. Deacon Fairbanks of the village of
                            Harvard, Mass, was interested to have a mob drive the Shakers from the town, and procured
                            two barrels of cider for his company. Four ministers were chosen as a committee, and Zabdiel
                            Adams was selected as speaker. On meeting the Shakers, he remarkt; Are you willing to take
                            up arms against Britain? Elder William Lee replied,I have never killed a creature with a
                            gun, "in my life. But, said Adams,Are you friends to America? Yea, said Elder James
                            Whittaker;We are friends to all the souls of men. But, supposing, said Adams, that one of
                            your people should go into the war and should live to return to his home, would he not have
                            to confess it was a sin ? Yea, said Elder James, if he, himself, believes it to be a sin,
                            but we do not bind men's consciences. The speaker then turning to Aaron Jewett, said ;When
                            you confest your sins, did you not confess that going into the army, was a sin? Aaron
                            replied,I was so far from confessing it as a sin that I never once thought of it. The
                            Committee then returned to the mob and reported,We think the people better let the Shakers
                            alone. A mob of four hundred persons including ministers and deacons and honorable men of
                            Society, as well as a coarse and vulgar company, being armed with whips, canes and cudgels,
                            entered the village of the Shakers of Harvard, <pb n="133" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 133
                            Mass, and demanded the Elders to come forward and give themselves up. Many of the Shakex-s
                            were on their knees, in prayer to God, that they might be guided in the spirit of Christ.
                            The mob soon burst open the doors and roughly seizing the Brethren and Sisters, by their
                            garments, or by the hair, inhumanly dragged them from the house. In this company of Shakers
                            were some one hundred persons who came from other towns and even from other states, and
                            these the mob had decided to drive out of the place. The infirm and those advanced in age,
                            who did not walk so fast as their inhuman drivers thought proper, were rudely admonisht by a
                            severe stroke of a whip or some other instrument of torture. For three miles or as far as
                            the town line, the Shakers were whipt and kicked or beaten with canes and clubs. One brother
                            had his arm broken, and another had several teeth knocked out. Jonathan Bridges was whipt
                            nearly every step for a quarter of a mile, and became so faint that he fell by the side of
                            the road. Neither sex nor age was regarded in this indiscriminate lashing and beating. After
                            all these cruel persecutions, the Elders would kneel in prayer to God, with this
                            petition,"Father, forgive them, for they know not what they do."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Frost lessons" TEIform="index"/>FROST LESSONS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Calver, Amelia J." TEIform="persName"/>By Amelia J. Calver.</byline><p TEIform="p">ONE beautiful warm day in October, I wandered out among the vines and plants of our spacious
                            garden, on which so much arduous toil had been bestowed, hoping to find some of nature's
                            gifts which at this season even should have been left for us. Generous had been the sower's
                            hand, faithful the cultivator's; but lo ! far and wide was seen only destruction. A single
                            night of severe untimely frost had destroyed the hopes of days to come. "Oh" I exclaimed
                            "why did not the frost delay until the abundant fruitage had ripened. These beautiful warm
                            days are of no use now; the destruction is complete." And standing amid the frost-bitten
                            vines and fruits, I read two lessons of life which so imprest themselves upon me that they
                            remain indelibly stampt on memory's tablet. In the first lesson these vines seemed to me
                            like a circle of friends, living, growing and thriving together. The warm sun, the gentle
                            rain, the refreshing dews brought forth delicious fruits of promist prosperity and all went
                            well. But the storm came, the winds blew cold, self-control was lost and the cruel,
                            heartless word fell like the biting frost, and the tender fruits of love, peace and
                            confidence were destroyed. The storm past, the sun shone again, but the former growths of
                            beauty and peace, where were they? Only frozen things. <pb n="134" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 134 THE
                            MANIFESTO. Then I lookt further where I found herbage whose tops were destroyed yet whose
                            perennial roots would after a time, again thrive in the sun and dew, and I said, "It is not
                            all lost." There is a principle of growth in some hearts, which will outlive the chill,
                            forgive and forget the frost and grow and thrive as kindly as ever. But these useful tender
                            annuals seemingly lost to all love and forgiveness will they never revive? Ah comes a
                            happier thought. The spring will come again, we will "resow with worthier seed" and pray the
                            "God of the Harvest" to perfect the fruitage ere the chilling frosts destroy. That lesson
                            was reviewed and on another page I read a. still more impressive one. Here was a spot which
                            I likened to inexperienced youth. Under the kindly hand of care and cultivation the fruits
                            were fast ripening. But the watchful eye of experience knew that the reckless winds would
                            bring destruction in their wake, and endeavors were made to shield the tender fruits from
                            the destroyer's hand. But alas! not all would be thus shielded, but wandering out from the
                            clustering protection, with heedless independence were left a prey to the cruel frost, and
                            life, growth and usefulness were destroyed, and tho the sun shone warm, and the rains were
                            reviving the once fair fruit was blasted which might have continued its growth until
                            perfected, had they kept beneath the protection given. And again I said ; ' 'Are these all
                            lost too ?" And again I saw perennial piinciples which will repent the past and take on new
                            life and growth. Again I saw the soil for annuals resown, and I knew the "Lord of the
                            Harvest" would watch to nurture the tender growth. And as I studied these comparisons, I
                            thought O what happiness would be mine if I could so impress the young, the inexperienced to
                            stay beneath the kindly protection of obedience and of love, until age and experience shall
                            perfect the fruit beyond the danger of destructive frosts. How many heartaches would be
                            saved for those who see in purity and culture their only growth, and how much tender fruit
                            might be saved which seems uselessly lost. But thank God that in this day of enlightened
                            revelation there is no eternal doom. There is always a way back to the path of safety and
                            virtue. It is never too late to repent, and for those who strive with an earnest purpose,
                            there is always a helping hand. So with hope and courage let us look forward to the new
                            perennial growth,, and the tender thriving of new seed. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Jets from the fountain of inspirational thought..." TEIform="index"/>Jets from the fountain of inspirational thought...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Jets from the fountain of inspirational thought are as prisms through which to attract the
                            rays of divine truth.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, C." TEIform="persName"/>C. Alien.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nothing more detestable..." TEIform="index"/>Nothing more detestable...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Nothing more detestable does the earth produce, than an ungrateful man.</p></div2><pb n="135" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Silent path" TEIform="index"/>THE SILENT PATH.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Massey, Arthur E." TEIform="persName"/>By Arthur E. Massey.</byline><p TEIform="p">The Silent Path is best For seekers after Peace, It yields the soul sweet rest, From outside
                            thingsrelease! It bears us up to heights That far outvie each star, Revealing glorious
                            sights No earthly pain can mar. It links us with the angels Whose strength becomes our own ;
                            We hear their sweet evangels A celestial loving tone, Now borne upon the vernal breeze Of
                            unseen realmsyet near! We sink in rapture on our knees In praise to God, so dear! We thank
                            Thee, God, with all our heart For restful calm beyond compare, And that the same Thou may'st
                            impart To all our brethren,is our prayer. Narcoossee, Fla.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What is it to be spiritually minded?" TEIform="index"/>WHAT IS IT TO BE SPIRITUALLY MINDED?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stephens, Annie R." TEIform="persName"/>By Annie R. Stephens.</byline><p TEIform="p">HE who discovers new forces in nature that uplift humanity to higher altitudes, is a
                            benefactor to all times. A century ago the noble Franklin caught the lightning from the
                            cloud, and since then man has harnest this subtle force to do his bidding,a willing and
                            obedient slave. The first message flasht across the ocean was, "What has God wrought," and
                            well may we re-echo this when we think of the marvels of electricity. What electricity has
                            been to the nineteenth century, the power of mind will be a similar, if not a greater force
                            to the twentieth. Men have been thinking since the Creator endowed them with the faculty,
                            but the majority of mankind have tended downward instead of upward, they have thought from
                            the outer rim of being, instead of the divine center. Thought is a force, and all forces
                            unless directed in their legitimate channels are destructive. Full well we know the
                            destructive force of evil thought, in the lust, greed, selfishness and disease exprest in
                            human lives. "Who knoweth the spirit of man that goeth upward, and the spirit of the beast
                            that goeth downward to the earth?" That spirit that goeth upward is the power of <pb n="136" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 136 THE MANIFESTO. pure, exalted thought; and the spirit that goeth downward
                            to the earth, is the power of sensual thought that seeks gratification through the senses,
                            wasting the life forces that should be directed in the channel of holy desire*. Paul refers
                            to the "carnal mind" and to the "spiritual mind," when he says, "I find a law in my members,
                            warring against the law in my mind, and bringing me into captivity to the law of sin and
                            death." To those who would be spiritually minded, who seek to live on the higher plane ol
                            existence, the inevitable conflict must go on between the carnal and spiritual mind. Which
                            one of us can claim that on all occasions we think that which is purely upright ? Which one
                            of us can claim that our higher will holds in absolute control that mighty current,mind
                            force ? Who can claim that they have brought into subjection to the law of Christ, all the
                            turbulent elements of the soul? Few have risen to such altitudes. We are all pilgrims
                            seeking perfection, and may keep before us that bright hope, that we may yet be perfect,
                            even as our Father in heaven is perfect, tho it may require conflict after conflict, and a
                            life-long struggle before we know of the supremacy of the God-life within. "My mind to me a
                            kingdom is," said a great philosopher. How may we rule and reign in this kingdom of mind as
                            the absolute authority? ' How may we assume the rightful sovereignty over this vast domain,
                            that reaches from earth to the stars, from the finite to the Infinite ? "If thine eye offend
                            thee pluck it out;" this must mean if thy thought offend thee pluck it out, and cast it from
                            thee. Are we dissatisfied with our mental or moral states ? do we wish to reconstruct our
                            own souls that they may reflect more clearly the divine image within? then we must begin
                            with the smallest flaw in our characters; it may be a thought of vanity, of self, of envy,
                            no matter what it be if it stands as a barrier between our soul and the light of truth. If
                            we have yet to learn, not only to control our thoughts, but to overcome evil with good by
                            transforming the low desire into the pure gold of spirituality, we are yet slaves, and not
                            conquerors in our own domain. The laurel-crowned victor of the coming age will not be the
                            blood-stained hero, but he who ruleth his own spirit; and in ruling his own spirit, man will
                            yet discover latent potencies within his own mind that will rise up and crown him king,
                            through which he will control all the forces of nature; for is he not made to have dominion
                            over all things ? When mankind realize that through their higher spiritual thought, they are
                            brought into oneness with the Infinite Spirit, they will be able to do all things through
                            the indwelling Christ. As light penetrates darkness and overcomes it, so the thought of good
                            is stronger than the thought of evil; and is it not the grandest truth of the age, that man
                            can so control and direct the powers of his mind, as to find the triumph of health over
                            disease, goodness over evil and truth over error? By correct thinking he may bring about
                            those Millennial conditions that bring forth love, wisdom and justice in the earth. <pb n="137" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 137 Down through the years men have hired preachers to
                            do their thinking for them, and relied upon them as infallible guides, instead of seeking a
                            knowledge of the truth that would make them free indeed. "We revert with pitying thoughts to
                            the serfdom of the body, but mental servitude is far worse. Mankind have been content to
                            drift with the downward current of thought; have tethered their Ship of Progress to the
                            shore of conservatism and filled it with the ballast of tradition, creeds and various forms
                            of ancient thought. A new age has dawned upon us, already we feel its thrilling tide of
                            life, awakening us to the consciousness of the life of God in the soul of man. A new thought
                            is rapidly filling the world, that ultimately will displace prejudice and selfishness, and
                            win human hearts over to altruism and brotherly love. It is astonishing to learn of the
                            various methods for spiritual culture adopted in all parts of the civilized world. The
                            "Whole World's Soul Communion" will yet, through the concentration of its silent, soulful
                            force, conquer the world to truth and righteousness. The increase of books, magazines on
                            topics pertaining to higher thought; and classes for mental and spiritual culture, predict
                            that thought, not swords; that ideas, not cannon are the conquering forces of the New Age.
                            What is it to be spiritually minded ? It is to keep the mind continually suffused with
                            uplifted thought; to keep the windows and doors of our mental mansions forever closed
                            against any inharmonious, intruding element. The wonderful power of mind has been likened to
                            a camera, that reproduces, on a rightly prepared plate, exact pictures of material objects ;
                            so the mind, with a greater exactness photographs all mental action, thoughts and ideas on
                            its plastic substance. Would we hang the corridors of our souls with beautiful pictures ?
                            then we must think that which is true and pure, image that which is beautiful and enduring.
                            By habitual contemplation of lofty ideals, we may make our mind a mansion to dwell in, a
                            treasure-house to explore. "Mind is a thing of progress. It is made to grow, not to remain
                            stationary ; there is no limit to its knowledge and Grod-like capabilities. Exert it
                            strongly and wisely and it will soon stand among the sons and daughters of light, and shine
                            among the cherubim and seraphim of the eternal world." " Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cause and effect..." TEIform="index"/>Cause and effect...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Cause and effect are two ends of the same beamthe positive and negative extremities. If they
                            could be separated, both would cease to exist at once. But when a magnetic beam or rod is
                            separated, both parts assume the positive and negative qualities of the original rod. So
                            cause and effect tho ever so obscurely hidden among the mysterious manipulations of
                            environment are never separated in their final issue.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, O. C" TEIform="persName"/>O. C. Hampton.</byline></div2><pb n="138" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. SEPTEMBER, 1898. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is publisht by the
                            "United Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued
                            regularly by the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the
                            religious views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. Address all
                            communications to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. TERMS. .50 One copy one
                            year, postage paid. A cross in the margin will show that your subscription has closed.
                            Eemittances for subscription by Money Order should be on the Post Office at Concord, N.
                        H.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">July. Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. Thermometer. Rain. 1897. 14.3 15 in. 1898. 75.3
                                2.125 " Highest Temp, during this mo. 94 above 0. Lowest " " " " 48 " " Number of rainy
                                days " " 6 " " clear " " " 16 " " cloudy" " " 9 August, 1898. We have past the summer
                                solstice and shall soon be face to face with the autumnal equinox. It is arranged that
                                twice a year the days and nights are equal from pole to pole. There seems to be an aim
                                at a semblance of equality in mundane conditions, and as earthly arrangements are said
                                to typify the ethnical, ethical and spiritual relations of the human race, as
                                anticipated in the era of the great Millennium, when all shall stand on the plane of
                                equality, where there are neither rich nor poor; where all are partakers of the bounties
                                of kind Providence, "Where God shall wipe away all tears from their eyes; where there
                                shall be neither sorrow nor crying, neither shall there be any more pain; for the former
                                things are past away;" the conditions in this anticipated era of superlative happiness
                                will by far exceed all the deductions drawn from present mundane presentations. It is
                                well to have anticipations of future improved conditions of humanity, as it forms an
                                impetus to induce us to strive for its attainment. So let us be faithful in our day and
                                calling, that it may not be said of us as it was to the Church of the Laodiceans,"These
                                things saith the Amen, the faithful and true Witness, I know thy works, that thou art
                                neither cold nor hot. So then because thou art lukewarm, and neither cold nor hot, I
                                will spew thee out of my mouth." Well as to present conditions, we are favored so as to
                                have a plenty to eat and to drink. New potatoes are served as a change from those of
                                last year's growth. Peas have proved nearly a failure; but cultivated raspberries and
                                blackberries have done well and are relisht by the majority. Cherries have been abundant
                                and have engaged the attention of several pickers for many days. Apples and pears are
                                now in use. All of these with fresh vegetables are pleasant to our hungering appetites.
                                July has been a pleasant but rather dry month up to the 25th; since this date we have
                                had an abundance of rain. Harvesting of hay and grain is occupying the strength of hands
                                and teams. The potato and corn crops look splendid. The hay crop is excellent. The oats
                                are affected with rust, but they are well filled and are being cut. <pb n="139" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 139 We are anticipating a pleasant visit with Elder Henry C. Blinn,
                                who is now only four miles east of us. We expect before long to shorten that distance by
                                four miles. In the Church family here, all are up and in duty serving God with heart and
                                hands. Calvin G. Reed. North Family. August, 1898. Nearing the harvest time of the year
                                we ask, are we not continually in the harvest time of life? are we not reaping today
                                what we sowed yesterday, and can we look with pleasure to our future reaping? If we are
                                in the ever living present, we need not dread a dark shadowy future. Life comes to us as
                                we draw from living or stagnant wells. To lay down our spiritual energy, and think to
                                subsist upon what we have already garnered will not satisfy. The manna, in days of old,
                                needed to be gathered every day to meet the demands of the people, and the spiritual
                                manna should descend upon us continually or else our souls perish. But what of the
                                material harvest? Sixteen bushels of beans have been pickt and canned for winter use.
                                Blackberries are growing abundantly, careful training by good Brethren make it quite
                                easy picking, but never-the-less thorns and briers cause many an exclamation from young
                                hearts who have not learned as yet how to avoid the piercing sting. Fifty letters have
                                already been received in consequence of the recent article in "The Ladies' Home
                                Journal," some asking for further information, others as applicants into our home life.
                                We hope, through the guidance of divine wisdom, souls who are hungering and thirsting
                                for the bread and waters of spiritual life will feel thir needs supplied. Sarah J.
                                Burger. South Eamily. August, 1898. Again we pause in our daily occupation and find
                                leisure for Home Notes. Our hay crop is of the finest; all grains have yielded a
                                splendid harvest. Potatoes are superior in quality and plentiful in quantity compared
                                with last year's growth. We have some splendid blackberries and raspberries of home
                                cultivation, so find no&gt; need of borrowing or begging from the mountain heights tho we
                                greatly enjoy our rambles up the cragged peaks of the glorious hills in search of blue
                                berries, which are quite a failure this year. We have secured some and hope to make sure
                                of more in a few days. We learn that our Editor-in-chief, Elder Henry C. Blinn is just a
                                little way over the mountain with friends at West Pittsfield. We hope he will deem it
                                wise to call on his Mt. Lebanon friends before his return home. We are all anticipating
                                his coming in the near future. Eldress Annie Case, of the Watervliet South family, in
                                company with Mrs. Maggie Barthwick of Albany, made us a hurried visit one afternoon in
                                July. Sister Marion Scott, of the Sonyea family at Watervliet, made us a brief but
                                interesting visit a few weeks ago. We are ever glad to meet our friends from far or
                                near, all bring sunshine and brightness with them. Genevieve De Grata.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">August, 1898. The public press has recorded the translation of one more of the veterans
                                who battled for the releasement of our nation from the thralldom of chattel slavery, he
                                has joined the church triumphant Parker Pillsbury in his association with those valiant
                                souls Garrison, Philips and Sumner formed a host who were invincible and could not be
                                defeated. We have perused with a great deal of pleasure and profit "Acts of the
                                Antislavery Apostles," by his pen. The coming generation could be benefitted by the
                                study of those lives, reviewing their conflicts and their victories, preparing
                                themselves, to deal intelligently and with decision <pb n="140" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 140 THE
                                MANIFESTO. with the questions that to-day are demand ing a righteous adjustment. We have
                                had beautiful weather for our grain and hay harvest, some three weeks past during our
                                harvesting season without rain. While some other crops were needy the excellent quality
                                of this harvest will more than compensate. We will again speak approvingly of the
                                subject matter in the Aug. Manifesto. The excellent ideas there illustrated must have a
                                beneficial effect. Where one listens to a verbal sermon one hundred peruse it when
                                publisht where it can be circulated among the masses. The age is a reading one and tho
                                our Manifesto may occupy only a little of the space and time given to the perusal of the
                                ideas publisht and placed before the public some of which are wise and some otherwise;
                                yet we believe it has its mission and should be sustained not by caustic criticisms but
                                by holding up the hands of the editorial department in their efforts to place before the
                                public that which is for the benefit of the masses, and willing to give time and means
                                to forward this end. Long live The Manifesto and our veteran editor. Hamilton
                            DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">August, 1898. Among friends entertained the past month, was Mrs. Chestina Hutchinson
                                Wooster, who is engaged in the W. C. T. IT. work, and who gave us an excellent discourse
                                upon Christian Citizenship. The Christian citizen, she said, will not only support those
                                who preach the kingdom of God, but he will have it his duty to inaugurate that kingdom
                                by his own daily life,by his influence,all placed in the balance against
                                unrighteousness. There is corruption in high places. Men divorce their citizenship from
                                their religion. Their prayer and their act conflict. They choose among evils, of two
                                evils, sometimes the least, when they should discard both. In this holy war of
                                righteousness against unrighteousness, we need not so much be fighters as buildersmen
                                who live and act by a habit within, of definite convictions on the important questions
                                the people's lives, having the courage to advocate civic righteousness and defend its
                                cause. "Grand, square and upright" are the characters demanded to work for God and home,
                                who cease to be competitors and become comrades in the onward march toward grander
                                developments of manhood and Christian duty. We also had the pleasure of again welcoming
                                to his old home, our reverend father, Elder Abraham Perkins, of East Canterbury. As he
                                went among the inmates of his former home, his physical sprightliness and mental
                                activity convinced us that ninety-one years had dealt well with him, and that he had
                                wisely kept the vigor of life that yields untold soul wealth to the faithful pilgrim.
                                True it is, "When each fulfills a wise design, In his own orbit he will shine." George
                                H. Baxter.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Aug. 1898. Not for ten years, at least, has such a heavy crop of hay presented itself for
                                storage. We shall not pull down our barns "and build greater," however, tho ingenuity
                                has been taxt to its utmost to take advantage of all available space of shelter for the
                                same. The upland haying closed on the 15th inst. Early apples furnish abundant dessert,
                                and late varieties are to be not a whit behind except in time. We have occasion to be
                                very grateful that this New England staple is so prolific. The Baldwin, Virgin and
                                Porter varieties are especially full and fine. A large strawberry bed is gradually
                                establishing itself in the midst of the vegetable garden, and next year we may write
                                more particular statistics. Ensilage corn has far outstript the human race, being twelve
                                feet tall at present writing, and some one ventures the perti nent fact that it is
                                co(r)nstantly growing. <pb n="141" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 141 Three huge silos stand
                                gaping to receive it, but "patient waiters are no losers" in this case. A heavy crop of
                                peaches is weighing down the branches of the trees, but quite lifting us up at the
                                prospect. Peach year comes here only once in seven, so say old residents, hence is a
                                special favorite. Sisters visit neighboring beaches at this season to solicit patronage
                                for our manufactures. Eeports from them strike a chord not inharmonious with Home Notes
                                and we are glad to remember that in seeking first the kingdom of God and his
                                righteousness to us are ensured "all these things" necessary to maintain the
                                representation of that kingdom on the earth. Jessie Evans.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Narcoossee, Florida" TEIform="index"/> Narcoossee, Fla.</head><p TEIform="p">August, 1898. Notwithstanding the cold weather, the dry weather and the wet weather there
                                is plenty of life left in the old land of Florida. From nearly all sections of the state
                                comes the cheering news that the orange crop will be good. There was a large summer
                                bloom this year and the late crop will be quite large. Our work through the month of
                                .July has been long and arduous. It consisted of fencing a five hundred acre lot on the
                                south side of our lake, to be rented as pasture. The rounding up of our cattle called
                                for a week of hard labor on horseback. The remainder of the month between showers has
                                been filled by planting our crop of sweet potatoes, which is done by resetting the vines
                                or tops which are cut from 12 to 14 inches long. Our cattle, which have been free to
                                roam over our vast acreage, have stood the drouth far better than we expected. The fires
                                that were constant and almost over every part of our plantation destroyed large amounts
                                of feed and this caused the cattle to narrow down on the feeding grounds. Even the muck,
                                the best part of the farming land, took fire and in some places burned for months^
                                causing quite a sensation among the farmers as to their pasturage, but since the winter
                                rains have commenced and the fires have gone, the farmers begin to have a little hope
                                that the hard times are past, and the indications of returning prosperity are here. It
                                is true, the people here have but little money, but they are at work, and the crops of
                                peas, potatoes, hay and velvet beans are exceedingly large. Added to these the sale of
                                cattle which is now opened with Cuba, looks to be the salvation of the country, which is
                                a thing now hoped for. "As thrashing separates the corn from the chaff, so does
                                affliction purify virtue,'' a well-applied motto to the Florida pioneer from the first
                                day to the present time. It has been a thrashing work, and we have; realized very little
                                wheat from our labor. True! physically we are resurrected from the every winter sore
                                throat and all other lung diseases, with the exception of our good Sister Nancy Dow, who
                                has been troubled all her life, more or less with inflammatory rheumatism and believed
                                she could find the elixir of life by removing to Florida. It has, however, been a sad
                                mistake, Florida climate can never cure rheumatic people, and she now lies patiently
                                waiting the call of the Boatman topass over to the other side where she can enjoy a
                                fulness of health. Andrew Barrett.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="history" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Turnkey, no. 3" TEIform="index"/>THE TURNKEY. No. 3.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/>By Elder H. C. Blinn.</byline><p TEIform="p">The attempt of the blacksmith to play the dentist, far exceeded that of the shoemaker, and
                            proved a sad disaster to the patient. This case will be found illustrated in Fitch's Dental
                            Surgery, page 341 and is in part as follows ; "In the year 1830 one Mcllhenny of Back Creek,
                            Va. called on a blacksmith by the name of Snyder, for the extraction. of the upper second
                            molar, on the right side. Snyder was considered an adept at <pb n="142" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 142 THE
                            MANIFESTO. extracting teeth with the blacksmith's pincers. He had powerful muscles and was
                            well calculated to tear the teeth from their sockets. He seated his patient on the ground,
                            and holding his head back as in a vice, placed the pincers partly on the right tooth. Taking
                            the handles in both hands he gave a tremendous pull. The fangs of the tooth were greatly
                            bifurcated, and the jaw bones proved to be too weak for such a strain. Suddenly a part of
                            the jaw was torn away, and with it six of the sound teeth." A similar case to the above is
                            publisht in Harris' Dental Surgery, page 361. This operation like the above was at the hands
                            of a blacksmith and occurred in Jackson, N. C. "In attempting to extract one of the superior
                            molar teeth, he brought away a piece of the jaw, containing five other teeth." These extreme
                            cases, however, do not occur every day, which is our great consolation. It seems like a
                            fearful accident, and should warn every one to exercise great care, in whom they place their
                            trust. But the Turnkey in the hands of the dentist has also made some sad records, and two
                            and three teeth have been pulled from their sockets, when one only, should have been taken.
                            It is no wonder that Dr. Harris calls the key a "dangerous instrument, which is only fit to
                            mask the unskillfulness of the operator. It is one of the most defective of surgical
                            instruments and no practitioner of good sense, being convinced of its mode of action, would
                            attempt to employ it if he wisht to extract a nail from a hole, if he did not desire to
                            break the wall." An illustration of this inquisitorial key can be seen in Bell's Surgery,
                            Vol. 4, Plate 4(5 and on the adjoining page, the figures of two instruments that were
                            invented in Europe for the extracting of teeth. These last are nameless, but one of them is
                            an exact representation of the "Canthook" that is used by the lumbermen. It is fortunate for
                            those who have any teeth, that the above oider of dentists and their special instruments of
                            torture are becoming less and less. Under the management of the family physician, serious
                            accidents did not very frequently occur, but there were incidents not really pleasant, and
                            at the same time, to both physician and patient, not very agreeable. The case of the doctor
                            dentist who had his student in attendance to witness the extraction of some teeth, is to the
                            point. After a long preliminary lecture on the use of forceps, and the correct way of using
                            them, he remarks;"Now, you must do like this," and placing the for- ceps, on the tooth, he
                            made one motion and broke the crown from the root. An apology followed, and of course, the
                            fault was in the tooth. The student must understand that such cases, altho rare, would
                            sometimes occur, and could not, possibly, be avoided. The forceps were then prepared for
                            another tooth, and the student was to observe just how it was done, in order, even, to avoid
                            an accident like the first. The forceps were again adjusted, amid a flourish of words on
                            practical dentistry, and a first class job was to be the result. As the hand tightened on
                            the handles of the forceps, and a pressure was brought to bear upon the tooth, it broke from
                            the root exactly as did the first. After a few words, a few looks and a few gesticulations,
                            the student's lesson in dentistry ended for that time. Sometimes the physician met with
                            wellearned success. He says to his patient, "Sit down on the floor." Then taking the
                            patient's head between his knees, he reaches for his lance. With this he cuts the gums from
                            the tooth. It is a painful operation and especially, should the lance slip and cut an
                            unpleasant gash across the adjoining tooth. This operation over the physician passes to the
                            table for the purpose of preparing the "Turnkey." An old silk handkerchief is twisted around
                            the instrument to form a pad, that in breaking the tooth from its socket, the fulcrum may
                            not hurt the jaw too severely. <pb n="143" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 143 The doctor dentist
                            is now ready: the turnkey is ready, and the patient with his head between the knees of the
                            physician is also ready. The adjustment of this inquisitorial instrument occupies several
                            minutes. Possibly this bungling mass of rags and iron, and the doctor's fingers, which last
                            have been added to hold the ckiw in place, till the pressure was applied, are all in the
                            patient's mouth. All these may be removed for a second inspection, that he may be sure not
                            to pull two teeth instead of one. The claw and rags and fingers are again pusht into the
                            mouth, when with one vigorous turn of the key handle, the tooth is thrown upon the floor,
                            With all the dread of waiting for the several varied processes of preparation, and the
                            savage cruelty of tearing out the tooth, there is a fractional relief to know that the job
                            is over. Very few persons at the present day will share the experience of having a tooth
                            extracted with a "Turnkey" or Dentist's key or even with a lumberman's "Canthook." But for a
                            genuine specimen of first class torture, that is to be consummated in so short a time, this
                            form is especially recommended for trial. Indeed, laid on the shelf. This is the fate of
                            many of the instruments that have been used in the extracting of teeth. Especially true is
                            this of the "Turnkey" and "Dentist's Canthook," which may now be found only among the
                            curiosities of a cabinet. I have before me specimen of the above Dentist's tools, and regret
                            that I can not learn the name of the last one, unless it is the same as I have written. East
                            Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Farnum, Louisa" TEIform="index"/>TRIBUTE OF LOVE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Berne, Joseph L." TEIform="persName"/>By Joseph L. Berne.</byline><p TEIform="p">[ Written in Memory of Eldress Louisa Farnum, who
                            departed this life June 2, 1897. At White Water, Ohio.] 
                            Louisa Fabnum came among Believers with her mother when a small child, lived the life of a
                            Christian Believer, and died with the harness unrusted, a noble follower of Christ. Eldress
                            Louisa needs no tribute to her memory, her life was a perfect pattern of holiness, and her
                            gospel children can "rise up and call her blessed." If ever there was a truly good woman,
                            that was Eldress Louisa. I knew her well when I was a young man, and she was the Elder
                            Sister of the Center family. She managed all under her control with Christian love, above
                            all setting an example of what her faith was, by good works. I can see her now at her work,
                            always busy, a good word and pleasant face encouraging all that came in contact with her.
                            Her influence was unbounded and entirely unselfish, for the good of every one and the
                            Society at large. She was truly a wonderful woman and had her life been thrown anywhere,
                            among any people, her influence would have been felt and controlled the many, for Louisa
                            Farnum was not a common-place person, but endowed with sound sense and profound judgment.
                            Her labors of life are ended and she is called up higher. This truly good mother in Israel
                            has left her children in the gospel, many examples of patience and a holy life, that made
                            her countenance that of open truth. When I last saw Eldress Louisa, she had grown quite
                            feeble, but the fire of zeal was there yet and the same pleasant face bade me welcome. We
                            all loved her who knew her, whether among the Shakers or outside. She has gone to her
                            reward, and has indeed past many places of crusht hearts, and felt the bitings of the chisel
                            that moulded her life into that which was beautiful and grand, for I knew of many severe
                            trials, and deep waters of anguish her soul past through and came out of the fire refined.
                            She has faithfully workt and earned her everlasting reward. One of the brightest of stars in
                            God's Kingdom that ever graced the household of White Water, her journey is over, the burden
                            of life laid down, <pb n="144" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 144 THE MANIFESTO. and she has entered those
                            mansions of joy, prepared for the pure in heart in God's everlasting Kingdom. Memphis,
                        Tenn.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shadow of self" TEIform="index"/>THE SHADOW OF SELF</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">It is told of Michael Angelo, the greatest sculptor the world has ever known,
                                    that it was his habit to work much at night, when quiet hours gave him opportunity
                                    for the severest thought, which is so evident in all he wrought. He found, however,
                                    that night labor was not without its disadvantages. No matter where he placed his
                                    light, at some critical moment or in some unexpected place his shadow was sure to be
                                    thrown upon the statue he carved. But at last he hit upon a plan that did away with
                                    the difficulty. He fastened a candle to the stiff paper cap he wore while working,
                                    and then the light shone clear and full upon the portion of marble he was carving,
                                    with no shadow of himself flitting between his eyes and his work. There is a lesson
                                    here for all. The greatest hindrance to us as sculptors of life is this shadow of
                                    self which is so prone to fall in unexpected places, dimming our perception of the
                                    clear, sharp outlines of truth and duty, and spoiling by false proportions the
                                    dignity and beauty of the character we would portray as our own. To do a kind thing
                                    that we may be thought obliging, is to miss entirely the grace of the act, so far as
                                    we are concerned. To be generous for fear of being thought mean, is little if any
                                    better than downright selfishness. In short, to do right for any other reason than
                                    because it is right, is to fall short of the ideal, to make a false stroke on life's
                                    statue because the shadow of self has come between it and the light. Does some one
                                    ask, What is the light by which we may guide ourselves as day by day we chisel out
                                    character that must endure throughout eternity? There is but one answerChrist. And
                                    as the great sculptor placed his candle on the front of his cap while he wrought, so
                                    we must put Christ above our own preferences, our own wills. The clear shining of
                                    that Light upon each day's appointed tasks, and working ever in its radiance, we
                                    shall make no mistakes.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Young People's Weekly" TEIform="index"/>Young People's Weekly.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>OUR EXCHANGES.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Humane journal" TEIform="index"/>The Humane Journal
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Humane Journal is publisht in Chicago, by the Illinois Humane Society. It is a
                                beautiful little teacher of the law of kindness. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Firebrand" TEIform="index"/>The Firebrand
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Firebrand is publisht monthly by
                                the "World's Faith Missionary Association" and edited by C. S. Hanley. It has come out
                                in a beautiful new dress, and the whole make up of the paper is pleasing to the eye. The
                                Firebrand is true to its name in the "lighting of Watch Fires " in every land." </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Evangel" TEIform="index"/>The
                                Evangel
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The
                                Evangel is devoted to the restoration of primitive Christianity. It is publisht in
                                Buffalo, N. Y. We shall wish the little magazine the best of success and shall be deeply
                                interested to learn how primitive Christianity is defined.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="McCoemack, Fannie" TEIform="index"/>Fannie McCoemack
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Fannie McCoemack, at South Union, Ky. July 20, 1898. Age 58 years 1 mo. and 6 days.
                                Sister Fannie entered the Community at the age of eleven years. J. C. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pilot, John" TEIform="index"/>John Pilot
                            </head><p TEIform="p">John Pilot, at
                                Watervliet, Ohio. Aug. 4, 1898. Age 83 years and 6 months. Brother John has devoted
                                forty years to the upbuilding of our Zion home, a conscientious Christian worker. J. O.
                                T. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Birde, William" TEIform="index"/>William Birde
                            </head><p TEIform="p">William Birde, at East Canterbury, N. H. Aug. 12, 1898. Age 43 years 1 mo. and 15
                                days. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Durgin, Dorothy Ann" TEIform="index"/>Eldress Dorothy Ann Durgin
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Eldress Dorothy Ann Durgin, at East Canterbury, N. H. August 24, 1898. Age 72
                                years, 9 months and 1 day.</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p19"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
AGENTS!
This is  the   opportunity of your life.
Agents are making $50.00 to $150.00 a week.
Fitzhugh Lee, Maj. Gen. U. S. V., and late
Consul General to Cuba, writes
A BOOK ON CUBA
AND   THE
SPANISH WAR.
We have on press for early issue, General
Lee's own story of Cuba and the Spanish War,
to be produced in a substantial book of over
500 pages, 7x9)4 inches in size and almost
ONE HUNDRED ILLUSTRATSONS.
This is the only authentic work published
on the one subject occupying the minds of the
entire civilized world.
OUTFITS READYLiberal commissions will be paid and credit
given.   Address for full paiticulars,
THE INTERNATIONAL SOCIETY,
91-93 FIFTH AVENUE, NEW YORK.
PUBLISHEKS OP GENERAL LEE'S BOOK.
We have authorized distributors everywhere
is an illustrated Monthly, now only 50 cts.
per    year,    devoted   to   PHKEN0L0GY.
PHYSIOGNOMY,  HEALTH,   MEDICAL
& SOCIAL EEI0EM.
Would you like a copy?
Send 5 cts. for Sample to Prof. Haddock,
Phrenologist, 1016 Market St.,
San Francisco, Cal.
SHAKES   THEOLOGY.
A Book of 320 pages.    It contains not
only the Shaker's Faith but explains
Scripture Metaphor.    By H. L. Eads.
Address H. C. Blinn, East Canterbury
N.  II.
DANIEL'S & ST JOHNS
48 page pamphlet.    Price 10 cts.
13 for $1.00.
Address,    H. B. Bear, Preston, Ohio.
By Old Established
HouseHigh Grade
Man or Woman, of good Church standing
to act as Manager here and do office work
and correspondence at their home. Business already built up and established here.
Salary $900. Enclose self-addressed
stamped envelope for our terms to A. P.
T. Elder, General Manager, 189 Michigan
Avenue, Chicago, 111., First Floor.
AGENTS WANTED
in Every County to Supply
the Great Popular Demand for
Compiled and Written by
SENATOR   JOHN   J.
Of Kansas.
The most brilliantly written, most profusely and artistically illustrated, and
most intensely popular book on the subject of the war;with Spain.    Nearly
taken specially for this great work.
Agents are making $50 to $100 a week
selling it.    A veritable bonanza for live
canvassers.    Apply for description, terms
and territory at once to
N. D.Thompson Publishing Co.
ST. LOUIS, MO.,or NEW YORK CITY
Wtmm strange URUm
EXPLAINING
PROPHECIES.
WANTED
HUMAN NATURE
AMERICA'S WAR FOR HUMANITY
INGALLS
<pb n="" id="p20"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
Royal makes the food pure,
wholesome and delicious.
50   YEARS'
EXPERIENCE
Trade Marks
Designs
Copyrights &c.
Anyone sending a sketch and description may
quickly ascertain our opinion free whether an
invention is probably patentable. Communications strictly confidential. Handbook on Patents
sent free. Oldest agency for securing patents.
Patents taken through Munn & Co. receive
special notice, without charge, in the
Scientific American.
A handsomely Illustrated weekly. Largest circulation of any scientific journal. Terms, $3 a
year; four months, $1.  Sold by all newsdealers.
MUNN & Co.361Broad^ New York
Branch Office. 625 F St., Washington, D. C.
HOW TO MAKE MOHEY!
If you are out of employment and want
a position paying you from $50 to $100
monthly clear above expenses by working
regularly, or, if you want to increase your
present income from $200 to $500 yearly,
by working at odd times write the GLOBE
CO. 723 Chestnut St. Phila., Pa. stating
age, whether married or single, last or
present employment, and you can learn
how to make more money easier and
faster than you ever made before in your
life.
AUTHOKISED   KULES
OF
THE   SHAKER   COMMUNITY.
The religious basis of the Order must
be a foundation resting on the principle of
righteousness, which principle is God.
This should rule the life of the individual for the protection of his own soul, for
the peace of the family and as an evidence
of his upright standing before the world.
Price, 10 cts.
SHARER HAMAMELIS
(WITCHHAZEL,)
.A. remedy for Cuts, Burns, Scalds,
Headache, Sore Throat and all
cases of external inflammation
Taken internally for Bowel
Complaint, Bleeding of the
Lungs or Bowels, and for
all aches and pains.
For nse externally, bathe the parts and
lay on a cloth wet with the Extract,    Internally, take one half teaspoonful three
times a day.    Use hot or cold.
Ask your druggist for it or send your
order to Arthtjk Bruce.
East Canterbury, N. H.
Absolutely Pure
ROYAL BAKING POWDER CO,, NEW YORK.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>