<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1205" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">12</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">5</biblScope><date value="18820501" TEIform="date">May 1882</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">97- 120</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="12" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="5" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--                     <pb id="p1"/>
                    <p>VOL. XII. MAY. NO. 5. MANIFESTO PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES. [ ''''OUR hoME AT SHAKERS, N. Y. " Blessed are
                        they that hear the word of God and keep it." Shaker Village, N. H. 1882. SHAKER</p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
--><pb n="97" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let us reason together" TEIform="index"/>LET US REASON TOGETHER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/>ANTOINETTE DOOLITTLE</byline><p TEIform="p"> Human life is enshrouded in mystery, from its incipient stages to the end. We hear, and see
                            through the medium of the: external, or physical senses. If we claim to believe in God—a
                            Supreme Ruler of tlip universe—a life in spheres beyond the present rtage of existence, and
                            are asked our reasons for such belief, we cast about to rind the clearest proof, that we may
                            reason lucidly and make our positions logical and easily understood. We know that we live,
                            move and have existence in this mundane sphere ; but how we thus exist is not so easy to
                            define. The mortal part is not the man, or woman ; the vesture worn is the first
                            presentation to the sight; it is a covering to the physical form subject to decay ; the form
                            is also composed of matter, that time, age and the action of the elements deteriorate, and
                            cause to moulder and return to its former constituent parts. Through the revelation of
                            science, in this comparativelv enlightened age, many claim that we derive our being from,
                            and exist in the sun, the great central source of light to this niate.-ial world ; if that
                            great luminary should cease to shine, and entirely withhold its rays from the earth's
                            surface, vegetable and animal life would become extinct, and all would be death. So much has
                            been said and written upon the subject, that it is unnecessary to go over the ground at this
                            time. It must be evident to every intelligent mind, that some invisible power or force,
                            outside or within, actuates and moves the material forms of what we call men and women, but
                            are in reality only frail tenements or caskets, for the real body to dwell in for a limited
                            space of time. This entity we call soul, a body more subtle and refined than the material
                            form, hence more substantial and enduring, and we call it the immortal part not subject to
                            decay like the mortal. This deathless part of the being is permeated with the essence of
                            life which fills every part, and <pb n="98" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 98 SHAKER MANIFESTO. inspires and
                            directs its upward and onward course. The organs of speech, of sight and sound are in the
                            soul, not in the body ; the external organs are only mediums of conveying ideas from mind to
                            mind, necessary to mortal existence. The eyes are merely windows through which the soul
                            looks to discover material forms and objects ; the eyelids are curtains to be drawn when the
                            eye needs rest. Only that which is visible and tangible to the external senses, are real to
                            the sensuous, physical part. The invisible must be reached through the soul senses, reason,
                            intuition and spiritual perception. The mere assertion that we do not believe because we
                            cannot see, feel and handle, is not sufficient for our purpose, for we still continue to
                            inquire and reason concerning those things which have been hidden from the external senses
                            for ages gone by. If the sun, in the outward firmament is the life of sentient being, where
                            is its source of supply? Shall we call it God, the great Intelligent, Central Source of all
                            light, life and motion, in the interior of all worlds and heavens ? Modern scientific
                            discovery has revealed the fact, that by the aid of the sun rays and certain chemical
                            processes, pictures or shadows of the outside visible forms of men and women may be taken so
                            perfect that we do not disclaim the science, nor question the artist's skill. In these later
                            times science claims to go still further, not only to produce shadows or pictures of human
                            forms, but real materialized tangible forms, and by some supernatural process to cause
                            them—for a space of time—to be inhabited by intelligence from spirit spheres, who speak as
                            with human voice and tell us of realities and experiences in the life beyond. Some say we do
                            not believe because we have not the evidence clearly presented to our senses ; if this is
                            not done, we cannot, will not believe. Moreover, they say there are so many conflicting
                            reports from so-called spirits or messengers from other spheres, if they are spirits—-as
                            they claim to be—they are untruthful and unreliable, and therefore unworthy of attention and
                            trust. How would it answer our purpose to bring the matter a little nearer home, a»d reason
                            somewhat after the following manner : We have heard of a country called Lapland. We have
                            never seen the land, and only know of its boundaries, the products of its soil, modes and
                            manners of its inhabitants from historians. Should we send messengers, two, three or four,
                            to that far off region, to inquire into the habits, intelligence and progress of the people
                            there, and to bring a full, and true account that we might the better understand and judge
                            of their physical, moral and spiritual conditions ? Would not their report correspond—in a
                            measure— to their own standard of intelligence and capability of perception and description
                            ? Still would we disbelieve their statement in general that there is such a country, and
                            that it is inhabited by human beings, even if their detailed account should vary in many
                            respects ? Let us continue our investigation, and send envoys into all peopled lands, from
                            the frigid zones to the tropical regions ; would they all agree? Would not the reports
                            descriptive of the people, correspond with the different climates, soils, productive
                            industries, modes of thought, manners, and degrees of intelligence possessed by the
                            inhabitants of those countries, and of those who visited them as well? <pb n="99" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/>
                            SHAKER MANIFESTO. 99 May it not be quite possible, and even probable, that in what we call
                            the spirit world, peopled by thousands of millions of immortal beings from every land and
                            clime, who have passed into spirit spheres, that in those supernal regions there are
                            existing today, nations, kindreds, tongues and peoples, in large multitudes, analogous to
                            those in our own world? and that at times—by permission—they visit, and revisit this earth,
                            and tell their story of the scenes beyond, from their stand-point, and aim to do so
                            truthfully ? That there are among myriads of spirits, many from dark spheres, who come to
                            mortals, and seek to communicate with them, who assume to be in name, and character, what
                            they are not, and who would work great mischief under a false guise, we would not deny.
                            Hence the necessity of the Apostles injunction lttry and prove the spirits;' and every one
                            who teaches anything contrary to the moral laws of God in nature, or the higher laws
                            pertaining to the spiritual angelic life on the resurrection plane—the Christ life—let him
                            or her be condemned as false and unworthy, and be remanded to their own place and sphere, in
                            dark regions. Mt. Lebannon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watching and waiting" TEIform="index"/>WATCHING AND WAITING</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Witham, Maria" TEIform="persName"/>MARIA WITHAM</byline><p TEIform="p"> Lord. lr:r watch thy church is keeping; When shall earth thy rule obey? When shall end the
                            night of weeping? When shall break the promised day? See the whitening harvest languish,
                            Waiting still the laborers toil; Was it vain thy son's deep anguish? Shall the strong retain
                            the spoil? Tidings sent to every creature, Millions yet have never heard; Can they hear
                            without a preacher : Lord Almighty, give the word. Give the word in every nation, Let the
                            gospel trumpet sound, Witnessing a world's salvation To the earth's remotest bound. To the
                            end thy church completed. All thy chosen gathered in, With their King in glory seated, Satan
                            bound and banished sin. Gone forever parting, weeping, Hunger, sorrow, death and pain ; Lo !
                            her watch thy church is keeping, Come Lord Jesus, come to reign. Enfield, Conn.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Communal relations" TEIform="index"/>COMMUNAL RELATIONS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, O. C." TEIform="persName"/>O. C. HAMPTON</byline><p TEIform="p"> In a Community of Believers, the interests of one are the interests of all. There are no
                            privileged parties possessing a right to absorb into themselves a greater number of communal
                            interests than any others. And yet communities and all other organizations must have
                            departments of direction and manipulation. These departments must be filled and manipulated
                            by Committees best skilled in their manipulation. These departments represent the interests,
                            spiritual, temporal, intellectual, financial and economical, of the Community. While all are
                            eligible to the privileges, gifts, comforts and blessings of the Community, still all cannot
                            belong promiscuously to any and all the Executive committees. The reason of this is found
                            1st, in the great inequality of physical and mental ability ; 2nd, in the immense
                            versatility in talent genius and experience. Consequently absolute equality of mere standing
                            as it regards the occupancy of offices of care and burden among Believers is <pb n="100" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 100 SHAKEIT MANIFESTO. an impossibility. But this does not necessarily
                            interfere with the equality of enjoyment in all the blessings of existence, spiritual,
                            intellectual or physical. It is only a verification of the great Law of God's Providence,
                            wherein "the greatest good is secured to the greatest number." Some of these offices are of
                            greater magnitude and responsibility than others, and consequently require minds of greater
                            magnitude to manipulate them successfully. This extends even to all departments of the
                            common pursuits of life. It is easier, and requires a mind of less magnitude to wind a ball
                            of yarn than to run a steam engine, a:;d so of all the rest. This is a species of inequality
                            among mankind that cannot be remedied in time. All cannot be equally good ball-winders,
                            engine runners, school teachers, doctors, mechanics, herdsmen or seamstresses. This
                            inexhaustible variety in mental and physical powers creates an everlasting inequilibrium
                            through all ranks of men and angels and the graduating scale of differences even in persons
                            pursuing the very same trades, callings and offices, forms another infinite series of
                            inequalities, some lower, some higher in the great scale, forever approaching toward
                            perfection. It is folly therefore, to talk about any possible equality of conditions among
                            mankind in matters and things above mentioned. Again, more or less experience in any
                            business, lot of care, whether temporal or spiritual, makes all difference between persons,
                            irrespective of their peculiar aptitudes therein. Another inevitable but vast difference and
                            inequality will be found between two individuals one of whom has aptitude and long
                            experience and the other inaptitude and an equally long experience. Once more ; one
                            individual has been created better than another and remains so through life ; yet, neither
                            is one entitled to special praise nor the other to special blame : but their inequality is a
                            fact all the same. Finally, this inequality obtains throughout the material and spiritual
                            Universe in the shape of inevitable gradations of intelligences from infinitely high and
                            holy, to infinitely low, ignorant and imperfect. But all these series are ever ascending to
                            higher and higher planes of perfection and goodness, and consequent happiness and glory,
                            through the all-potent instrumentality of the great Law of Evolution and progress. So that
                            each individual of the series will eventually enjoy not only all he is capable of enjoying,
                            but also find himself elevated as far above those below him as he may find others above him.
                            And in this sense as the series is infinite, without center or circumference; each
                            individual is as much the center as every other, and consequently all will consider
                            themselves equally blessed as soon as they are sufficiently developed to understand or
                            comprehend the full scope of this subject. But again, here comes in sight another of the
                            beautiful laws of the Universe, namely: that throughout the whole realm of existence, "The
                            lower or less progressed are blessed and elevated by the higher and more progressed" and
                            from the very nature of progression, cannot be otherwise elevated. The Units of relation
                            between intelligences are such, that no individual is independently capable of progress. If
                            he rises at all, it must be through attraction toward a greater body <pb n="101" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/>
                            SHAKER MANIFESTO. 101 of intelligence than he himself possesses, just as the attraction of
                            gravitation, or electricity operates. But this greater mass is found in an individual or
                            individuals immediately above him either visible or invisible, but most likely both.
                            Consequently, the much mooted theory of "Individual Sovereignty" of man or any other class
                            of finite intelligences, seems to resolve itself into impalpable nonsense in the light of
                            the theory of Evolution. These last remarks it seems to me might serve as a strong argument
                            in favor of the correctness of our theory and practice, relative to our governmental
                            machinery of Ministry, Elders, Trustees, Deacons and Instructors. Indeed it seems to me the
                            best proof of inspiration from on high having been given to the founders of our Organization
                            in the original establishment of the same. Now, I do not pretend to deny that the powers
                            delegated to burden bearers in our community may not be and have not been, and will not be
                            hereafter, more or less abused at times, and the rights of individuals ignored, through the
                            weakness and imperfections of our common undeveloped rudimental status. But this in no wise
                            militates against the theory here advocated, any more than the pains and sickness of
                            gluttony militate against the propriety of eating good wholesome food. Besides, by the
                            gradual diminution of our rudimental ignorances, arrogances, conceits, cruelties, jealousies
                            and lusts, all such unholy use of power will be done away and the attractive and divine
                            energy of Love, Mercy, Patience and Humility, take its place. Then will it be the sweet will
                            and choice of all to live in the practice of perpetual peace and harmony. Then will each one
                            "see the travail of his soul and be satisfied.'' Then "will there not be a dog to move his
                            tongue in all God's holy mountain." Then will a universal amnesty prevail, and charity and
                            forgiveness soothe and calm all the fierce winds of contention and all the rough billows of
                            practical injustice, insult, oppression and injury. Our organization is a self-mending
                            machine and friction and antagonism must finally be eliminated from it and forced to "flee
                            to the uttermost parts of Egypt." We shall progress in personal purity and practical
                            righteousness toward each other and both our Administration and ourselves shall and will be
                            all for peace, reconciliation and at-onement with God and each other ; not a system of force
                            and coercion, but of wisdom, love and attraction. I may not see it in this life, but I feel
                            it and know it and rejoice with joy unspeakable and full of glory in the halcyon prospect.
                            Union Village, Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Toil on" TEIform="index"/>TOIL ON</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hooser, Hortensy" TEIform="persName"/>HORTENSY HOOSER</byline><p TEIform="p"> Ye weary pilgrims here below, Who're blest the way of life to know, Your peace shall like a
                            river flow And crowns to you be given. Let all the tribes of earth rejoice And praise the
                            Lord with heart and voice, That from all turmoil, strife and noise A rest is found in
                            heaven. Thus ransomed from a world of sin, Thus sacrificed to be made clean, And bowed in
                            soul the prjze to win, You're o no with the Creator. 0 happy souls who're blest to share A
                            Father's mercy, love and care ! All glorious robes are yours to wear; .No gift in heaven is
                            greater. Pleasant Hill, Ky.</p></div2><pb n="102" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life's treasure" TEIform="index"/>LIFE'S TREASURE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, Catharine" TEIform="persName"/>CATHARINE ALLEN</byline><p TEIform="p"> Like balmy Soutli winds in the early Spring, That help the myriad buds their casements
                            burst; And like the perfumed freshness showers bring, When earth is parched, and nature
                            droops with thirst, Pure love doth come to me. Like warbles heralding the break of day, And
                            cheering us life's duties to pursue, And like their pensive notes at twilight grey, When
                            falls on leaf and bud the cooling dew, Are words of love to me. And like the violets
                            blooming in the grass, Which brightly covers o'er the faded sod— That greet with smiling
                            welcome those who pass, E'en though some heedless feet have on them trod, Is angel love to
                            me. And like the fragrance of the opening rose, Whose treasure unto all is freely given, A
                            beauteous life that silently outflows, As ministrations borne to us from heaven, Love's
                            breathings fall on me. Each gentle deed, and every kindly thought, I**to my soul a messenger
                            of good ; Far more than gems, or gold from Ophir brought, I prize the gift of angel
                            sisterhood. Whose love doth flow to me. The severing of earthly ties and kin, Though fraught
                            with trial, and with pain severe, And sacrifice of e'en the life within, I ne'er will count,
                            if gospel friends so dear With love encircle me I'll humbly walk the straight and narrow
                            way, And oft will seek the silent vale of prayer, Through self-denial strive each coming day
                            So true to be, as worthily to share The love bestowed on me. A shield that from all harm my
                            soul will keep; A light to guide me through the shadowy vale; And staff to help me climb the
                            rugged steep A living fount, whose waters never fail, I've proved this love to be. It giveth
                            holy courage to the heart, And strength that crowns with victory the strife, All radiant in
                            truth, it doth impart A joy, forever new in endless life, This power of love so free. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Job bishop" TEIform="index"/>JOB BISHOP</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>HENRY C. BLINN</byline><p TEIform="p">BY (Continued from last number.) During a term of more than forty years, Father Job Bishop
                            gave his whole life to the interests of the Societies in New Hampshire. He allowed no object
                            of minor consideration to absorb his time or to detract from the loyalty which he owed to
                            God. His willing obedience was far greater than he asked of others. The order before him was
                            his life pattern of righteousness. Conforming to this with a conscientious exactness, he
                            would allow of no varia'ion in the style of dress, in the form of a building, in the color
                            of the paint, or in the attachments or capacity of any thing that was manufactured, beyond
                            "the pattern shown in the Mount." Abundantly gifted in the manifestations of spirit power,
                            he was a firm believer that the pure in heart, only, could see God ; that those who really
                            hunger and thirst after righteousness are the ones that are filled with the treasures of
                            Christ's kingdom. Several instances are recorded where the power of healing was wonderfully
                            exhibited in him, and yet he rarely exercised this peculiar phase of spirit mediation. As
                            Mother Ann had beeo to her <pb n="103" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 103 spiritual son, Job,
                            all that a mother in Israel could be ; holding him to a strict accountability before God,
                            and instructing him in those lessons of wisdom that made his life a way of pleasantness and
                            his path one of peace, he returned the kindness by a reverential regard and an affectionate
                            love for his spiritual benefactress. These effectual prayers were wrought out in the gift of
                            God, and as seed "•sown in good ground," they yielded, in righteousness, an abundant
                            harvest. Three days previous to the death of Mother Ann, which occurred Sept. 8, 1784, Job
                            visited Watervliet, N. Y. for the express purpose of seeing her once more in the body, and
                            to testify again his thankfulness for her ministration to him, of God's love. Mother Ann
                            soon learned that he was present and sent word by her attendant, Lucy Wright, for Job to
                            call and see her. At this interview, she was sitting in a chair ; her bodily strength was
                            far exhausted, but her mind was sound and her spirit firm and serene. She spoke to him—"Job,
                            I shall soon be taken from the body, but the gospel of truth will never be taken away from
                            you, if you are faithful. Be not discouraged, nor cast down : God will not leave his people.
                            You are a young man, and have received many blessed gifts. Go and be faithful and zealous
                            and when you travel to your place in the Church, you will possess all these beautiful
                            treasures." In his extended ministration as a spiritual teacher every promise was verified
                            and the thankfulness of his heart was a living witness of the truth he had received. The
                            death of Father Job Bishop occurred in Canterbury on the 5th. of Dec. 1831, at forty five
                            minutes past ten o'clock, P. M. at the age of 70 yrs. 2 months and 6 days. The event had
                            been long anticipated as he was suffering from a dropsical affection of the heart. He had
                            returned from Enfield on the second of Feb. with the other members of the order of Ministry
                            and though feeble in body, was more comfortable on the day of his death than usual. Soon
                            after retiring to rest for the night he arose to relieve his difficulty in breathing and
                            immediately expired. Messengers were sent to the Societies at New Lebanon, N. Y. ; Harvard,
                            Mass. ; Enfield, N. H. ; and Alfred, Me., to give information of the death of our beloved
                            Father. Five persons arrived from Enfield, N. H. on the 7th., and on the 8th. two from
                            Alfred. The funeral was held in the church on the 8th inst. at two o'clock P. M. and
                            contrary to the usual custom of Believers, was made public. All the members belonging to the
                            Society in Canterbury attended, also those who came from Enfield and Alfred. Several
                            strangersAvere present, among whom was the Rerv-. William Pattrick of the Congregational
                            Church, and the Rev. John Harriman of the Free Christian Church. Elder Micajah Tucker
                            conducted the exercises and made the opening remarks which were replete with tenderness and
                            sympathy, as he illustrated the characteristic virtues manifested by our beloved parent in
                            the gospel. His precepts and his examples were lovingly conjoined. We were reminded of the
                            accountability that avvaite:] each one for the many privileges we had shared, while hearing
                            his kind instructions. Elder Benjamin Whitcher who had been the companion of Father Job for
                            more than twenty years, spoke of his <pb n="104" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 104 SHAKER MANIFESTO.
                            faithfulness and fervency in promoting the cause of truth ; that Father Job spared no pains,
                            day nor night, in sickness and in health, in doing his duty as a faithful watchman in the
                            Zion of God. He was a lovely teacher of Godliness. On the receiving of the least, favor he
                            had a very pleasant manner of manifesting his gratitude and in the returning of thanks. Even
                            the little children looked upon our kind Father with reverence and respect, and their
                            attention was always affectionately reciprocated. Elder John Lyon of Enfield, N. H.
                            delivered a very appropriate address concerning the world that is to come, in which he
                            illustrated the spirit of the Scriptures where they declared that in it should dwell
                            everlasting righteousness and peace. Elder Elisha Pote of Alfred, Me. arrived just as the
                            service was being closed. For many years he had maintained an intimate acquaintance with
                            Father Job and was considered a very near and dear friend. His affectionate regard for
                            Father was like the conliding trust of a child toward its parent. Elder Elisha entered the
                            church without ceremony and advanced toward the coffin, which was placed on a table in the
                            center of the room. With bowed head and in his feeble, tremulous voice he repeated the
                            Scriptural quotation,— kkBlessed are the dead that die in the Lord, for from henceforth they
                            rest from their labors and their works do follow them." Many wept in silent sympathy with
                            Elder Elisha. By invitation he made a few remarks touching upon their former acquaintance
                            and friendship and oi .the spiritual gift that should be maintained in the Church of God.
                            Liberty was now given for any who so wished to view the remains which were enclosed in a
                            plain, white coffm. Canterbury N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What shall the motives be!" TEIform="index"/>WHAT SHALL THE MOTIVES BE!</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cummings, Ada S." TEIform="persName"/>ADA S. CUMMINGS</byline><p TEIform="p"> What shall the motives be Throughout the present year? Shall they be for evil, Or shall they
                            bring good cheer: Shall the Angel Reaper's E'er search for wheat in vain? Or shall they find
                            a store Of ripened, golden grain? Shall my heart be growing A crop of evil deeds? Or
                            carefully produce A harvest of good seeds? Shall my hands cease labor Because the work is
                            hard? Or shall I with new vigor Discouragements discard? Shall my life be wasted And time be
                            spent in vain? Or, constantly improve Each moment for my gain? Shall I cultivate the thorn
                            And let the roses go? Or tares, cast in the fire That flowers sweet may grow? With careful
                            watch, I'll give The tares and thorns no room ; Rich graces from the spheres, Within my
                            heart shall bloom. That, when the Angel lieapers Bind up the golden grain, They find in me a
                            harvest,— A life not spent in vain. West Gloucester, Me.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The talkative listen to no one for they are ever speaking..." TEIform="index"/>
                            The talkative listen to no one for they are ever speaking...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Plutarch" TEIform="persName"/>Plutarch</byline><p TEIform="p">The talkative listen to no one for they are ever speaking. And the first evil that attends
                            those who know not how to keep silent is that they hear nothing.—</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The best of prophets of the future is the past" TEIform="index"/>The best of prophets of the future is the past
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Byron" TEIform="persName"/>Byron</byline><p TEIform="p">The best of prophets of the future is the past.—</p></div2><pb n="105" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What is the matter?" TEIform="index"/>WHAT IS THE MATTER?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>GILES B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p"> There is a conception, in the leading public mind, that even what is called enlightened, and
                            Christian Society is losing faith and fervor, in much that is called religion ! The Organs
                            of some of the Churches declare that the Churches are losing ground ; and, that of some of
                            the most popular and populous denominations the ratio of increase of Church Members is not
                            one to four thousand churches. That the numbers of young men for the Ministry, in our
                            Colleges is falling off every year. That many of the wealthiest Congregations in our cities
                            are without Pastors. That there is a general mourning that revivals cease ! That Church
                            attendance is falling off. That heretical Preachers have the largest audiences! &amp;c.
                            &amp;c. And, an able and eminent Scotchman tells M. D. Conway that ''The apparent
                            strength of the old theology in Scotland is all a sham ; that it is all undermined, and,
                            that at no distant day, it will collapse in a startling way!" (Scotland has been the strong
                            hold of Orthodoxy !) But, Dr. C. II. Balsbaugh affirms '"There is not a sillier, more
                            inconsistent class of men on God's earth than the God disowning scientists. In the same
                            breath, and with the same penfnl of ink, they are constrained to tell the world, that, at
                            every step, in their investigations of matter, they find the justification of the Christian
                            faith ! The day is here in which the boasters and blasphemers are strengthening the
                            testimony, and enriching the literature of the Church of the Living God." But, as says
                            Draper, '"We here, at the outset, distinguish between Christianity and Ecclesiastical
                            Organizations." "The former is the gift of God : the latter are the product of human
                            exigencies and human invention, and, therefore, open to criticism, or, if need be, to
                            condemnation." But. with reference to the waning of church members, church going, and
                            Church, or creedal Christianity, souls interested in human weal ask, What is the cause of
                            this state of society? In reply we would ask another question. Would a hungry man, seated at
                            a table laden with choice food healthful, tasty and savory, with-draw therefrom before he
                            has partaken to satisfaction, or before hunger is appeased? Such a mr.nner would be contrary
                            to common experience! May we not then reasonably conclude, that, at least, one strong reason
                            of Congregational decimation, the paucity of church members ; the lack of church attendance
                            and religious decline, is to be found in the lack of spiritual, soul food in the churches ?
                            And, may not another very prominent cause be found in the fact, as presented to the
                            conceptions of some souls at least, that light, on Christian principles, has so increased in
                            the public understanding, as to discover the errors in many of the Creeds of so-called
                            Christian Faith? Creeds which shroud faith and religion in mystery an'd inconsistency;
                            Creeds which make God a revengeful Tyrant, more cruel than the savages of the cannibal races
                            ! Creeds which despoil justice of her rewards, and give the lie to God's goodness and
                            love,*1 His charity and mercy makes as chaff, and crowns the fiat of His alleged decrees
                            with daggers which pierce the human soul with horror, and anoint their murderous wounds with
                            despair. In this we refer <pb n="106" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 106 SHAKER MANIFESTO. to what is taught as
                            the vicarious atonement of Jesus, for the sins of all who believe in His Divinity, and
                            confess him to be the Savior of man in sin, by, and through his sufferings for sin, on the
                            Jewish wooden cross. Orthodox Christian Believers, so called, affect to beh'eve in a
                            Heavenly Father God ; that Jesus Christ is God— the Son God ; that the Holy Ghost is God ;
                            that these three Gods are but one God; that Mary was the mother of God—the Son—though some
                            modify this, by assuming that Jesus was both God and Man—and that Mary was the mother of his
                            manhood, but the Holy Ghost was the mother of his Godhood ; yet, the Father, Son, and Holy
                            Ghost are all males, and all of an equal age, all eternal, yet, the Son God, though
                            uncreated, was begotten by the Holy Ghost, the male !—the mother God ! ! It is not revealed
                            how the Holy Ghost can be, at the same time one of the trinity of male Gods, and the mother
                            God of the Son ! and no older than his,—her child ! That God, the Father, in His anger with
                            the sins of man, laid ;ipon his fellow Son God—Jesus, the burden of the sins of humanity,
                            and provided for his death by the sin of the wicked Jews in crucifying him that His wrath
                            might be appeased, and His love to man thus manifested ! How His» attribute of justice, or
                            love to His Son God was thus vindicated we are not informed ! Is it strange, that, when the
                            spiritual understanding of mankind are enlightened to discover these inconsistencies in
                            religious creeds they should not be able to adopt them? To have faith in such a God requires
                            ignorance,—soul darkness, and slavish fear ! (To BE CONTINUED.)</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our own" TEIform="index"/>OUR OWN
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">If I had known in the morning How wearily all the day The words unkind
                                    Would trouble my mind, I said when I went away, I had been more careful, children,
                                    Nor given you heedless pain ; But we vex "our own'' With look and tone We may never
                                    take back again. For though in the quiet evening I may give you the kiss of peace.
                                    Yet it might be That never for me The pain at the heart should cease ! How many go
                                    forth in the morning That never come home at night! And hearts have been broken, By
                                    harsh words spoken, That sorrow can ne'er set right. We have careful thought for the
                                    stranger, And smiles for the sometime guest, But oft for "our own" The bitter tone,
                                    Though we love "our own" the best. All! lips, with curse impatient! Ah ! brow, with
                                    that look of scorn ! 'Twere a cruel fate, Where the night too late To undo the work
                                    of the morn.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Exchange" TEIform="index"/>Exchange.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Non-monopoly" TEIform="index"/>NON-MONOPOLY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>MARY WHITCHER</byline><p TEIform="p"> The higher up possessions go, The less of land-marks we shall know; God owns the air and the
                            blue sky, In which we share, and nothing buy. But that which is of earthly mold, By man, in
                            turn, is bought and sold: Only in God doth freedom reign, Above each hill, and earthly
                            plane. Then rise my soul and dwell above Where found is universal love; Cast off the bands
                            of self and sin And live as Christ without, within. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><pb n="107" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To-day" TEIform="index"/>TO-DAY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Danforth, Nancy G." TEIform="persName"/>NANCY G. DANFORTH</byline><p TEIform="p"> " To-day if ye shall hear his voice, harden not your hearts.''' The "to-day" when we hear
                            the voice of God, is the time present when conviction first enters the soul, calling ns to
                            leave the ways of sin, and yield oarselves, soul and body, to his service. To say that all
                            will be eternally miserable who do not repent in this life, would be to limit the power of
                            the Holy One of Israel. There are millions upon millions who have lived and died without so
                            much as ever hearing that there was a gospel, or a way of salvation, by which fallen man
                            could again find his union with his Creator. Shall they forever suffer for violating laws of
                            which they never heard? No hu nan earthly parent would be so unjust. Then why do we judge
                            thus of our heavenly Father, who is all merciful and forgiving? It seems like blasphemy to
                            say of our God that He, will punish to all eternity, any being which He has created, for the
                            sins committed in the short space of a mortal life, without any possibility of escape or
                            repentance. All the kindly feelings of our nature revolt at the idea, as being unjust and
                            cruel in the extreme. What is the term of three-score and ten years, when compared with etei
                            rial ages ? No more than an atom of sand by the side of the mighty universe. It would seem
                            to us, to be more consistent with the attributes of our God, who is a kind loving Father and
                            a tender forgiving Mother, that as the death of the body makes no change with the condition
                            of the spirit ; so probation does not then cease. In this way, those who have not had an
                            offer of salvation in the present life, may still have a chance to repent of their errors,
                            if they but heed the warning, when the "day" comes that they "hear the voice" of tender
                            compassion inviting them to leave the wilds of unrighteousness where they have so long
                            wandered, and henceforth walk in Wisdom's ways which are paths of pleasantness and peace.
                            This view of the subject gives no license to postpone the day of reconciliation to Gd, for
                            when his "voice' whispers that all is not well, urging us to leave old habits, andcomeinto
                            "newness of life," the work is to be attended to at once "while it is called to-day." Let us
                            not slight the drawings of the Father, whereby we may be led into sweet communion with
                            Christ: "In whom are hid all the treasures of wis dom and knowledge." Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Plea for the shade tree" TEIform="index"/>A PLEA FOR THE SHADE TREE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Collins, Elvah F." TEIform="persName"/>ELVAH F. COLLINS</byline><p TEIform="p"> O, "Woodman spare those trees!" whose mighty arms Stretch forth to shield from penetrating
                            glare, When o'er the hills, the sun with sick'ning heat Sends down its beams that scorch the
                            summer air. Proud in their bearing, lofty in their height, Exhaling moisture, cooling to the
                            brow, O, lay not low those breathing works of God, Which in each bough and leaf, His
                            kindness show. O, "Woodman spare those trees'." so sing the birds, The little warblers
                            perched on twig and stem, That we may longer find a leafy home, Prom which to pour our
                            praises unto Him Who gave us right to dwell amid the green, And quafi" the sweet aroma of
                            the air That's wafted to usfrom the breath of leaves, Which zephyrs cause to tremble
                            everywhere. O, "Woodman spare those trees!" the fruit of toil Of him who sought our comfort,
                            and our gain, <pb n="108" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 108 SHAKER MANIFESTO. When planting there the saplings
                            young, and fair, Which should such noble size, and strength attain. The cunning squirrel
                            runs from trunk to top, Deiying us with feet minute, and swift, And, heeding not the noise,
                            and hum of life, Cracks quickly, nut or pit, dame Nature's gift. O ! spare those trees !
                            that we may ever share, The blessed shelter they are won! to give ; Till age shall cause the
                            vitalizing stream No more to circulate, and make them live. Then, when the axe shall ring
                            with metal note When being plunged into the very heart, We can with thankfulness and
                            gratitude Say, "faithful servants, in our peace depart!" Mt. Lebanon,N. Y..</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Change" TEIform="index"/>CHANGE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="White, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>ANNA WHITE</byline><p TEIform="p"> ''Change is stamped on all things here below." Every thing that the eyes can see, the hands
                            handle, or, that any of the senses are able to discern, confirm the truth of that saying.
                            The rolling seasons as they alternate, bringing forth their extremes of heat and cold, at
                            one time producing fruitage in abundance, pouring into the lap of the industrious tiller of
                            the soil a rich harvest reward, and fiUing his storehouse with precious sheaves of grain
                            making his heart glad ; but, gradually a change comes over the face of the earth, and all is
                            reversed ! The streams that we saw while the summer's sun was shining, brightly sparkling
                            with beauty and running their course towards their home in those larger reservoirs, the
                            rivers, lakes and oceans, are now ice-bound and rigid, and seemingly all nature is wrapped
                            and infolded in the firm grasp of death. It is only so in appearance ; it is winter ; but
                            spring returns ; the birds again are heard filling the air with their musical notes, and the
                            fields are once more dressed in living green. Thus we see and feel that growth and
                            expansion, decay and contraction, i? the law or balancing force in nature. Analagous to this
                            is the history of the human race through the different stages of life from infancy to youth,
                            full manhood and old age. As they increase in stature, their strength—physically and
                            mentally if in a healthy condition—increases in proportion ; and the spiritual faculties
                            also develop to a greater or less degree. Thus change is wrought through the realms of mind
                            and matter ; and such has been the process from time immemorial and according to the nature
                            of things, will continue so to be, "For we are the same Our fathers have been; We see the
                            same sights Our fathers have seen—¦ We drink the same stream And view the same sun— And run
                            the same course Our fathers have run The thoughts we are thinking Our fathers would think;
                            From the death we are shrinking Our fathers would shrink* To the life we are clinging They
                            also would cling; But it speeds for us all, Like a bird on the wkig." If it be true, as the
                            wise Solomon declaimed in his day, that there is no new thing under the sun, then there
                            might be a suspension of ideas, a curtailing of thought, bounded by present conditions and
                            circumstances. The sun will never fail to warm and light the earth, if it proves true
                            according to promise : "That while the earth remaineth, seed-time and harvest, cold and
                            heat, summer and winter, day and night shall not cease." Life and death, in the outward,
                            visible creation, are inseparably connected ; they walk hand in hand together ; but <pb n="109" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 109 in the spiritual area, there is no death ! Life
                            and progress is the grand impress that is stamped upon all that is really spiritual and
                            divine; and whether we commence to ascend the high hills of religious truth, above the
                            material, outward and sensuous, while our spirits inhabit the clay tenement, or in spirit
                            spheres, in proportion to our zeal, energy and devotion, so will our inheritance be, and the
                            gift of eternal life our triumphant reward. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="science" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New science" TEIform="index"/>A NEW SCIENCE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p"> The discovery of a new planet is hailed by the scientific world as a valuable acquisition to
                            the grand science of Astronomy. How much more shall the discovery of a new science be hailed
                            and heralded as an invaluable addition to our Encyclopedia. Spiritualism is such a new
                            science. If some object that Spiritualism is doubtful in its phenomenal facts, uncertain in
                            its prophecies, incoherent in its utterances and wild in its ravings, may we not reply by
                            asking which of the Planets passed not through its nebulous stages in the process of
                            becoming a respectable world? And which of the sciences had any other origin ? Alchemy was
                            the child-state of Chemistry. Stargazers, waiting, watching shepherds, grew into
                            astronomers. In its incipient stages, Geology made Hugh Miller mad. Physiology is not yet
                            out of its teens. Its votaries do possibly let man's blood circulate, but they take
                            advantage of the fact to inoculate thousands with possible horrible diseases to save them
                            from becoming diseased. For ages upon ages, the diurnal and annual revolutions of the earth
                            were hidden from the eyes of those who were ignorant, that they were whirling through space
                            at the rate of 1,000 miles an hour. History itself is but a record of men and women who
                            believed that might made right, and, knowingthat Ideas are stronger than the Sword—that
                            Knowledge is Power—kept the people in ignorance and embroiled them in perpetual wars, by
                            which they destroyed their own power of progress, and passed their days in mutual slaughter,
                            keeping the nations stationary, so that at this present moment, not one nation allows its
                            Females to be represented in their Representative Governments, hold the land for the use of
                            all its inhabitants, or know that poverty is the cause of crime and fountain of war. Do they
                            not need a New Science, like Spiritualism, to teach them by the operation of their physical
                            senses, that men and women are immortal beings, that when dead they can still be seen, felt
                            and heard to speak, can rehearse the history of wrongs suffered in the body and punish the
                            offenders ; Can recall kindnesses, down to the reception of a cup of cold water, returning
                            the same with compound interest—proving beyond a doubt that the mighty men and women of
                            tvickedness, will indeed be "mightily tormented" by those whom they have injured, and that
                            justice-loving humanitai'ians will be like the stars, shining in garments of love and
                            gratitude bestowed upon them by those whom they have benefited while upon earth. Will not
                            such a Science be Religion to Mankind ? And was it not meet that Shaker Communists should be
                            its first pupils and staunchest witnesses, heralds of a coming Millennium ? Mt. Lebanon, N.
                            Y.</p></div2><pb n="110" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker manifesto" TEIform="index"/>SHAKER MANIFESTO</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">MA.Y, 1H82. Office of Publication. The "Shakes Manifesto" is published a Shaker Village, Mer.
                            Co., N. H. All business matters connected with the financial department of the paper will
                            be directed to the Publisher of Manifesto, Shaker Village, N. H. All other communications
                            may be ad" dressed, Editor of Manifesto, Shaker Village, N. H. TERMS. One Copy per. year,
                            Postage paid, .00 " " six months, , " " .85 Enclose a two cent stamp for a specimen copy. To
                            avoid mistakes, those who send money, should write the name of their Post Office, County and
                            State. —)««&gt;»-------TO ADVERTISERS. One inch, one insertion $ 1.00 " " three " each
                            .75 " six " " .05 " " twelve " " .50 " column ----- ----- ----- (5.00 Larger spaces, rates
                            in same proportion.</p></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes" TEIform="index"/>NOTES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">It is reported that a Conn. Jury, of recent date, set aside a will which had been made by a
                            spiritualist. The ground of this verdict was that a person who is a spiritualist is
                            necessarily insane. So much for judgment. Well, the Bible is filled with illustrations of
                            spiritual phenomena from Genesis to Revelations, so that whoever believes in the Bible must
                            believe in spiritual manifestations, consequently believers in the Bible are insane, and
                            such persons should not be allowed to make a will, A kind brother has offered a good word on
                            the writing of letters. "A Shaker ought to use good paper, good ink, a good pen, and hare
                            good thoughts, well digested." A careless draft, written with faint pencil lines and upon a
                            ;&gt;iece of paper, instead upon a sheet of paper, is indeed, not very complimentary. No
                            one can be particularly interested in the blots and multiplied mistakes thata negligent
                            writer may feel at liberty to send, but would prefer to receive a neatly finished letter, as
                            they would a present. Interlining should be avoided as much as possibly consistent. A nicely
                            written and clean page is a worthy commendation to any writer and for which the recipient
                            cannot avoid giving thanks. This may be one of the commendable forms in which to preach the
                            gospel of neatness and carefulness. One of our valuable Health .Journals does not hesitatate
                            to say, that—* -Sickness is a disgrace." And yet wiih that Stigma attached, we are scarcely
                            able to get beyond the reach of our pill box or syrup bottle without a fear of being caught
                            by one or more of the ills that flesh is heir to, and through this lose our right to remain
                            longer in this world. So long ago as 3000 years, Moses informed his brethren that if they
                            would teep (lie Covenant which God had given to them, the Lord would take from them ill
                            sickness, which promise, no doubt, remained good so long as the Covenant was kept. But we
                            are not Jews and lave never received any covenant that lad reference to the subject of
                            hygiene. As a large percentage of our ills comes from the food we eat, we blindly <pb n="111" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. Ill or otherwise transgress, while we make
                            ourselves omniverous Christians, for which we are made to suffer the inevitable penalty. By
                            this we are frightened and hastily chase after a remedy, which in some cases proves to be as
                            bad as the disease. It would seem that our Christian nation had fallen heir to the entire
                            list of Egyptian plagues, which fact demands of us a careful investigation into the laws of
                            our being and may be into the "Hygiene of the kitchen." We have just received the
                            electrotypes of Shakers, N. Y. ; Harvard, Mass, and Shirley, Mass., and shall give them a
                            place on the cover of the Manifesto as opportunity offers. Electrotypes of our other
                            Societies would prove very acceptable.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="London, England, Feb. 17, 1882" TEIform="index"/>London, England, Feb. 17, 1882</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="T." TEIform="persName"/>T.</byline><p TEIform="p"> London, England, Feb. 17, 1882 Dear Eldress Caroline:—Will you please accept my thanks
                                for your kind notice. I have looked forward to the pleasure of sometime visiting your
                                community again, but years roll on and one's youth and strength go past recall. Even
                                when we were in New England in 1879, I must have been not far from Enfield. for I went
                                across the state from Northern New York to Boston and then to Providence. At the end of
                                a long day I only reached the latter place at midnight to be in time for a funeral. Mr.
                                T - - went from Plattsburg to Montreal and south by a different route, or he would have
                                liked to look in on the peaceful life of your Community. Enclosed you will find five
                                dollars, which please credit to my account, in advance payment for the Manifesto. I
                                always read the Shaker paper with interest and pleasure, and sometimes pass my copy into
                                Mrs H—the widow of a prominent spiritualist and physician, who died a few years ago. She
                                is an advanced thinker and a splendid medium. She hardly ever speaks of her gifts and
                                only a few people know her as she is. Her daughters are good yoixng women. One of them
                                is in America and if it should be in your way to see her, you will find her full of
                                thought on all the great questions of the day. Mr. C—sent us his photograph the other
                                day to add to our collection of Anti-Vaccinators. I do not know, dear madam, whether I
                                may venture to place you with these people or whether Elder Frederic Evans will allow
                                himself to be classed withanti-vaccinators. The weather has been until now very dark
                                ever since early in December. No doubt you read of our fearful fogs which so alarmingly
                                increase our death rate. I was on a train that was run into on one of the worst days. It
                                fortunately happened that no one was hurt, but a good many of us were well shaken, and
                                an empty railway carriage at the end of the train was broken to pieces. I opened a
                                window to see where we were, but the fog rolled in exactly like smoke out of a foul
                                chimney and we could do nothing but sit still. Happily we soon drew up to a station
                                where there were torches. Gas is of no use in such dreadful darkness as fog makes. I
                                wish we might sometime show you or your friends, hospitality in our home. We are not
                                always in a fog, as the spring and summer are often delightful. I am sorry we were away
                                from England on the occasion of Elder Frederic Evan's visit to this country, but we hear
                                him spoken of with pleasure by our friends. There is a growing movement outside of
                                spiritualism mostly in favor of Vegetarianism. Do the Shakers form a system of living?
                                As a family several of us live as vegetarians tor a season and then go back to a very
                                little meat. I fancy meat rather clogs the system and prevents us from getting our best
                                inspirations On the other hand, meat may make us better able to "hew wood and draw
                                water" and do our work in the world. May you dear Eldress have much pleasure in all this
                                New Year. Truly yours—</p></div3><pb n="112" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tunnel Hill, Ga. Feb. 1882" TEIform="index"/>Tunnel Hill, Ga. Feb. 1882</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stevenson, Lizzie M." TEIform="persName"/>Lizzie M. Stevenson</byline><p TEIform="p">Tunnel Hill, Ga. Feb. 1882 Editor of Manifesto :—I feel impressed to write you a f'-w
                                lines. I have had the pleasure of reading the Manifesto some four years, and it is a
                                welcome visitor. From no other source could I get such good teachings, except from the
                                New Testament. I have a love for the Shaker Society : for its purity and self-denials. I
                                am led to believe that the Shaker Church is Christ's Clrurch, as the faith is that which
                                Christ teaches. I think, however, that some of the writers of the Manifesto are very
                                hard on the marriage question. If the married are all sinners against the law and
                                commandments of God, what is to become of them. I am married and the mother of six
                                living children, and yet I am desirous of living a true Christian life. I am seeking for
                                truth and knowledge and earnestly hoping to obtain it, and yet it seems almost
                                impossible to be a Christian while absorbed in the life of the world. My advice to the
                                unmarried, is like that of the Apostle ; if they are able to deny themselves and take up
                                the cross of Christ, to do so at once, and obtain happiness in this world, and the
                                reward of Eternal Life. I send my love and kind wishes to all the good Shakers. Your
                                well wisher,</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="McCuere, Laura" TEIform="index"/>Laura McCuere</head><p TEIform="p">, at South Union, Ky. Mar. 23. Age 79 years and (i mo.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Russell, Candace" TEIform="index"/>Candace Russell</head><p TEIform="p">, at North Union, Ohio. April 6. Age, 7G years 1 mo. and 18 days.</p></div4></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sun set" TEIform="index"/>SUN SET</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W.</byline><p TEIform="p">I'm greeted with the setting sun, As bright as the noon day ! Does this imply when life's
                                near done Like light shall gild my way? That sun set is as beautiful As sun rise, and as
                                clear? Then joy, my heart and be not sad Though close of life draws near. Canterbury, N.
                                H. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>Juvenile</head><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Scene in school" TEIform="index"/>A SCENE IN SCHOOL</head><p TEIform="p">An incident occurred in a public school of Roxbury, during the master-ship of Dr.
                                Nathaniel Prentice, which exhibited the noble side of boy-nature. It has been often
                                told, but will bear repeating. Dr. Prentice threatened to punish with six blows of a
                                heavy ferule the first boy detected in whispering, and appointed detectives. Shortly
                                after, one of them shouted. ''Master, John Zigler is whispering." John was called up,
                                and asked if it was a fact. John, by the way, was a favorite both with his teacher and
                                schoolmates. "Yes," answered John "I was not aware what I was about. I was intent on
                                working out a sum, and requested the boy who sat next to hand me an arithmetic that
                                contained the rule which I wished to see." The doctor regretted his hasty threat, but
                                told John that be could nbt suffer him to' whisper, or escape the punishment; and
                                continued, "I wish I could avoid it, but cannot without a forfeiture of my word. I
                                will," he continued, "leave it to any three scholars you may choose, to say whether or
                                not I omit the punishment." John said he would agree to that, and immediately called out
                                three boys. The doctor told them to return a verdict, which they soon did, after
                                consultation as follows : "The master's word must be kept inviolate. John must receive
                                the threatened six blows of the ferule, but it must be inflicted on voluntary proxies,
                                and we the arbitrators will share the punishment by receiving each of us two of the
                                blows." John, who had listened to the verdict, stepped up to the doctor, and with
                                outstretched hand, exclaimed, "Master, here is my hand; they shan't be struck a blow. 1
                                will receive the punishment." The doctor under pretence of wiping his face, shielded his
                                eyes, and telling the boys to goto their seats, said he would think over it to Ins dying
                                day ; but the punishment " ; never inflicted.</p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Subtlety may deceive you; integrity never will" TEIform="index"/>Subtlety may deceive you; integrity never will
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cromwell" TEIform="persName"/>Cromwell</byline><p TEIform="p">Subtlety may deceive you; integrity never will.—.</p></div3><pb n="113" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="College mouse" TEIform="index"/>THE COLLEGE MOUSE
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">THE COLLEGE MOUSE. There was a little mouse Who lived in a college ; Why did
                                        he live there? Was he fond of knowledge-'' Did he wish to master Philosophy and
                                        Greek? Did he think the music Better than his squeak? No ; he only wanted To be
                                        away from cats, And trap-setting Biddies, And overbearing rats. He roomed with a
                                        student Not very fond of study, Who often ate and drank Until his bruins were
                                        muddy. Then the little mousey, From his hole would peep, And when he saw his
                                        room-mate Safe and sound asleep, Would climb upon the table, And help himself to
                                        cheese, And sitting on his haunches, Would nibble at his ease When his meal was
                                        ended, He would run about the floor, Searching all the corners He had not
                                        searched before. His bed vras 'neath the hearthstone So cosy and warm. Nothing
                                        could get at him To do him any harm. He was a happy mousey As ever came along,
                                        Therefore have I made him The subject ot my song.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="S. S. herald" TEIform="index"/>S. S. Herald.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Letter Box</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Village, N. H." TEIform="index"/>Shaker Village, N. H.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lizzie" TEIform="persName"/>Lizzie</byline><p TEIform="p"> Shaker Village, N. H. Dearly Loved Mother Eunice ;—What could bring more pleasure to one
                                youthful like myself, than to realize the love of a dear good Mother and friend, as I do
                                through the medi um of your epistles, so fragrant with the wisdom and goodness of a long
                                experience in the Christian work. 1 hardly think strange that when I read them to my
                                companions they feel somewhat jealous. Last evening we had an unusually good meeting.
                                The recent anniversary of the birth of our Mother Ann Lee, caused many references to be
                                made of her, and the sacred revelation which makes her children free from the bondage of
                                sin. The following beautiful piece was sung : ¦'I am never forgotten, never forsaken
                                While I trust in my Mother above; She careth for me, and hath set me free, I joy in her
                                unbounded love. 0 Mother ! bright in thy glory 1 see thee, mid halos of light, Crowned
                                in thy victory, bathed in purity, Thy robes are eternally white " The meeting
                                throughout, breathed the inspiration of a Mother's Angel spirit. My soul enjoyed the
                                season, and I hope my life will be such, that the benefits received in these spiritual
                                seasons may leave its impress upon my character. You will please accept my promise that
                                I will "never weary climbing," or striving, until I am just the good girl that I so wish
                                to be. Be so kind as to still love and pray for me. I do so dearly love a good true
                                Mother; why sometimes when I think of it, it seems to me that a Mother is the most
                                beautiful being God ever made. Your Affectionate Daughter in the Lord</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harvard, Mass April, 1882" TEIform="index"/>Harvard, Mass April, 1882</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bathrick, Eunice" TEIform="persName"/>Eunice Bathrick</byline><p TEIform="p">Harvard, Mass April, 1882 My Dear Daughter;—I received yours on the second inst. Many
                                thanks for the same, when I read it, and look upon the pretty souvenir, I shall think of
                                my little daughter. I love birds and flowers, and have been delighted for several days
                                in listening to their sweet music; they seem to join in concert to welcome returning
                                Spring. The blackbirds have already held their annual Jubilee. It is really amusing to
                                witness their gleeful motions, hopping from twig to twig while they send forth their
                                joyous notes in merry songs of gladness, that winter has passed and they can return to
                                their pleasant haunts. It may seem trifling to some, in one who is eighty eight years of
                                age to think so much of birds and flowers ; but they have been strown <pb n="114" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 114 SHAKER MANIFESTO. in our path by creative Power whose works in their
                                primeval state of innocence I ever admire and why not enjoy them? While contemplating
                                the beauties of nature, I feel that I am communing with God ; for he seems to speak
                                through each tree, blade, and flower. I am much pleased with the account of your
                                beautiful meeting in commemoration'of the birth of our Mother, am glad you enjoyed it so
                                much for this is a good omen ; as children who love and obey their Mothers, generally
                                make the best men and women; and those who find a Mother in Christ, and love and obey
                                her, are sure of finding heaven here and here-after too. If I may judge by the
                                sentiments contained in your letter, and if you will patiently submit to the grinding
                                and polishing process you must endure before being fitted for the Master's use, you will
                                become u bright ornament in the courts of Zion. Ever aspire more ardently for vital
                                goodness than for greatness; a wise man once said: "All who are truly good, are truly
                                great." If we cultivate and improve "our talents to the best advantage, we shall be
                                satisfied in the end with our life work. You say : "I will never weary climbing.'' This
                                is just the state in which every true Christian will be found, whether aged or young;
                                and if careful to discard, as soon as discovered, every thing that does not harmonize
                                with the Christ spirit, it will greatly facilitate our ascent; for the less burden we
                                carry, the easier it is to climb. Give my love to all your dear companions. Tell them
                                never to "grow weary" in bearing the cross ; for their crowns will far outweigh all
                                losses, and crosses. Affectionately, Your Spiritual Mother,</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, Conn, Mar. 1882" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, Conn, Mar. 1882</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt</byline><p TEIform="p">Enfield, Conn, Mar. 1882 Dear Children ;—After reading the good letters in the Manifesto,
                                I concluded that I would also write one. Letter writing is an accomplishment, and if you
                                make correspondence a means of improvement, it may be productive of good. Perhaps some
                                of you have window gardens, if so, how carefully you watch the plants and buds. You are
                                disappointed, no doubt, when the buds do not open into beautiful flowers, because some
                                blight has injured them,—perhaps a worm has been eating at its heart. But do you watch
                                yourselves, as lovely plants and buds, tenderly gaurded by true friends, lest the vile
                                worm of sin destroys the beautiful flowers of truth and purity? Nothing but uprightness
                                of spirit and chastity of body, can shield you from such a dreadful fate ! If you wish
                                to have your lives bud and blossom into truth and virtue, shun the reigning blight of
                                sin, lest it bring sorrow and death to your immortal spirits ! Erom your Brother, </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>House-hold</head><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="When making pies of canned pumpkin, use..." TEIform="index"/>
                                When making pies of canned pumpkin, use...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">When making pies of canned pumpkin, use as little milk as possible, then one egg will be
                                enough for a pie ; otherwise the custard must be thickened with several eggs.</p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Eating too much" TEIform="index"/>EATING TOO MUCH</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lewis, Dio" TEIform="persName"/>Dio Lewis</byline><p TEIform="p">Ten persons die prematurely of too much food where one dies of too much drink. Thousands
                                eat themselves into fever, bowel disease, dyspepsia, throat affections, and other
                                maladies. Some years ago the residents of a German city were one morning wild with
                                excitement. Everybody was poisoned. The doctors were flying in every direction. Water
                                was the only thing they had swallowed in common. The reservoir was examined. In one
                                corner a paper of deadly poison was found. The stomach is the reservoir which supplies
                                the whole body. A fever, an inflammation, or some other malady appears. There you will
                                find the source of the disease. I am acquainted with the table habits of a large number
                                of persons. They have all eaten too much food. Nearly all, too much in quantity, but all
                                have eaten food too highly concentrated. Yesterday I saw a dyspeptic friend eating pears
                                at a fruit stand. He said with a smile "1 go a few Bartletts half a dozen times a day."
                                Certain dietetic reformers seem to think if they eat coarse bread «and ripe fruits, a
                                peck is all right. Eine flour bread, pies and cakes are great evils.» A <pb n="115" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> friend who has decayed teeth, dyspepsia, and a disagreeable eruption, all
                                produced by excessive eating of improper food, declared in response to my remonstrance,
                                "But I never eat more than I want." Every person wants the quantity he has been in the
                                habit of eating. If he could digest well two pounds a day but eat four pounds, he wants
                                the latter quantity. A man may want a glass of spirits on rising. He is in the habit of
                                drinking at that time. The body is strengthened by what it can digest and assimilate.
                                Every ounce more than this is mischievous. The large, eater is always hungry. The man
                                who eats just enough, suffers little from hunger. Pardon a word of my own experience.
                                During many years of practice at my profession, I had but little muscular exercise. I
                                ate enormously. An hour's postponement of my dinner was painful. Xow I can omit a dinner
                                altogether without inconvenience. I have lost twenty pounds in weight, but 1 feel a
                                great deal younger. (More than half the thin people would gain flesh by eating less.) I
                                have only one dietetic rule, from which I never depart; this rule, kind reader, I
                                commend to [you Always take on your plate, before you begin, everything you are to eat.
                                Thus you avoid the dessert, and are pretty sure not to eat too much. This simple rule
                                has been worth thousands to me. Yes, I think there are persons who eat too little, but
                                where there is one such, there are hundreds who eat too much. And when in this country
                                of plenty a person is found who eats too little, it is, generally speaking, by eating
                                fine flour bread and other unnutritious trash. Fine flour bread is but little better
                                than sawdust. If you eat oatmeal, cracked wheat, and beef, you will be surprised to find
                                how little food you require to run the machine.—.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ceilings" TEIform="index"/>Ceilings</head><p TEIform="p"> that have been smoked by a kerosene lamp should be washed off with soda water.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vinegar" TEIform="index"/>Vinegar</head><p TEIform="p"> should be kept in glass or wooden jars. The acetic acid acts on stone or earthen
                                vessels.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Red-cedar chips" TEIform="index"/>Red-cedar chips</head><p TEIform="p"> will drive away moths.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lesson in economy" TEIform="index"/>A LESSON IE ECONOMY</head><p TEIform="p">What could be more disagreeable and dee dedly uncomfortable, than stiff, hrrd boots and
                                shoes, made so by constant soaking, and the lack of greasing. Whenever we see little
                                boys or big boys with such comfortless coverings for the feet, we feel just like giving-
                                them this simple lesson in economy. Do you know that your boots and shoes are made from
                                the skins of animals? Now Nature has supplied the skia of all creatures with an oil to
                                keep it soft and pliable, if the oil which is natural is allowed to waste by constant
                                wetting, and none added to supply this waste, the leather in consequence becomes hard,
                                unpliable, and very soon unsuitable to be worn at all. To remedy this, if your shoes get
                                wet, thoroughly grease them ; then place where they can dry, but never near a hot tire,
                                where you cannot bear the hand. It is a better plan to oil the shoes before wetting
                                them, and the water will not be so readily absorbed into the pores of the leather.
                                Castor oil, and neat's foot oil are Doth good. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Oleander" TEIform="index"/>The Oleander</head><p TEIform="p">.—All parts of the oleander are deadly. A very small quantity of the eaves have been
                                known to kill a horse. The lowers have produced death in those persons who have
                                earelessly picked and ate them. The branches divested of their bark and used is skewers,
                                have poisoned the meat roasted on hem, and killed seven out of twelve people who partook
                                of it.—Southern World.</p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To beat the white of eggs..." TEIform="index"/>To beat the white of eggs...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">To heat the white of eggs quickly put in a )inch of salt. The cooler the eggs the [uicker
                                they will froth.. Salt cools and also xeshens them.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ink" TEIform="index"/>Ink</head><p TEIform="p">spilled on carpets may be entirely removed by rubbing while wet with blottingjaper, using
                                fresh as it soils.</p></div3></div2><pb n="116" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>Farm and Garden</head><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ashes as a fertilizer" TEIform="index"/>Ashes as a Fertilizer</head><p TEIform="p">.—Unleached wood ashes contain all the constituents of plant food that the ordinary or
                                worn out soil needs except nitrogen. By their chemical action, they render much of the
                                inert nitrogen in soils available, and in that way may be said to furnish nitrogen. This
                                is true of lime, and on this power of making nitrogen available, the greatest value of
                                lime, when applied as a fertilizer, depends. Ashes also have a good mechanical effect
                                upon the soil, especially heavy clay soils, which are made lighter and more porous, so
                                that air and water circulate more freely. Ashes do not suffer waste by being washed out
                                to the extent that is true of the mare soluable and concentrated fertilizers sold in the
                                markets their effects are therefore more lasting.'—American Agriculturist.</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mixed feeds" TEIform="index"/>MIXED FEEDS</head><p TEIform="p">One of the strong points in favor of the much praised ensilage, is that animals eat it
                                with a relish. No food, however rich it may be in food elements, will prove profitable
                                if the farm stock cannot be made to take to it kindly. It is on this account that a
                                mixing of feed has been so successful. Sameness palls upon the appetite—a change of diet
                                encourages and sharpens it. A few roots cut, or better, pulped and given to the animals,
                                will make them eat the corn fodder or cut straw with all the greater relish. Try and
                                make a little change in the diet of the animals, even though it be only once a week,
                                with some roots, potatoes, apples, &amp;c : it will pay, The more an animal eats,
                                and healthily digests, the more profitable it is.—Am. Agri.</p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Save the dead leaves" TEIform="index"/>SAVE THE DEAD LEAVES</head><p TEIform="p">The leaves which annually fall from any of our large deciduous trees will make sufficient
                                fertilizing materials to produce another tree of the same size. To accomplish this,
                                however, it will not do to allow the leaves to be scattered by the winds, washed down
                                creeks and rivers and wasted. We know that decomposed leaves make most excellent manure;
                                but the ground will not grow rich very rapidly, even under trees, unless the annual
                                deposit of leaves remains and decays where they fall, which is seldom the case except in
                                large forests. The leaves that fall from our shade and fruit trees are mainly blown away
                                into the roads and ditches and do nobody any good, when, if carefully saved, they would
                                add considerably to the fertility of one's garden. On damp days, and early in the
                                morning, while the leaves are wet, have them raked up and put into a compost heap, and
                                you will find that the twenty to thirty wagon loads of leaves annually saved about your
                                place, make one or two loads of superfine manure, and just the best thing known for
                                garden plants. Do not wait until all the leaves have fallen before commencing to save,
                                for a large proportion of them would be blown away by that time, but begin early, and
                                thereby nearly all can be saved.—Agricultural World and Michigan Homestead.</p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fence posts" TEIform="index"/>Fence posts</head><p TEIform="p">-—Char the ends of your posts before putting them into the holes. They will last much
                                longer. They may be charred a little higher than the ground, although that is likely to
                                make them a little unsightly. There are farmers who even after charring make an
                                application of thin tar.</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dust baths for poultry" TEIform="index"/>Dust Baths for Poultry</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Cleanliness is important in fowl-houses, for experience shows that poultry
                                        are unfavorably affected by the emanations from filthy quarters; and, besides,
                                        working in places where roosts and floors are covered with the droppings is
                                        decidedly unpleasant. Dry earth, in the form of powder scattered everywhere,
                                        will absorb the bad odors, giving a wholesome atmosphere to the hen-house, and
                                        at the same time preserve the manure in the least offensive condition. Besides
                                        these purposes, a box of dry earth should be in a convenieut corner of every
                                        fowl-house for the fowls to roll in. Dust from the highway is most convenient.
                                        Replace the same by an equal quantity of good gravel, and the public will be the
                                        gainer.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Live stock journal" TEIform="index"/>Live Stock Journal.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><pb n="117" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>Select</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Henry Vincent on Elder Evans" TEIform="index"/>HENRY VINCENT ON ELDER EVANS</head><p TEIform="p">Henry Vincent tells us this story: "While Elder Frederic W. Evans was holding meetings in
                                England in 1871, one of the Christian brethren became somewhat nervously excited over
                                some of the theological views expressed by the good elder, and called out: 'What did
                                Jesus Christ come into this world for? / demand of you what Jesus Christ came into this
                                world for f Elder Frederic paused in his discourse, and slightly leaning forward to get
                                a better view of his assailant, spoke in his peculiar, clear voice: 'My friend, Jesus
                                Christ came into this world to teach such men as you are how to govern their tempers.'
                            "</p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Minister of the olden times" TEIform="index"/>A MINISTER OF THE OLDEN TIMES
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">There was once a minister of the gospel Who
                                        never built a church. Who never preached in one. Who never proposed a church
                                        fair to buy the church a new carpet. Who never founded a new sect. Who never
                                        belonged to any sect. Who frequented public houses and drank wine with sinners.
                                        Who never received a salary. Who never asked for one. Who never wore a black
                                        suit, nor a white neck tie. Who never used a prayer book. Or a hymn book. Or
                                        wrote a sermon. Who never hired a cornet soloist to draw souls to hear the
                                        "words." Who never advertised his sermons. Who never even took a text for his
                                        sermons. Who never went through a course of theological study. Who was never
                                        ordained. Who never was even "converted." Who never went to conference. Who was
                                        he? Christ.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New York graphic" TEIform="index"/>N. Y. Graphic.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tapestry weavers" TEIform="index"/>THE TAPESTRY WEAVERS
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Let us take to our hearts a lesson—no lesson can braver
                                        be— From the ways of the tapestry weavers on the other side of the sea. Above
                                        their heads the pattern hangs, they study it with care. The while their fingers
                                        deftly work their eyes are fastened there. They tell this curious thing,
                                        besides, of the patient, plodding weaver; He works on the wrong side evermore,
                                        but works for the right side ever. It is only when the weaving stops, and the
                                        web is loosed and turned, That he sees his real handiwork—that his marvelous
                                        skill is learned. Ah, the sight of its delicate beauty, how it pays him for all
                                        of his cost! No rarer, daintier work than his was ever done by the frost. Then
                                        the master bringeth him golden hire, and giveth him praise as well, And how
                                        happy the heart of the weaver is no tongue but his own can tell. . The years of
                                        man are the looms of God, let down from the place of the sun, Wherein we are
                                        weaving alway, till the mystic web is done. Weaving blindly, but weaving surely,
                                        each for himself his fate ; We may not see how the right side looks— we can only
                                        weave and wait. But, looking above for the pattern, no weaver hath need to fear;
                                        Only let him look clear into heaven—the Perfect Pattern is there. If he keeps
                                        the face of the Savior forever and always in sight, His toil shall be sweeter
                                        than honey, his weaving is sure to be right. And, when his task is ended, and
                                        the web is turned and shown, He shall hear the voice of the Master, it shall say
                                        to him, "Well done!" And the white winged angels of Heaven, to bear him thence
                                        shall come down, And God shall give him gold for his hire— not coin, but a
                                        crown!</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Scribner's" TEIform="index"/>Scribner's for October.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><pb n="118" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Into surrender" TEIform="index"/>INTO SURRENDER</head><p TEIform="p"> Enfield, N. H. 1. Wouldst thou know the joys of Heaven, Wouldst thou find sweet peace with2.
                            While upon thy homeward journey, Friends may falter at thy 3. Every faithfill, firm endeavor
                            In the glorious cause of 4. Onward, then, let "no surrender" Be the motto of your in, Let
                            thy life to God be given, Shun the side, Weak in faith, may seek to turn thee From the
                            right, Stands for thee a star gem ever, Pleasing life. Knowing God is thy Defender, While
                            persnares of guilt and sin. Walk the path of selfdenial, Daily, strife thou wouldst abide.
                            Let not weakness, doubt, nor troubles Move thy in Jehorail's sight. Recompense for all thy
                            labors, Thro' thy sist ent in . the strife. Thy inheritanee is truly One of hourly watch and
                            pray; Trust in God heart from purpose true, Burst all bands earthly so journ here, One of Zi
                            blessed, rich in crease, While thy glo through every as ernpty on's blessed rious future,
                                <pb n="119" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 119 trial, bubbles, saviors— surely, And And
                            Such Shall thy each shall re holy day thy crown thy dound to faith faith blest end obey.
                            renew. career. less peace.</p></div2><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I may not reach the height nor depth..." TEIform="index"/>I may not reach the height nor depth...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Canterbury, N. H. I may not reach the height nor depth Of God's great love to me; Nor view
                            the Hand which turned my feet From harm, ¦ I could not see. But this I know, I've felt its
                            worth, And trust its saving power; I ask this searching, guiding light, In ev'ry passing
                            hour.</p></div2><pb n="120" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books and Papers" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Watchman : Weekly : By the Watchman Publishing Company, Boston, Mass. It is a devoted
                                and able exponent of that order of Christians known as Baptists. The information in its
                                columns having reference to the ecclesiastical policy of the church is very extended. A
                                Christian liberality makes it an interesting paper. The page devoted to the "Family
                                Circle," is always filled with stories long and short, with Poetry, with Pleasantries
                                and with knots to tie and untie, and cannot fail to instruct and amuse all who are so
                                fortunate as to see the paper. Hall's Journal of Health; March; Pub. by E. 11. Uibbs, A.
                                M., M. D. 141 Eighth St. N. Y. Among the long list of excellent articles may be found
                                the following. Men and Animals; Diphtheria and its Cause; Cure for Drunkenness; A Lesson
                                in Etiquette; The Demon of Chloral; To stop Coughing; Heart Disease; Fever and Ague; A
                                Small Pox Preventive; Daniel Webster's Presence, etc. Terms, $2.00 a year, $ 1.00 for
                                six months. Single copy, 20 cents. Phrenological Journal: April; Pub. by Fowler
                                &amp; Wells, 755 Broadway, A*. Y. This number has a fine life-like portrait of Hon.
                                Wendell Phillips, the Orator, Agitator and Reformer, also an extended biographical
                                notice of this remarkable man. "One looking at his amiable face, lit as it is with
                                smiling eyes, would not dream that he could say bitter words that could bite and
                                stinglong after they had been uttered." The Causes and Cure of Insanity, by Amelia V.
                                Petit; A very interesting and fully illustrated article on Tools and Instruments of
                                Ancient Man; Phrenological Commentator, No. 5; A well balanced Woman bj* Anna
                                Randall—Diehl; Louise Michel, the French Socialist, with portrait; In the Department on
                                The Science of Health, we find— Why there is so much disease; Unhealthy Reading; Kitchen
                                Leaflets; Hints to Sleepers; etc. Editorial Items; Personal, Wisdom, Mirth, Library,
                                etc. Riches and Poverty ; A Theoretical and Practical Solution of the Labor Question, by
                                William Hanson, New York, 128 Front Street. The Author is a professing Christian, and
                                out of sympathy for the distressed has given lifteen years of constant thought to a
                                solution of this difficult problem. Price, per copy, bound in pamphlet form, 25 cts. The
                                Southern World; Semi-monthly; W.G. Whidby, Ed. Pub. by the Southern World Pubi lishing
                                Company, Atlair.a, G.A. In its notice to correspondents it says, "Ft is our aim to make
                                the Southern World a medium for the diffusion of practical information upon all
                                agricultural and mechanical subjects, and to this end we invite communications upon all
                                rural subjects, experimental results, crops, news, Domestic economy, etc., and upon
                                topics of interest to mechanics, manufacturers and miners." Certainly this number of the
                                Southern World proves to be very interesting and instructive; Several of the articles
                                are illustrated. It is a paper of sixteen large pages of nice, white, paper and clear,
                                clean cut, black print, items of great importance in this day of feeble eye sight.
                                Terms, $1.00 per. year. The Medical Call : Quarterly; Edited by W. D.Foster, M. D. and
                                O. II. Crandell, M. D. Quincy, 111. Tue January number is the first of Volume second,
                                and has a very extended table of contents, which teaches what is "adapted to the wants
                                of the busy doctor." It also expressly invites the fullest expression of opinion from
                                all quarters." Terms, fifty cents per. annum. Single copies, fifteen cents. "The South;"
                                Monthly; Pub. by The South Publishing Company, Is. Y. This is a large, well printed,
                                excellent and interesting paper of 28 pages "A Journal of Southern and South-western
                                Progress." It is devoted expressly in the interest of developing the vast resources of
                                that wonderful Eden land. The South contains articles of information referring to the
                                climate, the soil, the products, the water courses, the forrests, etc. etc. so essential
                                to those who contemplate a journey into that section. It has departments
                                devoted"especially to scientific, Agricultural and home interest; also letters of travel
                                from interested friends, and an abundance of beneficial and profitable matter. Terms,
                                $2.00 per. year or 20 cts. per. copy. The following are among the contents of The
                                Homiletic Monthly for April; Sermonic; "Sin audits Reproof," by Joseph T. Duryea, D.D.;
                                "Difficulties of the Preacher," by Rev. Henry WardBeccher; Ko Waste in Love," by Joseph
                                Parker, D.D.; "Salvation and its adjuncts," by William Booth, D.D.; An Anniversary
                                Service: "Gratitude and Hopefulness," by T. De Witt Talmage, D.D. Then we have the
                                following papers : "Light on Important Texts," by Howard Crosby, D. D.; "Preaching to
                                Children," by Rev. W. F. Crafts; "Indexing a Clergyman's Library," by J. Stamford Holme,
                                D.D.; "Lecturers to my Students," by Rev. Charles II. Spurgcon. There are a score or
                                more of very suggestive articles, grouped under the heads of "Preachers Exchanging
                                Views," "Sermonic Criticisms," and "Living Issues for Pulpit Treatment." The magazine is
                                full of interest and instruction to clergymen and other students of Scripture. Price,
                                $2.50. per year; single number, 25 cents. Funk &amp; Wagnalls, 10 and 12 Dey Street,
                                New York. Herald of Health : April; Pub. by M. L. IIolbrook, 13 &amp; 15 Laight St.
                                N. Y. The "general articles" of this number are Habits of Journalists; Hygiene of the
                                Kitchen; The Child's Charter; Top-</p></div3></div2><pb id="p29" TEIform="pb"/><!--                     <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>