<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ss0509" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">Shaker and Shakeress</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Society</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Mount Lebanon, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">5</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">9</biblScope><date value="18750901" TEIform="date">September 1875</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">65-72</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="5" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="65" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="9" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">Vol. V. No. 9. PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETY. P. W. EVANS, , ¦•«-,» SlXTY Cents Editor. Mt* Lebanon Col. Co. N.
                        Y. September, 1875 PERANNUM.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spiritualists" TEIform="index"/>SPIRITUALISTS</head><p TEIform="p">Spiritualists are developing spiritual science, while Shakers are making it practical by putting it to its proper
                            uses. Spiritual movements, like stars in the firmament, have their risings and their settings — their voices of
                            promise and their frequent failures, in both letter and spirit. The barren figtree, after having been duly
                            digged about, yet found fruitless, was hewn down and " cast into the fire" — the fire of judgment. Has the
                            spiritualism, brought into public recognition nearly thirty years since, at Hydesville, New York, met the
                            expectations of its friends ? Are the devotees of Spiritualism purer, better, nobler than other people ? Are
                            they more honest, temperate, forgiving, benevolent, and self-sacrificing than other Protestant denominations ?
                            Our visionists prophesied of, and saw the workings of Spiritualism more than thirty years ago. The phenomena, as
                            facts, are not new. The u gifts," in some form, have always been in the world, and probably ever will be, as
                            witnesses of a future existence. But so far as resulting in any organization, or any general concert of action
                            for propagandism, for harmonizing the elements — for religious improvement, or benevolent purposes—it has proved
                            a failure. Though an angel of light having " great power," it has not proved itself an angel of salvation.
                            Spiritualists, with whom we converse, do not profess to be saved, nor to walk in the newness of the
                            resurrection. Disintegrated and divided, as their publications testify, they cry: " Lo, here ! " with V.
                            Woodhull ; " Lo, there !" with A. J. Davis ; or " Lo," in some other direction, " is Christ." Professing to have
                            no leaders, they are all leaders, clawing into each other like crabs in a bag. Surely, as words have meaning,
                            this is Babel ! While Spiritualism, as a science, is true, Spiritualists have not met our expectations. They are
                            not progressive. They continue in their bad habits. They love the fashions, the riches, and the pride of the
                            world. They " marry and are given in marriage." They fight, and, in many other ways, prove themselves anti
                            Christian. Mediums in cities are numerous; but to identify the " familiar spirits " communicating through them
                            is next to impossible. To " try " such spirits is like trying the case of Beecher and Til ton. Obsessions are
                            cDinmon. Some of this class have come to us to be " restored to their right mind." The materializations that we
                            witnessed a few months since at the Eddys were genuine ; and yet these materializing spirits, with few
                            exceptions, are from the lower spheres. They do good in so far as they prove a future life. Spiritually,
                            however, they are as children. Imposters, according to the Spiritualist journals, are numerous, while disorderly
                            circles and an irreligious spirit prevail extensively. If some get rich through clairvoyance, their riches often
                            take wings. Selfishness is the sin that so easily besets. Private property is neither Christian nor apostolic.
                            Most of the best Spiritualists, so we are informed, attend " liberal Christian denominations," and financially
                            support them. Many of the oldest lecturers upon Spiritualism, such as J. M. Spear, Joel Tiffany, A. E. Newton,
                            S. J. Finney, T.L. Harris, T. G. Forster, S. B. Britton, Emma Hardinge Britton, and others, do not now speak in
                            public. Andrew Jackson Davis neither lectures, attends lectures upon Spiritualism, nor the sessions of the
                            children's lyceums. So we are informed by a prominent New York Spiritualist. And then, where are Charles
                            Partridge, Dr. Gray, and others whom we used to meet in the New York conferences twenty and twenty-five years
                            since ? What does all this mean ? Are Spiritualists satisfied with themselves ? Satisfied with the lives they
                            live in a selfish, wrangling, competitive, fighting, speculating world of monopolies and legislative rings, with
                            the rich growing richer and the poor, poorer? My friend, the late Horace Greeley, once asked how long it " would
                            take to heat an oven with snow-balls." And, I ask, how long will it take Spiritualists to reform the world while
                            they continue in the fashions and evil practices of the world ? In Bible times, the angelic voice was, " Come ye
                            out from among them." This is now the voice of the Christ-spirit to Spiritualists. We have taken the ground all
                            along that Spiritualism was a science ; and, being a sci ence, lacking the religious element; lacking the
                            gathering, the harmonizing Christ principles of purity, consecration, and unselfish love, it would necessarily
                            degenerate into sharp individualisms, the " lusts of the flesh," the " pride of life," and the vain practices of
                            the world. When friend J. H. Harter, a Spiritualist preacher of Auburn, visited us, telling his trials among "
                            false brethren," and with unworthy clergymen, we could only say — while deeply sympathizing with him — that
                            those who choose to stay in the world must expect to be partakers of the world's tribulations. " I am not of the
                            world," said Jesus. And being not of the world, he had a " bread to eat that the world knew not of." Many
                            Spiritualists—excellent people after the world's model — as well as many in the Protestant churches, are
                            inquiring their way toward Shakerism — the church of the second coming — the pentecostal church, based upon the
                            Christprinciples of purity of life, peace, and " all things in common." We are pleased to know this. The Spirit
                            and the Bride say, come; come unto me all ye that labor and are heavy laden, and I will give you rest — the
                            "rest that remaineth for the people of God."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Visitors" TEIform="index"/>VISITORS</head><p TEIform="p">Recently, we have had Robert Cooper, an English traveler, who had spent two weeks at the Eddys', as a scientific
                            investigator of the supermundane phenomena occurring in their presence. His experience and observations are
                            given at great length, and in minute detail, in the " Religio-Philosophical Journal." His conclusion is, that no
                            person, of sound mind, unbiased by preconceived opinion, or partisan motives, can visit the Eddys, remain a
                            reasonable time, and come away other than a settled believer that spirits of men, women and children of
                            different ages, size, weight and general contour of face and body, and of various nationalities, do appear as
                            tangible materializations ; that they talk, dance, sing, lecture, prophesy and give tests, by knowledge of facts
                            respecting the history and domestic relations of the spectators, that dispel from their minds all doubts of the
                            supernatural origin and character of the manifestations. Robert Cooper is a cautious, cool, philosophical,
                            conservative Englishman. He is a witness, whose testimony would be taken in any Court of Law. J. J. Morse is a
                            trance medium, on a lecturing tour through the United States, and is also a believer in "Materialization."
                            Subjoined are a few lines of poetry of which he was the ostensible author. The Editor of the Shaker and
                            Shakeress became acquainted with both of these friends in London, and was pleased to meet them again in the New
                            World. "I MAY NOT BE A PROPHET." I may not be a prophet; but methinks T feel the time When freedom's breath
                            shall fan the cheeks of all in every clime; When labor shall be virtue, and religion shall be truth, And all
                            earth's sons and daughters shall enjoy a lasting youth! I may not be a prophet; but is not the era near, When
                            the Church will cease to rule men through dogma, creed, or fear? When human life and Nature's laws, in harmony
                            entwined, Will be the base of better lives, the Christ of all mankind ? I may not be a prophet; yet soon will
                            dawn the day When science and religion will the highest truths display; The voice of each, eternal, shall
                            resound throughout the land, A system then, for head and heart, will reign on every hand. I may not be a
                            prophet; but the time is almost here When the woman with the man shall stand and take her proper sphere.
                            Restricted and confined she's been, in all the ages past; Thank God! those states are almost dead —she will be
                            free at last. <pb n="66" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 66 SHAKEE A.ND I may not be a prophet; yet how soon may it arrive — That
                            epoch in the world's career when love for rule shall strive; The birth of peace, the death of war, the silencing
                            of gun, The prize of peace we're striving for will then be nobly won. I may not be a prophet; yet the fabled
                            time's at hand In which the nations shall combine as one united band. That day will see one God, one Church, one
                            government on earth, The long expected golden age, the truer second birth. I may not be a prophet; but methinks
                            I feel the time When freedom's breath shall fan the cheeks of all in every clime; When labor shall be virtue,
                            and religion shall be truth, And all earth's sons and daughters enjoy a lasting youth! New Haven, Conn., May
                            17,1875.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Moses and Jesus" TEIform="index"/>MOSES AND JESUS</head><p TEIform="p">It was one of the ambitions of our childhood to become wise enough to know how Moses, through the "law, was our
                            schoolmaster to bring us unto Christ." We think we have learned the lesson, at the expense of much damage to our
                            early religious education. It is conceded that general Christendom despise the Israelites — despise is a feeble
                            word to express the feelings of many, who think they are pretty good Christians. — It is common to hear them
                            terribly traduced ; and they must, apparently, forever, suffer the unequaled ignominy of killing the Lord Jesus!
                            Were I a Christian, after the heart of the so-called, popular, Christian Churches, I would thank the Jews as a
                            nation, and bless those who were conspicuous actors at the scene of Golgotha ; for have they not given to these
                            Churches the blood of Calvary, that they so fondly anticipate will be an atonement for the sins of their
                            miserable, sinning adherents ? The very common Sunday School impressions made on minds in the moulding state,
                            are, many times and in many directions, erroneous, cruel, wicked. By these we learned that the Jews were and are
                            a wicked, God-forsaken people — the very antipodes of true Christians; and that, after the appearance of Jesus,
                            the Mosaic statutes became of no effect — a worse than worthless instrument. As a consequence of such teachings,
                            tens of thousands of us became imbued with the idea that Jesus was not a Jew, but a born Christian ! that he did
                            not like the Jews ; that he taught doctrines, not only superior to, but the very reverse of those taught by
                            Moses ; and by his teaching aid example, his immediate disciples, and all who shall succeed them, were prompted
                            to discard and condemn the institutions of the great law-giver — Moses. These are terrible wrongs, committed in
                            the past, continued in the present, and for their correction, we ask a hearing while we cry " Halt !" to their
                            continued diffusion. I cannot conceive that doing Moses justice would be any detraction of Jesus ; and yet we
                            will compare some of his sublimest sayings with the same of Israel's prophets, and if they prove identical, or
                            nearly so, to whom shall we give the credit — Israel or Jesus ? That Jesus was a Jew, and did not assume his
                            Christos or Anointing, until he was thirty years of age, is too palpable to need proof, except with the very
                            ignorant. That he read the law for years, in the synagogues of the Jews, and expounded upon with all the
                            fascination of a brilliant, rising orthodox Rabbi, there is an abundance of proof in the gospels; and while not
                            doubting his loyalty, the people wondered whence this young man had so much wisdom ! His words breathed the
                            inspiration and the expression of the great days of prophecy. Isaiah never commended the law, nor more
                            faithfully followed it, than did Jesus of Nazareth. What could be stronger than " Till heaven and earth pass
                            away, one jot, or one title shall in no wise pass from the law, till all be fulfilled ? " Again, " Whoever
                            therefore shall break one of these commandments, or teach men to do so, he shall be called the least in the
                            kingdom of heaven." " Think not that I am come to destroy the law, or the influence of the prophets ; I am not
                            come to destroy, but to fulfill." In these sayings did the Jews perceive renewed demonstrations of the
                            permanence of the teachings of the great doctors of Israel; and they listened attentively to the new Rabbi, and
                            everywhere greeted him with this revered title. In a former paper we have stated, that had not Moses taken the
                            children of Israel out of Egypt, away from their bondage to physical and spiritual sins, we would never have had
                            a Jesus ! Herein is the key, how the law would teach us to come to Christ; even as in like manner it taught a
                            people so to live, that from them was produced so beautiful a specimen of humanity as was Jesus — one in whom
                            God's promise to Moses was fulfilled: " I will take all sickness from the midst of thee ! " Jesus kept the law,
                            and, as a consequence, his health ; and preached the gospel of health to his converts, teaching them, that by
                            keeping the laws of Moses, they would be in a prime condition to receive Christianity. I know of nothing, that I
                            think the spirit of Jesus has greater testimony against, to-day, than an unphysiological diet and practice of
                            life. And yet, there are many that are ready to affirm, that Christ cares only for the soul. It is beyond the
                            power of all Christs to resurrect the soul, while it is inhabiting a sickly, law-breaking body ! Let Moses
                            through the laws of health, be " the schoolmaster to bring us unto Christ." The baptism of Christ makes a reaper
                            of a sower, teaches the superiority of the angel, celibate estate, over the reproductive plane — resurrects from
                            the planting and sowing of the Adam, earthly to the harvesting, " cutting off from the earthly " condition, to
                            be as was Jesus — Christ — a Shaker! Did Jesus ever teach adversely to Moses ? Excepting a few instances, which
                            shall be noticed, I am persuaded that none did Moses more honor through obedience than did Jesus ; and none
                            indorsed the renderings of the law, as given by the prophets, any more than did he. So fully in accord with them
                            was he, that in his rebukes he followed in their footsteps, using almost identical language — (see Isa. I. II et
                            seq., and 58, 3, and continue); and then we find, that for what we have been giving Jesus credit, as an
                            originator, should have been more properly dated from the prophets. In the beauteous sermon on the Mount, who is
                            there but thinks that such sentiments were never uttered before ? Let us see : First, observe the scrupulous
                            care with which Jesus connected this sermon with the whole of Judaism. Here comes in the already quoted remark,
                            " I am not come to destroy the law;" and how frequently did he conclude, " That is the law and the prophets!"
                            Let the curious Bible reader compare the following passages : Matt. 5:5 with Psa. 32:11; Matt. 6:15 with Cant.
                            28:3, etc. In Talmud Massechet Kalah may be found: " He who looks upon a woman with impure intention, has, it
                            may be said, in so doing, committed adultery." Compare with Matt. 5:28. The principle of non-resistance
                            inculcated by Jesus will be found in almost identical language in the lamentations of Jeremiah, even to " he
                            giveth his cheek to be smitten ;" compare alsolVIatt. 5:44 with Lev. 19:17, 18; Ex. 23:4, 5 ; Ex. 23:17 ; and so
                            on through all the principal sayings of Jesus. There is no remark in all the beautiful sermon on the Mount, that
                            is so new, that its identity may not be found, in all richness in the older Bible or Talmud! The expressions,
                            that often follow : " Ye have heard that it was said by them of old," would almost lead us to think Jesus an
                            innovator, rising in condemnation of the past; which so far from being true, in the apparent repetition of
                            so-called statements, may rather be called a wholesale and indefensible calumny, which can be clearly proved!
                            The rebukes which Jesus uttered to the people, find an equal in the prophets ; and some of them sound like the
                            reading of the latter, as in Isa. 1:11, et seq. One subject of Jesus was particularly odious to Jews — his
                            professed divinity. For this they killed him, after giving him ample time to save himself if lie was divine. Not
                            being a believer in the Atonement, I am most sorrowful that Jesus was not left to die naturally ; when, I
                            believe, the Jews would have better understood him. By this provision, also, we might have been spared the
                            demoralization of Scripture as introduced by Paul, and learned by happy experience that Moses, through the law,
                            is yet " our schoolmaster to bring us to Christ," even as he so schooled Jesus.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/>G. A. Lomas, Shakers, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Extract of a letter from Wm. Wheeler" TEIform="index"/>Extract of a letter from Wm. Wheeler...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Extract of a letter from Wm. Wheeler, dated Hebron, Ind., June 23, 1875, to Elder J. S. Prescott, of North
                                Union, Ohio. " Please tell me if you believe in the Bible alone as the perfect rule and guide to heaven and
                                eternal life ? And also, will the " Shaker and Shakeress " allow our brief correspondence to be inserted in
                                it ? Please let me know. I hope to hear from you again soon. We join in sending our best love and wishes to
                                all. I must say I have particular regards for you and yours. Hoping all for the best,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wheeler, William" TEIform="persName"/>Wm. Wheeler, P. O. Box 38."</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reply" TEIform="index"/>REPLY</head><p TEIform="p">North Union, 0., June 28,1875. Wm. Wheeler, Dear Friend—Yours of the 23d inst. is received. We are not in
                                favor of theological discussions. If truth be the object, there is a better way to obtain it. It is well
                                known that we do not believe in the plenary inspiration of the Bible as being the only " perfect rule and
                                guide to heaven and eternal life." We believe that some parts of the old and new Testaments were given by
                                holy men of God, who wrote and spake as they were moved by Holy Spirits, the same as some do in this day.
                                The Bible of to-day, the day and age in which we live, is as much an infallible guide to heaven and eternal
                                life as the Bible of two thousand years ago, and more reliable, because it has never been corrupted by
                                translators. We believe that other parts of the Bible contain discrepancies and contradictions—¦ words of
                                wicked men and lying spirits, the same as are ministering in this day. It is generally admitted, and that
                                too by some of the greatest sticklers of Bible infallibility, that some parts of the old Testament are too
                                ottscene to be read before a public audience or a promiscuous assembly. And some parts of the Bible are
                                simply historical, and no more the " word of God " than the history of Rome or of the American rebellion.
                                And yet it is all summed up as the only infallible word of God. What an absurdity ! "All scripture given by
                                inspiration of God, whether ancient or modern, is profitable for doctrine, for reproof, for correction, for
                                instruction in righteousness, that the man of God maybe perfect — thoroughly furnished unto all good works."
                                2d Timothy, 3d, 16, 17. The design of all scripture, given by inspiration of God, both Jewish and Christian,
                                was the perfecting of the saints, the man and woman of God, that they might be thoroughly furnished unto all
                                good works. But how have these scriptures been perverted to sectarian purposes even unto the present day ?
                                Hence the necessity of a " more sure word of prophecy —' present Revelation' — whereunto we do well to take
                                heed as unto a light that shineth in a dark place." We are aware of the powerful organization now forming to
                                get the Protestant Bible, with all its imperfections, engrafted into the Constitution of the United States.
                                And what is all this for ? Is it to give these anti-christian Priestly bigots a chance to burn heretics and
                                all who will not subscribe to their religious dogmas 1 May Heaven save us from such a back-set into the dark
                                ages, is the prayer of thy friend</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescott, James S." TEIform="persName"/>Jas. S. Prescott</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Retaliation" TEIform="index"/>Retaliation.</head><p TEIform="p">Never retaliate nor seek revenge for real or supposed wrongs. By rendering good for evil, we not only disarm our
                            enemies, but oftentimes make them our truest friends.</p></div2><pb n="67" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bright side" TEIform="index"/>THE BRIGHT SIDE</head><p TEIform="p">Man's free agency allows him to view, either the bright, or dark side of life. Unrestrained by the invisible
                            powers, his aspirations produce the " conditions " which attract his proper spirit guides. If he court a
                            cheerful disposition, with pure and holy thought, the bright angels are his guides and constant companions.
                            Consequently he perceives the bright side of every thing and becomes a " bright and shining light." To those in
                            the " slough of despond " a beacon to guide them to higher and firmer ground. Imagination is the chief agent for
                            producing dark forebodings in the human mind, which are usually followed by disease and premature death. The
                            fact that Shakers, who love light, rather than darkness, and numerically considered in proportion to the masses
                            of the generative world, retain their physical life and vigor much longer than their neighbors of the natural
                            order, is due, in a great measure, to an unclouded conscience, and the dismission of imaginary condemnations
                            from their minds. It is recorded, that one of the primitive apostles of the Christ order, said, " From whence
                            come wars," etc. " Is it not from the lust which is in your members ? " It matters little with us, however,
                            whether these words were uttered by apostle or apostate. We know it is the truth. When lust is conceived in the
                            members, we soon become discontented with our surroundings, the life of purity becomes a grievous cross, the
                            wheels of progression are clogged, retrogression follows, darkness begins to obscure our spiritual vision and
                            our last state is worse than our first. When the unregenerated, in or out of Zion, are in the light, they
                            perceive it not. " Having eyes, they see not." Physical death is their " king of terrors " and they have no
                            victory over the grave. Community order, on the basis of celibacy and progress, is the consummation of the "
                            Kingdom of Heaven," to every truly regenerated soul. God's children are all equal " on change " — priest,
                            prophet and king — for all, who put on Christ, become priests and kings unto righteousness. Speaking of
                            communism the Boston Christian Era of March 18, 1875, says : " As a means for securing a comfortable animal
                            existence these communistic systems are successful. As aids for the developments of the spiritual and
                            intellectual life they are failures . : . they are of the earth, earthy. It is not from these that the social
                            and industrial redemption of the world will come forth." Leaving out the class of communists that are of the "
                            earth, earthy," I think our friend, by careful investigation, will find the average intellectuality and
                            spiritual developments of the Shaker fraternity on far, if not a little above, the masses of the private family
                            order. As to the redemption of the world, in the generative point of view, the Shakers spare no pains within
                            their power, to endeavor to elevate the sons of Adam to the standard of true humanity — righteous generation —
                            but it should be remembered that this is a deed of charity on their part, for the general good of the human
                            race, as their work is of an entirely different nature, viz.: Regeneration. Does it become those who profess to
                            '' love the ways of Jesus," to condemn the institutions of those who both love and follow his ways and receive
                            unto their homes and hearts every truly sinsick soul who flees from mystical and false theologies of Babylon,
                            aiding them by example as well as precept " to rise to joys of the Angelic birth 1 For nearly twenty centuries
                            the earth order have been looking for the redemption of the world, through the " blood " instead of the life of
                            Jesus. " New lights" have and are constantly rising upon the horizon of their troubled sea, only to be dimmed by
                            newer rivals. But the " age of reason," which is fast dawning, teaches them that nothing is of value, unless it
                            can be practically applied, that the zenith of human redemption can be attained only by a practical application
                            of the doctrines set forth in the earth life of Jesus,who became the first fruits of purity through the
                            spontaneous baptism of the Christ-Spirit. He rose from the sin-beclouded spheres of lustful generation, into the
                            bright spheres of eternal purity, and became the then " only Son of God," with power to confer the same honor
                            upon his followers, through all time, by owning them as brethren and sisters and " sons and daughters" of "our
                            father and mother — God." Have we not then the bright side for our portion? Can there be any dark side with the
                            " redeemed of earth ? " Then let " Storms of woe and whirlwinds rise, Bach cord on earth to sever, There bright
                            and joyous as the skies There is our home for ever." On the bright side.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Howard, Emery E." TEIform="persName"/>Emery E. Howard, South Hadley, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Adulterated candy" TEIform="index"/>ADULTERATED CANDY</head><p TEIform="p">A late writer on the subject insists that candy is injurious, not only to the teeth, but the stomach, and hence
                            to the health of children and adults. The oils and acids used in flavoring are particularly dangerous. He says
                            the jargonelle pear flavor is made of the acetate of amylic ether, which is prepared by distilling a mixture of
                            fusil oil, acetate of potash and concentrated sulphuric acid. The pineapple is made from butyric ether dissolved
                            in another portion of alcohol. Butyric acid is made from decaying cheese, grape sugar and chalk, fermented
                            together. Various mixtures of the ethers, with the addition of various agents, such as acetic acid, camphor,
                            orris, vanilla, the volatile oils, etc., result in imitations of strawberry, raspberry, apricot, currant, etc.
                            The tonka bean is used very much in place of the vanilla pod, to imitate the vanilla flavor. The common oil of
                            almond (bitter) always contains a considerable amount of prussic acid. This oil is said to be substituted
                            sometimes by the oil of mirbane or nitro-benzole, eight or nine drops of which is said to have produced death.
                            The peach and almond flavors are also imitations, made from prussic acid in some form, and are very
                        poisonous.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Extract from a letter to Elijah Myrick" TEIform="index"/>Extract from a letter to Elijah Myrick</head><p TEIform="p">Ayer, Mass. Buckland, Mass., July 4,1875. My dear Friend and Brother : I have been re-reading all those beautiful
                            and God-like utterances of the Shaker and Shakeress. Truly, if ever divinity shaped mortal aims and purposes,
                            and clothed in spirit dress and power, the thoughts and words of mortal men and women, it has been done in the
                            productions of this blessed paper. I think I see clearly a special new spiritual and physical revelation of
                            divine love and mercy to the race of man, in the inception and active promulgation of the principles underlying
                            the economy and faith of the Shaker system. Looking over the declaration of principles and the holy life and
                            simple purity exhibited in the whole system of Shaker life, I feel constrained to exclaim Eureka! the remedy is
                            found. I think Shakerism the only remedy for the miseries, political, moral and theological, of the race. I
                            think the solution of the perplexing labor question can be found in the Shaker community system only. I see
                            clearly that the only certain antidote for the moral pestilence, the social evil, is seen in Shaker celibacy.
                            The cure for financial ruin and distress can be found in the Shaker simplicity of dress and life. I fully
                            realize that the restoration of humanity to the blessings of full physical health and a development of full
                            physical beauty and moral and mental force, can be reached by a strict adherence to the Shaker system of food
                            and labor. In short, I am fully convinced that if men learn war no more, beat their swords into plow-shares, if
                            the lion in humanity lie down with the lamb, it must be done in and through a channel precisely like the life of
                            the disciples of Ann Lee. Your brother for truth, humanity, for God,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Alcott, William" TEIform="persName"/>William Alcott</byline></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Second visit to the Eddys" TEIform="index"/>SECOND VISIT TO THE EDDYS.</head><p TEIform="p">The Editor, accompanied by Eldress Antoinette and Louisa Green, has spent four days at Chittenden.
                            Result—Confirmation. See next number of Shaker and Shakeress.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mother Shipton's prophecy" TEIform="index"/>Mother Shipton's prophecy
                        </head><p TEIform="p">[From the Springfield Republican.] <cit TEIform="cit"><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Springfield republican" TEIform="index"/></bibl><quote TEIform="quote">MOTHER SHIPTOFS PROPHECYEvery now and then, for these four hundred years and more, some one has
                                    brought to light the prophecy and memory of Mother Shipton. As event follows event in mechanical
                                    progress, her doggerel verses fall in so pat that they must needs be quoted. One of the predictions
                                    thereof — "Fire and water shall wonders do"—has come to pass time and again, and the latest fulfillment
                                    is the Keely motor. This Mother Shipton was one that would have taken high rank as a medium in our day;
                                    in hers, the fifteenth century, she was said to have been begotten, like the wizard Merlin, of the
                                    phantasm of Apollo, or some aerial demon under that guise, and a beautiful orphan Yorkshire girl named
                                    Agatha. She had the weird lonely girlhood that the child of shame is apt to have, avoided or persecuted
                                    by those who should have been her mates. She was christened Ursula by the Abbot of Beverly, and grew up
                                    so eccentric and unnaturally shrewd that by and by this tradition, in those superstitious days, grew
                                    about her birth. She prophesied as she grew older, and even " persons of quality " consulted her. She
                                    told the great Wolsey that he should never come to York, and, indeed, when within eight miles of it, he
                                    was arrested by Northumberland, at King Henry's order, and brought to Leicester, where he died. Also,
                                    she is said to have foretold the great fire of London, the execution of Charles I, and many notable
                                    events, besides of the Reformation and the reigns of Elizabeth and James. At the age of seventy-three
                                    she foretold her death, and at the hour predicted she died. Her name is a popular tradition in Yorkshire
                                    even to-day, and the tradition is founded in part upon fact. Her famous prophecy was said to have been
                                    published in her life-time, and again two hundred years ago, for we have seen it in a book of that time,
                                    where it was said to be copied from an older book. Though most of the items are vague enough, some show
                                    a marked coincidence with remarkable events, such as the invention of steam, railway locomotives and
                                    tunnels, the telegraph, iron-clads, and the admission of Jews into Parliament (in 1858). Without further
                                    preface, these are the elegant lines : Carriages without horses shall go, And accidents fill the world
                                    with woe ; Around the world thoughts shall fly In the twinkling of an eye. Water shall yet more wonders
                                    do, Now strange, but yet they shall be true ; The world upside down shall be, And gold be found at the
                                    root of a tree ; Through hills man shall ride, And horse nor ass be at his side; Under water men shall
                                    walk, Shall ride, shall sleep, shall talk; In the air shall men be seen, In white, in black, in green;
                                    Iron in the water shall float As easy as a wooden boat; Gold shall be found and shown In land that's not
                                    now known ; Fire and water shall wonders do; England shall at last admit a Jew ; The world to an end
                                    shall come In eighteen hundred and eighty-one.</quote></cit></p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reform" TEIform="index"/>REFORM</head><p TEIform="p">On the first day of April, 1872, there were four brethren in the Canaan Upper Family who used tobacco. Now there
                            are none. The reform came in this manner : One day, Elder Frederick called at our house and asked to see those
                            four brethren. After we were seated, he began to talk about tobacco, and called it some hard names, which,
                            though true enough, we did not all of us like to hear. But, as long as he generalized and confined his remarks
                            to tobacco alone, we did not feel much disturbed. It was soon evident, however, he now meant something more. He
                            had come bearing a proposition, sanctioned by the ministry, that all the brethren in our little group who used
                            tobacco should now quit it. This was a "hard saying, who could bear it ? " " I'll quit it," said the eldest of
                            the four; and he has kept his promise to this day. Another argued stoutly for his quid, as if it were a good
                            thing ; but finally came up to the help of the Lord against the nauseous weed, and like a good Believer,
                            determined to conquer or die. He, too, has kept his resolution, and a short time since handed me two large plugs
                            of navy tobacco, saying <pb n="68" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 68 8HAKEE with a pleasant smile on his face, " I have not put a bit
                            of tobacco into my mouth from that day to this, nor shall I, as long as I live." The other two also took sharp
                            hold of the proposition and are steadfast. January 1, 1874, there were four brethren of our small group, of
                            about thirty souls, who ate animal food. Now there is but one. We have used in the past year 1,500 pounds
                            unbolted wheat meal; 1,400 pounds unbolted corn meal; 800 pounds of oatmeal.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Greaves, Charles" TEIform="persName"/>Charles Greaves, Canaan, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harvest period" TEIform="index"/>THE HARVEST PERIOD</head><p TEIform="p">The millennial age, or thousand years' reign of the saints, upon earth, with Christ, is the harvest age of the
                            race, in which time, be it longer or shorter, the Everlasting Gospel will be preached to every creature, and all
                            souls will enter the judgment— a new probation for their final order. It is the transition period of the race,
                            from their natural life, to the spiritual. It is the disciplinary stage, for the final rest — the glorified
                            state of all who receive the merciful offer of Christ, in his anointed messengers, and volunteer to follow his
                            self-denying footsteps, to life everlasting. Its duration may vary from 7 to 70 or 100 years, according to
                            diligence and faithfulness, after the work is begun. These messengers, or rulers — for they sit upon Thrones of
                            Judgment, and reign with Christ — are beheaded for the witness of Jesus, and the word of God. This signifies,
                            they have ceased to follow the lead of their own self-will and wisdom — the head of the earthly man — and have
                            submitted their necks to the Gospel yoke, whereby Christ has become their head. They are slain to the worldly,
                            or selfish life, by the cross of Christ, and by the sharp sword of the word of God, sitting upon purified human
                            tabernacles, likened to white horses. Their carnal pleasures, likened to flesh, from whence they arise, are
                            given to the fowls of the air and beasts of the desert, to whom they properly belong. Thus they are put to
                            death, flesh-wise, and quickened spiritwise, and bear witness for the Truth, as Jesus* did, by dying as he died,
                            to a self-pleasing life, and living as he lived, a life of Righteousness — daily rising from the dead, by
                            walking in newness of life.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo" TEIform="persName"/>Alonzo Hollister, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bolted superfine flour vs. teeth" TEIform="index"/>BOLTED SUPERFINE FLOUR VS. TEETH</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Cutter, Ephraim" TEIform="persName"/>EPHRAIM CUTTER, M. D.</byline><p TEIform="p">From <cit TEIform="cit"><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Boston journal of chemistry" TEIform="index"/>Boston Journal of Chemistry</bibl><quote TEIform="quote">BOLTED SUPERFINE FLOUR VS. TEETH. There is no doubt that the decay of teeth prevails to an alarming
                                    extent, and it is very humiliating to our modern civilization to have it characterized so generally by
                                    the occurrence of diseased teeth. The aetiology of this disease is a great, broad, and deep subject. No
                                    doubt many elements combine together to cause it; and the person who should positively announce a single
                                    agent would be dismissed as unworthy of attention. Still it is a matter worth discussing, and deserving
                                    the attention of the ablest minds. To ignore is not to arrest; hence we offer a few suggestions for
                                    consideration. " The Chemical News ascribes the potato rot to a deficiency of lime and magnesia in the
                                    soil. Different observers state the percentage of magnesia in the ash of sound tubers at from five to
                                    ten per cent.; in the diseased tubers an analysis shows only 3.94 per cent. Analysis of sound tubers
                                    shows over five per cent, of lime, but in the ash of diseased tubers only 1.77 per cent, was found. A
                                    similar observation was made some years ago by Professor Thorpe, with regard to diseased and healthy
                                    orange-trees; in the former there was a deficiency of lime and magnesia." According to these
                                    authorities, a deficiency of mineral salts in the vegetations named is supposed to be a sufficient cause
                                    for decay. Now it is an interesting question whether there is any article of food employed by mankind
                                    which is deficient in mineral matter. If so, then it should be made known to every family in the land.
                                    Perhaps there is no article of food more generally consumed than flour, i. e., wheat flour. In the forms
                                    of bread, cakes, and pastry of all kinds, it enters into every house, and is universally used and
                                    regarded as the "staff of life." Does flour possess a requisite amount of mineral matter ? To answer
                                    this question, Mr. Sharpies, the wellknown chemist, analyzed for me the "Peerless Flour." He found 0.55
                                    per cent of mineral ash, a little over half of one per cent. He stated also that the proportion of ash
                                    in the whole grain varied from 1.65 to 2.50 per cent. So that the diminution of mineral food varies from
                                    two-thirds to four-fifths. In other words, by the use of flour mankind loses from two-thirds to
                                    four-fifths of the elements that go to make up teeth and bony structures. This statement deserves to be
                                    written in letters of gold over the door of every bakery and kitchen in the land. Flour has been used
                                    for generations, and if we can rely upon Mr. Sharpies' statement, mankind has all this while been
                                    deprived of the greater moiety of the mineral food that the Almighty intended it should have the benefit
                                    of. Is it not natural to expect that the bony structures should suffer from this great withdrawal? For
                                    it is a great withdrawal. Suppose that a water supply pipe should be cut off two-thirds to four-fifths,
                                    would not the supply be greatly diminished ? Cut off the same quantity of time from the hours of
                                    daylight, would not our darkness be great? Take away two-thirds to four-fifths of our muscular food,
                                    would not a strong man become very weak? Cut off air to the same extent, would we not lose our breath ?
                                    And why should the bony tissues not suffer in like manner when their food is withdrawn? I think they do.
                                    Perhaps a little evidence in the contrary direction may throw light upon this. A dentist, whose name is
                                    well known, said that he filled some fourteen cavities in the teeth of his first-born child by the time
                                    he was four years of age. He put his family upon the use of the whole grains, and the next child had no
                                    retarded detention, and not a decayed tooth up to the same age. The same gentleman says that the teeth
                                    which decay are not compacted or knit together with the firmness of healthy teeth. There seems to be an
                                    arrest of perfect development. Though what can be more natural than to expect imperfect development and
                                    decay, when from two-thirds to fourfifths of the proper bone food is habitually withdrawn from an
                                    article of diet which is more largely used than any other? How common it is to see infants not cutting
                                    any teeth at all, until they are twice as old as they ought to be. The good effect of the whole grain
                                    diet is shown in Dr. Harriman's second child, above alluded to. To be sure it is only one case, and must
                                    not be made too much of. Now, what is to be done about it? Certainly, one man's dicta amount to but very
                                    little alone. What we need is evidence from others. Suppose every medical association of Massachusetts
                                    take up this matter, have analyses of flour made, try feeding mothers and children upon the whole grain
                                    of wheat meal, oat meal, corn meal, beans, etc., and suppose they all come to the same conclusion as the
                                    writer has done. Suppose they officially announce the result. Would it be long before the general public
                                    would heed the truth, and thousands of persons would rejoice in the possession of that priceless
                                    treasure, a set of perfect teeth ? Note.—Through the kindness of Mr. E. H.Davis, Superintendent of
                                    Public Schools in Woburn, Mass., the writer has been furnished with the following astounding statistics,
                                    embracing returns from several of the largest primary schools of Woburn, a fair representation of the
                                    prevalence of diseased teeth among children : No. of With sound scholars. teeth. Decayed. Lawrence
                                    Primary...... 113 13 100 Plympton St. Primary .. 94 27 67 Highland St. Primary... 71 25 46</quote></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Egotism" TEIform="index"/>EGOTISM</head><p TEIform="p">We, is the Community pronoun. It seldom offends the ear. We build the mill, and make the dam. We harvest the
                            Broom corn, and our money is in the Bank. We bought that farm, and paid $200, for the sorrel horse. This is our
                            house, and shop. We baked the bread, and made the dinner. Neither in, nor out, of community, is the ear offended
                            by this use of pronouns. Should we substitute 1, for we, and my, for ours, we alter the case, and run the risk
                            of offending the ear, if not more. Some years ago, an aged man planted a nursery. When Budding and Grafting time
                            came, he took, as assistant, a youth, who had been apprenticed to him, as Shoemaker. The youth became an adept,
                            and the entire care of this branch of the business devolved on him. One day, the aged brother was in
                            conversation, with another person, on the thriftiness and good order of the nursery. The youth, being within
                            hearing, noticed that the aged brother invariably said my nursery — 1 grafted those apple trees — 1 budded those
                            peach and quince trees. It was all / and mine — never a we, nor ours. Some persons are, unfortunately, so
                            developed in selfhood, that touch what they may — be connected with whom they will, they seem to think, the
                            success — if success there be — was largely owing to their wisdom, skill and manoeuvering. Few things fill
                            sensitive minds with deeper regret, than the effort, some persons make, to trumpet their own fame. They may, in
                            the main, have a fair record for just dealing, correct business habits and capacity; yet nothing whereof to be
                            vain. Had they been content with the consciousness of having done their duty, they might have finished their
                            mortal pilgrimage with good repute. From the miserable, selfish /, mine, and me, Good Lord, deliver us. We have
                            been told, that in other worlds, man's employ will largely consist in praising God. But what time will Egotists
                            find for such employ ? Habits are stubborn things. His penchant for self glorification will go with him. Let us
                            get out of our miserable selves, into community Heaven, and find an element in community praise. In community
                            life, it may not readily appear where praise, or blame belongs. Hence none should claim credit, largely, who are
                            not willing to take their share of blame. Of Josephine, it was said, She was the Power, behind the screen, that
                            gave success to the Armies of France. Her Wisdom and Gentleness sustained the Empire. When they were withdrawn,
                            the Empire fell — and great was the fall. There are reasons for believing, that in Community life, the real
                            worthies — the successful operators on the electric wires, who, by the force of their magnetism, give success to
                            our efforts, are but little known. They council in secret, and point where Wisdom directs — where success will
                            result. They weep over the failures and short-comings of Society—rejoice in the prosperity of all, and are
                            content to suffer, if Society prospers. Are not these the Fathers and Mothers, around whom the sacred influences
                            of our Gospel principles cluster, fathers and mothers whose unassuring, unobtrusive influence makes glad the
                            Zion of God ? And when the seekers of self praise are lost in forgetfulness, shall not these remain a blessing
                            and a praise to our sacred cause ?</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Reynolds, William" TEIform="persName"/>William Reynolds, Union Village, 0.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to break off bad habits" TEIform="index"/>HOW TO BREAK OFF BAD HABITS</head><p TEIform="p">Understand the reason, and all the reasons, why the habit is injurious. Study the subject until there is no
                            lingering doubt in your mind. Avoid the places, the persons and the thoughts that lead to the temptation.
                            Frequent the places, associate with the persons, indulge in the thoughts that lead away from temptation. Keep
                            busy ; idleness is the strength of bad habits. Do not give up the struggle when you have broken your resolution
                            once, twice— a thousand times. That only shows how much need there is for you to strive. When you have broken
                            your resolution, just think the matter over, and endeavor to understand why it is you failed, so that you maybe
                            on your guard against a recurrence of the same circumstances. Do not think it is an easy thing that you have
                            undertaken. It is a folly to expect to break off a bad habit in a day, which may have been gathering long
                        years.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Goodness in childhood and youth is the beauty of old age..." TEIform="index"/>Goodness in childhood and youth is the beauty of old age...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Goodness in childhood and youth is the beauty of old age. Any system of theology that shocks the mind of a child
                            is a false system.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Paine, Thomas" TEIform="persName"/>Thomas Paine</byline></div2><pb n="69" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakeress" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERESS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">At no time during the Ministry of the Apostle Paul, was he more deeply imbued with the Christ-Spirit, or had a
                            clearer perception of the duties of those who would live holily, than when he said " Be not conformed to, but be
                            transformed from the world. Ye are the temple of the living God. What agreement hath the temple of God with
                            idols ? Come out from among them and be separate; touch, taste, and handle not the unclean things thereof, and I
                            will receive you, and be a Father unto you. I beseech you by the mercies of the living God, that ye present your
                            bodies a living sacrifice, holy, and acceptable unto Him, which is your reasonable service." Have principles
                            changed since that time ? If a separation from the world, and a cross against the carnal mind were requisite to
                            the attainment of a true Christian character in the days of Jesus and his apostles, why not at the present time
                            ? The views, and teachings of the early Christians, have become antiquated ; and the popular theologians of
                            to-day, who are paid from five hundred to a hundred thousand dollars annually to preach smooth things, tell
                            their hearers to go their way, "eat, drink and be merry ;" they will not be brought to judgment for secret sins,
                            nor be rewarded according to their works. If they will only believe on Jesus, he will be their sponsor and
                            expiate their sins. They may continue to eat their own bread, live in worldly and carnal pleasure, "and wear
                            their own apparel," if called by the Christian name. And the people, as with one voice, respond, " Give us more
                            pleasure, and less of the cross of self-denial, and we will bestow honor, praise and riches upon our venerable
                            Clergy, crown them with laurels while living, and decorate their graves with floral contributions." The same
                            spirit is seeking to find entrance, and rule in the Shaker Order. And a voice from without is constantly
                            pleading with members of our institution, to " come down from the cross." It is said that we practice too much
                            self-restraint — that the line of demarkation is too apparent — that in manners, in dress and life-practice we
                            are too distinct from the world. They say, they like the Shakers, and if we would renounce some of the
                            peculiarities, which make us singular and unpopular, then we could fraternize; and many people who are seeking a
                            quiet home of rest, but cannot find it, would join out Community. A dear sister of the Shaker fraternity, who
                            has passed beyond four score years, sensibly, feeling the force of the worldly element, in different forms,
                            striving to undermine and destroy the very foundations of the Church of Christ in this day, writes to me,
                            confidentially, in regard to it. Her motherly and saintly spirit is pained at the apparent lack of faith in God,
                            and the growing desire of a class who bear the name of Believers, for more present pleasure and enjoyment in
                            worldly things, at the expense of their spiritual life, and soul's welfare. And I take the liberty, without her
                            knowledge, to make some extracts, hoping to benefit a few, and not do harm to any. When I meet a person, who has
                            lived in the service of God as many years as our venerable sister has done, with mental power so clear and with
                            spirit bright and inspirational. I am reminded of the saying of Christ, "I am the resurrection. He that liveth
                            and believeth in Me, shall never die." Our sister has lived the Christ-life —done the works — and knows on whom
                            she has believed. We may be numerically weak, yet be strong in virtue and spiritual power, or vice versa. About
                            the time of the recent revival in Plymouth Church, when over a hundred were added to that sanctuary in one day —
                            majority females — a young woman was visiting in our family ; and as she stood curling her hair in ringlets, at
                            which she had been engaged a long time — she remarked, "I am going to join the Church next Sabbath." "Forwhat
                            purpose," inquired one of the sisters ? "Is your motive to live more in conformity to Christ's teachings ?" "
                            Oh, no," she replied; "that time has passed by. No one is now expected to change their habits of life by joining
                            the Church. I can get access to certain individuals, and enjoy their society better if I join the Church, than
                            if I remain isolated from it;" intimating that it was more fashionable, and popular to be connected with some
                            Church, than to remain outside. How many such Christians would it take to make one perfect h eaven ?</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beloved Eldress Antoinette:" TEIform="index"/>Beloved Eldress Antoinette:</head><p TEIform="p">I would not willingly trespass upon your time, but I wish to unfold some of my thoughts, and disburden my mind to
                            you. I feel that I am committing myself to a faithful friend, unto whom I may speak confidentially. The
                            importance of the subject that I would portray, so impresses me, that I feel impelled to write to you. I realize
                            that my mental and physical powers are waning, and my best efforts are somewhat feeble. I perceive, in a certain
                            class of professed Believers, a great lack of Faith and Spirituality ; and such are fearful that the work of God
                            in the Millennial Order is dying out; because there are not greater accessions to our ranks. I cannot view the
                            subject in that light. I see the Sun rising, higher and higher in the spiritual horizon, as the day advances.
                            The increase of truth does not depend upon numbers. I am confident that many of the more spiritual and
                            enlightened class in society are now looking toward Zion for something higher and better than what they have yet
                            attained. Let her inhabitants keep the love-fires constantly burning on her altars ; and many truth-lovers, and
                            truth-seekers, will see the light, and be attracted to her Courts. As a senior member of the household of faith,
                            in this day of Christ's Second Appearing, I feel to ask in a spirit of kindness and sisterly love, that all
                            would strive to maintain true Christ-like forbearance and consideration; that the bond of peace may remain
                            unbroken, and the unity of the spirit be preserved in this time of conflicting opinions. It is noble, and
                            praiseworthy, to seek for new and increasing light; but it is unwise to let different views of minor importance
                            hinder the full flow of pure love from circulating through all the members of the body. New developments, in
                            religion and science, should be met by calm investigation instead of opposition and persecution. As far as 1
                            have obeyed the injunction—" Try the Spirit " — making due allowance for crudeness and error, — which always
                            attend the evoluting process of newly revealed truth — I have found safety. It is wise to look at principles —
                            to trace things to their source—thence to their ultimates as far as possible. Then reason, if not perverted,
                            will aid us in arriving at j ust conclusions. Truth will ultimately gather all its subjects into one spirit, and
                            God's people will see eye to eye in all things; but it will be a work of time. We need patience, even as the
                            husbandman, when he has deposited the precious wheat in the soil, awaits its growth and maturity bofore it can
                            be harvested; and then, it must pass through the process of threshing, cleansing and grinding, to make it ready
                            for use. So must we work, wait and trust, for the growth and unfoldment of new and advancing truths. Not hearers
                            of the word only, but doers of the work, will grow into a knowledge of true doctrine — be able to understand the
                            will of God and to do it — for through patience they will prove all things and hold fast the true and good. If
                            there be a division in sentiment, the enemy has the vantage ground and will work to hinder a spiritual harvest,
                            which may be nearer than, many now anticipate. According to both ancient and modern prophecy, the Law will go
                            forth, from Zion, to earth's inhabitants. There is a constant draught from without upon the strength and
                            vitality of our institution, which few seem to realize; but it causes spiritual debility and the members feel
                            that strength and life go from them,—as did Jesus when the woman touched the hem of his garment, — even if they
                            do not know where it goes. Believers sympathize with, and contribute to the support of all true reforms; but in
                            so doing we need unremitting energy to keep a separation from foreign, worldly influences, that would serve to
                            divide and dismember, or cause dissension in any way. O how much we need to watch, and to pray, that Angels,
                            from high and holy spheres, may guide and keep us! As I near the change that I feel is coming upon me, I
                            frequently review my life, from childhood to the present time ; and as I read the pages of my life-history — the
                            spiritual losses and gains — all the awakenings of conscience that I have experienced, which have brought me to
                            feel deep tribulation and Godly sorrow, and to utter strong cries to God for greater self-conquering power, have
                            helped me to quicken my pace for heaven, made my spirit more vigorous and active, and have filled my soul with
                            peace. I do not wish to leave this world in a state of stupor, from which it will take a long time to emerge. It
                            is my earnest desire to go to my home and friends in spirit spheres, living and growing; that I may commence my
                            work there, just where I leave it here. I have not attained unto the present state of peace and justification,
                            which I now feel, by blending and uniting with the spirit and practice of the world. I wish to give my testimony
                            in favor of a pure consecrated, life, and of non-conformity to the world, in dress, or manners. My spirit is in
                            unison with the founders of our Order. They strictly enjoined self-denial and crucifixion of the carnal mind and
                            all inferior •loves. It is claimed, by some, that if we would increase in numbers, we must conform more to the
                            people of the world, in manners, and in habits of life. What has been our experience in this regard, where the
                            experiment has been tried? Where concessions have been made, have our numbers been increased, or diminished
                            thereby? Or, has the power that is effectual in protecting souls from sin, been strengthened, or weakened ?
                            Justice demands, that we look at things j ust as they are; and then decide, whether it be a real desire to help
                            lift humanity to higher and better conditions that induce to action, or the pleadings of the worldly nature
                            within our own hearts, that seeks gratification, and goes forth to meet the spirit of the world without, that
                            would allure, and draw souls away from the pure virgin life. The greatest ingathering to Christ's fold, that /
                            have ever witnessed, was at a time, when there was the most exclusion from without, and the strongest and most
                            searching testimony, within our own courts, against all sin-producing causes. While a separation from the world
                            is necessary to maintain the Christian life and character, it is our duty to treat all with kindness and
                            respect, and to be ready to give to all a reason for our hope of eternal life, and to present the cross of
                            Christ by which we are redeemed unto God. In conclusion let me say, the " Shaker and Shakeress " is a real treat
                            to me; and I know <pb n="70" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 7O SHAKER A. 1ST 13 very few in Harvard, Shirley, or elsewhere, who could
                            bear the idea of having the paper discontinued. We hail its monthly arrival with joy ; it seems so much like
                            having a sweet visit with our dear Gospel friends at the Mount, and in other societies. I hope nothing will
                            occur to render it necessary to discontinue it. We recently had a brief, but very pleasing and instructive
                            interview with Elder Frederick. It was soul-cheering to witness the true Christ-like spirit that he manifested
                            on all occasions while with us. I suppose you are nearing the time of your annual " Social Gathering." How
                            delighted I should be, to be present, and participate with you. That Heaven's blessing may ever attend those
                            meetings, is the prayer of your aged friend and sister.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bathrick, Eunice" TEIform="persName"/>Eunice Bathrick (aged 84), Ayer, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The following communication is from..." TEIform="index"/>The following communication is from a Shaker Sister,
                            eighty-five years of age</head><p TEIform="p">Paul's exhortation to the Hebrews, " Seeing we are compassed about with so great a cloud of witnesses, let us lay
                            aside every weight," etc., will apply with force, reason and profit, to Believers in our own time. Another
                            octogenarian speaks through our little Monthly. She has proved the efficacy of Gospel faith — reduced to
                            practice — more than seventy years. Hear her: Ed. Eldress Antoinette : Dear Sister — I feel greatly interested
                            in the Shaker and Shakeress, and hail every new number with joy ; would be pleased if it were a weekly issue
                            instead of a monthly. Seeing many testimonies from brethren and sisters, that I love and prize for their work's
                            sake, inspires me to briefly add mine. While reading the Shaker and Shakeress I have been reminded of the flying
                            roll seen by the Prophet Zachariah which was sent forth as an accuser through the land, condemning sin in every
                            form. It is a]so a messenger of glad tidings to sorrow-stricken, sinladen, repentant souls. As I have nearly run
                            my earthly race, I feel that a brief synopsis of my experience may be of some interest to the junior members of
                            our society. I was brought to Mt. Lebanon, and placed under the guardianship of Believers when I was eight years
                            of age. My first baptism was a ministration of love, from my visible guides and protectors, which met a response
                            from my own heart, and influenced my actions. As I advanced in years, and grew in stature, I found that I had a
                            choice to make, between good and evil, which to serve. I read and believed the Scripture, which said, " To whom
                            ye yield yourselves servants to obey, his servants ye are," that by being made free from sin, we could become
                            servants of righteousness. I saw, and felt, that doing what was just and right, would give peace of mind — cast
                            out fear — and enable souls to serve and worship God in love. " Love would work no ill to its neighbor," and was
                            really "the fulfilling of the Law." I resolved to make Love my axiom, and I felt my heart expand with love
                            toward all the human family. My faith in God, and in the Gospel of Christ through the order of male and female,
                            increased. I believed " the pure in heart would see God," and be able to understand those things which pertain
                            to His kingdom. I strove with all the strength of my mind, to be pure, and to keep myself unspotted from the
                            sins of the world , to be meek — merciful — a peacemaker. Thus I progressed from faith to faith, and from
                            strength to strength. And it is still my determination to keep in the increasing work, which I believe will grow
                            brighter and brighter unto that perfect day, when every thought, word, and action, will be under control of the
                            Christ-Spirit. I have ever chosen to serve under the Christian banner, and have thereby been able to abstain
                            from a sinful life. And I now rejoice that I can testify, to all who may feel an interest in me, or in my
                            experience as a Believer in the work of Christ's Second Appearing, that I have so successfully fought the good
                            fight of faith, when evil, in its varied forms, is presented, it finds no abiding place in me ; and with many of
                            my dear companions in Gospel travail, I can raise a shout of victory. I would not exchange the peace and
                            satisfaction that I feel, in my advanced stage of life — blessed, as I am by visible and invisible friends — for
                            all that this world could give me. I am thankful to testify, that there is a fountain opened in Zion, wherein
                            souls may wash and be made free from the stains of sin ; and whosoever will may drink freely and live — live
                            forever.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hammond, Lucy" TEIform="persName"/>Lucy Hammond, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good works" TEIform="index"/>GOOD WORKS</head><p TEIform="p">Op what profit is faith unless it be made manifest by good works f Good words, when timely and fitly spokon,
                            often give solace to the afflicted, and comfort the mourner ; but to the naked and famishing, " Be ye warmed and
                            clothed," in word only, would be of little account. By good works we not only " lay up treasure in heaven," but
                            like Dorcas of old, confer benefits upon destitute humanity, and blessings return to us manifold. We may be very
                            correct in our faith, and love, admire and laud others, who show their faith by works, yet, if we lack the
                            courage and energy to reduce our faith to practice, it would be as unavailing as implements in the hands of the
                            husbandman who is too indolent to use them. Deeds of charity toward individuals, and acts of kindness and
                            generosity, attended with soft and gentle words that will prevent or turn away wrath in communities, would form
                            a heaven on earth, and pure, peaceful spirits would delight to gather around and hold communion with such souls,
                            for they are nearly allied to angels.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webster, Ruth" TEIform="persName"/>Ruth Webster, Union Village, O.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our gospel preceptors" TEIform="index"/>OUR GOSPEL PRECEPTORS</head><p TEIform="p">Why should we not love and revere the Ancients of Israel — our former Teachers — those Gamaliels, at whose feet
                            we have sat and listened, and received much valuable instruction ? They have been to us, spiritual Fathers and
                            Mothers, Brothers and Sisters, and were bright examples while here. Their lives were well spent, they have
                            passed on before us to the " summer land," and left behind them a record of good works. True, many of those
                            worthies drew spiritual life and sustenance, to a large degree, from the inspiration of the past, looked to
                            types and symbols, and were somewhat veiled in mists and shadows. They were accustomed to accept and revere
                            whatever they found between the lids of the Bible, without calling in question its consistency, or authenticity.
                            Now, the light of reason and Divine Revelation has opened, more clearly to our vision, the links of the great
                            chain that unites natural and spiritual truth — conjoins Science and Religion. Will that justify us in setting
                            at naught the righteous teachings of our Preceptors, or in discarding the good of the past ? There have been
                            good men, and women, in all ages, who were Saints. They were the salt of the earth; for they loved, honored and
                            served God, according to their understanding, and made their mark for good to humanity. Gleams of light
                            overspread their spiritual horizon, and lighted their pathway ; and, aided by Bible teachings, they lived
                            righteously, in their day, and were accepted. If, by increased light, we now see that they believed too much of
                            Bible records, and accepted them altogether, without reasoning, and making due allowance for mediums,
                            circumstances and conditions a* the various periods when the Scriptures were written, and did not distinguish
                            between fallacy and verity; it would seem unwise for the present generation, like the swing of a pendulum, to go
                            to the other extreme, and become infidel inspirit, if not in profession, and reject the true as well as the
                            false. One thing we must concede, if honest; i. e., many worthy souls in the past, who adhered to, and trusted
                            in, the Scriptures as their rule of faith possessed more vital religion, which consists in goodness of
                            heart—purity of life— and a willingness to suffer, and to do, for truth's sake, than the rising generation who
                            have cast off reverence for the past, and virtually deny present revelation, however much they may expatiate
                            upon Truth, Reason, and Common Sense. The goal of immortal happiness has been the highest aspiration of the
                            enlightened portion of our race — the boon for which humanity has sighed, and for which Saints have suffered,
                            and Martyrs yielded up their lives. Many have thus triumphed over death and the grave, and found a haven of
                            rest. But to those who at the present time denounce the Bible as a whole, and say that, as a sailing craft for
                            the mariner on life's sea, it is no longer reliable—there are so many loose planks, it is better to abandon it
                            altogether— we would suggest, whether it would not be better to cling to the old vessel, and to teach their
                            children to believe the story concerning the bears that came from the wilderness, and devoured forty and two
                            children, rather than have them grow up in a defiant, mocking spirit — destitute of the fear and love of God, or
                            respectful regard for their fellows, and superiors. Is it not a safer way, to hold on to the good of the past,
                            until we are sure that fate, destiny, inspiration, or whatever we choose to call it, gives us some better, more
                            reliable plan, by which to obtain the one object in view — happiness? Speaking from personal knowledge, I might
                            be considered incompetent to judge; for I came among Believers at an early age, and have never passed the ordeal
                            of orthodox Church discipline—Sabbath-school training— neither learned the Catechism, nor any creed ; and have
                            never committed any formal prayer to memory, — except what is known as the Lord's prayer. That prayer, I have
                            always thought beautiful, expressive and impressive; and it never waxes old. I have been free to be my own Bible
                            interpreter, — a privilege largely enjoyed by the members of our community. To observation, and the experience
                            of others, I owe what knowledge I possess of the present unsatisfied state of society without, and the
                            increasing tendency to disregard all that was once deemed sacred. Elder Frederick Evans says, that when we
                            advance into New Light, we are sure to take with us a portion of the old orthodoxy from which we emerge ; that
                            while new light is developing, the old conservative element, which has formerly environed us, is slowly removed.
                            That seems to me a wise provision to avoid confusion and inharmony. In this a'ge of free thought, free speech
                            and action, there is great need of a fulcrum, whereon to rest the lever of Truth, that the religious world may
                            move from its old foundations of error, without destroying its equilibrium, and tumbling it into worse confusion
                            than ever. I propose that firstly,— before throwing the old and new Scriptures away, and taking the ground that
                            Jesus of Nazareth was a myth — we find the Christ-spirit, and the power of God unto salvation; and learn to
                            reverence, and love all, who deny themselves of sinful works, live purely and deal justly, whether they be man,
                            woman, or child. Let us all remember, that he, or she, who sins against light and conviction, if not of the
                            devil, is not doing the will of our Father and Mother in heaven.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dodgson, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>Anna Dodgson, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear editors of shaker and shakeress:" TEIform="index"/>Dear Editors of Shaker and Shakeress :</head><p TEIform="p">We offer a tribute of thanks for our monthly visitor, the S. and S. It is hailed with joy, and love greetings,
                            every time it comes, and we invoke the blessing of heaven upon those who strive so much to make it interesting
                            and instructive. We need Saviors on Mt. Zion ; those who are eagle-eyed — clear sighted — divinely inspired, and
                            in rapport with spirit spheres. They will find the keys of revelation, that will unlock what have been called
                            the " mysteries of godliness "— of religion — reconcile the past with the present, give confidence in the <pb n="71" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKEEESS. 71 coming future, and show that Philosophy, Science and Religion are
                            indissoluble friends, and will walk hand in hand together. But the sword of truth, proceeding in love from the
                            mouths of the Lord's prophets, will separate the false from the true; and we pray that the days of the ever
                            faithful prophets, and prophetesses, that are now with us, may be lengthened. We also pray, that such greatly
                            needed laborers and teachers may increase manifold. Lovingly your sister,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Riley, Nancy" TEIform="persName"/>Nancy Riley, West Ptttsfleld, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I love to peruse the 'S— and S—...'" TEIform="index"/>I love to peruse the 'S— and S—...'
                        </head><p TEIform="p">I love to peruse the " S— and S—," and would signify my approval and appreciation of its contents. I feel deep
                            interest in the welfare of humanity, and would rejoice in spirit to see them elevated to better conditions ; to
                            see them rise out of the sphere of self-serving and self-pleasing, and devote their time and talents upon the
                            broad basis of universal love to God and mankind. Then justice would rule in the affairs of men. Great reforms
                            are needful; but where is the power to meet the present exigency ? Men and women, unassisted by the grace of
                            God, cannot effect the needed change ; it must be wrought through faith and prayer, accompanied with good works.
                            Omnipotent Power must fathom man's loss, And teach him the glory of bearing the cross, Until from all sin he
                            finds a release, Enhancing his joy, and his blessing. My sisters in suffering, I oft pray for you That angels of
                            mercy may guide you safe through, Where together we'll meet on Canaan's bright shore, A heaven of glory
                            possessing.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Scott, Julia" TEIform="persName"/>Julia Scott, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New Jerusalem" TEIform="index"/>THE NEW JERUSALEM</head><p TEIform="p">In the twenty-first chapter of Revelation, a City is described, as coming down from God, out of heaven ; and a
                            voice was heard, saying, " The tabernacle of God is with men." That city had twelve foundational stones —
                            representing twelve fundamental principles, from which all the Christian virtues proceed — and which form the
                            gates of entrance to that city, which was four square — equal in all its parts — and from which, every thing
                            impure, or untrue, was excluded. The New Jerusalem, that descended from heaven to earth, did not require natural
                            light, or heat, because God, who held the burning lamp of Truth—Divine revelation — lighted the whole city. A
                            pure River of water of life was also seen, proceeding from the throne of God, flowing through the city; and on
                            either side of the river were trees of life. To my understanding, that river signified waters of judgment and
                            repentance; through which souls must pass, to purify, and fit them to become indwellers in the temple, that was
                            lighted with God's glory ; and that judgment will be dispensed by, and through His witnessing saints, male and
                            female, who were represented by the trees on either side of the river. They, as good and true physicians of
                            souls, will distribute the medicinal leaves of those trees, which were to be " for the healing of the nations."
                            And it is there stated that " The nations and kings of the earth would bring their glory, and honor unto that
                            beautiful city and temple." When Jesus said to his disciples, " In my Father's house are many mansions ; I go to
                            prepare a place for you," we would not suppose he meant to convey to their understanding, that previous to that
                            time, there had been no place prepared in Spirit realms for saints of previous ages. There are heavens, and a
                            heaven of heavens. The antediluvians had their heaven, or state of justification ; which consisted in obedience
                            to natural and physical laws, as made known to them, by the ruling Spirits who were appointed to give them such
                            lessons, as they were able to receive at that time. In obedience, they were promised a fullness of temporal
                            blessings. That was the highest attainment which they could appreciate; for they were in a crude, undeveloped
                            condition. The highway of progression remained to be opened up, little by little, through succeeding epochs, in
                            future generations. The Jews had their heaven. The tutelage of the Jews was very superior, and in advance of
                            that received by the antediluvians. Hence, the requirements upon them were greater. They had prophets and seers,
                            who were blessed with rays of spiritual and divine light; and they caught glimpses of heavenly conditions in the
                            distant future — of the more perfected mansion which Jesus referred to, when he said to his disciples, " I go to
                            prepare a place for you, in my Father's house of many mansions." There are different degrees of knowledge, and
                            attainments in goodness and truth in each of those mansions; so that we might with propriety say, " there are
                            mansions within mansions ;" or there are ascending steps, like the rounds in a ladder, from the commencement of
                            one dispensation, until, by those progressive steps, the way is prepared for the opening of a New Epoch. A
                            friend once said to me, " You know that in our Father's house are many mansions. I belong to one of the
                            Churches, — one of those mansions — and am going to heaven," signifying, that the many Churches are the synonym
                            of the many mansions of which Jesus spake. In a qualified sense that may be true. If God's watchful care be over
                            all the works of his hands, and there be some truth, more or less, in all the Churches, mixed up with time
                            serving, and idol worship, that good, whatever its measure or degree, belongs to God. But the perfected Virgin
                            Church—the New Jerusalem—that was seen to descend to earth, attended with the heavenly Bridegroom and Bride,
                            wherein woman finds "her proper lot and place, as co-worker with man in the redemption of human souls, is the
                            highest spiritual condition on earth ; and represents the heaven of heavens in the Spirit world.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Danford, Nancy G." TEIform="persName"/>Nancy G. Danford, Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Know thyself" TEIform="index"/>KNOW THYSELF</head><p TEIform="p">In social life, and in all the relations that human beings hold to one another, how many ills would be averted
                            and unpleasant feelings avoided, were that most excellent rule of serious second thought more frequently called
                            into action. A moment's consideration of consequences would often check a quick impulse, quell fevered passion,
                            press the lips and put a bridle on the tongue, just in time to save a storm or tempest that might forever blight
                            the loveliest blossoms of the soul. A thoughtless act, a passing word, or a speaking glance — prompted by wrong
                            motives— tell volumes that would remain forever closed, were the mind bent on obeying the golden rule. It is a
                            wicked heart that magnifies, intensifies, and glories in enlarging its neighbor's faults, while striving to
                            conceal its own deformities. " Know Thyself," in a deeper meaning than that which is applied to the mental
                            faculties, should be stamped on every mind ; a meaning which penetrates the secret springs of life ; " tries the
                            heart and reins," and analyzes the motives which prompt to utterance, or to action. They who have a thorough
                            knowledge of themselves, and square their lives by the perfective spirit of Truth, nobly expand in God-like
                            charity and love for humanity, and become saviors to souls, messengers of wisdom and light, rather than
                            destroyers of virtue through evil judging. Where vain arrogance and jealousy, bitter envy and poignant malice
                            are harbored in the soul, peace departs, and the bliss of life is trampled in the very dust of earth. Friendship
                            there finds no lasting hold; love is reptilsed, and heaven-born charity spurned. Those direful enemies of human
                            progress and happiness can only be removed from society by individual effort; every one must discover in
                            themselves the root of bitterness, and destroy the very life that produces such evil fruit. A profitable
                            exercise of mind to be engaged in is discovering when and where we may make peace, and not break it. " Neither
                            give nor take offense." Speak no ill of our neighbor, and turn from the hearing of slander; that will produce
                            the desired effect. Words aptly spoken — kindly acts —loving smiles — and courteous manners, all conduce to
                            happiness and peace. If we always apply the rule to consider well before we speak or act, we shall never fail to
                            obey the promptings of the higher law of love. "He who can command his own soul is the bravest of the brave,"
                            said Mohammed. Ah ! this is life's great lesson. The strength of self-control is the secret power that is able
                            to manacle the strongest opposing powers of good that take possession of the battle-ground of the soul, and let
                            us attain it through the glorious cross of self-denial, that develops and unfolds the angel in our being, and
                            annihilates its opposite. Then shall we be able to see the angel in others, however dimly it may manifest
                            itself.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>Martha J. Anderson, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Peace" TEIform="index"/>PEACE</head><p TEIform="p">Pause, gentle angel, o'er us now, And spread thy wings divine, Let every heart in reverence bow Before thy sacred
                            shrine. We'll bless thee ever, angel Peace, With us, make thy abode, To thee our love will never cease, For thou
                            art born of God. Oft do we come to thee, fair one, To seek thy heavenly aid ; Thy pearly gates to us unfold, And
                            glories that ne'er fade. We'll praise thee ever, angel Peace, For works, both great and good, O may thy mission
                            never cease, Thou loved one of our God. We grasp the wealth that will endure, Such crowns as angels wear;
                            Immortal treasures, that are pure, And joys the ransomed share. We'll honor thee while here below We tread this
                            earthly sod ; All hail! sweet Peace —blest messenger — Thou angel sent of God. The angry waves upon life's sea,
                            At thy command are still; The fiercest storms that there may be, Are silenced by thy will. O, heavenly Peace
                            forever reign, Thy influence spread abroad; Till earth shall from thy spirit gain The love a«d power of God.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="De Graw, Genevera" TEIform="persName"/>Genevera De Graw, Sonyea, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Commune with nature" TEIform="index"/>COMMUNE WITH NATURE</head><p TEIform="p">Alone within the forest. Fair nature's balmy bowers, I hold commune with angels, Expanding hidden powers. Through
                            birds and beauteous blossoms, Am lifted far above, To the elysian cities Of God's eternal love. I walk his
                            golden temples And glorious gardens fair, Drink in at living fountains, And eat of fruitage rare. I list the
                            holy anthems Of souls redeemed from sin, The radiant band of heroes, Who fought, the race to win. I see their
                            whitened raiment, The diadem and crown, And in their foreheads written, True victors of renown. Who Jesus' cross
                            have carried, For love of truth and right, And now with him are seated In mansions of delight. And then a
                            precious healing Calms every inner strife, And all my heart is strengthened To cope again with life. Then soft
                            and gentle whispers Come stealing on the air, And back my soul is bidden To time, and toil, and care. I take the
                            heavy burden And lay it next my heart, With pledges unto heaven To act the Christian's part. With faith in God's
                            rich promise, That in his own good time, He'll crown me with these glories In fairer worlds sublime.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Johnson, Julia" TEIform="persName"/>Julia Johnson, W. Pittsfield, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How well to live and do no harm..." TEIform="index"/>How well to live and do no harm...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">How well to live and do no harm, Though very little good we do ; How great the lesson yet to learn, To be to
                            others kind and true. Snatched from the world, we know we are, To find the holy, just and pure, To calm the
                            elements that jar, And make a peace that will endure.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W., Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div2><pb n="72" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fount of love" TEIform="index"/>FOUNT OF LOVE</head><p TEIform="p">1. Uplifted to the realms above, Through living faith and prayer, Our souls can reach the fount of love, And find
                            a blessing there. 2. Life's rugged pathway oft is drear, When sorrows deeply roll, And we would speak a word of
                            cheer, To help each struggling soul; 3. Oh, let our lives be ever rife With kindly love and peace ! Through
                            meekness banish every strife, And let all discord cease ; Though trials oft the heart oppress, There is a
                            healing balm, A spirit ever near to bless. And shield from every harm. Then like the bread so often cast Upon
                            time's troubled sea, It will return again at last, With blessing pure and free. Then we may chant the
                            conqueror's song, And triumph in the right, Give praise to whom all praise belongs, When faith has turned to
                            sight.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker and shakeress; not all a dream" TEIform="index"/>SHAKER AND SHAKERESS. NOT ALL A DREAM</head><p TEIform="p">I dreamed of a flowing river, That was fed from mountain and plain, That came like a harvest giver. To gardens,
                            and fields of grain. Whatever it touched it brightened. For life was within its wave ; Whatever it washed it
                            whitened, For in it was power to save, But I dreamed that its waves, impeded, Shrank back to their little
                            springs; And the tide that the great world needed. Was circling in hand-breadth rings. I dreamed that the angels
                            planted A vineyard of God, below.; That unto the earth was granted The power to see it grow. That up from her
                            barren places, Her desert's extended scope, Like music the echo chases, Came voices of joy and hppe. But I
                            dreamed that the vineyard perished, That all but its roots were dead ! For strength, that its life had
                            cherished, Like dew of the morning fled. And I dreamed of a holy altar, Where Truth had kindled a fire ; A light
                            for the feet that falter, A gleam for the eyes that tire. Its radiance flamed with a glory, The dwellings around
                            to fill; And the earth was thrilled by the story, Of the city upon the hill. But I dreamed that the altar
                            tumbled ; That its glow became a spark ; That its steps and its pillars crumbled, And its dwellings around were
                            dark. I dreamed a new song was started, That floated the wide world o'er; That brought to the wreary-hearted A
                            courage unknown before. 'Twas the song of the Revelation, The song that the harpers sung ; Its theme was the new
                            salvation; Its w.ords were the glad new tongue. But I dreamed that its numbers ended Ere their import half was
                            told ; That the singers from heights descended, And covered their harps of gold. Yea, I dreamed that the dual
                            token Of Zion, was lost to sight; And I wept, that a bond was broken, And quenched was a heavenly light. Then I
                            dreamed that our hearts, in union, Went out to the children of men — That the swell of our love's communion, The
                            river sent forth again. By toil of our hands, united, The vineyard in beauty bloomed ! Devotion and truth
                            relighted The city, our home illumed ! And the gift of deep inspiration, That flowed through Mount Zion's
                            throng, Was heard by each listening nation, And known as the full new song.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Devyr, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/>Cecelia Devyr, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbath" TEIform="index"/>SABBATH</head><p TEIform="p">Turn from the outward leaf of life, And give the Sabbath place ; Be earnest in the upward strife, Be thine the
                            Christian grace. A Sabbath is a day of rest, Not measured by a span. They who with gospel faith are blest, Have
                            rest in God's own plan. Each covenant the Saviour taught, Gives peace unmarred within. And forms a Sabbath,
                            truly wrought, Out from a life of sin. Second to this, the work of hands, The toil on earthly sod; For when the
                            truth our life commands, We've constant rest in God.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, M." TEIform="persName"/>M. Whitcher, Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Point" TEIform="index"/>THE POINT</head><p TEIform="p">FACT, OR FRAUD — WHICH? When from five to twenty-five forms, of men, women and children, appear in an evening
                            seance, on the platform of the Eddy Hall, in Chittenden, in presence of from twenty-five to fifty spectators,
                            gathered from all parts of the Union, and some from foreign countries, one of two things occurs — either those
                            forms are the product of downright fraud and lying trickery, and all these spectators — leading minds, from
                            Chicago, New York, Philadelphia, London, Texas, Rhode Island and Mt. Lebanon— are imposed upon, deceived,
                            deluded, bewitched, and made to think and know that they see, and hear uttered, high and noble sentiments
                            touching the welfare of society, by the materialized spirits of men and women from the Spirit-World, when in
                            reality it is only the Medium and his co-conspirators — r, a Neio Epoch has opened to mankind, that shall
                            ultimate in the Kingdom of Heaven upon Earth, uniting God to Humanity, through the Law of Materialization and
                            (?-materializa tion. Through its agency Angels will descend upon the sons and daughters of men, eliminating,
                            from Humanity, evils, physical and spiritual—substituting in their place the virtues and graces of the Angelic
                            hosts — the consummation of the ages, so long looked for — the Millennial Era.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Creed" TEIform="index"/>CREED</head><p TEIform="p">I believe in God, the Father and Mother, in whose likeness Man will be when they grow to it. I believe in Jesus
                            and Ann, and in all who, like them, do right because it is right, irrespective of cost. I believe in the
                            Communion of Saints, and in courtesy and kindness to Sinners. I believe in the Resurrection of Body and Soul
                            from unphysiological diet, habits and appetites — from low ambitions, carnal desires and misuse of reproductive
                            powers — and from their use by such as aspire to Life Everlasting. Amen.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="P., O." TEIform="persName"/>O. P</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Speaking" TEIform="index"/>Speaking.—</head><p TEIform="p">In speaking, the object is, to be heard and understood. Every speaker to public audience, whether few or many,
                            should stand while speaking. To sit is disrespectful to the audience. Speakers in public should measure the
                            magnitude of the room, and so pitch the voice that all may hear — should speak 3lowly and articulate clearly. If
                            the hall echo, speak very slowly.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Swiss burials" TEIform="index"/>SWISS BURIALS</head><p TEIform="p">A REBUKE OF THE PREVALENT AMERICAN FOLLY IN FUNERALS. It is very doubtful how far we in America would be willing
                            to tolerate any invasion, by the government, of the inalienable right of the free citizen to run up a bill with
                            his own favorite undertaker. But those who have seen as much as I have of the suffering which is sometimes
                            produced in families of slender or even moderate means by the too unrestricted exercise of this liberty on the
                            part of both the contracting parties, will feel that these Swiss republicans (who have, withal, the reputation
                            of being reasonably jealous of their liberties) find some compensation in their hereditary bondage. I was
                            surprised at the small amount of the bill which I was called upon to pay at the mairie of Petit Saconnex for the
                            expenses of our modest funeral ceremonial. I could not help admiringthe success with which the people here had
                            protected themselves from the dilemma in which families of small means at home are often shut up — between a
                            pauper funeral and a crippling debt to the undertaker. The evil cries out for a remedy. The Roman Catholic
                            clergy have made honorable efforts to abate it among their flocks, and Bishop Coxe, of Buffalo, has done the
                            little that can be done by remonstrance in his denomination. If a sumptuary law is ever needed, it is on this
                            point. But a more hopeful prospect of success, considering the habits of our people, would be in the social
                            combination of individuals and families, beginning with those of large means and unquestioned position, to
                            discourage funeral extravagance. It would be a most Christian thing for rich and influential families to pledge
                            themselves to stand by each other and by their neighbors in the practice of a severe simplicity and economy in
                            such matters, and in providing a way in which funerals should be arranged in a modest but suitable mauner, with
                            absolute security against extortion.— Lippincott for July. A good point of practical reform. The Shaker
                            funerals, for a century, have been simplicity, neatness and economy combined. The love, sympathy and respect of
                            the survivors is directed toward the soul, just separated from earthly friends by the loss of the body, that has
                            been hitherto the lifelong medium of communication between them ; whilst the body is put in a plain board
                            coffin, without paint or ornament, and is quietly dropped into the ground—the grave of forgetfulness.—Ed.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pilot, Sarah" TEIform="index"/>Sarah Pilot
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Pilot, Sarah" TEIform="persName">Sarah Pilot</persName>, July 3,1875, aged 19, Union Village, O.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pearsons, Julia E." TEIform="index"/>Julia E. Pearsons
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Pearsons, Julia E." TEIform="persName">Julia E. Pearsons</persName>, July 25, 1875, aged 38, North Union, O.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Parker, Calvin J." TEIform="index"/>Calvin J. Parker
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Parker, Calvin J." TEIform="persName">Calvin J. Parker</persName>, June 17,1875, aged 76, Enfield, Conn.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="McComb, Sally" TEIform="index"/>Sally McComb
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="McComb, Sally" TEIform="persName">Sally McComb</persName>, April 22,1875, aged 79, South Union, Ky.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Norris, Ella" TEIform="index"/>Ella Norris
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Norris, Ella" TEIform="persName">Ella Norris</persName>, March 16,1875, aged 25, South Union, Ky.</p></div3></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>