<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2207" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">28</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">22</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">07</biblScope><date value="18920701" TEIform="date">July 1892</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">145-168</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="22" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="07" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
JULY.
MANIFESTO
Published by the United Societies,
VOL. XXII.
"For what is a man profited, if he shall gain the whole world, and
lose his own soul ? or what shall a man give in exchange for
his soul."Matt. XVI., 26.
Canterbury, N. H.
1892.
the
<pb n="" id="p"/>
TEE  MANIFESTO.
CONTENTS.
Page.
Kentucky Revival, No 19.           -         -        145
My Home,           .....    149
Confession of Sin,             -         -         -          "
Spiritual   Light,           -         -         -         -    151
In memory of A.N.Wayne,        -         -        153
Twilight Thoughts,      -         -         -         -      "
Open Letter,                                                  154
A Child's Hymn,          -        -         -        -    155
Editorial,.....        156
In memory of N. Frye,          -         -         -    158
Notes about Home,           ...          "
Inquiry,               .....    164
Scripture Text,         ....          "
Foretells the End,        .         .        -         -    165
Sowing Wild Oats,            -       . -         -          "   j
Finish thy Work,          -         -         -         -    166
Kind Words,            -         -         -         -          "
Deaths,      -...- -"
Music,Looking Upward,          -         -         167
Books & Papers,           -         -         -         -    168
If you oahnot get them op toob
local deals5b3, we will fdjp somb
waj of supplying tod w1tb ibs
STRATTON
RUSSIAN CUT
VIOLIN STRINGS.
Dealers send for Catalogue an* Price List.
JCWN F  STRATTON & SON.
By the noted Author, Pastor, Journalist
and Platform Oratcr,
RUSSELL  H, COGSWELL.
5OO Pages,
ELEGANTLY  ILLUSTRATED,
ON.ir   $1.50,
EVERY CHRISTIAN FAMILY WANTS HIS LIFE.
It is full of intensest interest from bppnnirg
to close.   It is a mine of viiiimble information, and filled with the purest thought, keenest
wit, richest experience and truest pniiosopliy.
It WILL PAY YOU to WGRfC for US.
 75c. OUTFIT FOR 30c.
 Greatest Ch:ince yon
 ever had to Kak? Money.
 fiooe Trade Mtattt,
SI usical Merchandise.
-48* 44 Walker St.'.        NEW VOitK
Remember we allow our agents to give so
every one who buys this book, which retails
for only $1.50, a free six maomf*s> euE>
cription to "The Christian," which was
Mr. Spurgeon's Favorite Paper,
he having had it for years, and having said of it:
" 'THE CHRISTIAN' is the Best Paper that comes to me."
It requires a salesman to sell some books;
this one anybody can sell, because the people
want it, and the premium we give ( Cub
Christian) makes the work still eaeie?.
The people are anxious to hare the b ok,
and wait with the money to pay foe it.
WILL YOU TAKE IT TO THEfifl ?
Sample Book, prepaid, and " Thk Christian "
six months, for only $1.60.
g^-Best Terms        I g^-Act  Quick!
To Our Agents.     |   No Time to Lose!
The flrst to send 30c. (postage) for Outfit, gets
the territory.   Address JOHN K. HASTINGS,
Mngr. of "THE CHRISTIAN," 47 CORNHiLL, Boston, Mss.
(Preserve this, it may not appear again.   Mention this paper.)
The Celebrated
BAND  INSTRUMENTS,
Snare and Bass Oruma, Fires,   Piccolos, Clarionets, Cym<
OalBand all other instruments pertaining to
Bra.ua Bands and DusiCor pa.
s
JOHN K. 8THATTOM & SOW,
43  &   45  Walker  Street.  NEW YORK.
DO YOU KEEP BEES
If so, send your name and address for a
Free Sample of the AMERICAN BEE
JOURNAL Weekly32 pagesOne
Dollar a year.
Thomas G. Newman & Son,
PUBLISHERS
CHICAGO, ILL.
./OHM   F.   6TRATTON   &
CELEBRATED
Importers of and Wholesale Dealers in all kinds of
MUSICAL     WIERCHANOSSE,
Violins, Guitars, Banjos, Mandolines, Accordeons,
Harmonicas, c, all kinds of Sirinos. etc.etc.
43 & 45 Walker St.,                   NEW YOKK.
SUBSCRIBE FOR
A Radical, Rational  and Racy
Reform Paper.
The bitter foe of every form of social abuse
in church and state, the expositor of Koreshanity, which is primitive Christianity revived, and the pronmlgator of an equitable
system of exchange which Is destined to revolutionize commercial methods and
Crush the Iniquitous  Money Power
SAMPLE    COPY    FREE.
Tie Guiding Star PhIl House.
3519 Cottage Grovs Avsnue.
CHICAGO, ILL.
LIFE OF G. H. SPURGEON,
THE FLAMING SWORD
Vol. XXII.
JULY, 1892.
No. 7.--><pb n="145" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kentucky revival. no. 19" TEIform="index"/>THE KENTUCKY REVIVAL.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="M'Nemar, Richard" TEIform="persName"/>By Richard M'Nemar</byline><p TEIform="p">of Union Village, Ohio. Published in Albany, N. Y"., in 1808. No. 19. Explanations.
                            Continued. THE MODE OF CONSTITUTION. Though God had much people scattered abroad among the
                            men of the world, yet they were not properly constituted into a distinct body, nor vested
                            with the powers of mutual government, until after Christ's resurrection. "Other sheep have
                            I, (that is, loving believers) which ai"e not of this fold; them also I must bring, and they
                            shall hear my voice, h,nd there shall be one fold and one shepherd." The state of believers,
                            or those that worshiped God at that time in the spirit of simple love, may be compared to
                            the materials of the tabernacle, before it was erected. They were scattered abroad in
                            different places, and did not exhibit that beautiful appearance or construction which they
                            afterward assumed. The miracles of Christ, and the wonders which attended his death, the
                            unnatural eclipse of the sun, the earthquake, the rending of the veil, the opening of the
                            graves, the resurrection, were calculated to bring the expectants of his kingdom to
                            Jerusalem, from almost every quarter of the world. Accordingly, about that time, we find a
                            vast concourse of people met together at that place. The Apostles who had long been in the
                            habit of believing the truth, were then by faith and fervent prayer waiting for the promise
                            of the Father Acts i., 4-5, and Acts ii., throughout. Christ had promised that they should
                            be baptized with the Holy Spirit and endued with power from on high. Accordingly on the day
                            of Pentecost, the spirit came like the rushing of a mighty wind, and they were all filled
                            with the Holy Spirit and spake with other tongues, as the spirit gave them utterance. They
                            being thus publicly set apart, and anointed with the Holy Spirit, were laid as the
                            foundation of this spiritual tabernacle. Men had long been accustomed to look for God on a
                            mount that might be touched, or in a temple made with hands; but now the dispensation is
                            changed and we behold the foundation of a spiritual temple, an house not <pb n="146" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> made with hands, nor built of dead materials, but of living stones. 1 Peter ii., 5. While
                            Jerusalem was the place to worship, the temple stood there and never moved out of the spot,
                            nor grew any larger, but this new temple was designed to eclipse all the glory of the
                            former, and fill the whole earth. Hag. ii., 9. Dan. ii., 35. The same day there were added
                            to this building about three thousand, who continued steadfastly in the Apostles' doctrine,
                            in breaking of bread and in prayers; and the Lord added to the church daily, such as should
                            be saved. This one church is represented as a growing body, but never a single idea of
                            others being formed out of it. Unity is one of its essential characteristics. Eph. iv., 4,
                            5. There is one body and one spirit, even as ye are called in one hope of your calling; one
                            Lord, one faith, one baptism, one God, and Father of all, who is above all, and through all
                            and in you all. This one church whose center was visibly marked at Jerusalem, spread its
                            circumference to all the countries round about, and will not cease to increase till it
                            includes the whole world, as leaven which is hid in three measures of meal, till the whole
                            is leavened ; or as mustard seed hid in the ground grows up into a great tree till the fowls
                            of the air can lodge in the branches of it. In a short time after the day of Pentecost, we
                            find the church of God planted in Samaria, at Damascus, in the house of Cornelius, where it
                            still appeared the same, composed of Believers, set up and anointed with the Holy Spirit.
                            Great opposition was made to its progress, but the more difl it daily increase, and
                            believers were the more added to the Lord, multitudes, both of men and women. This one
                            church of God did not respect the persons, but the characters of men. It included Jews and
                            Greeks, Barbarians, Scythians, bond and free. Hence we find, in a little time its members
                            were dispersed over all the world, and were found in every nation under heaven, of every
                            kindred and tongue upon the face of the earth. From this view of the matter would it not
                            appear next to impossible, that persons so widely dispersed could be preserved in unity? How
                            were they fashioned alike? Upon what principle were they united? And by what rules were they
                            obliged to walk ? What confession of faith had they as a bond of union? What compendium of
                            doctrines or definite code of laws to be universally subscribed? Unhappy for the church in
                            our day, if there were such, they have been lost in the ruins of time, so that not a single
                            trace of them is to be found. The only bond of union transmitted to us, and which is indeed
                            the only bond that can unite Christians, is found in the holy Scriptures, the true
                            confession of faith, see Eph. iv., 15, 16. But speaking the truth in love may grow up into
                            him in all things, who is the head even Christ, from whom the whole body fitly joined
                            together, by that which every joint supplieth (or by the supply of every joint) according to
                            the effectual working, or energy in the measure of every part, maketh <pb n="147" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/>
                            increase of the body unto the edifying, or building up, of itself in love. Col. ii., 19.
                            Holding the head, from which the whole body by joints and bands having nourishment
                            ministered, and knit together increaseth with the increase of God. We see here that from
                            Christ the head, the living spirit flows to all the members, which fitly or exactly joins,
                            compacts and knits them together in the bonds of love, builds or rears them up, worketh
                            effectually, or exerts and exercises its energy according to the measure or size of every
                            part, and ministers proper nourishment to promote the proportionate growth of every member
                            of the body of Christ. This is the sweet anointing oil, the unction from the holy One, the
                            spirit of God, or it is Christ himself by his spirit shed abroad or diffused throughout the
                            whole body, according to the capacity of every member. This spirit is the cement, 'the true
                            bond of union. Thus Christ prays, John xvii., 11, 21, 23. "Holy Father, keep through thine
                            own name, those whom thou hast given me, that they may be one, as thou, Father, art in me
                            and I in thee, that they also may be one even as we are one ; I in them and thou in me, that
                            they may be made perfect in one." We find here that Christ's prayer is, that his followers
                            may be made one, and kept completely so, not by means of some external law or form of words,
                            but by the name of God. That they may be one in us says he, living and walking in the Father
                            and the Son, and the Father and the Son living and walking in them; and thus to form and
                            preserve the union, he gives them the glory which he received from the Father, whereby they
                            are constituted one; for "He that is joined to the Lord is one spirit. 1 Cor. vi., 17.
                            Christ dwells in his heart by faith, and as long as the members of the body continue in the
                            faith they are so intimately united, that any outward bond could only serve as a burdensome
                            yoke. But if any of his professed members are not joined to the Lord in one spirit, their
                            outward bonds are only like binding two or more dead bodies together, which hastens their
                            putrefaction and renders their ill savor more intolerable to the living. Without this living
                            spirit the most perfect form or set of rules which could be made, though it were even by God
                            himself, could not cement them together in the bonds of love, nor make them one in heart.
                            Mankind are not bound together like the parts of a machine, nor put in motion by external
                            force ; they must be influenced by motive, and that motive must be in the heart. This is the
                            law of God received and engraven on the heart through faith; hence it is said to be written,
                            not with ink, but with the spirit of the living God; not on tables of stone, but on fleshly
                            tables of the heart. 2 Cor. iii., 3. After these days saith the Lord, I will put my laws in
                            their inward parts, and write them in their hearts. Jer. xxxi., 32. Christ is the end of the
                            law for righteousness, to every one that belie veth. Rom. x., 4. Now the end of the
                            commandment is charity out of a pure heart. He that dwelleth in love, dwelleth in God, <pb n="148" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> and God in him. The husbandman had an external law for his fig-tree,
                            that if it bore fruit, well, if not, he would cut it down. But the fig-tree was not governed
                            by this law, it acted according to a law in itself. So we are commanded to bring forth the
                            fruits of holiness, without which no man shall see the Lord. But this command, so long as it
                            is not in oar nature, has no more influence in the production of those fruits than the
                            command of the husbandman to his fig-tree. We see no outward law necessary to impel the
                            rivers to the ocean, bind the stones to the surface of the earth, or prevent the trees from
                            growing downward. No more does a Believer want an external law to oblige him to love God and
                            his neighbor, for if there had been an external law given which could have given life,
                            verily righteousness should have been by the law. Examine your wheat-field and you will find
                            uniformity among all the grains. By what rule is this uniformity effected? You may observe
                            the same uniformity in every species of vegetables, plants and trees. And are those meaner
                            things governed by real operative laws, and yet God's noblest creature, man, left at random
                            to follow every shadow or image, and bend to every device of human wisdom? Nay, there is one
                            law and one government for man, and all that are under that government are as uniform as the
                            leaves on. an apple-tree. This law is nothing less than the one spirit of the eternal God,
                            which lives and operates in the church as his body, for by one spirit we are all baptized
                            into one body, and have all been made to drink into that one spirit. Therefore, they that
                            have not this spirit, are iawless and disobedient, filthy dreamers that defile the flesh,
                            despise government, presumptuous are they, self-willed, who are not afraid to speak evil/of
                            dignities ; for if any man have not the spirit of Christ, he is none of his. Thus it appears
                            that the Christian's law is in his heart, a copy of which is drawn out in the New Testament.
                            The members of the human body need no bond of union to cause them to act in concert, or to
                            ktepthem from quarrelling and separating, but that spirit which animates the whole frame.
                            The whole current of the New Testament goes to show that the spirit of Jesus is the true
                            bond of union in his church ; but we find not the least intimation of any other bond being
                            necessary. All who have received this one spirit, and are living and walking in it, are
                            united together by the hand of God ; and what God hath joined together, let not man put
                            asunder; nay, it cannot be done, they are and must continue one, though they should be
                            called by never so many names, or externally distinguished by many peculiarities. The most
                            that these things can do is to make them think they are divided, and to prevent their
                            external communion, sweet fellowship and mutual comfort. But seeing Christians are one and
                            have fellowship with the Father and the Son by one spirit, it is the most unreasonable thing
                            in the world for them to be separated in their external com- <pb n="149" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> munion.
                            This separation has been the work of error, and it is by this means that it is continued in
                            the world. Let Christians look back to the history of primitive Christianity, as recorded in
                            the New Testament. Let them take a view of the plain and native simplicity which shines out
                            there, the beautiful equality that reigned among the Apostolic churches, and let them pant
                            to breathe that native air. They were all Brethren and Sisters, met together with one
                            accord, united in one mind and one judgment. They ate their meat with gladness and
                            singleness of heart, they went from house to house, from one love-feast to another, were
                            strictly forbidden to call themselves by the name of Paul or Apollos, and such as did, were
                            pronounced carnal, sensual, having not the spirit. View the churches scattered abroad,
                            planted and visited by the Apostles and others: They had all access to each other, and
                            communion together. And that one spirit of God which lives in every Christian, has made no
                            provision for acting otherwise, till the end of time. The evangelists went out two and two
                            or in larger companies, and in every place where the word was gladly received, those who
                            gave public testimony of their faith, were baptized, received the Holy Spirit, and were set
                            in order for the admission of others who might afterwards believe. E^Go and do likewise.
                            Christ. THE END.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Those who forbear to act, may be righteous for themselves..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Those who forbear to act, may be righteous for themselves...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Those who forbear to act, may be righteous for themselves; while those who venture to act,
                            must be allowed to make some mistake.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My home" TEIform="index"/> MY HOME.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/> Mary Whitcher.</byline><p TEIform="p"> I am walking 'mid sweet flowers, Blooming roses, lilies fair; And around these fragrant
                            bowers Stately oaks for shade appear. There are children of the household, Lovely youth are
                            flowers sweet; And the oaks are well-tried pillars, 'Neatli whose shadow we retreat. And
                            behold, within the center, Is the word of God revealed; By the union of the spirit Truth nor
                            purity concealed. "Line on line" and loving precept, With the "new commandment" came: "Love
                            and bless ye one another," This the language clear and plain. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Confession of sin" TEIform="index"/> CONFESSION OF SIN.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/> Martha J. Anderson.</byline><p TEIform="p"> "He that covereth his sins shall not prosper, but whoso confesseth and forsaketh them shall
                            find mercy.'1'' Prov. xxviii., 13. The voice of one crying in the wilderness, "repent ye for
                            the kingdom of heaven is at hand," is the voice of the true prophet or witness of God, who,
                            bearing the torch of truth, lighted by divine inspiration, precurses the opening of each new
                            dispensation or degree of progress among mankind. The wilderness signifies the uncultured
                            spiritual condition of humanity, the gross sensual state, where moral blindness precludes
                            the light. Only as new waves of life from the inner spheres of goodness and holiness roll
                            over the earth, penetrating the darkness and unfolding in the race a state of receptivity,
                            is there an awakening to soul needs, and at certain <pb n="150" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> times there cometh
                            the tpirtiially illumed teacher or witness, imbued with power from on high, and a testimony
                            that brings conviction for wrong doing, as on the day of Pentecost when there was a mighty
                            outpouring of the Spirit." "Many that believed" or were convicted, "came and showed their
                            deeds." Acts xix., 18. Israel had prophets of the Lord to proclaim judgment, with priests
                            and elders to hear the oral confessions of the people, and make atonement by offerings and
                            sacrifices, for all the sins they committed against moral and physical law. John the Baptist
                            came with a further degree of light; merging from the dispensation of types and shadows he
                            proclaimed the ushering in of a more spiritual work, "when the axe should be laid at the
                            root of the evil tree." He baptized with water, which signified a cleansing of spirit from
                            all impurity, and as he preached the word of righteousness, the people came confessing their
                            sins. Jesus came also, and upon him descended the Christ anointing. His baptism was of fire
                            and the Holy Spirit, the flame that reveals and then consumes the man and woman of sin,
                            whose carnal thoughts and deeds have defiled the very citadel of life through all the ages.
                            Verily in the great day of the Lord when the "veil of the covering"the lust of the
                            flesh"shall be taken from the nations," "that which is done in secret shall be revealed on
                            the housetops," not whispered in the ear of the Infinite, who knows all our errors; but,
                            confessed before the faithful servants of God, who have passed through the searching ordeal,
                            and through mortification and contrition have found and felt the loving mercy and tender
                            forgiveness of the Father and Mother of all. Joshua said to Achan, who brought judgment on
                            the camp because he hid the goodly garment and the wedge of gold ; "My son, give I pray
                            thee, glory to the Lord God of Israel and make confession unto Him, and tell me now what
                            thou hast done." He Joshuastood as a witness, heard the acknowledgment, and passed judgment
                            on the sinful deed. The open confession of sin was practiced in the days of the apostolic
                            fathers, and was deemed essential to the privilege of membership in the first Christian
                            Church. "If we say we have no sin, we deceive ourselves, and the truth is not in us. If we
                            confess our sins, he is fiatliful and just to forgive us our sins, and to cleanse us from
                            all unrighteousness." John i., 8, 9. The Catholic Church hold this as a cardinal doctrine,
                            but the abuse of the sacred functions of the clergy, has turned a real blessing into a
                            curse. Human nature is weak through the flesh. Masculine dominance with its powerful
                            impulses towards sensuality, has not been able to withstand the temptation of the
                            confessional, and saving grace has departed from whut should be the holy of holies. Woman
                            should confide to woman her heart secrets ; but, she had no voice or place in ministerial
                            administration, until Ann Lee, the first born among many sisters in the Second Christian
                            Dispensation, revealed the Motherhood in <pb n="151" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> Deity, the starting point of
                            woman's emancipation from sexual thralldom. She who came up out of great tribulation,
                            baptized and regenerated by the Christ influence, has wrought wisely in establishing
                            equality in spiritual as well as in temporal affairs, in the organization that bears the
                            name of "Believers in Christ's first and second appearing." Each sex comprehends its own
                            frailties, and each has its own spiritual advisers, in the order of Elders ; and where there
                            is harmonious action "the counsel of peace is between them," and the law of virgin purity is
                            maintained. "Now has come salvation and strength, the kingdom of our God and the power of
                            his Christ." The wings of the Cherubim touch over the mercy seat; and Urim and Thummimlight
                            and perfection shine in the breastplate of righteousness which is worn by those who minister
                            at the altar. In associative relations where persons are gathered together in a communistic
                            home, it is necessary that the chai'acter of each individual should be known; and the true
                            brotherhood and sisterhood formed on the basis of a religious life can only be permanent by
                            each member putting away the sins and errors of the old life in nature. The power of
                            protection can only be kept, through union with and confidence in a spiritual lead, from'
                            whom no secrets should be withheld. "Now, therefore, there is no condemnation to those who
                            walk with Christ," for they have put off the deeds of the old man and woman and are clothed
                            in the clean garments of the resurrection. "Light is sown for the righteous and joy for the
                            upright in heart;" and those who are true to the principles and rules of an organization
                            whose object is human redemption, cannot fail to find peace of mind and rest of spirit.
                            "Such shall see the travel of their souls and be satisfied with the goodness of God." Mount
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Physical and spiritual light" TEIform="index"/> PHYSICAL and SPIRITUAL LIGHT.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="White, Anna" TEIform="persName"/> Anna White.</byline><p TEIform="p"> "Light is the agent through which objects become visible to our senses ; it is indispensable
                            to the growth and development of all material substances ; without it there can be no
                            perfection." "To them that sat in death, light is sprung up." Matt. iv. 16. Plants kept in
                            dark cellars are pale and sickly in appearance, while those of tne same kind, when exposed
                            to the vivifying rays of the sun, present a richer, deeper hue. The same rule that leads the
                            horticulturist to prune and dress his vines, and the agriculturist to trench and prepare
                            land for his crops of grain and vegetables, should likewise lead him to observe and obey the
                            laws of his being, and that light as the focalizing source of his existence, should be woven
                            in that existence until it becomes an inseparable part of the integral body. If the law of '
                            'loving the neighbor as thyself" was imperative, this would be the case, and the common
                            blessings of a kind Providence be equally distributed upon each and every one of the human
                            family, but, unfortunately selfish interests and world- <pb n="152" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> ly loves for
                            me and mine predominate among all classes in so-called Christendom to an alarming extent,
                            producing inequality, injustice and avarice. We need but visit the coal mines of our own
                            country, to witness, in the truest meaning of the term, the culmination of an iniquitous
                            nefarious system. Here, hundreds of feet under ground, are men plodding from morn ing till
                            night and from night until morning without a sunbeam or a ray of diffused light to brighten
                            existence. Is it any wonder that we stop and question if these miserable specimens of
                            humanity were made in the image of the Creatora little lower than the angelsendowed with
                            reason and capacities exceeding all the other works of his hand? In our large factories and
                            dry goods' stores, where young delicate womanhood is forced to stand all the day long in an
                            unnatural, unhealthy atmosphere, we see the operation of the same law. And so with the
                            tenantry in oul' great cities, deprived of the main sources of existence, they become mere
                            beasts of burden, or resort to immorality and crimes as a consequence of their low
                            conditions. "The earth is the Lord's and the fulness thereof," though man claims to be the
                            lord of creation. He has certainly circumvented other ways, has hewn out cisternsbroken
                            cisterns that hold only the foul muddy waters of sensuality, selfishness and greed; still,
                            through the progress of the race in scientific truths, it will be shown that "the nations
                            are as a drop of a bucket and are counted as the small dust of the balance: "behold, He
                            taketh up the isles as a very little thing." From thorns and briars, from insect ravages and
                            destructive cyclones, the new earth is destined to be free, as well as from sickness, pain
                            and disease. We are convinced that physically, it is impossible to exist in a healthy state
                            without light. A dwelling or an apartment void of it, is unfit for occupancy. It was God's
                            first gift to earth. "Let there be light and there was light, and God saw the light and it
                            was good." Let us not shut itout. Spiritually, we need the light "as a lamp that burneth;"
                            the soul requires it for its advancement in spiritual life, as much as the body needs it for
                            physical development. By the light of divine revelation Mother Ann was enabled to see
                            through the veil of the flesh, and power was given her from the Christ spirit to rend this
                            veil in twain, and declare to the world the testimony of eternal truth. When this was done
                            persecution commenced, "for every one that doeth evil hateth the light, lest their deeds
                            become manifest." The same wicked spirit that crucified Jesus in his day, was as rife in her
                            day, and though she met not the same ignominious death, her physical life was prematurely
                            shortened by the sufferings she was forced to endure in pursuance of the spiritual gift of
                            God which rested upon and took up its abode with her. To Mother Ann was committed the keys
                            of the kingdom, and no one could enter into the fold but through the door of confession. So
                            keen was her spiritual vision that she could see the sins of a person, and when there was a
                            reluctance in confessing sins would <pb n="153" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> read them aloud to that person,
                            until in agony the soul would cry for mercy and beg for a privilege to confess them. That
                            was bringing light out of darkness, with convincing proof that Christ had indeed "appeared
                            the second time without sin unto salvation." When the blessed Millennium shall have come to
                            the many, as it has come to a few, the external and internal, or the physical and the
                            spiritual light, will penetrate and dispel all darkness. The soul that is touched with the
                            Christ baptism, and becomes imbued with saving power from on high, and faith to bring to
                            light all the hidden works of darkness in thought, word and action according to God's order,
                            is already in the Millennium. ' 'And there shall be no night there ; and they need no
                            candle, neither light of the sun, for the Lord God giveth them light; and they shall reign
                            forever and ever." Rev. xxii., 5. Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In memory of our young sister, Ada M. Wayne. There is no mystery--no death" TEIform="index"/> In Memory of our Young Sister, ADA M. WAYNE. There is no Mystery-no Death.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="De Vere, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/> Cecelia De Vere.</byline><p TEIform="p"> The germs of fruit cast petals on the ground, With perfume sweet exhaled on morning's
                            breath; And we perceive 'tis in the plan profound, We call it change, we never call it
                            death! The nurturing shell may now all broken lie, The chirping tenant leave the transient
                            nest, To gladly, freely, through the ether fly; And that is life, developed and progressed.
                            We mourn not day, that kissed the evening cloud, And left the crimson to dissolve in night,
                            We heed not whether black or silvery shroud Enwraps the hours,we wait the coming light. And
                            whether red leaves fall or spring delays, We cavil not, nor dread a chaos near, The natural
                            thought keeps pace with natural ways, And marks the certain advent of the year. When cold
                            the ice gate closes on the world, And snow-crowned evergreens their hands upraise, Though
                            wild tornadoes through the air are hurled, We know the coming of the sunny days. But wrhen
                            the hand of pain the door unbars And liberates the soul. Why should we mourn? We do not
                            tremble for the hidden stars, When morning o'er the firmament is born. But where is reason
                            when grief bows the head, And doubts rush in like comforters of yore, When wailing voices
                            cry, "the dead, the dead!" And have we lost them? lost them, evermore? Ah, there is
                            blasphemy in every breath, In every motion prompted by despair, Who dares to call the soul's
                            departure,Death, When God hath joined and keeps us in his care. He gave our souls affection,
                            as a bond For mutual help, for mutual growth while here, And stretched its circle to the
                            life beyond, That immortality might bless and cheer. And now behind the screen that lightly
                            veils, She has just slipped, a child that close we held. Safe is she now where evil ne'er
                            assails, Where note of sorrow, never sadly knelled. Dear one, we loved thee, in thy tender
                            heart There was a friendship sweet as violets' dew; A strong affection, undefaced by art,
                            Where pure, confiding trust its mantle threw. The simpleness that fathomed not the well
                            Wherein the pearl of truth in beauty gleamed; Nor noted its possession, nor could tell How
                            great to other eyes its value seemed. We will not say adieu, nor parting take, But on thy
                            heart we lay a lily-flower, The love we bear thee, may its bloom awake Within thy soul
                            unfailing source of power. Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Twilight thoughts" TEIform="index"/> TWILIGHT THOUGHTS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wayne, Sophia" TEIform="persName"/> Sophia Wayne.</byline><p TEIform="p"> What lovely views the golden sunsets are, They lead our thoughts to that bright land afar,
                            Where we can see the pearly gates ajar To our fair spirit home. And as we watch the daylight
                            fleeting fast, And think of earthly trials that are past, We know we'll gain that blissful
                            realm at last Where trials never come. Our loved ones who have journeyed on before Are
                            watching for us from yon peaceful shore, We soon shall reach the bright forevermore, Where
                            pain and sickness cease. No earthly creeds will gain our passport there, The Spirit
                            whispers, " 'Tis by deeds and prayer, Dependence on our heavenly Parents' care That wins
                            true joy and peace."</p><pb n="154" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Open letter" TEIform="index"/> OPEN LETTER,</head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon, April 1891" TEIform="index"/></dateline><p TEIform="p"> To John McCabe. Mount Lebanon, N. Y. Apr. 1891. Respected Friend ;Your plea for Liberty of
                            Conscience published in the "Evening Journal," Albany, N. Y., respecting the separation of
                            Church and State, is good and timelya word in season. It is as "apples of gold in pictures
                            of silver." One generation goeth, another cometh. Fifty years ago, the same problems about
                            the Sabbath, Liberty of Conscience, the Rights of man and woman, of Capital and Labor that
                            you set forth, were propounded and discussed, that are now agitating the whole civilized
                            world. These problems can only be settled by war. It is simply a question, shall it be a war
                            of monitors, guns and swords or a "war of ideas" as Napoleon predicted ? Think there can be
                            no doubt but that the last and final war that mankind will ever wage that will precede the
                            Millennium will be a war of ideas, of words, of reasoning, a mental war. Washington declared
                            that Paine did more with his pen, than he had done with his sword for the ultimate success
                            of the American Revolution. Are we ready for that kind of war. Then will come the New
                            Earthly Order receiving the inherent, inalienable rights of man and woman, common sense,
                            entire separation of Church and State into two distinct orders in which there shaU be no
                            theology and that will be founded in righteousness, giving to each child, hereafter to be
                            born, a natural, rational parentage. No more come-bychance, unwelcome children; children of
                            lust, to become victims of poverty, and material for Christian wars and murders. In America
                            lefc us have universal equal education in Public Industrial Schools, in which each child
                            shall have the same privileges and opportunities with every other child. Knowledge is
                            powerno class education, enabling one part of the people to rob the other part by making and
                            enacting Constitutions and Laws, without the robbed-oppressed understanding or knowing how
                            and why it is done. Inasmuch as all people have an inalienable right to an inheritance in
                            all the elements of life, land, sea, air, water, light, labor and reason, wherefore should a
                            present living generation be burdened with paying debts contracted by their dead ancestors ?
                            Lot each generation pay as they go, the dead have no rights the living are bound to respect,
                            as regards the earth and all there is therein. Abolish all laws for the collection of debts,
                            private and national, and in their place substitute a code of honor. More private debts
                            would then be paid than at present, when the lawyers get more money for collecting than
                            comes to the creditors. That would be a New Earth. And a New Heaven would come into
                            existence, a purely spiritual order, with its non-religious theology, free from politics and
                            perfectly separate from the State, or New Earth. It will be a Christian Church not of this
                            world and therefore its subjects wTould not fight nor marry, leaving that for the children
                            of this world. It wrould attach no blame to a clear materialist, like Paine, Lincoln and
                            Ingersoll, as belief is a result of evidence not of authority. Force, <pb n="155" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/>
                            however applied, cannot compel belief. An inquisition is unreasonable, illogical, it is
                            insanitylike war. If nations intend to do right all the use of fighting is to humble the
                            billigerents so that they will be willing to reason, to arbitrate. In the Millennium,
                            Krupp's cannon weighing 170, OOOlbs, sending a ball 4ft. long, weighing 3600 lbs., together
                            with monitors and all the munition of Christian wars will be kept as curiosities, as we now
                            keop the curious instruments of torture for heretics, which the Earl of Shrewsbury has
                            bought and brought from the castle of Nuremburg to London. In the times you refer to, G-. H.
                            Evans occupied the position that Henry George is now filling so efficiently. He edited "The
                            Man," "Young America," "Working Man's Advocate," the "Free Enquirer" and printed the "Bible
                            of Reason." I have imperfect files of these papers. Arthur Tapping was the leading orthodox
                            fanatic. Stopping the mail on Sunday was a favorite measure, of which you speak so wisely.
                            The present generation must fight these battles over again, or we shall become Church and
                            State and be ready for some new form of the Inquisition. Our own times must bring forth its
                            own leaders as did the civil war. In the Crimean War, England sent "an army of Lion's
                            commanded by Jackasses." As the warprogresed the right men got into their right places. Will
                            not the World's Fair do the same? The fanatical, fighting, marrying, Inquisition clericals
                            will think they have achieved a great victory in closing the Fair on their manmade
                            anti-christian Sabbath. Incon:mon sense, are they not braying out their own shame and
                            proclaiming to all nations that they are not equal to the great occasion of a World's Fair?
                            They can bray and kick but cannot command the respect of the great army of lions who will be
                            at the World's Fair, who have seven days of Sabbath one just as good as the other, and each
                            one as sacred and with the same right to have their Sabbath kept by all the others as have
                            the misnamed Christians.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/> F. W. Evans.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Child's hymn" TEIform="index"/> A CHILD'S HYMN.</head><p TEIform="p"> [Contributed by D. Orcutt.] Six Hundred Years Old. Guard, my child, thy tongue, That it
                            speak no wrong! Let no evil word pass o'er it; Set the watch of truth before it, That it
                            speak no wrong. Guard, my child, thy tongue. Guard, my child, thine eyes; Prying is not
                            wise; Let them look on what is right; From all evil turn their sight; Prying is not wise.
                            Guard, my child, thine eyes. Guard, my child, thine ear; Wicked words will sear; Let no evil
                            word come in That may cause the soul to sin; Wicked words will sear; Guard, my child, thine
                            ear. Ear, and eye and tongue, Guard while tliou art young; For, alas! these busy three Can
                            unruly members be; Guard, while thou art young, Ear, and eye, and tongue.</p><pb n="156" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p"> THE MANIFESTO. JULY, 1893. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is published by the "United
                            Society of Belie vebs" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued regularly by
                            the Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the religious views of
                            the Obdeb dfad to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. All communications should be
                            addressed to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer, Co., N. H. One copy per year, postage
                            paid, .75 " " six months, " " .40 Send for sample copy, free. Entered at the Post Office at
                            East Canterbury, N. H., as second-class matter.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial.</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The best use of the armor of the God of Peace..." TEIform="index"/>
                                The best use of the armor of the God of Peace...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> The best use of the armor of the God of Peace is becoming more and more a matter of
                                necessity. Professed followers of the divine Teacher have taught a singular gospel. They
                                have said,"Thou shalt love thy enemies," and then immediately send armies of tens of
                                thousands with implements of war to lay waste whole cities and villages, in the name of
                                this peace-loving Teacher. History affords us wonderful scenes of the great war gods who
                                gloried in the immolation of their victims, and made their highway a road of
                                devastation, and their glory the ruin of those who fell in their way. The religious
                                thought of the nations could get but a short distance above the heads of those
                                war-loving races, and as a natural result, their God was a god of war, and no less a god
                                of sensuality. These soldiers, however, had been learning to defend themselves,
                                skillfully, against their equally savage neighbors, by cunningly devised armor which St.
                                Paul observes with great interest, and makes of it a religious lesson, well worthy the
                                attention of a Christian pilgrim. If these murderous soldiers could use such special
                                care in their equipment to defend themselves against the weapons of an earthly enemy,
                                then, indeed, the follower of the peaceloving Jesus, should take no less care to defend
                                himself against the enemies that are seeking the ruin of his hope of life both in this
                                world and in that which is to come. It is needed, at the present day, most emphatically,
                                that men should put on the whole armor of God, and this armor should be complete in its
                                every part. So essential is this for the victory over evil, that some spiritually
                                awakened minds have written that "one reserve," one error persisted in may result in
                                complete failure. Deviations from the principle of right-doing is one of the dangerous
                                places in which some are inclined to walk. Their armor is defective and through a
                                careless indifference <pb n="157" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> they easily fall a prey to the spirit of
                                evil, and when quite too late, find that instead of having on the armor of God, they
                                have accepted a very inferior article. To the disciple of the man Jesus, it becomes a
                                matter of the greatest importance in our several homes, that our order of life should be
                                one of unflinching integrity, one of honest labor for the good of our fellow men, and
                                one of spiritual advancement over and beyond the idol worship that so prominently rises
                                before us. Of what benefit may a work be to those who seek, if they are never able to
                                find any satisfactory result? Of what benefit is it to any one, as said the good
                                Apostle, if "I bestow all my goods to feed the poor, and give my body to be burned," and
                                do not accompany this with charity toward our fellow men ? It is all valueless, time
                                wasted without compensation. Would it not be well to look a little more carefully to our
                                armor and especially to our breastplate of righteousness, which more than all things
                                else, aids us in doing to others as we would that they should do to us ? Of course we
                                are all interested in being successful in the maintenance of our gospel home ; of
                                securing the great blessings which have been promised to those who walk uprightly, and
                                in making our life to harmonize with the testimony we preach, and with the faith which
                                we profess. It is our great privilege to lovej God, and to depart from all iniquity. To
                                establish an honesty of purpose, and through this to inspire others with an earnestness
                                to seek with diligence the inestimable treasures of the kingdom of heaven.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How very singular it is for highly civilized and Christianized people..." TEIform="index"/>
                            How very singular it is for highly civilized and Christianized people...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">How very singular it is for highly civilized and Christianized people, in this wonderful day
                            of grace, to become excited and begin to "breathe out threatenings and slaughter" against a
                            little company of religionists. Persecution seems to be in the air, and after calling the
                            Koreshans of Chicago, a long list of bad names these self-styled Christianized lambs are
                            foolishly making ready to do violence to those whom they call the wolves of Koresh. This is
                            a queer exhibition of religion. It is, indeed, a change of base, and could only be brought
                            out in this nineteenth century. Those who viftit the World's Fair will also want to see this
                            wonder of the age.Christian lambs devouring the Koresh wolves. The little company in Chicago
                            who are under the charge of Dr. Teed and who at this time are unreasonably annoyed with the
                            indignities of an ignorant class, have our sympathetic regard and a wish for their peace and
                            prosperity.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The German Proverb says, ''By the street of By-and-By...''" TEIform="index"/>
                            The German Proverb says, ''By the street of By-and-By...''
                        </head><p TEIform="p">[Contributed by D. C. Brainaejx] The German Proverb says "By the street of By-and-By one
                            arrives at the house of never."</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="'Tis wrong to give offence" TEIform="index"/>'Tis wrong to give offence
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> 'Tis wrong to give offence.</p><pb n="158" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In memory of elder Nathaniel Fry" TEIform="index"/> In Memory of ELDER NATHANIEL FRY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Beaver, Orrin" TEIform="persName"/> Orrin Beaver.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Another well tried veteran and faithful toiler in Zion's fold has left our ranks to join the
                            band of brave, heroic souls who have made the way of God their choice, and freely sacrificed
                            all earthly pleasures, for an enduring inheritance with justified spirits in heaven. For
                            nearly half a century he has stood as a firm pillar in the cause of Christian purity. Ever
                            battling in the cause of right, never ashamed to be called a true Shaker, but ever ready to
                            speak in defence of its glorious principles before an unbelieving world. His parental advice
                            to those young in the faith was ever most judiciously given, and his great concern seemed to
                            be that they might gain a firm planting in the true principles of Mother's gospel, that
                            would prove an anchor to the soul,, sure and steadfast. A faithful Brother in the discharge
                            of all temporal duties, he was equally alive and zealous in support of all known spiritual
                            ones. Nothing in his later years gave him more pleasure than to listen to some soulstirring
                            communication, as given through our inspired spiritual instruments. At such times his eyes
                            would seem to kindle with all the enthusiasm of early youth and he would exclaim: Oh, how it
                            rejoices my soul to hear these precious promises of God to his chosen people. I have full
                            assurance that they will all be fulfilled to the very letter. He was a model of neatness in
                            all the relations of life, kind, loving and charita ble to all his Brethren and Sisters and
                            pa. tient in the midst of severe afflictions in a most remarkable degree. None but those who
                            were with him during his last illness can ever be fully conscious of the wonderful nerve and
                            fortitude displayed by him. During his greatest * physical suffering hardly a murmur or
                            complaint ever escaped his lips. We rejoice that his long-suffering spirit is at last
                            released from its weary prisonhouse of clay, and trust that it is happier than it was
                            possible for it to be here in time. His life-work was nobly, faithfully done, and in those
                            star-gemmed mansions of immortal life, he will, no doubt, be crowned with a royal diadem,
                            while through the corridors of heaven will ring the joyful refrain,"Well done good and
                            faithful servant, enter thou into the joy of thy Lord."</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/> NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mount Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/> Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> Average of Weather at Mount Lebanon. May. Thermometer. Bain. 1891. 55.48 2 in. 1892.
                                51.16 &amp;}4 in. Highest Temp, during this mo. 84. Lowest " " " " 36. Mean " " " "
                                51.16 Total Eainfall " " " 8% in. Number of rainy days " " 16 C. R. June 12, 1892. "What
                                is so rare as a day in June." Thus said the poet Lowell, and in reply we would say, "a
                                day in July." June has so long been the popular queen of the year, that the beauties of
                                the succeeding month seem lost under her royal shadows, and all the credit July gets is
                                for heat and thunder. But in this as in other things we take for granted what some one
                                else has thought, and forget that we can think for ourselves. Still there is a good
                                reason for the worship which the queenly June receives. After the cold, stormy winter
                                and fickle spring have passed we appreciate a beautiful day in May or June, when
                                vegetation almost suddenly dons its robe of delicate green, and the air seems full of
                                birds, blossoms and bees. By and by we become so used to the beautiful about us, that we
                                neglect to admire it. If a little thought is given to it we who live above the
                                forty-first parallel will find some of the rarest days of the year in July. The fine
                                weather is no <pb n="159" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> longer a petted guest, but it lias come to stay,
                                and is "at home" and settled down to business. There are days in July when the
                                transparent atmosphere would vie with that of far-famed Italy, and the rich leafy
                                verdure of the surrounding hillsides, with that of the tropics. Can we not gather a
                                lesson from this, and see if each and all about us who are toiling patiently in and for
                                the right, receive the appreciation and commendation they deserve? "The plaudits of the
                                crowd" are transient and fickle, but the kind word as we pass is a quiet and living
                                inspiration, a panacea for most of the troubles of life. Home is about the same as when
                                last reported. Crops in and growing finely. Showers and sunshine seem to be hurrying
                                matters along, and all from the oldest to the youngest are putting shoulders to the
                                wheel, comforted in the reflection, that "If denied the victor's meed, We shall not lack
                                the toiler's pay." Apples, pears, peaches, plums and cherries bloomed as full as last
                                year, and it only remains to be seen how much the blasting east storm of tliree days
                                duration in May, injured the fruit. We hope not much, for we observe that already the
                                early cherry trees begin to show the scarlet fruit. The piercing cold of that storm bade
                                us expect a solid freeze when the wind changed. But fortunately the skies remained
                                cloudy until the balmy south wind came to the rescue, and we experienced such a relief
                                from anxiety, that our joy was indeed, "a sweet and glad surprise." A. J. C. KTortli
                                TTamily. June 12, 1892. The June Manifesto came along ahead of time; but upon looking
                                for the music we found none. However, upon reflection, we remembered that in the May
                                number we had two pages; so we felt better. I love the inspirational songs of Zion; they
                                are the chief avenue of spiritual life between the heavens and the earth. On the 5th.
                                inst. our Society meetings opened for the season, very much to the satisfaction of all.
                                On the 3rd. we had the very great pleasure of entertaining our beloved Elder George
                                Wilcox who was expected to journey to the land of souls a short time since. We rejoiced
                                heartily. How much we need a manifestation of the Divine Spirit, to quicken within us
                                faith in the power of the gospel of Christ and Mother. Was it not the manifestation of
                                the power of good in the life of Jesus and Mother Ann, that inspired the faith of the
                                early and later saints. Webster defines saint as a person sanctified; one eminent for
                                piety and virtue. We are sanctified through obedience to the truth; obedience to the
                                truth means aggressive warfare against error and sin, which is the violation of the law
                                of good. Negative goodness is very pretty and should be the natural inheritance of all
                                children: but alas, it is not. Positive goodness that brings the saint out of the
                                sinner, and makes the just man perfect, is attained only by a positive warfare against
                                all the causes of evil in the individual, and in the systems under which individuals
                                live, which systems are very largely responsible for the condition of misery and
                                degradation under which they are forced to iive. The season with us is still behindhand,
                                and unless the summer days are extended we shall probably fall short in some things. The
                                long continued, cold wet weather has made it necessary to replant some fields of corn.
                                Even the weeds keep growing where they are let alone, which is a constant reminder to be
                                up and doing. It looks now, as though the great promise of fruit we had in the profuse
                                blossoms would, in part at least, be a failure: but it is a little too soon to pass
                                judgment. In kindest love, D. O. All in usual health at the Mount. Spring work outdoors
                                and in presses with uncommon force. Sisters have on hand over 200 doz. shirts. Two
                                hundred pounds of wool is being sorted, cleansed and dyed in the old fashioned indigo
                                blueing tub. <pb n="160" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> Four hundred yards of cotton cloth bleached in
                                chloride. Window painting, wall painting, staining, etc., is included in the sum.
                                Brethren are seen skipping here and there between the rain drops, to replant, or with
                                hoe in hand to uproot and so it goes. A. W.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/> Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> June, 1892. Since writing our Home Notes for June, we have had thoughts about Noah's
                                Ark, but fortunately May had only thirty-one days. We concluded our elevation would save
                                us from the necessity of building the second ark, but we have had rain, rain, rain.
                                Crops are backward and we shall have to trust Providence and better weather for the
                                result of the harvest. We had a pleasant visit from gospel kindred on the 29th. ult.
                                from the "Happy land of Canaan;" Sister Miriam Offord, with four young Sisters, and
                                while at Watervliet, established head quarters at our Family. Although the reaper Death
                                visited us twice during their short stay, we believe that they with us enjoyed a
                                pleasant season of love and exchange of good feelings. We would say to all concerned
                                that they honored their name and profession. Eldress Alvira Conklin of our Family
                                started to-day on a mission of love to the little Society of Believers in the city of
                                brotherly love; with her goes our love and prayers for the welfare of the little band
                                who are gathered there, striving to grow and increase in the knowledge of the Lord, also
                                for the whole household of faith. Elder Josiah Barker of the Church Family and Sisters,
                                Anna Case and Isabella Graves of the South Family have started on a visit to the eastern
                                Societies of Believers. Through the medium of the Manifesto, we send love to them, and
                                we hope they may impart and also receive much good to bring home. Through the same
                                medium, we send love and kindly greetings to all Believers east and west, and a double
                                store to our afflicted parents Elder Daniel and Eldress Ann. May Zion have a spiritual
                                baptism equal to the water baptism of the past month is our sincere desire and prayer.
                            *</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Canaan, New York" TEIform="index"/> Canaan, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> June, 1892. We are enjoying this pleasant season, having had an abundance of rain and
                                cold weather. Nature has, indeed, put on her most beautiful array. Orchards, gardens,
                                meadows, yea, all things seem to vie with each other in splendor and rapid growth.
                                Surely "the lines have fallen unto us in a pleasant place." Plowing, planting and sowing
                                have been done with zeal and energy. Sisters have done their part by getting various
                                kinds of plants well started in hot beds; besides many plants and flowers with which to
                                beautify our home. All, even to the children, have taken a lively interest in helping on
                                the good work of building up and supporting the cause, gladly performing manual labor
                                and home duties of every kind with the prospect of enjoying in common, the fruits of
                                unselfish, united labor. More than this, we are blest with good spiritual meetings,
                                blessed opportunities for developing the better part of our beings, for awakening pure
                                thoughts and holy aspirations and drawing down those heavenly ministrations which
                                strengthen both body and mind. What hour is so blest as that spent in spiritual devotion
                                when all hearts in unison are striving for the pearl of great price, the true spirit of
                                holiness. A good Shaker meeting, in which every heart is free from sin by an honest
                                confession and is therefore free in the spirit to impart and make manifest their best
                                gifts, is really and truly a feast of good things. It is the true impetus, the great
                                motor which gives life and growth to a religious organization. Then let us raise higher
                                the gospel banner and through the efficacy of living testimony and inspirational song,
                                gather that abiding power that wrill be a substance and treasure for other souls, that
                                they also may come and <pb n="161" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> glorify the eternal spirit of goodness by
                                helping to carry on the grand work of human redemption. Our five Sisters who have been
                                visiting the friends at Watervliet, have returned laden with gospel love and renewed
                                energy to persevere in well-doing, feeling quite refreshed by the kind hospitality so
                                nobly extended toward them. E. O.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/> West Pittsfield, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p"> June, 1892. Weather at present in our vicinity is extremely warm. July having taken
                                April as a precedent, seems to be endeavoring to supersede the month of June. A few days
                                since, our fruit trees were gorgeously bedecked with bloom and beauty. Grass is looking
                                finely, and present appearances betoken a fruitful season. Although there may not have
                                been too much of a rainfall, yet so much rainy weather has somewhat impeded the work of
                                the farmers. Nevertheless, with tact and energy our farmers and gardeners have succeeded
                                in getting in their crops in good time. Br. Ira, through the goodness of an all-wise,
                                compassionate Father, and the assiduous attention and care of physicians and nurses, is
                                rapidly regaining his health. Elder George Wilcox who had almost worked Ids passage to
                                the summer land, kindly favored us with his benign presence on the 31st. ult. It would
                                have been a great satisfaction could we have enjoyed the privilege of entertaining him
                                in our midst for many days, but he felt that home duties claimed his attention, and as
                                is his wont, pleasure and the rest and change he so much needed were sacrificed, and he
                                returned alter the brief stay of only three or four days. The age of miracles seems not
                                to have wholly passed away. Are not these two cases instances of almost physical
                                resurrection, though unlike Lazarus they had not been entombed? J. L. S.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/> Shaker Station, Conn.</head><p TEIform="p"> "Give us this day our daily bre^d." Why should we ask the Lord to give us what He is
                                constantly providing in some measure, whether we ask Him or not? Because by asking we
                                acknowledge that we are dependent upon Him for our bread by whatever agencies He sends
                                it to us. He feeds the fowls of the air and the beasts of the field. He clothes the
                                lilies with beauty and makes the hills and valleys smile with harvests. Our spiritual
                                and temporal food is truly the Lord's gift, and we should feel our absolute dependence
                                upon Him for all blessings. We should pray without ceasing and with perfect faith, "Give
                                us this day our daily bread." If we are living to God, our hearts will overflow with
                                gratitude and thankfulness, for blessings chiefly spiritual, but also temporal. Let us
                                praise God for his unbounded goodness. Our Hubbard squashes that sold at three cents a
                                pound were a paying crop. When stored in a dry and cool cellar they can be kept until
                                May. The poultry business is peculiarly adapted to all classes of society. The hen is a
                                general favorite all over the land, and she is ever ready to do a good deed for
                                humanity. Keeping fowls is a business that one should know something about before
                                investing too largely. Economical feeding involves a knowledge of the needs of the fowls
                                as well as the composition of the foods. Too much whole grain is not so good as a fair
                                supply of bran and milk. When chickens are two weeks old cracked corn may be used to
                                some extentcorn meal and bran. When grown together in large numbers and they have little
                                or no opportunity to forage for themselves, the food should be suited to their age and
                                wants. 4345 spaces of cream were sold in May. D. Okottt.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ayer, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/> Ayer, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p"> June, 1892. After a week of disagreeable, rainy weather, which has hindered outdoor work
                                and travel for that length of time, we have a chance to welcome again the rays of old
                                Sol, as almost a stranger. The <pb n="162" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> faces of the farmers are
                                brightened as they feel assured that their hard work for the summer is not to be cut off
                                by untimely frost. All hail to the faithful worker of the soil, as he follows his plough
                                and turns the sod, that will give to us our corn and potatoes. The farmer's life is one
                                of labor, if there would be success. The life of a Shaker is a life of industrious toil
                                and if we live aright we must labor; and as this is the home of our choice, why not put
                                forth our best life efforts to make it a beautiful home. It is said that the outward is
                                often an index of the inner man, and if we would convert others to our faith, we must
                                have our premises neat and orderly. There is but little hope for the sloven, but God
                                will bless the intelligent and persevering worker. June 1st. finds our crops all in. We
                                have about thirty acres under cultivation, and shall look forward to a fruitful harvest.
                                Our orchards give evidence of a bounteous crop of apples, and that will make the whole
                                family feel joyful as they anticipate the coming of another year. Warm weather has
                                driven away nearly all the sickness. A. D. B.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/> East Canterbury, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p"> Weather Eecord, for April 1892. Highest Temp, during the mo. 79. Lowest " " " " 32. Mean
                                " " " " 53.3 Total rainfall " " " 6.57in. Number of days' rain " " 14 N. A. Bkiggs.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Alfred, Maine" TEIform="index"/> Alfred, Me.</head><p TEIform="p"> June 12, 1892. "And God said, let the earth bring forth grass, the herb yielding seed
                                after its kind and the tree yielding fruit whose seed is in itself, upon the earth: and
                                it was so. And the earth brought forth grass and the herb yielding seed after its kind."
                                And it has continued to do so to this day, as our fields and pastures covered with their
                                beautiful mantle of green, give evidence. Just now we are anxious that rain may come and
                                give sustenance to all these beautiful creationsanxious, as though there were not a
                                Power above that careth for all these things. The Brethren are now busy with their hoes,
                                killing the noxious weeds that would rob the precious plants. And are we caring as
                                faithfully for our spiritual garden, the heart, that nothing remains there to rob us of
                                our happiness? If so, I believe it will be well with us, for we read: "Blessed are the
                                pure in heart, for they shall see God." Since writing "Notes" for last month we have
                                been blessed with a visit from our Parents, the Central Ministry with Eldress Dorothy
                                Wright from the Church Family, Mount Lebanon. Elder Joseph was never in Maine before.
                                His Christian love and humility call forth our choicest love. Eldress Harriet and
                                Eldress Augusta we had seen and learned to love years ago. The heavenly ministration of
                                love, blessing and charity which they brought with them will long remain with us to
                                strengthen and encourage us to still persevere on in this beautiful way of selfdenial
                                and the cross, each striving to be good and to do good. As we have received love and
                                blessing, so we would extend our choicest love to all our gospel friends. F. C.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine" TEIform="index"/> Sabbathday Lake, Me.</head><p TEIform="p"> June 13, 1892. The months seem to pass very quickly and there is no time to linger or
                                "put off" in regard to writing "Home Notes." Our good editor enjoins punctuality, which
                                is a very necessary attainment. The Mount Lebanon Ministry and Eldress Dorothy Wright
                                arrived at this place on the 20th. ult. They stayed with us four days and during that
                                time administered a mountain of strength. The Oi'der was new excepting our dearly loved
                                Eldress Harriet Bullard. There can be no failure in our Zion as long as it is strong
                                enough to supply such leaders as Elder Joseph Holden. We found in Eldress Augusta Stone
                                a spiritual mother well worthy of <pb n="163" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> our love and confidence, and in
                                Eldress Dorothy a pattern of purity and a spirit abounding in the lovely graces of the
                                gospel. On the 21st. ult snow fell to the depth of five or six inches and remained on
                                the ground most of the next day. Our house plants and seedlings were out and many of the
                                largest were broken by the weight of the snow, but otherwise no harm was done. From the
                                blossoming of our fruit trees we anticipate a bountiful harvest. The strawberry bed set
                                out last spring is now in a perfection of bloom and we are sure of plenty of that
                                delicious fruit later on. We have been somewhat troubled with measles; seven cases
                                within the last two months, and bad colds are afflicting many of those who are measle
                                proof. A. S. C.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sonyea, New York" TEIform="index"/> Sonyea, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> June, 1892. The new June is a terrific scorcher; without its frequent showers the dry
                                old world would soon become a mighty blaze. Western New York has a fine prospect of much
                                fruit. The yearly campaign that tries men's souls and women's soles too has passed.
                                "House-cleaning" is finished, our house is set in order preparatory for other scenes
                                that await perfection. The sowing and planting of spring crops was not all a success,
                                several acres oL' corn were replanted, as the over-drenched earth damaged the first; of
                                the second we cannot tell, that, too, may meet with a failure as well. During the past
                                few weeks Brother Henry Hollister has built new plank sidewalks around the buildings;
                                more comfort and less fear is now realized by the walking public than has been known for
                                many years. A portion of the large barn at the West Farm has found a renovation through
                                his much toil. The haying season has commenced, and rich will the harvest be, for the
                                grass grows fast where rain and sun cause blighting forms to flee. G. D. G.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/> Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p"> June, 1892. We had thought we would leave our allotted space this month for matters more
                                important, when, at the eleventh hour, a friend inadvertently made a statement bearing
                                rather upon the appreciative of what has heretofore been forthcoming from this branch of
                                the vineyard, and gave us an impetus to keep on the move. Such is the power of
                                influence; true it is that "the clarion voice of duty should ring high above all other
                                lesser sounds," and yet, we all at times find ourselves just human enough to joy in the
                                knowledge that even one finds benefit or satisfaction through our feeble efforts; it is
                                said that there are birds that sing the sweeter when caged and oppressed, so there are
                                human birds who apparently enjoy doing a duty for the very love of it, but they are
                                exceptions, not the rule, until that height is reached. We were especially glad to hear
                                from E. O. who wrote for the brave little circle in Canaan, that happy land, who are
                                denying self if need be, that they may be without hirelings. One writer says, "there is
                                a touch of flavor in garden sauce that a man never gets until he swings the hoe," and no
                                doubt the vegetables and fruits that find thtir way to your frugal board, are far more
                                welcome, and sweeter to the taste, for having been coaxed into perfection by your own
                                willing hands. The spiritual atmosphere of the home without hirelings, as a matter of
                                simple cause and effect, must be of a higher order; we shall be interested to hear from
                                you often, who have thus begun to build so wisely. Rain lias reigned with us, as
                                elsewhere, but it has only made the green look greener, thus enhancing, if possible, the
                                beauty of the natural scenery. Old Mascoma never over-reaches the bounds of propriety,
                                so we have had neither flood, nor flame, nor cloud burst to cause alarm. E. B.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Oh what is worth our thought, our labor our affections..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Oh what is worth our thought, our labor our affections...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Oh what is worth our thought, our labor our affections while here, but that which tells for
                            eternity?</p><pb n="164" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Inquiry. no. 5" TEIform="index"/> INQUIRY. No. 5.</head><p TEIform="p"> It is quite common to be asked the following question. "How do you settle difficulties that
                            arise between individual members of your Society ?" In a Christian Community the members
                            must be governed by the spirit of Christ. The contract which is signed by persons on
                            entering the Society, and the Rules and Regulations of the Order, which are for the same
                            purpose as the bye-laws of other Societies, determine quite clearly the course that must be
                            taken by each member toward every other member. To injure another person by word or report
                            or deed produces disunion and the trespass must be corrected by confession or
                            acknowledgment. The correct government of the mind is an essential Christian discipline, and
                            to be able to maintain a gospel relation, a good union must be sustained. No member has a
                            right to trespass upon the privileges of another and if this is done, either carelessly or
                            willfully, it must be apologized for, or if necessary made a subject of confession.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Scripture text. The puzzled young man" TEIform="index"/> SCRIPTURE TEXT. The Puzzled Young
                            Man.</head><p TEIform="p"> If any man come to me and hate not his father and mother, and wife and children, and
                            brethren and sisters, yea, and his own life also, he cannot be my disciple. Luke xiv., 26.
                            We do not wonder that he was puzzled. It must have sounded like a very singular religion, to
                            teach people to hate their best friends. The Teacher, so far as he was known, manifested a
                            very kind and sympathizing spirit toward the poor, and those under affliction, and then to
                            preach such a sweeping system of hatred was an unsolved enigma. This same text remains a
                            puzzle. Christians and Infidels are, alike, unable to render a reason for such a remark. The
                            Christians with their untempered mortar, attempt to cover it from sight or to so blind the
                            eyes of the readers that they shall not see it. And then they illustrate it by saying that
                            he did not mean for his disciples to hate any of these relations, but only that they should
                            not love them quite so much as they loved Jesus, while the Infidels say that Jesus went a
                            little too far in his zeal and overstepped the bounds of propriety. Some think that this is
                            in strange contrast with his language at another time when he said, "Love your enemies,
                            though they despitefully use you and persecute you." To teach people to love a class of men
                            and women who are doing all that lies in their power to ruin your character and to destroy
                            your happiness, and at the same time, teach them to hate their fathers and mothers and
                            children, is enough to puzzle a young man or even an aged wise man. But as Jesus was the
                            Teacher of a new and living way, the head of a new creation of God, his doctrine was not and
                            is not fully understood by either the Christians or Infidels who still claim Adam as their
                            gospel father, and the life of the generative world as their sacred treasure. The <pb n="165" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> new way of holiness does not harmonize with the old way of
                            worldiiuess. The first teaches the principles of peace on earth, and' that a virgin or
                            spiritual life are the only sure passports by which to enter the City of God, while the
                            others teach that might is right, whether of the brain or muscle ; and then the Christian
                            steps in to say that wars and the carnage that follows is ordained of God, and that
                            sensuality under cover of sensual lawgivers is justifiable.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Foretells the end" TEIform="index"/> FORETELLS THE END.</head><p TEIform="p"> In north Georgia the Rev. T. K. Hostell, a Baptist missionary from Indian Territory, claims
                            to be informed as to the date fixed for the end of the world. He says that during the last
                            year lie has had so many mysterious revelations made to Mm that lie felt called upon to
                            preach to his own people their impending doom. The Israelites, lie says, will take up their
                            journey to Palestine on the 3rd. of April, 1896. On the same date in the year 1900, the new
                            temple at Jerusalem will be dedicated with impressive ceremonies and Christ will make his
                            secoad advent on Mount Olivet the 15th of May of the same year. In the meantime all the
                            terrible disasters foretold for the last days will begin at once. Brethren will be arrayed
                            against each other as never before. There will be wars and political revolutions calculated
                            to drive people to a sense of their duty to God. His hearers listen with eagerness to his
                            revelations and will talk of nothing else.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sowing wild oats" TEIform="index"/> "SOWING WILD OATS."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bowers, Lucy S." TEIform="persName"/> Lucy S. Bowers.</byline><p TEIform="p"> The foregoing phrase is one which is in common use, and generally applies to the stages of
                            youth or early life, when both the body and mind are most buoyant and active in all their
                            natural tendencies, and the hardest to restrain and direct. It also seems to be a kind of
                            license and willing sanction of all the actions and dispositions common to youth, regardless
                            of regularity, submission or genuine morality ; anything which it occurs to them to indulge
                            in is apologized for, with the sentiment that they are "sowing their wild oats," from which
                            is to be inferred that in some near future they will settle into steadier ways of life. It
                            implies that youth must have a time of wickedness, the defying of authority and the abuse of
                            opportunity, after which all will come around right. Some one speaking keenly on this
                            subject said, that there was not a more certain mistake. That which you sow you shall reap;
                            if you sow "wild oats" you shall reap "wild oats." Not One instance can be found in all
                            humanity, where the evils indulged in in youth did not mar and scar the soul through life.
                            There is a penetrability and permanency in the virus of indulgence, that defies almost every
                            remedy for removal while we are in the bo Ay. Effect must follow cause ; if we eat that
                            which is unfit for our consumption we suffer the consequences; as the builder buildeth so
                            his house stands; as we do our duties so will they appear for or against us. Just so with
                            all our actions; it requires few repetitions comparatively to form a habit, and evil habits
                            however small, "well pursued betimes, may reach the dignity of crimes." The early formation
                            of a good character is an all important matter. <pb n="166" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> The following
                            contains a corresponding and undeniable truth: "An unrestrained childhood is the nursery for
                            the prison, the almshouse and a premature grave." Colton condemns the "wild oats" apology in
                            these words: "The excesses of our youth are drafts upon our old age, payable with fearful
                            interest from twenty to thirty years after date, and often much sooner." It is strange that
                            there should be so much heedlessness and latitude on the part of parents and guardians in
                            this respect. Healthful freedom, frolic and varied innocent entertainments appropriate to
                            early life, promate happiness and insure pleasant recollections in after years, but wiien
                            moral laxity is allowed, the consequences of suffering, sorrow and disgrace are as positive
                            and certain. "Train up a child in the way it should go" was the command. Many have credited
                            their successes in life to early teaching and discipline, and all who have chosen not to
                            depart from them, rejoice continually in their virtuous beginnings. If we sow and cultivate
                            good grain, and persistently destroy the evils that seem involuntarily to vegetate in the
                            soil of our minds, we shall find that we have enough to do, without wantonly and
                            deliberately sowing tares or any evil seed, which according to its kind, will bear the
                            bitter fruits of pain and regret. Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If thou art reproached unjustly, thou shouldst rejoice exceedingly..." TEIform="index"/>
                            If thou art reproached unjustly, thou shouldst rejoice exceedingly...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">If thou art reproached unjustly, thou sliouldst rejoice exceedingly in that thy condition is
                            so much better than if thou liadst deserved it.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Finish thy work" TEIform="index"/> FINISH THY WORK.</head><p TEIform="p"> Finish thy work, the time is short; The sun is in the west, The night is coming on; till
                            then, Think not of rest. Yes, finish all thy work, then rest; Till then, rest never; The
                            rest prepared for thee by God Is rest forever. Finish thy work, then wipe thy brow, Ungird
                            thee from thy toil; Take breath, and from each weary limb Shake off the soil. Finish thy
                            work, then rest in peace, Life's battle fought and won! And so to thee thy Master's voice
                            Shall say, "Well done!" Farm and Fireside.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="He that meddles with other men's matters..." TEIform="index"/>
                            He that meddles with other men's matters...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">He that meddles with other men's matters neglects his own.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>KIND WORDS.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We wish the Manifesto many happy New Years..." TEIform="index"/>
                                We wish the Manifesto many happy New Years...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New Hampshire, Enfield, March 1892" TEIform="index"/> Enfield, N. H., Mar. 1892,</dateline><p TEIform="p">We wish the Manifesto many happy, New Years. And the same to all who take an interest in
                                the cause it so nobly defends. This is the prayer of your Sister,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hart, Charlotte" TEIform="persName"/> Charlotte Hart.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fry, Nathaniel" TEIform="index"/>Elder Nathaniel Fry
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Elder Nathaniel Fry at Shakers, N. Y. May 26, 1892. Age 88 yrs. 9 mos. and 22 days.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Byram, Eliza M." TEIform="index"/>Sister Eliza M. Byram
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> 
                                Sister Eliza M. Byram, at Pleasant Hill, Ky., in the eightieth year of her age. Sister
                                Eliza came into the Society with her father when only ten years old. She has filled many
                                places of trust, during her long life, and lias been one who gave her all to the cause.
                                During the last years of her life, she has been an invalid, suffering much, and when the
                                last hours came, she feared not to "walk through the valley of the shadow of death." J.
                                W. S.</p><pb n="167" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/></div3></div2><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Looking upward" TEIform="index"/> LOOKING UPWARD.</head><p TEIform="p"> Mount Lebanon, N. Y. 1. I long in my heart for the truth, For something divine, Oh 2.
                            Temptations so often allure, And evils assail, Whence 3. The pow'r of salvation I seek, And
                            love's perfect light, Some 4. Thro' struggle is victory won, If holy the strife, Oh where
                            shall I look for that grace, I know should be mine ? cometh that pow'r that will cause, The
                            good to prevail? spirit to strengthen the faith, That leads in the right, give me a fullness
                            in Christ, The truth and the life. rit. Chorus. My soul reaches upward in pray'r, O Lord,
                            unto Thee, Thou wilt in Thy mercy appear, Yea, even to me, Yea, even to me. cres. - - - m
                            cres. - - - m rit.f rit.f</p><pb n="168" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ladies' home journal" TEIform="index"/>Ladies' Home Journal
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Bret Harte's young daughter, Miss Jessamy Harte, will make her literary debut in the
                                July Ladies' Home Journal with a most entertaining description of "Camp Life in the
                                Adirondack^," in which it is claimed every evidence shows itself of inherited literary
                                tendencies not unlike those evidenced in Bret Harte's earlier work. Miss Harte is a girl
                                still in her teens, and has artistic as well as literary proclivities, as one of the
                                illustrations accompanying her first article shows. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="World's Columbian exposition illustrated" TEIform="index"/>The World's Columbian Exposition
                                Illustrated
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The World's Columbian Exposition
                                Illustrated for June.This charming number retains those attractions that have made its
                                predecessors so popular, while it introduces new features that will make it more
                                interesting than ever. The question has often been asked, "Who reads a Chicago book? "
                                The 100,000 copies of this magazine now sold each month would seem to forcibly indicate
                                the propriety of the question, "Who does not read the 'World's Columbian Exposition
                                Illustrated'? " Certainly none should fail to read it who desire to be fully abreast of
                                the times and know of the grandest Exposition the world has ever seen. In the language
                                of our Consul-General to Austria, "It is the greatest feat of journalism of the age and
                                a credit to America." A mong its leading and interesting attractions we notice a
                                splendid full page engraving of the Hon. Elijah B. Martindale, National Commissioner
                                from Indiana, together with his biographical sketch. There is also sin admirable full
                                page engraving of the Indiana State Building, a gem of "architectural beauty. There are
                                several articles and engravings relating to Indiana's exhibit and its management.
                                Altogether the number is of vast interest, and will win many friends to the great
                                Exposition to which it i.-&gt; exclusively devoted. There have been sixteen numbers issued
                                to date. From first to last there will be five volumes of twelve numbers each, or sixtjr
                                numbers in all. Price 25 cents a copy. Subscribers for twelve issues at $3.00 will
                                receive free the World's.. Fair Album, containing views of the Exposition Buildings in
                                richest colors. Price of Album alone, 50 cents. J. B. CAMPBELL, President, 159 &amp;
                                161 Adams St., Chicago, III., U. S. A. The friends of practical art and design will be
                                highly pleased with the exceedingly well written sketch of Prof. Charles A. Barry, who
                                made the first portrait of President Lincoln. The late sudden death of Professor Barry
                                must add much interest to the publication. Dr. Edward A. Freeman, the emhiQsSfc'
                                historian, is very properly considered, and a portrait accompanies the brief account of
                                the man. Another worthy laborer in the phrenological field comes in for his share of
                                noticeMr. Phineas L. Buella descendant of the old Puritan stock. Why phrenology should
                                be studied is aptly shown by M. A. Thatcher. The transition period in child life
                                furnishes new hints to the parent, while the psychology of childhood confirms in
                                scientific fashion the plain truths of Mrs. Hull's article. Dreams are discussed. H. S.
                                D. answers certain pertinent questions regarding phases of catarrh that relate to
                                deafness. An enthusiastic writer draws a close connection between phrenology and
                                substantialism, and the editor comments on the late Chevalier de Quatrefages. Notes in
                                Anthropology are more than usually varied and instructive, and the editor's fresh paper
                                on Systematic Moral Education contains statements of an awakening character. The Journal
                                is published at $1.50 a year, or 15 cents a number, and is issued from the office of
                                Fowler &amp; Wells Co., 25 East Twenty-first street, New York. REMOVAL UP TOWN.
                                Fowler . &amp; Wells Co., Phrenologists aud Publishers, Have removed to 27 E. 21st.
                                Street, near Broadway, Where exchanges and all letters or other communications should be
                                addressed. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New England magazine" TEIform="index"/>New England
                                Magazine
                            </head><p TEIform="p">All interested in educational and Christian work will turn to the article on
                                "General Armstrong and the Hampton Institute," by Edwin H. Start in the New England
                                Magazine for June. It deals with the aims and methods of the institution, and describes
                                minutely the internal machinery of this great sociological experiment. An account is
                                given of the progress of the work since the founding of the institution, and a
                                biographical sketch of General Samuel Chapman Armstrong adds interest to the whole. The
                                article is finely illustrated from photographs and sketches made on the spot, the
                                management of the New England Magazine having sent the author and artist to Hampton,
                                Va., to prepare the article leisurely to get saturated with the ideas of the school and
                                the work. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Journal of hygeio-therapy" TEIform="index"/>The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy. May, Contents. Treatment of the Sick, No. 14;
                                Is Salt Dietetically Useful; Anti-Vaccination; Ladies and Tobacco; Keeley and his Cure;
                                Thoughts and Experience; etc., etc. Published by Dr. T. V. Gifford, Kokomo, Ind. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/>Hall's
                                Journal of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Hall's
                                Journal of Health. June, Contents. Talks with Dr. Mandeville; Emetics; Lumbago; The
                                Sunday Question; The Inquisitive Antelope; The Barefoot Teacher; Offensive Breath; Care
                                of the Teeth; Treatment of varicose veins; Infectious Diseases: The Keeley Craze;
                                Housework an Exei'cise; Exercise; etc., etc. Office 340 West 59th. St. New York.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p"> THE FAVORED CLASSES. Teachers, Ministers, Farmers, Mechanics, Merchants, as well as their
                            wives, daughters and sons, who would like to devote at least a part of their time and
                            attention to a work that would bring them in a lot of ready money during the next few
                            months, would do well to look up the advertisement of B. F. Johnson &amp; Co., Richmond,
                            Va., in another column, as it may be the means of opening up to many new life and larger
                            possibilities. These gentlemen have been extensively and successfully engaged in business
                            for many years, and they know what they are talking about when they tell you they can show
                            you how to better your financial condition.</p></div2><!--
<pb n="169" id="p"/>
We want one in every town
to handle the
A Scientific Machine made on a Scientific Principle. Save
their cost a dozen times a year. It is not mussy or sloppy.
A child can operate it. Sells at sight. Send for prices and
discounts.
29   Murray St.,   NEW   YORK.
lee   Cream    in   3D
64 Sudbury St..  Boston, Mass.
FIRE AND BURGLAR-PROOF SAFES.
Bank Safes, Bank Vaults, Bank Vault
Doors, and. Deposit Work of all kinds.
The Best Safe in the World.   150,000 in use.
Always preserve their contents
150 sold in Lynn, Mass., since that great lire
where 50 of our safes wore subject to intense
heat, preserving their contents.
Champion Record also in the Great Chieago Fire in 1871, in tho Great Boston fflrt in
1872, and in all the great fires since. Send
for circulars.        Agents Wanted.
tf7ROO 1. ffJEROO A MONTH can be
i/fii W |9Ui made working for us.
Persons preferred who can furnish a horse
and give their whole time to the business.
Spare moments may be prontably employed
also. A few vacancies in towns and cities.
B. F. JOHNSON & CO., 26th. and Main St.,
Richmond, Ta.
Scientific American
Agency for
CAVEATS,
TRADE MARKS,
__;SICN PATENTS
COPYRIGHTS, etc.
For information and free Handbook write to
MDNN & CO., 361 BROADWAY, NEW YORK.
Oldest bureau for securing patents in America.
Every patent taken out by ua is brought before
the public by a notice given free of charge in the
I * ft9*
Largest circulation of aTiy scientific paper in the
world. Splendidly illustrated. No intelligent
man should be without it. Weekly, S3.00 a
year; $1.50 six months. Address MUNN & CO.,
Vublishbhs, 361 Broadway, New York.
THE  AMRUIST.
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is published by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all
their property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing
officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. 50 cents a year;
specimen copy free. Address A. Longley,
901 Olive St.,   St. Louis, Mo.
I UlECIf working for W03LD 3 COLUMBIAN EXH WLLi\ POSITION ILLUSTSATED; authentic organ of the World's Pair. Most beautiful, interesting and popular publication issued. Sells
at sight. Send 15 c. in stamps for full particulars and sample copy containing COLOEED LITHOGEAPEIC VIEWS of EXPOSITION BUILDINGS. J. B.
Campbell, Pres., 218 LaSalle St., Chicago, 111.
AGENTS
DEALERS

JACK FROST FREEZER
Seconds.
E. C. Morris & Co.
AGENTS WANTED
MAK3 FROM
&5O.&1.5Q
<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure.
A cream of tartar baking Powder. Highest of all in leavening strength.Latest
United States Government Food Report.
Royal Baking Powder Co., 106 Wall St.,N. Y.
F. A. O;
Pkes. Am. CoPyRespostdenoe
Coi/lege:Dear Sir:Some of your
students afc this place having called my
attention to the course of instruction
provided by the AMERICAN COEEBSPONDBNCE COLLEGE, I
can say, from a personal examination
of the same, that I consider the information and benefit it imparts to be of
very great educational value to teachers and students as well as to any one
who wishes to increase or revive his
fund of practical knowledge.
Yours truly,
Louis Basting,  Pastor of Church at W. Pittsfield, Mass.
The above refers to our "REVIEW
& METHOD COURSE" given by
mail. A course of 10 weeks costs but
$2.50. (40 per cent discount to teachers.) A 32 page catalogue of all our
courses on receipt of stamp. Our mail
course in SHORT HAND is the best
and cheapest. Send stamps for full
particulars.
AMERICAN COERESPQNDSNCE
COLLEGE.
SOUTH DAUSVILLE, N. Y.
JOHN F. STEATTON & SON,
43 & 45 Walter St.             HEWYGRK.
Importers of all kinds o'
MUSICAL   MERCHANDISE,
Violins,  Guitars,   Banjos,
Accordeons, Harmonicas, &c.
All kinds of STRINGS, etc., etc.
TCASH   PRIZE.     Particulars   free.
)j. B. Caldwell, 104 Franklin St.,
Chicago.
THE WORLD'S FAIR. "
Whether you intend to visit the World's
Fair, Chicago, in 1893 or not you will want a
history of it from the beginning. Such a history is being magnificently presented "by
THE    EXPOSITION     GRAPHIC
Printed in English, G-erman, PrencTi anl Spanish
The first number of this great quarterly
edition of The Graphic, just issued, contains Views of all the Principal Buildings from
official designs (the Administration, -Fine
Arts, Manufactures, Fisheries, Mines and.
Mining. Agricultural Buildings and every,
thing else to date,) Portraits of the Principal Officers of the Commission and Directory, Views of the Principal Cities of America, full-page Portraits of President Harrison
and Secretary Blaine, and a superb triplepage Bird's 'Eye View of the Exposition
Grounds and Buildings from designs by the
Bureau of Construction.
You will want a copy for yourself and several for your friends.
52 Pages, with Supplement, The finest publication in America.
Do not fail to send for a copy or ask your
Newsdealer for it. Price 50 Ots. (with order.)
Subscription, one year, $2>
THE GRAPHIC~"THAT PHENOMENAL
SUCCESS OP ILLUSTRATED WEEKLIES   IN  THE
world's pair city." All the principal current events finely illustrated. The most
complete, the most popular, and altogether
the most valuable illustrated weekly. Ask
your newsdealer for it, or address the publishers.   Subscription, one year, $4.00
THE GRAPHIC CO.,
DEARBORN AND HARRISON STS. CHICAGO.
l=An agent wanted in every town in the U.S.
SHAKER'S   ANSWER
To THE OFT REPEATED QUESTION,
""What   will   become   of  the
World, if all become Shakers?"
Price, 10 cts.
West Pittsfield, Mass,
FROM      
A
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>