<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1310" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">13</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">10</biblScope><date value="18831001" TEIform="date">October 1883</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">217-240</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="13" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="10" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                <pb id="p1"/>
                    <p> vol. xiii. OCTOBER. NO. 10. SHAKER MANIFESTO. Published by the United Societies. OUR HOME AT
                        SHIRLEY, MASS. "Blessed are they that hear the word of God and keep it." SHAKER VILLAGE, N. H.
                        1883. </p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p> [Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --><pb n="217" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><!--                   <div2 type="none">
                        <p> CONTENTS Henry Clough, No. 1. Read and Understand, Resignation, .... Firm Footing, Religious
                            Status or Mankind, The Shaker, The Resurrection, Letter—T. Harding, A Morning Thought, Page.
                            - 217 220 - 222 - 223 226 - 229 In the Spirit, Notes,...... Beyond Thb Sunrise, ... Shakers
                            as Farmers, The Social System, Life in the Woods, No, 6. Faithfulness in Temporal Duties,
                            Music—Hour of Worship, Books & Papers, - Page. - 231 232 - 233 235 237 238 239 240
                            Vol. XIII. OCTOBER, 1883. No 10. </p>
                    </div2>--><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Henry Cloguh, no. 1" TEIform="index"/> HENRY CLOUGH, No. 1. </head><p TEIform="p"> The subject of this sketch was born in Canterbury, N. H. Feb. 6, 1751. His parents, in
                            regard to wealth and character, occupied a place among the first families. As religionists
                            they accepted the faith of the sect called Armenians. Jeremiah Clough, the father, owned a
                            large farm in the west part of the town, which was kept under good cultivation. He also
                            officiated for several years as Justice of the Peace. The means of acquiring an education in
                            those primitive days were very limited, compared with the facilities that hold out their
                            invitations at the present time, and into which the poor as well as the rich are freely
                            admitted. Henry was privileged to attend the district school and to obtain the advantages
                            which this humble institution afforded. As a literary distinction was not the passion of his
                            life, he did not seek admission into the schools of a higher grade. In fact, scholastic
                            attainments in those days, were not the insignia of manly dignity, but he was a man who had
                            muscle, and will, and judgment, and' morality, and religion. He was a man who earned his
                            bread by the sweat of his brow, and amassed wealth by honest toil, rather than to take from
                            others by fraud and deception. Instead of becoming a mere parasite of society, Henry
                            followed the wise example of his father, and became a tiller of the soil, and became also an
                            industrious, frugal, honest, moral, commonsensed, plain hearted, yeoman,—one of a class that
                            could meet difficulties and overcome them, and face danger with the firmness of the granite
                            hills, upon which he was reared. <pb n="218" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 218 THE MANIFESTO. Henry cared but
                            little for an outward appearance. He opposed all decorations of person with jewelry, and
                            consequently paid no titles to the high priest of fashion ; but was contented with the
                            needful things of life, which contributed to make the earthly pilgrimage pleasant and
                            cheerful. Modesty and virtue were his guides, in all his arrangements, whether it pertained
                            to his person or possessions. He was very punctual in all his duties, and the principle to
                            do right, because it was right, was his rule of action. In this he obeyed the counsel of his
                            parents, and inherited a blessing which enabled him through life to be reflective and to
                            judge with a righteous judgment. In personal appearance Henry was of medium height, and well
                            proportioned. His complexion was light, hair auburn, and his eyes hazel. His countenance was
                            grave, and his mind disciplined to meditation and penetration. He was at times, quite
                            serious, and yet in conversation, peculiarly agreeable. He was very fond of children and
                            delighted to notice them, and would often speak to them about being virtuous and kind and
                            encourage tiiem to be honest and truthful. He was open and frank in the expression of his
                            sentiments, with a marked honesty in his dealings with others. To those in need, he was very
                            hospitable, bearing in mind, that, "He that giveth to the poor shall not lack, but he that
                            hideth his eyes, shall have many a curse." In this way he prospered in the things of this
                            life. In his religious sentiments he was a Congregationalist, and in all propriety might be
                            called a just man. His moral faculties predominated, and when awakened to a duty or ,
                            religious obligation, he devoted his whole soul to the work. As a first and enduring
                            inheritance he sought the Kingdom of God and its righteousness and accepted the
                            manifestations of truth as revealed to him with fervency of spirit. He carefully examined
                            into the merits of all that professed to flow from the fountain of wisdom and knowledge, and
                            when he had ascertained that greater blessings of immortality and eternal life were the
                            result, he "conferred not with flesh and blood," but boldly entered the field with all the
                            ardor of a faithful and devoted soldier. In the year 1778 a religious awakening took place
                            in Canterbury and the adjoining towns, from which arose the sect called Free Will Baptists.
                            The peculiar tenets of this denomination were, that by the death of Jesus, salvation was
                            provided for all men,—that through faith in Christ and sanctification of the spirit, though
                            by, nature entirely sinners all men may become new creatures in this life, and after death
                            enjoy eternal happiness. They consider that Elders and Deacons are the officers of the
                            church, designed in the scriptures, and to maintain that piety and a call to the work, are
                            the essential qualifications of a Minister, without regard to literary attainments. They
                            agree in most other respects with the trinitarian Christians. This spiritual movement was
                            similar to the preparatory work which preceded the opening of the gospel in New Lebanon, N.
                            Y. and the adjacent towns ; the particular features being the numerous prophecies of the
                            near approach of Christ's second advent,—powerful testimonies against all sin, and the
                            fallen state of religious professors. Such a <pb n="219" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 219
                            preparatory work had preceded the Gospel in every place where Societies of Believers are
                            located. Henry took an active part in this revival and became a powerful preacher and a
                            zealous worker. He was now accepted as a prominent guide among the people, and from the
                            conscientious duty which he owed to God and to his own soul, he pressed forward in the
                            increasing manifestations of goodness and truth which had broken upon his vision. In this
                            advanced work, he continued steadfast until the gospel testimony was opened ; a testimony
                            which strikes at the root of all selfishness, and which is like a refiner's fire and like
                            fuller's soap, to cleanse the soul from the dross of sensuality and bring it into life by
                            the resurrection power of God. Henry was one of the first who received the faith of the
                            Gospel, in Canterbury, and having proved himself an honest, candid, upright man in the
                            natural order, he did not flinch at the crossbearing testimony of the Gospel, but passed the
                            fiery ordeal and was baptized into the awakening spirit which conquers all evil andieigns
                            triumphant over death. He was now 28 years of age, and had made all due arrangements for
                            entering into the marriage relation ; but finding that the gospel of Jesus Christ did not
                            admit of the relation of husband and wife, nor of the accumulation of selfish property, he
                            made a full sacrifice of body, soul and spirit, to obtain the Kingdom of Heaven, and was
                            very zealous in promoting the cause both as a preacher and as a practical worker. "I did not
                            set out to obey the Gos-' pel," said he, "because I felt pressed with the conviction of sin,
                            nor because I was afraid of being lost, but the requirements of the work appeared so
                            reasonable, that I obeyed them from choice, to do that which was evidently right. I was
                            drawn into it, and kept in it by my love for that which is right and good." At this date
                            Henry was the owner of some 400 acres of land. The farm was under good cultivation. The
                            buildings attached to the place were commodious and in excellent repair. In accordance with
                            his character as a man, he practically exemplified his faith by accepting some thirty or
                            more persons into his dwelling, where by his benevolence and hospitality *they enjoyed a
                            home, with the privilege of working on the place, and in this way, earned their living. For
                            all the improvement which they made, he liberally compensated them. Henry was an example of
                            prudence and frugality and very industrious with his hands when not directly engaged in
                            spiritual labors. In this last calling, however, he was an efficient worker and as a
                            minister, highly esteemed by the people. Frequently when visiting the departments of the
                            Brethren and seeing them busily employed, he would say, "Happy are they that have
                            employment." He knew that the idle would be tempted to wrong, and that suitable employment
                            was for the health and comfort of both body and mind. Father James Whittaker informed Henry
                            that it was the gift for him to give his attention more directly to the spiritual interests
                            and to devote himself to be a minister of the gospel, and from this date he was chosen to be
                            one of the traveling Ministry. It was a great cross for him to leave the management of the
                            farm, in which he had taken so much <pb n="220" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 220 THE MANIFESTO. satisfaction,
                            and his first impression was, "I cannot do it." Father James then informed Henry that there
                            were but two ways. "One way is for you to delve with your hands as you have done and lose
                            your union with the body of Believers, and the other is to leave your farm and all its
                            enjoyable surroundings and become a preacher of the Gospel and be saved." Henry accepted the
                            gift; gave his life to the work and was blessed of God' in his ministerial labors. From this
                            time he devoted himself to the preaching of the word wherever he was called. His zeal and
                            exemplary devotion were very influential among those who had accepted the testimony of a
                            united inheritance. Henry was not considered eloquent, in the common acceptation of the
                            term, but he abounded with that spiritual pathos which seldom failed to meet the state of
                            his hearers. He would quite frequently remark, "Innocence is our best defence." The divine
                            spirit which he was blessed to receive, in connection with his own unwavering integrity as a
                            natural man, made him a very powerful preacher. In his testimony against that which was
                            wrong he spoke without fear, favor or affection. He was inflexible in maintaining a
                            separation between Believers and the World, in all respects. In one of his public
                            testimonies while referring to those who neglected their sacred trust and slighted the call
                            of God, he said, "If you lose your birth-right through unbelief you can never have another
                            day. Other souls will be called in to take your place. They will come from the East, and
                            from the West, from the North and from the South, and sit down with. Abraham, Isaac and
                            Jacob, in the Kingdom of God, and the children of the Kingdom will be cast out. Reprobate
                            silver will men call them. They will wander in darkness and find no rest; for the heavens
                            over their heads will be as brass, and the earth under their feet as iron. Their judgment
                            will remain." His whole soul seemed to be filled with abhorrence to "the unfruitful works of
                            darkness," and this zeal for the cause continued throughout his whole life. (TO BE
                            CONTINUED.) </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Read and understand" TEIform="index"/> READ and UNDERSTAND. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/> ANTOINETTE DOOLITTLE. </byline><p TEIform="p"> As we trace the lines of the "pen of the ready writers" especially if they are intelligent
                            and liberal, we try to understand their language, to define the thoughts expressed, and if
                            worthy to claim our attention, to enter into rapport, in a limited degree—and see if we
                            cannot add to our cumulated knowledge already attained, something that will be useful and
                            make us wiser and better, whether it be in reference to material things pertaining to the
                            earth life, or the spiritual, bearing upon and pointing toward the life in the great beyond,
                            the boundless future. The revelation of true thoughts and ideas transmitted to
                            others,—"emptied from vessel to vessel," is beneficial to the giver and the receiver; it
                            prevents stagnation, and promotes growth and increase in knowledge, goodness and virtue. In
                            all that we do, and say, we should not only strive to enhance our own happiness, but lend
                            our best talents, and put forth our strongest energies as well, to benefit others ; thus
                            eschew selt- <pb n="221" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 221 ish aims and purposes, which in a
                            marked degree, is the bane of society. A proper digest of good substantial reading,
                            strengthens the intellect, and gives mental vigor ; while light trashy literature,
                            stimulates the passions, weakens the moral forces, instead of strengthening and elevating.
                            What we need, is the real; and if the appetites are not perverted, that is what we shall
                            desire and crave. Our delight will be to study the universality of God's Laws, as seen in
                            the great book of Nature ; to read and understand how fixed and unchangeable they are, and
                            with what precision they move from age to age. By the chart spread before us, which to the
                            external senses, is real and tangible, we can trace the source from which we derive
                            knowledge, even the secret springs of life. And that as we reason Godward, we are led to the
                            conclusion that the visible creation is an indicator of the invisible ; that there are
                            thrones of justice and judgment, and fountains of wisdom and knowledge established in
                            interior spheres from which we derive all true revelation, through mediatorial agencies,—and
                            receive power to act. He holds the balances in his hands and will de:,l justly. Measure by
                            measure, the Infinite makes known His will and purposes as mortals are prepared to receive.
                            "God is light," the great Central light of all worlds. Mortals in unprogressed conditions
                            could not bear the effulgent, piercing rays of light in great fullness to burst upon their
                            sight at once, it would create blindness. Hence scintillations are emitted; from which our
                            sight is strengthened, and we see more and more clearly the path of duty before us, as we
                            journey on ; in the highway of progression ; and we become more convinced, as the vision
                            expands, that the world which we now inhabit, and is so apparent to the outward senses, is
                            symbolical of other worlds, to us invisible. That if in this probationary state of existence
                            we take lessons and study them well, and grasp all the knowledge within our reach, we shall
                            find after all, that we are imperfect in knowledge and have only learned as it were the
                            first letters of the Alphabet. But the more true knowledge we gain of God as revealed in
                            natural laws, the more convinced we shall be that there is no inharmony between the Natural
                            and Spiritual, but are "parts of one great whole ;" the one well preserved, and kept
                            inviolate forms a basis for the other to rest upon. When children are young,—if well born
                            and morally trained, they look to their parents and teachers for instruction, and from them
                            take lessons, little by little as they can comprehend ; and that is the best method to
                            develop and strengthen the intellect, enlarge the understanding, and promote growth.
                            Reasoning from analogy, we judge that it may be the wisest for children ot larger growth to
                            learn to rightly read and understand the book of Nature, and the laws stamped upon her
                            pages, and learn through all the different ramifications of those laws, how to find and
                            commune with the Creative Source and center of those statutes. The more we learn, the
                            greater evidence we have that Infinite wisdom directs all, in the Natural and the Spiritual;
                            that the same good God who framed the one, established the other; and seeing the end from
                            the beginning, will perfect all in good time, if we co-operate with, work diligently, and
                            wait patiently. "Wisdom <pb n="222" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 222 THE MANIFESTO. is profitable to direct"
                            and will be justified, of, and is the justifier of her children. Among the lo heres and lo
                            theres in our own time when there are so many discordant voices and theories extant in our
                            land, we say, that they who find the true God, and the true altar of sacrifice, and make
                            their oblations there, and through spiritual faith place their offerings upon that altar,
                            are sure to find a steady, gradual growth, into the divine and heavenly. It is our privilege
                            to learn wisdom from the wise and unwise in every age and clime. Ancient Greek, Roman and
                            Egyptian philosophers, were more or less imbued with wisdom and held many truths which are
                            true today. They also imbibed errors ; and their mixed truth and error need fanning and
                            sifting, that the false may be removed and the true retained, the same as with modern
                            philosophers down to the present time. We have Simon Maguses in our own time who would
                            enchant and bewilder. Epicures who would, and do derive their chief happiness through
                            sensuous appetites and voluptuous living. In such we see little to admire, and much to
                            condemn. From those like Pythagoras who first was a follower of Epicurus—sought pleasure
                            through self-indulgence,—then through extreme abstinence, and finally found and chose the
                            middle line, we learn many useful lessons. Amidst it all, we need to listen to the still
                            small voice in our own conscious being and in deep soul communiugs find God, and feel the
                            holy inspiration that quickens into life. This must be attained by living faith in Him and
                            prayer which cannot find utterance in words ; but can only find expression by the deep gush
                            ings forth from the well-springs of the heart. This is the holy of holies ; in this we find
                            God, and rest in peace and love under the shadowing wings of the Cherubim. Mt. Lebanon, N.
                            Y. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Resignation" TEIform="index"/> RESIGNATION. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ervin, Anna" TEIform="persName"/> ANNA ERVIN. </byline><p TEIform="p"> Blest resignation, lend to me thy charms, That I unmoved may hear the worJd's alarms, May
                            learn to bear the ills I cannot mend, And suffer sooner than my God offend. When duty points
                            the course I ought to steer, And threatening clouds around my path apThy power I need to
                            bear nvy spirit up, [pear, And pour a cordial in ray bitter cup. Wisdom may point me to the
                            safer way; Danger may threaten if from it I stray; Hope may allure me in that course to run;
                            But resignation breathes, Thy will be done. Enfield, Conn. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Firm footing" TEIform="index"/> FIRM FOOTING.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/> MARY WHITCHER.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Without a power to cast me down I might on earthly soil recline, And wear alone an earthly
                            crown, With earthly friends alone for mine, God sees a higher for my good, And bears the
                            failing from my sight; Nor gives me any kind of food That perisheth as in a night. 0 God
                            above ! of light and truth, The Father and the friend of all, The guide alike to age and
                            youth, Who give their trust and heed thy call. This found by one connecting link, From soul
                            of mine to thy pure thought,. And felt through all we do and think, When into unison full
                            brought. Canterbury, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="When a friend corrects a fault in you..." TEIform="index"/>When a friend corrects a fault in you...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> When a friend corrects a fault in you, he does you the greatest act of friendship.— Golden
                            Rule. </p></div2><pb n="223" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religious state of humanity" TEIform="index"/> THE RELIGIOUS STATUS OF HUMANITY. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B" TEIform="persName"/> GILES B. AVERY.</byline><p TEIform="p"> In all human progress, except religion, men are reaching to the extreme limits of human
                            capacity, for the acme of perfection ; the farmer how to raise the greatest amount of the
                            best material food, with the least labor, on the smallest quantity of land. The
                            floriculturist the most abundant leaflets, and gorgeously glowing colors with the g:eatest
                            variety and beauty of development; the mechanic seeks the most simple device to accomplish
                            the greatest power with the least expenditure of force, and the most direct adaptability of
                            means to the ends desired. The philosopher searches for the foundation principles of forces,
                            and new sources of wealth and weal for humanity. The scientist searches for the laws which
                            govern the appropriate operations of organizing and disorganizing materials and directing
                            forces. But, in religion there is widely extant an organized effort to evade the force of
                            law and order ; to reverse the action of causes and consequences, and to affect faith in
                            abnormal productious. Arraigned at the bar of a civil tribunal there are probably few men to
                            be found, who, acting as jurors, would pronounce in favor of punishing the acknowledged
                            innocent and good, for the sins of the absolutely wicked and evil. But, in religious
                            professional belief men, in multitudes may be found who, while pretending to have faith in a
                            good, just, righteous, loving and merciful God, yet feign to believe that it is His Divine
                            will and purpose that His innocent Son Jesus Christ, should suffer physical death ; to
                            appease the wrath of God against the sinners who should acknowledge the gift and mission of
                            His Son. If reasonable and reasoning men, in their inward understandings believed in this
                            theological notion, in all sincerity, would they build state prisons, gallows, execution
                            blocks? Or would they organize and equip armies for battle to settle difficulties which
                            Jesus' merits would cancel? Would they institute courts of | justice, and enact laws for the
                            punishment of offenders for whom that Jesus' sufferings had already paid the penalty before
                            God ? In no wise ! All would depend on the atoning blood of Jesus for redress of wrongs !
                            But. be not deceived ! "God is not mocked," "Whatsoever a man soweth that shall he also
                            reap." Neither the physical blood of Jesus nor his righteousness, though in the imagij
                            nation of the worshipers at the shrine of human creeds, Jesus be exalted to the throne of
                            the Eternal, can ever make one sinner's robe white without that sinner's own confession,
                            repentance, and conformity to the life that Jesus lived. True religion's work is sot merely
                            to adopt a faith in some mysterious theological dogmas, to subscribe to some creed of human
                            formation ; it is to soften the obdurate heart; for revenge to institute pity, charity and
                            forgiveness, like our Heavenly Father and Mother, to bestow our love on those who love not
                            us ; to do good to all, even the evil, and unthankful ; to subdue the stubborn will, and
                            bend all its energies to the service of God; to cleanse and purify the heart and make it a
                            fit temple for the indwelling of the Holy Spirit, to bring harmony where discord reigns ; to
                            make the Earth an Eden, and Eden the Kingdom of Heaven; to institute "bounty for ashes ; the
                            oil of joy for the spirit of <pb n="224" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 224 THE MANIFESTO. heaviness" so that
                            the soul may sing, "I thank thee, Father, that I live, Though wailings fill this heart of
                            mine ; To labor for thy suffering ones, is joy Divine." But, in the popular theological way
                            of thinking and reasoning, termed religion, there is a very little free thought, it is
                            mostly creed bound ; and there is less free soul emotion that finds expression in practical
                            life experiences ; sectarianism trammels almost all; partisan policy cloaks error, varnishes
                            the sinner, and puts a lullaby on the conscience, and, because of the lack of faith in,,the
                            eternal and conscious existence of man, or, believing that death makes a saint of a sinner,
                            to the masses of mankind this world has more influence than the world to come. Multitudes
                            have yet to learn that moral and spiritual laws are as real and true to cause and effect as
                            the material. But, thinking to avoid superstition, millions are, at present, plunging into
                            the vortex of atheism ! This phase of human experience, future and near developments of life
                            will correct. The human state of progress is on the balance beam of the scales of
                            experience, and htr education will prove that truth will outweigh at last, and faith in a
                            God whose realm of law is righteousness, goodness, purity, and love, will at length be found
                            the safe school of ethics. Who would jump a precipice, ignoring the laws of gravitation
                            after witnessing a few people try it? So, jumping the precipice of sinful pleasure is
                            purchased at the expense of life itself! It was the vices of the Roman Empire that produced
                            its desolation. Thus the vices of the individual consummate ! And, sinful pleasures, so
                            called, are, at length, torturing pains, and should ever thus be pronounced. But, virtuous
                            life is the source of durable pleasures. The age we live in is an epoch of social and
                            religious transition. Change, and a desire for change, permeates society from circumference
                            to centre ; this is of two kinds, one reaching heavenward,— seeking the development of
                            spiritual life, the other, earthward tending to make of man a mere worm. Religious reasons
                            for being and doing good are called "old and time worn" and, with multitudes they are being
                            derided and rejected. This change is ominous of ruin ; for, when faith in virtue, and
                            confidence in God, and His laws of truth and Heaven are lost, what is there left for human
                            salvation ? All is blank and desolation ! "If the motives prompting to morals and religion
                            are lost, men will cease to be moral and religious." What have been these motives ? Fear of
                            Hell and love of Heaven ! Now some fickle shallow mind, or lover of sin tells us that one
                            "Ingersoll" "has knocked the bottom out of hell, and there is, therefore, no more sorrow for
                            sin." If so, then he has, at the same time, taken top, bottom and sides away from Heaven,
                            and left it to be blown away by the winds of sinful passions, like the chaff of the summer
                            threshing floor. But these sophists will yet learn that both hell and heaven, are, to each
                            soul, the production of that soul's own life deeds, consequently beyond the pale and
                            dominion of Ingersoll's wand of power. It is sorrowfully true that multitudes are now
                            throwing off both morals and religion, and lacking a knowledge of their own standing in the
                            scale of virtue and worth in society, and remind one of a narrative of a Colporteur
                            traveling in Illinois who called on a matron in an <pb n="225" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 225
                            out of the way location inquiring if the family had any bible? "Of course we have" said she,
                            ''Why ! do you take us to be haathen because we live away out m this new country." Would she
                            please let the visitor see her bible? "Certainly" But, after searching a long time she
                            finally produced one cover, and a few scattered leaves, and said to the stranger, "Really I
                            did not know we were so near out." Even so the masses of these scoffers at morals and
                            religion know not they are so near out of a vii tuous character and good standing in
                            society. They lustily declaim against so called Christian priests and people, declare these
                            all to be on the brink of one common ruin, and prate as though their own role of life was
                            the desirable path of reform. That there is error, and even iniquity to be found in the
                            ranks of the priesthood, and the ranks of church-going professors of Christianity, is sadly
                            too true. But this is no reason why morals, true religion, and the proper functions of
                            either the priestly offices or lay church membership of genuine Christianity should be
                            abandoned, and infidelity and immoral and irreligious latitudinarianism should be
                            substituted there for. There is a sneer upon religion, the credulity of faith in God, in
                            prayer, in spirituality, in soul existence, soul life and food, as though these were only
                            the ephemeral creations of imbecile minds, and, by these, only to be thought of while their
                            votaries were sailing on the crest of inspiration's wave of enthusiasm ! But, an every day
                            travel on the even highway of practical Christian life will convince the intelligent portion
                            of humanity that more and better brain is used by the consecrated moral and religious
                            devotee, who sincerely and truly lives to his best light, than was ever even dreamed of in
                            the infidel sophistry. This savors of Paganism which presents only inherent weakness, and a
                            cheerless prospect, not recognizing, or, at most, doubtfully admitting a future life ;
                            limiting the hopes and destinies of man to this world ; teaching that temporal prosperity
                            may be safely gained at any cost; and looking to suicide as the relief of the brave from
                            misfortune ! But, thank God for His revelations. There are those who can in truth declare
                            that the baptismal Christ (not Jesus,) has now come the second time, to some souls. What
                            for? To make an utter end of sin and bring in everlasting righteousness, to unwind the error
                            tangled skein of human conditions, and form, on earth, a heavenly pattern of society. To
                            cast in the sickle of truth "and reap the clusters of the vine of the earth"—gather the
                            natural families of this world, and garner them into the one family 01 Christ; to make the
                            sin-sick, world worn and weary, his guests. The Kingdoms of this world, and the kingdoms of
                            mere pseudo Christianity grow by natural generation and the spoils of unjust gains ; but
                            Christ's true kingdom grows by regeneration, virgin purity, the harvest of the world,
                            consecrated services and treasures to the redemption of humanity from sin and selfishness.
                            In Christ's kingdom the interests of every true heir is merged into and swallowed up of the
                            interests of the Kingdom, temporally and spiritually. But all persons who feed, at the
                            tables of Christ's kingdom temporally and spiritually, but still hold their own selfish
                            gains and earthly unconsecrated treasures are not true heirs of Christ's kingdom as sons and
                            daughters of the household of faith ; <pb n="226" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 226 THE MANIFESTO. they are
                            simply sojouniers.—boarders at its Inn. Selfishness is the bane of human society ; it
                            induces the murderer to slay his victim, either for earthly pelf, sensual pleasure, or the
                            love of revenge. Applied to nations as to individuals as witnessed in ancient Rome, it never
                            allowed man to be considered as a living, thinking, rational being, but simply as a thing !
                            Rome's course to greatness was pursued utterly regardless of human suffering ; she had no
                            conception of the equal rights of men. But, universal Christian equality, means universal
                            benevolence, and the upbuilding of that Kingdom seen in vision by the Prophet Daniel, which,
                            '"in the days of these kings the God of Heaven should set up that kingdom which should never
                            have an end I" Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker" TEIform="index"/>THE SHAKER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Knowles, Betsey" TEIform="persName"/> BETSEY KNOWLES</byline><p TEIform="p"> The traveler is occasionally surprised by a sight, new and striking, but, seldom one which
                            attracts his attention by its quietness, so much as does a Shaker Village. The simple forms
                            of architecture, the simple dress of the citizens and the air of quiet which pervade the
                            whole, strike us as something peculiar in this day of elaborate adornment. It would seem
                            that all the world had gone crazy for ornament, from the Emperor on his throne, who expends
                            fifteen millions in a coronation pageant, to the hardworking day laborer who exhausts his
                            earnings in trappings for the body. But to the contrast; on the busy street or in the
                            crowded car you meet the Shaker; perhaps old and wrinkled, his life may have been spent in
                            the outer world save a few declining years, or perhaps, a young man whose modest
                            self-possession speaks of the restraining love and care of Shaker discipline. The man by his
                            side is hastening on to his business, intent on procuring the means of sustenance for
                            himself and family; another is feeding ambition in the exciting whirl of politics
                            ;—believing that his candidate, if successful, will restore the country to the justice and
                            righteousness of the days of Washington. Still another fellow-traveler is preaching the
                            gospel of Christ, and on his merits, imagines that himself and like believers will find
                            acceptance. All these characters and many more seem to have their object, and to he
                            following their ruling love. We can understand that they have something to call out their
                            energies and make them participants and actors in this world's drama. The Shaker can take no
                            part in the political movements for Christ's gospel teaches him that his followers are not
                            of the world even as he was not of the world. While it does not allow him to fight, but to
                            "overcome evil with good," it says to him, "If ye forgive not men their trespasses neither
                            will your Father in heaven forgive your trespasses." "If the world hate you, ye know it
                            hated me before it hated you." No political scheme, not even the ballot-box, has called him
                            out from his quiet, contemplative home. Home, he calls it, but can that significant
                            designation be given to the Shaker's resting and abiding place? None of those ties which
                            impel his neighbor on to activity and toil are for him, and home, that sacred and charmed
                            spot, can be to him scarce more than a name. Like his Teacher whom he professes to follow so
                            closely, his "Mother and brethren are those who do the will of his Father in heaven." Like
                            him. he supports none of the natural or selfish relationships of the earth. He has no wife,
                            no natural descendants. "Who can tell his generation, for his life was taken from the
                            earth." The impulses and passions of his nature are held in check and overcome by the
                            mandate of his Teacher. "Whoso taketh not up his cross and followeth me is not worthy of
                            me," (or cannot be my disciple.) And although others around him, professing to be disciples,
                            live in the full indulgence of this nature, which they believe the Savior crucified, still,
                            to him this is no abatement of the injunction to take up the cross and follow Christ. A
                            follower, according to Webster is <pb n="227" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 227 one who comes
                            after another in the same course. As nothing tends more to mark out the order of one's life
                            than marriage with all the relationships consequent upon it, the Shaker considers this
                            special feature of the virgin life of Christ as most worthy of his imitation ; and as
                            nothing can be more crossing to the affections of nature, he considers this self-denial
                            emphatically the cross of which Jesus so often made mention. Tempted in all points like as
                            we are, his tender, sympathetic, nature yielded to the dictation of the God within. On this
                            point without conflict, stern and heart rending as his temptation of forty days and nights
                            in the wilderness is proof, "Yet without sin." The God triumphed over the man, the spiritual
                            over the natural, the mind and soul over the humanity and the pattern was set while Angels
                            came and ministered to him. What was the need of such a pattern? Adam and Eve had set one
                            years before, which had been faithfully copied. "Created in the image of God" they had
                            fallen from a high, natural, plane, by listening to natural enticements. Instead of
                            fulfilling the intention and perfecting the nature, created a little lower than the Angels,
                            this plane was reversed and sensuality filled the land. When, therefore, the time was come
                            for a more spiritual dispensation than the law or the prophets announced, they were still
                            unprepared. They imagined that the Messiah was coming to set up a temporal kingdom, to
                            overcome all opposition, and feeling the force of his spirit they -were ready to crown him
                            their King. But when they discovered that this was not his mission ;—when they heard his
                            rebuke for their hypocrisies and slowness of heart to believe ; in short when he offered
                            them the unacceptable life of the cross, they turne.l from it in disgust, and were ready to
                            accuse him of being an enemy to the country. They had already accused him of being a
                            disturber of the peace, for when the words "follow me," were pronounced, no ties of business
                            or relationship were sufficient to release them from the obligation of the call to forsake
                            all. "I am come" said he, "to set a man at variance against his Father and the daughter
                            against the Mother and the Mother-in-law against the daughter-in-law, and a man's foes shall
                            be they of his own household." "He that loveth Father or Mother more than me is not worthy
                            of me, and he that loveth Son or daughter more than me is not worthy of me ; and he that
                            taketh not up his cross and followeth after me is not worthy of me." The Shaker is,
                            emphatically, a subject of the higher law. When the lower or earthly come in collision with
                            the gospel law, the former must yield, as he considers himself not only a subject of the
                            gospel and of a new dispensation but as in the resurrection. Obedience to law is to him a
                            matter of duty and conscience, as a peaceable, rderly loving, citizen. Of the resurrection
                            of the body he has no comprehension, but to him the term resurrection implies a rising or
                            elevation from natural, ear hly and carnal, into spiritual, heavenly and refined states; a
                            work of the spirit which not only induces purity of thought and action but calls for a pure
                            receptacle. "Know ye not ye are the temples of God and the spirit of God dwelleth in you? If
                            any man defile the temple of God him will God destroy; for the temple of God is holy which
                            temple ye are." Purity of heart, is the talismanic charm to undo the gates of bliss.
                            "Blessed are the pure in heart for they shall see God," finds fulfillment with him for he
                            sees the manifestation of God m his people and feels a certainty of happiness such as none
                            others have. It is not with him "a hope" or "a trembling hope," he says, "my passport is
                            sure." He has the "white robe" and is confident that he shall stand with the Lamb on Mount
                            Zion. His confidence no man can shake. The children of this world marry and are given in
                            marriage, but those who are accounted worthy to attain to that world, neither marry nor are
                            given in marriage, and he considers himself no more of this world than was his Teacher. He
                            supports none of the private, or sensual relations with which the world is filled. By so
                            doing he lays the axe at the root of the tree, and in destroying that, feels that the limbs
                            or minor evils will die also. "Whence come wars and fightings? come they not of your lusts
                            which war in your members?" Subdue these lusts and the wars cease, <pb n="226" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/>&gt; 228 THE MANIFESTO. But while the Shaker is as rigid in his selfdenial as the
                            monk, while he craves none of the Corinthian indulgences for a sensual nature, he holds a
                            pure and elevated relation, ship with woman. The participation of woman in matters of
                            government both spiritual and temporal is a matter long since settled by the Shaker as the
                            prerogative of woman as helpmeet for man"The man is not without the woman nor the woman
                            without the man in the Lord." They were both necessary to constitute the image of God, and
                            therefore, he feels that in excluding woman from an equal participation, mankind not only
                            wrong her, but deprive themselves of the more immediate love and wisdom manifestation. "With
                            the Shaker, therefore, woman is neither an object of idolatry nor chivalrous devotion, nor
                            yet of sensual, selfish, love. She is the companion, the assistant, the Mary, or the Dorcas,
                            full of charity and good works in the household of faith. While the journals of the day teem
                            with accounts of cruelties inflicted by children of this world, the Shaker Sister in the
                            security of her peaceful home, blesses God for its quiet from the lawless, ungoverned
                            passions which rend and agonize so many in the world, who still continue to walk in the
                            broad way. Many of them know, by experience, that no relationship can be so near as those
                            that grow out of marriage, still none can be so agonizing in their misdirected or ill
                            assorted realizations; nothing so transforms the image of God into a brute and debases all
                            holy and generous impulses in man, as to give unbridled reins to sensuality. So far from
                            envying those who are living in that state where "they twain become one flesh," she blesses
                            God for a call into a work which teaches meekness, peacefulness, and righteousness. The
                            married woman careth for the things of the world, but unmarried for the things of the Lord.
                            She lives and believes in the angelic life. The loves of her aature are not cramped as many
                            suppose, but become widened and diffused, to embrace in the bonds of love all the household
                            of faith. In the depths of her soul, she breathes the prayer for more of that self-denying
                            love; that all-embracing love which animated her Lord. Dediicated to God, her life is not
                            only angelic in its purity and entire abnegation of self, but filled with use ; for industry
                            with her is morality and religion, indispensable for spirituality. When, therefore, the
                            early morn finds her in duty, cheerfully performing her allotted labor, not for herself
                            alone, who can say that her life is not heroic? The ancient mother who counseled her son to
                            return to her on his bier rather than his country be dishonored, is not her superior in the
                            heroic or the brave. Her life is continual sacrifice, a sacrifice not to the country,
                            however noble that may seem, not to any earthly mandate, but a cheerful, continual and
                            hearty response to the voice of illuminated conscience. She has no time to spend in idle
                            gossip as her religion teaches that if she has aught to say of another, it should be in her
                            praise of virtue and not of demerit. She can be no exclusive or aristocrat for her gospel
                            reads that they all may be one and thus the mountains of exaltation sink and valleys rise in
                            the Shaker life. She can covet nothing better for herself that is not consistent with her
                            love for others. Her deeds of benevolence and self-denial may never secure for her a
                            nation's gratitude or the approval of earthly rulers as her name may never be heard beyond
                            the precincts of her home, of consecration. The serene and quiet consciousness of right
                            abides with her, and the approval of him who was poorer than herself, in as much as "he had
                            not where to lay his head." She feels in harmony with prophets, saints and martyrs. They see
                            her mission sustain and bless her in it. Her life is comprehended and governed by the Mother
                            spirit above, and believing with her whole soul that the great problem of the elevation of
                            the race must be solved in this way, she stands among the first fruits of the new
                            dispensation. The ultimatum would reconcile her to crosses, trials and afflictions, but
                            present peace is more than sufficient to counter-balance all the trials. With her "The
                            Angels of the Lord eneampeth round about them that love Him." She feels that the calm and
                            quiet of that "city whose walls are salvation <pb n="229" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 229 and
                            whose gates are praise," are something to be enjoyed prized and loved. Harvard, Mass. </p></div2><div2 type="xxx" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Resurrection" TEIform="index"/> THE RESURRECTION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Woods, Joseph" TEIform="persName"/> JOSEPH WOODS.</byline><p TEIform="p"> The prophet Isaiah said of Jesus, His reward is with Him and his work is before Him ; and
                            speaking of himself, Jesus said, "My reward is with me to give to every one, according as
                            their works shall be." "I am the Resurrection and the Life." and those who believed on Him,
                            though they were dead, in trespasses and sins, yet they should live, and those who were
                            alive and believed on Him,— with a living faith—should never die. That the doers of good
                            works should come forth into the resurrection and life of Christ, consequently all we have
                            to do, is to obey his instruction, to deny ourselves, every moment, of all ungodliness, and
                            every worldly lust, that is presented, and to take up the cross as did Jesus and follow Him
                            in the regeneration. By this we put on the Lord, Jesus Christ, which is the resurrection
                            that Jesus declared Himself to be; and blessed, thrice blessed are those who have part in
                            this first resurrection, for their reward is with them continually, and their duty for each
                            day is before them. Canterbury, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My Dear Friend and Brother; In compliance with your repeated..." TEIform="index"/>
                            My Dear Friend and Brother; In compliance with your repeated...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Michigan, Sturgis, July 18, 1883" TEIform="index"/>Sturgis Mich., July 18, 1883
                        </dateline><p TEIform="p">Elder Mabee—My Dear Friend and Brother; In compliance with
                            your repeated invitation to express an opinion on your "peculiar institution" I shall say,
                            that I cannot but respect all who, from conscientious motives, devote their lives to what
                            they esteem the practice of virtue and self-denial. When one is weary of the world's strife
                            and vain-glory and desires to retire from its worries and disappointments, I do not think
                            there is, or perhaps can be, a better institution, to unite with, than a judiciously
                            conducted "Shaker Community," but never theless, as I am not a member of a "Mutual
                            Admiration Society" but in the habit of expressing my opinions unrestrained by a desire to
                            please, and seek the elucidation of truth in preference to imparting self complacency. I
                            trust you will excuse me if I write candidly; but do not, I request, suppose for a moment,
                            that I do not entertain for you and yours the highest respect and esteem. 1st. I cannot see
                            why your order should claim that you are leading a "purer" life than those who marry. To me
                            every natural act is pure and all the members of our bodies equally honorable. I presume you
                            do not object to the pleasures of the table, the pleasures of sleep, of contemplation, of
                            hope, of memory, of friendship then why object to the pleasures of matrimony? "To enjoy is
                            to obey" in my opinion. Society, for its own well being, has in this matter established
                            certain regulations, this is right! but had society emasculated, so to speak, any of its
                            members, by depriving them of any of their natural rights or privileges it would not be
                            right. Again, I do not think that a secluded life is necessarily a "holy" life. To me it
                            would seem more "holy" to enter boldly and actively into the battle against selfishness and
                            wrong. My dear brother I would rather be an "Angel of Power" in the future than an "Angel of
                            Innocence," I think they stand higher in the "Great Beyond" and I can gain increased power,
                            only, by the exercise of that degree of strength which I possess. I hope you will excuse :ne
                            for speaking plainly, I am in the habit of doing so, and that you will ever regard me as
                            your sincere friend, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Harding, Thomas" TEIform="persName"/>Thomas Harding</byline></div2><div2 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p"> Remarks.—The above open and candid communication was forwarded to us for perusal, and we
                            accept the liberty of placing it in the columns of the Manifesto. </p></div2><pb n="230" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We are aware that the subject..." TEIform="index"/>We are aware that the subject...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> We are aware that the subjects which particularly concern our religious and communistic life
                            are not so fully comprehended as they should be by persons not of our order and this is not
                            at all strange. Indeed it would be thought ,hardly possible for those absorbed in interests
                            so opposite to understand fully the reason for maintaining such a religious system. We
                            denominate ourselves Christians ; Believers in the spirit and testimony of Jesus Christ. He
                            always placed the children of this world and the children of his kingdom in antagonism. One
                            were the children of the flesh, the others children of the spirit, one holding and
                            sustaining all the relations of the Adamic order, the others at variance with that relation
                            which has its foundation in the sins of concupicence. The Shaker order, is .strictly a
                            religious order, and it might not, as a general thing, prove a congenial home to those who
                            simply wish to retire from the worries and disappointments of the world. There would be
                            quite a difference between entering the Society on this basis and entering it as is our
                            custom to teach: "To come.out from the world and be separate." To make an honest confession
                            of all sin, to God, Irefore an appointed witness. To consecrate all our time and talents to
                            the temporal and spiritual interests of the family in which we reside. If we accept this
                            testimony of Christ, we shall become crucified to the world, subjects of the spiritual
                            resurrection, and messengers, or if preferable, angels of God. Dunlavy writes,—-"We will
                            introduce a passage of scripture which draws the line of distinction and shows to what class
                            marriage belongs.- "The children of this world marry and are given in marriage : but they
                            which shall be accounted worthy to obtain that world, and the resurrection from the dead,
                            neither marry nor are given in marriage. Neither can they die any more; for they are equal
                            unto the angels, and are the children of God, being the children of the resurrection." Luke,
                            xx., 34, 36. Now the children of this world are not the children of God, nor followers of
                            Christ, as he said, "They are not of the world, even as I am not of the world." Those,
                            therefore, who marry and are given in marriage, are not the children of God, nor followers
                            of Christ. It is not to be denied, that all the true followers of Christ are, and shall be
                            accounted worthy to obtain that world and the resurrection from the dead. But those
                            accounted worthy, neither marry nor are given in marriage; therefore, noue of the true
                            followers of Christ marrv or are given in marriage." We do not think that a secluded life is
                            necessarily a "holy" life. Indeed, we think that the Christian must lead an active,
                            aggressive warfare against the undisciplined elements of the world and one of the strongest
                            powers with which to contend, is the selfishness of the human heart. Those who entertain the
                            idea that a communistic life is a secluded life, after the manner of the monks, nuns or
                            ascetics generally, must be very imperfectly informed. The general outline of our order of
                            life runs very closely by the side of that which governs most families. We are engaged at
                            home or abroad, in secular or religious duties as the occasion may demand, and regret that
                            we are net able to do more for the advancement of mankind in all that serves to make men
                            better in this <pb n="231" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> world, and better able to establish the principles of
                            righteousness in the heart which shall give a more glorious hope oi immortal life. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>Henry C. Blinn. </byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Morning thought" TEIform="index"/> A MORNING THOUGHT.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Williams, Flora" TEIform="persName"/> FLORA WILLIAMS. </byline><p TEIform="p"> Many Authors have found the morning the best time for study and composition ; hence, it has
                            been called the '-frierd of the muses." It would be easy to prove that it is equally a
                            friend to the graces and to the duties ; it is the finest season for reflection and
                            devotion. How much there is in the morning to call forth the voice of thanksgiving, as we
                            awake from our slumbers invigorated and refreshed, secure from accident by fire and from
                            other calamities. And with how many of theso merciful nights have we been favored! How
                            strange that what increases the greatness of our obligation should diminish its realization
                            ! For by the interruption, the suspension, or the want of comforts we are taught to value
                            them. Let us guard against this ingratitude, and remember that though our mercies are
                            common, they are greai and numerous, and thus increase the claim to our prayer and praise.
                            And shall our gratitude like volatile vapors pass away in a mere morning acknowledgment?
                            Shall we not, according to the mei'cies of God, dedicate ourselves to his service in the
                            morning, at noontide, and at evening and seek the gentle dews of refreshing through the
                            inspiration of prayer? We should be influenced and encouraged by the command and promise,
                            "Trust in the Lord with all thine heart and lean not on thine own understanding. In all thy
                            ways acknowledge Him and He shall direct thy paths." Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In the spirit" TEIform="index"/> IN THE SPIRIT. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Danforth, Nancy G." TEIform="persName"/> NANCY G. DANFORTH.</byline><p TEIform="p"> John was ''in the spirit" on the Lord's day: Why? In the first place, he had given his miud
                            to medication and prayer. He had thereby drawn around himself the ministration of Angels—the
                            holy influences of the heavens. Then again, his mission was peculiarly one of love. He
                            breathed love and good will to all, not only to the faithful and upright, but also to the
                            erring whom he followed with tears and entreaties, that they might return to their
                            allegiance to duty. In the same manner are the followers of Christ, in this age, called to
                            be in the spirit on the Lord's day. As the testimony of full and final salvation from all
                            sin is now freely proclaimed, it becomes our duty to esteem every day as belonging to the
                            Lord. Therefore, if all time is the Lord's, it necessarily follows, that we have none in
                            which to look after selfish ease and indulgence ; but we should each hour, be seeking
                            greater consecrations, and striving more earnestly to do all the righteous will of God. In
                            this strife we can live, and be filled with the spirit at all times, and receive the
                            manifestations of divine love and guidance through all the burdens and cares of life ;
                            although in the world, yet living above its influences, "redeeming the time knowing the days
                            are evil." Canterbury, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Never too old to improve..." TEIform="index"/>Never too old to improve...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Never too old to improve while intellect remains unbroken. </p></div2><pb n="232" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes" TEIform="index"/>NOTES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><index level1="[Editor]" TEIform="index"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> If all should become Shakers, what then ? If—and that diminutive word admits of a world of
                            doubt. It is surprising upon how small a pivot some of the greatest works in this world will
                            turn. It may not be for us to determine the interest that should be manifested in the
                            religious orders, but we may with all propriety be workers for good in the cause of
                            humanity. Other questions might be raised with equal propriety, as the above, and yet they
                            would vanish like the morning mist. No one would give them a second thought. If all persons
                            should insist upon following one occupation, what should we do? and we might add. If the
                            whole world wanted to live on the Sandwich Islands, what would they do? and these questions
                            are about as momentous as the first. Mankind, as a whole, care but very little what becomes
                            of the world if it can be made to subserve their selfish end. God's laws are as carelessly
                            thrown aside as a penny whistle, when they come to enforce a disciplinary order of life, and
                            the sins of indulgence of one generation are wickedly thrown upon another generation. When
                            Jesus made reference to the spirit of his gospel work, to the cross that must be borne, to
                            the separation from the world which his disciples must make, to the peaceable lives which
                            they must live and to the exceeding righteousness which was in harmony with his Kingdom, he
                            very considerately added this remark. "It is not given to all men to receive these sayings."
                            The voluntary crucifixion of one's own life was a work which demanded a deep spiritual
                            consecration. It was far more than the mere profession in which the Prophet says, "This
                            people draweth nigh unto me with their mouth, and honoreth me with their lips ; but their
                            heart is far from me." Jesus so well understood this fact that he was able to speak of it
                            without reserve, and yet he most affectionately invites all who are weary of sin and heavy
                            laden with the cares of this world to become disciples of the gospel work. While the family
                            of man are privileged to dwell upon this earth, there will, without doubt, be a graduated
                            scale of mind. The earthly have, and in all probability will predominate. Generation after
                            generation moves along on the same highway wholly satisfied with the present as was the
                            preacher,—because a man hath no better thing under the sun than to eat, and to drink and to
                            be merry. Below these are the sensual. Their baneful influence has its effect, and is too
                            well understood to need any illustration ; but there is a class whose lives we may emulate
                            with a good conscience. Those who hunger and thirst after righteousness,—those who are
                            peacemakers, and those who are pure in heart. Paul says that God will have all men to be
                            saved and to come to the knowledge of the truth. It is this word of truth and righteousness
                            that has awakened in the hearts of many an inspiration which glories in the cross of Christ.
                            The name by which this class may ba mown among the children of this world, is of the least
                            consequence. If they ac- <pb n="233" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 233 cept those principles
                            which Jesus taught, peace, purity and righteousness, it will carry them into that order that
                            neither marry nor are given in marriage, making them as he predicted, those upon whom the
                            end of this world has come.</p></div2><div2 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beyond the sunrise" TEIform="index"/>Beyond the Sunrise</head><p TEIform="p"> [Contributed by F. W. E.] BEYOND THE SUITEISE. This is really a new book. The authoress
                            tells unpopular truths in a fascinating style. To see it, is to read it. One can not afford
                            to lay it by without eating it. Its presentation of Ann Lee's mission is boldandfree.
                            Revelation ; Spiritualism ; Duality of Deity ; Probation in a future life;
                            Intercommunication of the dead and living; Two orders, composed of those who choose the
                            Family social relation, and those who choose the Kesui-rection Life on earth; The political
                            equality of woman, with an Order of male and female Celibates to fill all Civil Offices ;
                            are succinctly but pleasantly set forth, with many other topics intensely realistic and
                            interesting to be best learned from the book itself. Oil t It i:It* AS fARMXKI. Visit to the
                            Worth Family, at Mt. Lebanon.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers as farmers" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERS AS FARMERS</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A Visit to the North Family, at Mt. Lebanon On invitation of Elder F. W. Evans,
                                    of the North Family of Shakers, we visited that community recently, to note what was
                                    interesting from an agricultural point of view. So many times have the religious and
                                    social aspects of Shakerism been written upon, that anything we could say would be
                                    but a repetition of what has already been better said, hence we confined our notes
                                    strictly to what was either directly or indirectly connected with the farming
                                    interest. We met with a most cordial welcome from our genial friend, Elder Evans,
                                    the leading mind and chief head of the Shaker community in this country, or in fact
                                    of any country where Shakerism has been established. Busy as he always is, either
                                    with hand or brain, he yet found time to show us about the place, and call our
                                    attention to what would be of interest for us to relate. Directing our steps to the
                                    great stone barn, the Elder first called our attention to the three huge silos, that
                                    have just been completed. But first a word as to the barn itself. This was built
                                    several years ago, of stone, five stories in height, 196 feet in length, by 50 in
                                    width. Its cost was about $20,000. Below are the long lines of cattle stalls, and on
                                    either side on the floor above, bays run from the second to the third story upon
                                    which the loaded wagons are driven from the elevated ground in the rear. From this
                                    floor the hay, or other crops, can be pitched directly into the deep bays. On either
                                    side of the broad entrance door, are situated the silos above mentioned. The one on
                                    the right is 15 x 15 feet, and 37 feet high, and the two on the left are of the same
                                    height, but each is only 7 x 15 feet in the other dimensions, thus making two narrow
                                    silos, separated by a cement and stone wall. These two were built of Portland
                                    cement, used in about the proportion of one to five, cement and gravel, and cost
                                    about $300, the large one opposite being of Rosendale cement, and costing about
                                    $200. Openings about four feet by six are made on the first and second floors
                                    through which the ensilage will be taken out, when fed. The clover and corn which
                                    they propose to put in, will be cut by an ensilage cutter, and carried by elevator
                                    in at the top of the silo. On a scaffold between the silos, a strong platform is
                                    being made, upon which barrels of sand will be placed, which will be used as a
                                    weight when the silos are filled. "What is your opinion," we asked, "as to the value
                                    of ensilage as fodder?" "We should not judge as to the value of this fcdder from the
                                    mere fact that cattle eat it well. I look upon this as an abnormal appetite which
                                    cattle form, quite similar to that which a person forms for tobacco, for instance,
                                    and it does not follow that the value of the fodder is in porportion to the avidity
                                        <pb n="234" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 234 THE MANIFESTO. with which cows eat it. This musi; he
                                    judged by the condition of the stock in spring, after having been fed on it through
                                    the winter, by the quantity and quality of the milk, etc. Some claim that ensilage
                                    is a better fodder and more nutritious than was the original corn or clover, but we
                                    should be satisfied with' it if it is as good. A chemical change may take place, and
                                    the fodder be improved thereby, but just to what extent such change is desirable, is
                                    not quite apparent. When we have six months winter, and when we can keep three or
                                    four times the number of cattle that we could on pasture and hay alone, it is
                                    certainly worth trying. I consider it an excellent thing for stock, in spring; they
                                    will do well on it; but if it is fermented, it should be fed alternately with hay,
                                    or, if in summer, with pasture. But as to its value taken all together, there is
                                    little doubt." The Shakers take a pardonable pride in their fine cattle. The North
                                    Family now have about 100 head altogether, mostly a c ross between the Holsteins and
                                    native stock. Besides these they have several fine, pure-bred Holsteins, and also
                                    grade Durhams, Ayrshires and Jerseys. "You seem to prefer the Holsteins, and why?"
                                    we inquired. "Because they combine the good qualities of various breeds. Their milk
                                    is rich enough; they give a good quantity; they are docile; possess great vitality;
                                    make good beef, and the oxen are strong, sturdy workers. TYe were fortunate in
                                    having good stock to cross upon, and we now have as good a herd of cattle as one
                                    could wish for. We have 33 cows from which we manufacture about 130 pounds of butter
                                    per week, at present." The creamery where the butter is made is a model of neatness,
                                    and being in charge of an experienced dairy woman—one of the sisters—there is no
                                    wonder good butter can be made. "We believe," said our host, "that in order to make
                                    butter that shall be free from every taint, we must begin with the cowbarns. These
                                    are perfectly ventilated, so that even when doors and windows are closed in winter,
                                    there is sufficient ventilation to conduct away all offensive odors, which are so
                                    liable to taint the milk. Not onlv are our stables well cleaned, but they are
                                    perfectly ventilated." The milk is set in 20-inch cans in the creamery tanks, and
                                    the best appliances for churning and working the butter are used. One important
                                    consideration for every farmer has been met by the North Family, in providing an
                                    adequate supply of water for the stock. They have recently built a large reservoir
                                    on the hill above their buildings, and from this the water is conducted through iron
                                    pipes to the horse and cattle barns, the poultry-yard, and wherever pure running
                                    water is needed. Also, they provide motive power for running their barn machinery,
                                    their grain mill and laundry machinery, having a pressure of 65 pounds to the inch.
                                    Hydrants are built with which hose can be connected in case of fire, and each and
                                    every room in the dwellings can be flooded at short notice. Any poultry fancier
                                    -would be pleased to visit the spacious poultry yards, where now about 600 fowls are
                                    kept. "Poultry keeping pays," said Elder Frederic, and from the care given the
                                    poultry, and the accommodations they here have, we were not prepared to dispute the
                                    point. One brother has sole charge of the poultry-yard, and finds quite enough to
                                    do. Pure running water for the fowls is an essential to success, and this they have
                                    in abundance. Last winter eggs brought 35 cents a dozen, and we saw at once why
                                    there was money in the business. Speaking of each department of farming as having
                                    some one in charge of it the Elder said: ' Yes, that is advantageous. Each man does
                                    the work he likes best, hence it is well done." The kitchen garden was quite worth
                                    visiting. The brother in charge was hoeing the tomatoes, and was suddenly made aware
                                    of our presence by the Elder's saying, "Peter don't touch those tomato plants when
                                    they are wet; they will wither very quickly;" so Peter touched them not, and we in
                                    our ignorance learned something about tomato culture. In the garden everything in
                                    the vegetable line necessary for the large family of seventy is cultivated, and
                                    besides there was a fine display of blackberry bushes, quince trees—the largest we
                                    had ever seen—and almost everything to tickle the palate and please the taste. The
                                    Shakers being quite strict vegetarians, <pb n="235" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 235
                                    find here much that supplies their tables with daily food. But space will not permit
                                    us to go farther into detail. In conclusion we may remark that the Shakers raise the
                                    various cereals, grasses, potatoes, in fact all farm crops in large quantities,
                                    though much of their land is stony and mountainous. The benefits which accrue from
                                    their farming are shared in common, and they are, as Elder Evans remarked, "nothing
                                    hut a large family." Industry is practical not theoretical with them ; they have no
                                    room for idlers and all are busy. They use the latest and most improved machinery,
                                    and their farm lands give evidence that progressive farming is thoroughly believed
                                    in, and advanced farm methods are practiced. Could our farms in general be tilled
                                    with the care they use and with like industry, the products therefrom would
                                    aggregate much more , and labor would be better remunerated. That we may not seem
                                    ungrateful, we wish to say that our entertainment at the dinner hour was most
                                    sumptuous, and was most heartily appreciated, and we are under many obligations to
                                    our host—Elder Evans, for favors extended.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Chatham courier" TEIform="index"/>Chatham Courier</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Present vile social system and its remedy" TEIform="index"/> THE PRESENT VILE SOCIAL SYSTEM
                            OF SOCIETY AND ITS REMEDY. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stevens, Robert" TEIform="persName"/> ROBERT STEVENS. </byline><p TEIform="p"> Dear Friends ;—In making the following desultory remarks on this vitally important subject
                            (viz.) the present wretched social system, and its only adequate remedy, "Bible, Divine, or
                            what other name you may give," to constructive, not destructive communism, allow me to state
                            once for all, that I do not blame, or judge, or hold responsible any individual, or parties,
                            for the evils of the present social system. These evils are inherent in the system, itself
                            as absolutely necessary effects of certain false principles, upon which the system is
                            founded. We may lessen, or change these evils for a time as men and women of good hearts are
                            doing to-day, but who do not look deep enough for the cause, and therefore do not remove it,
                            so that our remedial measures are but palliatives, like the patching up of a dam, or
                            embankment that has been constructed on false principles. The water will ooze out in fresh
                            places, gather strength, and soon or late the whole erroneous construction will break up,
                            and over-whelm all in its terrible path. Again suppose the different classes of society,
                            labor and capital for instance the rich and the poor, the producers, and the nonproducers,
                            the monopolists, and the antimonopolists, change places when they are young, if they do so
                            we know that their thought and action, their general character, nationally speaking would be
                            reversed when they arrived at maturity. It is error therefore, erroneous systems that we are
                            at war with and not with men. Upwards of eighteen hundred years have gone, since the great
                            Paul, and the greater Christ inaugurated a new, a divine practical religion in which men
                            should be supremely lovers of God, and their neighbor as themselves. They also inaugurated a
                            new a divine, social system of society, a righteous, political, economy in order to make
                            that divine religion possible, for it would not have been wise to adopt the then, as now
                            rile social system. It would not have been wise to attempt to repair the old shoddy garment
                            with the new, the divine robe of righteousness. Therefore, soon after the terrible, the
                            lamentable death of the great, the self-sacrificing, the divine Master, for all goodness is
                            divine, the disciples came together with one accord, strong in spiritual life, over-flowing
                            with spiritual love, they were of one heart, and one mind, one with Christ, their beloved
                            Master, one with God their loving Father, and one in material things followed as an
                            absolutely necessary effect upon those previous causes. So full were they to over-flowing in
                            spiritual love, of unity in Christ, in God, that this their loftier, their higher state of
                            being outweighed every other consideration, and they sold their possessions, and brought the
                            prices and laid them down at the Apostle's feet, neither called any man anything his own,
                            that was his own, for they had all things in common ; and similar results will of natural
                            necessity follow to-day, whenever similar causes, similar means are realized. But these
                            noble men and women with the noble, thevv <pb n="236" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 236 THE MANIFESTO. brave
                            Paul at their head, were persecuted, were scattered and in seven years their wise social
                            organization was broken up, else there is little doubt it might have continued in the Church
                            till the present day, nevertheless the leaven was embedded in the heart, and in the mind of
                            humanity at that great Congress of spiritual love, and of wisdom, the day of Pentecost, and
                            the whole must be leavened, and if the Church continues to be unfaithful to its high mission
                            then rude hands—aye, terribly rude, will take it up and do it with vengeance. Day by day we
                            hear the ominous knocks of these rude hands at the very door of civilization: nay they are
                            already stained with its blood, and are but waiting like bloodhounds in the lash to go on
                            with the work. Allow me to repeat dear friends, it is for the professed Church of Christ, of
                            God, it is for the wise, and the good of the nations, those who alike freed God's colored
                            children from chattel slavery, and saved this great nation from wreck and ruin those who
                            to-day are redeeming the nations from the alcohol curse, and in a thousand ways persistently
                            working to lift up humanity to higher aims and realities, I say it is for these glorious men
                            and women to say whether the blood stained hands shall go on with this vital work of divine
                            constructive communism, (divine in itself as a higher truth,) or whether they will take it
                            from their fiendish grasp, supersede them, take the question from the turbulent sea of
                            politics altogether, and launch it into the peaceful, but not less buoyant, and progressive
                            stream of religio-social questions. Some of our friends say that communities fail, and so do
                            general business firms fail at the rate of a thousand a year. As to the practicability of
                            constructive communism, I need but point to the numerous communities of this country. The
                            Shakers' common property organization, and many others, in spite of what some conceive to
                            be, not errors of heart, but of brain, they have by their practical experiment in the case
                            of the Shakers of a hundred years duration completely solved the vital questions of the
                            present, senseless, social system. They have proved, demonstrated by actual experiment, that
                            with extremely few exceptions, all the vice, crime, poverty, disease, war; the awful amount
                            of general misery under which mankind suffer, is preventable. These communities for upwards
                            of a hundred years, have not had, or needed, prisons, police, war between capital and labor,
                            for they are all working capitalists. A man, or woman, or poor widow with a numerous family,
                            may join these communities, and that moment they become in law and in fraternal love equal
                            owners of all they possess, though they may not have brought in a dollar, and there are not
                            the drawbacks in them that is generally supposed. These practical demonstrations of the
                            possibilities of an infinitely higher social state, like all other truths, the more they are
                            examined the more positive they appear. It is either true, or false that the mental, and
                            physical labor of the world produce all the food, clothing, shelter and ^capital of the
                            world. It is either true, or false, that labor is the worst fed, the worst clothed, and the
                            worst sheltered. That it has the least chances of education and of culture, and that its
                            life is cut short by ten years of the average duration of life among other classes of
                            society. That more than one half of the children of the lower strata of society die before
                            they are five years of age. That labor is dependant for the necessaries of its life, and for
                            those of its wife and children upon the private capitalist as much now, or more, than under
                            a system of chattel slavery. If all this state of things be true and in the main, it is
                            self-evident, then is humanity cruelly outraged by fearful injustice, the very enormity of
                            which is a daily peril to civilization itself, and a positive menace that struggles for the
                            disruption of society will continue at whatever cost. Let therefore the goodness, and the
                            wisdom of the nations assert their strength (ere it be too late,) for love is more powerful
                            than dynamite, or the assasin's dagger, and it may make this vile, this senseless, selfish,
                            groveling system of society like chattel slavery, a thing of the past, so that
                            righteousness, and therefore happiness may dwell among the nations of the earth. Come forth
                            to community, Thou man of care, and toil, Leave competition's strife; In brotherhood, till
                            the soil, God would have thee holy, pure. With happiness to shine, Woi.ld strew thy path
                            with many a flower And dwell with thee, and thine. </p></div2><pb n="237" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life in the woods, no. 6" TEIform="index"/> LIFE IN THE WOODS, NO. 6. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sproat, Granville" TEIform="persName"/> GRANVILLE T. SPROAT.</byline><p TEIform="p"> We took our canoe, and crossed the Mississippi river. A party of Sioux warriors saw us from
                            a hill, and, with one accord, came rushing down to the river, armed with tomahawks. They
                            descried my O-jib-way. I placed Ma-gwah-gah-bo in the stern of the canoe, while I took the
                            prow, determined that they should pass over my dead body before reaching that of my guide.
                            "Where is your chief," I asked, with what little of the language I could command, as we
                            reached the shore, "Yonder, in his wigwam on the hill," they replied. "Send him tome," I
                            said. Presently I saw him coming down the hill, surrounded by his twelve body-guards. He
                            approached. "I have come," I said. "Take care of me, and take care of my guide!" pointing to
                            Ma-gwah-gah-bo. "I will!" he replied, at the same time ordering his body-guards to surround
                            us, and march with us up to his wigwam. Ma-gwah-gah-bo took his seat in the farther corner
                            of the wigwam. I was there seven days, vaccinating. During the seven days Ma-gwah-gah-bo
                            kept his seat in the corner of the wigwam, and never left it, for fear of these treacherous
                            Sioux. After my work was finished, I said to the chief, "My work is done. I will return
                            again to the O-jib-ways." "Very well," said he, "My warriors shall guard you to the river
                            and half way across,'' (they consider the middle of the river the dividing line between the
                            two countries,) "and I have commanded that not one of them shall follow you any farther,
                            *Os-kin-je-gon, you are safe!" So we bade adieu to the old chief, who made me a present of a
                            buffalo robe, curiously painted with the twelve great battle scenes of his life, and we
                            departed for the river to our canoes, the twelve body-guards accompanying us, also in
                            canoes, half way across the river. Then, both parties gave each other three cheers, and we
                            parted, one for the Sioux, the other for the O-jib-way shore. As we reached the shore, my
                            old guide *Silver Eyes. A name given to the writer on account of Ms wearing spectacles.
                            threw himself upon the ground. "There," said he, "I breathe once more! I have not breathed
                            before for seven days ! I was a pale face for seven days !" Big Buffalo, the O-jib-way
                            chief, came to visit me that night. He saw the buffalo robe, a present from the Sioux chief,
                            lying in one corner of the wigwam. He kept his eye upon it He knew it to be from the Sioux
                            counT try by its style of workmanship. He was in conversation, but suddenly stopped. "How
                            many strings of wampum must I give you for that buffalo robe?" he asked, earnestly. "That
                            buffalo robe was a present from the Sioux chief," I replied. "I cannot sell it." This I
                            said, for I knew that an O-jib-way cannot sell what is given him. It is contrary to the
                            Indian custom. He sat for a long time in silence. At last he spoke, with an earnestness
                            which amounted almost to furor. "How many beaver skins must I give you for that buffalo
                            robe?" I saw that the buffalo robe must go. "That buffalo robe was a present from the Sioux
                            chief," I replied, "I cannot sell it, but I can give it to you. Here it is, take it." He
                            called to a young man standing just outside the door. liJIou! Ish-ko-daT (Fire! Make a fire
                            !) The young man kindled a fire just before the door. Hou! Wa-be-non! wa-be-non!" (Throw it
                            on the fire !) said he. He threw it on the fire, and burned it up. It was not long after
                            this that I started in company with about one hundred and sixty O-jib-ways to visit Lake
                            Superior who were to receive payment from our government for the sale of their lands. We
                            were traveling in canoes, on the St. Croix river, which flows into the Upper Mississippi. We
                            were at least one hundred miles from the Sioux country, and did not suppose that there was
                            one of them within that distance. We drew up our canoes, at night, on the shores of the
                            river, to make our encampment, threw up our wigwams of birch bark, which we carried with us,
                            very hastily, (I had my own close by the river,) and laid down to rest. About four o'clock
                            in the morning, just as the day was breaking, I heard the sound of the Sioux war whoop
                            ringing all through the camp, and close by my door. I knew it, for I had heard it once
                            before, and it is a sound <pb n="238" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/> 238 THE MANIFESTO. that when once heard can
                            never be forgotten. I started from my couch, and that instant, a bullet came and penetrated
                            the mat where my head had lain. I rushed for the door and raised the curtain, when I saw the
                            arm of a Sioux warrior, with a tomahawk lifted directly over it, to take me as I passed. I
                            sprang back, and broke my way through the side covering of the wigwam. My canoe was there, I
                            seized it, and gave one shove for the river. I had reached it, and was just putting from the
                            shore, when a Sioux warrior seized the prow of the canoe, with his left hand, and, with the
                            other, lifted his tomahawk to take me down. He seemed to loom up, like a giant, right over
                            me. I cried out at the top of my voice, uKech-e Mo-ke-mon!" (I am an American.) His tomahawk
                            dropped. He looked at me very earnestly. The light was just dawning. uKa-get! Kech-e
                            Mo-kemon!" he exclaimed. (Truly you are an American.) and let go the prow of the canoe. I
                            floated down the river. It was a terrible massacre. Out of one hundred and sixty Ojib-ways,
                            only twenty escaped. They killed them, and set their dead bodies up against the trees by the
                            river shore, and, afterwards, their friends went out and buried them. My old guide remained
                            unharmed. He had been aroused from his sleep by the same wild war cry which had aroused me,
                            and had struggled fearfully for his life, against four armed warriors. At length he wrenched
                            the tomahawk from one of them, brained him on the spot, and fought his way through the
                            others to the river. There I found him, far down the stream, concealed by bushes, and took
                            him into my canoe, covered with dust and blood. And this was the most perilous, as well as
                            the most fearful of all the dangers that I encountered, while sojourning among the Indians
                            of the North West. —The End.— Canaan, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Faithfulness in temporal duties" TEIform="index"/> FAITHFULNESS IN TEMPORAL DUTIES. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Woods, Sarah S." TEIform="persName"/> SARAH S. WOODS. </byline><p TEIform="p"> Luke xvi., 11. "If therefore ye have not been faithful in the unrighteous mammon, who will
                            commit to your trust the true riches?" and 1 Cor. iv., 2. "Moreover, it is required in
                            stewards, that a man be found faithful;" (whether it be little or much entrusted to him.) It
                            would seem from these tests, that persons who are slothful, indifferent and dishonest in
                            temporal duties of any kind are not prepared to receive the true riches. Luke xix., we read
                            of a certain nobleman who gave to each of his servants a sum of money to trade upon, in his
                            absence to a far country. We find on his return that he bestowed his blessing and favor, on
                            those only who had gained other pounds in addition to what had been given them; while the
                            unfaithful steward had his money taken from him and given to him that had ten pounds. We
                            have testimony from scripture, also Mother Ann's words, that souls who were unfaithful in
                            temporal things, could not find the blessing and protection of God in their spiritual
                            travel. Mother Ann counseled her children to put their hands at work, and their hearts to
                            God. At one time she said to some Brethren, Be faithful with yoiir hands. Every faithful man
                            will put up his fences in season ; and will plough his ground in season, put his crops into
                            the ground in season ; and such a man may with confidence look for a blessing. She counseled
                            Sisters to be neat, industrious and prudent. She said also, don't speak harshly ; let your
                            words be few and seasoned with grace. In applying this subject at home, we find unless we
                            are determined to devote willing hands to faithfully labor with all our faculties combined,
                            for the upbuilding of the cause of God as our first parents have set us the example, we have
                            no right to call ourselves their children, or to claim their inheritance. Canterbury, N. H.
                        </p></div2><pb n="239" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hour of worship" TEIform="index"/> HOUR OF WORSHIP</head><p TEIform="p">Canterbury, N. H. 1. I love the hour of worship, Where angels gather nigh, 2. I love to know,
                            my spirit Is blending with the pure, With heav'nly inspration To raise our thoughts on high.
                            That I am storing treasures Eternally secure. I love to offer pledges Before my Father's
                            throne, And thus I feel exalted Yet humble, when I see Which will redeem from error, And
                            draw his blessing down. How good in all his dealings My God has been to me.</p></div2><pb n="240" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/> Books and Papers</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>
                                The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health. Sept. Contents : An Illinois Pioneer and
                                his Associates; This is an illustrated article of a very interesting character by Alice
                                D. Shipman; In this honored company we find Abraham Lincoln, James Shields, Stephen A.
                                Douglas, Joshua F. Speed and Judge J. Gillespie; A chapter on the Character of horses;
                                After thoroughly studying this article the reader can have the pleasure ef selecting the
                                horse that is most agreeable to his own mind; The Editor has told us a wonderful story
                                about this idolized and much abused animal; Read it. The true basis for the science of
                                Mind; The Parliament of the Faculties; Political Economy; The Kepples Head; Whims of
                                celebrated Men, are so very much like the whims of men who are not celebrated that this
                                article will be read with much interest; Women's Rights, is excellent, and if the Rev.
                                W. K. Darwood's sermon was equally as geod throughout, it is a sad pity that the whole
                                was not printed; Comus. by John Milton; The Blues; Notes; Editorial Items; etc. etc.
                                Fowler &amp; Wells, Pub. 753 Broadway, N. Y. $2. a year. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Halls journal of health" TEIform="index"/>Hall's Journal of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Hall's Journal of Heai/th.
                                Sept. Contents; Warnings; Neuralgia; Rheumatism; The Princis Escape; Treatment of
                                Goitre; Quinine in the Treatment of Whooping Cough; The Home Doctor; How a Man Walks;
                                St. Vitus' Dance; Food Adulteration; etc. etc. E. H. Gibbs, A. M., M. D. Editor, 21
                                Clinton Place, 8th. St. N. Y. $1. a year. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Herald of health" TEIform="index"/>The Herald of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Herald of Health. Sept. Contents: The
                                Salts of our Food; A Glance at Europe; The Habits of George Bancroft; In the Rain; Decay
                                of New England Stock; An incident in Sea Life; Studies in Hygiene for Women, etc., etc.
                                M. L. Holbrook, M. D. Pub. 13 &amp; 15 Laight St. N. Y. $1. a year. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cyclopedia of science" TEIform="index"/>CYCLOPEDIA OF
                                SCIENCE
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The publication of the World's Cyclopedia of Science is an event of remarkable
                                interest to many. For the first time, it brings the scholarly productions of the masters
                                in modern science within the reach of students and all readers who most need, and most
                                highly appreciate, their work. The plan of the Cyclopedia differs from any previously
                                published, in that, instead of being a mere alphabetical list of briefly treated topics,
                                including a mass of unimportant subjects, it will include, complete, the most important
                                works of leading scientific writers upon subjects of the highest value and interest.
                                Each volume will be complete in itself. Volume one, just issued, a large "model octavo"
                                of nearly 700 pages is sold at the price of$1.50 for the cloth, and $1 75 for the half
                                Russia binding, and contains what has heretofore appeared in numerous volumes obtainable
                                only at many times the cost; the works of such authors as T. H. Huxley, R. A. Proctor,
                                Herbert Spencer, Andrew Wilson, R. C. Trench, Alexander Bain, George Rawlinson, and
                                others. This volume will be followed soon by volumes two and three, the contents of
                                which are said to be of even greater popular interest and scientific value than the
                                present. It is almott superfluous to name the publisher of this grand contribution to
                                the intellectual progress of the masses, for who else would furni=h so .nuch that is
                                excellent for so little cost as John B. Alden, New York? For sale by booksellers and
                                club agents. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Homiletic monthly" TEIform="index"/>The Homiletic Monthly
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Homiletic Monthly. Sept. Contents: Swearing and Cursing; Winning Souls;
                                Sanctity of Vows; The guidance of God; Conversion of Children; The Jewels of the King;
                                The Cross of Christ; The Marvelous Magnet; Liberty through Love; Prayer Meeting Service;
                                Homiletic Studies in the Book of Hebrews; Commentary on the Epistle of James; Some Great
                                Preachers; Misquoted Scriptures; Sermonic Criticism; Queries and Answers; Voices from
                                many Pulpits; Suggestive Themes; etc., etc. Funk &amp; Wagnalls, Pub. 10 &amp;
                                12 Dey St. N. Y.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p"> The Bible likens the good man's life to a light. It is the nature of light to send forth its
                            rays in every direction; where light enters darkness scatters. The sun. gives light to the
                            earth, with this comes warmth and growth follows its healthful influence where life exists.
                            The Christian's example shines as a light, making the true Christian as a light and guide,
                            not so much because he seeks to be such, but being filled with the light of love, of truth,
                            of forbearance, of Godliness, the acts of his life are rays of divine light which, falling
                            in the path of another, cheers, brightens and encourages to good deeds.—</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="S., E. A." TEIform="persName"/>E. A. S.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Community Life" TEIform="index"/> COMMUNITY LIFE.</head><p TEIform="p"> How small our need, to daily want, Why should we avaricious grow, Since all is ours, and
                            nothing scant Which prudence can and doth bestow? Inheritance of selfish greed Should well
                            be overcome by grace ; That every want may be a need, And every need find only place. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/> M. W.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/> Deaths</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cloutman, John" TEIform="index"/>John Cloutman
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> John Cloutman, Sept. 10, at Harvard. Mass. Age, 75 yrs. He officiated as Elder in the
                                church forty seven years. He was ever true to principle, to his convictions of right.
                                The expression of Jesus "ye are the salt of the earth" finds in him a fitting
                                application. E. Myrick.</p></div3></div2><!--
                    <pb id="p29"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]<pb id="p30"/>
                            <pb id="p31"/>
                            <pb id="p32"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>