<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm0912" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title><editor role="editor" TEIform="editor"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/></editor></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">9</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">12</biblScope><date value="18791201" TEIform="date">December 1879</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">265-288</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="9" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="12" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                <pb id="p1"/>
                    <p>MANIFESTO. (OFFICIAL MONTHLY.) G. A. LOMAS, Editor. Published by the United Societies. 'And they shall turn to you
                        for a testimony, ''Go preach the Kingdom of God! " ADDTCESS ALL COMMUKICATIONS TO " The Shaker Manifesto, Shakers,
                        N.D." G. B. AVERY, PUBLISHER. 1879. Vol. IX. ) No. 12. J DECEMBER, 1879. 60 Cents Per Annum. The Shaker</p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --><pb n="265" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christmas" TEIform="index"/>CHRISTMAS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, G. B." TEIform="persName"/>G. B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p">"What is it?" In the popular sense, a day appointed by the Civil Governments of earth. Hold!
                            Civil? did we say? Civil? when by their laws, the poor, unable to obtain land wherefrom to
                            extract the sustenance for life, and unable to obtain labor to win that sustenance from
                            those who have land, and its hoarded harvests, are driven to crime and desperation! But (so
                            called) Civil governments oppoint this day to celebrate the advent of the birth of Jesus,
                            the poor man's Friend, by the institution of a ceremony of the Romish Church worship,
                            nominally meaning, " The office of prayers rendered at the Lord's Supper,"" called " The
                            Eucharist," which Eomish theology teaches is consecrating the notable bread and wine, of the
                            memorable " last-supper" fame, so that it may become transubstantiated — changed into the
                            real body and blood of Jesus! This is the Romish theory of " Mass," and the purpose of the
                            appointed day of Christmas. But this institution is now, by nearly all sects of so-called
                            Christians, converted into a holiday, just as the French nation has now converted the
                            Sabbath into a gala day, substituting feasting and revelry for prayers and sacrifices,
                            originally instituted in imitation and commemoration of Jesus' giving His life a ransom for
                            sinners, as His death on the Jewish cross, by the hands of wicked men is interpreted to
                            mean, by the theology of most professedly Christian sects. But, 0 ye bright angels from the
                            heavenly spheres, tell us, while the poor by thousands are starving, does a feast of roast
                            turkey, terrapinsoup, plum-pudding, cranberry-jelly, and visiting of wealthy friends, at
                            whose convivial board the sparkling bowl is drained, by lips that utter not thanksgivings,
                            and where are hearts that seldom or never bowed in gratitude, symbolically commemorate the
                            self-sacrificing life of Jesus, which He lived in order to become the treasury of power
                            wherewith to baptize a sinning world into repentance? Ah, who shares of the Christmas feasts
                            ? Alas! not these unto whom Jesus said: " Behold I come to bring unto you glad tidings." 0,
                            nay, not the poor, the needy, and destitute, but those unto whom Jesus said : " Behold ye
                            have received your consolations." Ah, would to heaven we might have one universal Christmas,
                            characterizing the life of Jesus, breaking bread to the hungry, and, with a life's
                            sacrifice, pleading the cause of the poor and needy! A day in^which every heart <pb n="266" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 266 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. should be made glad and thoughtful, by being fed,
                            warmed, clothed and comforted with the remembrance of care and human kindness; a day wherein
                            all souls could be made to feel the hospitality of man to man, and that of brotherly and
                            sisterly interest, love and friendship. Brother, Sister, Christian ! I know these names ;
                            they speak to us of bliss; they ope the gates of heaven ; in their bosomed sweetness rests
                            the ark of peace; upon their brows is poised the laurel wreath of union; charity and
                            forgiveness reign supreme ; harmony is spoken from their eyes, and a crown of love pure as
                            the virgin snoiv, rests upon their heads; love so tender, so deep and soul-thrilling that it
                            will never permit hard feelings, hard words, nor unkind actions, to be thrust upon a
                            brother, sister, nor friend, to mar the union, nor abraid the peace! Thus to live, is
                            keeping Christmas; thus to live is celebrating the memory of the birth of Jesus into the
                            resurrection order, the New Creation; and the self-sacrificing life of Christ, not only on
                            the notable anniversary of Jesus' birth, one single day in three hundred and sixty-five, but
                            three hundred and sixty-five days in every year; converting the epoch of a life-time into
                            one vast Christmas, a feast day of rejoicing, bringing heaven to earth, and making one
                            glorious Jubilee of the Lord! Brethren, Sisters, Christians, shall we not thus keep
                            Christmas ; thus set out anew to make our home a Paradise; our house the Court of the Angels
                            of the heavenly land, with " none to hurt or destroy in all God's Holy Mountain," the soul
                            life-bond of union? Our meetings thus freed from the bitterness of hatred ; the wickedness
                            of malice ; the ruthless barbs of jealousy ; the mockeries of hypocrisy; the deceitfulness
                            of lies, and the painful bondage of the sins of private life, may then be the assemblies of
                            blessedness, where fountains gushing full and free with soul-life and heavenly love are
                            inviting and invigorating, and the river of eternal life rolls smoothly on, without a ripple
                            from the discordant waves of unholy passion. This is a Christmas of the Lord ; this a
                            monument to the blessed, consecrated life of Jesus Christ, firmer, purer than the diamond's
                            crystal base; more trenchant than its angular point upon the institutions of a woe-stricken
                            world! Gospel friends, be this our Christmas ; this harmonious relation our Christmas tree,
                            bearing upon its boughs the luscious fruits of heaven, garnering 'neath its bending limbs of
                            grace, all the gifts of a beneficent Father and a Heavenly Mother, bestowed upon the
                            children of their consecrated Zion Home. 0, friends, grant me to be a guest at the feast of
                            the Christian's Christmas !</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Jehovah" TEIform="index"/>JEHOVAH</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Basting, Louis" TEIform="persName"/>LOUIS BASTING</byline><p TEIform="p">In a former article I advanced some arguments showing the fallacy of the claims in support of
                            the Divine Inspiration of the Bible, spoken of as an entirety. While those arguments were
                            based mainly upoxi such technical grounds as mistranslation and interpolation, I now propose
                            to show from the unquestioned text itself that there exists further and still weightier
                            reasons that should lead us to reject it as a book of <pb n="267" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. 267 supernatural origin and authority, spoken of as a whole. There is not a more
                            striking inconsistency exhibited in the whole system of orthodox theology than the
                            identification of the Jehovah of the Old Testament with the God of the universe. The most
                            enlightened men of all Christian denominations, men eminent for practical piety, and learned
                            in all the wisdom of this world, have united in ascribing to the Supreme Being all the most
                            exalted virtues the human mind is capable of conceiving; whose power is unlimited, in whom
                            mercy and justice are blended in harmonious grace ; they declare his eternal selfexistence ;
                            his omniscience ; his prescience ; his inconceivable mode of being ; his infinite wisdom
                            that cannot err ; his infinite goodness that can do nothing but what'is eternally just and
                            kind. Such are the attributes of the Deity, but how widely different is the character of the
                            God of the Jews ! It is unreasonable that God should create a race of human beings, endowed
                            with freedom of action, and, being enabled by prescience to foresee their career, that he
                            should " repent " of having made them, and to destroy them almost literally. Yet such is the
                            story of Genesis. It is absurd that a being of almighty power should not be able to overcome
                            a small tribe of men, " because they had chariots of iron," as we are told in the Book of
                            Judges. It is blasphemous to assert that the Eternal Fountain of Truth should " put a tying
                            spirit into the mouths of the prophets," as is stated in Chronicles. The God of the Universe
                            never gets angry at the children of his own creating ; he does not treat them as his enemies
                            ; he does not thirst for revenge ; he never required " eye for eye, tooth for tooth;" he
                            does not delight in war and bloodshed; and he never surrounded himself with such a murderous
                            class as Jehovah established. The conquest of Canaan, unjustifiable as it was, was
                            accompanied by atrocities which were never excelled in barbarity by any military chief,
                            ancient or modern ; yet they were all executed by the direct command of the Jewish war-god.
                            The portrait of Jehovah, as presented to us in the Old Testament, would undoubtedly
                            represent equally well the character of a sanguinary despot of Homeric times. But it has
                            been said, apologetically for those deeds which stand condemned by the criminal as well as
                            the moral code of our day, that they were done with a view of benefiting the Jewish people ;
                            that, considering their barbaric condition, it was the best mode of dealing with them, then
                            possible. Admitting that the argument appears plausible enough, it is in reality dangerous
                            and misleading sophistry; a miserable casuistry. The horrors of the medieval inquisition
                            were enacted with exactly the same end in view—to keep inviolate what was considered the
                            purity of the faith, and to save the souls of the people. It was this doctrine that the
                            means employed were justified by the end in view ; which justly or unjustly has been
                            attributed to the " Society of Jesus," which has been condemned by the moral sentiment of
                            all Christendom, and has made the name of '"Jesuit" odious throughout the world. There is
                            but one rule of action laid down for the guidance of all men : to do right according to the
                            light possessed ; and no possible contingency in human affairs can ever arise, which would
                            justify a departure from that rule. How inconceivably absurd, if not wicked, does it appear
                            then to attempt to explain away the barbarities and immoralities committed by the Jews at
                            the command of their God, as having been countenanced by that God whom we worship as the
                            embodiment of Truth and Love ! Murder is murder, lying is lying, sin is sin, whether
                            committed by man, by angels, or even the hoary Jehovah. The ways of Providence may often
                            appear mysterious and indefinable to human minds ; but we may rest assured that God
                            accomplishes his purposes by means which harm not one of his creatures. The anthropopathic
                            view of the Jewish Deity given in the Bible, is no doubt, in a large degree, the reflex of a
                            savage condition of society and of brutal minds, who ascribed every emanation from the
                            spirit world to God ; and spirituality and hope of immortality being almost unknown to them,
                            they worshipped their ruler with fear and trem- <pb n="268" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 268 THE SHAKES
                            MANIFESTO. Wing, knowing that to provoke his wrath would be followed by punishment swift and
                            terrible. Jehovah was to them indeed a terrible God! But are we who have learned to know God
                            as a loving Father and Mother, of ineffable mercy and goodness, who is never vindictive; who
                            never destroys; but who is ever ready to forgive and to bless every soul that turns Godward;
                            are we to regard him as one with the gory divinity of Jewry ? Itather let us accept the
                            revelation of our day and welcome the light of reason that rejects the traditions and
                            authority of antiquity whenever they conflict, or seek to compromise with what always has
                            been and always will be right and true Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What is life?" TEIform="index"/>WHAT IS LIFE ?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Rhoda R." TEIform="persName"/>RHODA R. HOLLISTER</byline><p TEIform="p">O ! what is life upon the earth, A ceaseless toil mid' pain and dearth ? For which no
                            recompense is given, Though every kindred tie is riven? May we not ever hope to find
                            Something to satisfy the mind? Through all the struggles that are rife, To win the goal,
                            eternal life ? Have all the battles bravely fought, With no sure victory been fraught ? But
                            doubt and fear, with ebbing tide, The surging waters still divide? And shall the spectre of
                            despair, With Upas poison fill the air ? Destroying buds of faith and hope, That would in
                            beauty gently ope ? Shall we then trust to shadows vague, Our time and talents to engage ?
                            When high and noble aims invite, Our aspirations for the right ? RESPONSE. Ah, nay, it is
                            not all a blank, Our being here below ; But rays of light from sunny climes, Their
                            brightness o'er us throw. And freshened hopes that in our hearts Are rising new each day—
                            Point ever to the glorious time, When love shall bear the sway. And superstition, caste, and
                            creed, No more can bind the soul ; But freedom's disenthralling power, O'er error will
                            control. New earth and heavens, clear and bright, Like clouds that upward rise, Unveils the
                            sun aglow with light, To flood the earth and skies. And sorrowing spirits that have trod The
                            martyr's rugged way May in this light be lifted up, And view the gladsome day ; When Zion's
                            Temple rises, grand, Above the plane of earth, While many there have entered in, And found
                            the heavenly birth. There no discordant spirits dwell, Her sacred courts to mar, But
                            quietude and order reign, With love the guiding star. And on her banner is inscribed, In
                            lines of purest gold, Peace, and good-will,to all mankind; Its blessed power behold. For
                            this the hundred-fold is given, The Saviour's promised boon ; That all, who kindred ties
                            forsake, May share this heavenly home. Can come, and with them be baptized, In Jordan's
                            cleansing wave, And find in Achor's valley low, A balsam that will save. 'Tis thus a pure
                            relation's formed, Strong in the love of truth ; Working together in the Lord, For its
                            increasing growth. Building upon this basis, A structure that will stand, Should threatening
                            storms and tempests, Sweep over sea and land. And while to heaven is lifted, A prayer to
                            haste the time, When souls that good are seeking, The harvest work will find ; We'll gather
                            to the standard, So beautiful and true, Borne by our faithful leaders, To guide us safely
                            through. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Who is Christ?" TEIform="index"/>WHO IS CHRIST?</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Sen, Baboo Keshub Chunder" TEIform="persName"/>BABOO KESHUB CHUNDER SEN</byline><p TEIform="p">I am not a Christian ; none of the numerous sects into which the Church of Christ is divided
                            would allow my creed to be identified with its own. I have not been nursed on a Christian
                            lap, nor have I been brought up under Christian teachers. The country in which I dwell is
                            not a Christian country, nor is my home a Christian home. I am deficient in biblical
                            knowledge, nor am <pb n="269" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 269 I skilled in exegesis. Yet
                            must I speak of Christ. My love of Christ constrains me to speak of Him. My loyalty to Jesus
                            is my apology. If any other apology were needed, I would invite your attention to India's
                            earnest and impassioned solicitation. Most eagerly and most earnestly she asks : Who is
                            Christ ? On all sides there are indications and signs which clearly and unmistakably prove
                            that this question emanates from the very heart of the nation. It is no wonder that India
                            should ask this question. For is not a new and aggressive civilization winning its way day
                            after day, and year after year, into the very heart and soul of the people ? Are not
                            Christian ideas and institutions taking their root on all sides in the soil of India ? Has
                            not a Christian government taken possession of its cities, its provinces, its villages ;
                            with its hills and plains, its rivers and seas, its homes and hearths, its teeming millions
                            of men and women and children ? Yes, the advancing surges of a mighty revolution are
                            encompassing the land, and in the name of Christ strange innovations are penetrating the
                            very core of India's heart. Well may our fatherland sincerely and earnestly ask : Who is
                            this Christ ? Perhaps you will tell me that this question has been answered already. Look at
                            the flood of Christian literature that has swept over the length and breadth of the country.
                            There are heaps of books and numberless preachers and teachers around you, all endeavoring
                            to give a complete answer to the question before us. Doubtless, from these sources, India
                            has had some knowledge of Christ of Nazareth. Bat such knowledge has not given her complete
                            satisfaction. It is true, the people of India have been satisfied in some measure, but they
                            have been disappointed in a much greater measure. For England has sent unto us, after all, a
                            Western Christ. This is indeed to be regretted. Our countrymen find that in this Christ,
                            sent by England, there is something that is not quite congenial to the native mind, not
                            quite acceptable to the genius of the nation. It seems that the Christ that has come to us
                            is an Englishman, with English manners and customs about him, and with the temper and spirit
                            of an Englishman in him. Hence is it that the Hindoo people shrink back and say, " Who is
                            this revolutionary reformer who is trying to sap the very foundations of native society, and
                            bring about an outlandish faith and civilization quite incompatible with Oriental instincts
                            and ideas? Why must we submit to one who is of a different nationality ? Why must we bow
                            before a foreign prophet?" It is a fact which cannot be gainsaid that hundreds upon
                            hundreds, thousands upon thousands, even among the most intelligent in the land, stand back
                            in moral recoil from this picture of a foreign Christianity trying to invade and subvert
                            Hindoo society ; and this repugnance unquestionably hinders the progress of the true spirit
                            of Christianity in this country. But why should you Hindoos go to England to learn Jesus
                            Christ ? Is not Christ's native land nearer to India than England ? Are not Jesus and his
                            apostles and immediate followers more akin to Indian nationality than Englishmen ? Are not
                            the scenes enacted in the drama of the Christian dispensation altogether homely to us
                            Indians ? When we hear of the lily, and the sparrow, and the well, and a hundred other
                            things of Eastern countries, do we not feel we are quite at home in the Holy Land ? Why
                            should we then travel to a distant country like England in order to gather truths which are
                            to be found much nearer our homes ? Go to the rising sun in the East, not to the setting sun
                            in the West, if you wish to see Christ in the plentitude of his glory and the fulness and
                            freshness of the primitive dispensation. Why do I speak of Christ in England and Europe as
                            the setting sun ? Because there we find Apostolical Christianity almost gone; there we find
                            the life of Christ formulated into lifeless forms and antiquated symbols. But if you go to
                            the true Christ in the East, and his apostles, you are seized with inspiration. You find the
                            truths of Christianity all fresh and resplendent. Recall to your minds the true Asiatic <pb n="270" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 270 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. Christ, divested of all Western appendages,
                            carrying on the work of redemption among his own people. Behold, he cometh to us in his
                            loose-flowing garments, his dress and features altogether Oriental, a perfect Asiatic in
                            every thing. Watch his movements, and you will find genuine Orientalism in all his habits
                            and manners, his uprising and downsitting, his going forth and his coming in, his preaching
                            and ministry—aye, in his very language, and style and tone. Indeed, while reading the
                            Gospel, we cannot but feel that we are quite at home when we are with Jesus, and that Jesus
                            is altogether one of us. He is our Christ. The outward Christ is certainly an Asiatic, and,
                            as such he comes to us, and rivets our national sympathies. But can we say the same thing of
                            the invisible Chriot, the spiritual Christ, the soul of Christ? Is that Oriental ? Can you,
                            as Asiatics, appreciate and accept the spirit of Christ? In the very outset of the inquiry,
                            we find the ethics of Christ asking us to accept it, and give it a place in our hearts. And
                            we readily acquiesce in it. The sublime and marvelous ethics of Christ, who can condemn—who
                            will not honor ? The rules of forgiveness and love, meekness, humility, charity, justice,
                            sincerity, and simplicity,the rules of propriety, self-restraint, asceticism, constitute the
                            highest standard of true ethics, which must find acceptance in all parts of the world.
                            Though we are Hindoos, we cannot help admiring the superior and exalted ethics which Christ
                            brings to us. You cannot deny it; you cannot set it aside. It is from God. Your consciences
                            attest it. Ancient philosophy bows before it. A greater than Socrates has taught us this
                            lofty ethical code; and we are bound for truth's sake to accept this legacy from Christ. We
                            are all agreed, irrespective of differences of creed and caste, as to the supremacy of the
                            ethical law embodied in Christ's teachings and character. If you Indians hesitate or refuse
                            to accept Christ, it is not because you dislike Christ's ethics. It is not Christ's humanity
                            that is a stumbling-block in your way, but his socalled divinity. His heavenly spirituality,
                            not his human morality, stands in the way of your accepting him. It appears to me that
                            Christ believed earnestly and consistently in what 'I should, in the absence of a better
                            expression, call the doctrine of divine humanity. Christ not only believed this, but he
                            carried it, theoretically and practically, to the uttermost logical sequence. But what was
                            this doctrine? Christ struck the key-note of it when he announced his divinity before an
                            astonished and amazed world in these words: "land my Father are one." He lived, moved, and
                            had his being in God. Not a breath he drew, but it was from the Lord. Not a drop of
                            life-blood was there in him, but it came from the very fountain of life and vitality in
                            heaven. He said, he heard, he touched, as we see, hear and touch. but he always felt that
                            the root of his being was God himself—a fact of which we are not always conscious. He had
                            his life rooted in divinity. He felt always that the Lord was underlying his whole
                            existence. And, therefore, without equivocation, and with all the boldness and candor of
                            conscious'simplicity, he proclaimed unto the world that he was one with God. But he asserted
                            the doctrine of spiritual oneness, not only with reference to the Godhead, but also with
                            regard to those around him. He was present, not only in God, but also in the hearts of his
                            disciples. What was his prayer to his Father regarding his people before he allowed himself
                            to be crucified ? Some time before that event occurred, Christ went to his Father and said,
                            " As thou, Father, art in me, and I in thee, that they also may be one in us." Thus, in
                            comprehensive unity, he sought to include God, himself, and all mankind. On the occasion of
                            his last supper, he. commended himself to his disciples and the world at large as mere bread
                            and wine, to be assimilated to the soul, as mere leaven, that in time leaveneth the whole
                            mass. Addressing those around him, Christ said : " He that eateth my flesh and drinketh my
                            blood dwelleth in me and I in him." The language is strange, indeed ! Christ's body should
                            enter into his disciples; his very <pb n="271" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 271 flesh
                            and his very blood should be tasted by his chosen and beloved disciples ! Those who loved
                            him were called upon to partake of his flesh and blood ! The thing seems absurd. How could
                            man eat Christ and drink his blood ? That was possible in one sense only. In the sense
                            already indicated of spiritual identification. All those who accept Jesus with thorough
                            fidelity are identified with him in truth, in love, in wisdom, and in purity of character.
                            As Christ was one with God, he wanted others also to be one with him and one with God, so
                            that all men might dwell together in the glory# of heaven, enjoying everlastingly a life of
                            purity and holiness and joy in God himself. That, indeed, was Christ's mission, that was the
                            great object of his life. He did not seek to place himself before his hearers as a dogma or
                            a doctrine or a theoretical truth. He wanted to live in them with all his ideas and feelings
                            and principles, his piety and godliness, his life of mystic absorption into the Deity. For
                            two thousand years men have been trying to find out the dead Christ under the stone. But the
                            Spirit of God has marveL ously rolled away the stone, and Christ is not there. Even for
                            three days Christ would not consent to live on earth as a dead Christ buried under the
                            stone. So the Lord took his Christ unto himself and has in all ages discomfited and
                            disappointed those that have searched for a dead Christ on earth. Where, then, is Christ
                            now? He is living in all Christian lives, and in all Christian influences at work around us.
                            Of the dead Christ I speak not. Of what use is a dead Christ to us or to our nation ? Put
                            the living spirit of Christ into your hearts and affections, your daily life and character.
                            Do you not see Christ existing throughout Christendom, like an all-pervading leaven,
                            mysteriously and imperceptibly leavening the bias of millions of men and women ? You cannot
                            resist his influence, you may deny his doctrine, you may even hate and repudiate his name,
                            but he goes straight into your hearts and leavens your lives. He does not care to inquire
                            what doctrine you believe, or what dogma you accept, nor even what sort of a life you lead.
                            You may be the basest of sinners. You may be intellectually opposed to many of his
                            doctrines. The truth that is in Christ will, perforce, overcome and penetrate your souls in
                            spite of your perverseness, and secretly influence your character. In all Christian
                            literature, laws and institutions, we see Christ's living influence as a reality. The Christ
                            that is advancing in all directions has touched India, and hence the question she asks—-Who
                            is Christ? The genius of the nation has asked this question, and you are bound to answer it.
                            In the interests of the country, in the interests of truth, the question must be answered
                            one way or another, now or hereafter. To India's solemn and thrilling cry you must some day
                            return a response. Meanwhile I must beg your acceptance of the truly national solution of
                            the problem I have presented to you. You will find on reflection that the doctrine of divine
                            humanity is essentially a Hindoo doctrine, and the picture of Christ's life and character I
                            have drawn is altogether a picture of ideal Hindoo life. Surely, the idea of absorption and
                            immersion in the Deity is one of those ideas of Vedantic Hindooism which prevail extensively
                            in India. From the highest sage to the humblest peasant, millions of men in this land
                            believe in the Pantheistic doctrine of man's identity with the Godhead. The most illiterate
                            man is heard to say he and the Lord are one. The doctrine of absorption in the Deity is
                            India's creed, and, through this idea, I believe, India will reach Christ. Will he not
                            fulfill the Indian Scripture ? I am reminded of the passage in the Gospel in which he says:
                            "I am not come to destroy, but to fulfill." The Mosaic dispensation only? Perhaps the Hindoo
                            dispensation also. In India, he will fulfill the Hindoo dispensation. The religion of our
                            ancestors was Pantheism from beginning to the end, and what is Hindoo Pantheism?
                            Essentially, it is nothing but the identity of all things with God. I do not mean that you
                            should retain Pantheism as it exists in Indian books. Oh ! there are mischievous errors and
                            horrid ideas mixed up with it, which you must eschew. Christ's Pantheism is a Pantheism of a
                            lof- <pb n="272" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 272 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. tier and more perfect type. It is the
                            conscious union of the human with the Divine Spirit in truth, love and joy. The Hindoo sage
                            realizes this union only during meditation, and he seeks unconscious absorption in his God,
                            with all his faults and shortcomings about him. But Christ's communion is active and
                            righteous ; it combines purity of character with devotion. Hindoo Pantheism in its worst
                            form is proud, being based upon the belief that man is God ; it is quietism and trance ;
                            Christ's Pantheism is the active self-surrender of the humble servant and the loving son. In
                            the midst of activity, Christ was absorbed in God. Eating or drinking, preaching or going
                            about doing good, his spirit was enjoying serene communion. There is no pride in him, for he
                            is dead to self. There is no dreamy mysticism in him, for he is ever doing the will of his
                            Father. In Christ you see true Pantheism. And, as the basis of early Hindooism is Pantheism,
                            you, my countrymen, cannot help accepting Christ in the spirit of your national scriptures.
                            You have already seen how, in his outward form and appearance, with his flowing garments, he
                            is acceptable to you. Now, you find that even the spirit of Christ draws you through your
                            national instincts. You have a national affinity to the invisible as well as to the visible
                            Christ. Can you deny it? Behold, Christ cometh as an Asiatic in race, as a Hindoo in faith,
                            as a kinsman and a brother, and he demands your heart's affection. Will you deny it ? He
                            comes to fulfill and perfect that religion of communion for which India has been panting as
                            the hart panteth after the water-brooks. Let all people in this country who bear the
                            Christian name remember that it is not by presenting a Western Christ to our countrymen that
                            they will be able to regenerate India. If you like, present the English side of Cbrist's
                            many-sided character to the English nation. If you wish, present a German Christ to the
                            Germans, an American Christ to the American people. But if you wish to regenerate us
                            Hindoos, present Christ to us in his Hindoo character. When you bring Christ to us, do not
                            bring him to us as a civilized European, but as an Asiatic ascetic, whose wealth is
                            devotion, and whose riches are prayers. That horrid form of asceticism which prevails in
                            this country in the form of mere self-mortification is, indeed, most harmful and pernicious.
                            True asceticism, as indicated by Christ, means simply this : " Seek ye first the kingdom of
                            God and his righteousness, and all things shall be added unto you." One word more and I have
                            done. The time is coming, and now is, when India shall worship the Father in spirit and in
                            .truth. Say unto Christ as unto your best friends — Welcome ! I say, emphatically, and I say
                            before you all, that Christ is already present in you. lie is in you, even when you are
                            unconscious of his presence ; even if your lips deny Christ, your hearts secretly accept
                            him. For Christ is "the light that lighteth every man that cometh into the world." If you
                            have in you the spirit of truth and filial devotion, self-sacrifice, that is Christ. Though
                            often defiled and persecuted by the world, I have found sweetness and joy unutterable in my
                            Master Jesus. Jesus is to me not a hard doctrine. He never was to me a doctrine. I am
                            thankful to say I never read any anti-Christian books with delight, and never had to wage
                            war with my Christ. The mighty artillery of his love he leveled against me, and I was
                            vanquished and fell at his feet, saying, Blessed Child of God, when shall others see the
                            light that is in thee ? Therefore, I say, countrymen, be not as the unbelievers are ; do not
                            throw yourselves into the vortex of materialism and scepticism. Christ, your friend, is
                            walking through the streets of this country, carrying the banner of God, the Most High. He
                            exhorts you to renounce self. My countrymen, throw off the scabbard then, unsheath the sword
                            and cut down this abominable self, and establish this kingdom of heaven in your lives.
                            Achieve the triumph and rejoice, for the Bridegroom cometh.</p></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How beautiful the remark of a little girl..." TEIform="index"/>How beautiful the remark of a little girl...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">How beautiful the remark of a little girl,, when looking up at the stars, she exclaimed: '
                            Oh dear ! If the wrong side of heaven is. so beautiful, what must the right be?"</p></div2><pb n="273" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Singing school" TEIform="index"/>SINGING SCHOOL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcomb, Ola L." TEIform="persName"/>OLA L. WHITCOMB</byline><p TEIform="p">Not the spectacled Master of Music, With a " do," and a " re," and a " mi," With a tuning
                            fork, pointer and blackboard, And a rule like the tough "Rule of Three;" But a sweet little
                            brook in the meadow—¦ Where the willows can dip in their leaves, That babbles, and ripples
                            and murmurs, Full of music ; the brook never grieves. A dear little bird on the walk there,
                            Sipping temperance wine at his will, And singing as though life depended On the force of his
                            not keeping still; A cricket, somewhere in a crevice, With chir-r, chirp, chimp and cheer,
                            Whoever heard tell of a cricket That had in its song an " Oh dear ! " A fly, spinning round
                            in the sunlight ; A bee, humming tunes to the flowers ; And the soft, sweet pattering music
                            Of raindrops in afternoon showers ; The teakettle, hung in the fire-place, What a marvel, of
                            music it owns ! No Mendelssohn, Mozart nor Blind Tom, Can equal its sharp and flat tones. I
                            remember the times of my childhood, Its music was charming to me ; Perhaps that charm
                            was—was—because — Wrell—we used to have dough-nuts for tea! The children out there on the
                            hill-side 'Mongthe violets, sweet is their song ; Young children, bright flowers and music,
                            Such beauties together belong. The brook, bird, bee, rain and fly, And children, are songs
                            without end ; Nature's grand concert of harmony Is the singing school 1 would attend.
                            Canaan, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dying year" TEIform="index"/>THE DYING YEAR</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Neale, S. A." TEIform="persName"/>S. A. NEALE</byline><p TEIform="p">Slowly, but surely, the passing moments are wending their way toward the grave of the dying
                            year. Each day we are nearing the closing scene. " Passing away" is written on Nature's
                            already sad countenance, and the forests even now wave to a mournful requiem. It would
                            almost seem to us that Mother Earth were mourning, so brown and sere has become her attire.
                            The light of much variety has gone out of her life, and she appears like one asking for
                            sympathy. Have we none to give ? Or shall we let this link in time's golden chain fall into
                            obscurity alone, unrequited, without even a farewell tribute — this year that has been so
                            much to us, contributing so largely to our comfort, hopes and happiness ? A year that has
                            grown us a harvest of plenty, and showered us with blessings so bountifully? This precious
                            year that has been all that time could be, that has given us opportunities, many and noble,
                            for the performance of Christian virtues; shall we bury this precious season in the grave of
                            forgetfulness ? Never ! This cannot be, for its feeble form still holds the germ of
                            rejuvenated life which the future claims for development. So its seeming decline leadeth not
                            unto death, but in reality unto a resurrection of life through all futurity. It ever remains
                            the living present, over which the past and future clasp their loving hands. Ah, yea ;
                            tender and true are the ties that hold us in the loving embrace of this season of seasons;
                            and though we are aware time tarries not for any, we would gladly stay the flying moments
                            for a brief period, even though we feel their progress is on to greater perfection. But such
                            is the course of events in the great cycles of time ; and thus it will ever be that one year
                            will follow another on through unnumbered ages in the unknown beyond. There will always be a
                            passing away of old life and an unfolding of the new. Growth and decay are stamped upon the
                            face of all existence. To-day we live in a material form; to-morrow our existence may be
                            elsewhere, we know not; but we do know the present holds friendship's magnet, and we trust
                            the future may retain the same, while the past holds the sunshine of happiness where
                            hallowed memory still loves to linger and grow warm in the reality of its pleasantness. And
                            if we are reminded that we have sometimes wandered where shadows have fallen and sorrows
                            come, tis pitiful ; but these we would quietly shroud in mourning, and bury where the
                            incoming tide of life cannot reach them. Thus we would preserve unto futurity only goodness
                            and joys of the past. And now we return with grateful hearts to our failing friend, the
                            dying year; or rather the old life that is passing away to make room for the new. We realize
                            that during its short existence we have been blessed <pb n="274" id="p154" TEIform="pb"/> 274 THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. with a rich increase; we have reaped a golden fruitage and garnered a bountiful
                            harvest; heaven's blessings have fallen upon us in many and various ways ; and now the
                            question arises, have these treasures invariably come to us for good? Have we so far
                            appreciated them as to adapt them to our needs only ? If so, what have we given in return ?
                            Is it willing hands and hearts to serve in a Christian cause? Is the world any better for
                            our having lived during this closing precious season ? We can hope so ; and in the peace
                            thereof will tenderly turn this golden leaf in life's historical book, and bidding it a
                            loving adieu, look on the next page to hail with joy the face of the newborn year. Shakers,
                           N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker theology" TEIform="index"/>SHAKER THEOLOGY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p">What Shakers have taught for one hundred years : 1.—Human beings have eternal existences, but
                            immortality of soul life is the fruit of obedience to Christian principles,— soul death the
                            fruit of sin. 2.—Probation continues in all stages of existence. 3.—The mercy of God is as
                            eternal as the existence of God. 4.—God is male and female. 5.—The Trinity, Atonement,
                            Vicarious Sacrifice—the Blood doctrine—Physical Resurrection, Deathbed conversions, Eternal
                            hell and heaven for what men and women can do in the body ; Salvation, simply for believing
                            sometliing, or damnation for not believing, are part and parcel of the old heavens passing
                            away. On all these points, Shakers have fought the good fight of faith, and have won. Their
                            ideas are becoming popular — millions are approximating the system of Shaker Theology.
                            Sph'itualism is the solvent to disintegrate the false Christianity of the Constantine
                            Church. With singing and dancing we rejoice before God, at the downfall of bloody
                            Christianity— all Church and State systems. Inasmuch as the " Great Whore" has lived
                            deliciously, drinking the blood of Saints—-so much sorrow and trouble are hers, which we
                            cheerfully accord to her.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Give us this day our daily bread" TEIform="index"/>"GIVE US THIS DAY OUR DAILY BREAD."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>MARTHA J. ANDEIRSON</byline><p TEIform="p">0, trustful prayer! by earnest heart expressed, The simple utterance of a common need ; A
                            want, awakened in each human breast, That seeks for some sustaining power to feed. Christ
                            taught his true disciples thus to pray— While by his gentle hand their souls were led To
                            trace the shining paths of wisdom's way— " Lord, give to us this day our daily bread." Along
                            the centuries' broadening aisles, Whence come the precious truths of long ago. We see the
                            sunbeams of those golden smiles, That flood the earth with an eternal glow. The bud and
                            blossom of the passing 3Tears, Their harvest fruitage in our pathway spread, To this blest
                            prayer the answer now appears. " Lord, give to us this day our daily bread." While millions
                            in the fated Orient Have yielded to starvation stern and gaunt; While plague and scourge, on
                            direful mission bent, Have filled the sunny South with woe and want, Our home'—-among the
                            hills that God hath reared, Where timely showers and gentle dews are shed —¦ Has not by
                            scorching heat and drought been seared, For we have shared each day our daily bread. Thus
                            while we ask, 0 ! let us not forget That constant blessing, like a silvery stream In
                            peaceful flow, our hearts' desires have met, Till all life's toil and duties pleasant seem.
                            Ah ! in the consciousness of doing right, The crystal sea of perfect truth we tread, And,
                            dwelling in the glory of its light, Receive from angel hands our daily bread. And now within
                            this sacred, calm retreat, Once more our gifts on Nature's shrine we lay; 0 ! may their
                            perfume rise like incense sweet, And mingle with our orisons to-day. While we commune from
                            all the world apart <pb n="275" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 275 As did that Judean
                            band, with Christ their head, Likewise we pray with fervency of heart, " Lord, give to us
                            this day our daily bread." The fruits of union and the sweets of love, The harvest-yield of
                            friendship's precious seed, The ripened sheaves that peace hath stored above, These shall
                            supply our spiritual need. And for the mortal we would seek for wealth That springeth from
                            earth's rich and fruitful bed, The food that giveth lengthened life and health. Give us this
                            day, O, Lord! for daily bread.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tobacco" TEIform="index"/>TOBACCO</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prentiss, Oliver" TEIform="persName"/>OLIVER PRENTISS</byline><p TEIform="p">Our debut in mortal scenes is, or ought to be, in a state of innocence. That a large
                            percentage of children come into the world laden with the iniquities of fathers,
                            grandfathers, great-grandfathers, and great-great-grandfathers, is truly lamentable. Such
                            unfortunates are justly entitled to much commiseration and tender sympathy. Any departure
                            from native innocence is a Fall— requiring a corresponding Resurrection. Children and youth
                            are more exposed to fall down hill, than up. 'Twas so with the first little Adam. When he
                            came to that little tree, about half way down the garden— put there to be let alone — to try
                            his integrity — when he dabbled and dandled at that tree — he fell I Too many other little
                            Adams do so. To nominate all the falls, down and up, is not our vocation. Having passed
                            lightly over one doion hill fall, as off-set, we modestly mention one up hill fall, to wit:
                            Tobacco. To native innocence, tobacco is uniformly offensive. By indomitable effort, worthy
                            of better achievements, the habit of using it is acquired. It is a crime against nature, a
                            tremendous fall up hill. How many I have heard ejaculate thusly : " I wish I could quit
                            tobacco !" But stop right here. It has been said, " There is no great loss without some
                            small gain." If, to be a man among men, a boy, of any age, has fallen up hill, acquired the
                            tobacco disease, he has an opportunity now—a splendid opportunity — to give practical
                            demonstration to himself and to others, that he has a hone in Ids back—-a forty-horse
                            will-power— that he believes " in the Resurrection of the body," resurrection from all that
                            does not accord with his divinest ideal of the true dignity of man in the likeness of God —
                            practical demonstration that in this individual, there is a Soul, and that the Soul, not the
                            body, rules the machine. [The writer of the above testimony has the right to speak that
                            seventy-one (71) years' use of the vile weed can give, a right to say to the tempted : "
                            Don't! " and to the poor, infatuated, enslaved human, who lias fallen into the snare of the
                            Devil, in the shape of tobacco, " Quit! "] F. W. Evans.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Light on the subject" TEIform="index"/>LIGHT ON THE SUBJECT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dibble, Chauncy" TEIform="persName"/>CHAUNCY DIBBLE</byline><p TEIform="p">We understand that Freeman, the religious lunatic, who sacrificed his daughter, stands
                            indicted for murder in the first degree. This is right. He should be thoroughly tried and
                            sentenced ; then of course pardoned. Meanwhile all Christian judges and lawyers who hold to
                            the infallible truth of every sentence contained in the Old Testament, should put their
                            theologies to the test, and see if they do not indorse the same view of God's character
                            which led Freeman to the commission of the deed. It may be easy to account for the
                            derangement of any one predisposed to and under temporary excitement ; but how forty
                            socalled rational men could be accessory to a deed so revolting, is hard to account for! And
                            yet, looking at the theological inconsistencies of priestcraft, we are convinced that there
                            would be more human sacrifices by inquisition, if certain classes of religionists had the
                            power. We love to look upon the more reasonable <pb n="276" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 276 THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. probability, that Abraham had no intention of slaying Isaac. The ceremony was a
                            sign of the consecration of his first born son to the service of his God. So of Jephtha, who
                            only consecrated his daughter to the service of the temple. We are prepared, however, to
                            excuse the worst barbarity of that age, in consideration that many of their customs, and
                            particularly their passion for bloody sacrifices was inherited from their ancestors. Never
                            more can we harbor the thought that God was pleased with these sacrifices nor took any part
                            in wars. Shakers, N. Y..</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bogus Christianity" TEIform="index"/>BOGUS CHRISTIANITY</head><p TEIform="p">[The N. Y. Graphic very pithily points to morals and religion in the two valuable chapters of
                            ancient and modern history, and we will either be ashamed of our Christianity if it is
                            represented truthfully in these, or we must disown such as being Christianity.—Ed.J
                            CONDENSED HISTORY OF THE NORTH AMERICAN INDIANS White man landing on the American continent,
                            remarks : Fine country this. B'long to anybody ? Conscientious White—Well, there's Indians
                            on it. W. M.—Oh ! They're only on it. They can't own it. They've no possessory rights. Con.
                            W. M.— Why? W. M,—Why? What a question. 'Cos they're not civilized. Don't know how to read
                            or write. No school-houses nor churches. Con. W. M.—But don't you remember the admonition, "
                            Thou shalt not covet! Thou shalt not steal! " W. M.—Nonsense! Doesn't apply in this case at
                            all. The commandments only take effect on educated and Christian people who build churches.
                            Gosh ! You'll talk next about skunks having possessory rights. However, to satisfy your
                            scruples, we'll buy this country from the Indian. CHAPTER II. The bargain with the Indian
                            for his lands. Time 1700. i Parties — Deuteronomy Sharp and the drunken chief.
                            Rum-trim-to-tum. Deuteronomy Sharp reading—"And in consideration of one pint of New England
                            rum and a jack-knife, I, Rum-tum-to-tum, Great Chief of all the Rum-tum-to-tums,do hereby
                            convey,remise, release, sell,etc.,and cease all further claim on a certain strip of
                            territory known as North America, extending from a certain point up the coast as far as the
                            coast extends, to a certain point down the coast as far as the coast extends, and as far
                            north as it extends north, and as far south as the land extends south, and ditto east and
                            west, and as far back as the land may go." Deut.—There, Rum-tum-to-tum, put your totem down
                            there. Rum-tum, etc. — Gimme rum. Me lub rum. Deut.—No Rum-tum, etc. You must sign first.
                            Business is business, you know. Rum-tum, etc., makes his mark. Deut. (fervently).---He hath
                            delivered the land of the heathen unto us to possess with our wives and children forever.
                            CETEWAYO'S SENTIMENTS. I like your guns, said Cetewayo. I think if we could make such good
                            guns as yours we could also soon make as good a Bible. Missionary.—As good a Bible?
                            Cetewayo.—Yes. You see your Bible is elastic. It stretches so as to cover almost any thing
                            you want to do. For instance., you want my land. You look into your Bible. You find it
                            commands you to go abroad and preach the Gospel to every creature. If the creatures won't
                            hear you, you make them hear you with your guns. You take their lands. Then, of course, they
                            must hear your Gospel. You have the pleasure of converting them and getting their'land
                            besides. That is a good Bible. I wish I had such good guns. I would have such a Bible also.
                            Missionary. — Would you like to visit England, King? Cetewayo.—Can you roast me a whole ox
                            daily ? Missionary. — Well, King, the fact is we haven't got quite enough beef for our own
                            people. Still— <pb n="277" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 277 Cetewayo. — Why do you keep
                            so many more people than you can feed well? Why don't you kill the runts when they're first
                            born ? Missionary.—King, that is murder. Cetewayo.—So is slow starvation. I have heard that
                            many of your people don't get enough to eat. Missionary. — But, King, the commandment says—
                            Cetewayo.—Yes, yes. It says, thou shalt not covet thy neighbor's ox, nor his ass, nor his
                            lands. Thou shalt not steal. Thou art the man. Thou— Missionary.—Hold on, King. Cetewayo. —
                            I see you don't like having your guns turned on you. Then you know how well they shoot,
                            don't you ? Missionary.—But, King, you don't realize all the blessings of civilization. Why,
                            it gives us— Cetewayo. — Taxes. Does your civilization give every man a house and lot ?
                            Missionary.—Well, no. Cetewayo. — And three square meals a day ? Missionary. —Well—
                            Cetewayo. —-And pure air like ours in your six-story tenement pigeon-holes ?
                            Missionary.—Well— Cetewayo. — Does it teach you to stay at home, mind your business and not
                            molest jour neighbors ? Missionary.—Well— But, King, civilization has done one thing for us.
                            We never have but one wife. Cetewayo.—What ! Never ? Missionary.—Well, liar— But, King, we
                            don't keep harems in— Cetewayo. —Public? Methinks it has come to my ears that the son of
                            your queen — But he's a jolly good fellow. Were he but here I would make him a second
                            Solomon in wives and wisdom. But I want my fourteen wives for company. Is your one wife
                            always company for you ? Missionary.—Oh, certainly. Cetewayo.—Do you always stay at home
                            evenings? Never go to the club, or the lodge or have sudden business just after supper, eh?
                            Missionary.—Well— Cetewayo.—Well ? It seems to be all well with you. No, I don't like your
                            civilization. Tt talks nicely on paper and in the pulpit. No. The only man of your blood I
                            like is Dunn, John Dunn. You have done well in making him chief of that fine district. He
                            has made a law that no missionaries shall go there. John has done well. Missionary. —Verily,
                            the King's heart is hardened.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Little things" TEIform="index"/>LITTLE THINGS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allerton, Ellen P." TEIform="persName"/>ELLEN P. ALLERTON</byline><p TEIform="p">We call him strong who stands unmoved— Calm as some tempest beaten rock—¦ When some great
                            trouble hurls its shock ; We say of him, his strength is proved ; But when the spent storm
                            folds its wings, How bears he then Life's little things? About his brow we twine our wreath
                            Who seeks the battle's thickest smoke, Braves flashing gun and sabre-stroke, And scoffs at
                            danger, laughs at death ; We praise him till the whole land rings ; But—is he brave in
                            little things? We call him great who does some deed That echo bears from shore to
                            shore,—Does that, and then does nothing more ; Yet would his work earn richer meed, When
                            brought before the King of Kings, Were he but great in little things? We closely guard our
                            castle gates When great temptations loudly knock, Draw every bolt, clinch every lock, And
                            sternly fold our bars and gates ; Yet some small door wide open swings At the sly touch of
                            little things. I can forgive—'tis worth my while— The treacherous blow, the cruel thrust;
                            Can bless my foe as Christian must, While patience smiles her royal smile ; Yet quick
                            resentment fiercely slings . .. Its shots of ire at little things. And I can tread beneath
                            my feet The hills of Passion's heaving sea, When wind tossed waves roll stormily ; Yet
                            scarce resist the siren sweet That at my heart's door softly sings "Forget, forget Life's
                            little things." But what is Life? Drops make the sea ; And petty cares and small events,
                            Small causes and small consequents, Make up the sum for you and me; Then, 0 for strength to
                            meet the stings That arm the points of little things !</p></div2><pb n="278" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Consecreation to a godly use" TEIform="index"/>CONSECRATION TO A GODLY USE</head><p TEIform="p">Covenanta] and real members of the Shaker Church consecrate themselves, services and all they
                            have possessed or may possess to the cause of Christ, as stated in the following language:
                            •'By this covenant we do solemnly and conscientiously dedicate, devote, consecrate and
                            give^up ourselves and services, together with all our temporal interest, to the service of
                            God, and the support and benefit of the Church of this Community, and to such other pious
                            and charitable purposes as the Gospel may require." * * * And we do hereby solemnly agree to
                            support and maintain the true primitive faith and Christian princip * * * pertaining to the
                            said Gospel, as ministered by the founders of the society * * * . And consider and
                            acknowledge ourselves as members of one general community, possessing one faith, and subject
                            to one united parental and ministerial administration." It is quite plainly manifested that
                            there are two prominent worldly interests in which personal individual photographs play an
                            important part, first, conspicuous popularity, worldly ambition, pride and vanity ;
                            secondly, use in the police department for the detection of criminals. But, it is not so
                            manifest in what way the use of individual e personal photographs can be consecrated to th
                            service of God, the support and benefit of this community, and such other pious and
                            charitable purposes as the Gospel may require," according to the covenantal consecration
                            before mentioned. It is consequently to be anticipated that a personal vanity and ambition
                            for distinction and individual exaltation shall be swallowed up by that noble purpose, which
                            by consecrating all the powers, faculties and labors of the indiv idu covenant member to
                            swell the united capacity of the Chur Christ's Second Appearing, to set fore the world a
                            sacrifice of self-pride, ambition and interest for the manifestation of a character of
                            devotion to God's work so full and complete as to make of one brotherhood and sisterhood the
                            whole household of f aith, toiling together on the beautiful level of love, not each one
                            striving to be the greatest after the fashion of the children of this world. The procurement
                            and display of individual personal photographs which have been obtained by members of the
                            Shaker Community are, we believe, justly deemed to be' in contravention of the foregoing
                            covenantal principles, and of course, disapproved by the leading authorities of the Church
                            and religious Covenantal Association aforesaid. It is therefore desired and will be
                            anticipated by the aforesaid authorities, that the use and further procurement of personal
                            individual photographs will be entirely abandoned by every professed member of the aforesaid
                            society andcovenantal constitution. The Ministry and Elders of Mt. Lebanon Shaker Society,
                            N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Petition" TEIform="index"/>PETITION</head><p TEIform="p">[The following Petition we copy from the Truth Seeker. It contains so much of the good gospel
                            of humanity, human, kindness, and true, Godly theology, we are glad to make a copy of the
                            same, as putting the Shakers anew in their theological teachings before the world. Ed.]</p><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Letter to the President" TEIform="index"/>A LETTER, TO THE PRESIDENT. </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon, September 29, 1879" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.,
                                Sept. 29, 1879</dateline><p TEIform="p">To the Hon. Kutherford B. Hayes, President of the United States of North America :
                                Esteemed and Respected Friend—As the chief executive of one of the most powerful and
                                progressive nations of the earth, we come before you in the capacity of one of the first
                                leaders of the entire Shaker fraternity, to represent our people, as supplicants for the
                                administration of justice to a fellow man, as a first request. Second. As a defender of
                                the constitutional rights of the freedom of conscience. Third. The liberty of free
                                .speech. Fourth. The protection of the freedom of the press. Fifth. The sanctity of our
                                mails. Sixth. The honor of our nation in sustaining the rights of man, and liberty of
                                just trial by jury, untrammeled by judicial field-fencing, as a bias, except the
                                boundaries of law ; for all of which sig2?8 <pb n="279" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO.
                                nal blessings our forefathers pledged and gave their lives, fortunes and sacred honor !
                                We submit if the judicial trial of D. M. Bennett, editor of The Truth Seeker, by which
                                he was condemned to a felon's cell, was not one of the greatest farces, mockeries of
                                justice, and exhibitions of spleen, personal revenge, rine: influence, judicial
                                turpitude and cruelty that has been manifest in the Anglo-American nation during the
                                whole history of her national jurisprudence, or on any civilized nation's record since
                                the days of the nefarious Judge Jefferies, of the sixteenth century, under King James
                                II, of England—not allowed the civilized privilege of the audience of the testimony of
                                his witnesses ; not allowed the privilege of any common felon, even a murderer, when
                                sentenced by the court—to speak for himself, as was allowed to Paul by King Agrippa, and
                                to say why judgment should not be pronounced against him! Is not the whole transaction a
                                miserable stain on our statute books, and on our country's escutcheon, which it becomes
                                the imperative duty of our nation's chief executive to tender his protest to wipe out?
                                The Shakers—a sect of virgin celibate non-resistants, and a law-abiding people, whom we
                                now represent—desire the moral, social and physical protection of our nation by her
                                laws, and have full fellowship with well-defined, appropriate laws, for that object. But
                                we indignantly protest against the maladministration of law in the personal interest of
                                individual revenge, and the resort of blackmailing, immoral and unchristian strategy, to
                                entrap victims for legal vengeance and pecuniary gain ! We further submit if it is not
                                too much power to put into the grasp of any one individual, in a nation whose
                                Constitution is republican in principle, to make such individual censor of the mails,
                                and virtual arbiter of the character of our nation's circulating literature ; aye, even
                                more, of her conscientious rights ? If laws for the prevention of obscene literature
                                should exist, which we approve, should not the censorship of their supposed infractions
                                be delegated to a committee of at least five, or s6ven men, thus guarding against the
                                unjust and unchristian exercise of power, as in the Bennett case, of personal revenge ;
                                or, as in that of many other casesr manifest in the action of Comstock, as a means of
                                obtaining money by rewards for prosecution ? D. M. Bennett was reared among the Shakers,
                                was a goodly young man; left our ranks because he preferred a married life to virgin
                                celibacy. We have kept track of him since his exit from our society, and never have
                                learned of any wickedness or illegality in his conduct as judged by the moral law, since
                                he quit our ranks. Some heavy charges are recently published against him, concerning
                                which we know not the truth; but if true, they would not justly incarcerate him, unless
                                accompanied by many thousands and hundreds of thousands of others equally guilty. He is,
                                we believe, thoroughly infidel to the character of so-called Christianity, whose
                                theology makes the innocent Jesus to cruelly suffer death as a ransom from suffering—the
                                consequence of sin—for all of those who should but believe in his mission, and so are
                                all the Shakers. If he is worthy of incarceration for this, so are all our people. We
                                understand he is also infidel to God ! the God character represented by a large class of
                                professed Christians who believe Jesus to be one of three Gods in one—the Father of
                                whom, and of which trio, demanded the death of this son God, by the hands of wicked men,
                                whom He proposes to punish for executing His will in killing Him ! If he is infidel to a
                                belief in a Spirit Being, the Creative Power, and All-wise Planner and Director of the
                                universe, in the attributes of male and female, as Father and Mother of heaven and
                                earth, and all the innumerable spheres of immensity, we do not know it, and do not
                                fellowship it. We do not approve of the spirit and sentiment of many of Dr. D. M.
                                Bennett's writings and publications, we think him too caustic and unwise, and, in some
                                instances, calculated to do harm by infidelity to Christ. But, that he has done great
                                good, we also know; and to err is human ; no one is perfect. But enough ; if the
                                judiciary of our country, through the influence of a clergy who279- <pb n="280" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 280 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. are influencing, by every plausible and secret art, our
                                rulers, so as to obtain the authority to rule the State as well as church, are to
                                establish the resume of the Inquisition against the exercise of the liberty of
                                conscience, in this, our boasted land of freedom, to us, it seems the chief executive of
                                our nation has a duty to do toward its repression. In the interests of our
                                constitutional rights as American citizens, claiming liberty of conscience, and belief
                                according to weight of evidence, both in religion and law, we solicit the executive to
                                release from prison D. M. Bennett, not as a pardoned criminal, but as a subject of
                                personal revenge, clerical chicanery and judicial ring influence! We also solicit a
                                protest from the chief executive of the United States against the form of law, and the
                                maladministration of legal authority by which D. M. Bennett was incarcerated ; for by
                                similar reasons for which this act was done, infidelity to a large portion of so-called
                                Christian theology, and the subject of personal revenge, the whole Shaker fraternity, or
                                other theological sect differing from the popular strain, may be liable to arrest and
                                incarceration, and the way be hedged against the manifestation of increasing light and
                                truth, both in religion and science. And, as in duty bound, we will ever pray. Your
                                friend for the truth,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>Giles B. Avery</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Women to the front" TEIform="index"/>WOMEN TO THE FRONT</head><p TEIform="p">Not long ago, while traveling in New England, we noticed a strong, high gate standing alone
                            by the way-side. There was no wall nor fence near it, but still, well-bolted and barred, it
                            stood up strong and straight as though it was doing guard duty. There was no need now to
                            draw out the rusty bolts to admit the passer-by, as it was just as convenient to go around
                            as to pass through it. This reminded us of the ecclesiastical gate which has been so long
                            closed against women. It stands bolted and barred ; but the ecclesiastical fence is nearly
                            all down, and, at the command of the Master, Christian women may march into life's great
                            harvest-fields to work without disturbing the gate or the gate disturbing them. With an open
                            vineyard before them, the women of all denominations are marching out for Christian effort
                            as never before.— The Christian Woman.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Virgin celibacy—marriage" TEIform="index"/>VIRGIN CELIBACY—MARRIAGE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We have often alluded to the first above subject, as the great "rock of offense" to the
                                vast majority who deign to give Shakerisrn a moiety of their reflections. That the
                                Shakers are wonderfully blessed in basket and store, has drawn the envy of thousands who
                                wished this blessing for themselves, but who were unwilling to bear the Shaker cross to
                                possess it. To preserve for themselves the easements for the flesh which marriage
                                induces, the vast majority leave no text of the New Testament unturned which encourages
                                the thoughts that marriage may be classed as a Christian institution. To do this,
                                observe how the grand array of Pauline instructions are culled from his numerous
                                epistles to prove that marriage is Christian! AVe frankly admit, that were Paul the
                                founder and head of Christianity and not Jesus Christ, we should sit on the fence of
                                hesitancy, finding it difficult to decide which he approved most of—marriage or
                                celibacy. But acknowledging Jesus as Lord and Head of Christianity, there can be no
                                doubt about marriage being a worldly, not a Christian institution. "I am the
                                Resurrection and the Life," said Jesus Christ; and so far from representing the
                                Resurrection as being in a state of future existence, follows up the subject in that
                                "the children of the Resurrection"—my children, children of the Christ life—"neither
                                marry nor are given in marriage." To save marriage and its worldly affections to
                                themselves, the children of the world, desirous of being called %ftitwci%X. <pb n="281" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 281 Christians, put off the Resurrection until they
                                drop their earthly means of fleshly qualification and unchristian indulgences. But
                                "Follow Me;" "deny yourselves of what I have denied Myself !" are the ringing
                                instructions of Jesus Christ. Of Paul, who claimed, and did in his life "follow hard
                                after Jesus," we can only say that while many of his instructions were very favorable to
                                a Christian life, still he was erratic, and often instructed in a very unchristian
                                manner. How does Paul's assertions, " marriage is honorable in all," coincide with his
                                own life, and "I would that all men were like me ? " And Avhat shall we do with his
                                astounding assertions concerning those " who marry, caring how they may please each
                                other, and not how they may please the Lord; while a virgin life careth how it may
                                please the Lord?" It is reasonably stated that Jesus never forbade to marry and we
                                believe this, and any follower of Christ who forbids any who wish to marry from doing so
                                acts differently from Christ. For the Shakers, we boldly state that they never "forbade
                                to marry," to those who wished an honorable worldly life and not Christ's life. It must,
                                however, be admitted that Jesus selected for his disciples those who would " hate
                                husband and wife" relations, and even their worldly "lives" also. To hate these, did
                                not, does not necessitate the hating of men and women as virgin brethren and sisters in
                                Christ, as was Christ ; but to hate the husband and the wife while ive love the brother
                                and the sister. We accept the life of Christ—the resurrected life he exhibited above the
                                world, and wherein he was " lifted up "—to be the life for Christians to live. We admire
                                the success which Paul attained in so fully representing in his life the life of Jesus;
                                and we honor him for his radical Christian testimony favoring the life resurrected above
                                marriage to all, excepting "foolish G-alatians" and "carnal Corinthians," to whom he
                                gave instructions : " To avoid fornication and adultery;" to prevent burning in their
                                lusts. "Let every such man have a wife and every such woman a husband," for they are as
                                yet very unready to adopt the Christ life! That earnest thinker, Henry C. Wright, said:
                                " I do not see how any believer in the New Testament can come to any other conclusion
                                upon marriage than that to which the Shakers have arrived; nor do I see how any believer
                                in the Old Testament can come to any other conclusion than that of the Mormons!" And
                                then sums up the subject, and in which summing up he has a numerous sympathy, "' both
                                are monstrosities to me!" We have written sufficiently to arouse renewed thought upon
                                the subject, and will close with the valuable testimony of the Rev. Dr. Bolles, who in
                                his book, "Holy Matrimony, "after extolling the beauties of marriage as few others could
                                do or have ever done, sums up the subject thus admirably and acceptably; and in the face
                                of all human inclinations, none would write thus were it not true: " But is there not a
                                higher life revealed in the Scriptures than even the holy state of matrimony—a life by
                                which an individual may voluntarily forego all the blessings of the mystery of marriage,
                                in order to become more and more absorbed in devotion to the duties of the Spiritual
                                union of Christ <pb n="282" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. and the Church—a life in
                                which the love of the antitype may be ever so great as to banish from the mind all
                                thought of the type— concentrating all the affections of the soul vpon the reality of
                                the substance—a life so entirely free from the temporal, with all its joys, cares and
                                entanglements, as to see nothing, to think of nothing but the eternal— Christ Himself
                                and the fruition of his glorious Godhead? How can it be denied that the scriptures do
                                reveal to us the possibility of such a life ? and that it is the life of the celibate "
                                for the kingdom of heaven's sake, —not the life of the mere unmarried, which in itself
                                considered is one of themost selfish of all lives, and which is not unfrequently chosen
                                for the sake of selfish and criminal indulgence, but the. life of the celibate ' for the
                                kingdom of heaven's sake.' Our blessed Lord said, indeed, ' all men cannot receive this
                                saying, save they to whom it is given ; but he that is able to receive it, let him
                                receive it.' "</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our peculiarity" TEIform="index"/>OUR PECULIARITY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">That the Shakers started in the Avorld with any ambition to appear eccentric, we do not
                                believe. That the converts imbibed principles that caused " a change of heart." to live
                                differently, apart from worldly fashion, fleshly lusts, and away, even from the
                                gratifications of much worldly good, we believe and know. At the beginning they dressed
                                as was the custom, and declined from principle to engage in the changing fashions of
                                following time. In this they were wise and truly religions. At several periods of
                                fashion's market, the dress of the world has very closely returned to " Shaker Styles."
                                We honor our forefathers and foremothers, not for any especially grotesque eccentricity
                                nor purposed oddity of dress, but for their inclination and persistence, even to
                                pertinacity to wear a, plain, comfortable, economical and comely divss. We hope all of
                                these points will be held closely to in the future, and we believe they will be fully as
                                operative in the years to come as in the past, even amid the many innovations now being
                                introduced in the way of dress. Oddity and eccentricity may be and will be cast out; but
                                the essentials, plainness and comeliness will be adhered to. But it must be seen that on
                                mere matters of dress, we are dealing with the comparatively non-essential features of a
                                peculiarly Christian life. Purity, extreme purity of life, with honesty of word and
                                manufactures must claim precedence always, and these must exceed the righteousness of
                                Methodist and Roman Catholics, or what, or wherein can there be a desired peculiarity ?
                                Among our most valuable exchanges, Ave prize very highly The Primitive Christian, one of
                                the advocates of the Tunker Church, and it has the following upon this "peculiar "
                                subject. While you read, brethren, think whether we, as a peculiar people, cannot be
                                reminded of a dutiful lesson : WE OUGHT TO BE A PECULIAR PEOPLE. It is said that the
                                Brethren are losing many of the peculiarities that formerly distinguished them from
                                other people, especially that of dress. Now while we believe that we should be
                                distinguished in this respect from the vain fashion worshiper, we also believe that we
                                should be a peculiar people in other things as well. We fear that we are losing our
                                peculiarities in some other things as much as that of apparel. How is it about our
                                honesty ? The time was when a brother's word was as goo4 as his note, but is not our
                                reputation wanting ? Are we as peculiar in this respect as we were years ago ? We
                                believe this matter is too much overlooked and that we have much cause to fear that we
                                are losing the distinguishing characteristic of honesty. Our ministers preach 282 <pb n="283" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 283 a great deal against pride and display
                                in dress, indeed some hardly ever preach but what this subject comes in, and would it
                                not be well to show up the evils of carelessness and recklessness in business a little
                                more. Brethren, in their aspirations to become rich, rush headlong into debt and as a
                                result, they have not, in some instances, been able to meet their Christian influence
                                which they are exerting'.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Civilization by the sword!" TEIform="index"/>CIVILIZATION BY THE SWORD!</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Of The Yates Co. Chronicle wo have had many good words to say; but when it imparts so
                                reprehensible a doctrine as '"The civilization of Africa even by means of the sword
                                which so often affords the only means of opening a way into barbaric regions, is a thing
                                to be hoped for!" then we object very strongly to its religious influences. It is too
                                late in the day for editors of moral and religious periodicals, and certainly too late
                                for socalled ministers of the gospel, to make appeals to the sword for aid, in extending
                                civilization or religion. Already we hear from the highest representations of civil and
                                military circles ¦extensive deprecations concerning weapons of warfare. Let not these
                                chieftains excel in advocacy of arbitration and peace ! When has the sword succeeded ?
                                To that grand old historical character, Wra, Penn, let us look for the brightest, best,
                                and ever and only successful means of civilization ever known. Pay for what you want,
                                when the owners are ready to sell: and after offering every inducement, wait until they
                                are ready. See the foolishness of N. 0. Meeker of forcing Indians to use the plough!
                                Muskets on one side, ploughs on the others, and then a raid upon their limiting grounds
                                and customs ! Meeker invited his slaughter ; and because of his massacre, when attacking
                                the rights of the Indians, his daughter exhibits an insight to her training, by calling
                                on the IT. S. government to "exterminate the race, for all the red skins extant are not
                                worth one white man." If so her father thought, and he acted so, he only received the
                                effects of which he alone was the cause. According to the statement of an Indian chief,
                                to the writer of this, Indians never fought with each other, nor the whites, until
                                incited to do so by the aggressions of white men. Let us use heathens and Indians with
                                kindness and humanity; and every experience of the past is declarative of there being an
                                excess of such compliments returned by them.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Glorious Christmas to all" TEIform="index"/>A GLORIOUS CHRISTMAS TO ALL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Elsewhere, our dear readers will find in what Christmas has a significance among the
                                Shakers. We as editor and publisher Avant to wish a hearty happiness to all, onv readers
                                in particular, upon that day and ever afterward. We do not believe in any happiness
                                without a corresponding goodness; and if able to be better than good, we promise an
                                increase of godly and everlasting happiness. Dear readers all: It has been solely our
                                object, in issuing our Manifesto, to give to all the key to an eternal, heavenly
                                Christmas; and none are more aware than are we, of the tremendous amount of the most
                                godly self-denial which superior goodness imposes. That we may continue to be your
                                humble servants another year successfully, aid us. Renew your subscriptions <pb n="284" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 284 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. promptly, for you all know that it costs money
                                to issue so many copies monthly, and that we do get out for your edification a nice
                                paper, and one that costs you but little in comparison with its good intentions. Now,
                                please renew, and may God bless yon if you do, and if you don't, may God remember, and
                                bless us.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">In the matter under this heading for this issue, we are pleased to present much valuable
                                material for thought and information. Elder F. W. Evans has long been a faithful
                                follower, and living exponent of the Christ Spirit. When he writes from experience, and
                                what he writes, all may place implicit reliance upon. Once a radical materialist,
                                talented so as to lead therein, yet stopped on the way to his Damascus by Shaker
                                Spiritualism which blinded him to all further materialistic efforts, he chose "the
                                better way," and obedience thereto gives him in his ripe life a peculiar significance as
                                a counselor. " Hear him !"</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Weed, Parsons &amp; Co." TEIform="index"/>WEED, PARSONS &amp; CO.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">To whom these presents shall come : Be it known unto all men, and women too, that Weed,
                                Parsons &amp; Co., Albany, N. Y., are the very best Printers, Binders, Stereotypers
                                and Electrotypers in the New World. Bear this in mind, and send to them or us for bids
                                for the best work at the most reasonable rates. We indorse this firm for excellence of
                                work and for moderate and reasonable charges.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Who is Christ?" TEIform="index"/>WHO IS CHRIST ?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The sermon of On under Sen", which was preached in India, we present with great pleasure
                                to our readers. To those who will attentively read its substance, we need not apologize
                                for the space it occupies. It is one of the most remarkable utterances of the times ;
                                and is certainly the most Godsend to the religious world at large of any subject we know
                                of. Treating the query as it does, coming whence it does, and being indorsed by so many
                                prominent periodicals—The Christian Union for instance— we must say we feel the Church
                                Universal to be nearer the present than ever before. Christ, and the life of Christ, are
                                foundation and Cap-stone of the union of Churches ; and just so soon as we accept
                                Christ's life as the best ensample and religiously and faithfully live it, every barrier
                                to the success of the Universal Church will be removed* Then will we have but " one
                                Lord, one faith, and one baptism; " and then will our missionaries, sent abroad, carry
                                in their lives the pattern Christ lived, and only then be worthy rivals of Chunder tien;
                                but when will they teach Christ by living Christ's life ?</p></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="There is, too often, a burden of care in getting riches..." TEIform="index"/>There is, too often, a burden of care in getting riches...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">There is, too often, a burden of care in getting riches, a burden of anxiety in keeping them,
                            a burden of temptation in using them, a burden of guilt in abusing them, a burden of sorrow
                            in losing them, and a burden of account at last to be given up for possessing and either
                            improving or misimproving them.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is they who glorify Him who shall enjoy Him..." TEIform="index"/>It is they who glorify Him who shall enjoy Him...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">It is they wlio glorify Him wlio shall enjoy Him ; tliey who deny themselves who shall not be
                            denied; they who labor on earth who shall rest in heaven ; they who bear the cross shall
                            wear the crown; they who seek to bless others who shall be blessed.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Guthrie, [Dr.]" TEIform="persName"/>Dr. Guthrie</byline></div2><pb n="285" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>The Children's Grotto</head><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Learn a little every day" TEIform="index"/>LEARN A LITTLE EVERY DAY</head><p TEIform="p">Little rills make wider streamlets, Streamlets swell the river's flow ; Rivers join the
                                ocean billows, Onward, onward as they go! Life is made of smallest fragments, Shade and
                                sunshine, work and play, So may we, with greatest profit, Learn a little every day. Tiny
                                seeds make boundless harvests, Drops of rain compose the showers, Seconds make the
                                flying minutes, Minutes make the joyous hours ! Let us hasten then, and catch them, As
                                they pass us on our way; And with honest true endeavor Learn a little every day. Let us
                                read some striking passage, Cull a verse from every page, Here a line, and there a
                                sentence, 'Gainst the lonely time of age ! At our work, or by the wayside, While the sun
                                shines, making hay ; Thus we may, by help of Heaven, Learn a little every day.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Be kind to the sisters" TEIform="index"/>BE KIND TO THE SISTERS</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Boys, be kind to the sisters. You may live to be old, and never find such
                                        tender, loving friends as these sisters. Think how many things they do for you;
                                        how patient they are with you ; how they love you in spite of all your
                                        ill-temper or rudeness ; how thoughtful they are for your comfort, and be you
                                        thoughtful for theirs. Be ever ready to oblige them, to perform any little
                                        office for them that lies in your power Think what you can do for them, and if
                                        they express a wish, be ready to gratify it, if possible. You do not know how
                                        much happiness you will find in so doing. I never yet knew a happy and respected
                                        man who was not in youth kind to his sisters. There is a beautiful song which
                                        says : Be kind to your sister—not many may know The depth of true sisterly love
                                        ; The wealth of the ocean lies fathoms below The surface that sparkles above.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Brethren's advocate" TEIform="index"/>Brethren's Advocate.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nobody has a right to put another under such a difficulty that..." TEIform="index"/>Nobody has a right to put another under such a difficulty that...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Nobody has a right to put another under such a difficulty that he must either hurt the
                                person by telling the truth, or hurt himself by telling what is not true.</p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Youthful sins" TEIform="index"/>YOUTHFUL SINS</head><p TEIform="p">The late Dr. Spencer said that when he was a lad, his father gave him a little tree that
                                had just been grafted. One day, in his father's absence, he let the colt into the
                                garden, and the young animal broke off the graft. It was mended, however, on the
                                following day, and continued to grow finely. Years passed, and young Spencer became a
                                man and a minister. Some time after he became a pastor he made a visit to the old
                                homestead, where he spent his boyhood. His little sapling had become a large tree, and
                                was loaded with apples. During the night after his arrival at the homestead, there was a
                                violent thunder-shower, and the wind blew fearfully. He rose early in the morning, and
                                on going out found his tree lying prostrate upon the ground. The wind had twisted it off
                                just where the colt broke it when it was a sapling. Probably the storm would not have
                                broken it at all, if it had not been broken when it was small.</p></div3><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Write to us, children" TEIform="index"/>WRITE TO US, CHILDREN</head><p TEIform="p">We are certain that did our dear children know how much comfort we would derive from
                                receiving some letters from them, they would want to send us a great many. In the coming
                                new year, we hope to get many such. Even if they are short and imperfectly written, do
                                not neglect to let us hear from you. In love from</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/>Ed. Manifesto</byline></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I heard two little girls talking under my window" TEIform="index"/>I heard two little girls talking under my window
                            </head><p TEIform="p">I heard two little girls talking under my window. One of them said, in a voice full of
                                indignation :—" If I were in your place, I'd never speak to her again; I'd be angry with
                                her as long as I lived." I listened, feeling anxious about the reply. My heart beat more
                                lightly when it came. " No, Lou," answered the other, in a sweet and gentle voice ; " I
                                wouldn't do so for all the world. I am going to forgive and forget just as soon as I
                                can."</p></div3></div2><pb n="286" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Seeds" TEIform="index"/>SEEDS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Reed, C. G." TEIform="persName"/>C. G. Reed</byline><p TEIform="p">1. We are sowing, daily sowing Countless seeds of good or ill, 2. Seeds that fall amid the
                            stillness, Of the lonely mountain glen, 3. Seeds that lie unchanged unquickened, Lifeless on
                            the teeming mould, 4. Thou who knowest all our weakness, Leave us not to sow alone! 5. Check
                            the froward tho'ts and passions, Stay the hasty, heedless hands, Scattered on the level
                            lowland, Cast upon the windy hill: Seeds cast out in crowded places, Trodden under foot of
                            men; Seeds that live and grow and flourish, When the sowers hand is cold; Bid thine angels
                            guard the furrows, Where the precious grain is sown; Lest the germs of sin and sorrow, Mar
                            our fair and pleasant lands. Seeds that sink in rich brown furrows, Soft with heavens
                            gracious rain; Seeds by idle hearts forgotten, Flung at random on the air; By a whisper, sow
                            we blessings, By a breath, we scatter strife; Till the fields are crowned with glory; Filled
                            with mellow, ripened ears Father, help each weak endeavor; Make each faithful effort blest;
                            Seeds that rest upon the surface, Of the dry unyielding plain. Seeds by faithful souls
                            remembered, Sown in tears and love and prayer. In our words and looks and actions, Lie the
                            seeds of death and life. Filled with fruit of life eternal, From the seed we sowed in tears.
                            Till Thine harvest shall be garnered, And we enter into rest.</p></div2><pb n="287" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Henry Kiddle, A. M. Dear Friend: We have just returned from our morning meeting..." TEIform="index"/>Henry Kiddle, A. M. Dear Friend: We have just returned from our morning meeting...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon, November 14, 1879" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, Nov. 14, 1879</dateline><p TEIform="p">Henry Kiddle, A. M. Dear Friend: We have just returned from our morning meeting, where we
                                read to our family of sixty people, your lecture in Brooklyn. I have never had the
                                pleasure of your acquaintance, personally, but know you by .my friend, and your friend,
                                Wickham, ex-mayor of New York. 1 have received, through him, a copy of your " Future
                                Life." Am much interested in it — still more interested in its author. We live in
                                stirring times. A Judgment day is upon Christendom. It began at the House of God, the
                                fountain of modern Spiritualism, the Shaker Order. I, too, once lived in New York. I was
                                a young man, but a confirmed materialist; also a communist. Humanity was all the God I
                                acknowledged. In 1830, visiting the Shakers, I found, in practical operation, principles
                                of equality and justice that we, as Infidels, had failed to actualize,—a Brotherhood and
                                Sisterhood, claiming to be the result of Spiritualism. By instruction from Spirits, a
                                woman, who could neither write nor read, established justice, where the wise and prudent
                                had failed. Ann Lee said she communed with five souls out of the body, where she did
                                with one in the earth-life. Two extremes—credulity and incredulity, faith and unbelief,
                                Spiritualism and Materialism, met together. After being here a few days, I began to
                                receive Spiritual ministrations in evidence of Immortality, and of intercommunication of
                                souls in and out of the body. These continued until I became satisfied. Prom that time I
                                have been a Spiritualist. I have seen the old Babel system of Christendom gradually and
                                rapidly breaking up. The old heavens are passing away, and New Heavens are creating. Old
                                Church and State Government must come to an end. Zulu wars, Irish and English domestic
                                troubles, Indian wars and Russian barbarities are products of false theologies. " Behold
                                I create all things new, " good and true. Spiritualism is the disintegrating element
                                that will bring the old world to an end. Out of the material of the past, the future
                                will be organized. Religion will be the cementing bond of union, gathering all things in
                                heaven and earth into one. God is Male and Female, Wisdom and Love, combined. Love
                                worketh no ill to her neighbor. Live and let live; enjoy and let others enjoy life and
                                its blessings. Why not? Why should I seek happiness at the expense of others, who desire
                                happiness as I desire it ? Dear Friend, I hail you as one of nature's noblemen. Heaven
                                bless you in standing for the right. Come and visit Mt. Lebanon. Judge Edmunds and
                                Bishop Hughes came to see us. We had good times and the sweet communion of saints.
                                Farewell,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Book Table</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ghosts" TEIform="index"/></head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ingersoll, Robert" TEIform="persName"/>Robt. Ingersoll</byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">The Ghosts, and other Lectures by Robt. Ingersoll, C. P. Farrell, Washington, D. C,
                                Publisher. In this book we have the embodied ideas of the most prominent materialist in
                                America—a noble man, a loving soul, nevertheless a man whom Alexander Clark loved
                                because there was much to love there; and in this book we find no hate, no malice, much
                                love and much good religion, Christian religion, but not such as is found in popular
                                churches, but a better theology, ana one more reasonably accepted than can there be
                                found. "Bob" Ingersoll is a Shaker after a certain type, for he is shaking Babylon
                                tremendously, and we gratefully acknowledge his tremendous work of iconoclasm, and would
                                follow him up with a genuine Christianity, Shakerism, for which we think he leaves in
                                The Ghosts, a fertile field. Remember November's offer of the Country Gentleman—the best
                                farm and garden paper extant; and now read carefully our offer connected with the very
                                valuable Scientific American. <pb n="288" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/> 288 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. We have
                                received from A. M. Purdy, of Palmyra, N. Y., a very interesting 16 page pamphlet,
                                telling how to grow small fruits successfully, describing sorts, etc., etc. He sends it
                                free to all applicants, as also a specimen copy of his monthly paper of fruits and
                                flowers. Those desirous of the newsiest paper at the Capital of the Empire State, and
                                one filled with the ardent patriotism that both made and saved our beloved country, will
                                send for The Morning Express, Albany, N. Y. To those desiring more extensive knowledge
                                of Shaker Theology, Elder John Whiteley offers the " Shaker Manifesto " for 1880, and an
                                Octavo tract of 20 or 24 pages, entitled " Divine Afflatus " to any and all persons who
                                will send him 60 cents each. Address, John Whiteley, Ayer, Mass. Read on cover of The
                                Manifesto the valuable " Contents" of Elder H. L. Eads' new book entitled '' Shaker
                                Theology." Every one interested in the subject will gladly pay its cost of One Dollar to
                                possess it, because "it will pay" to do so.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deceased</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Summerfield, Henry" TEIform="index"/>Henry Summerfield
                                </head><p TEIform="p">At North Union, O., Sept. 29, <persName reg="Summerfield, Henry" TEIform="persName">Henry
                                    Summerfield</persName>, aged 70 years.</p></div4></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">Received. From Abraham Perkins, $32.00. And we hope, still, from others of the
                                brotherhood, to enable us to close the year's accounts with honor.</p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head">George Washington, 'the father of his country'...</head><p TEIform="p">George Washington, "the father of his country," publicly stated that—" The United States
                                is not a Christian nation any more than it is a Jewish nor a Mohammedan nation ; it has
                                no religion established by law, and all religions are upon a perfect equality before the
                                constitution and laws of the country."</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>Home Topics</head><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to kill insects" TEIform="index"/>How to kill insects
                            </head><p TEIform="p">How to kill Insects. — A Michigan lady writes, that to kill insects she uses one
                                teaspoonful of kerosene to a gallon of water, and sprinkles it on the plants with a
                                handbroom. It destroys green flies, currant worms and other pests, and was used without
                                injury on Fuchsias, Geraniums, Callas, and other plants. But it must be used with care.
                            </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bed bugs" TEIform="index"/>Bed bugs
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Bed bugs.— I see frequent inquiry as to the readiest manner of getting quit of the
                                presence of this pest. A safe, sure and proved way in our family is to get a cup full of
                                fine table salt and fill every joint, opening, crack or crevice with the dry, fine salt,
                                even under the extremities of the laths scattering very profusely, and keep it so, and
                                your tormentors will very soon be finished without the use of any violent poison. — Com.
                            </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To remove grease" TEIform="index"/>To remove grease
                            </head><p TEIform="p">To remove Grease.— The collars of coats become soiled very quickly from contact with
                                hair, but chloroform will clean them very well without "any bad odor. Potato starch
                                water, made by grating potatoes in a little water and letting it settle, then pouring it
                                off and rubbing it with a sponge, will also take off the grease and spots. Ammonia in
                                water rubbed on with a flannel or sponge will answer the purpose. In all cases brush
                                thoroughly in the first place. To remove grease from carpets and restore colors, take a
                                handful of crushed soap bark (quillaqa) to a pail of water. Scrub the spots and sponge
                                the carpets all over. </p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Celery for rheumatism" TEIform="index"/>Celery for rheumatism
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Celery for Rheumatism. — Celery cooked is a very fine dish, both as nutriment and as a
                                purifier of the blood. Rheumatism is impossible on such diet. Cold or damp never
                                produces rheumatism, but simply develops it. The acid blood is the primary cause, and
                                sustaining power of evil. While the blood is alkaline, there can be no rheumatism, and
                                equally no gout. Cut the celery into inch dice ; boil in water until soft. No water must
                                be poured away unless drunk by the invalid. Then take new milk, slightly thicken with
                                flour, and flavor with nutmeg ; serve up with diamonds of toasted bread round dish, and
                                eat with potatoes.</p></div3></div2><!--
                    <pb id="p29"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>