<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm0808" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title><editor role="editor" TEIform="editor"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/></editor></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">36</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">N. A. Briggs</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">8</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">8</biblScope><date value="18780801" TEIform="date">August 1878</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">180-209</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="8" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="8" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--                <pb id="p1"/>
                        <p>Vol. VIII. NO. 8. AUGUST. 60 Cts. per Annum, POST PAID. MANIFESTO ('OFFICIAL MONTHLY.) ~ PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED
                        SOCIETIES. * OUR HOME AT SHIRLEY, MASS. "GO PREACH THE KINGDOM OF GOD." 1878. PUBLISHED AND PRINTED AT SHAKER
                        VILLAGE, N. H. N. A. BRIGGS, Publisher. THE SHAKER</p>
                    <p>CONTENTS. Prospective 181 The Shaker Manifesto :—The Best Children 182 Religion 191 Let the Churches be converted -
                        182 Shakerism Pre-eminent 193 Prayer 183 Editorial Notes 194 Indians No. 6 183 Correspondence 195 Relaxation vs
                        Dissipation 185 For the children 197 Self Abnegation 186 Types of Christ 200 Experience of Oassandatia Brewster, of
                        The Essential 208 Hancock, Mass., ag>xl 8G years 188 Obituary 209 Chemistry of Bread Makinsr 188 TERMS OF
                        ADVERTISING. For' one inch, one insertion $ 1. 00 " one half column, " $ 3. 00 one " " " $ 6. .00 * page, ". " ¦
                        $12.00 Continued insertion for three months, 20 per ct. discount. " six " 25 " , " " one year, 33J " "
                        Subscriptions, Sixty cants, per year. Address, N. A. Briggs, ' Shaker Village, Mer. Co., N. H. Subscription win
                        begin when order is received.—No back numbers. </p>
                        --><pb n="180" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notice" TEIform="index"/>NOTICE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We hope every one wilf.bear in mind,' when inviting Bro. J...M. Peebles to visit, and to speak to them, to
                            accompany the invitation with the necessary means to travel in iransitu. He labors for the good of souls. But he
                            cannoteat souls; nor will these be accepted as railroad fares; and if they could be eaten or pass current, it
                            would take so many of a certain class for meals and change, .that other food and currency are much more
                            desirable.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Types of Christ" TEIform="index"/>"TYPES OF CHRIST"</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> While presenting other valuable materia for the enlightenment and encouragement of all traveling Zionward, this
                            number of "the manifesto may be truly denominated "tub typks of ciirist number." The paper contributed by Elder
                            Eades is a yaluable one, even if it should not prove positively invaluable. Let the " Types of Christ Number"
                            have an extensive circulation, and invite the deepest, kindliest thought.</p></div2><pb n="182" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Perspective" TEIform="index"/>PROSPECTIVE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName">MARTHA J. ANDERSON</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">We've left the shells by the seashore Gathered in childhood's glee, The blossoms of youth are withered And
                            scattered over the lea; And the sands of life are flowing Steadily one by one Like the spiral circling hours ,
                            That pass from sun to sun. Only a few dark shadows Upon our way will fall, Only a few more sunbeams To duty's
                            path will call, Ere the feet shall cease from straying, The eye will dim and fade, And the form with life
                            pulsating In earth be lifeless laid. O the change is coming o'er us! Yet we think not of it now, When the flush
                            of health is on our cheek, And light plays round our brow, When footsteps tell of vigor, And the heart beats
                            free from care, And hands in present duty Are strong to do and bear. Yet anon as years roll o'er us, And the
                            vital tide runs low, When the fires that burned with brightness Emit no fervid glow; Tis then in our quiet
                            hours, In the calm deep realm of thought New scenes of change and action Before the mind are brought. Though
                            memories round us gather, With shades of life's ideal, And things we loved and cherished— That seemed so true
                            and real— Are gliding like phantoms ever To silence and decay, The treasured gain of the spirit Will never pass
                            away. How broad are the fields of progress That open to our view, With the work of life immortal That's given us
                            yet to do; And we feel a noble impulse Thrilling the mind and heart, Giving us strength of purpose, To act the
                            Christian's part. O what is time to the spirit? Eternity just begun; And our footsteps here are few compared To
                            the race we yet shall run; For mortal man as the flower that fadoa, Or grass that quickly dies Shall from
                            evolving elements In form superior rise. Rise to behold the glorious dawn Of truth's unfading light, Casting
                            aside the vail that screens The future from our sight, Reading with open vision then What now mysterious seems;
                            Waking to life's realities, The substance of our dreams. Viewing in clear portrayal The record we have made
                            Without a mask to cover Earth deeds of light or shade; <pb n="182" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 182 THE SHAKBE MANIFESTO. For back
                            of the soul's camera Imaged in forms complete The truth is photographing Scenes that we yet shall meet. Then let
                            us live so truly With honest heart and aim, With purpose pure and lofty, Above gross deeds of shame, That no
                            vain reputation As counterfeit shall pass ; But character refined shall stand As on a sea of glass. Then will
                            the future brighten, And the present glad appear, Free from the clouds that gather In sin's dark atmosphere;
                            Then we shall sing in triumph The song of the ransomed free, As the golden gates are opened To immortality. Aft.
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Children" TEIform="index"/>CHILDREN</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName">ELDER F. W. EVANS</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">The class of invited guests, to the feast when the first and second appearing of Christ were united in marriage,
                            received a blessing upon themselves and children. . Those children constituted the second class of invited
                            guests. They, generally, made Believers. The third class, from the highways and hedges—the debris of
                            society—were compelled, by poverty and destitution to come into Shaker societies. This class have, almost
                            universally, gravitated back to the world. A few, of each company of such children, remain as a seed of the
                            future. In the now opening cycle, a class of adults, similar to the first invited, will be called. They are
                            growing up to the Gospel-ripening, like a field of grain for harvest. She, who sitteth upon the white cloud of
                            witnesses, will thrust in her sickle and reap them from earth. Hereafter, when children are taken by Be-
                            lieversj they should be sound in body, bright in intellect, religiously educated and of good parentage. Brought
                            up in the way they should go, when they become men and women, they will not depart therefrom—They will be
                            pillars in the temple of the Lord. Those, who go out, after having had a Gospel privilege, do not lose their
                            faith, but are ministers of it, to the poor in spirit—Their sounding testimony and witness has gone into all the
                            world. A Shaker Society is, to such, as Paradise, from whence they are cast out. They have regretful hearts,
                            and, while wandering in the desert of evil—the wilderness of sin— look, with longing eyes, towards their lost
                            heaven. Oft come their children, with bended knee and humble heart, to those whom their parents forsook, and, at
                            times, persecuted. "0 glorious hope of immortal life! Its blessed joys I am sharing, With zeal renewed, in the
                            upward strife, My spirit for heaven preparing. The Angels of God hover o'er me, While running the heavenly race,
                            And their love, like a shadow of glory, Rests over this hallowed place"—Where self is sacrificed to truth and
                            the Spiritual supplants the natural—Children of the Resurrection. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let the churches be converted" TEIform="index"/>Let The Churches Be Converted</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Andrews, Watson" TEIform="persName">WATSON ANDREWS</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">Improved theories are at the base of all religious progress. What has been done in the improved machinery of
                            transit, commerce and agriculture, are only comparisons to the new and better modes of thought concerning
                            religion. The preacher who proclaims the doctrines of even five hundred years ago, unmingled with a larger
                            amount of modern, progressive thought, has a good deal of the mummy about him; and is so far as he relies upon
                            the inspirations of the past, unfitted as a living preacher of the present. And there are too many like this.
                            All around us, and for thousands of years past, the race has needed, but has not realized, present ialvation
                            from sin. The long-talked of millennium has ever been in the future. War has not ceased, but has improved
                                pros-<pb n="183" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER M_AJSTi:ffvESrrO. 183 pects; outrageous crimes stalk abroad in the
                            land by daylight, in excess of darker ages. The civil governments have done more for the comfort and progress of
                            the race, than all the mouldy theologies of the past. These dissipated the Inguisition; emancipated serfs and
                            slaves; encouraged literature, arts, science and agriculture ; and invariably have had to beat back opposition
                            from the so-called religious elements, which ever have been tenacious of the pet theory that the world stood
                            still! Let the world change its theologies; so that men will not be the slaves of lusts, pride, unholy
                            ambitions, fraud, violence and self-seekers. The religious theologies of thousands of years have not improved
                            men. Let the churches of today, in the face of the facts, experience the religion of Christianity ; be- come
                            manumitted from external and internal, worldy passions, and realize, that the Christ with us today, if with us,
                            is as capable for present salvation from our sins of the flesh as ever in the past. North Union, Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prayer" TEIform="index"/>PRAYER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName">DANIEL ORCUTT</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">Prayer is the earnest desire of the heart, ascending to God, the Author of life, and the Giver of all blessings.
                            Our first thought, in the morning, should be a prayer of thankfulness to God, for His watchful care over us ;
                            and through the day, our spirits should breathe forth holy desires, "on wings of prayer." And when night veils
                            the earth, then, too, let us raise our voices in supplication, and commit all our burdens to One, who hath
                            promised to sustain those who trust in Him. We can never pray too often, "Leave us not in temptation, but
                            deliver us from evil." "Watch and pray that ye enter not into temptation," was the wise command of our savior.
                            His whole life, from childhood to the cross, was constant prayer ; and shall we not imitate Him, by putting on
                            the whole armor of righteousness, which will alone be our safeguard ? Oft may our bark be tempest-tossed, but we
                            need not fear; He who "doeth all things well," is at the helm, and will guide the faithful, over the sea of
                            danger, to the desired haven. Have you never watched till you saw the first bright star shine through a dark
                            cloud? prayer and watchfulness, which is the armor for the battle of life, will surely bring in sight the star
                            of hope, dispelling the clouds of sorrow and gloom. Enfield, Gt,</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Indians, no. 6" TEIform="index"/>INDIANS. No. 6</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescott, James S." TEIform="persName">JAMES S. PRESCOTT</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">The Indians admit that they have some bad cases in every tribe ; and these bad Indians are made no better by
                            associating with the lawless whites, but rather made worse, and these would be given up to be punished according
                            to law, if tried and found guilty without going to war, if the whites would take the proper course in giving
                            them time and using a suitable degree of moderation. But why we would ask should a whole tribe be
                            killed,—indiscriminately slaughtered—because of the acts and doings of one bad Indian, or even half a dozen ?
                            Where is the justice in this? It is a poor rule that will not work both ways. We might ask how would the whites
                            }ike to have the population of a whole township killed, because of the acts and doings of one bad white man, or
                            half a dozen border ruffians ?<pb n="184" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 184 THE SHAKER Who among the free born citizens of the U. S.
                            would be willing to take the place of the Indians and be treated as they are treated by the . overpowering
                            whites? Not one! Therefore, "All things whatsoever ye would that men should do unto you, do ye even so unto
                            them, for this is the law and the prophets." This is a universal law which meets with a response in every man's
                            mind, saying, "that's right! do as you would be done by that's my religion !" any religion that does not embrace
                            this rule, practically, is not worth having. The Indians knoiv that they stand a poor chance to cope with the
                            white men in war, on account of superiority in numbers, arms, ammunition, and in all the im- provements and
                            tactics of modern warfare. But, what have the Indians left? The following is from the spirit communication of
                            Tecumwega, continued : "Four millions of the African race liberated from slavery was indeed one of the noblest
                            acts you have on the annals of history. But to think that the Indian, a poor ignorant native of the soil, an
                            inhabitant of the continent when discovered by Columbus, should remain in ignorance, is too much for a red man
                            to bear or endure. Had you, O white man, or your fore-fathers, taken the same .course with the Indian that
                            William Penn did, he would stand on a broader and higher platform of society and on a more equal footing with
                            the white man than he does now, and thereby have saved thousands of lives that the Indians ihave taken in their
                            wild, savage ""state. % will make to you a short but true statement of William Penn : "Win. Penn is now a
                            shining Herald of Truth in the Spirit world, and wherever, he meets an Indian spirit, he is highly honored and
                            esteemed by the same. We call him Father Penn, and look up to him as a great benefactor and spiritual guide to
                            the Indian, and long will his name be remembered within the Indian circles of the Spirit land, even for rolling
                            ages to come. "If you wish to prosper in your various occupations and pursuits of earth life, if you wish to
                            nourish like the beautiful rose of sunny climes, deal justly with all men, whether foreigners or natives, at
                            home or abroad ; to all ranks, classes, and dispositions. Carry no longer two faces to the Indian, appearing
                            before his face as his warmest and best friend, and behind his back his bitterest enemy. This will never do
                            under so noble a Constitution as is yours, where there should be brotherly love throughout the length and
                            breadth of this grand Republic." Who was William Penn, whose name has been handed down in history as one of the
                            world's benefactors ? He was an exception among white men—a friend to the Indians. His success among the natives
                            consisted chiefly in two things : First, he went among them unarmed and ministered to them the spirit of peace,
                            instead of war, if he made treaties with them, he fulfilled them, if he promised them money, he paid them—he
                            kept his word, by which he sained the love and confidence of the Indians. Secondly, he made them /eel that they
                            had rights, and he respected those rights ; that they were his equals before the law ; that if either party
                            violated the law, or rule of right, they should stand an equal chance at redress for their grievances. If all
                            men had progressed up to the M^JNTTiriDSTO. <pb n="185" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE 185 moral standard of Wm. Perm, the
                            whites would have advanced much nearer the millennium than they are now; or, i the United States' Government hac
                            early adopted his wise and humane policy and continued the same up to this time, it would never have had wai
                            with the Indians. North Union Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Relaxation v. dissipation" TEIform="index"/>RELAXATION vs. DISSIPATION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, G. B." TEIform="persName">ELDER G. B. AVERY</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">All created beings, from least to greatest, need rest,—relaxation from action in the same direction ; human
                            capacity for toil, burden, suffering, is limited; it cannot eternally bear the strain of continuous and
                            unremitted action in one and the same direction. Rest, recuperation, is a law of all being, animate and
                            inanimate. The Indian's bow, always bent, except when propelling the arrow, never springs well. The human limb
                            always cramped, or strained in the same direction and degree of tension, becomes powerless. Even so the human
                            mind always strained in the same direction, and to the same degree of tension, becomes imbecile, and insane. The
                            spirit, also, is subject to the same laws ; it cannot always endure the same degree of exertion, or strain of
                            either sorrow or joy ; to have a healthy and happy activity and existence, it must have seasons of relaxation ;
                            its extremes of sensitive feelings of either sorrow or joy must be modified ; if too fitful, quietude ; if too
                            dull, action. The entire forces of creation demand their night,—their season of repose. But what is rest ? A
                            poet hath truly said : "A want of occupation is not rest; A mind quite vacant is a mind distressed." Rest, is
                            not necessarily a cessation from all action ; this, the surgeon's patient well understands, when a limb is
                            confined for weeks in the same posture and place ; but rest is change of action and condition, releasement from
                            excessive exertion and conditions modified to the needed change. To the sedentary mechanic, as the shoemaker,
                            tailor, jeweler, engraver, and seamstress, exercise is rest and recuperation, while to the farmer, the
                            pedestrian, cessation from action is rest. To the merchant, wearied with the constant din of the transit of
                            bales and boxes, the clatter of feet and the prattle of tongues, the quiet retirement of the Sabbath, and its
                            hush of excitements is rest; but, the cloistered men or monk, tethered to the closet, prayer books and kneeling
                            stool, the busy scenes and transactions of the mechanic, farmers, or merchant's life, or the strolls of the
                            pedestrian are rest. But, relaxation from the rigorous duties and burdens of life in any or every direction,
                            does not, necessarily include dissipation ; it does not require that bright human intelligences should stoop
                            down to indulgences and pleasures which degrade their being to, or below the level of the brute, and load
                            themselves down with burdens of disease, the fruits of pleasure, more painful, in their consequences, than their
                            toils for honest subsistence. Because the mind, as well as he body, wearies of excessive toil and aurden, it is
                            not necessary, in order to secure rest, and recuperation, that its possessor should let go all mental restraint,
                            and betake one's self to the theatre, the drinking saloon, the gambling M^JNTIITESTO.<pb n="186" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 186
                            THE den, nor to give loose reign to physical passions and appetites for relief. Because the nerves are weary it
                            is not necessary, nor is it rest, nor recuperation to them to narcotize them with tobacco, stupify them with
                            opium, nor stimulate them with alcohol nor rubefacients for relief. The age in which we live is notorious for
                            instability ; feebleness seems an inheritance transmitted from parent to child ; even the educational
                            institutions seem pandering to this weakness of human condition, and nursing this fickle wight; much of the
                            mental food—our literature, is light, trashy, ministering to shiftlessness. Loiv, cheap novels,— iidime novels"
                            load the shelves of news rooms and bar saloons ! This is food for mental dissipation, not mental rest! But, when
                            the mind is jaded, let it find rest in quietude and the exercise of the muscles, or sweet sleep relieved from
                            worldly cares. When the spirit is borne down by the strifes and turmoils of life, it may find the most
                            appropriate and abundant repose, the most sumptuous rest and refreshing recuperation, in turning its energies
                            upon Divine and heavenly themes, with their sunbeams of an- gelic' smiles, and their panaceas of heavenly love
                            from the portals of the blessed in the land of souls. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Self-abnegation" TEIform="index"/>SELF-ABNEGATION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, O. C." TEIform="persName">O. C. HAMPTON</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">He who can rise to a state of practical self-abnegation, until it has become second nature with him, has arisen
                            to a very great height in human glory and felicity. If there is any man who is elevated above, and delivered
                            from, the thralldom and vexatious slavery to external circumstances, and temporary changes, it is he who has
                            gained the serene height of total self surrender of his own will—affections—yea even intellect and judgment into
                            wiser hands than his own. And paradoxical as it may seem, this total self-abnegation, must be an act of our own
                            deliberate choice, arising from our own sincerest judgment of its benefit and utility, or such surrender is
                            simply an impossibility. No doubt the advocates of individual sovereignty will sneer at this theory, as one
                            which makes a mere machine of a man, and even at that, subject to the whims and caprices of any and all to whom
                            he may have surrendered himself, and who profess (at least in our society,) , to have legitimate control of him
                            as being agents for God, in ultimating his highest individual good. Still, all who will take Jesus Christ's
                            method of proving the truth of this doctrine, (viz)being a doer of the work, will find a most glorious guerdon
                            of contentment and peace as the result of this lesson in self discipline. The philosophical grounds , for til is
                            safe and salutary self-surrender, are to be found in the solid granite of eternal principles. 1. It is a
                            necessary inference from God's'Goodness Love and Wisdom, that any plan or scheme he might employ for man's
                            elevation and progress, should be one which would secure the 'greatest amount of blessing to the greatest num-
                            ber. 2. It is an inexorable law of the universe that the less are to be blessed of the better if blessed at all.
                            These inferences from God's Love and wisdom are practically demonstrated it appears to SHAKEE
                                JVXAZNTIT'JSSTO.<pb n="187" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER 187 me in the present organization of Shaker Societies, and
                            their mode of administering the government of the same. And when the intrinsic elements of this administration
                            become sufficiently diffused, to economize and appropriate all the talent, wisdom and inspiration to be found in
                            all of the members thereof spiritual media-Prophets, Evangelists, Teachers, Preachers, Mechanics,
                            Mudgills—everything, it seems as if it would leave nothing more to be desired. But to get down to this hard pan
                            of self-abnegation once more : There are many worthy and excellent motives urging to the swift travel of all and
                            each of us into this sublime and heavenly state. 1. It is the next thing to the impossible to be strictly honest
                            and unselfish without it. I heard our good Elder Hervey L. Eades say many years ago that which I never forgot:
                            "'If" said he, "something were required of me to do_ by another whether agreeable to my feelings or not, I could
                            at least retain my integrity and honesty in complying with the demand ; because no wish nor choice in me has
                            been consulted. But if I proposed to do any certain thing of myself, my own integrity and sincerity would be
                            very much more questionable even in my own opinion; for how could I tell how far my own sinister interest might
                            be mingled, like so much strange tire in my offering?" And sure enough, there was the rub. 2. We all need an
                            immense amount of modesty, humility and general concession, before we shall be fit society for the angels. 3. No
                            man can exist independently of all organization. He could no more grow and progress independent of the
                            individual self-sacrifice he has to make of his private will and pleasure to the good of the organization, than
                            Simeon Stylites, situated upon a pillar 60 feet high and 4 feet in diameter where he spent many years in
                            complete solitude positively honest and sincere though he may have been, but wofully wanting in Wisdom. 4. When
                            we are so far subdued, and brought so completely under the influence of self-abnegation as to no longer feel the
                            agonies of its consuming fires, what is there that can disturb our serenity for a moment ? Nothing will be
                            unpleasant any more. Men in all ages here and there one—here and there an order have sown the precious seed and
                            reaped the golden harvests of this divine self-sacrifice. Brahmins, Buddhists, Essenes, Egyptian Hierophants,
                            Jews and Christians have all acknowledged and practiced this sublime self-surrender at times, even to those they
                            esteemed their inferiors. How serenely Jesus answered Pilate when questioned thus by the Jewish Ruler : "Know
                            you not that I have power to put you to death ?" Jesus said, "I know you have that power no more, no less, than
                            God will see fit to allow you to exercise it." There was the invulnerable foundation of confidence—"Thou art
                            still the Eternal God, and underneath are the Everlasting Arms." Let come what will, sorrow and adversity ; or
                            comfort and peace, it is God's plan and he must, he surely will vindicate his cause and in the end justify all
                            his ways to man—so thought Jesus. His Providence is over all— This boundless universe— And o'en the wormwood and
                            the gall, The blighting and the curse, Are but His mercies in disguise, The turnings of His hand, From which
                            salvation shall arise, At His Divine Command. Union Village, 0.</p></div2><pb n="188" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Experience of Cassandana Brewster, of Hancock, Mass, aged 86 years" TEIform="index"/>Experience of Cassandana
                            Brewster, of Hancock, Mass, aged 86 years</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Brewster, Cassandana" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">In answer to many inquiries why my lot was cast among the Shakers, I briefly reply :— When in the tenth year of
                            my age, my parents became religiously exercised and much awakened to the necessity of finding some way for the
                            salvation of their souls. After close examination among different Christian denominations, they became satisfied
                            that the Shakers lived nearest to God and in their lives were the most practical Christians of any people they
                            had found. In this belief they united with them, taking with them their family, where they finished their days,
                            having in their lives faithfully and conscientiously maintained their religious faith. I was reared in the
                            Society a contented and happy child, knowing little of burdens and cares, as they were borne for me. At about
                            sixteen years of age, there was a general religious revival among our people, the operation of which produced in
                            me a great change. Although young, I received the burning light of conviction ; and notwithstanding my favorable
                            situation from society relations, notwithstanding the good influence and kind labors of a Christian people which
                            gave me protection from sin, yet I found I was human and realized my fallen condition ; I felt I had a work to
                            do for myself; no others could do it for me, however much they might be able to aid me. I then and there raised
                            my standard high, and commenced the work in earnest, resolved, that whatever might be the trials I met or the
                            temptations which beset me, I would firmly stand, live my faith, bid the spirits of darkness depart and make my
                            house a house of order, allowing no place therein for sin or defilement. This resolution I have faithfully kept.
                            I have ever been ready for a helping word from my leaders, and faithful brethren and sisters. By following their
                            example and accepting their precepts, I have gained that victory over the power of evil, in which I can and do
                            rejoice, with unceasing thanksgiving to God, the giver of all good, for opening a way of salvation for all who
                            will accept the terms, by mortifying the deeds of the body that the soul may live. In truth I can exclaim,
                            blessed way of God, I do love it! Blessed cross of Christ, it frees my soul from sin and shame, it clothes me
                            with peace, love and purity, I do love it! In loving my dear gospel relations and knowing they love me is the
                            beginning of heaven upon earth and makes me exceedingly happyMay the knowledge of gospel truth be extended; may
                            the work of love and peace increase until it fills the whole earth, putting an end to all wars, strife and
                            contention, uprooting the three plants our heavenly Father hath never planted, na-mely:—"The lust of the flesh,
                            the lust of the eyes, and the pride of life." Then can we all rejoice together in the goodness of God.</p></div2><div2 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Chemistry of bread-making" TEIform="index"/>Chemistry of Bread-making</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, Daniel" TEIform="persName">DANIEL FRASER</persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> Scientific men have drawn their conclusions from facts within their knowledge, that alkaline salts break up the
                            coagulating power of the blood, induce a diminished vital cohesion of the textures JVLAJSITF'ZESTO <pb n="189" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER formed from it, impair the process of respiration, and lessen the production of
                            nutritive blood. Ff such is actually the case, then those who use alkaline matter, must find in proportion to
                            the quantity taken, lassitude and debility, an exhaustion of condition, a desire to rest and lounge, and instead
                            of being up and doing for the welfare of others they find enough to do in caring for themselves. That such is
                            actually the case needs no affirmation ; medical men can show cases by the thousand that need their at- tention,
                            strictly referable to laxity of muscular fibre, and want of strength in the frame-work of the body. Here we have
                            the facts of ordinary life sustaining all that has been advanced ; hence the disuse of alkaline matter in our
                            food in compliance, we promise you (the young more especially,) greater strength of bone, firmness of muscle, a
                            rallying power under fatigue, and a buoyancy of spirits at present unknown. The chemistry of Saleratus and Soda
                            in human food, and their action on the formation of muscle and bone etc ; have already been dealt with. The
                            chemical changes that take place by fermentation and by the heat of the oven in baking may now be noticed. Good
                            flour, good yeast, thorough kneading, and the proper degree of heat in the oven, are the essentials in making
                            good bread. How to make yeast: Boil with the skins on till well done, enough of potatoes to make a quart when
                            mashed. When done, peel the potatoes and mash them to fineness and mix with them one pint of flour ; then stir
                            the whole to an emulsion with the water in which the potatoes were boiled. Cool the product to eighty degrees,
                            and add half a pint of the best bakers' yeast and a tablespoonful of brown sugar. Set the mixture aside, and
                            maintain a temperature of eighty degrees till it works well. Of this yeast, take half a pint to seven pounds of
                            flour, mixed with three pints of water at eighty degrees ; if the weather is cold the flour may be warmed. Knead
                            till the dough is flaky, then set it aside to rise at eighty degrees. When the dough has risen to nearly the
                            full size, divide it into loaves and knead again, and set them aside at eighty degrees till the full size is
                            attained ; then put the loaves in the oven heated to not less than four hundred and fifty degrees. Keep the
                            loaves covered with paper till the dough is fully t aised ; then remove the papers and permit the browning to
                            take place. The larger the loaves the higher should be the temperature of the oven. Seven pounds of flour will
                            make eight loaves of bread twenty ounces each. When the loaves are. taken from the oven, place them in a current
                            of fresh air till they have cooled off to the temperature of the air. Covering bread fresh from the oven is an
                            injury to it. The yeast as above, will keep a week in winter ; and from two to four days in summer. Cool it off"
                            slowly before being set away. Bread made from it, in faithful obedience, will be good. The heat of the oven
                            renders starch soluble. The raising of bread-stuffs, and the cooking of food are the most important branches of
                            human industry. Chemistry enters largely into cooking and more especially in bread-making. Every cook should
                            know something of the nature of chemical action. There are three kinds of fermentation, the first, 1©9 M^NimE
                            STO. <pb n="190" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 19O THE SHAKER, M-AJNTIJEHESTO. develops sweetness, the second, sourness, and the
                            third, something worse. In making bread, fermentation should be arrested before the sour stage begins. Good
                            bread is the exception and not the ride in more than half the families of the world. With a little chemical
                            knowledge, and an eye trained to observe the little changes that occur in the dough and in the oven, good bread
                            may become the rule. To make good bread, is a higher accomplishment than musical proficiency. Wheat meal with
                            all the bran in it should be used in preference to superfine flour. In mixing the dough of this meal, it should
                            not be as stiff" as of fine flour : and when yeast is used, fermentation should be arrested sooner, and the
                            bread baked in a hotter oven. A great change has taken place in the habits of well-to-do people within the past
                            twenty years in relation to bread. Now, bread and puddings made of unbolted flour are used to a great extent.
                            Oat meal has also come much into use. This change is not confined to the East. In one of the Western States, a
                            Scotch miller had machinery which could turn out one hundred barrels of oatmeal per day. He increased the
                            capacity of his mill to double that amount. In bolting flour, the bone, muscle, and brain forming elements are
                            abstracted to a serious amount. As proven by chemical analysis, superfine flour has been robbed of nutritive
                            value to the amount of one seventh. In other words, one entire wheat crop every seven years is destroyed to suit
                            tastes and cravings, which have no founda- tion in physiological righteousness. The digestive functions bear
                            normal relations to the grains just as they are ; but when superfinely ground and bolted, over fermented, poorly
                            kneaded, half baked and dosed with saleratus—this long continued, the integrity of said functions finally gives
                            way, breaks up the nervous system, and a host of ailments locate themselves, and are transmitted from parents to
                            children. Hence the nearer we come to using the grains just as they are, the better. All grinding of grain, and
                            cooking, should simply be, to render the whole grain more easily digested and assimilated. The subject of
                            fermentation has engaged the attention of some of the best minds of Germany, France, and England ; and the
                            conclusion is, that leaven is living rottenness ; and the least degree of fermentation in dough lessens its
                            nutritive value. And that the whole process of fermentation is wasteful and unclean; microscopic organisms being
                            introduced and propagated in profusion. To obviate the waste and uncleanness of leaven, various methods of
                            making bread have been introduced. The Aerated bread is now used to some extent; but machinery is required in
                            its manufacture, and of course cannot be made by single families. There is a form of unleavened bread coining
                            into general use in leading families, called "Gems,'' wherever introduced they are pre-eminently acceptable. Dr.
                            Trail of Hygienic fame, introduced another form of unleavened bread ; both are excellent, the latter is more
                            strictly in accordance with physiological relationships. Gems are made as follows : Make a batter of unbolted
                            wheat meal and <pb n="191" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER 191 water, thick enough to run from the spoon and no more ;
                            have the gem pans hot, and just befora filling them, stir up the batter well, mixing with it all the air you
                            can. Have the oven hot, and in twenty minutes you may have nice gems. The origin of this form of bread, was in
                            this wise ; Dr. Trail, wishful to have an acceptable form of unleavened bread, found when baked in the ordinary
                            way it was sodden ; the happy thought struck the experimenter (Charles Hart, of Boston) that if the bottoms of
                            the baking pans were corrugated the results might be satisfactory, and they were so. The first point in having
                            good gems is to have the batter of the right consistency. Second, develop the gluten of the meal thoroughly by.
                            stirring up the batter. Third, have the pans and oven hot. A thin skin speedily incloses the air in the batter,
                            the expansion of the air with a small portion of steam, swells up the gem. When gems are wanted immediately make
                            the batter with hot water; if mixed the night before, warm water is not needed. The other form of bread, is made
                            of wheat meal and water well kneaded, and rolled out to about one fourth of an inch thick, and baked on a hot
                            (not too hot) surface. This cake is at once highly nutritive, needs a good degree of mastication, and is
                            actually delicious to a physiologically trained appetite. Appetites can be trained as well as created. ON THE
                            USE OF COMMON SALT : From what has been advanced of the action of saline matter, it is not too much to say, that
                            if we used only one tenth of the salt we usually do, it would be better for us. The Spanish race in the South,
                            have educated their tastes in a certain direction, till Cayenne pepper and garlick are leading articles in their
                            dietary ; and in families not so far south, where gross tastes prevail, everything eaten must be saline. The
                            great argument, (or rather no argument) in favor of salt, is, that animals like it; they do, but do they use
                            salt, with every mouthful of grass they eat? If salt was used at long intervals, its operation would be directed
                            towards the bowels and be discharged, and be less hurtful than when taken in small doses several times a day.
                            Those who use but little salt, appreciate the delicate flavor of the various grains, and they will more speedily
                            recover from internal and external injuries. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Manifesto:--the best religion" TEIform="index"/>THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. The Best Religion.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> That form of religious belief is best, regardless of its denomination, which does most for its adherents, in
                            moulding them into noblest humanity. All persuasions aim to do this; and that is the best which'most truly
                            accomplishes this grand desideratum. The poet rhythmically advises graceless bigots to cease fighting about
                            modes of faith, and asserts, "His can't bo wrong, whose life is in the right;" and could we all agree upon what
                            system of life is right, or most righteous, then would the era of great, good feeling be inaugurated—the dawn of
                            the M^JSTrFE STO. <pb n="192" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 193 THE millennium universally seen and felt. Still, while much
                            diversity of opinions exists and is likely to for years to come, there are ideas of what forms the best
                            character—what makes a human being the best man or woman—upon which we can agree very generally ; and a gener-
                            ous leaning towards this agreement, and away from ungenerous prejudice and unbrotherly bigotry, would soon bring
                            heaven to earth, and make us brethren in one universal religion. We hold a relation, by oneness of pro- fession,
                            with a few millions of Christians. The founder of the system bore a most lovable character and amiable
                            disposition. So beautiful wras Jesus in life, that all who know of him—even millions upon millions disowning his
                            leadership— pay willing tributes of respect to his excellent reputation—to the divinity of his humanity. . Now,
                            man was not made for this system of Christianity ; but this was made for his higher development; and in making a
                            god of Jesus, instead of an exampier, the greatest mistake ever made by human beings was, and is enacted—from
                            which mistake may be dated departures from the religion of a universal, loving brotherhood and a multiplication
                            of sects, all largely professing the name, while but few, very few make even an approach to the pattern. Yet,
                            the highest religious fervor of the human soul, brings mankind into a oneness of feeling, mutually deciding what
                            is right and what is wrong ; and thus men say : It is best to be pure as Christ was pure; and peaceable, as
                            Jesus was for peace ; and just and philanthropic after the Master's pattern ; and beautifully unworldly like the
                            example set—these are best; not simply because Jesus did so live and love to do, but because every engagement of
                            these practices makes of us better men and women., While making the profession of Chris- tianity, and adoration
                            for its founder, could we all so love the faith, and so love Jesus, that we would relinquish every inferior,
                            passionate inclination, (however natural) to be like Jesus, and to be living illustrations of his faith, then
                            what noble humanity we should be ! what a universal religion of love to men would possess us ! No quarrels nor
                            wars—but an eternal peace, a Christian calm and rest. None rich, tyrannical, "overbearing, proud nor high;" none
                            poor, servile, sick, sorrowful nor sinful; but rather obtain a brotherhood of most virtuous, extensive, and
                            gigantic proportions. We would, we will lay aside our bigotry, our unchristian prejudices, and admit joyfully,
                            the best religion is that which makes us love and bless one an- other the most. Leaving the future life out of
                            the question until we enter it, we would aim to be best in all that is selfsacrificing, noble, pure,
                            unretaliatory, golden-rule and unworldly in this life. If to live like the angels is desirable, then to separate
                            ourselves from all unangelic practices is a necessity. We want the best religion ; and we are willing to live
                            for it at any cost. Thus far, we have believed the Christian system was best; and yet it has cost us many
                            inferior practices ; but in lieu of these, to put on Christ has been a gain unto an exceeding nobility inasmuch
                            as we have done so. If there is any better religion than the life of Jesus—the Christ of the gospels— any form
                            that will make us more just, merciful, loving and peaceful than was SHAJKBR MANIFESTO. <pb n="193" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/>
                            THE SHAKER MANXF'EIS'X'O. 193 Jesus ; or more so than the Christianity called Shakerism returns to us when fully
                            and faithfully practiced, we want to know it, for we want the best religion— and to be humanly divine.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakerism Pre-Eminent" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERISM PRE-EMINENT</head><p TEIform="p">A writer asks : "What shall I do to be a Shaker?" While urging her to procure a. copy of "Plain Talks," we would
                            here ask and answer : What constitutes a Shaker? What is Shakerism? And wherein lies the necessity for either ?
                            The name "Shaker," was originally given in derision, to a little band of revivalists which was involuntarily
                            shaken by an irresistible and unknown power. The character of those bearing the name Is virgin in its largest,
                            purest signification. The profession of those called Shakers is particularly Christian, as it demands, that
                            being a disciple, means living like Jesus—the Christ. The system of Shakerism is peculiarly religious. The
                            necessity for it lies in the fact that there is no other system that gives so much soul satisfaction ; none that
                            establishes more resurrection life— a life most superior—while depriving its participants of nothing that
                            exalts, improves and makes superiorly blissful our life on the earth. The system of Shakerism is pre-eminent as
                            a salvator from sin ; and a redemptor unto most pristine purity; because it affects those who adopt it as a
                            life-practice, that they come in possession of an unusually discreet knowledge of what constitutes sin; and with
                            a keener vision of, and rare relish for the correlations of heaven and earth ; thus establishing on earth an
                            avenue, whereby strength from the heavens is procured to put away the last remains of sin, and live in heaven on
                            earth. It is a system that urges the possibility and certainty of living together as men and wometv—brethren and
                            sisters— in whom is so much of Christ, that all unheavenly, sensual, sexual lusts may not only be denied, but
                            spurned with a godly hatred. Thus does Shakerism portend what is possible to be, and what is established on
                            earth. It discloses to every investigator, a religion, based on the scientific basis of an exchange, by
                            selfdenial, of the inferior for the superior— a loss of unenduring pleasures,-for pleasures that will never die,
                            but increase, eternally in the heavens. Inseparably connected with this spiritual basis, is the successful
                            attempt to establish on earth, communal relations, whereby no physical want needs be felt, but rather, the
                            security of an abundance of everything that constitutes earthly blessings. The spiritual being supreme director,
                            has decreed that the consideration of self is Cithe accuser of the brethren" and shall be cast out. With its
                            outgoing, there follows as the most natural of consequences, a large train of devilish incendiaries, with whose
                            presence neither peace, purity nor partition of goods upon an equal, brotherly, heavenly basis is possible.
                            Prominent among these very worldly and grossly inferior proclivities are partiality ; ambition for pre-eminence
                            in position and in power of rule ; the selfish love of money, with the brief authority its assumption appears to
                            give; jealousy ; deceit; inequality of sharing burdens and blessings, etc. ; while the new occupant that puts
                            the house of the soul in order, and insures beyond a doubt, permanent peace and eternal happineee, <pb n="194" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 194 THE 8HAKEE MANIFESTO. is the spirit that works, lives and dies— ever ambitious to illustrate
                            the new gospel rule of "eachfor all—all for each." Even to the intelligent, but worldly minded, the prosecution
                            of such a scheme, for the attainment of present salvation, and assurance of future redemption, seems Utopian,
                            and very improbable of success. But such advantage has already attended the Shakers as far as they have
                            practiced Shakerism, that though acknowledging themselves yet imperfect, to a full attainment of complete heaven
                            on earth, sufficient is realized to encour- age their prosecution of an apparently perfect system, which they
                            believe originated in the heavens, and which by a foretaste, they are assured, a full elaboration of the same in
                            the soul, will result in the completest redemption. Investigation will prove to the sincere seeker after an
                            exceeding righteousnessperfection—as found in Jesus, that though Shakerism is a working religion, it removes all
                            dross and results in the purest of life. </p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>EDITORIAL NOTES</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="General Sherman vs. Jesus" TEIform="index"/>GEN. SHERMAN VS. JESUS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">In a recent speech, Gen. Sherman, testified that his profession as a soldier, was in the interest of peace !
                                We protest. A much more honorable personage than Gen. Sherman—Jesus Christ— made even louder and stronger
                                protests than, we now do. His testimony made it right for Jews, heathens and brutal barbarians to fight; but
                                not for Christians'; "else would my servants fight."</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christianity a failure?" TEIform="index"/>"IS CHRISTIANITY A FAILURE ?"</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">That which is called Christianity by the popular churches never has been a success in the line of dispensing
                                salvation ; and is full as much of a failure today as ever. The introduction of genuine Christianity was "to
                                save people from sinning;" the immense failure of salvation to the people, finds its cause in that the
                                people demand to be saved in their sins,—an utter impossibility, even for God to enact. We ask those who
                                want salvation from sin, to study and copy the life of Jesus, which will prove a veritable "power of God
                                unto salvation."</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christianity, too exacting" TEIform="index"/>CHRISTIANITY, TOO EXACTING</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> "I pray thee, have me excused from much that Christianity demands ;" has been the appeal of worldly,
                                pleasure-loving professors of the faith. For these reasons—the exacting demands of Jesus upon all who would
                                be true disciples—Jesus has been substituted for themselves ; made to bear their cross ; made sufficient for
                                the life they should live, but do not; caused to be crucified, in the hope that through this crucifixion
                                they might live and wallow in their sins ; made a god of, in the hopes, that, regardless of their sinful
                                lives he would' be all powerful to save them from their just punishment. Fellow men and women : These things
                                ought not to be believed. Stand up and face the consequences ; for so surely as effects follow causes, so
                                surely will we have our "reward, according as our works have been." Christianity is so exacting, many want
                                to be excused from bearing the same, full cross that Jesus did ; and in being so excused, they are excused
                                the salvation from sin, which alone makes Christianity invaluable. But so long as these excuses are indulged
                                    <pb n="195" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> TKJEO SHAKER MANIFESTO. in, just so long will there be a multiplicity of
                                denominations, each proposing equally to shun Shakerism and Christianity, and to obtain all that these
                                promise without any exertion on their part! Christianity is based upon principles as permanent as God ; and
                                to escape the just consequence of our doings, by hiding behind the ambush of a meaningless faith, is simply
                                fallacious. Christianity, though a spiritual system, is no less true as a scientific institution ; and all
                                science, teaches that as the causes, so will be the effects that follow.</p><p TEIform="p">The Dunkards are making innovations on their past history, by sending out missionaries, and sustaining
                                salaried officers.</p><p TEIform="p">What is the reason that so little is mentioned by those who praise Jesus, of the modes of life he practiced,
                                but which are too repugnant to human senses to copy ?</p><p TEIform="p">A writer in the N. Y. Observer contributes a poem, entitled "Live, looking to Jesus !" yet no reference is
                                therein made of living just like him. From this course the majority pleads : "Please excuse me !" or less
                                politely: "I wont live like Jesus !" Ingersoll thinks that it is too bad to make so much fuss about original
                                sin, while so much copy remains on hand. The "All for Christ" expression, very commonly fails to express
                                full honesty, by omitting "-excepting a good deal of self." The Chinese have a maxim, that he who speaks
                                most of himself, is the greatest of liars ! The Mohammedans—the genuine ones—look upon Jesus with great
                                respect. They say "Jesus was good; Mahomet was greater !" Gen. B. F. Butler makes the grand and good
                                suggestion, to spend the usual $40,000,000, annually wasted on the army of the U. S. in promoting settle-
                                ments in the West. In a few years, he contends, no army would be needed; and instead of wasting these
                                millions of mouey, the increase of the country's revenues through the industry of those now assisted by
                                them, would be returned many-fold. Let us try it.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Characteristic letter from Brother J. M. Peebles" TEIform="index"/>Characteristic letter from Bro. J. M.
                                Peebles.</head><p TEIform="p">HE CONFESSES NEGLECT : G. A. Lomas, Dear Bro. If you were not gifted with a rich abundance of good nature,
                                common sense and charily, I should commence these lines with an apology for my sins of omission. Your
                                excellent letters received about the time of my arrival in London, from South Africa continue unanswered;
                                and the reception of papers and pamphlets you forwarded at that time remain unacknowledged ! Can you for-
                                give such delay—such seeming neglect? While self-denial is so divine, I am sure you will not deny yourself
                                the luxury of forgiveness. HIS STYLE OF REBUKING : Now that I've got your attention, I propose to stone you.
                                Stand up and take the missiles manfully; remembering that though "no chastisement for the present seemeth to
                                be joyous, but grievous, nevertheless afterwards it yieldeth the peaceable fruits of righteousness to those
                                exercised thereby." THE CAUSE OF HIS REBUKE : I see from The Shaker Manifesto, that in your references to me
                                you have scattered 1L&gt;5 <pb n="196" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> all sorts of barbarous prefixes and annexes about my
                                name; such as "Rev." "Hon." "Dr." etc. It is true that in my more verdant years I was ordained to the
                                ministry by the laying on of sectarian hands—hands as dry and non-magnetic as chips in the scorching summer
                                time. But you will agree with me that it is not the most attractive of sights to see the follies of youth
                                repictured before us! It is equally correct that I was commissioned to fill the Consular position at
                                Trebizonde in Asiatic Turkey during Gen. Grant's administration. But there was nothing very "honorable" in
                                that. American politics are anything but honorable or honest. The appointment may have been beneficial hi
                                opening to me the gates of the East, and introducing me to the Mohammedans, Brahmins and Buddhists of the
                                Orient. It is also true *that I studied medicine, attended medical lectures, served my time in the
                                dissecting room and received a diploma. But I studied medicine to know how to avoid talcing it, rather than
                                how to admimste" it! HIS MEDICAL PREFERENCES : Really I have more faith in dieting, bathing, catnep tea,
                                sisterly nursing and healinghands controlled by Indian spirits, than all the nasty, pungent medicines ever
                                compounded by apothecaries and pseudo-saddle-bag bearers! HIS CHOSEN TITLES : Therefore write me down as
                                plain James M. Peebles—speak of me in social circles as your Brother James—and refer to me when absent as
                                Bro. James, the Pilgrim, on his way to Zion. HE SOFTENS THE REBUKE : Of course, I understand that in
                                fastening these handles to my name there is no blame to be attached, because in thus doing, you only copied
                                them as you found them in the newspapers of Cape Town, South Africa, India, Ceylon, and other eastern lands.
                                Still they are superfluous, cumbersome, useless, and belong to "the fashion of this world that passeth
                                away." HE RESEMBLES A "NONDESCRIPT CREATURE:" I sometimes permit reporters and commit- tees to use these
                                titles because of the good they hope to accomplish. These are of the world. I am sure that Elder F. W. Evans
                                will grant me some considerable latitudinarianism while locomoting like that nonde- script creature seen in
                                John's vision, "standing with one foot upon the sea, and the other on the land." ELDER FKEDERICK'S SCRIPTURE
                                QUOTATIONS : Exactly what the revelator's symbolical vision signifies, /do not know ; but I am sure that
                                Elder Frederick does. He, as you know, is "mighty in the scriptures;" and also mighty out of them! For, in a
                                controversy, if no "passage" occurs to him just to his liking, he deliberately makes up one with all the
                                gravity of an apostle. And then, if subsequently told that "Paul did not say so," he coolly replies : "Well,
                                he ought to have said so!" WHAT IS ORTHODOX? Are you sure, my dear Bro., that Elder Frederick, yourself, and
                                Shaker elders generally are soundly "orthodox?" I am fearful that you believe in neither the infallibility
                                of Pope Leo xiii, nor of King James' version of the Bible ! And then, to make yourselves more uncomely in
                                the eyes of the evangelical world, you believe in visions, spiritual manifestations, perpetual revelations,
                                community of property, and a pentecostal church of peace ! What are evangelical Christians going to do with
                                the Shakers when their day of increase comes? And inasmuch as they will not shoot down their fellow men on
                                battle field, what will the British Government do with you when you establish Shaker societies n England?
                                There are waiting souls there now, ripe, and ready to be harvested. * * * * A SORRY CONCLUSION ! And now,
                                that I am once more on my naive land, after making two circuits of our lanet, I must sorrowfully conclude
                                this leter by saying, that the superior morality of eathen lands is noticed by every unprejuiced traveler!
                                May God and good angels less you and all—including your valiant Standard—The Manifesto. Yours in love,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Peebles, J. M." TEIform="persName">J. M. Peebles</persName></byline></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Truth" TEIform="index"/>Truth
                        </head><p TEIform="p">If it is truth what does it matter who says it?</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Aurelius, Marcus" TEIform="persName">Marcus Aurelius</persName></byline></div2><pb n="197" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>For the Children</head><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Quondam sailor, chapter VII" TEIform="index"/>QUONDAM SAILOR CHAP. VII</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Libbey, William G." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> I soon learned that Captain Hall wished to take his schooner into the lagoon, and as we had learned the rise
                                and fall of the tide during the time we had been on the island, we were able to act as pilots in guiding
                                this little vessel into our island harbor. Going ashore with the captain, and up to our hut where my brother
                                was mending his shirt, .(the only one he had,) I introduced him to Captain Hall, who cordially shook hands
                                with him. He was a kind, benevolent man, and we soon learned to love him for his great kindness to us. A
                                signal was made by my brother at flood tide, being previously agreed upon, and understood by the mate on
                                board, who brought the schooner safely into the lagoon and anchored her in its smooth waters ; for it was a
                                beautiful place for a vessel to anchor. Soon after the schooner arrived, we packed up our little all at the
                                hut and went on board, making it our home while she remained at the island. Our duties were light as there
                                were four men before the mate, when we went on board. The first work after the sails were furled, was to
                                prepare the outfit of the company who were to remain on the island to make cocoa-nut oil. There were three
                                white men, the Frenchman Louie, and two Americans. One of them quite a young man of rather delicate
                                appearance, and I think well educated. The other was an ingenious mechanic ; who, we learned, had been taken
                                from the calaboose, by the Consul, on conditions that he would accompany this expedition and fill the place
                                of blacksmith, carpenter, and whatever other skill this cocoanut oil-making might require. He was indeed a
                                very skillful man, for with the help of the natives he erected houses in a few days, large enough to
                                accommodate a party of nearly thirty persons. Their food consisted of fish, cocoa-nuts, birds, shell-fish,
                                or whatever could be picked up on the island. The vessel they came to the island in had no provisions, yet I
                                do not think they suffered for want of food. The Parmeto natives were quite as well supplied with food here,
                                as on their native islands, for as I have before stated they were very much like Fanning's. "VVe found our
                                food in the schooner very poor; not so good as we had been able to provide for ourselves on our island. It
                                seems that there were two pipes of bread put on board at Tahiti; one for the officers and crew of the
                                vessel, the other for the natives, who ate day and night on theirs, until it was all gone; and then slyly
                                broke into the pipe provided for the ship's crew, and before they were discovered had consumed nearly the
                                whole. They were in truth wild natives, with whom it is either a feast, or a famine. The porpoises caught as
                                the vessel came in,—and which were mentioned in a previous chapter,—the natives baked in the ground and had
                                a very cheerful time eating them. Having eaten an abundance of cocoanuts, I tasted of this meat, but did not
                                relish it, for the fiber was coarse and dry. After the apparatus for oil-making had been put ashore, we
                                commenced filling the schooner with cocoa-nuts, which were collected by the natives and taken to the shore
                                of the lagoon, where they were tied together by starting a strip of the fibrous husk, leaving one end fast
                                to the nut. In this way the natives made long rafts of them which were towed with the boat along-side, and
                                were then hoisted up and dropped into the hold of the schooner. Our vessel was ninety tons burden, and we
                                were a little more than a week filling the hold with nuts. She remained in the lagoon about three weeks,
                                once narrowly escaping being wrecked in a gale, which dragged her anchors ; yet escaped through the good
                                management of the Captain and crew, who carried out a kedge anchor in the long boat, and warped the vessel
                                off the coral, thus saving her. Among the great variety of sea-birds on M-A-NTIPIESTO. 197<pb n="198" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 198 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. this island, there was one land bird, a very beautiful paroquet,
                                with green glossy plumage, and a very bright scarlet spot on its wing. This little bird appeared to
                                advantage when flying about in the. tops of the low growing trees: in the bright sunshine, the deep green of
                                the palm seemed to blend with the plumage of the little bird, while the contrast of the red wings as he
                                hopped nimbly about, made a small panorama for us "Crusoes" to view. My brother had tried to catch one of
                                these little birds alive, but was unsuccessful; but when the natives came, they caught one and brought it to
                                the vessel to the captain and his wife, who were pleased with it, for they had a little daughter who was
                                quite fond of birds. The little girl was just learning to talk, and would repeat after her mother in her
                                native tongue ; Manou, Te, Ai. This became a by word on the passage to Tahiti, and when transposed was
                                something like, "O what a pretty bird !" She was an interesting child and the captain seemed to be very fond
                                of her. The captain appeared to me like a person who had met with trouble in his relations •with society,
                                and had left the States and gone to the islands for refuge. He had united his fortune with that of a native
                                woman, who was a perfect Zantippe, and with whom this refined, well educated man could have no real
                                sympathy, nor social enjoyment. After remaining at anchor in the lagoon about three weeks, the word was
                                passed to fit the schooner ready for sea; a great supply of green cocoa-nuts were brought on board by our
                                kind natives, which was a luxury, as sea provisions were scarce. At last our anchor was weighed, and we ran
                                safely out through the narrow passage, into the great Pacific ocean. Soon after leaving the island a gust of
                                wind took my ftiat overboard that had cost me so much time and labor to make, it seemed like a serious loss
                                to me, as it was all I had one side of the Scotch cap, which was well enough in dry weather; but when it
                                rained as it frequently did on our passage, and my cap would become so filled with water as to run down my
                                face, I would take it off and wring it out. repeating the operation as it became necessary; but suffering
                                all tha while with a severe toothache, it was anything but pleasant, In fact I never was so uha?-d up"
                                before nor since, as on this passage, for the only means by which I could relieve the terrible pain, was by
                                heating a sail needle red hot, and have my brother thrust it into the cavity; thus searing the nerve, and
                                giving temporary relief. If that was not the "Cure Heroic," what could have been? &gt;• Again we had no
                                change of clothing, and during our watch on deck were frequently drenched, and when we went below there
                                being no beds, we would wring out our scanty clothing and lie down in a bunk, with no covering but a cotton
                                cloth, loaned us by two of the natives who formed part of our crew. The great kindness of these two men,
                                whose names were Charlie and Jack, impressed me deeply; none of out own country, or color, were so attentive
                                to our necessities as these so-called half civilized men, who acted the Christian's part. When we went on
                                deck to relieve the watch, if it was cool they would take off their jackets, and urge us to put them on. The
                                last mentioned individual was very small, and wrinkled in the face, which may have been caused partly by his
                                laughing so much; he was indeed a very pleasant, cheerful little man, and yet we loved them both, for their
                                kindness to all on board the little schooner Emerald. One especial act of kindness we Crusoes in disguise
                                received, was the making of a coarse cotton shirt for each of us, by the wives of the captain, and second
                                mate. This was done by direction of Captain Hall, who was, as previously said, very kind, benevolent and
                                just in his dealings with all: of this we had abundant proof, and will relate this one instance. After we
                                left Fanning's island, he had all the provision on board equally divided, every person sharing alike ; yet
                                with all the captain's fairness, we were very short of food before we reached the Society Islands. (to be
                                continued.)</p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Righteousness is not in creeds or solemn faces" TEIform="index"/>Righteousness is not in creeds or solemn faces
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Righteousness is not in creeds or solemn faces.</p></div3></div2><pb n="199" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="figure" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Village, Canterbury, Merrimack County, N. H." TEIform="index"/>SHAKER VILLAGE, CANTERBURY, MER. CO., N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">[Figure]</p></div2><pb n="200" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Types of Christ" TEIform="index"/>TYPES OF CHRIST</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Eades, H. L." TEIform="persName">ELDER H. L. EADES</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">"But God hath chosen the foolish things of theworld to confound the wise; and God hath chosen the weak tilings of
                            the world to confound the things which are mighty."—I Cor. i, 27. Notwithstanding the great veneration that
                            people seem to have for truth, it is still a diffieult pill to swallow when it interferes with any idol of the
                            human heart, or crosses any cherished or loved opinion. Still the cry is : let us have truth. Our object is, to
                            endeavour to show that all the types and symbols of the Old Testament scriptures, have their fulfilment in the
                            Bridegroom and Bride—in Christ's first and second appearing—not such a Bride as some have made from Rev. xxi: 2,
                            who give this name to the Church; but a real counterpart for the Bridegroom. The apostle does not say that he
                            saw the Bride coming down from heaven, in the form of a Church, but the "New Jerusalem coming down adorned as a
                            Bride." But the Bridegroom was a man : the Bride must be a woman—even "a woman clothed with the sun, and the
                            moon under her feet." (Rev. xii: 1.) Having mentioned the second appearing, we will quote the promise (Heb. ix:
                            28.) "So Christ was once offered to bear the sins of many; and unto them that look for Him shall He appear the
                            second time without sin unto salvation," we ¦will further add that, in order to have a second appearance, it is
                            not necessary that the same identical flesh and bones should return, neither that it should he the saine gender.
                            In fact it were more apropos that the gender should be different, in order to have co-ordinate counterparts. The
                            first, the bridegroom ; the second, the bride. This is well exemplified by Christ himself, who said of John the
                            Baptist: "This is Elias that was to come." The second appearing consists in the re-appearance of the same gift,
                            spirit, power and substance, for the same purposes ; to execute and carry out the same work. John was the second
                            coming of Elijah, because he came in the same gift and power of that prophet. And the reappearance in and
                            manifestation by Ann Lee of the same spirit, testimony, life, power, and wisdom which was exhibited by Christ as
                            much constitutes His second appearing as that which constituted John the second appearance of Elias. This is
                            plain. And we here boldly testify that in all the fruits shown forth by Jesus in His anointed capacity did he
                            reappear, in the anointed Ann. Such, then, manifestly, was His second coming. Thus are the two foundation
                            pillars established, to whom the Scripture types refer, which we will now proceed to set before you, and compare
                            with the substance they were designed to represent. It is said in Rev. x: 7, "That in the days of the voice of
                            the seventh angel, when he should begin to sound, the mystery of God should be finished." To finish a mystery is
                            to explain it, which is a part of the work now before us. We need not seek, nor have we any need to know, the
                            precise time of the formation of our planet, nor the origin of primal man; these are hidden from the world, and
                            we have no revelation disclosing the secret. God hath revealed by Moses, recorded in Gen. i, that in the
                            beginning he did thus and so, but when that beginning was, no man knoweth. But it is proper that man should
                            know, when the "old heavens and earth were created that were to pass away," and when "all things were to become
                            new and all things of God." This can be ascertained by noticing the generations of the heavens and earth,
                            treated of in the second chapter, which has special reference to man, and is given for our instruction. Here we
                            may easily arrive at the precise time of the first called or created man from the primal structure, or dust of
                            animal promiscuity. It is generally admitted that the first chapter, treats mostly of the creation of the
                            universe, in six periods of time called days, and if it is observed that the second chapter treats of the
                            generations of the earth with respect to man, we then hold the key to unlock the mystery, and have no difficulty
                            with the commands given to man in the first chapter, and that given to the first called man in the second
                            chapter, of Edenic order, with whom we very readily perceive was God's first covenant, called the "old
                            covenant," which was the type of the new in that man was raised from a lower to a higher condition.<pb n="201" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. SOI This was the beginning of God's special dealings with his creature man.
                            "He breathed into him the breath of (spiritual) life (the inspiration of lives,) and he became a living soul."
                            Here, it is evident, is the commencement of the types of Christ. The first called man was the first type, and
                            corresponds completely with the second called man, Christ who is*his antitype. The first "a living soul;" the
                            second, "a quickening Spirit.'' The first "to multiply and replenish the earth ;" the second to multiply and
                            replenish the heavens. The first called man was the head of the orderly, natural, Adamic church : the second
                            called man was the head of the Spiritual church. Cain was the first apostate from the Adamic church, and was the
                            the type of Judas, the first apostate from the Spiritual Christian Church. The first church arose from the lower
                            order of the world to that of orderly generation. The second, or spiritual, arose from orderly generation to
                            that of regeneration. The first, forsook the old, disorderly animal world. The second forsook the orderly,
                            natural World, for the spiritual. The twain were to become one flesh in the natural order. The twain to become
                            one spirit in the spiritual order. Having risen above, and forsaken the natural, "father, mother, brother,
                            sister, houses, lands, and all the contingencies thereunto be- longing. Thus the types agree with their
                            antitypes, and show clearly, the distinction between the two orders. From our basis, will be perceived that the
                            first man, Adam, who "was taken from the pre-adamic body to institute a new order of things, was the beginning
                            of the "old heavens and earth that were to pass away." Having no reference whatever to this planet being, "into
                            heaps of ashes turned, When Heaven itself the wandering chariot burned," but to the earthly order then created,
                            at which time all those who came into this order, and embraced this gospel, were "Sons and daughters of God." As
                            Adam was raised up from among the brethren of the pre-adamic body to establish the old heavens and earth, so
                            Jesus was "raised up from among the brethren," of the Mosaic body to establish "the new heavens and earth." And
                            all who embrace this order are the sons and daughters of God, and sing and shout for joy at the establishment of
                            this new order. Thus far we see the types and antitypes are perfect, and as the first called man was a perfect
                            type of the second called man, so Eve, the first called woman, was a perfect type of the second called woman. As
                            the first Eve was taken out of the sleeping body of Adam —from among the disorderly flesh there, to be with the
                            man Adam one flesh—so the sec- ond Eve was taken out of the sleeping body of the world from among the orderly
                            flesh there, to be with Christ one spirit. Thus do the types and antitypes agree. A letter from our pen is not
                            the antitype of the pen, while a printed letter is the antitype of the metal face; their faces must correspond.
                            So it is with all types and their antitypes ; their faces must agree. Then, if one is understood, the other will
                            be also. While the first Adam and Eve of the natural order were types of the second Adam and Eve of the
                            spiritual order, they could not have been types of a pre-existent Christ nor Christ spirit, as this would make
                            the type come after the antitype, which is impossible. Let us repeat, that the first man, Adam, was made out of
                            the ground on which pre- adam or Adamkind stood, and was thence called a "living soul." The second was made out
                            of the ground on which the Mosaic body stood, and was called a "quickening spirit." And the first Eve was taken
                            from the flesh of the sleeping Adamic body for a help-meet for the first Adam, and was called the "Mother of all
                            (the) living;" that is, all living the the higher, natural life. The second Eve— Ann Lee—was taken from the
                            flesh of the sleeping anti-christian body* for a helper for the second Adam, Christ Jesus; and she is called the
                            Mother of all living the higher, spiritual. Thus we see what becomes of the "wisdom of this world," who have
                            three male deities, with neither type nor antitype! Such metaphorical expressions as we have noticed are very
                            common. How often do spiritual leaders inquire what ground we stand on? How often cite to the "hole of the pit
                            whence we were digged, and the rock whence we were hewn." The simple truth is: God<pb n="202" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> SOS THE
                            SHAKER MANIFESTO. made man out of the ground then, as he "digs them out of the pit and hews them out of the
                            rock, now." "Whoso is wise shall understand these things, and whoso is prudent shall know them," although they
                            may confound the wisdom of the wise! But it is said : "The Bridegroom hath the Bride," long before Ann Lee had
                            existence ; and we are asked : How could she fulfill the conditions, who yet had no existence? In answer we
                            would say, he had her prospectively. Such expressions are frequently in holy writ: "This day I have begotten
                            thee ;" "Before Abraham was I am;" but which simply means I am before what Abraham was. Joshua said the Lord had
                            delivered the enemy into his hand, before he commenced the battle. Just so the Bridegroom, Jesus, had the Bride
                            Ann, prospectively, but was as sure of her as Joshua was that he would conquer the enemy. This is true, although
                            it be to the "Jews a stumbling block," and to the Greeks "foolishness." It may be.observed that Ann Lee, of
                            Manchester, England, was the first woman that was baptised and quickened into the spiritual life of Christ, to
                            rise out of nature's loss and order, to live above these, and proclaim the higher life to the world. Hence she
                            has the honor of being the Bride, the Lamb's wife." Being ignorant of this fact, some have supposed that the
                            Bride which the Bridegroom had was a spirit from some foreign world which he had in him ; but it is time that
                            the mystery of such a moon-struck chimera was disposed of; to admit which, would spoil the agreement of all the
                            types and their antitypes. When the indisputable truth becomes known, that Christ, in any age of the world, was
                            no mysterious being, but simply a Godanointed, or which is the same thing, a Godappointed, commissioned agent
                            for a special purpose, all this chimerical, mysterious chaff will be blown away, no more to disturb a dreaming
                            world. Abraham and Sarah were types of Jesus and Ann; not only in.their obedience to the Adamic Gospel, but they
                            were of one stock or race—begotten and born alike} equal as to mode of existence, as man and woman may be heads
                            of a Family. "Abraham hearkened to the voice of Sarah," But what did this hearkening typify ? It was, that in
                            the new covenant the man should hearken to the woman, even so it is. In the second appearing, where a "woman
                            compassed the man," all hearkened to the Bride, Ann. While under the old covenant, the law is, "Thy desire shall
                            be to thy husband, and he shall rule overthee." Millions find this true to their sorrfew, and see no way of
                            relief; but there is a way. To all who wish deliverance from such bondage we would say : Leave the
                            rudimental—come up stairs into the new covenant. Some orthodoxans tell us, in justification of the
                            saved-by-faith doctrine, that Abraham's faith was "counted to him for righteousness." So it was, because it was
                            accompanied by good works. "Faith without works is dead;" and who can be saved by a dead faith? They tell us
                            also, that the offering up of the ram was symbolical of the sacrifice of the "Lamb slain from the foundation of
                            the world." Now the theological student is considerably advanced when he can tell the difference between a
                            typical ram and a typical lamb. Then there is some hope of him. If they had told us that the ram offered up was
                            a symbol,—that the ram that had ruled the world from Adam to Christ had to be slain and burned up—they would
                            nearer have approached the truth. But Sarah called Abraham her Lord, or head. So Ann called Jesus. Not only so,
                            they were types in sacrificing that which was most dear to them, typifying, that in the gospel of Christ, that
                            which was most dear to the natural man and woman must be sacrificed. But you will say : Isaac was not
                            sacrificed; but the ram was taken in his stead. This is true, and agrees perfectly with the antitype. Isaac was
                            saved, and Abraham was promised an hundred fold in the seed of IsaacSo it is now. All the Abrahams and Sarahs
                            that come into the gospel of Christ must offer up their little Isaacs, who will thus be saved: and they shall
                            receive an "hundred fold of Isaacs and other gospel relations, and in the world to come eternal life." Such is
                            the promise of Christ—the type and antitype complete. But the ram was put on the sacrificial altar, and was
                            consumed with fire.<pb n="203" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> ^HE SHAEEE M^JNnLF'ZES'rO. 2O3 This typified that the animal passions
                            must be sacrificed, and utterly consumed by the fire of Christ's gospel. Could types and an- titypes be more
                            complete? The rite of circumcision, typified that in Christ the works of the flesh must be cut off". The mystery
                            makers contend, that they were types of Christ, because "Isaac was begotten by promise." Isaac was.not begotten
                            by promise : • He was begotten by Abraham— "Abraham begat Isaac." There is no mystery about it. He and Sarah
                            propagated children according to the law of generation. Jesus and Ann propagated children according to the law
                            of re-generation. The first natural; the second spiritual. Thus were Abraham and Sarah the types of Christ in
                            Jesus and Ann in being, in call and work, whose offspring are' the seed of the "Free Woman;" who are "the weak
                            things of the world, whom God hath chosen to confound the things which are mighty." Moses and Zipporah were
                            plain and perfect types of Christ in his first and second appearing. We will repeat what Moses said to the
                            fathers: "A prophet shall the Lord raise up unto you, of your brethren like unto me. Him shall ye hear in all
                            things whatsoever he saith. (Actsiii: 22.) Some, in order to keep this mystery from being explained, have left
                            out or omitted the words "of your brethren" in their writings, and also, where it is said the "sanctifier and
                            sanctified are all of One," the preposition of has been omitted, lest we should get a peep into the fact that
                            they were of one stock or race,' and so save one prop to the miraculous story—well knowing, that if they were of
                            one stock, this would be wiped out. We have no apology to offer for such omissions. The preposition clearly
                            shows they were of one race—the human. But Moses not only truthfully declared from whence Christ should arise ;
                            but he was an eminent type of Christ, in that he was called to deliver his people from Egyptian bondage. Some
                            say Moses was not a perfect type of Christ—an imperfect type is no type at all. But Moses was a perfect type of
                            Christ. He was begotten by a man, and born of a woman : so was Jesus. He was raised up from among the brethren;
                            so was Jesus. He was called to deliver his people from Egyptian bondage; Jesus was called to deliver them from
                            the bondage of sin. Also Zipporah was a type of Ann :• She was raised up from among the Sisters; so was Ann. She
                            forsook her own people and followed Moses; suffering the toils of the wilderness, while journeying to the
                            promised land, and became a Mother in Israel. So Ann Lee forsook her own people and followed Christ through the
                            sufferings and toils of the wilderness of this world for the Kingdom of Heaven's sake, and thus conjoined to him
                            became the Mother of spiritual Israel. Of animals and things, we may go through the good book and find agreement
                            in types and symbols throughout. The "two cherubim, covering the mercy seat with their wings, and their faces
                            one toward another," were excellent types of Christ and Ann. They were wrought gold of beaten work; not only so,
                            but were out of one piece* So plainly does every type represent the pure, simple truth, that the two foundation
                            pillars, male and female, in whom they have their fulfillment, were alike and equal in all respects—no more
                            mystery about the one than the other. The two cherubim were types, in that their "faces . looked toward each
                            other, and the word of peace was between them both"—were not only pure gold, but were "taken and made of one
                            piece." Alike in purity, made alike, were alike, all around, all over, inside and outside, and so were the
                            antitypes, Jesus and Ann, the same life, the same word, the same work, the same everything in the second as in
                            the first appearing. And on we may go, and find every joint to fit without the sound of the hammer. The two
                            silver trumpets, the two tables of the Covenant, the two olive trees, the two olive branches, the King and
                            Queen, the son and daughter, etc., all have their accomplishment in Jesus Christ and Ann Lee, the Bridegroom and
                            Bride of the new creation of God. We look in vain among the lower-floor Churches and our theological seminaries
                            to find agreement of the types with their antitypes. With all their learning and worldlX wisdom, they only pile
                            mystery on mystery : and the further we follow them the more dense the fog grows, until we reach a cloud of
                            impenetrable darkness.<pb n="204" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER "But God hath chosen-the foolish things of the world to
                            confound the wise, and the weak things to confound the mighty." Thus, under the seventh-sounding angel, this
                            mystery of God is finished. It would seem that enough has now been said to satisfy the most carping critic of
                            the falsity of the miraculous statement, and of the far-fetched, foreign Christ theory. It is a rule in
                            mathematics that when there are unknown quantities to be found, they must be ascertained from quantities which
                            are known. The same is true in logic— truths may be ascertained by reasoning a posteriori, as well as the
                            contrary. Types and antitypes come directly under this rule ;• so if we know what the antitype is, from this we
                            may learn what the type is, and vice versa. Thus when Are see a printed letter we know what the face of the type
                            was ; or, when we see a type's face we know what the letter will be. The question recurs, Have we known data?
                            Ans.—We have. Of types we have shown, in person and work. Of the antitypes we have Ann Lee, to whom the female
                            types pointed, and in whom they have their fulfillment. She is the known quantity, whom Anti-Christ cannot
                            mystify. We know she came into being by the same law of all her typical females. The two must agree. So, in like
                            manner, of types we know the law by which they came into being, and from this, the law which brought the
                            antitype Christ, into being. There is no possibility of dodging this conclusion. And as Elijah was a type of
                            Christ, and left his mantle behind for Elisha, so it was with his antitype Christ, and so it continues to this
                            day. "All power to save was committed to the Son, who committed the same to his successors." Jesus testified :
                            "All that the Father gave me have I given them." And the call now is, to the whole world, of every nation,
                            tongue, and kindred, to come, accept Christ's term and be saved. To be saved, does not mean to be saved in sin,
                            but from sin: and all it deathly and damning effects, which can onlj be done by forsaking the world, finding
                            God'; order of finite agencies, and there confessing, forsaking, and repenting of all sin, and becoming
                            "crucified to the world and the world crucified to you;" and henceforward, living the life of the Redeemer. We
                            purpose further to institute a comparison between the modes of the first and second appearing of Christ, showing
                            the similarity as well as their equality in person and commission. But by way of leader, will remark that, from
                            what has been previously said, it must be perceived that every succeeding order of God among men-, from the
                            first record to the present time, the instruments have arisen out of a previous body by a higher unfolding and
                            increased inspiration of the spirit of God, and hence every such order has superseded the previous one. Witness,
                            as shown, the creation or call of Adam or Eve from the primal, animal adamic body—the rite of marriage first
                            instituted— orderly generation enjoined on pain of the displeasure of the Creator. See this order building and
                            establishing the first old heavens and earth that were to pass away, and shadowing forth the new. See what
                            gospel was preached and lived, by those who constituted the Adamic church—Seth, Noah, and othersuntil Abraham,
                            with whom God renewed his Covenant, shadowing forth the Increasing steps in the new and everlasting Covenant.
                            Circumcision was instituted under the Old Covenant, which is a type of what should take place in the new—that of
                            cutting off all the fleshly works of generation and becoming "eunuchs for the kingdom of heaven's sake."
                            Advances were made in the old heaven gospel which shadowed forth the gospel travel in the new, and was practiced
                            and lived until Moses, when God's covenant was again renewed, with additional sacrifices and self-denial, and
                            which, being kept, brought renewed blessings. These were enjoined and kept by some, with little modification,
                            until Christ; with whom the new Covenant was made. The substance now appeared, and the work of forming the new
                            heavens and earth was begun. The Creation of the world—the new world, which the apostle says, truly, was made by
                            Him, which we now enjoy with increasing light and power in his second appearing in Ann Lee. Thus we see what
                            God's uniform law and order are : First, the Adamic arose out of the dust of the pre-adamic body; the Abrahamic
                            out of the Adamic ; the Mosaic out of the Abrahamic, and the Christian out M. AISTLF'ESTO. SO4=<pb n="205" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER 2O5 of the Mosaic, and the second appearing in Ann out of the so-called Christian,
                            which was fast asleep when she was taken out of that body; and it is snoring yet. We will now call attention to
                            the history and biography of Jesus, the Christ, and examine the manner of his call, to which we beg especial
                            attention. It so happens that we have no reliable history concerning him until he was about thirty years old;
                            precisely what kind of life he lived previously to that time is unknown to history and mankind; nor is it
                            necessary that we should know it; but John the Baptist doubtless knew all about it, by his confession; as well
                            as Jane Wardley knew about Ann's. In turning to the New Testament we find the gospels beginning with the call of
                            God to one John, the son of Zecharias, who was to be the forerunner, to prepare the way for the "man, Christ
                            Jesus," the son of Joseph. John did not come with a new gospel, but in the power and spirit of Elias, and "was
                            that Elias," to turn the hearts of the children to the fathers, to revive the spirit of Moses' gospel or law,
                            from which many had backslidden—to administer the gift of repentance and forgiveness of sins, to all euch as
                            would honestly confess and forsake them, and return to the lgw. The account reads thus: "The word of God came to
                            John, the son of Zecharias, in the wilderness ;" hence, it is truly said, "A man sent of God," just as Christ
                            was—God sent John for one purpose and Christ for another, both being God-commissioned Agents—One to revive an
                            old institution, the other to create a new one—one to baptize with water, the other with fire. It is further
                            recorded : "Multitudes came confessing their sins (violations of the law,) and were baptized into the spirit of
                            repentance." And here is where we get the first reliable account of Jesus, who was among the brethren there, and
                            who came for the same purpose that the rest did—to acknowledge the gift of God in John, confess and repent, as
                            it was impossible that he should supersede John without acknowledging and accepting the gift of God in him, who
                            was as yet before him. From St. John's account it would seem that the Baptist did not knew Jesus to be the
                            chosen one that was to supersede him, even from his confession, as he said, "I knew him not" (John i: 31.) But
                            he was pointed out by the descent of the Holy Spirit. Then says John : "I saw and bear record that this is the
                            Son of God." It would be warping the record, as the Gnostics have done, to say the descending Spirit was the
                            Christ, for John testified he knew the coming Christ stood among them, before he was pointed out to him • by the
                            Holy Spirit. Jesus could no more have superseded John, without submission to the order of God in him, than Ann
                            Lee could have superseded that of James and Jane Wardley, without confessing, acknowledging, and complying with
                            that order. Thus we may see the first steps that Jesus took towards the priesthood or Christship. was his
                            childlike humility in bending before the gift of God in John, setting us an example in the very beginning of his
                            work. We have no more right to dispute Jesus' confession to John than we have to dispute his being baptized by
                            him unto repentance, of which his soul-melting prayer on the banks of Jordan gives ample proof. It is all plain;
                            there is no mystery about it. Do any of us think we can get to heaven with less humility than Christ did? If we
                            do we are wofully mistaken. He is our exemplar, and as he worked out his salvation so must we ; and we shall be
                            called to take no mortifying step, that our Father and Mother have not taken before us, but these we must take
                            or never be saved. God will not provide one way for their salvation and another way for ours ; hence they say
                            follow us. To follow one is to follow the other, for they are one—their example and teaching the same; both
                            after their anointing, lived free from sin. The reason Jesus was "anointed above his fellows" (mind he had
                            fellows,) was because he was the best of his class—"loved right- eousness and hated iniquity" more than any of
                            them. It is written of him thus : "After his temptation, he returned in the power of the Spirit to Galilee, and
                            thence to Nazareth, where he was brought up; and, as his custom was, he went into the synagogue, and stood up to
                            read. And there vras delivered unto him the book of Esaias, and when he had opened it he found the place where
                            it was written : M^JNTIIPISSTO.<pb n="206" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/> 2O6 THE SHAKER 'The spirit of the Lord is upon me to
                            preach the gospel to the poor, to heal the brokenhearted, to preach deliverance to the captives, to set at
                            liberty them' that are bound, to preach the, acceptable year of the Lord.' He then closed the Book, gave it to
                            the minister and sat down." All eyes were fastened on him. An electric flash from a cloudless sky at noonday
                            would not have shocked them more than the next words he uttered from his seat: "This day is this Scripture
                            fulfilled in your ears." Thus was announced to an astonished world for the first time that the Christ they had
                            so long expected was then sitting in their midst! At first they were pleased with the gracious words that
                            proceeded out of his mouth, but after a few home thrusts, and the affirmation that he was the man to whom the
                            prophetic word applied, they became enraged, and wanted to kill him. A young man whom they had known, to presume
                            so much! He was now Jesus, the Christ, the commissioned of God, according to his own declaration. There was no
                            miraculous dove talking or speaking through him, as the Gnostics have reported. He was now at home among his
                            brothers and sisters and young acquaintances, and well he knew they would suppose he had faults as well as they;
                            so he took the start of them, by saying: "You will say unto me this proverb," "Physician, heal thyself." Hut
                            there was one thing that, perhaps, his relatives did not know, and that was, the physician had healed himself in
                            the order of God under John. Thus, in short, we see the mode of his first appearing; the second must be like
                            unto it. Thus it was with Ann Lee, who went through the same ordeal, setting the same example for womankind,
                            that Jesvjs did for men, since which time the Church has rested on these two pillars, no more to be overthrown.
                            Thus, the "mystery of God. in the blazing sunlight of this day, is finished." Amen; it is finished. These truths
                            may set hardly with some who have considered Jesus to be superhuman ; but such must remember that He was one of
                            the brethren, and not at all ashamed to call them so. But we are told that, although "tempted in all points as
                            we are, He was without sin; and that He always did the things that pleased His Father." The same may be said of
                            Ann, who manifested tin' mother in Deity. She was without sin, and always did the things things that pleased her
                            Mother and Lord after she was commissioned. So it was with Christ; for Jesus became the Christ by virtue of his
                            appointment. He was not Christ before that time, but simply, as the apostle John said: "Jesus of Nazareth, son
                            of Joseph." But the anointed man was tempted in all points as we are, for saith the apostle, "We have not an
                            high priest who is not touched with our infirmities." Now, it is a fact worthy of note, that all temptations
                            must come through some department of our nature. It is irr possible for any one to be tempted by an external
                            presentment, unless he has something within him which desires it. The serpent that tempted Eve only showed
                            something which she desired; and Adam could not have been overcome, only from the fact that he had as strong a
                            desire for the fruit as Eve had; and his throwing the blame on her was simply cowardly, contemptible, low and
                            mean. Now, if we know how we are tempted and what tempts us mo,st, we knowT how Christ was tempted and what
                            tempted him most; but that he successfully resisted all temptations after he became the Christ none will
                            dispute. This and this alone, is the apostle's declaration, and is true. This adds an hundredfold more luster to
                            his brow than to admit the Gnostic doctrine, that a Christ came from some unknown world, entered into him and
                            rendered him impeccable ; or that" God sent an additional spirit, giving him a double entity, the latter to rule
                            the former. Little is known of Jesus' history previous to his baptism by John; but if we examine the word of the
                            apostle closely, we find that they thought him not impeccable previous thereto, "In that he died, he died unto
                            sin once ;" as we also must die. We cannot die to a thing to which we have never been alive. r fie was sis we
                            are in this world." Do we not know how we are? "He learned obedience by the things he suffered," as we must.
                            Also Pet^r iv : 1, 2 : "For as much as Christ suffered for us in the flesh (not in our stead,)<pb n="207" id="p29" TEIform="pb"/> the; shaker manifesto. 207 arm yourselves likewise with the same mind, for he that hath suffered
                            in the flesh hath ceased from sin [as Christ did,] that he no longer should live the rest of his time [as he had
                            done apart of his time,2 to the lusts of men, hut to the will of God." What sublime pathos in the soul-melting,
                            out-pouring of the spirit through the prophet Isaiah, in which it is shown that Christ did the work for himself.
                            "Who is tins that cometh .from Edom, with dyed garments from Bozrah? He that is glorious in his apparel,
                            traveling in the greatness of his strength?" "Wherefore art thou red in thine apparel, and thy garments like him
                            that treadeth inthe wine-fat? (His answer is enough to draw tears from a stone.) I have trodden the wine press
                            alone, and of the people there was none with me : And I looked and there was none to help, therefore my own arm
                            brought salvation unto me. Isa. Ixiii; 1, 2, 3, 5. It wovdd seem that enough had been said showing the
                            similarity between the first and second appearing; but people are hard to believe if one stone be left unturned.
                            It could not be said to be a second appearance if there was any essential contrast, either in the mode, effect,
                            operation, or ultimate. We have shown that it was unnecessary for the same flesh and bones to reappear, to
                            constitute a second appearance—but that Christ was manifested, and reappeared in Ann's testimony, her searching
                            power, her self-denial, tribula- tion, etc.; in fact, all the evidences reappeared in her that appeared in
                            Jesus. He did not come with the nature of angels, but the seed of Abraham. She appeared likewise, not with the
                            nature of angels, but with our nature; hence Jesus and Ann are alike in their natures. As there was a forerunner
                            in the first appearing to prepare the way for Jesus, so there was in the second appearing to prepare the way for
                            Ann. Previous to the second appearance, antichrist began to be weakened by that memorable division called the
                            "Reformation;" by which a way was opened for man to contend for his long lost liberty About this time, many
                            religious revivals broke out in various parts of Europe, particularly in France and Germany. The remarkable
                            revival which happened about the year 1689, in the province of Dauphiny and Vivarais, in France, excited great
                            attention The subjects thereof testified that the end of things drew nigh; they preached repentance, stating
                            that the kingdom t&gt;f God was at hand; that the marriage of the Lamb would soon take place. These
                            witnesses increased until about the year 170G, when a few of them went over to England, where many were united
                            to them, and both their numbers and powers of ministration, like the sea, ebbed and flowed for forty years, when
                            a small number of the most faithful were led by the spirit to unite themselves into a small society near
                            Manchester, under the ministry of James and Jane Wardley. These were the John Baptists of the second appearing
                            of Christ, to whom the people came and were baptized into the spirit of repentance, confessing their sins ; and
                            Ann Lee was among the rest, who came for the same purpose the rest did; and as Jesus confessed to the forerunner
                            in his day, so likewise Ann Lee confessed to the forerunner of the Second Advent, and came up through that
                            order, as Jesus did through that of John. So that the forerunners declared her to be, first, a woman "coming
                            after them, but was preferred before them, for she was before them." Thus it is seen that the second was the
                            reappearing of the first; hence, as promised, Christ has appeared "the second time without sin unto salvation"
                            to all who will accept, believe and obey. The little handful continued to increase in light and power until the
                            year 1770, when by a special manifestation of Divine light the present testimony of salvation and eternal life
                            was fully revealed to Ann Lee, and by her made known to the society, and thus she rose above them and became the
                            anointed and acknowedged leader of this faithful band. From this time forth Ann knew herself to be the bride,
                            the Lamb's wife, being baptized with the same spirit, and by perfect obedience to the light, received from God,
                            she became conjoined to the bridegroom, and co-worker with him in the regeneration and redemption of the race.
                            He the father and she the mother in spiritual Israel. Thus we cannot fail to see an absolute sameness and
                            equality between them and alj the types and symbols that have their fulfill-<pb n="208" id="p30" TEIform="pb"/> SOS SHAKER
                            ment in them. Thus we hold the truth, that The Christ to which all prophecy pointed, and in whom all the types
                            and symbols centered, have here their fulfillment. The one the son of a carpenter, the other the daughter of a
                            blacksmith. And now let us ask : Are these too humble, lowly and mean to be honored with the leadership of God's
                            people? or shall we, Gnostic-like, look high up among the stars for a greater? It were folly to do so. We trust
                            it is now seen, that all the types and symbols under the shadowy dispensations of the law and the prophets are
                            completely fulfilled in the "two anointed Ones" who stand as the first foundation pillars in the new
                            creation—Jesus Christ and Ann Lee. whose ultimates are the same. The first appearing ultimated in a living body
                            or Church, which had all things in common. The second appearing ultimated in the same, hence we see in every
                            particular, from the first shadowing forth—from the first promise of God that a Redeemer should appear, through
                            all prophecy up to the substance, the first and second the male and female are perfectly equal in type and
                            symbol, in prophecy and person, in call, in character, in operation, in substance, in effect, in culmination and
                            in ultimate; equality ! equality !! equality !!! is ineffaceably stamped upon them, never more to be blotted
                            out. The same spirit now calls that called then; the same doctrine is taught now that was taught then; the same
                            exhortation is made ; the invitation is given now to all kindred, nations, and tongues that was given then;
                            "Look unto me and be saved, all ye ends of the earth." The last silver trumpet is now sounding to the
                            inhabitants of the earth, and may its shrill and piercing note reach every mountain-top, penetrate every forest,
                            echo in every land and extend over every wide sea, till the whole earth shall know that "now is come salvation
                            and strength and the kingdom of our God and the power of His Christ." South Union, Ky.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If you don't want to be robbed of your good name, do not have it painted on your umbrella" TEIform="index"/>If you don't want to be robbed of your good name, do not have it painted on your umbrella
                        </head><p TEIform="p">If you don't want to be robbed of your good name, do not have it painted on your umbrella.</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We make a reprint of 'The Essential'...'" TEIform="index"/>We make a reprint of 'The Essential'...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">We make a reprint of "The Essential" which appeared in the July No., to correct an error of the printers. We
                            regret the necessity for this apology.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Printers" TEIform="persName">Printers</persName></byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Essential [corrected]" TEIform="index"/>THE ESSENTIAL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName">WM. H. BUSSELL</persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> The grades and forms of life appear to be innumerable. Doubtless, each has some special significance, though in
                            many cases, not yet made evident to the human mind. To the Infinite all things are simple, but to the finite
                            capacity many seem complicated and difficult of solution. Man needs to know Vhat among the wThole are necessary
                            for hia present welfare, and to feel the assurance that'all things will become clear in the future as his power
                            to investigate increases. There seems no limit to this power in man. At the present time he contains within him-
                            self the treasures of all past ages. Those, it is true, have been handed down embedded in a mass of apparent
                            rubbish, like gold in the midst of various other materials. But however tenacious of their treasure these may
                            be, they are obliged to yield to the separating forces applied to them, and the valued metal appears at last
                            free from allitsincumbrances, Truth is essential. Though from age to age it has seemed to be mixed with error,
                            yet its nature has not been changed thereby. It never was the Divine intention to revea\ all truth at once, only
                            that which is essential for the time being; its highest forms are reserved for the latest times ; or it would
                            have been so revealed, and there would have been no need of investigating and inquiring here and there where
                            truth is to be found; in fact, there would have been in man no faculty for investigation and discovery. Is the
                            All-Wise anxious in respect to the estimation in which he shall be held by his creatures? If so, he would have
                            endowed them at once with the proper powers of appreciating himself. But from the beginning the objects of
                            Divine worship have been, the sun, moon and stars; beasts of various kinds ; men remarkable for their physical
                            endowments ; creatures of the imagination— gods and goddesses—possessing all the human passions and vices; an
                            eternal being styled God, yet limited in his attributes and MAJsraPESTO. THIC<pb n="209" id="p31" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                            JVrA.NTF'JCSTO. mode of existence ; and yet another who, according to some theological authorities, ventured to
                            set himself up as the rival of the last named, thougli but a mere creature ; and last, though not least, an
                            eternal power concentrating in itself all the evil elements or principles supposed to exist in the universe. It
                            is not in the human mind to cease thinking. It must continue to think though error is often the result. System
                            after system of philosophy may be devised by thinking minds and then be discarded, yet they each contain
                            valuable truths that can never perish. Scientific minds are noted for the theories they devise in order to
                            explain natural phenomena. Yet from age to age they are making discoveries in the field of truth that more than
                            compensate for erroneous theories. The medil ums of communication between the inhabitants of earth and other
                            spheres of existence, styled seers or prophets, by no means give us all truth respecting Avhat they claim either
                            to see or to hear. But, to say the least, they are in this respect the peers of the philosopher and the
                            scientist. When these have established unerring methods of arriving at all truth, then the seer and the prophet
                            may well be dispensed with, for their "occupation will be gone." Till that takes place, the candid mind will not
                            discard any mode of arriving at truth, even thougli "seducing spirits" may still find room to practice their
                            arts and impose upon the understanding. The lover of truth and goodness may ask if error and its consequences
                            are to be perpetuated forever. Doubtless, until all have "ceased to do evil and learned to do well." When they
                            shall govern their appetites and passions instead of being governed by them ; when they "shall learn war no more
                            ;" when they shall recognize the fact that "the earth is the Lord's and the fullness thereof," and is not to be
                            appropriated by a single individuato the exclusion of any other, his equal before God; when they shall
                            understand, and act in accordance with this understanding, that human beings are temples of the Holy Spirit, to
                            possess a purity far surpassing that of the inner sanctuary of the ancient temple, then will the consequences of
                            error and vice cease. Peace instead of war, abundance instead of destitution, health instead of disease, and
                            virtue instead of vice will be man's inheritance upon the earth. These will come gradually, because man is but a
                            gradual learner. The most essential thing is that each individual should know himself thoroughly and what is
                            best adapted to hia particular case. There are general laws applicable to all persons, and there are particular
                            rules far more numerous than the general. These are all stringent because they are intended to make strictly
                            upright men and women— "Who know their rights and knowing dare maintain." in spite of.the clamor of appetites
                            and passions pleading for self indulgence. Who shall know also how to respect the rights of each other in all
                            the relations of social life and yet make social life infinitely preferable to the solitary's cell. When all
                            shall have learned to govern themselves in accordance with Divine Love, then those cumbersome machines called
                            civil government will no longer be needed. Religious parties and theological rules will be superseded by a state
                            of things in which the individual shall belong completely to the whole and the whole devoted supremely to the
                            individual. Groveland, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dewitt, Maria" TEIform="index"/>Maria Dewitt
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Dewitt, Maria" TEIform="persName">Maria Dewitt</persName>, at Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. June 14, aged 74 years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Georgeson, Adam" TEIform="index"/>Adam Georgeson
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Georgeson, Adam" TEIform="persName">Adam Georgeson</persName>, at Canaan, N. Y. June 4, aged 70 years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Olson, Oloff" TEIform="index"/>Oloff Olson
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Olson, Oloff" TEIform="persName">Oloff Olson</persName>, at Pleasant Hill, Ky. Apr. 30, aged 30 years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Downing, Ann" TEIform="index"/>Ann Downing
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Downing, Ann" TEIform="persName">Ann Downing</persName>, at Pleasant Hill, Ky. May 1, aged 43 years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Barnett, John" TEIform="index"/>John Barnett
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName TEIform="persName">John Barnett</persName>, at Pleasant Hill, Ky. May 2, aged 75 years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Goodwin, Ann" TEIform="index"/>Ann Goodwin
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Goodwin, Ann" TEIform="persName">Ann Goodwin</persName>, at Mt. Lebanon N. Y. June 20, aged 78 years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hooper, Dorcas" TEIform="index"/>Darcas Hooper
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At South Union, Ky. June 27, Dorcas Hooper, aged 74 years.</p></div3></div2><pb id="p32" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial Notes</head><p TEIform="p"> We are using a number of The Bickford Knitting Machines; and they are very satisfactory indeed Being among "the
                            wonders in this age" of machinery Their utility and expedition in business should be expt rienced by all, at so
                            small cost. Material for Fences of wood variety is getting scarce. We must soon accept the alternative of no
                            fences, or rely on the 'metal ones offered us by Washburn, Moen Co. We are at a loss to speak as yet, of the
                            best Water Wheel ; but we are at no loss to say that the firms ot Leffel &amp; Co. and N. F. Burnham, who
                            enter into friend. ly competition in our columns,are both most honorable Oftentimes, we are led to regret, that
                            there are un scrupulous persons, who, realizing the solid benefits oi judicious advertising, will use it most
                            freely on some useless or worse than useless articles, and soon retire with fortunes of ill-earned gains. But we
                            can still point to thousands who by a wholesome judicious judgment, have used advertising to their exceeding
                            profit! and to the most creditable advancement of useful materials. Such, we believe our patrons to be. We have
                            taken considerable and particular pains to acquaint ourself with Dr. Frazier's remedies, and find from those
                            using them, only a good report. His Bitters are purely medicinal, and not an intoxicant beverage. Elder James S.
                            Prescott gives his endorsement of Dr. Frazier's Cough Remedy—and he is good authority. We, find Stinson and Co.
                            very honorable in their dealing. Try them. We hope "everybody and his neighbor" will send us six cents for a
                            copy of "Plain Talks;" or ten cents, for two copies post paid. It is a pretty book. Please procure it and
                            present it to yoar friend. We are able to speak of the various agricultural implements of Wheeler &amp;
                            Melick Co., and of West' inghouse manufacture. We have tested their Threshers and Powers for years, and found
                            them unexcelled. We would call especial attention to the new advertisement of N. F. Burnham. As enterprise is
                            ever praiseworthy when applied as they apply it, let every one lend this firm a token of praise. If any can do
                            better for the furnish of Dry Goods, etc. than can be done at Wm. M. Whitney &amp; Co., we would be pleased
                            to hear from such party. Take choice and choose soon from among the most beautiful musical instruments
                            advertised in our columns. Quite a number of families are the happier to-day for taking our advice, and buying
                            their Organs and Pianos of - well "read and you will know." D. II. Fonda, the most enterprising of
                            Druggists, etc. can be relied upon by parties, near by or distant, who are in want of anything in his line,
                            wholesale and retail. Try him, prove him. Any parties who would learn how we make such good, "gilt-edged''
                            butter, must read an article entitled "Gilt-Edged Butter Maker."</p></div2><!--
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p> [advertisements deleted</p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>