<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm1709" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">23</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">17</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">09</biblScope><date value="18870901" TEIform="date">September 1887</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">193-216</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="17" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="09" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1">
                    <!-- 
<pb id="p1"/>
SEPTEMBER.
THE
MANIFESTO.
Published by the United Societies,
'' Every plant which my heavenly Father hath not planted shall be rooted
up."- -Matt, xv., 13,
Canterbury, N. H.
1887,

<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
CONTENTS.
The Gospel Testimony, No. 18.
Public Discourse, No. 2,   Jteyerie,   *
As Jesus Taraght,   Tashion,
Letter,- -H. Wormboat,   Xetteiv-1" Ba&ting,
Prayer,         Retrospection,
Letter,- -D. Orcratt,
Testimony of Jethro Turner,
The Art of Giving-,
Prayer and Potatoes,
Notes,- - -Preaerh the Word,
Scientific and Practical,
The Voice of a Friend,
A Discourse,
Wfay we wear Uniform ?
ITaitb, Hope, and Love,
Words,         -.- - - - -'Books & Papers,
Kind "Words, '
Deaths,               193
197
199
202
204
205
208
209
210
211
212
214
215
216
NEW HOME SEWWG MACHINE aORANCLMASS
chsoago - 30 UNION SQUARE.N.Y-   DALLAS
Send    10 cents
and   receive   6
CHEAP Reading.
back numbers of THE HOME COMPANION, no two aiike, filled with good
reading for  all homes.           Address,
The Home Companion,
Troy, N. H.
SHORT HINTS
SOCIAL ETIQUETTE,
Compiled from, the latest and best worJcs
on the subject by "Aunt Matilda-?
PRICE, 40 cents.
 book should be in every
 family desirous of knowing "the proper thing to do."
"We all desire to behave properly and to know what is the best
school of manners. What shall
we teach our children, that they
may go out into the world well
bred men and women?
"SHORT HINTS" contains
the answer and will be mailed
to any address, postage prepaid on receipt of price.
SPECIAL
Until further notice we will
mail each of our friends a copy
of the above valuable book
gratis and free of postage, if
they will mail us 15 wrappers
of Dobbins' Electric Soap.
By folding up the wrappers
as you would a newspaper, the
postage will only be 2cts.
Always put your full name
and address on the out side of
the bundle and write the word
"Etiquette" also, and then we
will know who sends it.
I. L. CRAGIK&Co.,
PHILADELPHIA, PENN'A. i
200
<pb n="" id="p"/>
Vol.  XVII.
SEPTEMBER,  1887.
No. 9. --><pb n="193" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gospel testimony of Mother Ann Lee and the elders, William Lee and James Whittaker no. 18" TEIform="index"/> The Gospel Testimony of Mother Ann Lee and the Elders, William Lee and
                            James Whittaker. No. 18.</head><p TEIform="p"> Published expressly for the several Communities of Believers in 1816. Re-written
                            by Henry C. Blinn. Miraculous Gifts. In the history of the church of God from the earliest
                            ages we have the record of gifts which have been held as miraculous. The healing of the sick
                            has been a speciality. A faithfulness to the laws of God has sometimes been a requisite, and
                            God has healed them, as was promised in Exod. xv., 26. "It* thou wilt diligently hearken to
                            the voice of the Lord, thy God, and wilt do that which is right in his sight, and wilt give
                            ear to his commandments, and keep all his statutes, I will put none of these diseases upon
                            thee, which I brought upon the Egyptians: for I am the Lord that healeth thee;" and in Deut.
                            vii., 15. "The Lord will take away from thee all sickness, and will put none of the evil
                            diseases of Egypt, which thou knowest, upon thee ; but will lay them upon all them that hate
                            thee." Since this early date the sick have been healed by prayer, by the laying on of hands,
                            by faith, by signs, by pilgrimages aud by the ministration of spirit influence. The prophets
                            were gifted to heal the sick, and to give sight to the blind. Jesus gave this gift a
                            prominent place in his ministry, and it continued to be one of importance with all of the
                            apostles. Many of these marvelous gifts attended the spiritual work of Mother Ann and the
                            Elders, and were received as among the blessings of the gospel. The Believers, however,
                            never placed these gifts so fully in the foreground as to exclude others of more value. They
                            taught that.the blessed fruits of the gospel, a practical righteousness and a victory over
                            wrong, were the most powerful evidences in favor of its truthfulness, and that honest,
                            upright souls would not be anxious for outward demonstrations. That ten thousand outward or
                            physical miracles would never redeem the soul to God. It was a love for the truth, and a
                            spirit of obedience for the principles of righteousness that would establish the Believer
                            upon a sure foundation. That these gifts of healing have been manifested by the righteous
                            and as well by the unrighteous, and given occasion for controversy, which in the end has <pb n="194" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/>produced offences against the sacred cause. A better test
                            of a divine life is,- -By their fruits ye shall know them, whether they be good or whether
                            they be evil." Multitudes of cases might be collected, bearing an extraordinary appearance,
                            but the following may prove sufficient. Noah Wheaten of New Lebanon, was formerly the
                            captain of a whaleship a man of singular courage and invincible fortitude. In the year 1780
                            in July he was clearing a piece of land about forty rods from his house. On going to a
                            spring for some drink, he jumped from a fence and by mishap, dislocated his ankle, and broke
                            the outer bone of his leg just above the ankle joint. He crawled back to the place of his
                            work, as he was unwilling to go to the house, on account of the enmity of his unbelieving
                            neighbors, to whom he had often testified his faith, and now could expect from them nothing
                            but derision. The pain increased in the swollen ankle, as he continued in the woods, for
                            some two hours or more, and this was accompanied with great distress of mind. At length he
                            crawled home on his hands and knees, under extreme mortification, of spirit for this
                            misfortune, yet he was full of faith and confidence in the gift of miracles which he had so
                            strongly testified to his unbelieving neighbors. He now felt the trial of his faith, and was
                            resolved not to mar his testimony by flinching from it. He refused the assistance of a
                            physician, or any attempt to set the bone, or even any outward application for the
                            mitigating of the pain. Consequently his ankle and leg swelled greatly, and was excessively
                            painful. While in this situation several of his unbelieving neighbors came to see him, and
                            also many of the Believers. Confident of a miraculous cure to confirm his testimony to the
                            friends present he would not submit to the ordinary means of relief. He remained, as above,
                            from two o'clock P. M. till the evening of the following day, during which time he was in
                            prayer to God for a miraculous cure. While the family were assembled for their evening
                            worship, the spirit of God came upon him, and he was taken from his seat and whirled swiftly
                            around on his feet like a top for nearly two hours, without the least pain or inconvenience.
                            He then retired to rest, well and comfortable, and the next morning arose in health and took
                            his team to plow in the field. The neighbors hearing of the miraculous cure came to see him,
                            and to express their wonder at so remarkable au event. Phebe Spencer of New Lebanon in the
                            year 1781 while erossiug a bridge, the horse broke through throwing her backwards, and
                            falling upon the timbers broke two of her ribs, on the right side. She was carried into the
                            house in an insensible condition. The neighbors urged her to send for a physician, but she
                            could feel no freedom to do it, although in extreme pain. Jabesh, her husband, was also
                            asked to send for a physician, but hesitated on account of her objectionable feelings. The
                            neighbors considered this unwillingness to be obstinate wilfulness, and that as she was a
                            Shaker, she would not receive any assistance from the physicians. She still refused to
                            accept medical aid and remained a sufferer till the next Tuesday, when her husband
                                reminded<pb n="195" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> her of the advice given by the Apostle James,
                            "Is any sick among you, let him call for the Elders of the church," A proposition was then
                            made to send for some of the Believers, to which Phebe consented. At this time she was
                            unable to rise from her bed. Hezekiah Hammond took hold of her hand, and told her to labor
                            for the power of God, and take faith. She was immediately released so far as to be able to
                            breathe and speak without difficulty. The next day, the whole family kneeled by the side of
                            the bed and soon after she arose and sat in a chair. In a few moments she stood up the
                            recipient of a healing gift. From this time she continued to improve aud did not share the
                            least symptom of pain or inconvenience, arising from the fall. This miraculous gift was
                            accepted by the whole family, Jonathan Turner when nine years of age was chopping wood, aud
                            by a stroke from the ax, received a very bad wound on the top of his foot. He was carried to
                            his home, the wound bleeding profusely. His mother was in distress as she did not know what
                            to do for it. She then retired to another room to pray, aud receiving an answer to her
                            prayers, by being filled with the spirit of God, and feeling confident that it was a gift of
                            healing for her son, she returned directly to the room and put her hand on the wound, and it
                            instantly ceased bleeding. She now walked the floor, and again laid her hand on the wound;
                            this she repeated seven times, during which time it closed up and was healed. The next
                            morning no appearance of the wound was seen, except a small white seam. The boy was fully
                            restored and found no inconvenience from it afterwards. Sarah Jewett of Littleton by a
                            sudden cold, lost her health and for some time was unable to take her food. At this time the
                            Elders were on a visit to Littleton. Father William admonished her, saying,- -'' You do not
                            do as well as you know. Go," said he, "and sin no more, lest a worse thing come upon thee."
                            From this date her health began to impruve, till she was better than ever before. In 1783
                            Abiathar Babbitt was sick with the mumps and having taken a sudden cold he was dangerously
                            ill. Elder John Hocknell was sent to Petersham to see him, and soon ordered him to take the
                            muffler from his face, which Abiathar resented. Elder John then bid him run aud leap, which
                            he did with much difficulty. Elder John then bid him take faith aud go to work. From that
                            day he was healed of his disease. Elizabeth Robinson of Harvard was suffering with a badly
                            swollen and sore throat. Mother Ann laid her hand on it, and the throat was healed. Lucy
                            Prescott was afflicted with a severe cough, and was reduced to a low state of health. Mother
                            Ann asked Lucy- -"Are you not willing to suffer with me? I experience much suffering." Lucy
                            answered, "Yea Mother I am willing," Mother then gave her a little cordial, but Lucy
                            hesitated to drink it as her stomach was so inflamed. Mother said to her, '' Drink it; it
                            will not hurt you," and from that time Lucy improved in health.<pb n="196" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> Moses Mixer had his ankle bones dislocated and though they had been set
                            by a skillful surgeon, yet he remained very weak. His friends prevailed on him to visit the
                            Elders at Watervliet. He traveled some distance on foot which increased the swelling and
                            made the ankle, very painful. On reaching the house he was obliged to sit quietly for some
                            time on account of the pain, Elder John Hocknell asked him why he retired and then bid him
                            take faith in God. As Elder John placed his hand upon the swollen limb the pain and swelling
                            immediately left it. and from that moment he was able to walk with neither pain nor
                            distress. Daniel Goodrich went to Watervliet to see the Elders. Some of his children
                            accompanied him. One of the little girls was carried as she by a fall had dislocated the
                            hip, and they had fears that her l'jg would perish. Daniel was sadly afflicted by this
                            circumstance and expressed the same to the Elders. Mother Ann soon after assembled his
                            children in the room and spoke to them. - -'0 Daniel, God has given you a special gift of
                            faith. Signs and operations will fail, but faith and obedience will carry you through. Bear
                            your testimony, purge your house and your family from sin, and you will gather your whole
                            family." Mother then took the little lame girl to her and placed her hands on the injured
                            part, and said, "Go home, Daniel, and be faithful. This your child will become well." They
                            soon left the place and the child was healed. The whole family embraced the faith of the
                            gospel. Zacheus Stevens was on a visit to Watervliet with Eleazer Rand. Zacheus was taken
                            dangerously ill. He informed Mother Ann that he had a large amount of unsettled business.
                            Mother Ann then told him that he must send Eleazer for his horse, as, said she, " You must
                            take faith and leave tomorrow morning for your home, and you will recover your health. "
                            This command was unexpected and seemed strange to Zacheus ard to all who saw him. Eleazer
                            thought it very singular to attempt a journey of one hundred and fifty miles, when a man was
                            thought to be so near to death. In obedience to Mother Ann the two Brethren left the place
                            the following morning and traveled thirty miles the first dav and on the whole journey
                            Zacheus continued to increase in strength and arrived at his own house in Harvard Mass., in
                            comf rtable health. John Bishop of New Lebanon made a journey to As'ufield to see the
                            Elders. 1 he first day he walked ten miles and the next day thirty miles and reached the
                            house of Asa Bacon not far from six o'clock. P. M. As he was unaccustomed to traveling on
                            foot, he felt very wear}7 and lame. Mother Ann passing through the room, placed her hand on
                            him, but did not speak to him. In a moment his weariness and lameness was gone, and John
                            remained in the meeting till twelve o'clock. He then walked half a mile to the residence of
                            Moses Bacon, wrapped himself in his great coat, and making the floor his couch slept as
                            comfortably as though he had been on a bed of feathers. Zadock Wright visited the Believers
                            at Ashfield. He was under deep anxiety of mind and felt very sad. Moth- <pb n="197" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> er Ann, passing through the assembly, said to Zadock '-Repent" and the
                            burden immediately left him. Numerous instances like the foregoing were very common, during
                            the ministration of Mother Ann. Brethren and Sisters who visited the church under
                            tribulation and sufferings of either body or mind, were often instantly released and filled
                            with prayer and praise. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Public discourse no. 2" TEIform="index"/> PUBLIC DISCOURSE, No. 2.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="McNemar, Richard" TEIform="persName"/>BY RICHARD MC. NEMAB.</byline><p TEIform="p"> It is also to be considered, as an undeniable truth, that when Christ came, his
                            commission was not to sanction and continue the old covenant, but to bring in and confirm a
                            new covenant of greater efficiency and more direct efficacy. "- -But now hath he obtained a
                            more excellent ministry, by how much also is he the mediator of h better covenant, which
                            hath been established on better promises. For if the first covenant had been faultless, a
                            place should not have been sought for the second. Behold, the days are coming, saith the
                            Lord, when I will make a new covenant with the house of Israel, and with the house of Judah.
                            In that he saith a new covenant he hath made the first old. Now that which decayeth and
                            waxeth old is ready to vanish away." Jt is however, to be remembered, that not the
                            righteousness or spirit of the law is rejected, by doing away the old testament of outward
                            ordinances, for the law is confirmed in Christ. "Do we then make void the law through faith
                            ? By no means ; but we establish the law." It is farther to be considered that the opinion
                            that salvation was to be found by faith in Christ before he was revealed is founded on a
                            false view of his errand into the world ; namely, that he came as a surety for sinners, to
                            pay to God, in their stead, the debt which they owed; or to fulfill the law, suffer its
                            penalty, and satisfy divine justice as their surety and substitute, and that his
                            righteousness might be imputed to them for their justification and acceptance with God. But
                            we have not so learned Christ. That was not his errand ; but to reveal or declare the
                            Father. " No man hath seen God at any time ; the only begotten Son, who is in the bosom of
                            the Father, he hath declared him." To declare or set forth to view, his righteousness, not
                            for the remission of sins by imputation : but as "a propitiation through faith in his blood,
                            for an exhibition of his righteousness for the dismission of sins before committed, in the
                            forbearance of God, that he may be just aud a justifier, who is of the faith of Jesus." "If
                            any one will come after me, let him deny himself, and take up his cross and follow me." "Be
                            ye followers of me, even as I also am of Christ." This is the true order of God, in the
                            redemption of souls, and though little understood before the coming of Christ, we find it
                            well expressed in the words of Elihu. "If there be a messenger with him, an interpreter, one
                            among a thousand, to show unto man his uprightness ; then he is gracious unto him." This is
                            very contrary to the prevalent notion of man, that a man may obtain redemption in secret,
                            with God alone, without any visible medium. There must be an interpreter or minister to show
                            to man his uprightness, to declare the righteousness of God, which<pb n="198" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> is found in the minister, and is his righteousness, and can be shown no
                            other way. Thus the errand of Christ was to consecrate the new and living way, in
                            distinction from the old way of sin, condemnation and death. "Behold I have given him for a
                            witness to the people, a leader and commander to the people.'* The apostle is very pointed
                            and explicit that the way into the holy of holies, that is into heaven, was not opened or
                            known during the dispensation of the law: for speaking of the tabernacle, he saith. "Now
                            when these things were thus prepared, the priests entered indeed at all times, into the
                            first tabernacle, accomplishing the service ; but into the second went the high priest alone
                            once in the year without blood, which he offered for himself and the errors of the people,
                            the Holy Spirit this signifying, that the way into the holiest of all was not yet made
                            manifest, while the first tabernacle was yet standing; which was a figure for the time then
                            present, in which were offered both gifts and sacrifices, which could not perfect him that
                            served, as pertaining to the conscience ; which consisted only in meats and drinks, and
                            divers washings, and justifications of the flesh, imposed until the time of reformation.
                            Christ being come, a high priest of the good things to come, by a better and more perfect
                            tabernacle, not made with hands, that is, not of this creation ; neither by the blood of
                            goats and calves, but by his own blood, he entered once into the holy place, having obtained
                            eternal redemption." It may be said, Of what use was the law, and what benefit was by it, if
                            it did not save the people, and no redemption could be found, during its operation ? Was it
                            not a hindrance to life and salvation, rather than any benefit to its subjects or to
                            mankind? What preference then had the Jew ? Much every way. In the first place, indeed,
                            because the oracles of God were delivered to them and believed. The oracles of God,
                            therefore, were not unprofitable to all. The law served to keep the people in remembrance of
                            their rebellion, and their exposedness to misery, by the just judgment of God, without a
                            Redeemer. But the law did not, and could not abolish and make void the testament, or promise
                            which God had confirmed to Abraham and his seed before the law was given. These things are
                            briefly stated in the following scriptures. "Brethren, I speak after the manner of men ;
                            likewise, a man's testament when confirmed, no man disannulled or addeth thereto. Now, the
                            promises were spoken to Abraham and his seed. And this I say, the law, made four hundred and
                            thirty years after, cannot disannul the covenant before confirmed of God to Christ, to make
                            void the promise. Now if the inheritance were of law, it were no longer of promise. Then
                            what doeth the law ? It was added because of transgressions, until he should come to whom
                            the promise was made, being ordained by angels in the hand of a mediator, who was a proper
                            type of Christ, the mediator of the New Testament. "Now, a mediator is not of one, but God
                            is one," therefore his work is uniform, and the use of a mediator was to show the nature and
                            intent of the testament between two,- -the testator and legatees, and to unite the people
                            into one with him.<pb n="199" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> " Is the law theu against the promises
                            of God ? By no means ; but if a law had been given able to communicate life, verily
                            righteousness had been by the law," and thus the law had been contrary to the promise. "For
                            if the inheritance were of the law, it were no lowger of promise. For if they who are of the
                            law be heirs, faith is made void, and the promise disannulled." "But the Scripture hath
                            concluded them all under sin, that the promise by faith of Jesus Christ might be given to
                            them that believe," in him when he came and his faith was made known. For before the faith
                            came, we were kept under the law, shut up to the faith which was about to be revealed, and
                            which we could not know nor put in exercise until it was revealed. Wherefore the law was
                            made our schoolmaster unto Christ that we might be justified by faith. But the faith being
                            come we are no longer under a child guide. For ye are all children of God through the faith
                            which is in Christ Jesus. For as many of you as have been baptized into Christ, have put on
                            Christ. There is neither Jew nor Greek, there is neither bond nor free, for ye are all one
                            in Christ Jesus. Union Village, 0. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reverie" TEIform="index"/> REVERIE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cumings, Rosetta" TEIform="persName"/>ROSETTA CUMINGS.</byline><p TEIform="p"> However varying the scenes of time, Which mark the busy moments as they pass;
                            Sometimes disclosing joys unsought, unseen, And yet again with chilling, icy grasp- -
                            Destroying bliss which in prospectus beams, Fond hopes of pleasure which the future holds.
                            All beautiful and bright the vision seems, Thefutuie moments valued are as gold. Vet when
                            the present brings within our reach Those joys which in the distance seemed so fair, The
                            blessing vanishes; we sets it not, The promised bliss is gone we know not where. And yet the
                            Father merciful and kind, Unable as we are to scan his way, Provides with ever bountiful
                            design, Blessings unnumbered for us every day. O! that we learn to prize his goodness more,
                            And view in every gift his love divine, fpower The same strong arm which holds the tempest's
                            Scatters the dew and bids the sun to shine. And though his smiling face be veiled today,
                            'Tis all the same his goodness and his care Are just as real, as when with milder grace, He
                            answers to our fondest wish and prayer. And Heaven's best gifts to us are often sent
                            Disguised in sorrows which we welcome not. We take them, but how little realize If rightly
                            borne, what good in us is wrought. We sigh and murmur when our Father's hand Is working for
                            our best eternal good; Accept we must, the good we do not find, Did we but prize these
                            trials as we should. For though in stormy paths our feet must walk, Pierced with the thorns
                            of worldliness and pride, We have no reason to complain or doubt If in a Father's care our
                            souls confide. And wheresoe'er our lot in life is cast, Whate'er the trials which to us may
                            come, Help us repeat with confidence and trust Thy righteous will O Lord, not mine be done.
                            Enfield, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="As Jesus taught" TEIform="index"/> AS JESUS TAUGHT.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Woods, Joseph H." TEIform="persName"/>JOSEPH H. WOODS.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Jesus for the joy that was set before him endured the cross, despising the shame
                            and is set down at the right hand of the Throne of God. When the council of the Jews had
                            punished the disciples and commanded them that they should not speak in the name of Jesus,
                            the Apostles departed, rejoicing that they were accounted worthy to suffer shame for his
                            name. The doctrine which Jesus taught of regeneration, the virgin life, breaking up of
                            earthly selfish ties, the forsaking of all that a man hath for Christ's sake, was treated
                            with contempt by the Jews ; and such as confessed that Jesus was the Christ, they cast out
                            of the Synagogue. Jesus said, "Whosoever is ashamed of me and my words of him<pb n="200" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/>shall the Son of man be ashamed, when he cometh in . the glory of
                            his Father with the holy angel?. " Herein is the Christian's duty clearly exemplified. Let
                            us more closely follow in the footsteps of him who so encouragingly testified to his
                            followers "Be of srood cheer for I have overcome the world," that we may be worthy to sit
                            down with him in the Kingdom of our God. Canterbury, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fashion" TEIform="index"/> FASHION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/> MARTHA J. ANDERSON.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Fashion sways the world ; her dictates are absolute, and her whims imperious.
                            The worshipers at. the ancient shrines of heathen deities, were not half so numerous as the
                            devotees who compass her altars. Her image is in every household, aud in the througing
                            thoroughfare her name is flaunted to your sight. ''Great is Diana of the Ephesians !" was
                            the cry of old; so we may repeat. Mighty is this sovereign goddess of the people ! No matter
                            what her hideous transformation from crown to heel, she is the same beauteous creature, sent
                            by Jove, to fascinate and afflict mankind. All the nymphs of earth, air and water, combine
                            to lend some novel charm to her changeful being. Unsightly shapes dame Nature never wore ;
                            ludicrous bumps, aod abnormal compressions, that distort the human form divine ; and all
                            that fancy's vagaries can invent, are forced upon her votaries, and they, her willing or
                            unwilling slaves are fast bound in the thralldom her service imposes. Is there no power that
                            can rise in the name of common sense and justice, to dethrone this tyrant, and proclaim
                            mankind free to live, to dress and act, according to the demands of their own conscience and
                            reason ? Men and women should be noble in mind, perfect in form and upright io spirit; not
                            mere apes or illusory phantoms of life. A sound mind in a sound body cannot be attained, so
                            long as the people allow themselves to become mere manikins in the hands of the fashionable
                            mantua-makers aud tailors of the world. If men aud women who love truth and righteousness,
                            and hate the hollow shams of society, had the moral courage to rise superior to their
                            surroundings, and live for health and comfort; practically and earnestly bearing their
                            testimony against the evils and follies of fashion ; soon would the vain goddess turn her
                            face, abashed, and retire in ignominy and disgrace, acknowledging that she had ruled the
                            world too long. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear elder Avery: Your very kind and interesting letter..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Dear elder Avery: Your very kind and interesting letter... </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Holland, Schiedam, June 1, 1887" TEIform="index"/> Schiedam, Holland, June 1,
                            1887. </dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Elder A very :- -Your very kind and interesting letter, together with the
                            books, were duly received by me, and I must first of all thank you and the society which you
                            represent, for sending me this most instructive reading1 matter. I have read the pamphlets
                            and am about to read the large book. I have at any rate obtained some idea of your views in
                            regard to doctrinal points wherein you differ from the other denominations, and I must
                            admit, that however new and strange they appeared to me at first, I can concur in many of
                            them. For instance, your teaching in regard<pb n="201" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> to the divine
                            Fatherhood and Motherhood of God is to me a sublime idea. For as in nature no child is the
                            offspring of but one parent, so in the divine order of things Christ must have had an
                            Eternal Mother as well as an Eternal Father. And likewise as a male does not represent a
                            whole human family, neither can there be a perfect divine family without a daughter. This is
                            clear to me, but, what I should like to read above all things is an impartial Biography of
                            Mother Ann Lee. I can fully believe that she was a very holy woman, but the subject is too
                            scantily treated in the books which you had the kindness to send, to take away my doubts on
                            that point. You surely are not ignorant of the fact that other women have put forth claims
                            of a divine mission; amongst others I will name a country woman of Mother Ann Lee, Johanna
                            Southcote, who also professed to receive revelations from heaven. Now I know nothing of the
                            latter person but what I have just stated. If we believe in the manifestation of the divine
                            daughter, it is of the highest importance in whom that Daughter Spirit was revealed. I
                            admire your views upon matrimony very much. To my mind they are most logical. A tree is
                            known by its fruits and if the fruit is bad, how then can such a tree be called good. Let
                            the tree represent the marriage state and the children, (conceived and born in sin) the
                            fruit, how then can a state of life which is a continual spreading of sin, be called holy?
                            And if not holy, how can it be a gospel state of life, pure in the sight of God and
                            permitted by Him in his true church ? Your having all things in common is too plainly
                            apostolic to require any discussion. Your place for our Lord Jesus Christ in Shaker theology
                            I can't comprehend very well, but I believe Him to, be equal to the Father in divinity, and
                            therefore as much, according to his divine nature, an object of supreme adoration. You Jpave
                            not mentioned anything about the price of the books in your letter. If you intended them as
                            a present from the Society, permit me to express my sincere thanks; if not I thank you all
                            the same for the trouble you have taken, and beg to know how much I am in your debt.
                            Thanking you once more for your kindness, I remain, dear Elder, gratefully your friend</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wormhout, H." TEIform="persName"/>H. Wormhout.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="No time to waste" TEIform="index"/>NO TIME TO WASTE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hastings, Marcia E." TEIform="persName"/>MARCIA E. HASTINGS.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Moments are precious, spiritual needs abundant; there is no time to be spent in
                            frivolous use, talking aimlessly on subjects that are of no consequence, harping on
                            something that roils our selfish sensitiveness, affecting no good purpose, in fact effecting
                            nothing only weakening our ability to concentrate our minds and efforts to do and accomplish
                            something in the way of improvement upon ourselves or others, defiling our own spirits and
                            making us unhappy,- - sour and unlovable; even the saints feel pity for such rather than
                            admire them. So let us cherish love and sweetness ; diligently pursue the ways of Wisdom
                            which are ways of pleasantness, and all her paths are peace. Canterbury, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Absence of occupation is not rest..." TEIform="index"/>Absence of occupation
                            is not rest... </head><p TEIform="p"> Absence of occupation is not rest; A mind quite vacant is a mind distressed.</p></div2><pb n="202" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My good sir: Will you kindly..." TEIform="index"/>My good sir: Will you
                            kindly... </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New Hampshire, Exeter, June 23, 1887" TEIform="index"/> Exeter, N. H., June
                            23, 1887.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> My good sir :- -Will you kindly give me information regarding the Shakers? Their
                            history, customs, religious services, requirements for membership. Do they perform the
                            ceremony of baptism? If so, by immersion or sprinkling? Have they a creed or ^articles of
                            faith? A reply will greatly oblige, most sincerely yours, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="M., C." TEIform="persName"/>C. M.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Respected friend: In answer of your favor..." TEIform="index"/> Respected
                            friend: In answer of your favor... </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon, July 2, 1887" TEIform="index"/> REPLY, Mt, Lebanon,
                            N. Y., July 2, 1887.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> C. M., Exeter, N. H. Respected Friend:- -In answer of your favor of June 23rd, I
                            beg to say that a full reply to y- -ur questions would necessitate the writing of a small
                            volume, which the multitude of other duties forbids. However I will endeavor to gratify your
                            wishes as far as possible within the limits of a letter. 1. History. The history of Shakers
                            and Shakerism is bound up in the history of the Christian church from the remotest primitive
                            times up to the present day. The truths which our Savior Jesus Christ taught were to be
                            applied to two separate orders- -the earthly and the spiritual. The former was to conform to
                            the standard of righteousness as set forth in the Mosaic law, i. e. they were to do right in
                            all their social and private, political, commercial and economic relations ; while the
                            adherents of the latter were neither to marry nor to be given in marriage, but to be as the
                            angels in heaven ; they were not to hold private property, not to mix in political affairs,
                            forsaking father and mother, wife, husband and children, houses and lands, tor the kingdom
                            of heaven's sake, and live apart from the world, being: obedient to the requirements of
                            their faith in all things. These principles were largely adopted in the early church where
                            celibacy and community of goods were distinguished features. The celibacy of the priesthood
                            and the mouasticism of the Roman catholic and Greek catholic churches, and the movement now
                            going on within the Episcopal church for the creation of celibate societies, are all
                            recognitions of the same principles. Modern Shakerism was founded in the latter part of the
                            eighteenth century by Ann Lee, of Manchester, who resuscitated from oblivion the divine
                            principles of the higher life and embodied them in a rational commonsense system of theology
                            and practical life. 2. Customs. Believers, called Shakers, dress plainly and for comfort
                            an.! utility ; they do not follow the ups and riovvns oi' the fashions of this world; they
                            use plain forms of speech ; men and women dwell apart, yet are united as Brethren and
                            Sisters, taking their meals together in silence, aud meeting in social intercourse and
                            devotional worship. All are expected to take part in physical labor according to capacity
                            aud training, and all good Believers engage freely in spiritual labor for the overcoming of
                            the world within and for the acquisition and maintenance of true gospel faith and practice.
                            3. Religious services. Religious services are held in family privacy aud at the society
                            meeting he use, and are conducted by elders appointed for that purpose. The exercises
                            consist of marching, singing and speaking, and the cultivation of such spiritual gifts as<pb n="203" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> may best meet the necessities of individuals and
                            societies. 4. Requirements for membership. Persons desirous of uniting with us must adjust
                            all lawful debts and obligation they may be under. Married people are expected either to
                            separate by mutual consent or legal process and the right of children are to be carefully
                            guarded. The first step on entering is the confession of all known sin in the presence of a
                            witness. Novitiate members may re tain control of their property ; covenaut members
                            consecrate all interests to the use of the society. Obedience to the authority vested in
                            Elders and other offi cials and faithful conformity to such rules and orders as "\re or may
                            be established, is required of all. 5. Baptism. Nay ; the Shakers do not baptize with water,
                            neither by sprinkling nor immersion. While they have a profound admiration for the efficacy
                            of water, when frequently and freely applied in connection with soap and sponge and towel,
                            the baptism they believe in and are seeking for is that spiritual baptism that even Jesus
                            declared he was much straightened to obtain. 6. Creed. Nor have the Shakers a written creed
                            or formal articles of faith, but they hold to certain well-defined principles the fruits of
                            which appear in the inner life and outward appearance of Shaker communities. They also
                            possess a complete system of theology that for beauty, simplicity and sound sense challenges
                            comparison with any other system, old or new. They believe iu God as the creator and
                            sustainer of the universe and worship him as the Father and Mother of all. Jesus Christ, a
                            man divinely inspired to teach and reveal by word and example the truth of life and
                            immortality, our Elder Brother ; Mother Ann, a follower of Jesus, our Elder Sister; the
                            resurrection of the bo:'y is denied, but the immortality of all good souls rejoiced in ; the
                            communion with the spirit world is accepted, but the external phenomena of spiritualism are
                            considered as of rather doubtful utility ; there is progressive development of the soul in
                            the next world- -"the gospel will be preached to all in the spirit-land," was the teaching
                            of Mother Ann ; an endless hell does not exist, but souls suffer the consequences of their
                            wrong-doing till repented of and atoned for, while the good and the righteous enjoy the
                            fruits of well-doing. It is held that the Bible contains a large portion of the word of God-
                            -not all, but for its interpretation neither Rome nor Westminster, Andover or Princeton, are
                            appealed to. Shakers do not believe in the propriety of making themselves unhappy and
                            miserable in this world for the sake of being happy in the next. A. good Shaker is the most
                            thoroughly happy being in existence. Why not ? The world, the flesh and the devil have no
                            attractions for him ; he is at peace with God, himself and his neighbor; he lives by the
                            fruit of his own labor and owes no man anything but love and good will; he is prepared at
                            any time, come the call to-day or to-morrow, to meet the blessed realities of the unseen
                            world. This felicity is not, of course, obtained by the mere adoption and outward conformity
                            to Shaker life and rule ; it is a matter of growth, labor, and patient endeavor. What do you
                            think of it all? I am your friend and well wisher, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Basting, Louis" TEIform="persName"/>Louis Basting.</byline></div2><pb n="204" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prayer" TEIform="index"/> PRAYER.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Carll, Anna P." TEIform="persName"/> ANNA P. CARLL.</byline><p TEIform="p"> See Luke, chap, xiii., 11, 12, 13. Jtjdea's hills were clothed with light. A
                            light was on the plain ; And Sabbath peace was over all That to the temple came. 'Twas in
                            that Jewish synagogue, This sunny Sabbath morn, A woman bent with weight of years, Came
                            there among the throng;- - She came to hear the holy word, To join in humble prayer; She
                            could not know her blessed Lord Would meet and heal her there. He saw her needs and from
                            that host, He called her to his side; Then with a touch he healed her pain, And God was
                            glorified. And there she stood in perfect health, Her bonds were rent in twain; She felt the
                            saving power of grace, Restore her strength again. And so I come into Thy House, Bent low
                            with cares and fears ; O may I hear Thy heavenly word Fall on my listening ears. That as I
                            hasten to obey The pleadings of Thy voice, My troubles all will fade away And leave me to
                            rejoice. For now I bend beneath the load Of sin and sore distress ; If thou but touch the
                            burden Lord, It can no more oppress. And like the stricken one of old, 0 grant me full
                            release; So shall I find Thy ways my choice, And in Thy paths my peace. Providence, R. I.
                        </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Retrospection" TEIform="index"/> RETROSPECTION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Calver, Amelia J." TEIform="persName"/> AMELIA J. CALVER.</byline><p TEIform="p"> There cometh a time when we shall look back upon life, and see in the many
                            vicissitudes of our pilgrimage here, that the real " means of grace" by which the true
                            development of spirit has been attained, have been unappreciated. As such then, should we
                            view the shaded glen of the pathway. In the broad sunlight we walk by sight, thus develop
                            strength, activity; but as the shadows lengthen we feel our way, and thus grow careful and
                            thoughtful, while a trusting confidence in the good within and without leads us on. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear children: The wages of sin is..." TEIform="index"/>Dear children: The
                            wages of sin is... </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Connecticut, Enfield, 1887" TEIform="index"/> Enfield, Conn., 1887.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Dear Children:- -k-The wages of sin is death." Sin hardens the heart, darkens
                            the conscience, and leads away from the love of good. Many desire the pleasures of sin but
                            not its punishment. The law of retribution is inevitable ; if you cin you must pay the!
                            penalty. Every act reacts on the actor. Consider the consequences of sin and shun the
                            beginning of it. Sin, if not subdued, grows from bad to worse. Living in sin blights the
                            spirit. Die to sin. Bad habits are vile weeds. Shuu them ever. Oue sin subdued brings joy to
                            the soul. Each victory will help you some other to win. Watchfulness is a safeguard against
                            sin. Watch all the time. Resolutely turn from all deceit and wrong, and do just as nearly
                            what you know to be right as possible. Wrong is no less wrong because you may think it a
                            little item. You are developing your characters by the lives you live, and by the thoughts
                            you indulge. Soon the fruit will appear. Tares produce poisonous fruit. wt Walking the path
                            of death and sin yields naught but pain and grief within." Sin cannot be too faithfully
                            fought <pb n="205" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> against and resisted. While your day lasts guard
                            well your hearts that no evil shall grow therein. Say to the tempter " Get thee hence."
                            Close your minds to thoughts that soil the life ; your souls to impressions that may destroy
                            your happiness. Practice virtue and vice will be hateful. If temptation insists, persist in
                            resisting. Sinful by-paths are alluring. Beware. When you are tempted to do wrong, keep your
                            promise and be strong. Your brother, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt. </byline></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Testimony of Jethro Turner" TEIform="index"/> TESTIMONY OF JETHRO TURNER.</head><p TEIform="p"> In the spring of the year 1780, we heard of a religious people residing in the
                            wilderness, about seven miles northwest of Albany, who were different from all other sects
                            known in the world. During the preceding year, there had been a great out-pouring of the
                            spirit of conviction, which produced a remarkable revival of religion in and about
                            New-Lebanon. The subjects of this revival felt assured by the spirit of prophecy which
                            attended it, that the commencement of the latter day of glory was approaching, and very near
                            at hand, and were therefore anxiously looking for it. But knowing that the world was full of
                            professions, and that false religion greatly abounded, they were determined not to be
                            imposed upon by any religious pretensions which did not save the soul from sin, and afford
                            that enduring substance of spiritual life which could not die away. With these impressions,
                            some of the leading characters of the late revival, at the solicitation of the people, went
                            to see these strangers, to inquire into the nature of their religion. After a close and
                            careful examination, they were fully satisfied, and on their return made a favorable report,
                            and advised (he people to go and see, and judge for themselves. Soon after this, many of the
                            inhabitants of New-Lebanon and the neighboring towns, went to visit these singular people
                            and satisfy themselves ; and they were soon convinced that this little family, who dwelt ia
                            the wilderness, retired from all the rest of the world, were the people of the living God
                            and possessed the gospel of salvation. In June following, I went, in company with my father,
                            to see them, being then sixteen years of age. We were kindly received by Mother Ann Lee and
                            her little family. Several young people of my acquaintance were there at the time; and the
                            weather being warm, Mother Ann came out and took a seat in the shade ol the house ; and we
                            soon gathered round her to see how she looked, and what she would say to us. She spoke to us
                            iu the following manner : "They that are wise will consider their latter end before it be
                            too late. Itisa beautiful sight to see young people set out to follow Christ in the
                            regeneration, before the evil days come." I asked, ilow shall we follow Christ? She said, '-
                            -'There is no one that can follow Christ short of confessing and forsaking all their sins."
                            She also spoke in substance as follows: ''They that are young, who make it their abiding
                            choice to follow Christ in the regeneration, will find it much easier to travel into the
                            gifts of God, in the union of the spirit, than those that have lived many years in the sins
                            of the world : or every work of the flesh is death to the soul." There were several young
                                people<pb n="206" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> present who had already confessed their sins,
                            and had received the power of God which was manifested in various and marvelous operations,
                            in signs and visions, in speaking with tongues, prophesying. But these gifts of the Spirit,
                            though marvelous and striking, did not operate so effectually upon my feelings, as the
                            heart-searching power of Mother Ann's labors with me the next morning. Here she wrought up m
                            my sensibility, and made me feel the force of the cross to some purpose. Nothing in nature,
                            nothing short of Divine Power could have given me such a feeling and powerful sense of the
                            cross of Christ ag .inst a carnal nature, as her labors at this time. I had, the day before,
                            manifested a state of mind by no means consistent with the demeanor of a humble penitent
                            seeking the mercy of God, and meekly subjecting to the cross of Christ for salvation ; but
                            had rather affected to consider the cross as no weighty matter with me. I was therefore
                            fully convinced that this powerful sensation of the cross was laid upon my spirit, to show
                            me that I could not treat the cross as a trifling matter, without being bi'ought to feel its
                            force. Here I received the first planting of the gospel of Christ in my soul; and here was
                            the beginning of my obedience to my gospel parents. After Mother Ann had given my father
                            some counsel concerning his family, and taught us our duty in the path of righteousness, we
                            returned home. In about two or three weeks from this time, I went again to see Mother and
                            the Elders at Watervliet, where, after opening my mind, I found much comfort and
                            releasement. At this time they were thronged with people from different places, who came to
                            see the work of God. The testimony of the gospel was strong and powerful against the man of
                            sin, and all that was of the world- -"the lust of the flesh, the lust of the eye and the
                            pride of life." Believers daily increased in numbers, and grew in the knowledge of the
                            gospel, and in the gifts of God. But the more Believers increased in number, and in the
                            power and gifts of the Spirit, so much the more did the enmity of the wicked rage against
                            the work of God ; which was vented out in malignant slanders and false accusations against
                            Mother and the Elders. These accusations brought against Mother Ann and the Elders were
                            known to be false ; because the Believers were personally and intimately acquainted with
                            her, having been, more or less of them, continually with her, by day and night, from the
                            time the people in this country began to embrace her testimony till she left this world ;
                            except when she was in prison at Poughkeepsie; and even there she was several times visited
                            by them. So that they well knew, and were fully able to bear witness to the purity of her
                            life and character, and could easily see from what spirit such accusations proceeded. After
                            Mother Ann and the Elders were imprisoned in Albany, I went to see them again, and was
                            permitted to enter the prison where they were, and stayed with them some time. Their spirits
                            were clothed with meekness and innocence; and though their bodies were confined within the
                            walls of a prison, yet their souls were not bound. Here they worshiped God, and sung his
                            praise in heavenly songs. Nor was the word of God bound : for they preached <pb n="207" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> the gospel through the grates of their prison, to multitudes of
                            people ; and mauy there embraced it, and set out thenceforth in the way of eternal life. I
                            was frequently with them from the time I first found them till they left this world. And in
                            all my acquaintance with Mother Ann, in all places, I never saw anything in her but the
                            image and spirit of Christ. Her temperance in eating and drinking; her patience and
                            resignation tn tribulation and sufferings ; her firmness, meekness and humility in times of
                            persecution and affliction, all bore incontestible evidence of the spirit of Christ, with
                            which her soul was abundantly filled. The s-ame remarks will apply to Elders William Lee and
                            James Whittaker, who were her companions in tribulation, and helpers in the ministration of
                            the gospel. Their unbounded love to the souls of men- - their kindness and charity to the
                            poor, and their exemplary lives and manners in all things, were evident manifestations of
                            that heavenly spirit which dwelt in them. When we visited Mother Ann, and heard her
                            testimony, we found that the first thing required of a convicted soul, in order to obtain
                            admittance into her society, was to make an honest coufession to God, in the presence of one
                            or more of his witnesses, of every sin, whether secret or open, and to forsake them forever.
                            By actually doing this, we gained her union, and felt the boundless love of Christ flow from
                            her into our souls. The next thing required was, in case we had injured any of our fellow
                            creatures, in person or property, by theft, or fraud or violence, or wronged any one, in any
                            way or manner whatever, we murt make confession and restitution to the satisfaction of the
                            injured party. By doing these things we found forgiveness of God. and felt his blessed power
                            and gifts flew in upon us, in various ways and manners, blessing all our undertakings, both
                            iu things spiritual and temporal. The next requirement was, to put our hands to labor and
                            our hearts to God, and pay all our just debts. "- - In so doing," said Mother, '"God will
                            bless you iu your basket and in your store ; and you will soon be able to pay your debts,
                            and have a sufficiency to support your families, and to help the poor and needy the widow
                            and fatherless of this world." Such were the instructions we received from Mother Ann ; and
                            we to whom these instructions were given, have proved and realized these things by
                            obedience. The blessing of God attended our obedience to Mother's counsel, and we were soon
                            able to discharge our debts, and to assist the poor and needy with a charitable heart and
                            hand ; and our Society is at this day, a standing monument of the truth of these things. It
                            is admitted by all, that the fruit of any tee is the best evidence of the nature of the tree
                            which produced it. And if" Mother Ann's ministration has be.-u productive of good effects on
                            those who received it, then it must certainly have been a good ministration, and must have
                            proceeded from a good source. We know, and can bear witness, that Mother did effect a work
                            of righteousness, which no earthly power, no human wisdom ever did or could effect. That
                            spirit which she administered to us, has turned many souls from darkness to light, and from
                            the power of Satan to God. It has caused the dishonest, the<pb n="208" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> knavish and the fraudulent, to become honest and upright. It has caused the thief to
                            restore his stolen property, and pursue an honest calling for his support. It has caused the
                            idle to become industrious, the prodigal to be prudent, the covetous to be liberal, the
                            false to speak the truth, the proud and haughty to be meek and humble, the contentious and
                            quarrelsome to become peace-makers, the glutton and the drunkard to become temperate, and
                            the lewd and wanton to become chaste and honest. In short, it has caused "the wicked to
                            forsake their ways, and the unrighteous their thoughts, and turn to the Lord who has had
                            mercy on them, and to God who has forgiven them." These things we know to be true ;" and
                            now, "either make the tree good and its fruit good, or else make the tree corrupt and its
                            fruit corrupt: for the tree is known by its fruit." I can now testify that, by careful
                            obedience to her instructions, and by folfowing her footsteps, I have been saved from the
                            lusts and corruptions that are in the world, and from all sin for many years ; so that I
                            know of a certainty that the way she taught, and in which she walked, is the way of
                            salvation. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. 1826. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Art of giving" TEIform="index"/>THE ART OF GIVING. </head><p TEIform="p">[Contributed by Elder G. B. Avery.] <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Prudent thrift- -the art of saving, is a virtue that all should
                                    cultivate. The accumulation of property as a shelter and protection to old age, or
                                    as a shield against sickness and misfortune, is always commendable. But, in the
                                    exercise of this virtue it is not necessary that one should be wholly wrapped up in
                                    self as to be unmindful of one's obligations to society, or to the wants and woes of
                                    the unfortunate members of the household of our common humanity. In the churches,
                                    everybody, from the toddling infant to the gray haired sire, is expected to give,
                                    for the support of their religious institution*. * * * We see what Christianity is
                                    doing for the spread of its doctrines, and for the alleviation of wants and
                                    wretchedness in the world. * * * It is not the wealthy alone that should give, it is
                                    a moral and spiritual duty devolving upon all alike.- -The exercise of charity is a
                                    necessary means of spiritual unfoldment. It enlarges ones nature and brings one
                                    nearer to the heart of God. In proportion as we take an interest in the welfare of
                                    others, and aid in promoting the happiness of our common humanity, so shall we lay
                                    up treasures of soul that shall stand to our credit in the coming time, and far
                                    outweigh all the baubles of earth. When one has enough for all reasonable earthly
                                    needs, what does he want of more? He can only appropriate a certain amount of this
                                    world's goods to himself, and for the needs of those depending upon him. All else,
                                    which he must soon be called to leave, will go, perhaps, to feed the earthly
                                    vanities of those who have done naught to acquire it, and who are anxiously waiting
                                    the time that shall put them in possession of their inheritance. How much there is
                                    that needs to be done; our periodicals and publications and missions need a better
                                    support. We need homes for the poor, and schools for psychical support and research.
                                    * * * We need an organized missionary system for the dissemination of our Gospel!
                                    Indeed the harvest is ripening, for the sickle all around us! Where are the laborers
                                    to gather it in? Is it not time that we were up and doing? For lo the shadows are
                                    thickening and the night cometh apace, when no man can work." </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Golden gate" TEIform="index"/>Golden Gate. </bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our consolation of to-day..." TEIform="index"/>Our consolation of to-day... </head><p TEIform="p"> Our consolation of to-day, Is doing just the best we can, Not having done,
                            that's passed away, Will still suffice the inner man.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="No man is a competent judge of his own conduct" TEIform="index"/> No man is a
                            competent judge of his own conduct </head><p TEIform="p"> No man is a competent judge of his own conduct.</p></div2><pb n="209" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If a brother and sister be naked..." TEIform="index"/>If a brother and sister
                            be naked... </head><p TEIform="p">[Contributed by James S. Prescott.] <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">If a brother or sister be naked, and destitute of daily food, and
                                    one of you say unto them, Depart in peace, be ye warmed and filled: notwithstanding
                                    ye give them not those things which are needful for the body; what doth it profit?-
                                    -James ii., 15, 16. An old lady sat in her old arm-chair With wrinkled visage and
                                    dishevelled hair, And hunger-worn features; For days and for weeks her only fare, As
                                    she sat there in her old arm-chair, Had been potatoes. But now they were gone ; of
                                    bad or good Not one was left for the old lady's food Of those potatoes; And she
                                    sighed and said, " What shall I do? Where shall I send, and to whom shall I go For
                                    more potatoes?" And she thought of the deacon over the way, The deacon so ready to
                                    worship and pray, Whose cellar was full of potatoes, And she said " I will send for
                                    the deacon to He'll not mind much to give me snme [come Of such a store of
                                    potatoes." And the deacon came over as fast as lie could, Thinking to do the old
                                    lady some good, But never for once of potatoes : He asked her at once what was her
                                    ehief want, And she, simple soul, expecting a grant, Immediately answered
                                    "Potatoes." But the deacon's religion didn't lie that way , He was more accustomed
                                    to preach and to pray Than to give of his hoarded potatoes : So not hearing of
                                    course what the old lady He rose to pray, with uncovered head, [said But she only
                                    thought of potatoes. He prayed for patience, and wisdom and grace But when he prayed
                                    "Lord give her peace,'' She audibly sighed," Give potatoes." And at the end of each
                                    prayer which he said, He heard, or thought that he heard in its stead The same
                                    request for potatoes. The deacon was troubled, knew not what to do 'Twas very
                                    embarrassing to have her act so "About those carnal potatoes." So, ending his
                                    prayer, he started for home: But, as the door closed behind him, he heard a deep
                                    groan, il0, give to the hungry potatoes! " And that groan followed him all the way
                                    home In the midst of the night it haunted his room- - " 0, give to the hungry
                                    potatoes!" He could bear it no longer; arose and dressed From his well-filled cellar
                                    taking in haste A bag of his best potatoes. Again he went to the widow's lone hut;
                                    Her sleepless eyes she had not yet shut; But there she sat in that old arm-chair,
                                    With the same wan features, the same sad air, And entering in, he poured on the
                                    floor A bushel or more from his good'y store Of choicest potatoes. The widow's heart
                                    leaped up for joy ; Her face was haggard and wan no more. "Now," said the deacon "
                                    shall we pray?" "Yes," said the widow '- -'- -now you may." And he kneeled him down
                                    on the sanded floor, Where he had poured his goodly store, And such a prayer as the
                                    deacon prayed As never before his lips essayed; No longer embarrassed but free and
                                    full, He poured out the voice of a liberal soul, And the widow responded a loud "
                                    amen!" But said no more of potatoes. And would you who hear this simple tale, Pray
                                    for the poor, and praying, '- -''prevail" [deeds; Then preface your prayers with
                                    alms and good [needs; Search out the poor, their wants and their Pray for peace, and
                                    grace, and spiritual food, [good, For wisdom and guidance, for all these are But
                                    dont forget the potatoes. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/> Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What we can't prevent..." TEIform="index"/>What we can't prevent... </head><p TEIform="p"> What we can't prevent should never worry us What we can prevent should always
                            hurry us. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leopold" TEIform="persName"/>LEOPOLD. </byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life is more than meat..." TEIform="index"/>Life is more than meat... </head><p TEIform="p"> The life is more than meat The spirit more than form ; The living Christ we seek
                            Who in the soul is born. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="N., A. E." TEIform="persName"/>A. E. N </byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Be deaf to the quarrelsome..." TEIform="index"/>Be deaf to the quarrelsome... </head><p TEIform="p"> " Be deaf to the quarrelsome, blind to the scorner and dumb to those who are
                            mischievously inquisitive." </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Swift to hear and slow to speak" TEIform="index"/>Swift to hear and slow to
                            speak </head><p TEIform="p"> Swift to hear and slow to speak.</p></div2><pb n="210" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>NOTES.</head><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> THE MANIFESTO. SEPTEMBER, Office of publication. The Manifesto is published
                                at Shaker Village, Mer. Co. N. H. All articles for publication should be addressed to
                                Henry C. Blinn, and all letters on financial business to A. Y. Cochran. One cony per
                                year, postage paid, " " six months, " " Send for specimen copy, free. .75 .40</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Preach the word" TEIform="index"/> PREACH THE WORD.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> The sacred charge that was given to the apostle, in his ministry before men,
                                should never be lo&gt;4 to sight, it may not at all times and under all
                                circumstances be the most popular amoug men and on this account may fail to receive the
                                general approbation. Conditions arise in every age of the world that are held in close
                                correspondence. These have been so marked that they have drawn forth this peculiar
                                expression. "As it was in the days of Noah, so shall it be in the days of the son of
                                man." During those two thousand years human nature had not materially changed, so that
                                in the midst of the most wonderful events that had ever transpired in the world, mankind
                                neglected to turn aside from their daily avocations to find safety on earth or to learn
                                righteousness for righteousness' sake. " They bought and sold, they married and were
                                given in marriage till the day that Noah entered into the ark." Contemplating that awful
                                catastrophe, from the distance at which we now stand, it seems very stupid in those
                                people that they did not avail themselves of the proffered privilege, as received from
                                Noah, to enter the ark and be saved from destruction. The same indifferent spirit was
                                manifested at the advent of Christ. The loving friend who came with good news and glad
                                tidings ; the messenger bearing the words of eternal life ; the physician sent from God
                                to heal the sick and to raise the dead, received no more attention than did the buying
                                of a yoke of cattle or the ploughing of a newly purchased field. Men continued to buy
                                and to sell and to foster all their evil propensities as though such things were the sum
                                total of life, and nothing higher had appeared to claim their interest. Nearly two
                                thousand more years have passed and a revelation from the resurrection heavens, has in
                                its fulness been given to man. The angel from the temple of God has said, "Thrust in thy
                                sickle and reap for the harvest of the earth is ripe." Light from God is now shining
                                from the east to the west, and yet the unchanged human nature goes on as in the days of
                                Noah, and as in the days of the son of man. Witnesses have arisen from time to time and
                                through them the words of living truth have been made manifest. Faithful unto death they
                                have testified of a life above the world and of a time in which the new earth and new
                                heavens would be revealed, wherein all things should be holiness to the Lord. The day
                                dawn of prophecy is with us, when "judgment will be laid to the line and righteousness
                                to the plummet;- - TERMS 1887.<pb n="211" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> "When swords and
                                spears of needless worth, Shall prune the trees and plough the earth; When peace shall
                                spread from shore to shore And nations shall learn war no more." Walking in this light,
                                God's witnesses can have no doubt. Their mission runs parallel with that of the apostle
                                ; "I charge thee before God and the Lord Jesus Christ, Preach the word; be instant in
                                season, out of season ; reprove, rebuke and exhort." In this duty so imperative, comes
                                the necessity of using the sharp, two-edged sword, that it may reprove and rebuke wrong
                                in the speaker as well as in the hearer, lest that by any means, as remarked by the
                                Apostle, when I have preached to others, I myself should be a castaway. Let us work with
                                earnestness and care to build upon that foundation as permanently laid through the
                                testimony of Jesus that we may abide in safety through all trials and temptations. </p></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> The Manifesto returns thanks to our very kind friend, and well wisher
                                Hamilton Arnot for the generous gift of five dollars for the free distribution of our
                                paper. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary. </head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Scientific and practical" TEIform="index"/>SCIENTIFIC AND PRACTICAL </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> Prof. John Nott has proposed that some formula be printed as
                                        a warning to school children not to abuse their eyesight, and posted in front of
                                        every book, as follows : " Caution.- -Reader, your eyesight is worth more to you
                                        than any information you are likely to gain from this book, however valuable
                                        that may be. You are, therefore, earnestly cautioned- - 1. To be sure that you
                                        have sufficient light, and that your position be such that you not only avoid
                                        the direct rays upon your eyes, but that you also avoid the angle of reflection.
                                        In writing, the light should be received over the left shoulder. 2. That you
                                        avoid a stooping position and a forward inclination of the head. Hold the book
                                        up. Sit erect also when you write. That at brief intervals you rest the eyes by
                                        looking off and away from the book for a few moments. And you are further
                                        cautioned TO AVOID AS MUCH AS POSSIBLE, BOOKS AND PAPERS PRINTED IN SMALL TYPE,
                                        and especially such as are poorly printed; also to avoid straining or overtaxing
                                        the sight in any way. All may need to be reminded of the great importance of
                                        thoroughly cleansing the eyes with soft, pure water both morning and evening."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Popular scientific monthly" TEIform="index"/>Popular Scientific
                                        Monthly.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Voice of a friend" TEIform="index"/> THE VOICE OF A FRIEND.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bush, Belle" TEIform="persName"/> BY BELLE BUSH. </byline><p TEIform="p">Oh, pleasant to me is the voice of a friend, Whose thoughts and whose deeds unto
                            harmony tend, Whatever his station may be. We're brothers and sisters, all children of God,
                            And, whether or not we have acres of sod, We each can be happy and free. We can speak a kind
                            wofd, we can do a good deed, And reap for our planting a harvest of seed; And that is the
                            way to be free. We. can sing for the weary, can pray for the weak, And jewels of truth for
                            humanity seek; And thus shall we happiness see. For happiness springs from each labor of
                            worth, And every good deed that we do upon earth, The angels above us can see. When cheerful
                            and patient, when loving and mild, We turn to each task with the trust of a child, Then the
                            white-winged watchers are nigh. They know every thought, every beautiful de il, And their
                            lovetaketh note of whatever we nc d, And lo! ere we know it, 'tis nigh. Sometimes it is
                            pleasure, sometimes it is pain. 'Tis sunshine to-day, tomorrow 'tis rain, 'Tis best whatever
                            may come : For God on whose wisdom and bounty we call, Embraces not one, but embraces us all
                            In a love that is leading us home. - -Belvidere Seminary, New Jersey. </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="He who follows his own advice..." TEIform="index"/>He who follows his own
                            advice... </head><p TEIform="p"> He who follows his own advice, must take the consequences.</p></div2><pb n="212" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Discourse delivered at Canterbury, N. H.- Shakers- June 19, 1887" TEIform="index"/> Discourse delivered at Canterbury, N. H.- Shakers- June 19, 1887.</head><p TEIform="p"> The apostle Paul iu one of his letters to him whom he called his son Timothy
                            penned these words ; " Consider what I say; and the Lord give thee understanding ;" and I
                            would say the same to those who hear me today. I tak.3 it for granted that among the friends
                            who have met with us this morning to participate in our worship are some who never before
                            attended a Shaker meeting, who know nothing of our lives and our belief, but who would like
                            to obtain some knowledge on those points. They will after sharing in our worship form some
                            opinion of us from what they see and hear, and though opinions are not always correct and
                            sometimes are not of much value, yet we should aid where we can in that direction. Now the
                            opinion of one man about another or the opinion of a number of men in regard to a movement,
                            a cause or a sect, does not necessarily imply a correct premise or an unbiassed
                            investigation. And yet there are today and have existed in the past, men whose opinions as
                            to a cause and its advocates are worth careful consideration, because such men investigated
                            from a desire to learn the truth. Such a man was one who passed on a few years ago to a
                            higher life. He was one who loved to search out causes, to investigate and weigh in the
                            scale of reason ideas and their advocates, and when he reached a conclusion and formed an
                            opinion he uttered it in plain language that no one could fail to comprehend. This is what
                            he put on record. " With the Shakers so named, I hare some personal acquaintance, and I am
                            not ashamed to own that I have been instructed and cheered by them. They have never been
                            fairly appreciated by the world. Their condemnation of marriage and of individual property,
                            their ceremonies of divine worship, and their testimony against all departures from celibacy
                            as impure and sinful have repelled nearly all who are not of their own body. But might not a
                            more expansive philosophy, a more liberal culture, discover in these very traits a moral
                            worthy of the gravest attention? Are our relations as men and women so universally pure and
                            exalted [it was one of yourselves, a married man who propounded this query] that we may
                            rightly despise those who, unable to separate the palpable evil from the latent good reject
                            both together? Is exclusive property so beneficent a feature of our social order as
                            practically exemplified around us, that we may fairly stigmatize those who not needing its
                            incitements to thrift or industry, see fit to decline them? The peculiarities of Shaker
                            worship I readily abandon to the ridicule of the caviller, only wishing that theirs were the
                            only errors committed in attempting to honor our Father in heaven, and that no religious
                            errors more popular and more enduring than theirs were worse than simply ridiculous. When
                            all that may be said against these simple-minded people has been freely admitted, there is
                            yet left enough in their character and history to challenge our admiration. They present the
                            sublime and hope-inspiring spectacle of a community founded and built up on the conquest of
                            the most inexorable appetites ; lust, avarice, ambition, revenge,- -these are not merely
                            discountenanced by the social economy of the Shakers, but this economy is based on their
                            entire crucifixion. Nor can I see how any man can rationally conclude, as some have
                            nevertheless asserted, that all this show of subduing the appetites is hypocrisy and a
                            delusion. I can conceive no earthly motive for practising so much outward self-denial at so
                            great inconvenience, and with no hope of honor or popularity, but a certainty of the
                            reverse, if not based on obedience to an inward conviction. The uncharitable theory supposes
                            a refinement of absurdity and self-<pb n="213" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> annoyance which never
                            yet possessed for any period the brain of any one sane man, much less of a whole community
                            for generations. Let us then, profit by the lessons which these enthusiasts read us, while
                            discarding what to us are their errors. Let us remember that they have solved for us the
                            problem of the possibility, the practicability of a social condition from which the twin
                            curses, pauperism and servitude, shall be utterly banished. They have shown how pleasant may
                            be the labors, how abundant the comforts of a community wherein no man grasps for himself,
                            but each is animated by a spirit of devotion to the common good. When I have stood among the
                            quiet homes of this unaspiring, unpoetical people and marked how they have steadily, surely,
                            advanced from poverty to competence; when I have observed how their patient but never
                            excessive toil has transformed rugged barrenness into smiling fertility and beauty, how
                            could I refrain from thinking lightly of that blind dogmatism which asserts the
                            impossibility of inducing men to labor except for their own selfish gratification, and
                            affirms the necessity of the stimulus of personal acquisition to save mankind from sinking
                            back into the darkness and destitution of barbarism." That was the deliberate judgment ot
                            Horace G-reeley, who whatever may have been his idiosyncracies was certainly up to the level
                            of the time in which he lived. He did not have the shallow idea that because our numbers are
                            few the cause is a failure. A celebrated English preacher has said "no man is a failure who
                            is faithful and upright; no cause is a failure which is just and true. There is but one
                            failure ; and that is, not to be true to the best one knows." Now our numbers may be, nay,
                            they are few, as compared with other churches and as a sect we have not spread as have
                            others. But there is a difference between the spread of a sect, and the spread of ideas. In
                            this sphere we claim that we have done some work, and that we have not labored in vain. The
                            Shakers are a small body, arn-1 if there w no success but what depends on worldly
                            combination, organization or policy, never had any men and women less chance of it than we.
                            Bound only by mutual love an ! good-wi'l, with no creed but the gospel, thinking each one
                            what he will, questioning ourselves and our actions sharply, finding all the fault we can
                            with ourselves, looking out our defects and criticising them keenly as those only can who
                            believe in immortal truth ; certainly we are the least politic of all people. Those who know
                            of us say "the Shakers are dying out," and ''they believe in nothing." Yea, we do believe in
                            truth. And here we stand, "as chastened and not killed, as dying and behold we live ; as
                            unknown and yet well known ;" here we stand, this forlorn hope, if we are named such, we say
                            rather this vanguard in the army of Christian progress, a vanguard which cannot be
                            conquered, which cannot die for ideas never die. The breath goes out of a man's body and it
                            is dead ; synods and councils of mighty men are dissolved and scattered ; churches and
                            hierarchies decline and crumble; but ideas never die, truth never dies but is immortal. It
                            may for a brief period be hid, but the time will surely come when "truth crushed to earth
                            shall rise again," for "the eternal years of God are hers."'</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A." TEIform="persName"/>A.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="O let me bless..." TEIform="index"/>O let me bless... </head><p TEIform="p"> O let Hie bless, The blessings of each day,- - And let me chide not But in a
                            humble way.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Improve your minds while you may" TEIform="index"/>Improve your minds while
                            you may </head><p TEIform="p">Improve your minds while you may.</p></div2><pb n="214" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="acvice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Why we wear uniform?" TEIform="index"/>WHY WE WEAR UNIFORM? </head><p TEIform="p">[Contributed by J. B. Vance.] <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> One would almost think to hear some people talk, yea, and even
                                    some of our professed friends, that it was really more humble to dress like the "
                                    world " than to wear uniform, and that to have salvation in our hearts, and in our
                                    outward dress was a sign of inconsistency. How often one hears the uniform, and
                                    those who wear it, slightingly spoken of by those who themselves have not got the
                                    moral courage to wear it, although professed followers of Jesus ! Says one, "If I
                                    thought MY RELIGION WAS IN MY BONNET, I'd burn it!" Well, but why shouldn't your
                                    religion be in your bonnet? Would it be any the less a sign that you had Christ in
                                    your heart because you acknowledge Him in the shape and style of your bonnet? Rather
                                    one should expect to hear a child of God say, that if their religion was not in
                                    their bonnet they would burn it. "God doesn't look at the cut of a man's coat," says
                                    another. We humbly beg to differ. God does look at every action of a child of His.
                                    What! would you have us believe that it is a matter of indifference to God whether
                                    His people dress like the world or not? "O," but you say, "we don't go in for
                                    dressing up gaudily, but we like to look decent and respectable." Yes, and in your
                                    "looking decent and respectable," you look so much like the unsaved world, that no
                                    one could tell whether you were on the Lord's side or the world's side from your
                                    outward appearance. But. you say, " Would you then have everyone dress in Salvation
                                    Army uniform?" We answer, we would have everyone who professes to be a child of God,
                                    "come out from among the ungodly and be separate." We would have them, "not
                                    conformed to this world;" we would, therefore, have them not to dress like the
                                    "world" but to be so "transformed, inwardly and outwardly by the renewing of their
                                    minds" as to make it manifest to all around by their outward dress, as well as by
                                    their inward lives, that they are followers ot Him who was "not of the world." Why
                                    do professed Christians persist in dressing like the world? We maintain that it is
                                    because, in heart, whatever they may be by profession, they are of the world. They
                                    esteem the world's friendship. They will not " Come out from among them, and be
                                    separate;" they will have so much, and only so much, religion and swim with the
                                    tide. The secret of it all is they love themselves, their own skins, their good
                                    name, their reputation, their own ease better than they love God, and numberless are
                                    the excuses they have on hand to justify their conduct. What a mean, dishonest style
                                    of argument it is to pretend there is nothing in dress and that it is NO CROSS TO
                                    WEAR UNIFORM ! Why don't these modest people who say so put it on and try? Go
                                    through the streets of a crowded city on a Saturday evening, in full uniform, with a
                                    bundle of War Crys to sell, and then talk about there being "nothing in dress," and
                                    no cross in wearing uniform ! Does the devil molest a person going inoffensively
                                    along dressed in the ordinary style of the world? Of course not. Why? Because they
                                    are not damaging his kingdom by doing that; but let them take the course we have
                                    just described, and see how they come on! They will soon find out there is a devil,
                                    and also that a very large number of those they meet are serving him; nice,
                                    respectable, quiet-looking people, whom they would have thought saints, under
                                    ordinary circumstances, they now find are possessed of the devil. Why? Because these
                                    nice quiet people hate the light that condemns them, because their consciences are
                                    pricked, because they are of the devil, and the right of anyone wearing something
                                    openly and boldly for God in their midst is more than they can tolerate; they hate
                                    him in consequence, and many of them, could they have their way, would serve him the
                                    same as the Jews served Jesus Christ; and yet our modest friends tell us there is
                                    "nothing in dress," and that it is pharisaical to wear something to show you belong
                                    to God. What an awful Pharisee Daniel must hare been to have prayed three times a
                                    day with his window open. Why didn't he shut it? He could have prayed just as well
                                    with it shut?<pb n="215" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> Because he had a living God in Him;
                                    because he was not a coward; because he was resolved to be true to God, in defiance
                                    of the devil and the world, and for the selfsame reasons the Salvation Army means to
                                    wear uniform. Take the case of a man at work among his shopmates. Let him be an
                                    ordinary Christian; does anyone molest him? No; he can jog along peaceably enough.
                                    Before we were saved we worked with several such Christians for years, and never
                                    suspected they professed to be followers of Jesus until we got saved and began to
                                    talk to them about salvation, when to our astonishment they professed to be saved
                                    also, and to have been saved years. But let a man wear a bit of the Army ribbon on
                                    his working dress, HE 18 A MARKED MAN AT ONCE. Let him do anything wrong or
                                    inconsistent with his profession now, he'll soon hear about it. Why? Because the bit
                                    of ribbon is a continual and open confession to all around that he professes to
                                    belong to God, and, so far from desiring to hide the fact under a bushel, he is
                                    desirous that all shall know it; and, secondly, because such a person is a standing
                                    rebuke to sinners and lukewarm professors. One thing more- -just in proportion as a
                                    person takes up his cross and boldly stands for God in defiance of men or devils, in
                                    just such proportion do they enjoy the presence and fulness of God in their souls.
                                    "He that will save his life shall lose it, and he that will lose his life for My
                                    sake shall find it." Which side do you belong to? One Who Loves Keality. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="War cry" TEIform="index"/>From, the War Cry.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Faith, hope and love" TEIform="index"/>FAITH, HOPE AND LOVE </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">There are three lessons I would write, Three words as with a
                                    burning pen, In tracings of eternal light Upon the hearts of men. Have Faith,
                                    where'er thy barque is driven, The calm's disport, the tempest's mirth, Know this,
                                    God rules the hosts of heaven The inhabitants of earth. Have Hope! Though clouds
                                    environ now, And gladness hides her face with scorn ; Put thou the shadow fi om thy
                                    brow, No night but hath its morn. Have Love! Not love alone for one. But man as man
                                    thy brother call, And scatter like the circling sun, Thy charities on all. Thus
                                    grave these lessons on thy soul, Faith, Hope, and Love and thou shalt find Strength
                                    when life's surges wildest roll, Light when thou else wert blind. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/> Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Seeking for the pearl of great price" TEIform="index"/>Seeking for the Pearl
                            of great price </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> The pastor of a colored church in Atlanta, Ga., thinks he has a
                                    commission from on high, and for ten days the members of the congregation have left
                                    their plows idle and houses empty, literally looking in hidden places for the "
                                    pearl of great price."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Albany evening journal" TEIform="index"/>Albany Eve. Journal.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Words" TEIform="index"/>WORDS </head><p TEIform="p">[Contributed by Harriet Shepard.] <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> Words are very important things. They are but breath, and yet
                                    what deep furrows of joy or sorrow do they plow in the human heart! How do harsh
                                    words rend the feelings and fill the eyes with tears! How do approving and kind
                                    words thrill like music, and often influence a whole life. Words have either hurried
                                    individuals to vice, or bound them to virtue. As well might we sport with fire
                                    brands as be careless and inaccurate in the use of words. Form in early life the
                                    habit of severe accuracy in the use of language- -words planned and chiseled by the
                                    law of truth. See that they express what you mean; the slightest voluntary deviation
                                    is a lie, and every lie dishonors and begrimes and bemires the soul.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let truth have its perfect work in my heart..." TEIform="index"/> Let truth
                            have its perfect work in my heart... </head><p TEIform="p">Let truth have its perfect work in my heart, no matter how closely it bears upon
                            self, what interests it opposes, what worldly tie it severs or through what narrow path it
                            leads me, I am resigned to follow its guidance.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Baker, A. I." TEIform="persName"/>A. I. Baker.</byline></div2><pb n="216" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers </head><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/>Hall's Journal of Health</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cosmopolitan" TEIform="index"/>Cosmopolitan</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>Phrenological Journal and Science of Health</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> Hall's Journal of Health. Aug. Contents: Mind Reading; Seeing by the
                                interior Sense; Healing by Laying on of Hands; The Comparative Energy of Nutrients; A
                                Psycographic Experiment; Equilibrium, the controlling force in Nature; Milk and its
                                Products; Spurious wines; Little Busy Bee; etc, etc. Office 206 Broadway, N. Y. As the
                                season has come when miracles are reported from Ste. de Beau Pre J. Mi- -cdonald's
                                article in the August Cosmopolitan on " Pilgrims and shrines in Canada " is especially
                                timely. He gives the hifetory of this famous shrine and relates the story of many
                                remarkable cures performed there. The article is handsomely illustrated. The
                                Phrenological Journal and Science of Health. August, Contents : Some Foreign Ministers
                                at Washington : The article has eight portraits; The Province of ^Esthetics; Progress in
                                England; Natives of North America. This article is illustrated with six portraits;
                                Charity; The Late Timothy Coop; Women should combine; Ancient Witcheries ; The
                                California Grebe; To the Institute Students of 1885; Christian Ontology; Health Papers;
                                A candid Doctor; Fifty-two Centenarians; Notes in Science and Industry; Poetry; etc.,
                                etc. Fowler &amp; Wells Co., 775 Broadway, N. Y. $2 a year. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>KIND WORDS. </head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To my sense the July Manifesto..." TEIform="index"/>To my sense the July
                                Manifesto... </head><p TEIform="p"> To my sense the July Manifesto is full of good meat. I might name first, "
                                What of the future of ShaJcerism? " It is a mirror in which to look, and if we do not
                                like the reflection, whose fault is it? Jealousy that heartless, deadly foe to human
                                happiness received another javelin. Then the amount of hospitable and friendly reception
                                of the missionaries in the old world from whence our anc-stors were driven a hundred
                                years ago for bearing the same testimony which now returns to them, is really
                                encouraging. Truly the world moves.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, Elijah" TEIform="persName"/> Elijah Myrick. </byline></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What is true and becoming..." TEIform="index"/>What is true and becoming... </head><p TEIform="p"> What is true and becoming in life, I study and investigate ; and on that I am
                            intent.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Horace" TEIform="persName"/>- - Horace.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The system of truth..." TEIform="index"/>The system of truth... </head><p TEIform="p"> The system of truth, is single and each part is connected with every other.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Randall, S. S." TEIform="persName"/>- -S. S. Randall. </byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Contentment is the golden chalice..." TEIform="index"/>Contentment is the
                            golden chalice... </head><p TEIform="p"> Contentment is the golden chalice, in which pleasure continually drcps her
                            sweetest nectar.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. A. </byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Temptations at a distance..." TEIform="index"/>Temptations at a distance... </head><p TEIform="p"> Temptations at a distance are easily resisted, but now and today they are hard
                            to stand against.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W. </byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Every truth is a clue..." TEIform="index"/>Every truth is a clue... </head><p TEIform="p"> Every truth is a clue to unravel the tangled thread of thought.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Randall, S. S." TEIform="persName"/>- -S. S. Randall. </byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths. </head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Stewart, Sally Maria" TEIform="index"/>Sally Maria Stewart</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="S., J. E." TEIform="persName"/>J. E. S.</byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Freehart, Eunice" TEIform="index"/>Eunice Freehart</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="E., H. L." TEIform="persName"/>H. L. E.</byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Richmond, Galen" TEIform="index"/>Galen Richmond</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dibble, C." TEIform="persName"/>C. Dibble</byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cochran, Nancy" TEIform="index"/>Nancy Cochran</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="C., C." TEIform="persName"/>C. C.</byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> Sally Maria Stewart, at Second Family, Mt. Lebanon, July 24, 1887. Age 80
                                yrs. 9 mo. and 9 days. Our Sister sank peacefully to rest, a firm pillar in the temple
                                of God and a true Believer in the gospel of Christ: an obeyer from childhood. J. E. S.
                                Eunice Freehart, at South Union, Ky., July 28, 1887. Age 92 yrs. 5 mo. and 28 days. She
                                entered the Society in her thirteenth year, and has been a faithful soul for eighty
                                years, "Well done, good and faithful servant. " H. L. E. Elder Galen Richmond, at South
                                Family, Watervliet, N. Y. Aug. 1, 1887. Age 83 yrs. 8 mos. and 10 days. He united with
                                Believers, Jan. 1849. Has officiated as business agent thirty years. His whole interest
                                was consecrated to the gospel. His integrity was unsullied. He was a zealous convert to
                                the Advent Cause, prior to his acquaintance with Believers, and had, therefore no reason
                                to change his views of the Second Coming of Christ only with regard to the form. His
                                life went out like a candle. He was busy up to the hour of his decease. C. Dibble. Most
                                noble has thy record been. And though we miss thy cheering voice, Amid the daily walks
                                of life ; We oft' shall feel thy presence near, To cheer us in the daily strife. O. B.
                                Nancy Cochran, at Union Village, Ohio, Aug. 10, 1887. Age 86 yrs. 1 mo. and 1 day. Has
                                been a good and faithful Sister among Believers for sixty years. C. C.</p></div3></div2><pb n="217" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/>
                    <!--  
THE MANIFESTO.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure.
This powder never varies. A marvel of
purity, strength and wholesomeness. More
economical than the ordinary kinds, and
cannot he sold in competition with the multitude of low test, short weight, alum or phosphate powders. Sold only in cans. Royal
Baking Powder Co., 10G Wall-st., N. Y.
MEDAL   MACHINES.
NEW 70SX STA2S AQBICULTUSAt, W0SX3.
1st, Premiums at all Competitive  Trials
Railway, Chain and JLever Home Powers, Threshers and Cleaners, Threshers
&- - Shakers, Clover Hullers, Feed Cut*
ters, Wheel Iforse Rakes, Morse Pitchforks, Shingle machines, Straw Preserving- Rye Threshers,
Portable Steam-Eng-ines, Cider and "Wine mills and Presses,
Dog- and Pony Powers, Disc Harrows
& Springy Tooth   Harrows.     " Robin son's Hay Press, of four sizes- Will
work as easy with one horse, as
others with two. Made with Steel
Gearing which can not be broken."
WHEELER & MELICKCo.,
aimawk, st. ir.
Send stamp for Circular and report of Centennial
trial.
65
A MONTH   and BOARD Guaranteed
3 Young Men or Ladies in each  country,
and highest commission paid (often $150
a month.)    WEW ROOK: already on
in North and South America, at the Ice-Bound
Poles, over the lands of the Midnight Sun, under the
Equator, through the Dark Continent, among the Old
Temples of India, in the Flowery Kingdoms of China
and Japan, amid the ruins of Incas, Aztecs and Zuni, within Canons, Cliff Buildings, and Gardens of
the (rods, on the Isles of the Sea, and in all parts of
the globe. 300 engravings, Low Price. Quick Sales.
Send for Circular. P. W. Ziegler, & Co., 720 Chestnut St. Philadelphia, Pa.
A EEAL NECESSITY.
We presume there is hardly a lady to be
found in our broad lone who, if she does not
already possess a sewing machine expects
some day to become the owner of one.
But after the mind has been fully made up
to purchase one of these indispensable articles, the question arises as to what kind of a
machine to buy.
It should be so simply constructed that the
most inexperienced can successfully operate
it. The other points mainly to be considered, and which are the most desirable, are
durability, rapidity, capicity for work, ease
of operation, regularity of motion, uniformity of tension, and silence while in operation.
The " Ligh't-Running New Home" fills
the above requirmehts, and is said to combine the good points of all sewing machines
with the addition of many new improvements and labor-saving devices.
The price is no higher than that of other
machines, and every lady who is the happy
possessor of one may rest assured she has
indeed a treasure     See advertisement.
"The Catholic " is an exponent of the
principles of that order of Christians and
is published by Jacob Porter at Pittsburg,
Pa., on Sat. of each week.
The Gospel Wagon of Washington, X).C
is an omnibus, drawn by four horses and car
rying twenty persons, and a cabinet organ
It passes around the city on a circut of re
ligious services.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
WATERVLIET, N. Y.
SHAKER VILLAGE,  N. H.
SHIRLEY, MASS.
HARVARD   MASS.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
 --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>