<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1311" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">13</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">11</biblScope><date value="18831101" TEIform="date">November 1883</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">241-264</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="13" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="11" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                <pb id="p1"/>
                    <p> VOL. XIII. NOVEMBER. NO. 11. SHAKER MANIFESTO. Published by the United Societies. OUR HOME AT
                        SHIRLEY, MASS. "Blessed are they that hear the word of God and keep it. SHAKER VILLAGE, N. H.
                        1883. </p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p> [Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --><pb n="241" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><!--                   <div2 type="none">
                        <p> CONTENTS. Prophecies Fulfilled, Henry Clough, No. 2, Education, No. 1, Letter from, A. C. S.
                            A "Vision, Autumn, Watchfulness, Gentle Words, Woman, Prophetic Dreams, Page. - 241 Grace
                            and Knowledge 242 Progress, Order, etc., - 244 Letter box, 240 Notes, - 247 House and Farm,
                            " Sanitary, - 248 Home Questions, 249 Music—Sweet Praise, - 250 Books and Papers, 251
                            Deaths, Page. - 25-3 255 - 257" 25S - 259 263 - 264 Vol. XIII. NOVEMBER, 1883. No. II. </p>
                    </div2>--><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prophecies fulfilled.  Signs manifested" TEIform="index"/> PROPHECIES FULFILLED. SIGNS
                            MANIFESTED.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>GILES B. AVERY.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Lo Christ again hath come! The Prophet's purpose Now begins to dawn! Christ, Our God
                            reveals— A Dual Spirit,—Father,—Mother,—God. Thus all the signs declare : First, Tables two
                            Mosaic Law proclaim'd; then Cherubs two The Mercy Seat adorn. Next, Trumpets two The call of
                            God proclaim. Two Goats were used The judgment to dispose. Two tabernacles The temple
                            signified. Two souls were God's Anointed to reveal His will to Man! Two Trees of Life, whose
                            leaves for healing were On either side Life's river seen to grow. Two Olive Trees, that
                            stood on either side Of Zacharias golden heavenly bowl. Two Holy Cities, principles declar'd
                            That build the heav'nly Paradise of God. The first, down trodden by the Gentile horde; The
                            next, descending out of Heaven from God. The Spirit and the Bride,—The heav'nly Twain,
                            —"Christ in His Glory," now has come to reign! Come to fulfill the Law to Moses given, Come
                            to create the Heavens and Earth anew, Baptiz'd with pow'r salvation to dispense To whoso
                            wills; All nations to embrace, May all their courts now ope, their doors ajar Now stand, and
                            let the Queen of Glory in! The Dual Christ upon the "Cloud" now sits Sickle in hand, to
                            thrust, and reap the world! The "clusters" of earth's vine* to gather home, To garners of
                            Our Father,—Mother,—God. The field is ripe; the harvest is at hand, Christ, in a Cloud of
                            Witnesses now comes; •Judgment, his sceptre, now o'er earth lie waves, "Not to condemn"! but
                            rescue,—save his people, Save by his cross; the same on earth he bore Those who'd be sav'd
                            must ever also bear 'Gainst sin, and strife, and worldly lust and pride,. Hypocrisy, and
                            cant; 'Gainst Pharisaic lies! Christ comes the temple courts to cleanse anew. Her
                            money-mongers' Mammon worship, chide I Drive out the rabble; Altars purify! Truth off'rings
                            bring, and heav'nly incense rise, Prepare a church,—A Body, for the Lord! The Living Christ
                            is come, Not Jesus, but The Comforter, to build the heav'ns anew, Anew the earth, where
                            righteousness shall dwell. The worshipers of Antichrist reprove, Creed thongs, that millions
                            bind, to rend away, That on Truth's ocean wide the soul may sail To Wisdom's port, and at
                            her altars bow, Truth's boundless sea, no human creed hath spann'd", Her waves new trophies
                            to our ports do bring Christ's church to garnish, and her courts to pave? For peace the
                            Christ is come! But Antichrist [war, Hath strewn the earth with gore; her priests teach And
                            drown the nations in a din of strife!</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="'Vine of the earth' is natural generation..." TEIform="index"/>'Vine of the earth' is natural generation...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The "Vine of the earth" is natural generation, "clusters" its families. "I came not to
                            condemn the world, but to save the world."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Jesus" TEIform="persName"/>Jesus.</byline></div2><pb n="242" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Her church, for bread, the Stones of Creed hath giv'n" TEIform="index"/>
                            Her church, for bread, the Stones of Creed hath giv'n
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Her church, for broad, the Stones of Creed hath giv'n, For living water, they earth's vine
                            have tax'eL! Kot God, their saints do serve, but self adore. [bind! The souls Christ's love
                            would free, their creed doth But Christ is come! Not to select a few And damn the rest; but
                            gather to his fold The penitent from ev'ry land and clime ! Walls Antichrist hath hedg'd
                            round Heaven's Courts By election's frauds, and Adam's sins of yore Christ razes to the
                            ground; and it; their stead He opens Heaven, with her courts of bliss To ev'ry soul who
                            overcomes the world, The world within, whose adamantine walls Like Babel's Tow'r reach
                            upward to the skies! The Dual Christ is come! Anew the Heavens form —A Galaxy of Sainted
                            Virgin Souls from earthly pleasures reaped; from sin set free. Anew the earth will trend,
                            corruption freed, Its pow'r from strife redeem'd; Its people pure, Its Man and
                            "Woman,—Creatures new be form'd A Gioky TO OurUod! Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Henry Clough" TEIform="index"/> (Continued from last number.) HENRY CLOUGH, No. 2.</head><p TEIform="p"> In 1788 by the request of Father Joseph Meacham, Henry moved to the Society in New Lebanon,
                            which from this date became his permanent home. He was now, in company with several other
                            members of the family, appointed as an assistant minister to be sent from place to place as
                            necessity demanded. Each society, by divine revelation, had their Elders or Bishops, for
                            both Brethren and Sisters, selected from among this number. No one of this class of
                            assistant laborers of Father Joseph Meacham and Mother Lucy Wright, in the great work of
                            establishing the church, was more efficient or helpful than Elder Henry Clough. In company
                            with others, he was frequently commissioned to visit the Believers where tb.3 societies were
                            being formed, and to assist them to a better understanding of their spiritual duties. Those
                            who accompanied him testify of his gift of wisdom and discernment, and of the great blessing
                            that attended all his ministrations. Elder Henry Clough was one of the three messengers who
                            were sent to Hancock in 1790, to assist the Believers in making arrangements for the
                            establishing of a Society at that place. When the people had assembled they were addressed
                            by two of the Brethren, but Elder Henry did not feel to speak at that time. A second meeting
                            was held but Elder Henry still remained silent. A third meeting was called, and after the
                            two Brethren had spoken in accordance with their gift, they asked him if he felt to speak.
                            He replied, "I believe I will say a few words," and his discourse wrought a deep conviction
                            in their souls. He urged them to put away all that was wrong and by an honest confession and
                            repentance seek earnestly the blessing of God. The gift which Elder Henry had administered
                            was universally received, and he felt the burden of the Society upon him to that extent that
                            he thought it might be his duty to abide with them. When this was referred to Father Joseph
                            Meacham he replied, "Well Henry, if you can find no one who can take the burden from you
                            then you must go and take the charge; but if you can find some one, then that person is the
                            one to take charge of the Society." Elder Henry accordingly conversed with several of the
                            Brethren who seemed best qualified for the place ; but it was not till he had made known the
                            gift to Elder Calvin Harlow that his burden left him. Elder Calvin was soon after appointed
                            to the charge, and with the assistance of Elder Henry established the Societies of <pb n="243" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 243 Hancock, and Tyringham, Mass., and Enfield, Conn.
                            Elder Henry now became the most prominent minister in assisting Father Josep'h. In 1791 he
                            was commissioned with the gift to establish Elder Eleazer Hand over the Societies of Harvard
                            and Shirley, Mass. In 1792 the Society at Canterbury was formed into an order, and until
                            this date the property owned by Elder Henry was under the charge of a large family of
                            Believers. After he had entered the Society at New Lebanon, the Believers occupying his
                            place moved to the family of Benjamin Whitcher, and the property was sold for some $3,000 to
                            Seth Turrell. A generous settlement Avas made with those Avho had been employed on the
                            place, after which he contributed $176 to assist in building the "Meeting House" for the
                            Believers in Canterbury. The remainder of his property Avas given to the Society at New
                            Lebanon. At the time that Father Job Bishop was commissioned to organize the Societies of
                            Believers in New Hampshire, Elder Henry Avas appointed to assist him. Father Job had
                            preAdously made a journey to NeAv Hampshire but his labors did not prove satisfactory, and
                            he so reported himself to Father Joseph Meacham, Avhose reply was, "Well, Elder Henry may go
                            with you." The tAvo Brethren noAv set out on horse back to make a journey from New Lebanon,
                            N. Y. to Canterbury, N. H., a distance of about one hundred and thirty miles. A curious
                            incident occurred while the Brethren were traveling along the road and about one half of the
                            trip accom. plished. Although Elder Henry was the youngest Believer his official position as
                            a spiritual teacher Avas now in advance of Father Job, but had not been publicly recognized
                            as they both had lived Avith Father Joseph. On this journey Job fell into a contemplative
                            state of the mind while meditating upon this subject, and finally fell some distance in the
                            rear. While in this labor, Job caught the impression that he had not publicly acknoAvledged
                            Elder Henry as his spiritual adviser. Putting spurs to his horse he soon overtook Elder
                            Henry and riding up by his side, said, "Elder Henry, you are my Elder in the Gospel." j
                            Elder Henry stopped his horse quite suddenly and said,—"Job, go on, you Avill have a gift of
                            blessing. I will return to New Lebanon." Father Job entreated fo/ him to go the remainder of
                            the journey. ' 'Nay," said Elder Henry, "it will be of no use ;" and turning his horse drove
                            on toward his home. At a subsequent date Elder Henry visited the Societies in N. H. and
                            permanently established Father Job as the director of the Believers. In the fall of 1792
                            Elder Henry accompanied Elder John Barnes to the State of Maine, and assisted in appointing
                            him the Elder OA^er the Societies of Alfred and Gloucester. In the Society at New Lebanon
                            Elder Henry felt it to be of primary importance that the youth and children should receive a
                            careful, moral and religions instruction, as a present protection, and as a future safeguard
                            against the temptations of a sinful world. At one time he Avas appointed their mediate
                            counselor, and became deeply interested in their behalf. His prayers and care were not
                            Avithout effect. Many of the number accepted the instruction and became faithful and
                            honorable mem- <pb n="244" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 244 THE MANIFESTO. bers of the institution. He
                            instructed them to avoid all rude, unbecoming conversation, but to speak and act before each
                            other in such a manner as to increase their union and respect. By the death of Father Joseph
                            Meacham, the first gift in the order of the Ministry devolved upon Mother Lucy Wright, who
                            had occupied a place in the Ministry, as well as the title for several years. Elder Henry
                            remained in the Ministry, and acknowledged and supported the ministration that was placed
                            upon Mother Lucy. By his humility of spirit, and his untiring devotion to the cause, he
                            became the beloved friend of the Believers in every society. On the 30th. of Jan. 1798,
                            Elder Henry in company with the Ministry of New Lebanon, made his last visit to Watervliet,
                            N. Y., and returned Feb. 3rd. From this time his health began rapidly to decline. He was
                            taken very sick on the 7th. of March, when everything was done for him through the day and
                            night that the physicians could suggest for his recovery. Hopes were entertained that his
                            life would be spared still longer, but it was soon evident that his work on the earth was
                            nearly finished. He continued to fail and on the 12th. day of March, six days only after he
                            was taken ill, he calmly departed this life, at half past seven, A. M. and his soul was
                            removed to higher and more extensive labors. His age was 44 yrs. and 34 days. The funeral
                            was attended by all the members of the First Family, and by the Leaders of the whole
                            Society. The service was very impressive. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p"> An undisciplined life, is an unfruitful life.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="M., E." TEIform="persName"/>E. M.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Education, no. 1. Its importantce" TEIform="index"/> EDUCATION, No. 1. Its Importance.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Reed, Calvin G." TEIform="persName"/>CALVIN G. REED.</byline><p TEIform="p"> "Youth it instructs, old age delights, "Adorns prosperity, and when, "Of adverse fate we
                            feel the blights, " 'Twill comfort and solace us then." In this world surely, if not in all
                            spheres of existence, education is man's best, most constant friend. It aids us in all our
                            needs, wisely directs us in the performance of all our duties, and helps us to bear with
                            equanimity, dignity and patience our allotted burdens of life. When, however, the importance
                            of education is espoused and advocated by its friends, defenders, and disciples, immediately
                            the fears of the uneducated are aroused, their antagonism is stirred, their opposition
                            placed in battle array prepared to combat a fornaidable and vindictive foe. The illiterate
                            try all the arguments presented in favor of education by their imperfect standards, and what
                            does not agree with these, are judged erroneous, and ignored as unsound and injurious ;
                            validating the maxim : " 'Tis with the judgments as with watches; no two Times just alike,
                            yet each believes his own." Education is a vital force ; an intelligent power ; a royal,
                            ruling puissance, guiding and controlling the opinions; social relations ; philosophies ;
                            theologies ; and governments of mankind; a surer and more potent conqueror than the sword;
                            "For just experience tells in every soil, That those who think, must govern those who
                            toil."' Education is the eye of the mind, and the observatory, laboratory, and conservatory
                            of the soul. With it we scan the visible and the invisible Avorlds, and weigh, measure, and
                            compare the ponderable and unponderable elements of <pb n="245" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 245
                            •creation. It is the Archimedean lever with which we move the world. Man without education,
                            like a lever without fulcrum, has only the power of liis own weight of animal life. God
                            designed man to be educated and intelligent ; to seek and know the truth. He constituted him
                            with faculties, ability, and desire to acquire, retain, and use knowledge, and to become a
                            repository and exponent of wisdom and understanding ; a true legitimate child of his
                            omniscient Father ; a wise and noble headship of creation. If our Heavenly Father intended
                            that we should remain in a state of ignorance and continue in our childhood sphere, and not
                            use the talents conferred upon us ; it was a marked exhibition of folly, unbecoming the
                            Supreme Architect, to place them in the structure of the human edifice. Lawful possession
                            and ownership implies the right to use. Jesus in the parable of the talents clearly taught
                            the use of them to be our sacred duty. Through long, tortuous, tedious centurias, truths and
                            blessings the present age enjoys, forced their way through hosts of ignorance, error, folly,
                            misrepresentation, oppression, persecution and blood. At last, the white-robed angel of
                            Freedom, with out-spread wings, reared his invincible, invulnerable standard of glory and
                            triumph, upon the Mountain of God's Holiness, proclaiming life, liberty, and happiness, free
                            to all the sons and daughters of men, who through wisdom and understanding will defend and
                            preserve them. Blot out all art and science ; seal up the book of knowledge and experience
                            that has come to us through the growth of the ages ; return man to his pristine state, when
                            first he breathed the breath of life, and looked through infant eyes upon the wild primeval
                            world. Draw, thoughtful reader, draw the picture plain I. Fill out the canvas full and true
                            ! Sketch witli artistic skill, the dark, the vapid, the gloomy pall of weakness, ignorance,
                            and barbarism, that then would bind us down with stronger chains than chains of steel; with
                            denser darkness than the darkest night can boast! Who would ask it ? Who would wish it? Who
                            could bear it? Who would not shudder at the thought of such a withering, chilling, terrible
                            prison state ? Yet do not all, who see but little else than glory, honor, virtue,
                            righteousness, and grace, adorn the past; and folly, shame, duplicity, and crime, pervade
                            the present ; who look with longing eyes to days forever gone, and fancied bliss they think
                            their minutes bore ; but in the present, find but weary toil and anxious care, a lurid
                            sunshine, fading hope, and gloomy future who see through Education's course, but worldliness
                            ; do not all such, cast in their mites, to backward roll the car of Progress, and stay the
                            reign of the Millennial Day ? "The prudent, the wise, the intelligent, the educated, foresee
                            evil and shun it; but the simple, the ignorant, the foolish, the uneducated, pass on and are
                            punished. The wise shall inherit glory; but shame shall be the promotion of fools. The way
                            of life is above to the wise. The wise and their works are in the hands of God. But the fool
                            hath said in his heart, there is no God. Wisdom strengtheneth the wise more than ten mighty
                            men. The multitude of the wise, is the welfare of the world." "Wisdom hath builded her
                            house; she hath hewn out her seven pillars ; she hath also furnished her table. Whoso <pb n="246" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 246 THE MANIFESTO. is simple let him turn in hither, as for him that
                            wanteth understanding, she saith to him : 'Come cat of my bread ; forsake the foolish and
                            live ; and go in the way of understanding.' " "Now we see through a glass darkly" (2000
                            years ago) but in the l'Jth century and onward, "Knowledge shall be increased ; but none of
                            the wicked (ignorant) shall understand ; but the wise, (intelligent, educated) shall
                            understand, and shall shine as the brightness of the firmament." God does not work by
                            partial, but by universal laws, the grand, the best results He keeps in view. He is the
                            fountain, source, and power of wisdom, knowledge, and intelligence. All true educational
                            systems, primarily, emanate fiom Him, and consequently must be of universal application,
                            adapted to our legitimate unfolding and best development. (To BE CONTINUED.)</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My youthful sister M; would you..." TEIform="index"/>
                            My youthful sister M; would you...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New Hampshire, Shaker Village, August 1883" TEIform="index"/> Shaker Village, N. H. Aug.
                            1883.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> My Youthful Sister M ;—Would you like to see how one good thought clothed in earnest words,
                            even by yourself, can be treasured like good seed in other hearts, and anon, be made to grow
                            and expand one at a time perchance, like the tiny leaflets from the auxiliary bud, and lose
                            no virtue by the change ? Well then, let me show you the phenomena. Last evening after a
                            day's pleasant toil together, you and I had the privilege of joining in worship with the
                            good Brethren and Sisters where much was spoken, felt and heard. Much, which, I trust, will
                            be wisely heeded by both speaker and listener. One voice in particular, arrested my
                            attention, while in earnest tones its owner pleaded to be more sincere in prayer, remarking
                            that "though accustomed to kneel eight times a day, yet I can not be content to treat this
                            exercise as a mere ceremony. I would have my mind busy in prayer." As I listened to this
                            last expression I mentally rejoined, You are right sister M., and let me add, "Blessed be
                            even the 'form of Godliness,' to all who are able to understand what it implies. Blessed be
                            the discipline which elevatesthe mind, even though it bows the physical form to meet its
                            kindred dust." The attitude of prayer, in my view when reverently assumed, is in itself a
                            manifestation of the triumph of mind over matter, and is often far more eloquent in its
                            silence than the most glowing passages which one might quote from human speech. In the brief
                            moments of silent prayer before and after meals, at rising in the morning and retiring at
                            night, one must realize that hero the soul asserts its supremacy, its peculiar character as
                            an immortal existance. All animal life can be sustained by material substances alone ; not
                            so we who are able to reason ; we want to maintain our superiority by some appropriate token
                            of moral and mental power every where. Therefore, let us command ourselves often, to pause
                            amid the hurry and bustle of worldly cares, and gratefully recognize the Source of our many
                            bounties. When I was but a youth it was once my privilege to wait upon an aged Sister on one
                            day of her last illness. She seemed to me then, a pattern of Godliness, or like an
                            impersonation of modesty, humility and chastity. One expression which she made at that time,
                            left a lasting impression upon my memory, wThich I will insert for you. On carrying
                            breakfast to her one morning, <pb n="247" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 247 which was simply a
                            cup of gruel, I invited her to eat. She, putting the cup aside for a moment, said," I must
                            pray first, because, you see, I would not he like the swine, they cannot pray." This little
                            remark, so pleasantly spoken, rises like a star in the mind's sky often when I kneel at
                            table, and sheds a mild radiance on the^ceremony, as some term it, of kneeling before and
                            after meals. And though I may not always have given by example the decided influence which
                            the subject demands, yet a ready departure from this custom to favor some petty excuse,
                            seems not only careless but Godless to me. So, my dear M., you have my testimony in favor of
                            prayer, just as it grew out of the seed planted in one willing mind. If you can recognize
                            the leaf-bud closed, please accept the same expanded, with my best love. Mention me kindly
                            to your youthful class-mates, for 1 love you all, and hope you will never be loth to
                            acknowledge the goodness of God in the spirit and attitude of prayer. Yours in interest, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stickney, Asenath C." TEIform="persName"/>Asenath C. Stickney.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Autumn" TEIform="index"/> AUTUMN.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/> MARY WHITCHER.</byline><p TEIform="p"> The Autumn leaves are falling, My heart expands to sing This is a solemn warning To every
                            earthly thing. We've had our day of Summer, And Spring-time in, its place, And soon must
                            meet the Winter, In honor or disgrace. If we have stored our garner And precious wheat lies
                            there, We have no fear of hunger Or feelings of despair. The God of justice ruleth, And
                            giveth to each one According to their labor, Or timely service done. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vision. no. 1" TEIform="index"/> A VISION. NO. 1.</head><p TEIform="p"> I had solicited the attention of kind guardian spirits to watch over me and to assist me in
                            all the walks through life. T now felt a heavenly baptism and found myself in the presence
                            of her to whom I had directed my humble petition. I asked her name. She answered;
                            Sarah-----and that she lived before the church was gathered in Niskeyuna. That it was her
                            spirit duty to take charge of those who came to untimely deaths by carelessness. Would you
                            like to accompany me? I said the privilege would give me great pleasure. She remarked, I
                            have often heard you express a desire to sec L.-----your companion. Do you wish to see her
                            now? I answered, Yea. She then took me by the hand and led me through an obscure passage, in
                            and around which, everything looked sad. At last we came to a long, narrow house, painted
                            red, which I should not have thought was calculated for any human beings to dwell in, but on
                            entering the door, the first object which arrested my attention was L.-----sitting upon a
                            footstool, her face being turned from me. She did not appear to mind anything about me until
                            I spoke and said,— L.—is this you? She said very composedly,—-"It certainly is." She was
                            clothed in a dark colored dress. A white neckerchief, having a. red border was thrown over
                            her shoulders. Her employment, at this time, was sewing strips of cloth together. I was
                            surprised at the presentation before me and immediately asked,— What can be your object in
                            being thus engaged? "Alas!" said she, "all these strips of cloth which you see around me are
                            those which I wasted while dwelling in the body. They are now all presented clearly before
                            me, and I must sew them together for my garment and wear it." <pb n="248" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 248 THE
                            MANIFESTO. Some of the strips were only half an inch wide. The arrangement inside of the
                            building seemed much like the stalls in the market place. The building had a long, narrow
                            hall running from one end of it to the other. On the right were places numbered from one up
                            to thirty. Over the one of which I am speak ing was written in large letters, "Selfishness."
                            S.—asked me to look around the apartment where L.—was and inform myself, particularly, in
                            regard to the order of the place. In one corner I observed some crumbs of bread. They were
                            left among the dust. A short distance from this place stood an earthen vessel with soap in
                            it. On a shelf I sawpieces of bread and of cake. By the side of these were fragments of
                            meat. On another shelf I saw some fruit and vegetables in a state of decay. I asked S.—What
                            does all this mean? She said, it was as wrong to eat too much, as it wa3 not to eat enough.
                            I have known persons to waste their food, when it was prepared, rather than to eat it. She
                            then pointed to a dish in which were several varieties of food. Nothing, said she, should be
                            thrown away which will serve as food for any creature. Under a shelf were large quantities
                            of yarn broken into small pieces. By the side of these were pieces of thread, and fragments
                            of garments. I asked S.—if all this belonged to L.— I think it did. 1 was made sick at the
                            sight, and turned to trid her "good bye" when she said,— "The next time you come, you will
                            not see me here. I must work diligently now, I did not profitably improve my time when I was
                            upon earth." I now left my sorrow-stricken companion. (To be continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Every thing has both a relative, and fixed value..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Every thing has both a relative, and fixed value...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Every thing has both a relative, and fixed value, which is equal and unchanging to all. if
                            the full price be not paid, the end sought is not obtained, but something else—for this is
                            the unalterable Law of the Kingdom; "Every one shall receive the reward of his works,"
                            exactly "according to his works." This is the law of just remuneration.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="H., A." TEIform="persName"/>—A. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watchfulness" TEIform="index"/> WATCHFULNESS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName"/> ABBAHAM PERKINS.</byline><p TEIform="p"> '•Every good tree bringeth forth, good fruit; but a corrupt tree bringeth forth evil fruit."
                            Matt, vii., 17. We are scripturally taught to judge no man ; yet from that book, which
                            exceeds all others in teaching us wisdom and portraying Christian life, and also from
                            personal experience which gives us the most certain knowledge, Ave are made to know
                            truth:—"-5.V their fruits ye shall know them." Matt., 20. Such evidences are indubitable,
                            sufficient to enable us to understand with what we are dealing, what the character and what
                            the individual or society would be safe and honorable for our association, friendship and
                            relation. When we see youth and young men attracted to the gay and giddy, to the idle and
                            unrestrained, whose element is in that which is light, empty and irreligious, using their
                            language and adopting their manners and habits, we say,— Young man, you are establishing
                            life character, your destiny is being sealed and ruin is sure. On the other hand, when the
                            spirit of caution is manifest in the selection of associates, when a reserve is maintained
                            in language and manners, when respect is shown for the feelings and characters of others,
                            then we may look for growth of the soul, development of just principles and respect for
                            one's self; then we may find a place to repose confidence, a repository commanding respect
                            and a character unblemished if in this world such a condition is possible. The pathway of
                            life is pregnant with danger, full of snares, and few escape falling into some of them. None
                            are <pb n="249" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 249 secure because of their station, their honors,
                            their education or their talents ; and however frequent the repetition, that safety lies
                            only in watchfulness and care, or however delusive the idea in a regard of these points as
                            beingprotective, if uttered with the mouth or heard with the ear, yet it is a fact, here is
                            the secret of a prosperous and resurrected life. It is yet to be learned, if not understood,
                            that simply making a profession and having fellowship with a religious body, having
                            associations with good society, being constant at church and uniformly attentive to prayers,
                            although in themselves all good, unless a foundation is laid by cleansed hearts, and lives
                            made perfect by obedience to the light and conviction of conscience, life is a blank,
                            profession a sham, we have no part in Christ and are none of his. "Every association we
                            form, however limited, exerts some influence upon us. The extent to which we yield to that
                            influence, will be determined by the degrees of intimacy, the constancy of the intercourse
                            and our love and veneration for those with whom we associate." Therefore, how vital to
                            safety, to protection, to the salvation of the soul and its final redemption, that we are
                            choice in the selection of intimate friends and companions, that no habits of others become
                            ours, unless they be those of genuine principle, which, of course, must be founded on the
                            basis of truth. Our own hearts we should examine critically, our individual course judge
                            impartially, carefully shunning all associations unfriendly to religious life, being
                            faithful in our sacrifices of all worldly considerations that imperil the soul. To the
                            pleasure-seeker, danger seems afar off; to those who are at ease in Zion, the cry is peace
                            and safety, when Heaven declares swift destruction upon the transgressor. Watch, pray, work
                            ;— this is true life, from which we cannot fail of reaping a harvest' of precious fruit.
                           Enfield, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gentle words" TEIform="index"/> GENTLE WORDS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bush, Clara" TEIform="persName"/>CLARA BUSH.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Why not let our words be gentle? Harsh words rudely jar On the feelings of a brother; And to
                            kindly greet each other Would be better far. In the plainest words of converse Music sweet
                            is heard; If in tenderness they're spoken ; But the melody is broken By an angry word. It
                            would show a strength of spirit To let no hard word Fall petulantly from our tongue, And
                            strike the notes to music strung, Making rude discord. We would find it just as easy, In
                            kind tones to speak; Hasty, cruel words are grievous, And too sadly, truly prove us
                            Pitifully weak. Oft a little word, soft spoken, Falling on the ear, Throws a passing ray of
                            gladness O'er the heart darkened with sadness, And dispels the tear. Gentle words ! they
                            cost so little, And such power hold To impart to olhers pleasure, Why not greater make their
                            measure Many thousand fold? It will make our own hearts richer, If we will but give Lavishly
                            to our fellow man, Gentle words whene'er we can, While on earth we live. We are lowly,
                            sinful creatures, Sadly prone to err; <pb n="250" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 250 THE MANIFESTO. Yet, if
                            we've blindly gone astray And ean make amends to-day, Let us not defer. If one kindred heart
                            we've wounded, By a word unkind, Oh, let us now forgiveness ask, And make it our most
                            willing task The sad wound to bind. There may be less sweet than bitter, In the cup of life
                            ; There may be more thorns than flowers Yet, if unbroken love be ours, We can bear the
                            strife. Kenton, Tenn.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Woman" TEIform="index"/> WOMAN.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>MARTHA J. ANDERSON.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Who shall define her sphere, or mark her boundaries? If she was created man's help-meet, why
                            should she not stand his equal in all the relations of life? Their qualities are admirably
                            adapted to run parallel and aid each other, in balancing the accretive and concretive forces
                            that are continually molding forms of beauty and use. Woman, dwarfed and crippled, by
                            erroneous customs of society, cramped by false ideas of education, and fettered by fashion,
                            is not the being of whom we speak; but, woman emancipated from the thraldom of ages, with
                            equal facilities for mental expansion with her brother, which have been denied her for
                            centuries because she was the weaker sex, and man has been her Lord and master. If her body
                            and brain are smaller, they are finer, and active enough to make up for deficiency in size.
                            Exercise gives development; if you compress the powers of a human being, or a race of people
                            in a small compass, and restrict their unfoldment, of course you necessarily have dwarfed
                            capacities, and where this continues for generations it becomes a natural inheritance.
                            African slavery established this fact, and you only need to trace the effects in another
                            form of bondage and there will be seen as marked results. It is true that man is organized
                            for the heavier burdens of life, where muscular strength is required. But, on the other
                            hand, he prostitutes his manly qualities for the sake of ease, and blocks the avenues to
                            many a field of labor that woman is pre-eminently fitted to fill. If she is obliged to toil
                            for her own support, or that of a family, which care alas, too often devolves upon her, it
                            must be at the stipulated wages that man chooses to give her, regardless of the actual worth
                            of the labor. Thousands of women work for starvation prices, breaking down their delicately
                            organized nervous systems, suffering untold agonies the while in trying to eke out a
                            miserable existence ; or else happily find an early grave, as the only end to mortal
                            trouble. Under these unjust usages of society, it is no wonder that so many lead a life of
                            vice. Infringement of God's just law has blotted out the seal of true equality which He
                            enstamped on human life ; passion has blinded man's vision, and liquidated his obligations
                            to do right; all things subserve its base purposes, and what, or who, more than woman? Her
                            school of culture has been to perfect the art of seduction ; her accomplishments, the
                            blandishments and charms of personal grace and mental refinement, that captivate and lure to
                            pitfalls of sensual pleasure. Turn the currents of her life in channels of usefulness ; open
                            to her the halls of legislature, the academies of science <pb n="251" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/>THE
                            MANIFESTO. 251and art, and you will soon see a new unfoldment of powers that man never
                            dreamed she possessed. Some feminine minds are absolutely starved, because they are hampered
                            by masculine opinion, and are by the sterner sex refused admittance to those fields of study
                            and research which they are often better qualified to fill than their own brothers, who have
                            all the opportunities to follow out their inclinations ; while their genius must be blasted
                            on account of the imagined limitations of sex. A few strong-minded women have pushed their
                            way into medical colleges, and struggled to maintain their position despite the sneers and
                            frowns, accompanied by personal insult from the chivalrous male students, with whom they
                            were obliged to associate ; and where they have been able to break the barriers of
                            prejudice, at the expense of their keenly sensitive natures, they have proved by true
                            womanly courage and persistence worthy the highest honors of the institution. Society
                            demands a change, especially in this line. Woman is eminently fitted to attend her own sex,
                            and nurse the afflicted of tender years. Her qualities as an efficient nurse combined with a
                            thorough knowledge of the human system, make her more skillful than man in the treatment of
                            some diseases as has been practically demonstrated. Does knowledge unfit her for domestic
                            duties ? Far otherwise ; it enlarges her perception of those duties, and causes her to work
                            intelligently wherever life's needful burdens fall to her lot to bear. When educated aright,
                            she puts thought, system and thoroughness in all her work. Domestic relations do not claim
                            the attention of all the lair sex. Some are capacitated for intellectual pursuits; their
                            thoughts and ideas are the oiFspring they cherish ; others engage in philanthropic work, and
                            through their largeheartedness and desire to do good, enlarge the sphere of their love, and
                            go out from their homes on true missions of mercy and charity, prompted by a desire to
                            uplift the fallen, and place humanity on higher planes of thought and action. Let woman move
                            in the way that her mind and intuitions dictate as right, and there will be great changes in
                            social life. The world will have nobler mothers and better developed children; consequently
                            superiorgenerations, of men and women will be the effect of the new evolution of things—And
                            out of it shall come seed for the New Creation—the Christ Order—for nature molds her highest
                            types in God's divine ideal. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prophetic dreams" TEIform="index"/>PROPHETIC DREAMS
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Reynolds, H." TEIform="persName"/>BY H. REYNOLDS, M. D
                        </byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Several instances are recorded in the
                                    Bible in which the future was made known by dreams, and the interpretation of dreams
                                    was sometimes an important part of the prophet's mission. Dreams in all ages have
                                    been believed in as affording indications of the future. In ancient Greece it was
                                    believed that dreams came from the great Jupiter, the king of gods. In ancient Egypt
                                    and Babylon, the interpretation of the monarch's dream was an important state
                                    office, and was intrusted to a college of wise men. In consulting the Greek and
                                    Roman oracles, it was common after performing sacred rites, to sleep in the temple,
                                    so that the information desired might be made known in dreams. Ancient philosophers
                                    wrote treatises upon the interpretation of dreams, as even Bacon seems to have
                                    believed that something might be learned from them. In modern times, however, very
                                    little <pb n="252" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 252 THE MANIFESTO. attention is given to dreams, and
                                    they are generally dismissed from the mind with only a passing thought. The popular
                                    saying, "As idle as a dream," well expresses the sentiment of people generally in
                                    regard to this kind of phenomenon. This popular estimate of the nature of dreams is
                                    undoubtedly a just one as regards dreams generally. Yet it is possible that there
                                    may be exceptions. Some dreams may have a meaning which it is important that the
                                    dreamer should interpret aright, and understand its import. The mind, sometimes, in
                                    sleep can do that which it failed to do when awake. A difficult mathematical problem
                                    which, during the working hours, had baffled all efforts for its solution, is
                                    sometimes solved with ease during sleep. Many events, experiences, and impressions
                                    which apparently had long been forgotten, and could not have been recalled in the
                                    waking state, may come back vividly to mind during sleep. The mind can accomplish
                                    some tasks during sleep which it could not accomplish during the waking hours. It is
                                    possible that the mind, during the sleep of part of its faculties, may receive at
                                    times foregleams of the future, which, rightly interpreted, may be of advantage to
                                    the dreamer. In ancient times, too much reliance was placed upon dreams. In these
                                    modern times it is possible that dreams are too indiscriminately thrust aside as
                                    belonging to the vagaries and fancies of the night. The venerable Ralph Waldo
                                    Emerson says of dreams : "A skillful man reads his dreams for his selfknowledge, yet
                                    not the details, but the quality. What part does he play in them—a cheerful, manly
                                    part, or a poor, driveling part? However monstrous and grotesque their apparitions,
                                    they have a substantial truth. The same remark may be extended to the omens and
                                    coincidences which may have astonished us. Of all it is true that the reason of them
                                    is always latent in the individual. Goethe said: 'These whimsical pictures, inasmuch
                                    as they originate from us, may well have an analogy with our whole life and fate.'
                                    The soul contains in itself the event that shall presently befall it; for the event
                                    is only the actualization of its thought. It is no wonder that particular dreams and
                                    presentiments should fall out and be prophetic. The fallacy consists in selecting a
                                    few insignificant hints when all are inspired with the same sense. Every man goes
                                    through the world attended by innumerable facts, prefiguring (yes, distinctly
                                    announcing) his fate, if only eyes of sufficient heed and illumination were fastened
                                    on the sign-" Some very remarkable instances have occurred in which dreams have come
                                    to pass in the manner revealed to the dreamer. According to the London Mews, on the
                                    occasion of the terrible railroad accident from which Charles Dickens narrowly
                                    escaped with his life, there was in the same train a lady and gentleman just landed
                                    in England, after their return from India. Just before the accident, the lady said
                                    to her husband: "I seethe great wave rolling; it is close to us;" and then the crash
                                    came, and she was killed. The husband was unhurt, and at a later time, explained the
                                    strange words of his wife. Ever since they set out from India, she had been haunted
                                    in sleep by the dream of a vast silvery wave, and always as it was about to break on
                                    her, she had wakened in terror. This was the wave she recognized immediately before
                                    the accident which caused her death. Prof. Hedge relates that "when Andre, in a
                                    visit to friends in Derbyshire, before his embarkation for America, was introduced
                                    to a certain Mr. Cummington, that gentleman recognized in him the original of the
                                    countenance of a man whom he had seen in a dream, arrested in the midst of a forest,
                                    and afterwards hung on a gallows." The subsequent death of Major Andre in the manner
                                    indicated in the dream was a remarkable point in its fulfillment. Prof. Hedge in
                                    commenting upon this dream and others in which the event took place as foreseen in
                                    the dream regards them as tending to show "that the soul is essentially clairvoyant;
                                    when not impeded and overpowered by the action of the senses and the exigencies of
                                    the waking life, it seems to be taken up into unison with the universal spirit, to
                                    which there is no here nor there, no now nor then, and to have sight not only of
                                    what is, but of what has been, and what is to be." During our long civil war, many
                                    instances occurred in which men were forewarned in dreams of their own death or that
                                    of their <pb n="253" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 253 comrades. A week previous to the
                                    battle of Fair Oaks, a New York volunteer dreamed that in just one week there was to
                                    be a great battle, in which he would he killed while charging across a field; that
                                    two sergeants of his acquaintance would be killed in the woods, one shot in the
                                    breast and the other in the groin, and that a large number of others would be
                                    killed. The soldier appeared so depressed in spirits the next day that his
                                    companions rallied him about being homesick, and he reluctantly told his dream. In
                                    just a week the battle took place, and the dreamer was killed in full sight of his
                                    regiment, and the two sergeants were killed, twenty minutes after, in the woods, one
                                    shot through the breast and the other in the groin, just as had been foretold in the
                                    dream. More than fifty men, it is said, were witnesses of the truth of this
                                    statement. The night before the cavalry fight at Brandy Station, a trooper who slept
                                    as he jogged along in the column, dreamed that a certain captain in his regiment
                                    would be unhorsed in a fight the next day, and while rising from his fall would be
                                    wounded in his left knee. He told the captain his dream, but was laughed at for his
                                    credulity. But in the very first charge the next day, the captain was unhorsed by
                                    the breaking of the girth, and he was pitched heels over head into a patch of
                                    briars. While he was struggling out his horse was killed by a shell, and a fragment
                                    mashed the captain's left knee so that he had to have it amputated. Three days
                                    before the engagement at Kelly's Ford, "a corporal in the Sixth Michigan cavalry
                                    dreamed that a brother of his, who was a sergeant in another company, would have his
                                    horse killed in the action, and would almost immediately mount a dark bay horse with
                                    a white nose. Within five minutes both horse and rider would be killed by a shell.
                                    This dream was related to more than a score of comrades fully two days before the
                                    fight. Early in the action the sergeant's horse was struck square in the forehead by
                                    a bullet, and dropped dead in his tracks. It was scarcely three minutes before a
                                    white-nosed horse, carrying a bloodstained saddle, galloped up to the sergeant and
                                    halted. He remembered the dream, and refused to mount the animal, and soon after
                                    picked up a black horse- The white-nosed animal was mounted by a second corporal in
                                    another regiment, and horse and rider were torn to fragments by a shell in full
                                    sight of four companies of the Sixth." In the last instance, apparently, the life of
                                    the sergeant was saved by heeding the admonition of the dream. The writer who
                                    narrated this and other similar instances, adds, that "there was a time when a
                                    soldier's dream saved Gen. Kilpatrick's life: when a dream changed Ouster's plans
                                    for three days ; when a dream prevented Gen. Talbert's camp from a surprise and
                                    capture ; and when a dream gave Gen. Sherman more accurate knowledge of Early's
                                    forces than all the scouts." Numerous other instances of prophetic dreams might be
                                    narrated, but enough has been adduced to show that there is something worthy of
                                    considerate attention in some dreams, however trivial the greater part of them may
                                    be. The prophetic revelations made through dreams in ancient times are perhaps
                                    sometimes repeated in these modern times.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Phrenological journal" TEIform="index"/> [From the Phrenological Journal.]</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Grace and knowledge" TEIform="index"/> GRACE AND KNOWLEDGE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Field, Floyd C." TEIform="persName"/>FLOYD C. FIELD.</byline><p TEIform="p"> "But grow in grace and in the knowledge of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ." 2 Peter, iii;
                            18. There are two points brought to view in tin's passage; growth in grace, and a knowledge
                            of Christ. Webster defines grace as follows :—"The exercise of love, kindness or good will;
                            disposition to benefit or serve another; favor bestowed or privileges conferred." Therefore,
                            grace is a practical illustration of the teachings and life of Christ, and the exercise of
                            grace or love should be the guiding star of all our actions and the foundation stone upon
                            which we should build our thoughts, impulses and character, as the Apostle expresses it;
                            "being grounded and rooted in love." Therefore we should grow in that spirit of love which
                            characterizes the life of Jesus, and follow his example that the same pure love that
                            manifests itself in him by action, word and deed might find a dwelling place in <pb n="254" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 254 THE MANIFESTO. our heart, thus following the advice of Peter by adding to
                            faith, virtue; to virtue knowledge ; to knowledge, temperance; to temperance, patience; to
                            patience, godliness; to godliness, brotherly kindness; and to brotherly kindness, charity:
                            for if these things be in us and abound they shall make us that we be neither barren nor
                            unfruitful in the knowledge of our Lord Jesus Christ." Thus Christ by tthis pure love and
                            grace, conquered the" evil propensities that had so long reigned supreme in the affections
                            of man. Peter knowing Jesus, personally, and being one of the disciples and practicing the
                            same pure principles, and looking around him and seeing man reveling in his lower nature,
                            and utterly disregarding the teachings of Jesus, is it any wonder that he should exhort the
                            brethren in this language, "But grow in grace and in the knowledge of our Lord and Savior
                            Jesus Christ?" Every blessing and favor which we receive from the Divine Father, is a grace,
                            and all favors we bestow on each other are graces whether by kind words, brave deeds or
                            worthy acts. It was by grace, that the noble founders of our grand Institution toiled,
                            labored and gave their all, that the future generations might enjoy the fruits of their
                            labor; it is by grace that the doors are open to all who desire to live the life of Christ,
                            and they can come and partake of the waters of life freely, and reap the reward and
                            blessings that are given to those who live a life of self-denial, and receive heavenly grace
                            that flows from the great fountain of light. A knowledge of Christ is as truly a requisite
                            as grace. To know Christ is not simply to know him historically, but experimentally and
                            practically. First, look at his sacrifices. He sacrificed wealth, honor, home and friends
                            and entered life with nothing but the true principles of manhood, having not even where to
                            lay his head. Look at the kindness he manifested in all his actions. In all the record we
                            have of his life we find no human heart made sad by unkind words or ungenerous acts, but
                            that his loving tender mercy gave joy to even the thief upon the cross Look at his power to
                            resist temptation, for when the evil one offered him the whole world he preferred the
                            integrity and purity of his holy, beautiful life. Nothing is • too great, good, or precious
                            to give for the Pearl of great price. As Paul says, "Yea doubtless, and I count all things
                            but loss for the excellency of the knowledge of Christ Jesus my Lord: for whom I have
                            suffered the loss of all things, that I may win Christ." And also we should know him by his
                            sufferings and the power of the resurrection. As Paul says, "That I may know him, and the
                            power of his resurrection and the fellowship of his sufferings" also, "I am crucified with
                            Christ, nevertheless I live; yet not I but Christ liveth in me." No one can have a true
                            knowledge of Christ without having his spirit, living his life and dying as he died to sin.
                            Paul says to the Romans "For in that he died, he died unto sin once; but in that he liveth,
                            he liveth unto God " May all, indeed, die unto sin, and live unto God taking the cross, not
                            as a burden or dread, but as a treasure by which we shall become victorious over sin and
                            death and by having a true, inward knowledge of the sacrifices and sufferings of Jesus we
                            are prepared to live the same pure life and rise above impurities which we behold at every
                            step; for go where we will we see the need of that divine and holy life. Yea, we must have a
                            true inward knowledge of the resurrection and realize what it is to come from the lower to
                            the higher, from the animal to the spiritual; from death unto life. If we follow Christ and
                            receive this' grace and knowledge we are prepared for soultravel, and in order to make
                            proper progress we must throw off all the weights that are antagonistic to the divine
                            principle within, for so long as the carnal nature has the ascendency or control of our
                            being there is no progress. Before grace and knowledge can produce that soul-travel which
                            Christ enjoyed, we must cast aside the weight of worldly love. One may strive to soar in the
                            ambient air of God's love but how soon he realizes he is still groping in darkness with the
                            children of earth; and there are many in this sphere of life that are honest in their
                            convictions, but their minds are so befogged by the dogmas of <pb n="255" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. 255 the antichristian world, that even the near whisperings of angels cannot be
                            apprehended by them. Anger and hate must also be thrown aside and the last vestige
                            completely severed before man can soar in the realms of peace, joy and love, and partake of
                            that divine spirit of purity that comes from God. Sensuality, pride, anger, hatred, deceit,
                            hypocrisy and backbiting can never be in harmony with the divine elements of our nature, and
                            as long as man clings to those evil propensities, just so long lie will remain in darkness,
                            doubt and misery. When man is willing to throw oft his evil nature and sever the last chord
                            that is antagonistic to the divine principle within, then he will receive that love and
                            peace that surpasseth all knowledge ; his heart will expand with tenderness and love, and
                            hate will be unknown; for where purity dwells, hate cannot enter. If those who desire to
                            grow in grace and knowledge, would follow the example of Jesus, the weights of sin would
                            fall, as the scales from the eyes of the blind man, and they could travel in the sunny skies
                            of purity and be wafted higher and higher in divine love that flows from the angelic sphere.
                            This is the resurrection life in which the pure can travel and be fed with spiritual food.
                            And may we all attain this happiness and we can if we grow in grace and a knowledge of our
                            Lord and Savior Jesus Christ. South Union, Ky.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Progress, order and individualism" TEIform="index"/> PROGRESS, ORDER AND INDIVIDUALISM.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo G." TEIform="persName"/>ALONZO G. HOLLISTER.</byline><p TEIform="p"> It is our understanding, that a Shaker's progress is with his back to the world and its
                            customs, for "the fashion of this world passeth away," as well as the lusts thereof, and the
                            whole fabric is destined to cease, and be no more forever. That when the essentials of a
                            true Shaker faith are complied with, all minor matters will be adjusted and disposed
                            according to interior law. No matter how small the beginning, if we continue increasing in
                            the right direction. Better begin small as "a grain of mustard seed," and keep advancing,
                            than to commence with a long stride and have to recede because we have not grown to it. That
                            the New Creation to which we are called, including the new earth possesses all the
                            principles and elements of life, growth, and happiness, necessary to perfect the entire man.
                            That in the spirit revealed in Christ, are "hid all the treasures of wisdom and knowledge,"
                            conferring superior advantages to the learning and science which the natural creation
                            affords, admitting a portion of the latter to be ever so useful and necessary, in its place,
                            and of sufficient amplitude to employ the most capacious minds of our race, all the ages of
                            Eternity in acquiring it. And all that it needs to obtain these priceless treasures, is to
                            devote our energies to the new creating work, and obey its requirements as fast as they are
                            made known to us. That the Order of the Church of Christ's Second Appearing, established
                            under the ministration of Father Joseph Meacham and Mother Lucy Wright, and confirmed by
                            their successors, is a revelation of the Order of the Kingdom of Heaven upon earth; of which
                            it is written, "Of the increase of its government and peace, there shall be no end * * to
                            order it, and to establish it, with judgment and with justice, from henceforth even
                            forever." That as the "little horn" foretold by Daniel, drove the witnesses of Truth raised
                            up in Christ's first appearing, into a wilderness or foundationless state, by "scattering
                            the power of the holy people," the second appearing of Christ was to be signified by a
                            reverse process ; for "He shall send his angels with the great sound of a Trumpet, and they
                            shall gather together his Elect," etc. Jesus when asked by his disciples "Where, Lord?"
                            replied "Wheresoever the body is, there will the eagles be gathered together." That "the
                            Eagles" are those who hear and obey the voice of the Son of God, in this dispensation ;
                            which is likened in the visions of John, to a flying Eagle, because its subjects fly above
                            the spiritual elements of the natural earthly man. That "the body," is that Christ-like
                            unity of spirit, and action, symbolized by one loaf of bread, and one cup, of which his
                            disciples partook at the last supper; for Christ is "the bread of God." 'See Eph. i., 10.)
                                <pb n="256" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 256 THE MANIFESTO. Hence the Psalmist sings prophetically "Gather
                            my saints together unto me ; those that have made a covenant with me by sacrifice." What
                            sacrifice? The sacrifice of sin by coming to judgment—and of their carna' wills, that they
                            may do the will of God. Jesus said, "I came not to do my own will," implying the possession
                            of a will distinct from the will of God; which he submitted, or sacrificed. That as God is a
                            God of order, and order is Heaven's first law, "the nearer we approach the Kingdom of God,
                            the more order we must come to" and, according to the most reliable evidence that can be
                            had, Shakers are in the commencement of that Kingdom which is destined in its progress to
                            "break in pieces and consume all other Kingdoms," while to the increase of its own
                            government, order, and stability there shall be no end, consequently, Shakerism is
                            aggregation, centralization, organization,—a building up, a progress into increasing degrees
                            of order and government, while the progress of the world, and its systems, effected by the
                            great increase of light, is towards disorganization, individualism, and final dissolution.
                            That this demolishing work, which produces so much clash, confusion, and distrust, in the
                            mental, religious, and political world, is nee essary that the Kingdom begun to be set up,
                            may have room to expand—"For in the place where the Most High beginneth to show his City,
                            there shall no man's building be able to stand." It is also necessary that souls may be set
                            free from the binding influence of all man-invented creeds and dogmas, and from all
                            institutions of power that bind the conscience, and obstruct the proper exercise of rational
                            freedom ; that they may be at liberty to accept the terms of the "everlasting gospel," when
                            that is presented, and to press into the Order of the Kingdom of Heaven, and furthermore, to
                            educate them to the true dignity of manhood, that they may rightly appreciate the heavenly
                            call. The Kingdom of Heaven is composed only of volunteers, and built up by a continual
                            volunteer service, as shown by the following testimony. "If any man will come after me, let
                            him deny himself, and take up his cross daily, and follow me." This shows that we advance in
                            self-denial. It also shows a daily sacrifice required, as the price of the daily bread, for
                            which we are taught to pray. Finally, it shows that the only way to follow Christ in the
                            regeneration, is by denying our own wills daily, until it becomes our meat and drink to do
                            the will of God. This affects individuality which is God's own gift, similar to a school of
                            training, where there is freedom to withdraw in case of insufficient inducements, to which
                            agrees the words of the prophetic singer; "Thy people shall be willing in the day of thy
                            power." By voluntarily subjecting individuality to the Order of God made known in the
                            dispensation of His mercy. When souls enter this heavenly Order, the work of demolition and
                            dissolution, proceeds upon the elements and principles of the world within. "Whatever trials
                            or disadvantages one may labor under who is called into this work, because of circumstances,
                            and the frailties of human nature, these can never be but temporary to those who abide
                            faithful; an J every one will reap what they sow, and be recompensed according to
                            faithfulness and the degree of sacrifice made; for such is the pr mise, founded in the
                            justice of God. The government of this Kingdom is the most stable, because it is just, being
                            founded in the revelation of God, and conserving the highest interests of the governed.
                            Though its laws are absolute in their cognizance and control over individual actions, they
                            leave the individual free to unfold in the line of eternal life, because they emanate from
                            these principles, as revealed in the gospel of Christ's first and second appearing. They are
                            administered by a parental authority, which is the highest expression of the united wisdom
                            and faithfulness of the body, guided by revelation and experience; through the most truth
                            loving individuals, whose own interests are identical with the interests of the governed.
                            For none can be more truth loving than those who cease from their own wills ; in other
                            words, l-ay down their lives daily for the sake of the Truth, and for those who have come
                            into it. This is God's way, therefore, man can never improve it, though many have tried. It
                            is the only way yet made known whereby suffering mortals can escape victors from the <pb n="257" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 257 Beast, his image, and the number of his name ; and
                            it is free for all who will, to enter. All are invited to thoroughly examine its claims.
                            Those who have tried it, testify that it has made "new creatures" of them, and their works
                            bear witness that their testimony is true. We who follow in their footsteps, find in present
                            attainments, a prophecy of the same result. For as God makes no arbitrary changes in the
                            life or character of individualized intelligences, every kind of life contains the seed and
                            prophecy of what its future will be, under appropriate conditions. Ours therefore, is
                            irradiated with the prospective attainments and glory of the future for which we strive ;
                            and though at times beset with difficulties which must be overcome in order to secure it,
                            the contimial positive gain of the present, united with patience and perseverance, assures
                            the final triumph, after which, nothing can impede our progress into the everlasting
                            increase of order, beauty, glory and felicity of the Kingdom of the Saints of our God. It is
                            a long and arduous journey through the transition state, the furnace of purification, and
                            what mortal ever found life's journey anything but arduous? But it is the only one that
                            gives assurance of ending our trials and sorrows by removing the cause— while the pay is
                            sure, and ample, along the entire distance, to those who win and the final result more than
                            a thousand, yea ten thousand fold rewards the toil. ML Leba?ion, iV".</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Letter Box</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear children, you cannot look after your..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Dear children, you cannot look after your...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Connecticut, Enfield, 1883" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, Conn., 1883.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Dear Children ;—You cannot look after your habits too carefully. You desire to be happy
                                ; with bad habits you cannot enjoy real happiness. Every wrong habit is injurious, and
                                produces evil results. Bad habits are strong, and continually lure their victims to
                                pleasures, which satisfy not. "The way of the transgressor is hard," as well as foolish,
                                while ^'Wisdom's ways are pleasant" and peaceful. Every act contributes its iota toward
                                forming your characters, moulding the individual beings which you become. Day by day,
                                you are sowing seed, from which must come the fruit of your after lives. Consequences
                                are inevitable. W/iat you sow, you will reap. Sow only good seed. Destroy the weeds.
                                "Sow an act, and reap a habit; sow a habit, and reap a character; sow a character, and
                                reap a destiny." Conquer sinful habits, or they will conquer you. "Array a bad habit in
                                costly attire, it is a bad habit still." Bad habits, in their beginnings, may soon be
                                overcome ; but when grown into your very lives, they are difficult to subdue. Shun the
                                beginning of evil, is golden advice to follow. You may form habits of kindness, or
                                unkindness, honesty, or dishonesty, vice or virtue. Virtue's path is safe. Walk therein.
                                Watch for the sinful habits, and uproot them before they get a firm hold. I want to say
                                to every one that I find indulging in wrong habits, Beware ! You are sowing seed for a
                                harvest of woe ! Your Brother, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Sister L; As Sister Asenath gave the..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Dear Sister L; As Sister Asenath gave the...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New Hampshire, Shaker Village, June 13,1883" TEIform="index"/> Shaker Village, N. June
                                13, 1883.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Dear Sister L ;—As Sister Asenath gave the scholars the privilege to write to the
                                sisters that we would like to talk with, so I thought I would write to you and tell you
                                how I am getting along in school. I feel more interested this year than I did last
                                summer. I study Physiology, Grammar, Arithmetic, Geography, Heading, Spelling, Writing,
                                Drawing and Singing. I know a good deal in all these studies, I like Physiology the
                                best. I know a little about many of the bones in the body. To show you what I know about
                                the arm and hand I will tell you all the bones in them. There is one bone in the arm the
                                name of it is Humerus; two in the fore-arm, Kadius and Ulna; eight in the wrist,
                                nineteen in the hand, fourteen in the fingers, three in each finger, two in the thumb.
                                This is all I have to say about my studies. Now I will tell you about the cherry tree by
                                the East House. Sister Edith told me that the robins would eat all the cherries on our
                                cherry tree so Lizzie and I planned to make a scare-crow and put it in the tree so as to
                                keep the robins away so that we can have some cherries. I often have wished to thank you
                                for taking care of me. With love I close, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blanche" TEIform="persName"/>Blanche.</byline></div3></div2><pb n="258" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>NOTES.</head><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The very simplicity of the advent of Jesus..." TEIform="index"/>
                                The very simplicity of the advent of Jesus...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> The very simplicity of the advent of Jesus was undoubtedly the great stumbling block to
                                the worldly wisdom of the Jewish Church. They had anticipated an heir from the royal
                                family, and to this end consulted their genealogical tables with rigid exactness. lie
                                was to be a lineal descendant of the house of David, and they were, by no means,
                                prepared to accept the Christ from any other source. Several of the prophets had seen in
                                their revelations, the coming Messiah, but he had assumed so many peculiar forms, that
                                the revelations became obscure to the Jewish mind. By some he was exalted even to the
                                Creator of (he heavens and earth, by some to a conquering King, while on the other hand
                                he was to be of the most obscure origin, and was even likened to a root in a poor soil.
                                Such conflicting views were not calculated to establish in the minds of the Hebrew
                                nation a harmony which! could accept the advent of any messenger. To those who had
                                anticipated a King, commissioned with authority from the very God who had so signally
                                delivered them from the Egyptians. Jesus was at once denounced as an impostor. The
                                sacred books had informed them that their Redeemer was to restore, the glory of
                                Jerusalem and take vengeance oj their enemies. To the common people he was to be a
                                prophet, a friend to the poor and a physician to mitigate all their physical ills. To
                                these sons of God, whose habitations were to be like the everlasting hills, enduring
                                throughout all generations, the holy city has been lost for centimes and their people
                                scattered among every nation on the earth. Nearly two thousand years have passed and the
                                religious nature of man, is as ever demanding a knowledge of the highway to eternal
                                life, and yet but little has been learned beyond that which actuated the Scribes and
                                Pharisees in the city of David. Regal splendor and self aggrandizement would be the
                                demanded: credentials of him who came as the anointed Christ of the nineteenth century.
                                The messenger Avho came having no where to lay his head, and urging men to dispose of
                                their property for the benefit cf the less fortunate of this world, before he could be
                                accepted as a disciple, would undoubtedly be in the minds of the Christians, at a very
                                great discount. It has become one of the enigmatical problems of the day, to be able to
                                harmonize the selfishness and war-loving spirit of the worldly-minded Christians, with
                                the pure and peaceable followers of the Son of God, and yet there are thousands who
                                earnestly contend that this very thiug can be done. They implicitly believe in the
                                amalgamation of the flesh and the spirit, and that they can, acceptably to Jesus, serve
                                both God and mammon. There may be dissenters from these views, lights which come down
                                from God, whose voices are yet but feebly heard on the earth, and how very fortunate it
                                is for this class in their every degree of advancement that religion may become a work
                                of conscience, that there are no bands nor bars to prevent the offering of a pure heart,
                                of becoming peacemakers, and of crucifying all selfishness and following the living
                                Christ in the regeneration. The scriptural order that was given, <pb n="259" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/>
                                THE MANIFESTO. 259 says—"Follow the Lamb whithersoever he goeth." Not a pre-arranged
                                course as conducive to our fancied pleasure, but wherever the spirit of the Christ shall
                                lead. Earthly rulers demand a corresponding obedience of their subjects; the army no
                                less of its soldiers, and we are looking with interest to see that order arise from
                                among men that may be known by their acceptance of the principles of Christ and can be
                                designated as the friends of righteousness.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>House and Farm</head><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Forest culture" TEIform="index"/> F0REST CULTURE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Holloway, Cephas" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">An Essay by Cephas Holloway of Union Village, Ohio., delivered before the June meeting
                                Warren County Horticultural Societ3'. The Best Practical Mode of Preserving and
                                ^Restoring tlie IToi ests of Ohio. An intelligent observer can not fail to see that our
                                timbered lands are in a rapidly failing condition, and that unless a radical change be
                                made in their management the end or entire destruction of our timber will be seen in
                                fifty years. We think the time has come for deep thought and decisive action to discover
                                and adopt, if possible, the best practicable method of preserving and perpetuating the
                                most useful kinds of timber trees, and also to determine what is the best use to be made
                                of the existing growth, whether it should be permitted to die upon the ground in which
                                it now stands or whether it should be cut down and taken to market while it still has
                                the highest value, namely, Avhile it is still alive. At the present rate of consumption
                                and decay entire destruction of living timber must follow; and the source of future
                                supply has long since become a subject of anxious thought, a subject which all will
                                admit is one of universal concern for all are cognizant of the manifold uses of wood and
                                how absolutely essential it is to our comfort and well being, nor need we now remind our
                                readers of the scientifically ascertained fact that the total destruction of forests of
                                a country will ultimately unfit it for the occupancy of man. The prospective scarcity
                                and high price of timber, necessarily consequent upon the present devastations, would be
                                of themselves sufficient reasons for planting forests of suitable timber, but when to
                                these considerations are added the probable ruin of habitable districts and
                                deterioration of climate in a whole country, there is an imperative demand for decision
                                and immediate action. Hitherto, the best energies of our rural population have been
                                largely employed in the extermination of forests. The time has come now for a change of
                                policy, one which will secure for us neither too much nor too little timber, but a
                                continuous supply if possible of so much, at least, as will approximately meet all
                                reasonable demands, and this subject has now justly become one of National concern, for
                                taking official statistics as a basis for their calculations, careful observers have
                                demonstrated almost to a certainty, that at the present rate of consumption and decay,
                                the pine woods of the great north-west will be exhausted in less than twenty-five years.
                                The pine woods of the South will hold out for a few years after the former shall have
                                been exhausted and after that, if nothing has been done in the way of reproduction in
                                the mean time, we shall have to look to South America for our supplies. That so little
                                attention, comparatively, has been given to this subject, in the past, seems to us
                                strange when we consider the fact that the raising of timber is by no means
                                unprofitable, and that so much of our land is peculiarly fitted for this industry,
                                consisting as it does, of broken or uneven tracts, partially or entirely unfitted for
                                the cultivation of crops, or it may be of shifting sands which may be made a source of
                                income by being planted with pine trees—these trees serving to stay the sand. Apart from
                                considerations of public good, the first question that may suggest itself to tillers of
                                the soil is, will it pay us to plant and cultivate trees? This question we do not
                                hesitate for a moment to answer in the affirmative if as in all matters pertaining to
                                    <pb n="260" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 260 THE MANIFESTO. husbandry as well as in other matters
                                pertaining to this life due discretion be exercised in the first place it must be
                                ascertained what timber is most in demand and therefore likely to bring the highest
                                price, at the same time, having a regard to what is best adapted to the climate and soil
                                in which it is to be planted. The proportion of a farm to be appropriated for
                                timber-raising, should be in our judgment, at least 1-10 to 1-20 of the number of acres
                                composing it, this much would we think, be sufficient for home wants. Next the ground
                                should be prepared for planting by removing all timber already growing upon it, and by
                                destroying by tillage, all seeds for two or three years before planting. We believe that
                                the original growth of trees in Ohio and Kentucky can not be profitably perpetuated,
                                because of the destruction of the undergrowth, and the cultivation of grass for lawns,
                                pasturage etc. Where these have occurred, both being prejudicial to timber growth,
                                because the tramping of cattle injuring the roots, will ultimately cause trees to die
                                exposed to it, and further, because of the fact that leaves alone should cover the
                                ground in tracts devoted to the culture of trees. And hence we have no hesitation in
                                saying, that the better way to perpetuate is by successive periodic cuttings and
                                plantings so managed, that there will be a regular rotation of the same established, by
                                the time that the primitive growth has been consumed, or otherwise made use of;
                                arranging at the same time that trees shall be cut while still in full life and vigor,
                                so that the cutting shall not be delayed until the trees have become useless by reason
                                of decay. As to the best kinds of trees to plant, we would recommend the walnut, oak,
                                poplar, pine, hickory, butternut, Scotch larch etc. Oak sneds or acorns should be
                                planted immediately after they fall, they should not bo dried for they will strike root
                                immediately, the root running down from four to eight inches in the fall, starting as
                                soon as planted, the tops not starting until the following spring. The black-walnut,
                                butternut, hickory, and other nut trees, should be planted where the trees are to
                                remain; other trees, the seeds of which are small, or which make but little growth the
                                first year, are best grown in seed beds until they are of proper size for transplanting.
                                When trees are taken from the seed beds all the branches should be cut off" and the tops
                                shortened. It will more certainly grow and less exhaust the root. Only one leading shoot
                                should to each tree be allowed, and it not be permitted to fork. All large side branches
                                should be shortened or entirely taken off. The best plan for profitable culture is to
                                plant those kinds to be used for lumber— such as Avalnut, oak, poplar, etc., from one to
                                two rods apart, and to fill the intervening spaces with smaller growths—such as locust,
                                Osage orange and Scotch larch; also, hickory and oak, the two latter to be used for hoop
                                poles. If desirable, or deemed more profitable, fill such intervening spaces—one way
                                with corn, potatoes, etc.,—that is, four and one-half feet in all intervening space
                                between standard trees. The best time for thinning is either in the winter or in tke
                                early spring, otherwise the root will be destroyed. The second thinning would be on the
                                locust and orange plants, for bean poles, grape stakes, etc., leaving a portion for
                                still larger growth and use—say fence stakes and posts, leaving a portion still for rail
                                road ties, etc. There should at all times be a sufficient number of the second class of
                                trees left to keep standard trees trimmed and forced up without branching out. The
                                stumps of the second class may be allowed to reproduce, until the standard overtop and
                                destroy them. Thus may timber land be made productive, also to yield returns in money,
                                within twelve months from so laying out the ground. Care should be taken that no
                                domestic stock be allowed to graze on the land, so planted in timber, whether in winter
                                or in summer ; the hog may be admitted after the third year, indeed the animal may be
                                said to be almost indispensable to many trees, being useful because of its tramping and
                                rooting out ground mice, etc, which would, if not interfered with, gnaw off' the bark of
                                such trees under and above the ground, thus destroying them; should this animal be
                                admitted the first year however, it would destroy <pb n="261" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO.
                                261 all seeds. The expense of fencing can be obviated by the planting of Osage trees to
                                answer that purpose, this species being at the same time one of the best timber trees
                                grown. The best mode of planting for this purpose is to plant a single or double row say
                                one foot apart or wider and plash them the second year down to sixteen inches above
                                ground or less, later plashing them the second time say two feet above the ground, and
                                then permitting them to grow for timber. In planting standard trees, care must be
                                exercised to prevent their being sunburnt. If no intervening trees be put between them,
                                all trees planted should be crowded so closely that no tree will need pruning. Thinning
                                should be carefully attended to. Say hoop poles first, in from three to five years after
                                planting; by pursuing this course, we think that at present prices every acre might be
                                made to return one hundred dollars in poles at each cutting; after cutting let the trees
                                reproduce from the stumps until the larger trees overtop them. It would be our maxim to
                                prevent no timber trees to remain on lands after they are in condition for the most
                                profitable use, as they should then be harvested. Most tree seeds should not be allowed
                                to dry, but should be kept in moist sand or earth in a cellar, but not wet sand, better
                                be entirely dry. They should be gathered through the latter part of the season at
                                maturity or procured from some reliable seed-man, and should be ready to plant in early
                                spring. If preserved as above, keep a tharp look-out and make provision against rats and
                                mice depredations. Every planter will have to select such a list of trees to suit
                                himseli and climate, location, etc. We feel impelled to make an urgent request to
                                parents as an imperative duty to provide by successive planting of lumber trees for
                                their children especially, and also as a national duty, a humanitarian duty. The large
                                dots or stars are the standard treess. The small dots are the four feet apart filling
                                between the standards.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="That old burner" TEIform="index"/> THAT OLD BURNER.</head><p TEIform="p"> Perhaps some young housekeeper would like to know how to clean up an old lampburner and
                                make it as good as new. I had one that I was told to throw away, when a friend told me
                                to boil it in strong soap-suds and it would be all right. I did so and saved my burner
                                and the trouble of sending for a new one.;—</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., M. A." TEIform="persName"/>M. A. B.</byline></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To remove paint from old doors..." TEIform="index"/>To remove paint from old doors...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">To remove paint from old doors, etc., and to soften putty in window frames so
                                        that the glass may be taken out Avithout breaking or cutting, take one pound of
                                        pearl-ash and three pounds of quicklime ; slack the lime in water, then add the
                                        pearl-ash, and make the whole about the consistence of paint. Apply it to both
                                        sides of the glass, and let it remain for twelve hours, when the putty will be
                                        so softened that the glass may be taken out of the frame without being cut, and
                                        with the greatest facility.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Scottish American" TEIform="index"/>Scottish American.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cleaning woodwork" TEIform="index"/> Cleaning Woodwork.</head><p TEIform="p">—An exchange, speaking of the necessity of cleaning woodwork, comments as follows: It
                                often happens that the woodwork on doors, particularly near the handles, will become
                                quite dirty and badly stained by the frequent running back and forth of careless
                                children. In these cases it is sometimes found impossible to remove the marks with cold
                                water, or -without the vise of soap, however undesirable. If this occurs, throw two
                                tablespoonfuls of powdered borax into a pail of hot water, and wash the paint with it.
                                Do not use a brush: but if found impossible to remove the marks in this way, the soap
                                must be resorted to. Rub the soap on the cloth and then sprinkle on the soap dry borax,
                                and rub the spots faithfully, rinsing with plenty of water. By washing woodwork in this
                                way the paint will not be injured, and the borax will keep the kands soft and white.
                                Borax is not half as freely used in domestic labor as it would be if all its usefulness
                                were better known. Its help in increasing the cleansing properties of soap, and at the
                                same time correcting its corrosive tendency, is one most of its valuble properties.</p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Little duties faithfully performed..." TEIform="index"/>Little duties faithfully performed...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Little duties faithfully performed are the stepping stones to perfection.—</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="M., E." TEIform="persName"/>E. M.</byline></div3></div2><pb n="262" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Care of the feet" TEIform="index"/>CARE OF THE FEET
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">When the feet are damp and cold it is impossible to keep
                                        well. There will be cough or sore throat, or hoarseness, sick headache, or some
                                        other annoyance. If cold and dry, the feet should be soaked in hot water for ten
                                        minutes every night, and when wiped and dried, rub into them well, ten or
                                        fifteen drops of sweet oil; do this patiently with the hands, rubbing the oil
                                        into the soles of the feet particularly. On getting up in the morning, dip both
                                        feet at once into water, as cold as the air of the room, half ankle deep, for a
                                        minute in summer ; half a minute or less in winter, rubbing one foot with the
                                        other, then wipe dry, and if convenient, hold them to the fire, rubbing them
                                        with the hand until perfectly dry and warm in every part. If the feet are damp
                                        and cold, attend only to the morning washing, but at night always remove the
                                        stockings, and hold the feet to the fire, rubbing them with the hands for
                                        fifteen minutes, and get immediately into bed. Under any circumstances, as often
                                        as the feet are cold enough to attract attention, draw off the stockings, and
                                        hold them to the fire ; if the feet are much inclined to dampness, put on a pair
                                        of dry stockings, leaving the damp ones before the fire to be ready for another
                                        change. Some persons' feet are more comfortable, even in winter, in cotton,
                                        others in woolen stockings. Each must be guided by his own feelings. Sometimes
                                        two pairs of thin stockings keep the feet warmer than one peir which is thicker
                                        than both. The thin pairs may be of the same or of different materials, and that
                                        which is best next to the feet, should be determined by the feelings of the
                                        person. Sometimes the feet are rendered more comfortable by basting half an inch
                                        thickness of curled hair on a piece of thick cloth, slipping this into the
                                        stocking, with the hair next the skin, to be removed at night, and placed before
                                        the fire to be perfectly dried by morning. Persons who walk a great deal during
                                        the day, should on coming home for the night, remove their shoes and stockings,
                                        hold the feet to the fire until perfectly dry; put on a dry pair, and wear
                                        slippers for the rest of the evening. Boots and gaiters keep the feet damp,
                                        unclean and noisome, by preventing the escape of the insensible perspiration and
                                        odor which are constantly emanating from healthy feet; hence the old-fashioned
                                        shoe is the best for health and for the strengthening of the ankles, by
                                        habituating them to support themselves. Pieces of newspaper wrapped around the
                                        feet over the stockings keep the feet remarkably warm. Cold feet arise from the
                                        want of a vigorous circulation in them; this is often remedied by putting them
                                        in hot wate* in a wooden vessel, so as to cover the toes; in about ten minutes,
                                        put both in cold water, the colder the better, of the same depth, for half a
                                        minute ; the object being to produce a shock, calculated to draw the warm blood
                                        to the soles; this may be done on retiring and rising. Nothing should be
                                        considered a trouble, which can have even a slight tendency to keep the feet
                                        warm, because there can never be recovery from disease or substantial good
                                        health without it.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/>Hall's Journal of Health.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home questions" TEIform="index"/> HOME QUESTIONS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Woods, Sarah S." TEIform="persName"/>SARAH S. WOODS.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Am I improving my time to the best advantage? Do I exercise my mind and hands to
                                accomplish the most my strength and ability will permit ? Am I as efficient as I might
                                make myself? Would I not exert myself more to promote a selfish interest, or to gratify
                                ambition, than my interest to promote the commonwealth stimulates me to? Am I not too
                                selfish to make the sacrifice required of a faithful steward, devoting all my services
                                to my Master's interest, that I may be entrusted with the true riches ? If I am not
                                faithful in the righteous mammon who will commit to my trust the true riches ?
                                Canterbury, N. H.</p></div3></div2><pb n="263" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sweet praise" TEIform="index"/> SWEET PRAISE.</head><p TEIform="p"> Enfield, N. H. In songs of sweet praise our voices we will raise, Imploring the angels
                            to aid; Behold! they're descending, in our music are blending, Bright vision of
                            beauty! Each soul, strike the chord. We'll sing away sadness, bring joy and gladness; Sing
                            away trials that cumber the mind; Sing away sorrow, bring hope for the morrow ; Sing away
                            darkness, bring sight to the blind </p></div2><pb n="264" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Herald of health" TEIform="index"/>Herald of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Herald of Health. October. Contents : Family Registers; How can we escape Insanity ? How
                                to make life worth living; Long hours and Health; Almost a Centenarian; The EdenicDiet;
                                How to keep from drowning; Apples for food; Studies in Hygiene for Women; etc. etc. M.
                                L. Holbrook, M. D. Publisher, 13&amp;15 Laight St. N. Y. $1,00 per. year. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Elzevir library" TEIform="index"/>Elzevir library
                            </head><p TEIform="p">THE
                                EJLJEJEVIH, Among the recent issues of this unique, and in respect to cheapness and
                                beauty of form and typography, really remarkable publication, are the following :
                                "Aristotle," by Sir Alexander Grant; "Plato," by C. W. Collins; "Horace," by Theodore
                                Martin. These are in the famous and excellent "Ancient Classics for English Headers"
                                series, heretofore obtainable only at the price of $1.00 each, but now published in this
                                handsome form for 15 cents each. "The Indian Song of Songs," by Edwin Arnold, author of
                                "The Light of Asia," is published at 6 cents, the cheapest edition heretofore issued
                                being $1.00. We also have the "Life of Alex. H. Stephens," by F. II. Norton, author of
                                "Life of Gen. Hancock," and other works. It contains an excellent portrait, and a fine
                                illustration of "Liberty Hall," Mr. Stephens' famous home. Though a copyright work,
                                paying the usual royalty to the author, it is published at the astonishing price of 10
                                cents. The last issue is Schiller's celebrated "Song of The Bell," and "Hero and
                                Leander," all for 2 cents. These publications are not sold by dealers generally, but
                                only direct, by the publisher, John B. Alden, 18 Vesey St., N. Y.,</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>Phrenological
                                Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> In the Phrenological
                                Journal and Science op Health for October, the reader finds special attractions as
                                striking facts of human science are interwoven with literary sketches and illustrated
                                descriptions, and the whole is presented in a very entertaining style. On opening the
                                Number a fine portrait of the late Montgomery Blair greets us, and an interesting digest
                                of his character follows. Next we have a well-written discussion of the "Relations of
                                Phrenology to Modern Philosophy," in which the criticisms of Professor Bain are sharply
                                analysed. Next we read a beautifully illustrated description of the "St. Gothard
                                Railway." Following that are "Some Observations on Amativeness," The unfortunate Capt.
                                Webb receives an appeciative notice, and an instructive article on Ossian, the ancient
                                Scottish poet, follows. Eleanor Kirk gives some items of good advice to the modern
                                youth, who thinks keeping his bureau-drawers in neat condition is woman's work; and a
                                Western journalist sends the result of an interview with a deaf, blind, and dumb woman,
                                who is certainly a remarkable case of intuitive apprehension. There is also a portion of
                                Milton's charming "Comus," with notes by the editor, and original illustrations. In the
                                Health Department Dr. Allen discusses the "Laws of Heredity," and other writers who know
                                of what they speak, give excellent advice on the "Eft'ects of Alcohol;" "The Food of the
                                Brain and the Teeth;" How Warm Water Cools," etc. The subscription price is $2.00 a
                                year. Address Fowler &amp; Wells, Publishers, 753 Broadway New York. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Homiletic monthly" TEIform="index"/>The Homiletic
                                Monthly
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Homiletic
                                Monthly for October begins theeighth volume, and gives promise of decided improvement.
                                Its new cover and broader margins, and delicate tint of paper, show it off to advantage,
                                and its contents are fully up to its high standard of excellence. The foreign pulpit is
                                represented by Dr. Parker, Rev. Stopford A. Brooke and Rev. C. II. Spurgeon; while Dr.
                                J. M. Buckley, Dr. Buttz,. of Drew Seminary, Dr. Dobbs, Dr. Jeflry and. others, sustain
                                the high character of the American pulpit. Dr. Ormiston's able "Commentary on the
                                Epistle of James;" Dr. Howard Crosb}''s "Lighton Important Texts;" and Dr. Curry's''
                                Great Preachers Whom I Have Known," are continued. "The Minister's Study," by Rev. W. T.
                                Crafts, and "Homiletic Spectacles," by Dr. Holme, are suggestive. "The Prayer-Meeting
                                Service," as usual, cannot fail to be helpful, while the numerous editorial departments
                                are crowded witli matter full off pith, interest, and suggestive thought. The
                                announcement of numerous papers on a great variety oi important subjects, by some of the
                                most distinguished scholars and divines of America and of Europe, specially written for
                                this work, must make the current volume by far the richest and most valuable of any that
                                has proceeded it. $2.50 a year; 25 cents a single number. Funk &amp; Wagnalls, 1O
                                and 12 Dey street, New York.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vanzandt, Helen M." TEIform="index"/>Helen M. Vanzandt
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Helen M. Vanzandt, Sept. 3, at Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. Age 23 yrs. 1 mo. and 18 daysFaithful
                                in duty, true to the cause, and beloved by all. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Word to the careless" TEIform="index"/> A Word to the Careless.</head><p TEIform="p"> —''Order is Heaven's first law." We should think that those who visit this place, did not
                            expect nor intend to keep Heaven's first law, in this world The neglect to return the
                            articles to their proper places, gives the room a very disorderly appearance. Possibly, they
                            may think that time is too short to allow them to attend? to duty, but that, in eternity,
                            there will be nothing to hinder them from keeping the good old law, and which may, in that
                            day, be as easy to regard, as it is for water to run down, hill.—</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., J." TEIform="persName"/></byline></div2><!--
                        <pb id="p29"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]<pb id="p30"/>
                            <pb id="p31"/>
                            <pb id="p32"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>