<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2910" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">20</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">East Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">29</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">10</biblScope><date value="18991001" TEIform="date">October 1899</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">145-160</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="29" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="10" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
THE
MANIFESTO
1S99.
Sketches of Shakers and Shakerism. A synopsis of the United Society of Believers in Christ's Second
Appearing. Illustrated. By Giles
B. Avery.    Price 15 cts.
strange

DANIEL'S & ST JOHNS
PROPHECIES.
48 page pamphlet.    Price 10 cts.
13 for $1.00.
Address,   H. B. Beab, Preston, Ohio.
A SUMMARY VIEW
OF THE
CHURCH,
OF
"United   Society   of  Believers"
It treats of the Rise and Progress of the
Society, together with the general Prin
ciples of the Faith and Testimony.
Price, 50 cts.
BRIEF EXPOSITION
or the
Principles and Regulations
of the
SOCIETY   OF   BELIEVERS.
Price, 10 cts.
THE ALTRUIST.
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is publisht by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all their
property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. It now has 5,000
acres of land in Southeast Missouri on
which it offers a home and employment
for life to all acceptable persons who may
wish to join it.          50  cents a year;
specimen copy free.    Address A. Longley, 2819 Olive St. St. Louis, Mo.
OCTOBER,
WONDERFUL
REVELATIONS
EXPLAINING
MILLENNIAL
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
At the present time there are 320 women
nurses in the service, and these are scattered
from Puerto Rico to Manila.   A nurse now receives under contract forty dollars a month,
and fifty dollars if serving out of the States.
An army uniform has not yet been adopted,
but is in contemplation.   Steps are being taken to place the woman nursing corps of the
army on a permanent and satisfactory basis.
But it is very true, as Dr. McGee says; "This
is a thing which it is impossible to do empirically, or at one stroke."   With our increasing
responsibilities in other lands, responsibilities which entail the keeping of a large force
of our soldiers in countries and climates generally alien to them, the continued maintenance of the corpe of women nurses seems
nothing more or less than a humane necessity.   The woman nurse during the recent
campaign proved herself capable of rising
above the most trying and usual conditions.
She has been a success; more than that, she
has been acknowledged a necessity.   Nursing is distinctly a woman's vocation.   It is a
profession which, under all ordinary and
the most extraordinary circumstances,
should belong to women.     Ask any one of
the soldiers who lay ill or wounded in the
hospitals during the late war what they think
of the woman nurse.   There will be but one
answer to every query, and it will be seen that
the moral strengthening and support of a good
woman's presence is, in time of war and suffering, as great as that of her professional
skill.Anna Northend Benjamin, in Frank Leslie's Popular Monthly for September.
"It is estimated that during the last year
6,000,000,000 pieces of mail matter, including
all classes, were posted in the United States,"
writes Patti Lyle Collins in The Ladies' Home
Journal for September.   "Of this number,
6,312,731 were sent to the dead-letter office,
making an average receipt of about 21,000 letters and parcels for each working day.   During this period more than 85,000 pieces were
dispatched either with insufficient postage
or none at all, 32,000 bore no address whatever
34,000 were misdirected, 200,000 were unclaimed
at hotels and something more than the last
number were sent to fictitious addresses.
And to these figures must be added 2,973,387
letters and circulars without inclosures of
obvious value which could not be returned to
the senders and were destroyed.   More than
50,000 letters contained monej~ amounting to
$38,595 while 32, 422 included drafts, money
orders, etc., to the value of $945,000, to say
nothing of 30,000 with photographs."
"Our Animal Protective League."   We
have received one of the first numbers of the
League, which is a very pretty, illustrative
pamphlet.   The object of the League is to
awaken a deeper interest in "the care, protection and kindly treatment of animals."
The leaflets will be issued monthly, well
printed and well edited, with stories generously illustrated.   The Leaflets are 5 cts. each
or $3.00 a hundred.   Pub. by Our Animal Protective League.   105 East 22nd St. New York.
In hardly any sub !ect are educators interested more just now than in the adequate and
satisfactory representation at the Paris Exposition of American education.   The Director of Education and Social Economy for the
United States, Mr. Howard J. Rogers, writes
on this topic for the twelfth annual Educational number of The Outlook describing
the plans adopted and the character of the
exhibits to be made.   There are several striking pictures with Mr. Roger's article.   ($3 a
year. The Outlook Company, New York City.)
The Journal of Htgeio-Therapt for August has an abundance of truth for those who
are willing to accept it.   The lecture read by
the Rev. Aaron Walker is full of valuable infoimation and equally full of salvation.   He
says that a "clean life is an important factor
in the regeneration of the race."
Dr. Gifford in "The Science of Life," works
earnestly for the advancement of truth while
he says that "Life Science is a word representing a system of philosophy that, when understood and fully developed, will be to mankind in all of his life needs and possibilities,
what addition, subtraction, multiplication
and division are to numbers."  Other valuable
articles may be found in this number which
should claim the special attention of those
who wish to be well informed.    Pub. by Dr.
T. V. Gifford & Co., Kokomo, Ind.
Women hold an important place in the
world's history.  They were the power behind
the throne in ages past.    Every era produced
its heroines, and down through the ages history gives to us noble, cultured women whose
lives have been an inspiration to all.    Their
deeds are recorded with those of men.   They
wore their laurels and won renown by helping
man not by usurping his place or claiming
equal rights with him.   Their first duty was
their home, and around the hearth stone they
inculcated into the minds of their children the
duty they owed to God and to their country.
What place in the world's history will the
twentieth century women occupy? Where
will posterity find the heroines of our day?
Will it be among our so-called highly educated women? Will history record the "century
runs," "golf games," "women's conferences,"
where stupid theories are discussed and
homes neglected?   Will it give a place to club
women with their teas and gossip?Zn Sept.
Donahoe's.--><pb n="145" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Move on!" TEIform="index"/>MOVE ON!</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>By Eider Henry C. Blinn.</byline><p TEIform="p">IN the Providence of God, Move on! Keep moving on ! ! Move on toward improved conditions for
                            society, where men may have confidence in men, that the best interests of society may be
                            conserved. Move on toward an individual cultivation in self-denial and into a high
                            appreciation of practical righteousness. Moving on seems to be so in harmony with the
                            creation or the revelation of God1 that we have every inducement to accept the sacred
                            privilege. Whatever variations in life are for the better, moving oh toward goodness is
                            indeed, moving on toward God. The whole creation seems to share in the universal evolution,
                            and to work as was designed by the laws of nature. We may well contemplate with astonishment
                            the wonderful work that has been wrought in all that pertains to life, since the day it was
                            called into existence. Moving On, best expresses our idea of the successive changes that
                            have taken place on the earth. The animate and inanimate, more or less, share in the general
                            law. The rivulets and rivers are moving on toward the sea, and even the great oceans
                            themselves are moving upward to form the clouds, and then moving down again to fulfill their
                            mission over the whole earth. Individuals, families and nations are moving on from ignorance
                            and barbarity to higher and higher forms of education, and to a wonderful progress in
                            civilization. Human kindness is being more largely developed in merciful forms toward the
                            weak and simple-minded of our own race, and then toward <pb n="146" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 146 THE
                            MANIFESTO. all the lower orders of animal life. Man is growing in this divine revelation,the
                            merciful man is merciful to all the creation of God. There can be no limit to the distance
                            to which this may move on, in its mission of peace on the earth. During that period of time
                            which we are pleased to call the "Stone Age," we read of man, only, as a wild and savage
                            race, and but a slight remove from the wild beasts. Happily for us, man also moved on to
                            another age, and to better and better conditions for the race. We now anticipate a brighter
                            age than ever has been, as the light continues to shine and the hope of the millennium may
                            not be so very far distant. That anticipated season is certainly coming, is moving on, if it
                            be not already at our door. People who stand in their own light, and are determined not to
                            see how beautifully the knowledge of God is beginning to cover the earth, must make the
                            pilgrimage of life a sad, dreary journey, as has been largely the case with the religious
                            world. That has moved at a less accelerated speed than some of the above as it has
                            multiplied a thousand different forms of belief and ceremonies, till it is more of a wonder,
                            than otherwise, that its progress as a whole has been so fortunate. In this year of our
                            Lord, religion, with many persons, means honesty in trade, truthfulness in speech and
                            kindness to man and beast. This form of religion, though destitute of all ceremony, is quite
                            acceptable throughout the whole world. There has been a time when the making of a fetish or
                            the praying to one was called religion. A stick or stone became the representative of a
                            wonderful power. As time moved on, a creed or a ceremony became the vital point on which to
                            form a judgment respecting religion. But in common with everything else, religion has been
                            forced to move on, and although at a snail's pace, fetish, worship and churchal dogmas have
                            largely given place to other forms and systems, more in accordance with the civilization of
                            the age. Religionists from an early date have made capital of the errors of mankind, and
                            have not failed to afflict and to anathematize all who dared to differ from their
                            established form, either on points of faith, or doctrine. The horrors of religious
                            persecution have marched by the side of religious zeal, from age to age, rushing the masses
                            into a baptism of blood, that for fiendishness has not its parallel in the history of
                            heathenism. In the Apocalypse may be read, a vision which illustrates a religious beast,
                            having no less than seven heads and ten horns. This hideous creature was able to draw down,
                            with his magnetic tail, not less than a third part of the stars of heaven. As repellent as
                            the picture is, commentators of all shades of religious belief have charged it upon each
                            other, that their religion embodied this dragon-like representation. Traces of this
                            unchristian spirit are occasionally discovered, even at the present date, but as the world
                            is obliged to "Move On," this form of cruelty will evidently grow less and less till it <pb n="147" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. , 147 will, finally, all fade away and become things
                            and experiences of the past. Dark and sinful days may corne to individuals who neglect to
                            watch, or like the foolish virgins who fail to replenish their lamps with oil, but it may be
                            with them as with the hypocrites of whom Jesus said,"Verily, verily, I say unto you, They
                            have their reward." One most beautiful relief to this sad picture is found in the life of
                            Jesus. His mission of self-denial and soul consecration assures us that the spirit of God
                            still dwells among men, and that even the religious element is moving on, and that
                            righteousness is growing in the earth. This light, so effulgent, agreeably to the prophetic
                            voice, must yet fill the whole earth with its glory, and transform the kingdoms of this
                            world into the kingdoms of our Lord. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Scenes of glory" TEIform="index"/>SCENES OF GLORY.</head><p TEIform="p">Away I have turned from this world's transient glory, From evil and all that the wicked can
                            boast; And have set out for Zion, O hear the glad story, To gain, more than gain, what in
                            Eden was lost. Behold the sweet prospect of life never ending, Here scenes of bright glory
                            will open to you; And as all the strong ties of nature are rending Kind heaven will grant
                            you a life that is new. 'Tis here you may find the true balm of the Spirit, And feast on the
                            bread and the waters of life; Yea, rich treasures eternal may safely inherit, Secure from
                            this world of confusion and strife. Though trials await me the light has descended, The
                            highway of heaven to me has appeared, Though my life it will cost me, I'll not be offended,
                            But keep the straight way which the Lord has prepared. South Union, Ky.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Virgin relation" TEIform="index"/>THE VIRGIN RELATION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo G." TEIform="persName"/>By Alonzo G. Hollister.</byline><p TEIform="p">WHEN the rich young man came running and kneeled before Jesus, and asked him Good Teacher,
                            what shall I do to inherit eternal life? Jesus answered, "If thou wilt enter into life, keep
                            the commandments." The <pb n="148" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 148 THE MANIFESTO. man said, "Which?" Jesus
                            replied, "Thou shalt not kill; Thou shalt not commit adultery; Thou shalt not steal; Thou
                            shalt not bear false witness ; Thou shalt honor thy father and thy mother; Thou shalt love
                            thy neighbor as thyself." The man said, "All these have I kept from my youth up. What lack I
                            yet?" # , A good man it seems, according to his own account of himself ; but he was not
                            satisfied with the life given in these commandments. Jesus looked upon him, and loved him ;
                            gauged himtook his measure. Then he said, "One thing thou lackest; If thou wilt be perfect,
                            go and sell that thou hast and give to the poor, and thou shalt have treasure in heaven, and
                            come follow me." Several things may be learned from this relation. First, that one may enter
                            into life simply by keeping those commandments which enjoin us to do good and to abstain
                            from eviland still not be a follower of Christ, nor have treasure in heaven. Second, to
                            follow Christ and have treasure in heaven of eternal life, one must, in addition to keeping
                            the commandments, renounce earthly possessions if he have any, and be joined in associated
                            and consecrated service with the members who are of Christ's body. Third, for those who
                            selfishly cherish earthly possessions, this requires a change of heart. For where the
                            treasure is there will the heart be also. If the heart is set upon earthly things, it can
                            not be upon heavenly things, for no man can serve two masters. That the reign of the heavens
                            abolishes all private ownership is confirmed by what follows. The young man went away
                            sorrowing for he had great possessions. Observing this, Jesus said to his disciples, "It is
                            easier for a camel to go through the eye of a needle than for a rich man to enter into the
                            kingdom of God." Then Peter began to say to him, "Lo, we have left all and followed thee."
                            That there might be no mistake, Jesus said, "Verily I say to you, there is no man who has
                            left house or brethren or sisters or father or mother or wife, or children or lands for my
                            sake and the gospel, who will not receive a hundred fold now in this time, houses and
                            brethren, sisters and mothers, and children and lands, with persecution and in the world to
                            come eternal life." This can be fulfilled only in the order of communal life, such as was
                            practiced in the primitive Christian church at Jerusalem,such as we are called by the
                            instruction and training we have been privileged to receive, to set an example of, before
                            the world. Is not the reward more than commensurate with the sacrifice we are called to make
                            ? We voluntarily lay off that which is self-limited and perishing, full of conflict and
                            unrest in exchange for which we are promised a hundred fold in this life of all we need for
                            life's support, with life everlasting that has no flaw, to complete our joy when the goal
                            has been won and all conflict is ended. <pb n="149" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 149 Jesus
                            declared that heaven and earth shall pass away, but my word shall not pass away. That is,
                            the heaven and earth built upon the selfish, natural life of the world in its highest reach
                            of perfectness. It is limited, full of antagonism and subject to death, designed from its
                            beginning to pass away, that it might be supplanted by the spiritual and eternal, which is
                            revealed to us in the word that shall not pass away. And this is the -word which is preached
                            to us in the gospel of virgin purity,and of love in self-sacrifice and mutual serving,
                            ultimating in complete death to the old man and old woman, and the birth and growth unto
                            highest perfection and harmony of the new creature in the anointed Savior. Mt. Lebanon, N.
                            Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Least of these" TEIform="index"/>"THE LEAST OF THESE."</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> She had little of earthly beauty; She had less of earthly lore ; She climbed by
                                    a path so narrow, Such wearisome burdens bore! And she came with heart a-trembling
                                    To the warden at heaven's door, And said, "There were hearts of heroes," She said,
                                    "There were hands of might, I had only my little children, That call to me day and
                                    night, I could ouly soothe their sorrows, Their childish hearts make light." And she
                                    bowed her head in silence, And she hid her face in shame, When out from a blaze of
                                    glory, A form majestic came, And sweeter than all heaven's music, Lo, Christ did
                                    call her name !</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Christian Herald" TEIform="index"/>Christian Herald.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Art of government" TEIform="index"/>THE ART OF GOVERNMENT.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Farmer, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>By Henry C. Farmer.</byline><p TEIform="p">T I ^HE present war in the Philippines has caused much discussion in the JL daily-newspapers
                            and literary publications, and the paramount question seems to hang on the Jeffersonian
                            opinion that there should be no government without the consent of the governed, or in other
                            words, that no government or country, the United States, for instance, should attempt to
                            subjugate, control or govern any people without first obtaining their consent or
                            ascertaining if such action would be approved by any country or people it might be our
                            fortune to have power over. <pb n="150" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 150 THE MANIFESTO. I have alluded to this
                            matter, not to discuss it but to apply it to the government of a household. There must be a
                            director, a person in authority, who shall have full charge, complete control in minor as
                            well as in more essential matters, for without such an officer there would be the most dire
                            confusion. It is imminently necessary that there should be a center which all things should
                            revolve around in order that everything have its proper bearing to preserve its equilibrium,
                            and that there be no friction ; without this center,this governor, no system would be
                            successful; no good results, no benefit be derived by members of a family or nation. If the
                            system is a wise one, administered for the common good of all which is generally the
                            intention of the persons in authoritythen success is sure to follow and a benefit to all is
                            assured. Then the governed should yield a ready compliance to all rules and regulations of
                            the government or officers when the affairs of a family or country are honestly and
                            faithfully administered. But the rules and regulations of a family, a community, or a
                            country should be based on the law of equal justice to all,justice tempered with mercy. A
                            careful diagnosis is made by a wise physician, the remedies and treatment decided on, then
                            the patient must faithfully and rigidly follow the direction, the rules which the wise
                            physician has prescribed else the result may be most disastrous; in the same manner and with
                            the same care must the affairs of a family, a community, or a country be obeyed, or the
                            results will be anything but satisfactory. The governor of a state; the judge on the supreme
                            bench ; the officers of a community; all persons in authority have annoyances, trials and
                            perplexities of which the persons having no such responsibilities have no conception and
                            consequently, cau not realize or appreciate the situation. The governed should acquiesce
                            cheerfully and willingly in all reasonable rules, for this is not only making it more
                            agreeable and easy to such officers but is more satisfactory to the persons yielding to
                            them. No abject manner; no humiliating one's self is necessary ; one has only to do this in
                            a manly or womanly manner, fearlessly and honestly. But the governing power owes a duty to
                            those not in authority, and wise managers will not govern with an iron hand, but will
                            administer the affairs of their office in a mild and gentle manner, that good results may
                            follow; will approach those dependent on them as if they had good news to tell; it is not
                            only what is said, but hoiv it is said that produces the desired effect and to which all
                            persons will, usually, quickly respond. Discipline can be maintained sufficiently and with
                            better effect if justice is tempered with leniency and mercy. There are cases where certain
                            laws, rules and regulations seem harsh, unnecessary and uncalled for, but we must bear in
                            mind that such laws are made not to control persons who do not need stringent measures, but
                            to re- <pb n="151" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 151 strain the lawless element, to control
                            persons who, otherwise would not live up to the requirements of society unless they were
                            compelled to do so by such laws. There is only one way to make the affairs of a nation, or a
                            family, a great success, and that is for all to work for the good of others, for the common
                            good, to have confidence in each other, to have no jealousies, to extend to others the same
                            treatment which one wishes accorded to himself, to follow the golden rule, "Do unto others
                            as you would they should do unto you." The provident manager of a household, stores his
                            granary which is still overflowing when it is spring and seed-time and the dearth of winter
                            nearly past; let us, then, apply this to ourselves and store our minds to repletion with
                            good resolutions to govern ourselves wisely, to faithfully perform our duties, and we will
                            find ourselves met in kindred spirit and will have discovered "The Art of Government." Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reform" TEIform="index"/>REFORM.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="McKechnie, Frederic" TEIform="persName"/>By Frederic McKechnie.</byline><p TEIform="p">T I TEMPTED in all points like as we are, Jesus, the Nazarene, must have _L faced the same
                            temptations that to-day assail many an earnest soul. For, whoever has a heart to feel or a
                            brain to think, and looks at the condition of things around him to-day, both near and far,
                            can not help becoming possessed of a longing desire to do something to better conditions. We
                            can not blind our eyes to the fact that all is not as it should be. We would fain help.
                            After long and painful pondering, at last we think we see the cure. The erring nations need
                            no longer err, we say in all good faith; we know how to set them right. Those who walk in
                            crooked paths, if they will only be guided by us, will be set in straight places. Ignorance
                            and sin shall no longer have dominion, for we have the light that will banish all such
                            darkness. Only let us flash it in the sight of a bewildered world, and that world will
                            instantly hail us as its deliverer. Self-love is aroused. We are overpowered by the subtle
                            tempter, and forthwith become eager and zealous reformersof somebody else. "Get thee behind
                            me, Satan!" That is the only reply to be made to this and to every other offer of the
                            deceiver. "Get thee behind me, for it is written, thou shalt love the Lord thy God, and Him
                            only shalt thou serve." Thou shalt not serve self under this or any other specious disguise.
                            Thou shalt serve "Him only." So it is written, and so it is felt, whenever the better self
                            is allowed to speak. To Jesus, the temptation, to go up to Jerusalem, enter the schools of
                            the Rabbis, and as a spiritual teacher make a name for himself outshining that of the
                            illustrious Hillel himself, must have come with terrible strength. But, he put the sweet cup
                            from him, and mended <pb n="152" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 152 THE MANIFESTO shattered masts and broken
                            oars for a few fishermen on a little Syrian lake, and waited till he knew before he spoke;
                            until, in his own life, he had faced and mastered the problems that so pressed for an answer
                            in the life of his times. When that answer came, it was not to name and fame that he was
                            directed, but, to blame and shame. He was not to become one of the great ones of the earth,
                            but simply to go about doing good, to the mean tax-gatherer and the despised woman of the
                            street, and any one whomsoever he might meet by the wells or the wayside. And if any might
                            wish to become the follower of one such as he, here was the preliminary instruction ;"Sell
                            all that thou hast, and give to the poor," words which in the ears of a high-born Roman or a
                            law-revering Pharisee could only sound like madness. But he shrank not from the cross that
                            was henceforth to be the symbol of* his life, and which he carried to the end, from the time
                            when he went home to become subject to his parents. That cross was the entire subjection of
                            his own personal, private will to the will of God. It lay in perfect obedience to the new
                            spirit, the Christ, that took possession of him as he brought his own spirit into subjection
                            to the behests of the divine law, and he preserved it unbroken even unto death. His
                            disciples, to-day and through all days to come, can only take the same path. If we do not,
                            if we reject as unnecessary the cross of self-denial, we are not his disciples, talk and
                            preach as fervently as we may. The world is saved by doers of the word, and not by hearers
                            only. It will be redeemed, is redeemed by those who count not their own lives dear, who seek
                            not to* save the carnal will, but freely lay down their lives for Christ's sake and the
                            gospel's. "All for all," is here the governing law. Give all and you receive all. He who
                            loses his life, finds it again, with some strange element of eternity so Worked into it,
                            that he can never again lose it. He has saved it in the only sure way that it can be saved,
                            and the small satisfaction that comes of having one's own way and will gives place to a
                            satisfaction that knows no bounds, for its root is henceforth set, not in the finite, but in
                            the infinite and the eternal. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="Section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Elder R. M. Messick, Dear Friend..." TEIform="index"/>Elder R. M. Messick, Dear Friend...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Idaho, Star Ada County" TEIform="index"/>Star Ada Co., Idaho.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Elder R. M. Messick, Dear Friend ;Your letter of February 19th at hand and finds us in
                                usual health, for which we are indeed thankful to the Giver of all blessings temporal
                                and spiritual. "You say my views on married life are all wrong and not in harmony with
                                God's word." Jesus in all his teachings, by exam- <pb n="153" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO.
                                153 pie and precept, taught a life of purity, such as is not found on the Adamic plane.
                                He said "All men can not receive this saying save they to whom it is given. He that is
                                able to receive it let him receive it." If one must become emasculated to enter the
                                kingdom of heaven, all must or not enter. It is an inward work. Paul told the
                                Corinthians that the unmarried cared for the things of the Lord, but the married cared
                                for the things of the world how they could please their husbands and wives.1 Cor. vii.,
                                3234. "So then they that are in the flesh can not please Grod."Rom. viii.,8. In my last
                                letter I requested a solution of the above, but you were silent, yet it clearly
                                specifies who those are which care for the Lord and those who care for the things of the
                                world. John says "all there is in the world the lust of the flesh, the lust of the eye
                                and the pride of life is not of the Father but is of the world.'' You say marriage is a
                                divine institution; if divine, why is it under the entire control of the civil law?
                                Abraham, to whom you refer, was under the law, as all are who do not accept the life and
                                example of Jesus the Christ. You say "when the Millennium comes then marriage will
                                cease." To every faithful follower of Christ the Millennium has appeared, and marriage
                                ceases with them. Jesus said, "The children of this world marry but they which shall be
                                accounted worthy to obtain that world neither marry or are given in marriage." Peter
                                says there will be a new heavens and new earth wherein shall dwell righteousness. You
                                say that you infer from my leiter that I am not now with my wife. It is with me as Paul
                                said, "This I say brethren, the time is short; it remain eth that both they that have
                                wives be as though they had none."-l Cor. vii., 29. The meaning conveyed is, that they
                                live as virgins, wholly abstaining from the gratifications of the flesh. Paul says "They
                                that are of Christ Jesus have crucified the flesh with the passions and the lusts
                                thereof." The keys Peter received of Christ unlocked to him the great mystery of
                                godliness and he had a desire to know the truth for he said to Jesus; "Lo ! we have left
                                all and followed thee." And Jesus said, "Verily I say unto you, there is no man that has
                                left house or brethren or sisters or father or mother or wife or children but shall
                                receive an hundred fold now in this time and in the world to come eternal life." In the
                                hundred fold promised in return there is no wife but persecution is mentioned in lieu
                                thereof. In his first epistle he said ; "Dearly beloved, I beseech you as strangers *
                                and pilgrims, abstain from fleshly lusts which war against the soul."1 Peter ii., 11.
                                You say no one can be saved without immersion into water. To be baptized into Christ is
                                to be baptized into his death to sin, for millions are baptized in water and still
                                remain out of Christ. "For by one spirit are we all baptized into one body or church,"
                                which is the church of Christ. Give me the baptism by the spirit into the Christ life
                                then I know I am saved from sin and by no other baptism can anyone find salvation. Your
                                friend,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bellmire, William W." TEIform="persName"/>Wii. W. Bellmike.</byline></div3></div2><pb n="154" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mother Ann Lee" TEIform="index"/>MOTHER ANN LEE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">T I 1HIS is a befitting opportunity to renew our vows of consecration to the _l_ noble cause
                            which she espoused. We exalt the integrity of purpose which fitted her as a pure agent to
                            disseminate light and truth to the world, clearly defining the nature of sin and revealing a
                            way of salvation therefrom to all souls. Those who are blest to associate as Brethren and
                            Sisters in the Virgin order which is the fruit of the revelation of God through Mother Ann,
                            have a debt of gratitude to render for sacred protection and liberty which no others
                            comprehend. Its blessing and beauty open anew to our minds as we realize that one baptism,
                            one cross and one sacrifice enables whosoever will, to find a spiritual home for both soul
                            and body, under the parental guidance of God's love to mankind. We have unlimited confidence
                            in that Christ which spoke through Jesus of Nazareth, giving to the world as much of truth
                            as it was then prepared to receive, and which was opened afresh and finally perfected,
                            through Mother Ann. Only for this sacred feature connected with the journey, the landing of
                            Ann Lee on the shores of America would be an event of no more moment to us than the landing
                            of hundreds of people, before or since. The spirit breathed into her soul, opening to her a
                            purely unselfish mission to which she ever remained faithful. We rejoice that the testimony
                            of Mother Ann was preached in a free land, and that this blessed church was established upon
                            principles which are life unto life to those who obey them. The crowning feature of her life
                            was loyalty to principle. She was opposed and severely persecuted by both men and women
                            whose favor she might have sought, but she reviled not. We honor and seek that birth of the
                            spirit, which through obedience may be ours, and which was possessed by Mother Ann so that
                            she flinched not before her duty but published the truth in all its might, receiving often
                            in return great persecution with malice and enmity against the Christ testimony. The mission
                            of Mother Ann made it possible to build and maintain homes on a spiritual, communal basis,
                            and many happy communistic homes of Brethren and Sisters, prospering in each other's union
                            and blessing have been the result of this suffering and labor. We have a peaceful, happy
                            home, blest with the comforts of life, with temporal, moral and spiritual protection by the
                            faithfulness of our parents in the seen and unseen worlds. Above and beyond all for which we
                            give thanks is the knowledge of her Christian mission which has opened its arms as a loving
                            fatherland mother, enabling us, if we are so minded, to stand as brothers and sisters in
                            gospel union and equality in Christ. <pb n="155" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFES TO. 155 We are
                            members of a Church which should be "without spot or wrinkle," a faith which is as the "keys
                            of the Kingdom," a light which showeth us the "exceeding righteousness" demanded of "his
                            people" a relationship which claimeth "he that doeth the will of my Father which is in
                            heaven, the same is my brother, and sister, and mother;" an inheritance which makes us heirs
                            of the kingdom, "joint heirs with Christ." With such a legacy what shall the future of our
                            church biing forth? Shall it not be an hundred fold of the fruits of the Spirit? The "Spirit
                            and the Bride" demand it of those who would "enter in through the gates into the City." East
                            Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thy kingdom come" TEIform="index"/>"THY KINGDOM COME."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Horton, Lizzie D." TEIform="persName"/>By Lizzie D. Horton.</byline><p TEIform="p">THE kingdom of Christ, which we pray may be establshed upon the earth, does not come with
                            display, for it is the enthronement of Christ in each individual life. Its perfect
                            consummation, will be the obedience rendered to the will of God. The law of this heavenly
                            kingdom is love; as its principles of righteousness and peace are made the guiding and
                            controling elements in the hearts of men, the knowledge of the truth, is extended to all
                            people. It was the mission of Jesus to lay the foundation of this spiritnal kingdom and
                            having taught many truths as the laws for its government, he left with his disciples,
                            instructions for its growth and development, commanding them ; "Go ye therefore and teach
                            all nations," baptizing them through faith and love, as members of the kingdom of God or
                            Christ Church, of which Jesus is the "corner-stone" its life and the source of its power.
                            The majority of those who followed Jesus, failed to understand the distinction between the
                            Kingdom with its spiritual rulership, and the earthly kingdom which they Iiad expected he
                            should establish in Jerusalem, and many discussions arose from time to time, as to which of
                            them should be the greatest in the kingdom of heaven. Jesus taught them that these
                            distinctions did not exist in his kingdom, but the highest place should be given to him who
                            was most willing to be the least, or servant of all. "Blessed are the poor in spirit, for
                            theirs is the kingdom of heaven." In this kingdom, there are neither rich nor poor, high nor
                            low, as shown in the words of the Divine Teacher,"I have not called you servants, but I have
                            called you friends," also, "I am among you as he that serveth." As we accept the life of
                            Christ, just so far are we able to proclaim his mission of peace and good-will. When Christ
                            reigns as King the powers of darkness will be dispelled by the light of that spirit which
                            fashions the life according to the perfect Pattern. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><pb n="156" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. OCTOBER, 1899. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is publisht by the "United
                            Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued regularly by
                            the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the religious
                            views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. Address all communications
                            to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. j One copy one year, postage paid. .50 A
                            cross in the margin will show that your subscription has closed. \ Remittances for
                            subscription 5 by Money Order should be on the Post Office at Concord, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">August. Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. Thermometer. Kain. 72.4 10.75 in 1899. 69 1.75
                                " Highest Temp, during this mo. 84 above 0. Lowest " " " " 48 Number of rainy days " " 5
                                " " clear " " " 11 " " cloudy" " " 15 Sept. 1899. It is harvest time in this quarter of
                                our Masterly Globe. We are gathering apples, pears, sweet corn, potatoes, etc, all of
                                these look so perfect in form, and are of such excellent quality, we might imagine they
                                grew in the garden of Eden. In hrashing our grain, the oats turned out over fifty
                                bushels to the acre; rye yielded in proportion. We have a full supply of garden products
                                from vegetables, fruits, and roots each in its season. The weathr being so dry during
                                April, May and June our meadows did not yield the amount of hay they did last year,
                                consequently there will not be so many tons to sell. We shall have enough to supply home
                                stock. The standard of our moral obligations we endeavor to bear aloft both by precept
                                and example. In our connection here we find, Many men of diverse minds, Many men who
                                choose to stray And their foolishness display. Many who their wills control, Exhibiting
                                a dingy soul, There's a few who still declare, By the Truth their lives they square.*
                                The health of Community, generally, good. There are some who can not always stand erect
                                under the pressure of Life's burdens and so need the help of a good physician. Elder
                                Arthur Bruce gave us a short call on Aug. 28th, which was very pleasant. It increases
                                our love which is the life of the soul. Calvin Q. Eeed. South Family. Sept. 1899. "The
                                world moves" bringing to us blessings, rich and many. The new highway is rapidly
                                approaching completion; the traveling public are watching and waiting for the good time
                                coming, when the old road shall be no more, and the crooked, winding ways of the old
                                mountain road will give place to the strait path where the wayfarer can travel without a
                                fear. Brothers, Frederic McKechnie and Daniel OffordSisters, Eldress Anna White, Sarah
                                Burger and Cecelia DeVere who attended the Peace Convention at Mystic, Conn., on Sunday
                                afternoon, the 27th ult. gave a rehearsal of the meetings, in the TERMS. <pb n="157" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 157 Hall of the Church family. As we listened to their
                                remarks we were more and more convinced that the "world moves," and that goodness is
                                filling the souls of men. Elder George Clark, of Enfield, Conn., called here on a sunny
                                morning in Aug. and in the afternoon Elder Arthur Bruce of East Canterbury paid us a
                                hurried visit. The "world moves" and so they could not tarry long, for the call to all
                                is Forward. We shall much regret the passing away of The Manifesto, it was such a
                                pleasing medium of communication with friends far and near, but the "world moves" and
                                all things of this world must pass away, but the word of eternal truth and light which
                                we have sought to publish in the earth can never die. Genevieve De Grata. North Family.
                                Sept. 1899. The beautiful autumn weather of September, clear and sunny, yet cool, finds
                                us with haying all finished, potatoes almost all in, and rye and other grain crops
                                safely housed. We are now awaiting the arrival of a portion of our corncutting machinery
                                from the repairer, and then we shall be able to cut the ensilage corn that is to feed
                                our milk-producers throughout the approaching winter. Of fall apples we had a very
                                plentiful supply from our Eed Astrakhan, Twenty Ounce, and other trees. Winter apples
                                still remain to be gathered, so soon as they shall ripen, and though they are not
                                over-abundant we shall yet have enough, and that as the proverb tells us is as good as a
                                feast. Our bee-keeping experiment has been quite a success. From our five hives we have
                                so far, taken 100 lbs. of honey and expect to get yet more before winter comes. Meantime
                                the bees, angry at the robbery of their stores, are continually on the alert to sting
                                any one who comes near their homes, or else diligently search into belated squash and
                                bean blossoms for the means to make up that "more" which we are expecting. We have
                                received in printed form copies of a vote of thanks from the authorities of New Lebanon,
                                expressing appreciation of our liberality in donating right-of-way for the New State
                                highway that runs through our lands. Such tokens of the good-will of our neighbors are
                                valuable and to be valued, and we feel correspondingly grateful for them. In concluding
                                these Notes we have only to mention that a few of us had the privilege of visiting the
                                34th Annual Conference of the Universal Peace Union at Mystic, Conn, towards the end of
                                August. It was very pleasant to meet with so many lovers of the cause of peace and
                                good-will among nations. We are all agreed that peace and good-will between individuals
                                is the only right thing. Those who met at this conference met to maintain that it is
                                also the only right thing between nations. We derived much good from our brief
                                intercourse here, and believe that vs e also ministered good and the whole aim of life
                                can be summed up can it not?in these few brief words, to give and to get good. Frederic
                                McKechnie.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Sept. 1899. Well, so we must say goodbye to The Manifesto! It is like saying farewell and
                                giving the hand shake to a friend from whom we are being parted, and whom we do not
                                expect to again meet until we clasp hands on the other side of the mystic river. It
                                causes a feeling of sadness to come over our spirit and a regret that conditions
                                necessitate such a change. Longfellow beautifully expresses the sentiments that should
                                dominate the soul under such conditions. "As one by one thy hopes depart Be resolute and
                                calm; O fear not in a world like this And thou shalt know ere long, Know how sublime a
                                thing it is To suffer and be strong." While we are penning these lines by the light of
                                the evening lamp we realize plain- <pb n="158" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 158 THE MANIFESTO. ly the
                                presence of some of those saints who have journeyed on and they minister hope and
                                courage; they were faithful unto the end and our prayer is may we be worthy to follow in
                                their footsteps; and may those who to-day, here in earth life, are bearing the brunt of
                                the battle to sustain the cause and uphold the principles of the higher life be
                                comforted and strengthened. The trend of thought manifested in the writings of the
                                advanced thinkers, religious or political, point very plainly to the culmination of
                                another of those wonderful cycles that, as mile-stones, mark human progress; and the
                                race is entering upon a new cycle that will bring to the front powers that have in the
                                past laid dormant, and by their use human life will be lifted higher in the scale of
                                spiritual evolution. The testimony that Believers have held forth, that a denial of the
                                attractions of the lower life and a spiritual growth away from those conditions is
                                necessary for a development of the spiritual life is stronger to-day in the world than
                                ever, and though sects and parties may rise and then decay, that truth will remain
                                forever a beacon light showing the way to attain to those treasures that perish not with
                                their using. Hamilton DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Sept. 1899. The foliage, already turning to view its fast fall colors, and the bleak
                                winds, so familiar to September and its followers in New Hampshire, are striking the
                                death knell of our short-lived Summer. Of small fruits she offered us a bounty, and we
                                were quick to seize a goodly share during her prime. Now that she is leaving us, we are
                                pleased to find ourselves entitled to valuable property in the shape of cranberries,
                                grapes, butternuts, with a promise of our full share of chestnuts and beechnuts when
                                Jack Frost is ready to help us. The cutting of ensilage is now in progress. 400 tons of
                                corn, 15 ft. tall will yet come under the power of McCormick's Corn Binder. The more we
                                use this machine the better we like it. Nothing that chews the cud and parts the hoof
                                will suffer when supplies are safely stored in the three huge silos. While squashes are
                                not considered in quality quite as good as last year, 1038 are now at hand for winter
                                storage and demolition. Day school opens this month, in common with neighboring ones,
                                twenty-seven pupils in prospect. Our full order of Ministry visited the Society at
                                Enfield, N. H., between Aug. 28 and Sept. 15, and are now at home once more. Jessie
                                Evans.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Sept. 1899. It was with heartfelt sorrow we read the notice of the intended suspension of
                                our Manifesto, whose pages for many years have helped to cheer us along life's way. Our
                                Society as a whole has had an extra fine trade in Fancy Goods this season. The Sisters
                                of both families who attended fairs and went to hotels to sell their articles, have put
                                into the family purses sums of money, pleasing to the eyes of all. During the past month
                                the writer with Eldress Eosetta Cummings and six Sisters, of the Church order, spent two
                                days at the Lake Sunapee Spiritualist's Camp Meeting. There we met an old-time friend
                                Dr. J. M. Peebles, of Battle Creek, Mich., who delivered a lecture upon his travel and
                                experiences in India. His kindly remembrances of Elder Frederick Evans and recital of
                                their doings while in England, were very pleasing. On Sabbath evening, nothing would do
                                but we must occupy the platform and sing and speak in their conference meeting. At time
                                of writing, we are entertaining Elder Abraham Perkins of East Canterbury. <pb n="159" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 159  We see that time has laid no severe hand upon
                                him. We can say as we think of his 92 years of lifeVirtue pays those who prefer
                                soul-elevating influences and pleasures to those that debase and degrade. Even blessed
                                are those whose lives have ebbed away many years below the life-mark Elder Abraham has
                                attained, having given their all to the work of human advancement. Consoling is the
                                knowledge, "Not all earth's denizensthe human race To sensual life their noblest pow'rs
                                have given On history's page this glowing truth we trace, That souls for high and
                                glorious aims have striven." George H. Baxter.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Sabbathday Lake, Me.</head><p TEIform="p">Sept. 1899. While we have seemed to be neglectful of "Home Notes," home work has required
                                constant attention and in that capacity we have striven to be faithful, for the elements
                                have been against us in floral culture. The early drought affected our sweet peas so
                                much that the vines were completely covered with the green aphis. This fly absorbed the
                                goodness from the vines, and only by the persistent efforts of shot guns, Sprayers,
                                etc., did we succeed in subduing them. As it is, we got no flowers in July, but through
                                August we had abundant bloom, and what is better, found a ready sale for all the sweet
                                peas, asters and carnation pinks we could raise Since Sept. came in, heavy winds and
                                more drought again played havoc among our vines, but now it is too late to save them.
                                Sisters have canned green peas and string beans for winter use, and the season is at
                                hand for fruit canning. Of some kinds we shall have enough to be comfortable. Apples in
                                our section are scarce. Repairing buildings is the order of the day. In the Dwelling
                                house a large room is being fitted up for music; and at the Laundry the Sisters are
                                arranging a nice, light room where they can be together while making the fancy work. The
                                fall term of school is about to open and the pupils are rejoiced to welcome Wentworth,
                                the mathematician, instead of Walsh. We are delighted with "Gentle Manners" and shall
                                use it in our school. We were not unmindful of the anniversax-y of the sixth of August.
                                Appropriate songs were sung and selections from the "Life and Experience of Mother Ann
                                Lee" were memorized and rendered in our Sabbath evening Service. Ada S. Cummings.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Alfred, Maine" TEIform="index"/>-Alfred., Me.</head><p TEIform="p">Sept. 1899. We regret to hear that the publication of The Manifesto must be discontinued.
                                We wish to thank the Editor and publishers for their efforts to continue it as long as
                                they have under the pressure of so many financial difficulties. On Aug. 26, through the
                                kindness of the Portland and Rochester R. R. our young people enjoyed an excursion into
                                the city of Portland, and after a sail to Peak's Is. where lunch was served, we returned
                                to the city and took a ride of about five miles on the electrics, arriving home at 1 p.
                                m. tired and glad to be in our quiet home again. We hope to be blessed with an abundance
                                of rain before long, for the springs and wells are failing us and all the water for
                                kitchen and laundry purposes has to be pumped. The spring that supplies the tank at the
                                foot of our hill where the trains fill their boilers, which has never been known to fail
                                since the railroad was built, some thirty years ago, in now so low that the Railroad
                                Company have had to put in a steam pump to pump the water from the lake into the tank.
                                The sweet corn is being harvested and taken to the corn factory. We find the amount from
                                15 acres to be 28,Yo9 lbs. after being cut off ready for the cans. Eva M. Libbey.</p></div3><pb n="160" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="White Oak, Ga." TEIform="index"/>White Oak, Ga.</head><p TEIform="p">Sept. 1899. To-day the first brick of our enlarged Southern home was laid by a son of
                                Ham, and we are glad to record progress and encouraging prospects. Ten months ago a
                                small company from Union Village and White Water, Ohio, accompanied the beloved Western
                                Ministry to this location, close to the town of White Oak, in the extreme south east
                                county of Georgia to found another center of spiritual life and light as understood and
                                enjoyed by the "people called Shakers." A few persons from the South joined us and in a
                                beautiful Southern mansion with abundant acreage, timber, fish, sea-breeze, promising
                                fruit we daily perform our duty, asking God's blessing upon our labors. This
                                newly-acquired estate of 10,000 acres is peculiarly adapted to stock raising and dairy
                                purposes and is located on the F. C. &amp; P. K. R. midway between the important
                                cities of Brunswick, Ga., and Jacksonville, Fla., and extends to within six miles of the
                                Atlantic swell,in fact the tide steals up to our asparagus bed not 100 yards from the
                                house. We have already proved that our home farm is capable of raising 50 bu. of corn
                                per acre, and 300 lbs. of pumpkin per vine, and sweet potatoes to astonish even New
                                Jersey. Asparagus equals anything North, and melons, wellthey are at home here, and just
                                enjoy growing "big and beluscious" as the darkey declares. Thirty of our lange-fed
                                cattle were rounded up for sale, a few days ago, and all were surprised at their fat and
                                healthy condition. On another branch of our possessions, a $10,000 crop of excellent
                                rice is being harvested, and this will very materially help to raise the new and
                                conveniently modern 90x40 two-story extension to our home. Our climate is not
                                accompanied with more, but probably less disadvantages than Maine, Minnesota or
                                Mississippi, and there is much good to rejoice over and share every way and alway. We
                                humbly and confidently look to the divine Spirit to gather to us an earnest,
                                self-conquering, spiritually Christ-baptized company to carry on the work of the pure
                                gospel of love in labor and life our precious heritage and present and eternal hope and
                                heaven. The Ministry of the West expect to spend the winter with us, and we hope to
                                welcome them next month. We feel waves of loving interest and spiritual blessing,
                                reaching and touching us from so many believers in other homes. We send back the
                                overflow' of our thankful hearts to you all, and pray that big billows may break in
                                blessing on every shore of our rock-bound Zion. Elder Charles Faraday or Eldress Laura
                                Fridger will gladly give any further information desired. Let us do right as we eat good
                                food, not for reward but for health. Courtney Rundelle.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Help one another" TEIform="index"/>HELP ONE ANOTHER.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hunting, George F." TEIform="persName"/>By Rev. Geo. F. Hunting.</byline><p TEIform="p">''Help one another," the snowflakes said, As they cuddled down in their fleeey bed. "One of
                            us here would not be felt One of us here wouldjquickly melt! 'But I'll help you, and you
                            help me, And then what a big white drift we'll see." "Help one another," the maple spray
                            Said to its fellow-leaves one day; "The sun would wither me here alone -Long enough ere the
                            day was gone; But I'll help you, and you help me, And then what a splendid shade there'll
                            be.' "Help one another," the dew-drop cried Seeing another drop close by its side; "This
                            warm south breeze would send me away And I should be gone ere noon to-day; But I'll help
                            you, and you help me. And we'll make a brook and run to the sea!" "Help one another," a
                            grain of sand Said to another grain just at hand; 'The wind may carry me over the sea, And
                            then, oh what will become of me? But come, my brother, give me your hand, We'll build a
                            mountain and there we'll stand?" ***** And so the snow-flakes grew to drifts, And grains of
                            sand to mountains; And leaves became a pleasant shade, And dew-drops fed the fountains.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kirsten, Caroline W." TEIform="index"/>Caroline W. Kirsten
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Caroline W. Kirsten, at Hancock, Mass. July 26, 1899. Age 18 years, 1 mo. and 28
                            days.</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p19"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
Christianity and Science, by Daniel T.
Taylor.   The best thing to say about this little
book isread it, and then make your own
conclusions.   It was published for the purpose of throwing a little more light upon the
subject, and we want all the light that can be
given on any subject.   Pub. by H. L. Hastings
47 Cornhill, Boston, Mass.
That there are five thousand theatres in
America, and that one million and a half people attend them each week-day night, spending seventy millions of dollars a year on theatre-going, are the surprising facts with
which Mr. Franklin Fyles, the dramatic editor of the New York Sun, will open an important series in the next issue of The Ladies'
Home Journal.    The series will be called "The
Theatre and its People," and will run through
seven numbers of the magazine, lavishly illustrated with pictures made by twelve different artists.   The articles will treat of every
phase of the theatre, the play and the actor,
from the inside, and will tell how a theatre is
managed; the actual money which plays have
made; how an actor is trained and what the
actors are actually paid;   ho w a play is written and what the authors receive; how a play
is rehearsed; the first night of a play; how
the actresses "make up" and what they use;
and in a minute way the two last articles will
show what goes on behind the scenes on the
stage during a performance.    It is a curious
fact that this will be the first time that the
theatre and the actor have ever been exhaustively treated in a magazine, and that there is
no book on the subject in existence.
"The Art of Buying Food for a Family," by
Mary Graham, is an able paper in the September "Cosmopolitan" on the very practical subject of purveying for a household. The
writer shows just where the average housekeeper is wasteful, and tells many things that
will enable a purveyor to supply her family
with variety in food at less cost than that
with which she now endeavors to maintain a
household with a too frequent accompaniment of complaint and criticism.    This "Cosmopolitan," seems to be a household need,
for it contains another article in the same
vein, by Anna Leach in the '-Delightful Art of
Cooking."    It is remarkable what a wealth of
information she crowds into a few pages. One
longs for meals prepared and served as she
suggests.   She promises endless variety, just
as cheaply too, when one learns to prevent
the wastefulness which is the besetting sin of
the American kitchen.
AND
SHAKERISM.
By Giles B. Avekt.
Price, 15cts.
From the  Bible  Class.
FORGIVENESS.
By A. B. Chittenden.
"Lord, how oft shall my brother sin
against me, and I forgive him? till seven
times? Jesus saith unto him, I say not unto thee, Until seven times: but, until seventy times seven."Matt, xviii., 21, 22.
In the above texts Jesus plainly teaches
that the bestowal of forgiveness is a virtue
having no limitations.
Forgiveness is not a synonym for a forgiving act, a word or a mere thought, but
it is the divine influence of the Christ love
which falls as the soothing balm upon the
penitent soul who seeks remission from
sin.   Those endowed with this Christ-like
love wait not the transgressor to return to
them in the deep agony of sorrow and repentance to beg forgiveness but even in
the midst of his transgressions they pray,
Father, forgive him.
Perhaps there are those who may say
that it is easier to write of this spirit than
really to possess it, and to the Christian
learner it is, yet when we think that if we
forgive not men their trespasses neither
will our heavenly Father forgive us our
trespasses, will not the knowledge that
we ourselves at times yearn to know more
of the forgiving power of God help us to
do unto others as we would -be done by?
There is a condition of mind where a
wrong has been committed, forgiveness
been sought and still the spirit is not at
rest.    Why? Because, deep in the heart is
the knowledge of an unearned forgiveness
and instead of the needed balm, the encouragement and strength desired is the
bitter sting of a conscience which can not
be eased until the steps dictated by it have
been taken which bring the forgiveness
so long sought.
East Canterbury, N. H.
 says, that young or
old, in play or in earnest, man is prone to
be a brute.
Hawthorne
<pb n="" id="p20"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
"GENTLE   MANNERS."
A Guide to Good Morals.
Published   at   East   Canterbury,   N. H.
"Nothing on earth is more beloved and
honored in the world's great heart, than a
noble youth, whose aims are high, and
whose life is a moral essay."
Gilt edged20 cts., postage 4 cts.
Boards, 16 cts. postage 4 cts.
Paper, 10 cts. postage 2 cts.
AddressH. C. Blinn.
East Canterbury, N. H.
SHAKER HAMAMELIS
(WITCHHAZEL,)
A. remedy for Cuts, Burns, Scalds,
Headaohe, Sore Throat and all
oases of external inflammation
Taken internally for Bowel
Complaint, Bleeding of the
Lungs or Bowels, and for
all aches and pains.
For use externally, bathe the parts and
lay on a cloth wet with the Extract.    Internally, take one half teaspoonful three
times a day.    Use hot or cold.
. Ask your druggist for it or send your
order to Arthur Bruce,
East Canterbury, N. H.
"INTERPRETING PROPHECY"
AND THE
"Appearing of Christ,"
is the title of a neat little pamphlet of
some forty pages, just sent out by A. G.
HOLLISTER Of MT. LEBANON, N. Y.
The many at the present time who are
interested in the fulfillment of prophecy,
and in its mathematical calculation, will
find themselves by the side of the good
old prophet Daniel, and with him illustrating the Coming of Christ so clearly
that no occasion can arise for the least
doubt.                             Price, 10 cts.
50   YEARS'
EXPERIENCE
Trade Marks
Designs
Copyrights &c.
Anyone sending a sketch and description may
quickly ascertain our opinion free whether an
invention is probably patentable. Communications strictly confidential. Handbook on Patents
sent free. Oldest agency for securing patents.
Patents taken through Munn & Co. receive
special notice, without charge, in the
A handsomely illustrated weekly. largest circulation of any scientific journal. Terms, $3 a
year; four months, $1.  Sold by all newsdealers.
MUNN & Co.361Bpoadwa^ New York
Branch Office, 625 F St., Washington, D. C.
 to advanced thought peoplesam ple copy of the most original and.
practical occult journal of the age.
The exponent of West Gate Philosophy.
A.  new occult system..An unlimited field of labor open to teachers, lecturers
and healers.   Address,
The ORACLE, Sta. A.    Boston, Mass.
HAVE YOU "'OOMMON SENSE?"
If not, send at once for a free copy of this
liberal-minded  advocate of advanced
thought, which brings health and
success.    Address
"Common Sense," M. O. 55 State St.
Chicago, 111.
AUTHORISED   RULES
OF
THE   SHAKER   COMMUNITY.
The religious basis of the Order must
be a foundation resting on the principle of
righteousness, which principle is God.
This should rule the life of the individual for the protection of his own soul, for
the peace of the family and as an evidence
of his upright standing before the world.
Price, 10 cts.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>