<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0210" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Mount Lebanon Bishopric</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Albany, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">2</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">10</biblScope><date value="18721001" TEIform="date">October 1872</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">73-80</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="2" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="73" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="10" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p"> I WILL SHAKE ALL NATIONS, AND THE DESIRE OP ALL NATIONS SHALL COME ; AND I WILL FILL THIS HOUSE WITH GLORY, SAITH
                        THE LORD. Published Monthly, by and under the direction of the Mt. Lebanon Bishopric. Vol. It. G. A. Lomas, Editor.
                        SHAKERS, ALBANY CO., N. Y., OCTOBER, 1872. No. 10. Fifty Cents per Annum.</p><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What cheer?" TEIform="index"/>What Cheer?</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Webster, E. H." TEIform="persName"/>E. H. WEBSTER</byline><p TEIform="p">There's a light streaming forth from the east, That gilds the horizon afar, And says to each suffering heart,
                            Look aloft to the blest morning star, There's a promise of day in its beams; There's a promise of freedom and
                            right; There's a promise of peace on the earth, And the triumph of love over might. There's a joy for the clean
                            and the pure; There's a rest for the weary of sin. There's a peace for the conqueror of self, And its seat and
                            foundation 's within. There's a love for the trusting and frail; There's a tender, compassionate heart, That
                            weeps o'er the sinner, and cannot assail, Nor add to its suffering smart. There's a light glowing bright in our
                            heart, For our Father, who led us this way; There's a love, ever warm in our breast, For our Mother, our comfort
                            and stay, Who suffered and toiled to spread the pure faith That shines on our every-day life, And lightens and
                            cheers its thro' sorrow and toil To faint not, nor sink in the strife. There's a gratitude due to our King, For
                            all of his infinite care; There's a duty we owe to our Queen ; A loyalty everywhere; To honor their cause, in
                            word and in deed, And light up the temple anew; And worthily walk in their footsteps, so pure, And oil in our
                            lamps oft renew'd. There's a question will come to each soul, When eternity opens its light; There's a sorrow
                            will over us roll, If we keep not our lamps burning bright. Let us banish all discord, and work while we can,
                            And lighten each burden we may, While joyfully walking in duty, and nse The straight and still brightening
                        way.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to be an angel" TEIform="index"/>How to be an Angel</head><byline TEIform="byline">BT <persName reg="Eades, H. L." TEIform="persName"/>H. L. EADES</byline><p TEIform="p">It is but rational to conclude that all who enter the kingdom of heaven, in the spirit world, on leaving this,
                            are angels (I go, said Christ, to prepare a place for you—John 14: 2, 3), and that they became so, previous to
                            their entrance there. How to become so is the grand problem the world has been trying to solve from Adam to the
                            present hour. For this purpose are all religions instituted among men, that they may be prepared to reach the
                            home of angels when their bodies are consigned to dust. If this be true, it is important that we should know how
                            to become angels, before we ascend to knock at the pearly gates, lest it may be said to us, " Depart from me, I
                            never knew you." Comte says, every " Religion demands the concurrence of two spontaneous influences: the
                            objective—intellectual; the subjective— moral." He should have said spiritual, but thank him for not making the
                            animal a neces- sity. One thing is very certain, and that is : All religions that ever existed were, in the
                            beginning, precisely alike, that is, their basic pillars are the same; all the deviations arise from the modes
                            of building after the religious idea is conceived. The first is a feeling of dependence on some power above that
                            of man; the second is the desire to know something of that being or power on whom they depend; the third is the
                            desire to know how to act to propitiate his favor, and come into harmony with him ; the fourth is to pray to,
                            love, and worship him. These are the basic pillars of all religions, and as said, all the variations after this
                            arise from the modes adopted by each to accomplish the above ends. Leaving all others for the present, I will
                            present the true Christian or Shaker plan, which is, in a nutshell: to confess, repent of, and forsake all sin;
                            take Jesus Christ as our exemplar; follow his footsteps, and live the pure, chaste, and holy life that he lived.
                            1 might stop right here, only for the fact that thousands declare the impossibility of mortals bearing so great
                            a cross, or living a life so pure as to become angels on earth—to be " overcomers as Christ overcame," and thus
                            secure our right to sit with him in his kingdom. But as'it has been done, and is now done, I propose briefly and
                            inductively to tell how, after assuming the above pure conditions necessary to our union with Christ.
                            "Religion," says Gould, " undertakes to encourage man with hopes; if he will expend his vital energy in the
                            development of his higher powers, he will be happier. It also deters him by threats from resisting his spiritual
                            instincts, and burying them in fleshly indulgence," legal or illegal. " For man's faculties sweep far beyond the
                            development of his sensual life. He derives his liveliest gratifications and acutest pain from objects to which
                            his animal consciousness is a stranger " He further adds this great truism: "If man requires a great exemplar,
                            so does woman require one, too. A religious system which would provide man with a model, and leave woman
                            destitute of one, is imperfect, and inadequate to supply the wants of human nature." Thus he makes his own Roman
                            Catholic, and all other religions inadequate, Shakers alone excepted, who have Mother Ann Lee as the exemplar of
                            womankind, who bore the same testimony, led the same life, and overcome the same adversary as did Jesus Christ,
                            her Lord. Thank him for the compliment. What I shall say is equally necessary for both sexes to know and
                            practice, in order to become angels, and must ask pardon for any necessary plainness which may exceed their
                            sense of the true bounds of modesty. It is a matter well known to physiologists that all have the power, by
                            their will, to direct and precipitate the vital forces to any part of the system, to develop and strengthen the
                            animal, intellectual, or spiritual brain, or any of the organs of the body. " For intellectual development, the
                            spontaneous force must be precipitated on the cerebral hemispheres. For sentimental [spiritual] development, it
                            must be turned upon the sensory ganglia. For animal development, upon the cerebellum, or lower brain. That
                            luxury and sexual indulgence are ruinous to mental, and therefore to moral health, is well known to physicians."
                            In man, the intellect is coupled either with the spiritual, sentimental, or animal brain, at pleasure. When it
                            is coupled with the cerebellum, it is for the purpose of inventing means to aid and heighten animal pleasures;
                            when coupled with the cerebrum, it is for the purpose of devising means for spiritual growth and happiness. "Now
                            [the highest] happiness is to be found either in the co-ordination of all the faculties, mental and bodily (and
                            this the sensualist claims), or in the development of the highest, at the expense of those less noble. If a man
                            is content to remain on the dead level of the majority of other men, he will adopt the first course. If he feels
                            a desire to rise above them, he will adopt the second." Now, because God has endowed us with animal and lower
                            faculties, as well as the spiritual and higher, it does not relieve us from culpability when we submit to the
                            rule of the former instead of the latter, because he has made us "masters of the situation." " The government of
                            the passions," says Locke, "is the right improvement of liberty; nor let any one say he cannot govern his
                            passions [if he take the proper means in time], nor hinder them from breaking out, and carrying him into action
                            ; for what he can do before a prince or great man, he can do alone, or in the presence of God, if he will." In
                            order to retain this ability, the work must be begun in the mind, and the vital forces precipitated upon the
                            cerebral hemispheres, and not upon the cerebellum and animal organs. " What I say unto one, I say unto all,
                            watch.'" When the mind is permitted to dwell on sensual delights, the vital currents are directed to the
                            generative organs, when a state of orgasm is induced, and active and vigorous secretions there commenced, and
                            graduated at the expense of the higher faculties and upper brain; for nearly seven per <pb n="74" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/>
                            cent, of the solids of the adult brain is pure phosphorus, and this, to be continually posited in the generative
                            system and cerebellum, makes the man or woman a brute, and the cross of Christ and higher life become to either
                            an impossibility, yea, not even desired by them, so thoroughly subdued are all their spiritual aspirations. They
                            now can join with Heine in saying, "I scorn the heavenly plains above me, In the blest land of Paradise," or
                            with the exclamation of Jean Reynaud, "Ah ! Christ, how your paradise scares me ! I prefer my life with its
                            lights and shadows, tribulations and pains, to that blank immortality with its sanctimonious peace." This is the
                            sunken, low, and hardened condition that mortals reach who allow their thoughts to run on sensual and carnal
                            things, instead of intellectual and spiritual. When even a state of orgasm is not perceptible, the indulgence in
                            luxuries and carnal thinking will polarize the phosphoric fires on the cerebellum, and strengthen the animal,
                            which will predominate, govern, and direct the body. We then hear the complaint, " Oh, I can't bear the cross;
                            were it not for this one requirement, I would join the Shakers forthwith," etc. But you can bear the cross, the
                            weakest mortal, if you will take the course indicated; but if you do the contrary, all your prayers will be
                            unavailable, for then "A transient gust, Spent in a sudden storm of lnst," will be the consequence. There is no
                            retreat, as some suppose, by reabsorption into the blood, by the will, of misspent organic life, and thence
                            carried to the upper brain for spiritual uses. Its stand is taken ; it will not retreat. " The wise foreseeth
                            the evil, and hide themselves, but the simple go on, and are punished." Yea, the simpletons go on, repeating the
                            process again and again—resolve and fail, and re-resolve and fail, until they become wholly subdued by
                            sensuality, their angel of hope droops her wings, and they sink in the gulf of despair. Then they may well
                            repeat to themselves the vision of Jean Paul, "All around me is a wide, petrified humanity. In the dark,
                            unpeopled stillness no love glows, no admiration, no hope, no aim—I so all alone ! Within me the dumb, blind
                            Demigorgon is concealed, and I am in it. So I proceed into eternity—and who knows me, and hears my sorrow ?—I.
                            Who knows me, and hears to all eternity?—I." Now, by heeding what I have said, this terrible state can be
                            avoided. Take not, I beseech you, my young friends, the first backward step, then the second will never be
                            taken. But bear with me a few moments longer, if it be not too great a strain upon your patience and modesty,
                            whilst I state a few things it would be the part of wisdom to avoid, though considered by many, harmless and
                            inoffensive. I address those now who really desire in their hearts to be successful in cross-bearing, and
                            gaining the pure angelic state. Those who chant the little popular song, " I want to be an angel, and with the
                            angels dwell," will find it necessary to avail themselves of the smallest advantages, to insure a speedy
                            progress to the angel condition. It is written, "Resist the devil, and he will flee from you." But it is a poor
                            time to resist, after you have invited him into your sanctum, and embraced him. Those who really desire purity
                            above all things, will refrain from reading novels and love stories, or singing worldly love songs, or any
                            sexual dalliance; arm-in-arm promenades; moonlight riding, and masquerades, balls, bacchanal carousals. Such
                            will find the words of Byron but too true: " The gay companions of the bowl Dispel awhile the sense of ill j
                            Though pleasures fire the nmdd'nlng soul, The heart—the heart—is lonely still." Yea, things that seem still
                            smaller, ma}r be noted, such as holding the fingers after the grasp of friendly recognition; fondling with dogs,
                            cats, and other animal pets (" without are dogs," etc.); looking at and contemplating half nude pictures;
                            reading stories of crim. con., and unnecessary conversation thereon. Yea, the truly earnest soul will take the
                            Christ stand, rejecting all partial affections of natural kindred (since now you have a better), husband, wife,
                            children, father, mother, brother, sister, uncle, aunt, cousin, or what not. If, since you have chosen the
                            spiritual relation, they will not come with you, let them have the natural; being "joined to their idols, let
                            them alone." All these, and stich like things, precipitate the vital forces downward, and strengthen the animal
                            nature—yea, " cause the animal nature to tread out the life of the spiritual nature, and lower man to the beast,
                            and this is sin." As the old saying is, they " make Jordan a hard road to travel." But let no discourage- ments
                            come over your spirits, or weaken your resolutions, for complete victory is within your grasp. These are the
                            words of experience. The maxim is true, " Whatever can be diminished, can be destroyed." Only keep up the
                            diminishing process, and the end, to your great joy, will surely come, when 3'ou will fully realize the truth of
                            Pope's beautiful picture : "Happy the blameless vestal's lot, The world forgetting, by the world forgot; Eternal
                            sunshine of the spotless mind, Each prayer accepted, and each wish resigned. Labor and rest, that eqnal periods
                            keep; Obedient slumbers that can wake or weep; Desires composed, affections ever even; Tears that delight, and
                            sighs that waft to heaven. Grace shines around them with serenest beams, And whispering angels paint their
                            golden dreams."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Extend the truth" TEIform="index"/>Extend the Truth</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Hurlbut, S. G." TEIform="persName"/>S. G. HURLBUT</byline><p TEIform="p">We will premise the necessity of some definite and concerted action for the spreading of the doctrine of
                            Believers. Ignorance is the great barrier to its reception by those prepared for it. Whatever will enlighten the
                            minds of the people, helps the spread of Shakerism. There is now not one in a thousand that knows even
                            theoretically anything about what constitutes the difference between Shakers and the rest of Christian
                            professors. We aim to live a life of purity—absolute purity—free from sin and all evil. This is the ideal
                            Christian life, and had we the capabilities of an archangel, and the voice of Gabriel's trumpet, we might tell
                            all of earth's inhabitants, at once, that there was something to do besides buy and sell, to get gain, marry,
                            and build up selfishness, and run riot over the rights of each other, the strong oppressing the weak, and they
                            in turn cursing their oppressors. In the absence of these powers, we will content ourselves with writing the
                            truth as sharp as possible, and send it forth on its errand of mercy. If it executes judgment, we will not
                            sorrow; truth will harm no good. Our needs, as an organized body of Christian Believers, at present, is
                            increased facilities for giving our peculiar views to the world. There is an unprecedented call from all
                            quarters of the globe for more light on the very subjects that, of all others, Believers feel themselves in
                            advance of all other people, viz.: how to live pure lives, and enjoy the social relations between the sexes at
                            the same time. How can we do this better than by doubling the size of our missionary sheet, The Shaker, trebling
                            our efforts to fill it with well worn, bright truths, and then quadrupling our efforts to spread it to all who
                            would appreciate or pay for it ? If there is a better way than this, let us have it. " The best way is as good
                            as any." We have the greatest good revealed to us of any mortals that we know of. It is our duty to spread it "
                            in all the ways we can." It seems fitting that from the multitude of home blessings we spare a portion to the
                            needy and honest seekers outside of our community. They ask not the bread that perishes, but the truth ; and
                            they expect it, and reasonably, too, of us.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakerism" TEIform="index"/>Shakerism</head><byline TEIform="byline">Extract from "Hints towards Reform," by <persName reg="Greeley, Horace" TEIform="persName"/>Horace Greeley</byline><p TEIform="p">With the Shakers, so nick-named, I have some personal acquaintance, and I am not ashamed to own that I have been
                            instructed and cheered by them. They have never been fairly appreciated by the world. Their utter condemnation
                            of marriage and of individual property,* the grotesque ceremonies of Divine worship, and their incessant
                            declamation against all departures from celibacy as impure and sinful, have repelled and disgusted nearly all
                            who are not of their own body. But, might not a more expansive philosophy, a more liberal culture, discover in
                            these very excesses a moral worthy of the gravest attention ? Are our relations as men and women so universally
                            pure and exalted that we may rightly despise those who, unable to separate the palpable evil from the latent
                            good, reject both together ? Is exclusive property so beneficent a feature in our social order, as practically
                            exemplified around us, that we may fairly stigmatize those who, not needing its incitements to thrift or
                            industry, see fit to decline them ? The peculiarities of Shaker worship I read- ily abandon to the ridicule of
                            the caviller, only wishing that theirs were the only absurdities * This is a gross mistake on the part of a
                            large majority; we never condemned either. G. A. L. THE 8HA.KER. 74 <pb n="75" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> THE SECA.KEH. 75
                            committed in attempting to honor our Father in Heaven, and that no religious errors more popular and enduring
                            than theirs were worse than simply ridiculous. When all that may be said against these simple-minded ascetics
                            has been freely admitted, there is yet left enough in their character and history to challenge our admiration.
                            They present the sublime and hope-inspir- ing spectacle of a community founded and built up on the conquest of
                            the most inexorable appetites; lust, avarice, ambition, revenge —these are not merely discountenanced by the
                            social economy of the Shakers, but this economy is based on their entire crucifixion. Nor can I see how any man
                            can rationally conclude, as some have nevertheless asserted, that all this show of subduing the appetites is
                            hypocrisy and a delusion. I can conceive no earthly motive for practicing so much outward self-denial, at so
                            great inconvenience, and with no hope of honor, or popularity, but a certainty of the reverse, if not based on
                            obe- dience to an inward conviction. The uncharitable theory supposes a refinement of absurdity and
                            self-annoyance which never yet possessed for any period the brain of any sane man, much less of a whole
                            community for ages. Let us, then, profit by the lessons which these enthusiasts read us, while discarding their
                            unpardonable errors. Let us remember that they have solved for us the problem of the possibility, the
                            practicability, of a social condition from which the twin curses, pauperism and servitude, .shall be utterly
                            banished. They have shown how pleasant may be the labors, how abundant the comforts, of a community wherein no
                            man aspires to be lord over his brethren, no man grasps for himself, but each is animated by a spirit of
                            devotion to the common good. When I have stood among the quiet homes of this unaspiring, unpoetical people, and
                            marked how they have steadily, surely, advanced from abject poverty to amplest competence ; when I have observed
                            how their patient but never excessive toil has transformed rugged barrenness into smiling fertility and beauty,
                            how could I refrain from thinking lightly of that blind dogmatism which asserts the im- possibility of inducing
                            men to labor except for their own selfish gratification, and affirms the necessity of the stimulus of personal
                            acquisition to save mankind from sinking back into the darkness and destitution of barbarism ?</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Real Christianity versus profession" TEIform="index"/>Real Christianity versus Profession</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">"There is one argument in favor of Christianity, which I could never reason away," said a young man
                                    who was trying to be an infidel, and could not, " and that was the consistent, godly conduct of my own
                                    father." To which any bystander might have replied: " There is one argument against Christianity, which
                                    I could never reason away, and that is the inconsistent, ungodly walk of a majority who call themselves
                                    Christians. These men and women are fathers and mothers in our own neighborhood, and are asking all to
                                    become Christians, which means a profession o1 something which grants an indulgence to its possessors to
                                    do that which should make humanity blush." If to be a Christian means to follow the example of those who
                                    monopolize that title, I, too, must look in another direction. And if to be a Christian means to be
                                    good, I will try to be good, without making confederates of a set of hypocrites.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Religio-philosophical journal" TEIform="index"/>Religio-Philosophical Journal</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Communism" TEIform="index"/>Communism</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Andrews, Watson" TEIform="persName"/>WATSON ANDREWS</byline><p TEIform="p">The idea of communistic life seems to have been entertained by men in very early times. Instances are not
                            wanting, even before the advent of our Saviour, of communities estab- lished upon this principle. People, in all
                            time, seem to have been aware that there is not only a disposition, but a necessity in man's nature leading him
                            to hibernate; to congre- gate into communities, and live in as close a relation as the nature of his
                            circumstances would permit. In obedience to this law, men have endeavored in various ways, and at vari- ous
                            times, during their history, to establish communities, wherein all the members should fare and share alike;
                            having common interests, tables, and privileges generally, varied only by the tastes, condition and capabilities
                            of the individual. And although there has been no lack of talent, of means, nor of good intentions engaged in
                            these enterprises, they have, for the most part, signally failed. And the cause of these failures is always the
                            same old story—disagreement, antagonisms among the members; a preference for self and family connections in the
                            individual. Nature, first of all, must needs provide for the reproduction, care and culture of the race, and the
                            way she has chosen to effect this, was by endowing man and woman with the parental instincts ; an unlimited
                            partiality for their own offspring. Without this, the race could not have survived a day; and with it, there was
                            necessitated private families, private property, and private residences. Hence all attempts to maintain
                            community of interest and of residence, while retaining the family relation must ever fail; for it is no less
                            than attempting to do away with an effect, while continuing the cause. The human race depends for its existence
                            upon the family relation; and the family relation, as we have seen, depends upon isolation of interests and of
                            resistance for its existence. Likewise, the human race depends for its happiness upon congregation—the community
                            relation ; and this equally depends for its completeness and permanent existence upon identity of interests and
                            residence, and both phases of human life are alike called for by the nature of things. The family relation,
                            therefore, is a great primal necessity; perverted though it is, yet it is a fundamental necessity nevertheless ;
                            the seed-field of the human race. It antedates the birth of the race ; it produced, and it sustains the race;
                            and the last echoes of its knell will be heard only by the last of the race. The communistic relation also is a
                            great necessity; a kindred necessity, of even more importance. And although not primal, it is final, and
                            completes what the other begins; being the harvest-field of the human race. The necessary self-love of the one,
                            with its consequent antagonisms, and the equally necessary social-love of the other, with its consequent
                            harmony, are alike but parts of the Divine economy in the affairs of men, for growing and harvesting a crop of
                            human souls divine. And " the husbandman that sowed the seed is the Son of man, the field is the world, and the
                            reapers are the angels." In the first, self-preservation is the standard of excellence; in the last,
                            self-abnegation. In the first, except a man provide for his own household, he is said to be worse than an
                            infidel ; and in the last, if he do not " forsake and hate" his own household, he is an infidel. Beside these,
                            there is no true wTay for men and women to live upon this planet; all others are but these in incipiency or
                            decay, presaging or recalling normal, human society. The family relation requires that a man be governed by the
                            selfish sentiments; an almost exclusive care for himself and family. Directly or indirectly, whatever he plans
                            or executes, has for its object the support and comfort of his own household. He contributes, it may be, to the
                            support of the state; to liberal institutions and various public enterprises ; but it all means only this : that
                            his nature prompts him (and very properly) to provide for his own in preference to another's. He gives in
                            charity where he can, without depriving his own, not otherwise; self must have the preference, or the race
                            "would speedily become extinct. And this is by no means the result of calculation mainly; but it has its source
                            in man's original nature—in the necessities of the case. The true communistic relation, on the con- trary,
                            requires that a man be governed by the liberal sentiments—an almost exclusive care for his fellow man. Whatever
                            he engages in has for its object the well-being and happiness of his fellows; for he has learned that the way to
                            be happy is to make others happy. And the only way to do this permanently, is to make a full sacrifice of all
                            selfish considerations ; all natural, partial, private relations and possessions—" father, mother, brother,
                            sister, wife, children, houses and lands ; yea and his own (peculiarities of) life also." Retaining a preference
                            for any of these, proves a rock to the voyager in communism, and a rock upon which, sooner or later, he is sure
                            to split. For the least thing partaking of the nature of possession, possesses the nature of antagonism, and
                            antagonism and harmony are incompatible; and harmony is the cement of society, without which it speedily falls
                            in pieces. No matter what the society, whether savage, civilized or Christian, there must needs be a common bond
                            of union; a universally pervading element, in which all interests centre, and toward which all aspirations
                            point, as the needle to the pole, in order to have that degree of harmony which creates, and which alone
                            sustains, society. In natural, generative society, this harmonial bond is the reproductive instincts (errone<pb n="76" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 76 THE SHAKER. ously called love), culminating in the family relation, with its "trouble in
                            the flesh"—its care, its anxieties, its fears and its sorrows. Antagonistic in its nature, .and limited in
                            duration, its pleasures are necessarily limited, and speedily pass away. In spiritual, regenerative society,
                            this harmonial bond is love—-love to God supreme, and neighbor as self; culminating in the communistic relation,
                            with its freedom from " trouble in the flesh"—the cares, the anxieties, the fears and the sorrows of the family
                            relation. Harmonial in its nature, and continuous in duration, its pleasures are necessarily unlimited and never
                            pass away. For, having reference mainly to the spiritual of man's life, which is eternal in its nature, the true
                            religious communistic relation is equally eternal;— a life—habits of thought and of social intercourse which
                            time cannot affect, and which death does but sever from whatever of anno}^ance things of time occasioned.
                            Instead of stripping the soul of its treasures, death does but place it in the full enjoyment of all that
                            constituted its happiness while on the earth. And this is eternal life, the voluntary relin- quishment of all
                            that death can take from the soul; and the formation of tastes and habits, while in time, which Avill eternally
                            endure, and in the exercise of which souls are forever increasing in wisdom, in purity and in happiness. And as
                            fast as men progress to the condition of understanding these great truths—of comprehending the grand system of
                            nature— of God, with regard to man; that it necessarily embraces a harvest as well as a seed-time, a
                            regenerative as well as a generative dispensation ; that these two states are necessarily of an exactly opposite
                            character, inasmuch as the one is a purely natural state, indispensable in the development of natural beings,
                            and the other a purely spiritual state, equally indispensable in the development of spiritual beings ; that the
                            ripening of the spiritual depends upon the decay of the natural, as really as the ripening of the grain depends
                            upon the decay of the stalk; and therefore that what is pleasurable in the one is painful in the other; what is
                            life to the one is death to the other, and vice versa;—so fast will they comprehend that all pertaining to the
                            natural, generative order, either in this mode of existence or any other, must be stripped off from the immortal
                            mind of man, as the chaff from the grain, before he can become capable of those complete soul-blendings with the
                            Divine Source and his fellow man, which alone produce the harmony, and ensure the happiness of heaven.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wait no longer" TEIform="index"/>Wait no Longer</head><byline TEIform="byline">BV <persName reg="Ervin, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>ANNA ERVIN</byline><p TEIform="p">" Shall we wait and wait forever, Still procrastination rueing, Self-exertion trusting never, Always dreaming,
                            never doing? " Truth claims limitless dominion, Ease and pleasure, what are they? There are souls well worth the
                            winning Who must live through endless day. Souls there are that long have slumbered, Great in heart, and strong
                            in hand; Awake, awake, rise unincnmbered, And scatter trnth throughout the land. "Wait no longer! Hope, faith,
                            labor," Bear our spirits to the prize; Let ns give unto our neighbor What has made us heaven-wise. What wait we
                            for? 'Tis for thy blessing, O God of love, of life, and power! Give us zeal to aid progression, And around us
                            light to shower.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Daniel and John, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>Daniel and John.—No. 2</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="E., F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. E.</byline><p TEIform="p">John saw (by symbols) the four great dispensations, which extend from the beginning to the end of human history.
                            Daniel saw (by symbols) four great kingdoms, beginning in his own times, and running parallel with John's vision
                            to the end. Daniel was a subordinate, John a universal prophet. John was " more than a prophet;" far beyond even
                            John the Baptist. A prophet was not, necessarily, any better, personally, than the people to whom he proph-
                            esied ; even as a spiritual medium is so physiologically, not necessarily any better, as being either morally or
                            religiously superior to the body of Spiritualists. But John the Baptist preached repentance, in addition to
                            foretelling future events; and John the Revelator, in his private life, walked closely in the footsteps of his
                            spiritual guide and leader, Jesus. He was not only a prophet, but a good man, which is being more than a mere
                            prophet, like Balaam, and many others, who were beautiful Christ Prophets, but who did not reduce to practice
                            the principles they set forth, that would finally redeem humanity. Daniel saw a lion, a bear, a leopard, and a
                            complex beast that had ten horns. These were the Babylonia, the Medo-Persia, the Greek, and the Roman empires.
                            The fourth beast, or system, is represented as "dreadful and terrible, strong exceedingly. It had great iron
                            teeth, and it devoured and brake in pieces, and stamped the residue with the feet of it." This was the Roman,
                            and is graphically described. " It was diverse from all the beasts, or systems, that were before it, and had ten
                            horns." In truth, the other systems were merged in it; so that all the elements of preceding human governments
                            were incorporated therein. The ten horns, or powers, represented Republicanism, which was gradually rising and
                            predominating over every other form-of governmental polity; the antithesis of despotism or monarchy—the one-man
                            power —being a subdivision of power among the many men. This fourth beast gradually supplanted despotisms,
                            monarchies and aristocracies, and destroyed them. Again. In the midst of this system came up a little horn, or
                            power, before which there were three of the first horns plucked up by the roots. " In it were eyes like the eyes
                            of a man, and a mouth speaking great things,"— the Papal power. The Babylonia, the MedoPersia, and Greek systems
                            were subdued into one universal government—the Roman. Pagan Rome built the Partheon, a house for the gods and
                            goddesses of all nations; thus blending them together in one grand system of theogony. She offered to put a
                            statue of Jesus with the rest ; but the iconoclastic Christians waged a war of words against all other deities
                            but their own Trinity ; and " the little horn" prevailed over all other civil governments upon the earth. But
                            Daniel gives us the history of the rise of still another, and more interior power—"a little stone cut out of the
                            mountain without hands." "I beheld till the thrones "—despotisms and monarchies—" were cast down, and the
                            ancient of days did sit. A fiery stream issued and came forth before him; thousand thousands ministered unto
                            him, and ten thousand times ten thousand stood before him: the judgment was set, and the books were opened."
                            Memory is the book; the memory of each individual—his and her history. It was not by adulation and praise, but
                            by their lives, the product of their freeagency, that these souls ministered to and stood before the Ancient of
                            Days. It was human history, the judgment day, in which the errors of each individual will be illuminated by the
                            light of God's countenance, by the presentation of the abstract principles of right, as seen in the judgment
                            upon human history, or accumulated human experience, as they exist in the Christ element, into which all the
                            prophets, at the time of their prophesying, were baptized. This judgment scene is paralleled in John's vision,
                            thus: " And I saw a great white throne"—Shaker Order—"and her that sat on it, from whose face the (old) earth
                            and the heaven"—the theologies of Babylon—"fled away; and there was no place for them" in the new spiritual, or
                            Shaker Order. "And I saw the dead, small and great," in the spiritual world, " stand before God; and the books
                            were opened"—memories of their past histories ; " and another book was opened, which is the book of life; "
                            because it is the memory of their present and future obedience to the testimony of Jesus, the principles and
                            orders of the new creation. "And the dead," who had had the everlasting Gospel preached unto them, "that they
                            might be judged according to men in the flesh," " were judged out of those things that were written in the
                            books, according to their works. And the sea— world—gave up the dead that were in it ; and death and hell," not
                            being eternal, "delivered up the dead which were in them ; and they were judged every man" (and woman) "ac-
                            cording to their works ; and death and hell," being mortal, " were cast into the lake of fire," and destroyed. "
                            This is the second death;" being the death of death itself; the destroyer is destroyed: he that leadeth into
                            captivit}r is gone into captivity; and there remaineth life eternal. See the Shaker Order, under the title of
                            New Jerusalem, still more minutely described in Rev. xxi. " Because of the voice of the great words which the
                            little horn spake, I beheld till the fourth beast was slain and his body destroyed, and given to the burning
                            flame." This fourth beast, or man-Republicanism, will be destroyed by the burning fire of truth, and a system of
                            dual or true Republicanism will be <pb n="77" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. 77 substituted therefor, in which the male
                            and female elements will be equally represented in the executive, and will form the more interior order of the
                            senate, with the house of representatives as an external covering; and having Divine revelation, conjoined to
                            human experience, as the soul of the whole governmental system. " As concerning the rest of the beasts, or
                            systems, they had their dominion taken away; yet their lives were prolonged for a season and time." What could
                            better portray the gradual supplanting of one system by another, whether civil or ecclesiastical ? DUPLICATE
                            VISION. The same ideas, represented to Daniel under different imagery. " The four winds of heaven striving upon
                            the great sea" of humanity, is a beautiful use of the natural to convey spiritual conceptions. " The four beasts
                            com' ing up from the sea, each diverse, as they follow in the grand procession of empires, is sublime
                            symbolizing of truthful history then in the future, now actualized and actualizing. The great Image : head of
                            gold—Baby Ion ; breast and arms of silver-—Medo^Persia; belly and thighs of brass— Greece; legs of iron—
                            Imperial Rome ; feet and ten toes of iron and clay—man-Republicanism again. All the systems blended together in
                            one history ; then comes " the little stone cut without hands, which becomes a great mountain, filling the
                            earth"—the Christ revelation. It smites the image upon its feet—in the latter days; and the iron, clay, brass,
                            silver and gold are all broken in pieces together, not annihilated; for in Babylon—mixture—they all still exist,
                            and nullify each other. The great image, and the four beasts, are duplicated history of male governments, which
                            the revelation of the Mother element in deity and in humanity will remove, displace; and " no place will be
                            found for them." For the dual natural civil government, and the dual spiritual religious government "will fill
                            the whole earth." This will be the Millennial period, the culmination of all prophecy. " I saw in the night
                            visions, and, behold, one like the Son of man "—a female—" come with the clouds of heaven"—Shaker
                            communities—"and came to the Ancient of Da}rs ; and they brought her near before him; and there was given her
                            dominion and glorj^ and a kingdom"—the kingdom of heaven—" that all peoples, nations, and languages should serve
                            her. Her dominion is an everlasting dominion, which shall not pass away, and her kingdom that which shall not be
                            destroyed." This is the appearing of the Christ spirit in the female humanity, described by the Christ prophet,
                            David, as "the King's daughter, who was to forget her own people, and her father's house, that she might become
                            the mother of spiritual offspring, whom she might make princes (and princesses) in all the earth; " or, as the
                            Christ prophet, John, ex- presses it, "kings and priests unto God and the Lamb," who should administer the
                            resur- rection to the countless myriads of souls who had passed from earth, and were still in the generative
                            order, in the spirit world. Well might the Spirit say (through David), " I will make thy name to be remembered
                            in (or by) all generations. Therefore shall the people praise thee forever and ever." John says (Rev. 14: 14), "
                            I looked, and behold a white cloud, and upon the cloud one sat like unto the Son of man, having on her head a
                            golden crown, and in her hand a sharp sickle." Nothing so like the Son of man as the Daughter of man. "An angel
                            cried to her that sat upon the cloud "—Ann Lee—" Thrust in thy sickle, and reap; for the harvest of the earth is
                            ripe. And she thrust in her sickle, and the earth was reaped." Behold the days in which we live, and the great
                            "winepress of the wrath of God" against lust and war (which grows out of it) will be trodden without (or
                            outside) the holy city—the spiritual Order—being in the natural order itself, which will execute judgment upon
                            its own members; and "blood will come out of the winepress, even unto the horses' bridles "—the guides and
                            rulers of the Order. For the whole natural order, civil and ecclesiastical, is "turned to blood." The rulers and
                            their people are alike baptized into the spirit of murder; for there is no place, nor people, excepting the
                            Shakers, exempt therefrom; as Was shown in the late civil war. And the Shaker Order—" the little stone" —"the
                            kingdom of heaven," for the coming of which, humanity have all prayed, although as yet in only its mustard-seed
                            state, is assuredly destined to become " a great tree," among whose branches the birds of heaven— the religious,
                            spiritually-minded—can find food and shelter ; and beneath whose shade—the civil government—the beasts of
                            earth—the natural or earthly-minded—can rest in peace, and " none to make them afraid." Thus constituting new
                            heavens and a new earth, wherein will dwell, in place of oppression, war and bloodshed, peace and plenty, in
                            universal righteousness.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sketches of shaker life, no. 1" TEIform="index"/>Sketches of Shaker Life.—No. 1</head><p TEIform="p">We very agreeably comply with an urgent demand to know the inner life of the Shakers, when we begin these
                            "Sketches," and give notice of their continuance. We are often asked: " Are you happy?" "How do you amuse
                            yourselves?" "Does your business engross your whole attention ?" These are a few from a multitude of questions
                            constantly recurring. Ere we conclude these " Sketches" you will know. We were one of a happy party of four that
                            took the early Boston and Albany train for Canaan, N. Y., being invited to a SOCIAL GATHERING, under the
                            auspices of the Novitiate Order of Mt. Lebanon. Arriving at the Canaan Families not far from 8 o'clock a.m., we
                            leaped from the carriage with hungry stomachs, but with merry hearts, received by Sister Louisa Green and
                            others. Breakfast was waiting for us, prepared by our Sister Marcia, and this thirty miles from home ! We again
                            entered the carriage, and were conveyed to Mt. Canaan, only 150 perches from the buildings—a spot made by nature
                            to greet the children of Grace where, upon our arrival, nearly fifty voices, singing in harmony, opened a
                            welcome hymn, while, from all around, beginning with the Elders, and extending to the multitude, greetings of
                            welcome met our eyes, ears and feeling, while the trees and undergrowth seemed to lend their assistance to the
                            mountain breezes, to accord with the hundreds of voices in the jubilee of welcome. The school children had
                            remembered us, for their busy fingers had worked upon a wire net-work, with tiny white flowers, the letters in
                            good Roman— Welcome ! A large awning, on the top of the hill, was sufficient covering for all, in case of a
                            storm— which, however, they never have needed for this, as the best of weather has annually cheered the spot for
                            twelve years, by some arrangement Elder Frederick claims to have made with "Old Probabilities." Seated 'neath
                            the monstrous tent, a set of "Resolutions" Were in order; their tenor being, that each one assembling there,
                            should love every other body present! Of course, so easy a rule was adopted unanimously. A dialogue followed,
                            spoken by eight of the children, upon " Useful Knowledge," which was well arranged and nicely spoken, closing
                            with a pretty song. Individual contributions or essajrs, prepared for the occasion, were next in order, and
                            these gave evidence of having been filled with the results of good mental culture, and deep, religious feelings.
                            Again the choir sung "Jerusalem " in harmony, and with such spirit as to remind one of a thorough-going
                            Methodist after his baptism by Shakerism ! Now a very agreeable circumstance was enacted : Six or eight young
                            sisters spoke for half an hour or more, a dialogue of their own composition, upon " The Fundamental Principles
                            of Shakerism." Its composition and deliver}* were worthy of any institution of learning, and contained so much
                            information that is worthily and eagerly sought for by many, that we urged its publication. Next, we had an
                            address by Elder F. W. Evans, upon " Active Shakerism ;" and by Eldress Antoinette, upon the " Purpose and Value
                            of this Jubilee;" then a few remarks by the writer, upon " The Honor due Modern Saints ;" when recess and
                            refreshments followed; then lemon juice and frozen cream mingled very agreeably with our mortality. Soon, a call
                            to dinner : and now, oh, ye epicures, attention ! ye who dream that meals without meats are without pleasure or
                            profit, look over the tables ! The tables could not groan, or they would, beneath the weight of fruits, flowers,
                            vegetables, custards; all the products of the dairy, and these conjoined to the cereal class. Here was "the
                            staff of life," unrobbed of its muscle-making bran, which is so basely displaced by violence to the animal
                            creation, and with such poor returns, by the yet xmcivilized bar- barities of our age ! Here was a table that
                            would have adorned any Eden ever thought of; and while we joyed in its health-giving pleasures, the flocks and
                            the herds, whose dead carcasses would have disgraced the occasion, were frolicking in the fields, praising God
                            with us ! Next followed a very agreeable chit-chat, which amounted to a real love-feast, and this <pb n="78" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 78 THE SHAKER. might have continued ad infinitum, had not a call to the tent notified all that our
                            time of departure had arrived. Now we received love ; and now we realized more than ever, that hosts of the
                            invisible world were enjoying with us the beauties of the occasion. A beautiful farewell song was rendered for
                            us, as our carriage arrived to convey us back to the depot; and here ended the loveliest six hours of our
                            existence. And as we left the grounds, we responded in our hearts: Farewell, dear, loving souls! You whom the
                            world at large look upon as robbed of all comfort, you, alone, are the true comfort-takers ; for, as you shake
                            from your souls the bondage of sin and selfishness, all heaven flows in upon you. Yours is already a life
                            eternal ; " a thing of beauty, a joy forever." All was concert, all was love ; and here was a Shaker Picnic—a
                            Social Gathering—where souls, whose lives are thoroughly virginal, were giving and receiving an affectionate
                            love, unequaled by anything else in the world. True Shakers are happy. One place on earth, thank God, can that,
                            which has been said to exist only in the dictionary—" happiness"— be found and continually enjoyed; and this
                            place is in a Shaker life, at a Social Gathering, with F. W. Evans, Levi Shaw, Antoinette Doolittle and Olive
                            Holden as its living heads —who are, most truly, " the servants of all" their people. We never expect to be
                            worthy of a second invitation; but whoso is the guest, let him or her "proclaim it upon the housetop." *</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Angel messenger of peace" TEIform="index"/>Angel Messenger of Peace</head><byline TEIform="byline">Bl" <persName reg="Stebbins, Olive" TEIform="persName"/>OLIVE STEBBINS</byline><p TEIform="p">Fly, fly through the heavens, thou Gospel proclftimer, To earth's needy children, I earnestly pray; For truth and
                            salvation will greet God's creation, O, may they thy warning and precepts obey. Fly, fly through the heavens,
                            thou angel of mercy, Proclaim the glad tidings of " peace and good will; " To cultivate earth, use your warlike
                            utensils, That it may bring forth, and jour granaries fill. Let news from Mount Zion waken every sleeper, To
                            rise from their slumbers, and hail the glad sound, For now is salvation from war's desolation, Where
                            righteousness reigns, and rich blessings are found. For all wars will cease where the Gospel is planted,
                            Christ's mission was "peace and goodwill" unto man; The same voice to-day, in this last visitation, Since it is
                            revealed through our good Mother Ann. We now have a warfare, not with carnal weapons, The Avar we engage in
                            begins at the gate; The sword points within us, the pure testimony, Our own life of sin we must certainly hate.
                            All sinners must bow to the Lord in his temple, Before his true witness their deeds bring to light, Or they
                            cannot enter this beautiful city, Where purity reigns as a standard of right. O come, all ye weary and ye heavy
                            laden, To Mount Zion's borders, where sweet rest is found O come to the feast, is the kind invitation, O come
                            and be saved on God's holy ground.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Says Dr. Holley..." TEIform="index"/>Says Dr. Holley...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Says Dr. Holley :—" No faith is more easily misunderstood and misrepresented than tha of the Shakers. The
                            metaphysical explanation of it is so different from popular appre hension, that great pains and some talent are
                            necessary in conducting a moral analysis, to do justice to this remarkable sect."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reminiscences" TEIform="index"/>Reminiscences</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Buckingham, D. A." TEIform="persName"/>D. A. BUCKINGHAM</byline><p TEIform="p">HOXESTY TUB BEST POLICY. It was the labor of Mother Ann and the irst Elders to impress upon the minds of their
                            mmediate successors, or members of the then Shaker fraternity, the importance of true honesty and just dealing,
                            one with another, and with all mankind. They were so strenuous on his subject, that they thought it wrong to
                            take even the amount of a pin of that which did not &gt;elong to them personally, in any dishonest way. If
                            necessity pressed anyone to take or use that which belonged to or was under the care of another (in their
                            absence), it was to be returned to its place immediately after using, and an acknowledgment rendered, or
                            restitution made or offered to the owner or caretaker, as soon thereafter as consistent. Special care was taken
                            to avoid all grievances and all wrangling; knowing that small errors led to greater ones, as does a " little
                            leaven leaven the whole lump," or as the " little foxes spoil the vines." This agrees with the testimony of
                            Jesus, that, " Whosoever shall break one of these least commandments, and shall teach men so, he shall be called
                            the least in the kingdom of heaven.3' Or, according to the Apostle James, that, "Whosoever shall keep the whole
                            law, and yet offend in one point, he is guilty of all." Thus the necessity of being strictly honest, dealing
                            justly, walking uprightly, in all places and cases. To some persons it may appear like folly to be thus mindful
                            in small matters. But in the observance or non-observance of minor duties or things, we testify to each other,
                            and to all around us, the principle by which we are governed—whether by the true spirit of honesty, or by the
                            spirit of selfishness and double-dealing. In a fraternity like ours, where all things are held in common, and no
                            one in truth and reality calleth anything, of all he possesses, his own, how important it is to closely adhere
                            to the fundamental principles and rules by which our first founders were guided and governed. There is a just
                            and proper way oi doing things, and of dealing one with another. Let us have the right. We read that " God's
                            house is a house of order, and not of confusion." So each and every person, with each and every thing, make up
                            the consecrated whole—the common Brotherhood; all of which —though not mine nor thine—is yet under the special
                            care and superintendence of some individual or individuals, and is ours. Would it not be well for the present
                            anc rising generation of believers in Christ's second appearing, to compare themselves with the above, and see
                            how nearly they carry out the principles inculcated by our first founders ?</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Modern bishop and Christ" TEIform="index"/>The Modern Baptist and Christ</head><p TEIform="p">The much-abused and neglected Swedenborg stock is rapidly rising in the theological market. A writer in the
                            Golden Age thinks the whole tendency of religious thought, for thirty years, has been in this direction. Now,
                            let it be understood, that Swedenborg was the angel of Spiritualism, the forerunner, or John baptist, of Mother
                            Ann; that he did declare, ' the Lord is preparing at this time, a new learen, of such as look to him in their
                            lives." liet the good work proceed. The body of Christendom is being found and acknowledged n the labors of
                            Swedenborg; the soul of Ohrisianity will ineyitably appear in the life-labors of those who practice the
                            principles inaugurated by one, An"jt Lee. We call egpecial attention to the leader in March number of The
                            Shaker, Vol. I, upon this subject. #</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><p TEIform="p">The following letter was written by a Shaker sister to a lady in Mt. Holly, N. J. As it contains answers to
                            ever-recurring questions, we place it before the readers of The Shaker. with pleasure; and shall give other
                            letters from the same pen to the same individual, as space will permit us: *</p><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear sister Mary:" TEIform="index"/>" Dear Sister Mary :</head><p TEIform="p">—We feel it a duty to ' be ready always to give an answer to every one that asketh a reason of the hope that
                                is in us.' But I am no theologian, and cannot pretend to answer your questions in orthodox style, but will
                                endeavor to give you true and simple answers according to my own experience, feelings and reflections. You
                                ask, ' What were the reasons these good men and women had for retiring from the busy world and leading the
                                life they do r' No other reason or motive than a purely religious one—an intense desire to live pure and
                                spotless lives—in a word, a desire to become true Christians—true followers of Jesus. Not merety outward
                                followers, but to gain and possess his inner life —his spirit. * If any man have not the spirit of Christ he
                                is none of His.' Kom. 8 : 9. And if we have His spirit it will be manifest in us hj our • ivallting even as
                                he walked J 1 John 2 : 6. You next ask: ' What reasons do you give for dissolving the ties of husband and
                                wife, parent and child—the ties which we consider, of all others, the most binding ?' Perhaps you will
                                understand me as thoroughly as by any other answer I could give, were I to say, we dissolve those ties for
                                similar reasons, that a young man ' forsakes father and mother and joins himself to a wife.' He has outgrown
                                his childish and boyish affections and ties, and looks upon the married relation as a higher enjoyment and
                                happier life. So the Christian, when he becomes 'wedded' to Christ—when he gets a taste of divine, unselfish
                                love—when he feels that same sacred and holy tie of love to Christ in his true members—in his brethren and
                                sisters in Christ—he is weaned from all partial, sensual and lower loves, and gives his whole heart and all
                                his faculties to the building up and support of this holy relation and institution. And who can doubt that
                                this divine, spiritual life of Christian love is infinitely higher, holier and happier than the sensual life
                                of the world, with all its comparatively low ties and relationships ? If the Christian institution has no
                                ties, no loves, no relationships nor enjoyments which equal those natural ties and relations of the world,
                                as professing Christians testify, what can it do for the world ? How make them happier or better ? And with
                                all reverence I would <pb n="79" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHA.K1ER. 79 ask : Why should Jesus expect that men and women
                                would forsake fathers, mothers, wives and children, houses and lands for His sake, and in order to become
                                His disciples, as he required, unless His religion and its relationships would afford them higher enjoyments
                                ? Indeed, our Saviour did promise 'a hundred fold' of gospel relations in exchange for the natural relations
                                of the world, which He required them to forsake. This increased and spiritual relationship is the promised
                                inheritance of Christ's true followers; and to us this promise is fulfilled. The inworking of the spirit of
                                Christ ultimately develops this high and holy state of the affections, and those who hear its still, small
                                voice and follow it diligently will surely be led in the right way; and this, dear sister, is my prayer in
                                regard to you. "It is according to the spirit and practice of the world to propagate its species; but the
                                spirit and work of Christ and of Christians, who are one with him, is to save those that are propagated. And
                                they have business enough of their own, without meddling with that of the world, out of which the}r are
                                called and chosen. ' Come ye out from among them.' 'I have chosen you out of the world, therefore the world
                                hateth you,' saith the Saviour to His followers. So, then, as it is the law of the first Adam, and the
                                propagating order to 'forsake father and mother and cleave to the wife,' it is the law of Christ and His
                                order or institution, to 'forsake father and mother, wife and children,' 'all' for Christ's sake a»d the
                                Gospel. Luke 14: 26, etc. Of course, if any of these relations choose to go with the Christian into the
                                higher spiritual life of Christian love, they will be embraced in that impartial love on equal terms with
                                others. The Gospel is an expansion of love, not requiring us to love our natural relations less, but to love
                                others more, and all on a different and higher principle. It is only such as hate and reject Christ that are
                                to be forsaken, and even they are still to be loved and prayed for. We can only know the spirit of Jesus by
                                His teaching and example, till the same spirit takes its abode in us and becomes a saving power On a certain
                                occasion, Jesus was teaching an assembly, mostly of his disciples, and some one informed him that his mother
                                and brother stood without, desiring to see him. He did not do as the spirit of the world would have
                                dictated; he illustrated his teachings by hi example. He asked, ' Who is my mother r and who are my brethren
                                ?' and he stretched forth his hand toward his disciples, and said ' Behold my mother and my brethren !
                                Whosoever doeth the will of my Father in Heaven, the same is mjr mother, sister and brother.' Mat. 12: 48,
                                etc. Thus He rejected all mere fleshly ties, and gave His disciples a practica lesson to do the same. He
                                owned no parenta! relations except those of a spiritual nature With him the mere fleshly relations of the
                                world were nothing; those of the kingdom o God everything. On another occasion, Jesu? assured His disciples,
                                ' that there is no man that has left house, or parents, or brethren, or wife, for the kingdom of God's sake,
                                who shal not receive manifold more in this present time and in the world to come life everlasting.' Luke 18:
                                29. In Mark, 10: 30, the things ;o be received and enjoyed in this present life, instead of those forsaken,
                                are more particuarly specified. • Houses, and brethren, and sisters, and mothers, and children, and lands.'
                                STow, as all the names of relations here mentioned as being restored are the names of spiritual relations,
                                We must see that • wife,' though mentioned among those to be forsaken, is not named among those to be
                                restored, because it is the name of a carnal or fleshly relation—a relation not known to the kingdom of
                                Heaven or Church of God. In view of these sayings and doings of Jesus Christ, and more that might be
                                mentioned, we think the question, ' What reason have we for dissolving the ties of husband and wife,' is the
                                same as to ask why we have become practical Christians— real followers of Jesus Christ. We have dissolved
                                those ties because He required it of all that would become His disciples—Luke 14: 26 because our spiritual
                                natures demand it— because we hungered and thirsted for righteousness, and were totally dissatisfied with
                                our own earthly, sinful, sensual lives, and because we longed for a higher, holier inner and outer life than
                                could be found in any of the earth relations. I know it is as you say, that those natural ties ' are, of all
                                others, the most binding.' And it is a sorrowful fact that they bind too many from entering into the more
                                happy relations of the kingdom of God. " You further ask what reason I can give for men and women living in
                                celibacy. This question, I think, has been alreadjr in some measure answered, and much more might be said on
                                the subject; but the very best reason we can give is, that Jesus, who was set as an example, that we should
                                follow His steps, did set us this example, and encouraged us by the promise of all the blessings of earth
                                and Heaven, of time and eternity, to follow him in this thing—to forsake wife or husband— forsake all for
                                His sake and the Gospel. You add : ' Marriage was appointed by God— by it the human race is propagated.' So
                                it was appointed by God, and so is celibacy. The first was given to the old man, Adam— the second to the
                                New Man, Christ. Therefore Christians are required to ' put off the old man with his deeds, and put on
                                the new man, which, according to God, is created in righteousness and true holiness.' ' The first man (Adam)
                                is of the earth, earthy; the second man (Christ) is the Lord from Heaven; and as is the earthy, so also are
                                they that are earthy; and as is the heavenly, so also are they that are heavenly.' See 1 Cor. 15: 47, 48,
                                etc. That is, the followers of the first Adam are like him, and the followers of the second man (Christ) are
                                like him. ' No man can serve two masters.' And now, sister, you say, ' Perhaps I think you should not ask
                                such things.' But indeed I do think you should ask just such things, and as many more as you may feel an
                                interest in asking; and if, in my broken and fragmentary way, I have satisfactorily answered you in any one
                                point, I shall be pleased. If I have failed, do tr}^ me again. Tell me where the lack is, and I will try and
                                do better next time. " Truly your friend,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sarah" TEIform="persName"/>Sarah."</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What is a celibate?" TEIform="index"/>What is a Celibate?</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Elder Giles B. Avert :—On last Feb. 26, I sent a communication to The Shaker for insertion. It was
                                headed, " Second Revelation of the Gospel," in which was set forth my objections to the statement, " Christ
                                has made his second appearance in a woman—in Ann Lee," or to the kindred phrases such as "Christ's second
                                appearance;" " He, Christ, has made his second appearance in a woman." 1 set forth how I was puzzled with
                                this phraseology, when in my youth I first tried to grasp Shaker theology. In those days of my simplicity,
                                when I had but one single idea represented by the word Christ, to wit, the man Jesus, I had not then learned
                                the hocus pocus game that might be played with that protean term—how many changes of form, and different
                                meanings it could be made to represent. Christ then to me represented nothing but the man Jesus, and how He
                                could come in a woman was past my comprehension ! When I came to learn the real facts of the case, the true
                                interpretation was this : That the man Jesus had in his day revealed the true way of salvation— the Gospel;
                                that Revelation was ultimately lost, and after a thousand sects with as many different gospels, and through
                                many centuries, had cried lo ! here, and lo ! there, proclaiming their false gospels, behold, the true
                                Gospel, which Jesus the Christ had first revealed, was now revealed a second time, by and through a woman.
                                So, then, it was not Jesus the Christ—the man that had come the second time, but his Gospel had been
                                revealed a second time. This, I belieA^e, is a fair outline of the communication above mentioned, and I
                                close this preliminary by stating that I was not much disappointed that it was not published, nor have I the
                                least dissatisfied feeling toward our good editor, believing that he only exercised his undoubted right. The
                                following communication I had designed as No. 2 to the one above outlined; but as that was not accepted, I
                                do not present this for publication, but for the consideration of our much beloved Central Ministry, and for
                                them to dispose of as they may think proper. There is a term which has, I think, come into vogue within the
                                last fifteen or twenty years, which I think is very improper, and ought to be dropped, as it really
                                misrepresents, and does not convey the idea intended. The word is celibacy, and its kindred term celibate.
                                The first is thus defined by Worcester : " The life or state of a person unmarried, a single life." The
                                other, as a noun, is defined: " One who adheres to,, or practices celibacy ; an unmarried man, a
                                bachelor.''' As an adjective, this word is defined, "unmarried, single." Not one idea of virginity,
                                continency, or even chastity in either of these definitions—nothing that implies the least restraint on
                                licentiousness, or the libidinous instinct. In fact the "bachelors and unmarried men" of our cities are the
                                most thorough debauchees, and in calling ourselves celibates, we rank ourselves with this class. In olden
                                time we carefully avoided professing celibacy, and assumed to be virgins, to live virgin or continent lives.
                                I do not object to the terms " celibate " <pb n="80" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 8O THE S H A. K E Pt . and " celibacy"
                                because they are of recent introduction among us, but because they really misrepresent us. For myself, I had
                                rather be called a monk than a celibate. There are thousands of celibates throughout our country, but very
                                few who live continently, or live in virgin purity. Those who do not so live, would do quite as well or
                                better to take Paul's counsel : " If thej' cannot contain, let them marry." As one of our poets says : "If
                                they're In pain, and can't contain, And will not serve the Lord, yon know, Then sure they mast live in their
                                lnst, And take their just reward, yon know." One thing is certain: the term celibate cannot be applied to
                                Shakers distinctively, and we must have it, if at all, in common with a class whose purity of life is very
                                questionable, or rather unquestionably impure and unchaste. As observed above, we did not in former days use
                                the terms celibacy and celibate, as characteristic of our lives and practice, and it was intentionally
                                avoided. I can remember well that our good elder of the novitiate order would often correct outside
                                inquirers, when they called the Shakers " celibates," or spoke of our living lives of " celibacy." He would
                                give them a definition of the words, and show them that thejr did not characterize or distinctively apply to
                                us. Whoever will examine our early publications, will discover that these terms were never used by our
                                former writers. " The Kentucky Revival " was published in 1807; "The Testimony" in 1808; " The Manifesto "
                                in 1818; " The Mil. Ch." in 1823, and "The Book of Testimonies" in 1827, besides divers smaller pamphlets,
                                and I question whether those objectionable terms can be found in any of those works. There is another
                                unanswerable objection to applying the terms in question as characteristic of the Shaker society or
                                institution. They represent the males only. The females, full one-half of the community, are ignored and
                                unrepresented. There is not the least respect paid to "woman's rights." Again, there is a respectable
                                proportion of the members of these societies who are married people. They, too, are unrepresented, and a
                                chosen few, who can properly be called celibates, represent and give name to the whole community. Is it true
                                that all married men who come into our Society, thereby become celibates? I see in the statistics of London,
                                1860, they number celibates or bachelors by themselves, and make a distinct class of the ividowers,
                                confining the celibate class to single adult males who had never been married. A certain man once informed
                                me that he was raised in the city of New York, and was apprenticed to a mechanic who carried ok his trade in
                                that city, and employed several other apprentices. It was the custom of this man to take his apprentice boys
                                once a week to a house of prostitution, and there indulged to the full. He was a " celibate," and his
                                apprentice, my informant, was now forty years old, and he had practiced what his master had taught
                                him—celibacy. He was a " bachelor, a single man, a celibate!" Ay, there are thousands of such celibates to
                                one Shaker in this wicked world of ours; and though I am willing to call them brothers, as being of the same
                                race, yet, to go by the same name, as a religious characteristic or designation, I emphatically do object.
                                There are divers cases outside of our Society, in which the heads of families, the husband and wife, take
                                separate lodgings, and live strictly continent or virgin lives, and yet keep their families together, and
                                apparently live like other people. Are they celibates, bachelors, single people ? In fact we must come at
                                last to confining the application of the term celibates to the few adult males of our community, and leave
                                the whole sisterhood, all the married males, and all the adolescent class unrepresented; or drop the title
                                celibate, and call ourselves by a name that will legitimately represent the whole. As it is now, our
                                testimony to mankind should be, " Come and join us, and be bachelors, live single, and eschew marriage." And
                                as our title does not recognize the sisterhood, we should say, "If any women choose to join us, we will give
                                them the honorable title of ' old maids,' which is the proper correlative of ' bachelor.' " But if we cast
                                away our inadequate and absurd title, what shall we have in its stead ? There is none better than virgin.
                                Though this is more commonly ap- plied to females, yet there is the very best of authority for applying it
                                to males. Jeremiah, ch. 31:13, calls young men and old virgins. One of Worcester's definitions of the word
                                virgin is, "a male who has preserved his chastity." He refers for authority to Rev. 14 : 4 : " These are
                                they which are not defiled with women, for the}r are virgins." Not being defiled with women shows that they
                                were males. Parkhurst, in his Lexicon, de- fines the Greek word for virgin [parthenos], "A person in a
                                virgin state," and adds, "The word plainly includes both sexes." Let us then boldly assume our proper title,
                                and honor it by our lives. Your Brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pelham, R. W." TEIform="persName"/>R. W. Pelham</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Natural religion" TEIform="index"/>Natural Religion</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p">Is religion natural, that necessitates the murder of human beings ? In China, the problem of population versus
                            faith has been solved so far as the propagative order is concerned. There, four hundred millions of human beings
                            have been stationary and stagnant for thousands of years, kept so by the law that two things cannot exist in the
                            same place at the same time. Not having sufficient foreign or domestic war to check population, China has
                            legalized childmurder by parents; and, for ages, female infants have been and are still exposed, as was Moses,
                            in little fragile arks, on some pond, or lake, or river, as soon as born, there to perish, or be rescued, as the
                            case may be. There is simply space for no more human beings; nor is the power revealed amongst them to dry up
                            the great river Euphrates, the river of human, animal propagation. J. B. Bradley, formerly Consul to China, is
                            my authority for these facts. In India, unknown ages ago, the same conditions were met by the institution of a
                            spiritual celibate order-—Indian Shakerism; Maria Childs asserting that thousands of monasteries and nunneries
                            flourished in that country many ages before it was visited b}" Roman Catholic missionaries. No ancient highly
                            civilized nation is known which did not possess similar institutions. Egypt had her Theraputes, and the Jews
                            their Essenes, all down through their history to the time of Jesus, who himself was educated in that remarkable
                            order, which so correctly portrayed American Shakerism. As the Chinese have set their faces towards the western
                            continent, which seems to be the reservoir for the overplus population of the world, it is only a matter of time
                            as to how soon the same point will be reached in these United States, that China has touched so many ages in the
                            past. Will any form of theology that now exists in this new world meet and solve this problem, except it be
                            American Shakerism ? In other words, is there any other that is justly entitled to be termed a scientific and
                            natural religion ? it being the only system that makes provision for two orders—the natural, or propagative, and
                            the spiritual, or resurrection ; each possessing its own dual government distinct from the other, like the moon
                            and the sun. "When, by increased knowledge of law, and obedience thereto, there shall be "no more pain, nor
                            sorrow, nor sighing," nor premature death, the result of physical disease, and war shall be a thing of the past;
                            when there shall be no more poor, for all shall inherit the earth, Shakerism will be the last and only hope of
                            the race; the godly and natural agency to balance the principle of population, and to check the unnatural
                            increase of human beings on this limited earth.</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Any subscribers failing to receive their copy of The Shaker regularly..." TEIform="index"/>Any subscribers failing to receive their copy of The Shaker regularly...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Any subscribers failing to receive their copy of The Shaker regularly, will please notify us. </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Publications" TEIform="index"/>PUBLICATIONS.</head><p TEIform="p">Christ's First and Second Appearing Dnnlavy's Manifesto ... Millennial Church Compendium of Shakerism Three
                            Discourses on United Interests Shaker Communism—Evans Shakerism, the Possibility of the Race Tracts free, where
                            postage is paid. m 25 1 25 1 00 0 50 0 50 0 50 0 10 </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Members of society" TEIform="index"/>MEMBERS OF SOCIETY</head><p TEIform="p">Appointed to answer Correspondeiits, among whom are the Board of .Editors. Elder F. W. Evans. Mt. Lebanon,
                            Columbia Co., N. Y. " Galen Richmond, Shakers, N. Y. " Calvin G. Heed, Mt. Morris, Livingston Co., N. Y. " Simon
                            Mabee, West Pittsfield, Mass. " H. S. Kellogg, Thompsonville, Conn., Shakers. " Albert Battles, Tyringham,
                            Berkshire Co., Mass. " Wm. Leonard, Ayer, Mass.. Shakers. " Jonas Nutting, Shirley Village, Middlesex Co., Mass.
                            " B. H. Smith, Shaker Village, Merrimack Co., N. H. " Henry Cummings, Enfield, Grafton Co., N. H. " John
                            B.Vance. Alfred, Shakers. York Co., Me. " Joseph Brackett, West Gloncester, Cumberland Co., Me., Shakers. "
                            Chas. Clapp, Union Village, Warren Co., O., Shakers. " Ezra Sherman, Preston, Hamilton Co., Ohio, Shakers. "
                            Stephen Ball, Dayton. Shakers, Ohio. '' Jacob Kulp, Pleasant Hill, Mercer Co,, Ky. " J. R. Eades, South Union,
                            Logan Co., Ky. " J. S. Prescott, Cleveland, Ohio, Shakers.</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>