<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ss0309" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">Shaker and Shakeress</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Society</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Mount Lebanon, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">3</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">9</biblScope><date value="18730901" TEIform="date">September 1873</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">65-72</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="3" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="65" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="9" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!-- 
                    <p>Vol. III. No. 9. PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETY. F W EVANS Fifty Cents " Editok/ ' Mt. Lebanon Col. Co. N. Y.
                        September, 1873. PKB AJfNXJM</p>
                    --><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Man v. Earth" TEIform="index"/>MAN v. EARTH</head><p TEIform="p">The First Cause of all things is Spirit — God. The material worlds are the last procedure—
                            the ultimates—from this Primal Cause. The Spirit of God is, in a low degree, in the natural
                            worlds, and is exhibited in the creation of human beings — the representatives of Deity. Man
                            and Woman is the Lord of this planet. The vitalizing power of the human body is the soul;
                            the vitalizing power of the soul is the spirit. Body, soul, and spirit, are the product of
                            the earth, and of its soul and spirit. In other words, the spiritual world is as soul to the
                            earth ; and the inner heavens as spirit to it. Human beings are the earth elements in their
                            highest form of organization ; and that is why Swedenborg declared the earth and the heavens
                            to be in the form of a man; and man and woman in the form of Deity—Wisdom and Love. When we
                            contemplate the fact, that the human race use the constituent elements of a country—fire,
                            air, water, land, mineral, vegetable, and animal, it becomes evident, that, in a nation like
                            China, where 400 million men and women have lived, generated, and died, during countless
                            ages, the whole nation, in general and particular, is humanized. Is it unreasonable, or
                            illogical, to assume that the people control these elements; and that, if they were
                            permanently in a Divine life, every thing would be under their jurisdiction and
                            manipulation; and that, in conjunction and co-operation with the myriads in the soul of the
                            eajth-the world of spirits— directed by the Deific Spirits in the inner heavens, they could
                            realize the position, that God would " withhold no good thing from those who love and serve
                            one another"—which is to love and serve God ? Inference. That the saints of all ages and
                            races are but as drops before the shower, in their power over the physical elements—signs of
                            what the whole race will attain to in the coming Millennium. History abounds in miracles
                            that are no miracles at all, having been wrought under law. " Elias was subject to like
                            passions as we are, and he prayed earnestly that it might not rain: and it rained not on the
                            earth by the space of three years and six months. And he prayed again, and the heaven gave
                            rain, and the earth brought forth her fruit." (James, 5 : 17,18.) The great power possessed
                            by Moses over the material elements is latent in the entire human family. He " was the
                            meekest man" that existed at that period. His humility, simplicity, devotion, and
                            spiritual-mindedness, rendered him an eminent medium of occult forces. He was in the life of
                            God in Nature—a creator. In power over the mere earthly elements, in their unorganized
                            condition, Moses exceeded Jesus. But, in power over the human body—those elements highly
                            organized, Jesus exceeded his predecessors. All power in heaven and earth was his, as a type
                            of what all men will or may become and possess. The whole nation of Egypt—its land and
                            water, its air and fire, and the very souls of the people—seemed plastic in the hands of
                            Moses. Even the sea obeyed the touch of his magical wand, and was his weapon of war, and
                            instrument of instruction and destruction. The whole body of Israelites acted efficiently
                            upon the food-producing elements of the country through which they were forty years in
                            passing, into a land of milk and honey. There, food was more the product of labor. MANNA.
                            What have we here ? What was this manna, and how was it produced ? Was it of the same
                            chemical substances in the atmosphere, and in the soil upon which it gathered, that under
                            other conditions would have assumed the form of wheat? It must have been thus; for law could
                            not have been any more violated in its creation than when bananas, or any other kind of
                            fruit, is the result. As to the how, I have not yet found a teacher to instruct and make me
                            understand the origin of rice or oranges; nor do I know the process of the growth of a blade
                            of grass, or of the California Washingtonian G-igantica. " The soul of things " is in the
                            spirit world; " for there the Lord God formed every herb and every plant before it grew " on
                            the earth — before it was externalized. The earth is the mother of us all — of the various
                            races of humans — in a far more real and practical manner and sense than any but poets have
                            thought or imagined. As the body of the mother of any animal, man included, naturally and
                            spontaneously produces food for her own offsprings, so is food for man and beast equally
                            spontaneously produced ¦— eliminated from and of the elements of which man and the earth
                            itself, and all the genera of animals are constituted. To my mind the historical fact that
                            for forty years manna-food ("what is it?") assumed the form of a deposit, like coriander
                            seed, on the surface of the ground, is as simple and as scientifically understandable—as
                            natural—¦ as is the analogous fact of the deposit of honey-dew, which is very nutritious,
                            sometimes sufficiently so to sustain life. On this earth man and woman, standing in a normal
                            relation to the lower spirit sphere, would need to " take no " more " thought as to what
                            they should eat and drink, and wherewithal they should be clothed," than do " the ravens "
                            or " the lilies of the valley." But what of the ethics ¦—of the moral aspect of this great
                            question of Nutrition ? The Scotch have their oatmeal, the Irish their potatoes, the
                            Asiatics their rice, as Israel had their manna. What was the effect of this one kind of
                            simple food, so long continued as to extend be3^ond that generation to their posterity, who
                            went over Jordan ? Why this was the physiological effect, that, when the Israelites, as
                            slaves, came out of Egypt — the richest food-producing country upon the then known earth —
                            the granary of the world — they, as a people, were precisely in the same physiological
                            condition as American Christians; ?". e., they were utterly given over to their physicians,
                            unto whom. they had " turned," and not unto their Lord, " the God of Abraham, Isaac and
                            Jacob," who would have taken " all sickness and diseases " and physicians " away from the
                            midst of them." And they were tilled with Egyptian maladies, "from the crowns of their heads
                            to the soles of their feet." From every one of those diseases they were healed and delivered
                            by the daily use of their God-given manna; by the exercise necessary to secure this food; by
                            the pure air breathed consequent upon living in tents, and while at work early in the
                            morning, to gather it before it melted ; conjoined to the pure water from the rock of Horeb,
                            and from other springproducing rocks in the Wilderness. By these means not only were they
                            cured of their physical ailments, but there ensued a sensitive, psychical, magnetic
                            condition of body and soul throughout the whole camp of Israel. And they informed Moses that
                            " Eldad and Medad prophesied in the camp " among the people; and they sought of him
                            authority to suppress them. And Moses replied: " Enviest thou for my sake," because the
                            common people are exercising my peculiar gifts ? Why, " I would that all the Lord's people
                            were prophets." That is just what I am trying to make of them, even as a schoolmaster is
                            intent upon making learned men and women of his scholars, and as a good father and mother
                            desire to have their children become even superior to themselves. Such, in substance, was
                            the nobly grand response of this archetype of the first real living Shaker, Jesus of
                            Nazareth. Jesus was a scholar, and Moses, whom (in vision) he saw personally from time to
                            time, was his schoolmaster, to bring him to Christ; and Elias, who was a Christ Prophet,
                            came with Moses to the mount; and, while Moses brought Jesus near to John the Baptist, his
                            successor, Elias, brought him to the Christ Spirit, with ¦which John baptized him. Thus we
                            have the Law and the Prophets until John, and then the kingdom of heaven was preached.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="J. M. Peebles" TEIform="index"/>J. M. PEEBLES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Peebles, J. M." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We are in receipt of letters and communications, written in April, from this well-beloved
                            friend, who accompanied us in our English Mission, and who is now on a flying trip around
                            the Earth planet. From New Zealand, he writes, that man, as a religious animal, is polygamic
                            and promiscuous; as a spiritual being, he is monogamic in marriage, and chaste in marital
                            conduct; and, as an angel, he is a celibate. The embryo angel is within. Men may become
                            angelic on earth. This is the resurrection, with God's " will done on earth as in heaven."
                            EdrOT^TTIBCILY'c <pb n="66" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 66 8HAKEE .A.ND The ancient inhabitants were called
                            Maori. He thus writes of maoki spiritualism:. Relation to, and communion with, a world of
                            spirits, are beliefs almost, if not completely, universal. The native tribes and clans of
                            these islands are not only aware of holding intercourse with the so-called dead, but they
                            understand the abuse, often using their mediumistic privileges for selfish ends. Daring
                            their wars with the English, they were uniformly made acquainted, by vision, clairvoyance or
                            clairaudience, with the movements of the British troops before action in battle. Not a plan
                            of Her Majesty's officers could be kept from them. The leading chief of the Han Hans was a
                            noted medium and medicine-man. He distinctly said that the " spirits of the dead" guided him
                            to his victories. The Maoris in the north islands still own much territory, have their king,
                            and hold but little intercourse with pakeha, the white man. The medium-priest in a tribe is
                            called Tohunga. They meet in close apartments, and chant their songs till the flickering
                            lire fades away, when the Tohunga goes into his ecstatic state, and the spirit controlling
                            tenders counsel, describes his new habitation in spirit-life, gives the names of those whom
                            he has met, and bears messages in return to kindred in the higher life. That these Maoris of
                            New Zealand talk wjth immortals, no intelligent man having lived among them disputes. From
                            Hong Kong, China, May 27th, we have the following sermon: (The Shaker and Shakeress-)
                            Pacific Ocean, April 25, '73. Elder Frederick : The other day, on the clipper
                            harquellarrietArmitage,hound to Hong Kong, China, from New Zealand, we crossed the equator
                            in longitude east 166°, 20". We have passed a great number of islands, between two of which
                            we were becalmed for five days. Several sharks surrounded our ship. The weather was
                            intensely hot, the southern cross shining beautifully each night. The voyage reminds me of
                            our trip to England only in this — the unfathomed depths of waters beneath and the infinite
                            expanse of blue above us. On the " Atlantic," White Star Line, we had excellent
                            accommodations, and intelligent associates, with essays, lectures, and the mirth of the
                            eccentric George Francis Train. . On this vessel, we have accommodations and food not easily
                            described, with 107 noisy, homeward-bound Chinamen, a portion of whom occupy the cabin.
                            Confucius may have been a most eminent sage, but these, his disciples, are dirty, ignorant,
                            and selfish specimens of humanity. They are properly " Coolies." Seeing them in their own
                            country may improve my opinion of them. There is no line of steamships from Australia or New
                            Zealand to China; neither is there at present between the English Colonies in the Pacific
                            and California. The line started by Webb &amp; Co. proved an abortion. I gave the reason
                            of the failure in one of my letters to the Banner of Light. By the way, I fear that two or
                            three of these " letters of travel" have been lost either through postal mismanagement, or
                            the Boston fire. Traveling, I find that Spiritualism has believers and representatives in
                            all the enlightened portions of the world. The Pacific Islanders are no exception. Surely it
                            is the " angel having great power." Time, you may well know, hangs heavily. Dr.Dunn
                            constitutes my most intimate companionship. I have heard him say," knowing the treachery and
                            wickedness of the world," that, if he should be called to spirit-life, he would desire to
                            have his children brought up Shakers. Having nothing else to do on Sunday last, I fell to
                            preaching. You know I was ordained a preacher some thirty years ago, by the laying on of
                            hands, which hands had about as much influence as so many dry chips. It was a church form,
                            nothing more. But I fell to preaching pen-and-ink sermons the other day; and although
                            decidedly dissatisfied with them, I venture to forward the gist of them to you, to dispose
                            of as the spirit moves. They may not abound in the right kind of theology, according to your
                            conceptions of " sound doctrine." But I remember the circumstance of the English churchman
                            coming to you in London to inquire about " Shakerism." You informed him that believers,
                            constituting the Millennial Church, had no crafty creed, no hireling priesthood, and no
                            ecclesiastic yoke of theological belief to fasten upon men's necks. "But," you added, "those
                            joining us must be good; must plant their feet firmly upon the platform embodying these
                            principles, purity, peace, and ' all things in common.' ' Faith without works is dead.'" But
                            to my preaching. SERMONS AT SEA. NO. 1. "I am the good Shepherd. The good Shepherd calleth
                            his own sheep by name and leadeth them out." John, 10: 3-11. If rational in the ancient
                            Greek to put over the portal of the temple, " Know thyself;" if justifiable in Whitman the
                            poet to write, " I celebrate myself," and in our favorite Emerson to " affirm " himself, it
                            certainly was not egotistic in Jesus to say, " I testify of myself." And this he did when he
                            said, "lam the good Shepherd." The words were born out of a conscious consciousness of his
                            divine mission, or a realization of the fact that his " kingdom was not of this world." The
                            symbol of the Shepherd is beautiful. Eastern Shepherds knew and named each sheep of the
                            flock. And in early morning they led them out into green pastures, watching them by day, and
                            carefully guarding them by night. Jesus, conversing with the spirits of Moses and Elias, and
                            aflame with the " baptism of fire," was pre-eminently " the good Shepherd." Every man
                            anointed or baptized into the Christ-spirit of love and purity is a good Shepherd, and every
                            such woman is a good Shepherdess. These, by the logic of circumstances, are leaders. It is
                            embodied prin- ciples that naturally constitute them such. The " body-politic," as well as
                            the human body, must have a head, the office-work of which is to lead or rightly direct. An
                            organization without competent officers to govern and direct would be comparable to a
                            headless body, or idiocy, fruiting out into shapes as monstrous as ungovernable. Jesus
                            "leadeth his own sheep out;" leads them by love, or love and wisdom combined. These dual
                            principles run like golden threads through the realm of universal being. Love, void of
                            parasitic attendants — passion, suspicion, and selfishness ; love, acting in concert with
                            wisdom and power, is the mightiest redemptive force in the universe. Every human being has
                            something good within; some qualities to admire and love. These God-implanted excellencies
                            should be searched for and unfolded. Love not only seeks, but it is a mighty invigorator.
                            The vine is a dry, leafless thing in early springtime, but the warmth of summer brings out
                            the blossoms and the purple clusters. The infant, at times, is peevish, cross, and
                            self-willed ; but maternal love,with skillful fingers/touches and tunes the better chords,
                            till the life-strings become accustomed to vibrate in harmony. Winter, in northern
                            latitudes, is any thing but inviting; not a tiny flower above the ground; not a song among
                            the trees, and not a flush of summer in the sky ! Spring is the resurrection time. Many men,
                            though in the prime of life, are in the winter of their days ; cold, hard, worldly! Can we
                            hope for buds of benevolence ? Can we look for the " fruits of the spirit 1" Aye, there are
                            silent whis- perings ; these are stirring at the roots of their being. Conscience, at times,
                            arouses itself; the good Shepherd calls ; the " Spirit and the Bride say Come!" Charity "
                            hopeth all things." European travelers tell us that the journey is rough and rocky from the
                            " garden home of Adam," on the Euphrates, to the Calvary, in Syria, that echoed with the
                            words, " Father, forgive them." So, spiritually speaking, the " travel" is often long from
                            the Adamic nature, with its appetites and passions, to Christ, the victor. "Be of good
                            cheer," said Jesus, " I have overcome the world." This " travel," this pathway, is not
                            always flowery. There are trials, disappointments, and thorns to pierce the feet; there are
                            cups of gall to be tasted, and heavy crosses to be borne. All higher births are preceded by
                            pains. " No cross, no crown," said the noble-hearted Quaker, Wm. Penn. Crosses and
                            sufferings are good angels in disguise, and O how divine to bear them without a murmur. "
                            Not my will but thine, O God, be done !" When a lad, in Vermont, I remember of seeing a
                            shepherd-farmer, on a bitter, snowy day, gathering all his sheep carefully to the windy side
                            of the hill. The silly creatures, left to themselves, would all take to the other side,
                            going to the sheltered spots, where the deep snow-drifts would silently furnish them at once
                            with a refuge and a grave. On such a day, the life of some of the sheep depended upon facing
                            the blast. Lying down cozily, they would become chilled and benumbed! Therefore, the
                            shepherd would not let even the weakest and youngest lie down in the shelter, but by turns
                            called, led, carried, and drove them, facing bitter winds and blinding snows. This is but a
                            faint symbol of the " good Shepherd," of the good angels, of good men and women, and their
                            plans to find, encourage, and gather into the fold the " lost sheep." Life is a puzzle.
                            There are many ways to a city, but only one that is direct. Sunny roads are not always the
                            safest. There are fields of temptation, where the moral strength is tried; fields of danger,
                            where great caution is required ; fields of toil, where harvests come only through incessant
                            labor ; fields of quietness, where a little rest is allowed ; fields of darkness, where the
                            sheep huddle close to the Shepherd; and there are refreshing fields of plenty upon the
                            higher pasture lands of true living. Every right step taken is eternal gain. " Sweet fields,
                            beyond the swelling floods, Stand dress'd in living green." Up to these heavenly fields,
                            where the crystal waters flow, flow so gently, by the tree of life, the "good Shepherd"
                            leadeth the sheep. The lamb that is faint and weary he carries in his arms, till it acquires
                            a little strength, then he expects it to use that strength. Effort and will-power are
                            indispensable to success. The inimitable Emerson recommends " self-help." The " good
                            Shepherd," says the Evangelist John, " calleth his own sheep by name, and leadeth them out;"
                            that is, leads them out of darkness into light; out of the earthly into the spiritual; out
                            of moral feebleness into manly strength; out of sluggish indolence into stirring activity;
                            out of sectarian theology into religion " pure and undefiled ;" and, finally, out of earth
                            and earthly associations into the gates of heaven, where they are as the angels of God.
                            Amen.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enon Valley, Pennsylvania, july 6, 1873" TEIform="index"/>Enon Valley, Penn., July 6,1873</head><p TEIform="p">Friends, Editors of the Shaker and Shakeress : As all the readers of your beautiful,
                                clean-faced paper feel an interest in the great question now before the American People,
                                of converting the United States Constitution into a theological creed, and the
                                government under it into a persecuting power, they will be sorry to learn that the Penn-
                                sylvania Constitutional Convention, now in session at Philadelphia, have taken a step
                                backward on this subject. The old Constitution, in its preamble, declares, " We, the
                                People of the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, ordain and establish this Constitution." The
                                draft of the new one has this preamble, " We, the People of Pennsylvania, grateful to
                                Almighty God, for the blessings of civil and religious liberty, and humbly invoking his
                                guidance, do ordain, &amp;c." To be sure there is nothing in this change very
                                alarming, except that it panders to the determined set of bigots who wish to push back
                                the cause of human progress ten hundred years, and who are the <pb n="67" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/>
                                SHAKERESS. 67 most thankful for small favors of any people I ever knew. If I were of
                                those who would do evil that good might come, I could wish that the Convention would
                                gratify the bigots, and put into the new constitution the whole Westminster Confession
                                of Faith and Catechisms, and thus give the people a belly-full of it. Such a proceeding
                                would raise a ferment that would rid the public stomach of every atom of theological
                                poison that has been smuggled into it by these unscrupulous men, But I have something to
                                tell you as an offset to this. The Baptist clergy of Philadelphia have been discussing
                                the subject of the religious amendment. Remembering how the Puritans of Massachusetts
                                persecuted Roger Williams, the great founder of their sect, and drove him down to Rhode
                                Island, the Baptists have always, as a general rule, taken right ground on the question
                                of Church and. State. The Rev. Dr. Howard Malcom, one of their oldest and most
                                influential ministers, declared, in the Philadelphia discussion, that the advocates of
                                this religious amendment were either fools or wicked assailants of our free
                                institutions. The Rev. Dr. Cathcart, another eminent man, declared that the intelligent
                                and consistent Baptists held to the secular theory of government, and admitted that
                                nations, as nations, can have no God; that the same is true of families ; that religion
                                is purely an individual, not a social, principle, and that the demands of liberalism
                                ought to be conceded. The demands of liberalism referred to, are the nine following
                                propositions issued by Francis E. Abbot, the able and distinguished Editor of the Toledo
                                Index, and generally adopted by the Radicals of the country: THE DEMANDS OF LIBERALISM.
                                1. We demand that churches and other ecclesiastical property shall no longer be exempt
                                from just taxation. 2. We demand that the employment of chaplains in Congress, in State
                                Legislatures, in the navy and militia, and in prisons, asylums, and all other
                                institutions supported by public money, shall be discontinued. 3. We demand that all
                                public appropriations for sectarian, educational and charitable institutions shall
                                cease. 4. We demand that all religious services now sustained by the Government shall be
                                abolished; and especially that the use of the Bible in public schools, whether
                                ostensibly as a text-book or avowedly as a book of religious worship, shall be
                                prohibited. 5. We demand that the appointment, by the President of the United States or
                                by the Governors of the various States, of all religious festivals and fasts shall
                                wholly cease. 6. We demand that the judicial oath in the courts and in all othei
                                departments of the government shall be abolished, and that simple affirmation, under the
                                pains and penalties of perjury, shall be established in its stead. 7. We demand that all
                                laws directly or indirectly enforcing the observance of Sunday as the Sabbath shall be
                                repealed. 8. We demand that all laws looking to the enforcement of " Christian "
                                morality shall be abrogated, and that all laws shall be conformed to the requirements of
                                natural moral ity, equal rights, and impartial liberty. 9. We demand that not only in
                                the Constitutions of the United. States and of the several States, but also in the
                                practical administration of the same, no privilege or advantage shall )e conceded to
                                Christianity or any other special religion; that our entire political system shall be
                                founded and administered on a purely secular basis, and whatever changes shall prove
                                necessary to this end shall be consistently, unflinchingly and promptly made. These
                                demands are reasonable ; and, unless the Young Men's Christian Association, which is
                                made up of members from all the Evangelical sects, override the Baptist Church in their
                                plans " for giving this country to Jesus," we may calculate on the help of this large
                                sect in our endeavors to keep the State free from the adulterous embraces of the Church.
                                Those religious Bourbons, who, like their political allies in Europe, " neither learn
                                any thing, nor forget any thing," have no idea that they are fabricating a two-edged
                                sword that will cut both ways. The emigration that is swarming to our shores from Europe
                                compels us to think of the future, and the possible complications that may arise in
                                religious matters. Each sect has now an unquestioned right to believe and worship as
                                they please, and to propagate their opinions by the pulpit and the press. But if the
                                majority of to-day have the right to foist their creed into the Constitution, and
                                persecute all non-conformists, the majority of next year can "amend" it out, and put
                                their own in, and send to prison those who don't conform. And the struggle thus
                                inaugurated will make this land just what England and Scotland were in the 17th century,
                                when Presbytery and Prelacy took the field, and drenched those countries in blood. But
                                what we want is discussion of the subject. When the people are informed on governmental
                                questions the danger is over. Respectfully yours,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., A. B." TEIform="persName"/>A. B. B.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Two governments" TEIform="index"/>TWO GOVERNMENTS</head><p TEIform="p">A Civil Government, that shall be male and female, to begin with, will have taken an ad-
                            vance step in the direction of the Millennium. Other radical changes and improvements would
                            speedily follow, as naturally "as day the night." An influx from the Divine Order would com-
                            mence which would never cease, until the land should be as common to the people as is the
                            air and water. Poverty would be no more ; for the Lord would greatly bless such a people. "
                            War would cease to the ends of the earth ;" the social evil would not be so much as named;
                            and sickness an evil unknown. For great would be the peace, and perfect the righteousness,
                            of the nation whom a dual God should direct through its Civil Government. While the
                            Spiritual Church, "not of this world," and as perfectly aloof from the Civil Government as
                            is the sun aloof from the moon would be " the tabernacle of God with men ;' "the kingdom of
                            heaven upon earth," with no generative elements or practices ; and with all the property of
                            life, and its labor products enjoyed " in common," by the subjects of the Resurrection.
                            Thither would the nations of the earth go up to inquire of the Lord, as the tribes of Israe'
                            went up to the temporal Jerusalem — to it; Temple, its Altar, and its Priesthood. The " ark
                            " — organization ; the " pot of manna" — spiritual instruction; the " Covenant " — the
                            abstract laws of Divine Love and Wisdom in government, leading into all truth, which would
                            perfect human happiness in the Natural and Spiritual Orders, with their dual ivil
                            Governments, and the dual Church of hrist, would be the Millennial Epoch.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dress reform" TEIform="index"/>DRESS REFORM</head><p TEIform="p">SoROSis has spoken some sensible words on Dress, while partaking of an im-sensible dinner at
                            Delmonico's. Resolved, That the dress and customs of a people are the outward indications of
                            its character, and should engage the thoughtful attention of its most intelligent men and
                            women. Climate, and the well-established laws of health and comfort, should regulate it.
                            That the Dress question has been left too long in the hands of the ignorant, who furnish
                            waists of torture, and skirts of burthen; producing a female figure out of strange stuff,
                            having but slight resemblance to a natural woman, until the taste of the nation is
                            corrupted, and their good sense impaired. Sorosis further " resolved, that, as mothers of
                            daughters, and sisters of all womankind, we pledge ourselves not to dress, either ourselves
                            or our daughters, in any style of fashion condemned by the wise and prudent, the artistic,"
                            the physiologist, or moralist.</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Impending crisis" TEIform="index"/>THE IMPENDING CRISIS</head><p TEIform="p">" C^ESARISM IN THE U. S." The " Woodhull &amp; Claflin's " says: — " At last, that to
                            which we have been endeavoring to wake the consciousness of the people-^the fact that th.ere
                            is a well-organized plan to remand this country to despotism—is becoming the subject of
                            lengthy editorials in the columns of the paper which, in some respects, is the greatest of
                            all newspapers in the world. "It is a generally-conceded fact, that Protestantism as a
                            finality is a failure in the world. Leaving Catholicism, there is no legitimate, permanent
                            halting-place, until the opposite extreme is reached—that of individual freedom. Protest-
                            antism is the road over which people travel from Catholicism to Individualism ; while,
                            ultimately, all people will be obliged either to advance to Individualism, or to retreat on
                            Catholicism," or Shatter Dualism. " The same is true of our politics. The government
                            represented by our country to-day, is to politics what Protestantism is to religion. Having
                            made a departure from absolute monarchy, the people must advance to complete republicanism—
                            individualism in politics—or retreat on absolutism. One of the two extremes only is possible
                            as an ultimate condition; and the sort of government now existing here is therefore
                            impossible as a permanency; and the people—some of them— begin to comprehend this fact.
                            Those who openly advocate the true democratic government, favoring individuality in
                            politics, and those who secretly favor a return to Csesarism, believi ng in absolutism. And
                            this is the battle that must next be fought in this country.. " The magnates in politics,
                            religion, and finance, those who now virtually rule, see that the people are awaking to
                            their natural rights, as constituent members of the community, and they know right well
                            that, when once they are thoroughly comprehended, their sway will end. To crush this, some
                            movement must be made to stop the progress of these liberalizing, humanitarianizing ideas.
                            It being impossible that existing things will continue, there is but one way, so they think,
                            in which present potentates can still continue to remain potent in the affairs of the
                            country, and that is by a retreat on absolutism, for the time called Caasarism; and this is
                            what the secret organization to accomplish a third term for Grant, and ultimately a life
                            term for him, means." Upon the truth or falsity of the mutual charges of sexual immorality,
                            by which the Brooklyn church and the Woodhull &amp; <pb n="68" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 68 SHAKER
                            Clafiin company have assailed each other for some months past, the Shaker and Shakeress has
                            no public opinion to express. But, when the Orthodox Church-and-State party take up the
                            quarrel, and, evading the direct point at issue — the character and personal conduct of
                            certain prominent leading members of the Brooklyn church — prefer unfounded and ridiculous
                            charges of obscenity against the " Weekly," for simply reporting the facts at issue, and
                            throw the case into the United States Courts, it looks very much like clerical trickery, and
                            carries the mind back to the time of William Penn and the English Courts who tried him. As a
                            society we have had some experience in the matter of having " all manner of evil" spoken of
                            us. If the Brooklyn church did not choose to follow our example of " suffering wrong rather
                            than doing wrong," still continuing to be good, and to do good, as the best rejoinder we
                            could make, but had sued the Woodhulls for libel, the case would have been decided upon the
                            evidence adduced, and would have been definitively settled, pro or con. This
                            straight-forward course would have given general satisfaction. Whereas, arresting the
                            parties upon an entirely false issue of obscenity (of which every editor in America is
                            equally guilty), and then exacting enormously excessive bail, multiplying vexatious suits,
                            and actually imprisoning both male and female editors, " revered citizens," to whom
                            thousands of the people were hopefully looking as the possible future President and
                            Presidentess of the United States, has caused very many impartial observers to view the
                            proceedings with terror and alarm, as constituting one of the most direct assaults, by the
                            God-in-the-Constitution party, that has hitherto been made under the American Government.
                            And, after keeping these innocent-untilproved-guilty, talented men and women in loathsome
                            dungeons for months, awaiting trial, destroying their health (if not the life of one of
                            them), they proceeded, by highhanded Jeffrey's-like legal quibbles, to send one of them to
                            an insane asylum, by the merest arbitrary power of the court. The effect produced upon the
                            public mind, by these unusually cruel and tormenting measures, has been to create grave
                            doubts as to the innocence of the projectors of the prosecutions. Thanks are due to the just
                            Judge Blatchford, for thwarting the evil intended by the legal Orthodox prosecutors and
                            persecutors. Let us all be warned to keep the Gods of these people out of our Constitution,
                            lest a worse thing come upon us.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dr. Livingstone says that 'Schele' a famous African Chief, said to him..." TEIform="index"/>Dr. Livingstone says that 'Schele' a famous African Chief, said to him...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Dr. Livingstone says that " Schele" a famous African Chief, said to him, on the
                                    occasion of his preaching to his tribe," Do you imagine that these people will ever
                                    believe by your merely talking to them. ? I can make them do nothing except by
                                    thrashing them ; and, if you like, I will call my head men, and, with our whips of
                                    rhinoceros hide, we will soon make them all believe together."—"</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Dr. Livingstone lost and found" TEIform="index"/>Dr. Livingstone Lost and
                                Found.</bibl></cit></p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Livingstone" TEIform="persName"/></byline></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Despotism." TEIform="index"/>Despotism.</head><p TEIform="p"> The Shah of Persia, after dining with the Duke of Sunderland, and observing his immense
                            wealth, proposed, the next morning, to the Prince of Wales, to have the Duke beheaded, as
                            too powerful a subject for the safety of the Government. Being informed that it would not be
                            lawful, " Then," said he, " I would at least have his eyes put out."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Confession of sins" TEIform="index"/>CONFESSION OF SINS</head><p TEIform="p">There is, at the present time, great excitement, in England, upon the subject of confession
                            of sins. It has got into Parliament. Under the Church-and-State Government of England, the
                            Upper House — Lords temporal and spiritual — has the care of the souls and bodies of the
                            people. Their theology is still cut and dried to order, just as our orthodox priests are
                            hankering to cut and dry it for the people of America, Shakers included. Four hundred and
                            eighty-three priests have signed and sent to Parliament the following Petition: " That, in
                            view of the widespread and increasing use of sacramental confession, your .Right Reverend
                            House may consider the advisability of providing for the education, selection, and licensing
                            of duly-qualified confessors, in accordance with the provisions of canon law." Of course the
                            English objections to this are, first, The principle is anti-Protestant; second, That it
                            means Roman Catholic Church-andState, instead of " the Establishment." As things are going,
                            the Pope may pretty soon emigrate to England; unless Infidelity, Spiritualism, Rationalism,
                            and Shakerism, rise up as opposing powers, and saving influences. The logical end of
                            Protestantism is Catholicism. And, when they coalesce, all the above opposing powers will
                            also coalesce, and it will be the battle of " Gog and Magog around the camp of the saints."
                            Then the " unwalled villages " will have to be protected by fire from heaven — Divine
                            Spiritualism.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Art of newspaper making" TEIform="index"/>THE ART OF NEWSPAPER MAKING</head><p TEIform="p">Of all writings of man, none is so widely perused and critically examined as the newspaper;
                            and of all public characters, newspaper contributors mostly require diligence, energy, and
                            patient application. The necessity of giving variety to their articles, in length, and
                            subject, and style, creates a heavy draft upon the intellect. The articles must not be too
                            long, or they will weary, no matter how much thought expands, it must be contracted ; nor
                            how many ideas may suggest themselves, they must each be condensed into a narrow compass ;
                            the marrow of the subject must be extracted by patient toil, and served up in tiny morsels
                            to fastidious readers. They must not be too short, or some will complain that the subject is
                            not finished. They must not be too dry, or the fitful or careless mind will not read ; they
                            must not be too light, or the austere will turn from them with disgust. The language must
                            not be too learned, or it will shoot over the heads of the youth, the future strength of the
                            land ; it must not be too simple, or the self-styled learned will reject the pieces With
                            contempt. The style must be easy, flowing, or none will be pleased.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Temperance" TEIform="index"/>TEMPERANCE</head><p TEIform="p">In reply to a liquor dealer, who proclaimed, with an air of professional triumph, that he
                            "sold to decent people only, and that his business was highly respectable," a Quaker said, "
                            Friend, that is the most damning part of thy business. If thee would only sell to drunkards
                            and loafers, thee would help kill off the race, and society would be rid of them, But thee
                            takes the young, the poor, the innocent, and the unsuspecting, and makes drunkards and
                            loafers of them; and, when their character and money are gone, thee kicks them out, and
                            turns them over to other shops to be finished off; and thee ensnares others, and sends them
                            on in the same road to ruin." Surely the good Quaker had the best of the argument, for he
                            had facts on his side.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Menageries" TEIform="index"/>MENAGERIES</head><p TEIform="p">We wish we could send a word of warning to the towns which Barnum's show is to visit. There
                            travels with it a gang of pickpockets,sneak thieves, and burglars, for which, of course,
                            Barnum is not to blame, nevertheless these scoundrels accompany the exhibition, enter and
                            rob houses while the people are away to witness the parade, and in the crowds upon the
                            streets and around the tents they do a big business in taking purses from countrymen's
                            pockets. We reported a dozen cases last week, and probably didn't hear of half the cases of
                            pocket-picking that occurred. The show draws thousands of dollars from the pockets of the
                            communities where it is exhibited, and it is rather grinding to have the rest snatched by
                            thieves. Two or three visits of Barnum at this rate would be as unprofitable as a
                            destructive fire.— Saratogian.</p></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Signs of progress" TEIform="index"/>SIGNS OF PROGRESS</head><p TEIform="p">In the British House of Commons, on the 8th inst., Mr. Henry Richard, member for Merthyr
                            Tydvil, and Secretary of the London Peace Society, moved, That in the opinion of the House,
                            her Majesty's government should communicate with foreign powers for the purpose of improving
                            the international law, and with a view of establishing arbitration as a permanent resort for
                            the settlement of differences between nations. Mr. Richard, in a speech in support of his
                            motion, stated that he had received a large number of letters from America, expressing
                            sympathy with his proposition. He proceeded to show that danger of war kept four millions!
                            of men armed annually in Europe, rendering necessary a taxation of two thousand million
                            dollars, and payment of yearly interest on war debts of seven hundred and fifty millions. In
                            addition to this, the value of labor withdrawn from industry wag estimated to be twelve
                            hundred and fifty millions. In Germany conscription forced an emigration which was
                            depopulating the country, and Russia, France, and Italy were financially crippled by the
                            expense of their enormous military establishments. Mr. Gladstone opposed the motion. He
                            argued that it would defeat its own object, because continental nations held widely
                            different views on the subject. He asked the gentleman to withdraw the motion. Mr. Richard
                            declined to withdraw, a'nd the House divided. The division resulted in a tie — ninety-eight
                            yeas to ninetyeight nays. The Speaker gave his casting vote in favor of the motion, which
                            was adopted.</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Advertisement nuisance" TEIform="index"/>ADVERTISEMENT NUISANCE</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> Turn whichever way you may, and the printed or painted announcementof
                                    Squillgut's or some other eminent physician's syrup, purgative, or salve, greets the
                                    eye, in letters long, short, tall, extended or condensed, according to the
                                    opportunity the size of the fence-board gives for display. Every bridge in the town
                                    is plastered with the glaring advertisements of pills, balsams, lotions, remedies,
                                    oils,liniments and painkillers, utterly hiding the color the authorities thought
                                    appropriate for the structures, and making them frightful objects. Trees, stumps,
                                    rocks, and fences along every highway are em- blazoned with the names of bitters,
                                    plasters, ointments, purifiers, and cure-alls, and there is no place or no thing
                                    that the modest agents for these various compounds hesitate to appropriate for their
                                    purpose. The outer walls of our beautiful Academy of Music are pasted over with
                                    posters, telling the virtue of some windy decoction, and there isn't a rod of
                                    fence-board between the village and the cemetery that doesn't beg the mourning
                                    processions that go that way to use this, that, or the other relief from all the
                                    ills that flesh is heir to. We have nothing to say against the stuff advertised. It
                                    is one of the inalienable rights of the Yankee to get up patent medicines, and to
                                    sell them if he can find simpletons to buy them, but we do protest against this
                                    making such bad use of private or corporation property. We wish every fence owner,
                                    or owner of any other thing that is used for these announcements, would visit every
                                    paste brigade that uses them with the vengeance of the law, or compel them to
                                    obliterate their work. As for using the bridges for this business, we hope the
                                    selectmen will stop it at once, and make every offender hereafter feel the penalty
                                    which the statute provides.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Pittsfield Eagle" TEIform="index"/>Pittsfield Eagle</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Excitement over the 'Romanizing tendencies' of the Church of England..." TEIform="index"/>Excitement over the 'Romanizing tendencies' of the Church of England...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Excitement over the "Romanizing tendencies" of the Church of England has been growing
                            during the last week or two. On Monday, June 30, a large and influential meeting was held in
                            London to denounce the practice of confession in the Church. That meeting was called as a
                            protest against the petition of " 483 priests " to the Upper House of Convocation. </p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A Christian has advanced but a little way in religion when..." TEIform="index"/>A Christian has advanced but a little way in religion when...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> A Christian has advanced but a little way in religion when he has overcome the love of the
                            world; for he has still more powerful and importunate enemies; self, evil tempers, pride,
                            undue affections, a stubborn will. It is by the subduing of these adversaries that we must
                            chiefly judge of our growth in grace.</p></div2><pb n="69" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakeress: to the rescue" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERESS: TO THE RESCUE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">If there ever was a time in the history of our race, when honest, earnest workers were needed
                            in the field of reform, it is now. Never before were there so many momentous questions, and
                            of such vital importance, agitating the public mind at the same time. It was but yesterday,
                            as it were, that all the forces of the American nation were turned to war. Liberty and
                            Slavery met in open combat ; and history will reveal to unborn myriads, at what a fearful
                            sacrifice of human life and limb, with thousands of millions of wealth added thereto, the
                            Ethiopian chains were broken. Now, the sound of artillery from the gory battle-field has
                            ceased, the smoke is cleared away, and the camp-fires have died out; and thousands who were
                            clad in habiliments of mourning for fathers, sons, and brothers, slain in battle, have laid
                            them off, and other subjects engage their attention. The majority of the people at the
                            present time, are in the " broad road " of pleasure seeking ; and many, we regret to say,
                            seek it at the expense of honesty and virtue. There is also a large class of deep-thinking
                            men, and women too, who are eagle-eyed, and who have taken their stand upon certain
                            watch-towers, and they look at causes which, if carried into effect, they see, will
                            ultimately destroy the peace and welfare of individuals, and of the nation. The social,
                            sexual relation as it now exists, is filling the land with untold misery, and threatens to
                            depopulate the earth. Men and women look at the subject scientifically, and are alarmed!
                            Many feel that the time has fully come for the vail to be lifted, that light may shine upon
                            the hideous monster; and that the covering, which wealth and ingenuity combined have woven
                            to hide its deformity, may be torn off. But the question arises, where is the remedy ? It
                            was much easier for Milton to tell how paradise was lost, than to show how Jieaven could be
                            gained. Men " by searching," through natural wisdom and sagacity, may learn to comprehend
                            things below them ; and may study the great book of Nature, which is ever an open volume
                            before them; but a Divine revelation from the inner spiritual spheres is needed, to find and
                            apply a remedy that will be effective in removing the cause of the diseases engendered by
                            the violation of law, (whose name is legion) and to heal the waters of the great sea of
                            sexual impurity. The question of the Rights of Woman, firstly to her own person ; then the
                            God-given right to the elements of life (called property) equally with man, which are as
                            necessary to her existence as to Ms; also her right to co-operate with him in framing the
                            laws by which she is to be governed, and her much needed power and influence in sustaining
                            those laws, is becoming so apparent, and the tide of public opinion is running so high con-
                            cerning it, that we think the time cannot be far distant, when ignorance and superstition,
                            made strong by custom and common consent, must yield before the potent advancing truths upon
                            this subject. Progressive truth, whether relating to civil Polity, to Science, or Religion,
                            has always met with opposing forces ; and Reformers in every age have had to wrestle against
                            principalities and the ruling power of public opinion for a time ; and it would seem that
                            spirits who were imbued with the war element when they left this world, and who have not
                            risen out of that condition, but still remain in the lower spheres though in the spiritual
                            world, lend their aid to contending parties in this mundane sphere, who are striving to
                            block the wheels of progress. They may come in a false guise, and assume the appearance of a
                            lamb, or of an angel of light, and thus deceive the simplehearted ; while their real mission
                            and incentive to action, is to darken counsel, by smooth and persuasive argument, and to
                            perpetuate human slavery. Although the strong have failed in their purpose to oppress the
                            weak, and to continue to inthrall the souls and bodies of the African race, the same spirit
                            is rife to-day, and seeks to control the minds, and bind the consciences of men and women.
                            The founders of the American Government were providentially raised up to perform a great
                            work for humanity. It was not their mission to found a religious order. They were called
                            Infidels because they would not bow down and worship the Sectarians' God, and acknowledge
                            that their creeds and dogmas were an embodiment of the Divine essence. They saw that the
                            civil and ecclesiastical powers (combined) served to bind and fetter the consciences of
                            individuals, and to impede the laws of progress generally. And " horns"— power — was given
                            to them, with which they broke in pieces the hierarchy, and severed Church and State. They
                            emerged from the narrow sphere of sectarianism, and felt the universality of God's love and
                            goodness to all of his creatures; and that all had an equal right to the elements of
                            subsistence in this world, and an inherent right to worship God in accord with his or her
                            conscience, free from priestly rule. It was the burden of their minds to form a basis of
                            civil government so broad and strong, and so j ust in principle, that all nations, kindreds,
                            and colors, whether religious or irreligious, Jew or Gentile, might find a home, and be free
                            from religious intolerance, and that would be invulnerable to political storms that might
                            arise, and from the subtle invasions of priestcraft. And now, what do we see and feel ?
                            Unclean spirits like frogs are coming forth from the mouth of the dragon, and from the mouth
                            of false prophets, under the sanctimonious sacerdotal robe, to invade the religious rights
                            of the people: And this element is working (like leaven) in the commonwealth, throughout the
                            American nation to-day. If they succeed in grafting the name of their God and their Christ
                            into the Constitution of the United States, then will they re-unite Church and State, and
                            join together what the God of universal love and justice, through his own agencies has put
                            asunder; and will therebj kindle anew the persecutors' fire—open the way to the gibbet and
                            the rack—and fill dungeons with heretics, as in the past! " Cry aloud, and spare not," O ye
                            lovers of truth and liberty, lest this great evil come upon us If you cannot be a great
                            river, bearing great vessels of blessings to tne world, you can be a little spring by the
                            dusty wayside of life, singing merrily all day and all night, and giving a cup of cold water
                            to every weary, thirsty one who passes by.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Setting sun" TEIform="index"/>SETTING SUN</head><p TEIform="p">Who can behold the splendor of the setting sun reflecting its golden rays upon the face of
                            nature, when clad in its most lovely attire, without feeling grateful emotions ? Every tree,
                            plant, and flower, bespeak the love and goodness of the Creator to his creature man. The
                            sweet songsters which so fearlessly hover around our lawns and dwellings, fill the calm,
                            clear atmosphere with their warbling music ; and, at times, they seem like little messengers
                            sent from angel-spheres to enliven and cheer our pleasant, quiet home below, and to inspire
                            us to open our vision to the realities and beauties of our final home in the land of souls.
                            If at even-tide, when the labors of the day are past, we can look upon the setting sun with
                            such pleasurable sensations, and with a confiding trust that another day will dawn— that the
                            sun of the morrow will rise to warm and vivify the earth—what will be the Chris- tians'
                            confidence and hope when they shall have passed through the conflicts of life, and when
                            their earthly pilgrimage is about to end, and they feel that the sun of their earthly
                            existence is going down, and life's evening shadows are gathering around them ? If they can
                            then look upon the record of the past, and see that their lives have been fraught with noble
                            deeds of charity, benevolence, and virtue, and that, under the guidance of Gospel
                            principles, they have helped to bear aloft the standard of Truth, will they not feel a
                            bright hope in the future, and have a full assurance that, in the heavenly land to which
                            they are going, and where they have laid up immortal treasures, there are expansive fields,
                            and beautiful groves, filled with the harmonious music of spheres divine 1 Purity,
                            Innocence, Peace, and Joy, are the virtues which adorn those regions; they are more
                            enduring, and more fragrant, than the flowers which beautify our earthly home. For the
                            flowers of earth, at best, are only symbolical of the lovely graces which bloom in the
                            garden of God, and ornament his spiritual temple. Truth is the Rock upon which the Temple of
                            the Lord is being built; and all intelligent souls who love and do the truth, help to form
                            this Temple, which is composed of " living stones." In conclusion, I will add, that from the
                            age of fifteen to sixty-five years, I have been striving, by a practical life of
                            self-denial, to be so nearly allied to goodness and truth, as to be counted worthy to occupy
                            a small space in God's holy temple. This life of consecration, has brought sweet contentment
                            to my spirit; and the heavenly breezes which are borne from the celestial clime, are
                            refreshing and soul-reviving. I feel peace while reviewing the past; and am now enjoying a
                            foretaste of the joys of the " better land !" The blessing of visible and invisible friends
                            falls upon me like a morning dew upon opening flowers. While bright the evening suu
                            descends, 'Mid rays of golden hue, I think, how soon my sun of life To earth must bid adieu.
                            Reflections peaceful, calm, serene! No " sting of death " I dread ; My spirit, borne on
                            angel •wings, Is upward, onward, led. For angel purity will lead The soul that seeks her
                            power, On to the rest that doth remain Within her fadeless bower. 0 happy thought! Who would
                            refuse The kindly proffer'd hand, To bear, through shades and toils of life, On to the
                            heavenly land? Hail! Angel guide to heav'nly life, Thy precepts are Divine; The laurels of a
                            lasting peace Thy foll'wers' brows entwine : Simplicity is ever found Wher'e'er thy hand
                            doth rest: In thy protection's holy sphere, The soul is truly blest. 1 sought thee early,
                            found thy care, Beneath the sacred dome, Where hearts and hands, united, join To form a
                            happy home. 8HAKEEE8S. 69 <pb n="70" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 7O A.ISTI3 With kindred friends, the balm of
                            life Was to my spirit giv'n ; With them I've shared the joy and love Which cometh down from
                            Heaven. I sought thee early, found thy prize, Within the lovely bower, Where oft the Saviour
                            calls his flock To spend devotion's hour : 'Tis there the way of life is taught, And there
                            thy blessings pour; 'Twas there I made my faithful vows To serve thee evermore. Methinks I
                            hear a question breathed, In accents deep and low, Where may we find this pleasant bower,
                            This rest of God below ? Not, I reply, amid the walks Of grandeur, pomp, and pride ; Nor at
                            the shrine of selfishness, As Jesus testified. But self-denial, and the cross, Forsaking
                            ev'ry sin, And father, mother, houses, land,— The very life within : Yea, more; the husband,
                            wife, and child : Break all the ties they hold, And God will bless the sacrifice With gifts
                            a hundred fold. The Saviour own'd no earthly bond. Who were his kindred ? They Who sought to
                            do his Father's will, And wTalk'd the narrow way.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Crosman, Abigail" TEIform="persName"/>Eldress Abigail Crosman, Grovdand, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Eldress Antoinette, Editress" TEIform="index"/>ELDRESS ANTOINETTE, EDITRESS</head><p TEIform="p">Desiring to add a few lines to your columns, I am impressed by an oft-recurring objection to
                            our faith by those who partly, and only imperfectly, understand our religious tenets. Many
                            aver that our system militates against itself; and that if all the world should become
                            converted to a virgin life, it would exterminate the race, or, as is often expressed, " run
                            the world out." Admitted ! To any reflecting, investigating mind, I would say, Come and let
                            us reason together, as a man (or woman) would reason with a friend. Perchance, you are a
                            Christian advocate, and believe in Jesus Christ, the Saviour of the world, as firmly as do
                            the Shakers, and would think it amiss for any one to misconstrue his words, and lead others
                            into error by explaining them in a wrong manner. Some affect to believe that the Shakers are
                            adverse to generation per se, and stand in antagonism thereto, because of their oft-repeated
                            denunciations of a worldly, sinful life, and their seeking to reform the natural, social
                            system. Your objection is always presented wherever the principles of our faith are made
                            manifest. Christ, in his teachings to his disciples, being questioned upon this subject,
                            said unto them, "All men cannot receive this saying, save they to whom it is given." (See
                            Matt., xix.) And, while he did not condemn generation,he taught a higher and more perfect
                            way ; for this purpose came he into the world. So long as mortals are content, and
                            soul-satisfied, to live after the similitude of the first Adam, without" seek- ing, that
                            they may find," the higher life, so long will they be left uncalled. God is willing to wait
                            for his creatures ; Christ is willing to wait; still offering and inviting souls to come to
                            him. But, when they become sin-sick, and weary of a worldly life, and cry, in the depths of
                            their souls, " Good Master, what shall I do to inherit eternal life," then will they hear
                            the voice of the Son of God, and be taught how to forsake the world and " follow the Lamb
                            whithersoever he goeth." Again, saith the Saviour : " He that will save his life, shall lose
                            it; and whosoever shall lose his life for my sake, shall find it;" for the life of the
                            natural man must be rejected, in order to follow Christ in the regeneration, and find a
                            spiritual life in him. Is it consistent with the workings of the Divine Spirit that all
                            should be converted at one and the same time ? Is it likely to occur in any one of the
                            Christian Churches of the present day ? While humanity exists, opinions will differ ; and
                            they alone are right and safe who take for their guide to heavenly light and peace the life
                            and teachings of our Saviour, Jesus Christ. Let us take a simile. Compare the spiritual
                            organism of the immortal mind, with a beautiful orange grove. Should any one with common
                            mental endowments reach forth the hand, and pluck the fruit in its first opening blossom, or
                            in its green and unripe condition, though it may have reached its full size, yet wanting the
                            rich flavor of the ripe, sweet and luscious orange, we should at once style him non compos
                            mentis who would insist that all the fruit of the grove should be gathered at one time,
                            whether in blossom, in the bud, or in any of its imperfect conditions, and thus lay waste
                            the entire grove ! On the contrary, would not the careful fruit-grower often inspect his
                            beautiful trees, selecting only the ripe and mellow, plucking it carefully and placing it
                            where it might subserve a better purpose ; and so continue doing, until all the fruit was
                            gathered in its proper time and season ? Yea, verily. In this way will each individual, when
                            properly prepared for it, be gathered from the worldly elements ; and it matters not whether
                            he had been removed from time in infancy or old age, as the immortal life is commenced with
                            the body's first respiration, and the frail tenement which holds the spirit for a time, does
                            not prevent its onward and upward tendency. Souls may continue in the body until they become
                            centenarians, and within the hearing of the Gospel of Christ, and yet, like the an- cient
                            Jews, disbelieve his mission: " Seeing, they do not see : Hearing, they do not hear nor
                            understand " the Word of Life, until they become fitted by Divine Intelligence to receive
                            the Holy Spirit, the Dove from heaven, and the voice of the Son of God, speaking to their
                            souls, convincing them that to them the " end of the world has come; " and that henceforth,
                            they must give up the worldly life, and seek the life in Christ. And having received faith
                            that God has called them to his work—the work of redemption — which brings conviction for
                            sin, and enables them, through an honest confession of the same, to rise in the resurrection
                            of life, thus becoming " new creatures; old things " pertaining to the carnal life, " being
                            done away." Your queries, though perfectly consistent with natural reasoning, reminds one of
                            a bright and intelligent school girl in her rudiments, puzzled with a mystical mathematical
                            problem. Advancing to her teacher, with book and slate in hand, she insisted that the
                            compiler of the work had made a mistake, she was sure of it, for she had tried it in every
                            way, and could not bring the correct answer. Seeing her despairing looks, and knowing that
                            she had toiled in vain, her teacher said pleasantly, " sit down, please, and I will assist
                            you." A few figures sufficed to enlighten her understanding ; she had made the mistake, and
                            with an animated countenance, she caught the pencil, saying " I see it now,v and commenced
                            to figure in earnest, and soon obtained the desired result. And thus, it seems to me, many
                            are inclined to misunderstand the Scriptures, and the call of mercy to their souls, and
                            believe that the Saviour has made a mistake. They think Christ could not have meant
                            precisely what he said, when he taught his disciples that " If any man will come after me,
                            let him deny himself, take up his daily cross and follow me." And, " whosoever shall do the
                            will of God, the same is my brother, and sister, and Mother." He surely did not mean that we
                            must forsake our near relatives, those connected to us by the ties of consanguinity, and
                            cleave to those only who are of like faith with himself, in order to become his disciples
                            and walk with him. We may delight in, and enjoy the worldly life, if we love Christ the
                            best. Thus reasons the human heart while bound in nature. I ask, in what respect do the
                            children of this world differ from the first advent of our Saviour ? Is there any material
                            change, except in civilization, arts and science ? Are not the Jews, Hindoos and Mahometans
                            in the same progressive scale ? Where is the distinction ? Do they not all marry and give in
                            marriage after the form and fashion of their respective countries ? It is so, and it is
                            well! With such we have no controversy. Still, we think no one will infer that all or any of
                            them are the true followers of Christ. In the Adamic life he set no example. He taught the
                            higher and more angelic life. Do the professing Christians of the present day " forsake all
                            for Christ's sake and the Gospel," any more than mankind have ever done ? Or, do they
                            interpret the teachings of our blessed Saviour to suit their own life and pur- poses, and
                            fear to "read the writing on the wall," lest it should cut them off from their idols, and
                            oblige them to seek the life in. Christ, that they may be saved ? Christ did, indeed, come
                            into the world, to teach the way, the truth, and the life, to all who believe in him. But is
                            it rational, is it consistent, to suppose that all who will ever believe in Jesus Christ, as
                            their Saviour, will receive the call in this life, when departures from mortality are
                            momentarily occurring, and millions enter eternity before the God-given faculty of reason
                            has ascended her throne, or they know the right hand from the left ? And are not millions,
                            who now inhabit the earth, doomed to continue in ignorance, as well as those who have passed
                            away, having lived out the natural length of time allotted to man, without ever having heard
                            the sound of the Christian religion ? And are they not all God's creatures? and will they
                            not ultimately find rest in some of the many " mansions in the Father's house," and accept
                            the terms of salvation, granted by the Gospel of Christ, when they are willing to receive it
                            — and are anxious to " come up out of deep tribulation, and wash their robes and make them
                            white in the blood (or life) of the Lamb ? " How transcendent and blissful the thought!
                            Christ, in his first advent to earth, had but few followers, and of them, one proved a
                            traitor, and another, through fear of persecution, denied his Lord, though he stood before
                            the world, the living embodiment of the Christ Principle, declaring his mission to earth to
                            be of God, his Father. Was his ministry accepted by the masses? Nay, in no wise! Only the
                            few were ready to receive him : And he—this Messenger of God—was derided, insulted, and
                            slain. Does this not show that poor frail humanity is difficult to be convinced, and slow to
                            believe ? Faith is given to those who ask, and are willing to receive it, and " to no
                            others." " Two may be in the field, or grinding in the mill, the one taken, and the other
                            left," until he too shall be convinced that Christ has appeared again, without sin, unto
                            salvation, creating all things anew, (in his heart.) Then will he exclaim in the earnestness
                            of his soul," I see it now," and will sell all that he has of a worldly, carnal life, to
                            purchase the "pearl of great price," even the salvation of his soul. Thus reviewing the
                            subject, the sophistry and fallacious reasoning of non-believers, have no more weight than
                            if the same person should affirm, that, because he sees a loaf of bread, there will be no
                            more grain raised. The idea is analogous to saying that because a few have chosen the virgin
                            Christ life, it must consequently run the world out. " Strait is the gate, and narrow is the
                            way that leadeth unto life, and few there be that find it." " The Shakers (a name given by
                            their persecutors) do not worship the person of any man or woman ; but purely the Christ
                            Spirit; though mention is often made of the first Medium through whom this saving Gospel was
                            preached to us ; and the devotional Spirit of the Believer in Christ's Second Appearing, as
                            quickly reverts to our Saviour Jesus Christ as to our Mother Ann. They stand as
                            Representatives of the Father and Mother Spirits of the New Creation (Wisdom and Love),
                            attracting and holding the children of the Resurrection, subjects of the New Birth.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="White, Aurelia" TEIform="persName"/>Aurelia White, Watervliet, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Episcopalian, commenting on the folly of a war..." TEIform="index"/>The Episcopalian, commenting on the folly of a war...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The Episcopalian, commenting on the folly of a war establishment, remarks , " How many
                            millions of waste of material and money, now consumed in the manufacture of war material and
                            in the support of standing armies would be saved ! What a multitude of idle officers and
                            soldiers would be liberated to increase the wealth of the country !"</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ex." TEIform="persName"/></byline></div2><pb n="71" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My offering" TEIform="index"/>MY OFFERING</head><p TEIform="p">I OFFEit a few expressions of love and affection to my Gospel friends, with whom I love to
                            commune, whether they are in the visible form, or have passed to the inner spheres. Their
                            influence aids me along on life's journey, and is a solace in the hour of adversity, and a
                            guide in prosperity. The ties that are formed between earthly connections are frail and
                            unreliable; but those which are formed by living in obedience to truth, are invincible; they
                            are true in life, and death cannot sever them; but they will continue to grow stronger as we
                            progress in the spirit spheres. I own a heavenly Parentage, and rejoice in the beautiful
                            relation that I hold to them, and to my faithful brethren and sisters of the household of
                            faith; and with them I am privileged to leave the lofty hills of pride and self-indulgence
                            (where is continual unrest), and descend into the low valley of humility, and work in the
                            Lord's vineyard, and cultivate the flowers of innocence and peace, while we eat of the fruit
                            of the tree of life, and drink from the wells of salvation; and here the guiding star of
                            purity sheds a halo of light over our pathway as we journey on. Here, dear Gospel friends,
                            let us faithfully perform all our vows, and never be willing to sell our birthright for the
                            vain pleasures of time, for what will they avail the soul ? Were we to climb to the eminence
                            of worldly honor, gain wealth, and win the laurels of fame, it would only serve to bewilder
                            and dizzy the mind; it would not insure a safe passport to a heavenly home, nor would it fit
                            us to stem the strong current of temptation, or to ride over the billows of the sea of time,
                            or to meet the incoming tide from the boundless deep which rolls from the shore of the
                            eternal world. But, if we choose our inheritance with those who fear God and work
                            righteousness, and walk humbly before Him, performing deeds of charity and love, " binding
                            up the wounded spirit, comforting the afflicted, giving drink to the thirsty, and washing
                            the saints' feet;"— then we shall look back upon a well spent life, and feel that we have
                            justly earned the treasures of immortal glory, and are worthy to be numbered with the jewels
                            of Christ's kingdom ; while they who place their affections upon earthly things, and regale
                            themselves with vain pleasures, will, in the end, find bitter disappointment.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Jones, Phebe A." TEIform="persName"/>Phebe A. Jones, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Freedom" TEIform="index"/>FREEDOM</head><p TEIform="p">It is a time-honor'd custom with the American nation, to celebrate the anniversary day, when
                            her people were declared to be free and independent. Upon such occasions, the booming of
                            canons, the ringing of bells, and almost every conceivable noise is heard from city, town,
                            and hamlet, to show forth the great joy of the inhabitants that America is a free land —free
                            to the home-born, and to the stranger. Great enthusiasm usually prevails at such times, and
                            a majority of the people, from hoary age to lisping infancy, seem to partake of it, and feel
                            that it is such a glorious thing to be free. Would it not be well to pause amid the
                            rapturous, and often times tumultuous shout of Liberty, and ask the question, Are we really
                            free f The little maxim reads, " Let no man call himself free, who is enslaved by any
                            passion." Where shall we find a man, woman, or child, who is not bound to some bad habit, or
                            fast becoming so—habits ruinous to body or mind, or both ? True liberty is found in the
                            truth. Those whom " truth makes free, are free indeed." Not free from physical tyranny and
                            servitude merely, but free to become elevated in mind and feeling, released from injurious
                            customs, redeemed from bad habits, and free to rise into a moral and spiritual atmosphere.
                            Then we may rejoice, and sing of the blessings of true Freedom, as do the Angels in heaven.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Neal, Emma J." TEIform="persName"/>Emma J. Neal, Mount Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If sensuality were happiness..." TEIform="index"/>If sensuality were happiness...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">If sensuality were happiness, beasts were happier than men; but human felicity is lodged in
                            the soul, not in the flesh.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Plain dressing for meetings" TEIform="index"/>PLAIN DRESSING FOR MEETINGS</head><p TEIform="p">The house of prayer is a poor place to exhibit beads, ribbons, ruffles, gewgaws, and
                            trinkets. The evils of such vanity and extravagance are many. It keeps people from meeting
                            when they have not apparel as gorgeous as their neighbors. It loads the poor with burdens
                            too heavy to be borne, to procure fashionable clothing. It leads many into temptation, debt,
                            dishonesty, and sin. It causes many a poor shop-girl to work nearly all of Saturday night,
                            that some customer's fine clothes may be ready for Sunday show. It keeps people at home in
                            cloudy or stormy weather, when, if they wore plain clothing, they could defy clouds and
                            storms. It consumes the morning hour in dressing, crimping, and fussing, keeping people away
                            from worship, wasting time, exhausting strength, hindering the reading of the Scriptures,
                            and making the day of rest a day of toil and folly. It makes the poor emulous, malicious,
                            and envious; and sows many a bitter thought in the minds of children and others, when they
                            see their neighbors decked in finery,—often not paid for,— and feel that people are
                            respected, not for the value of their characters, but for the vanity of their clothes. It
                            causes many a frivolous, trifling mind to forget God, and Christ, and the Gospel, and to
                            spend the hour appointed for religious service in comparing garments, studying fashions, and
                            arranging their own gay attire. It causes vanity in the rich, and murmuring in the poor. It
                            wastes the Lord's money that is needed for other uses, and should be applied to more noble
                            and important ends. It leads the young in the path of pride, gratifying the lust of the eye,
                            cultivating an extravagant taste, justifying attire, and seducing to the paths of shame and
                            ruin, many a poor girl who might have lived an honored and virtuous life, had she never
                            known or been led to think that she was beautiful, nor desired more finery than she could
                            honestly earn, nor decked herself out in such a way as would attract the attention of
                            libertines and seducers. This style of dress degrades the taste of society toward the level
                            of those Hottentots, wild Indians, and African savages, whose chief delights are war-paint,
                            feathers, rings, spangles, rag-roses, buttons, beads, and bugles —¦ things which are as
                            repugnant to a refined and cultivated taste as they are contrary to the spirit and letter of
                            the Holy Scriptures. Let us dress plainly before the Lord, for economy's sake, for example's
                            sake, for decency's sake — for Christ's sake.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hastings, H. L." TEIform="persName"/>H. L. Hastings</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Angel eyes" TEIform="index"/>ANGEL EYES</head><p TEIform="p">We often think of angel eyes That watch us here below, Of spirit friends — the good and wise,
                            Who light the path we go. They lift for us the mystic veil, That in vision we may see, The
                            beauteous scenes that will not fail In blest eternity. They sing for us seraphic strains Of
                            yonder peaceful shore; And show to us the golden gains Of heaven's garner'd store. And, with
                            rejoicing, make us feel The strength of angel love, That lifts the soul, through faith and
                            zeal, To brighter spheres above. Where love, unmix'd with earth's alloy, Pure as the
                            Mother's own, Crowns dear departed ones with joy, In their celestial home. We love those
                            blessed angel eyes, That search us through and through, And read the heart's intents, as
                            well As actions that we do. They would, in love, our souls baptize, And be our guardian
                            friends ; They listen to our earnest cries, Which oft to heaven ascend.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Johnson, Julia" TEIform="persName"/>Julia Johnson, Hancock, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Petition" TEIform="index"/>PETITION</head><p TEIform="p">Lord, give me power myself to know ; I seek not earth's delusive show, But all I ask, while
                            here below, Is what the Gospel gives me. Inspire my heart with love supreme, That flows from
                            Zion's living stream, Whose virtues will my soul redeem, Of every fault relieve me. Though
                            friends should fail, or foes betray, There's light enough in this pure way To lead my soul
                            to realms of day, And thither I'll be going. I'll brave the breakers, stem the tide, Though
                            billows rise on every side ; Iti God's sure promise I'll confide, While boist'rous winds are
                            blowing. O God of heaven, hear my prayer, And let me rest beneath thy care, My soul from
                            judgment never spare, Let holy Angels guide me. Assist me to be just and true In all I say,
                            and all I do ; Each day my vows to thee renew, Whatever may betide me. O, help my soul to
                            stand the test Of this pare Gospel's high behest, That I may be by angels blest For every
                            good endeavor. O, grant me wisdom, strength, and power, To guard my spirit every hour, To
                            toil in sunshine, shade and shower, To keep the truth forever. O holy Saviour, pure and
                            just, Thy sacred name I love and trust; To follow thee, I know I must Accept each gift
                            that's given. Thy soul redeeming power I crave, To bear me o'er life's rolling wave, As
                            Peter cried, O Lord, do save, And guide me on to heaven. Earth's children find a vale of
                            tears, But Virtue's pathway bright appears : It leads the soul to higher spheres, Where
                            flows life's healing river. O, there with myriad saints I'll be, Adorn'd with virgin purity;
                            And there, to all eternity, Bless God the boui.dless Giver.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Chamberlain, Harriet F." TEIform="persName"/>Harriet F. Chamberlain, Pleasant Hill, Ky.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>HOME</head><p TEIform="p">0 HOME, blest home, where friends sincere, Life's weary pathway bless and cheer ! Where all
                            harmoniously combine, In purity and love divine. Naught can compare with such a home, In
                            palace fair, or splendid dome! Here true contentment fills the heart, And holy joy to each
                            impart. Though they renounce all carnal ties, And worldly pleasures sacrifice, They find
                            that tranquil peace of mind Which is to heaven-born souls assign'd. They seek no laurels of
                            renown, No earthly coronet or crown ; But, in the heavenly spheres above, They're clothed
                            with innocence and love. 1 love this quiet, peaceful home, Nor do I ever wish to roam, To
                            seek for bliss in worldly gain, Or glittering honors to obtain. Here true confiding friends
                            abide, Whose love no sorrows can divide : O give to me while here I plod, A Shaker home — a
                            Home in God.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sears, Elizabeth" TEIform="persName"/>Elizabeth Sears, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Polygamy" TEIform="index"/>POLYGAMY</head><p TEIform="p">A Petition for the legalizing of Polygamy in Massachusetts, numerously signed by the un-
                            married women of Lowell, has been presented to the Legislature. It states the fact of the
                            excess of females over males, as a principal reason for this Petition. In ancient times,
                            Moses, agreeably with the practices of the Eastern nations, permitted Polygamy, as a
                            secondary evil, because of man's lusts. Brigham Young assigns the same causes for its
                            existence in Utah. Is it, or is it not, better for a nation's posterity, that it practices
                            plurality of wives, provided that they otherwise observe natural laws in reproduction, than
                            that they should do as do the Gentile Christians, " who walk after the flesh " ? is an
                            unanswered question. Those who live in generation should cease to call themselves Christians
                            ; and those who call themselves Christians, should cease from " the works of the flesh,"
                            including reproduction.</p></div2><pb n="72" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prayer and praise" TEIform="index"/>PRAYER AND PRAISE</head><p TEIform="p">(Sentiment taken from Fifth Psalm.) 1. Tin to my words, O Lord, give ear, My meditation heed,
                            While lowly bow'd in sacred fear, Thy strength my soul doth need; 2. My voice, O God, in
                            morning light, I will direct in pray'r, Guide thou my wand'ring thoughts aright, And shield
                            me by thy care; O, hearken when to Thee I cry, Thou art my hope and stay, I feel Thy Though
                            tempting snares my path be set Steadfast my faith shall be, Thy promise spirit drawing nigh,
                            When unto Thee I pray. I will not forget, But look for help from Thee. In wickedness and
                            vanity No pleasure dost Thou show, No evil thing shall dwell with Thee, All wrong Thou wilt
                            o'erthrow; The false shall not stand in Thy sight, The nattering tongue thou't bind, For
                            truth with clear and glowing light Will search the heart and mind. 4. Those who rebel
                            against Thy law, And in defiance sin, Upon their souls true judgment draw, And feel its pang
                            within ; But as for me I'll seek a place Within God's house of prayer, Where dwelleth mercy,
                            truth and grace, My soul shall worship there. Within Thy temple songs of praise Shall
                            evermore resound, In anthems sweet my voice I'll raise For blessings that abound ; Let them
                            rejoice that in Thee trust, And shout in songs of joy, Thou ever wilt defend the just Who
                            evil works destroy. Those who Thy name adore and love, Shall sound a joyful strain, As they
                            advance to realms above, Away from earth's low plane; Thy favor to the righteous show, O
                            Lord be thou their shield, Till they Thy perfect life shall know, In endless light
                        reveal'd.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lament" TEIform="index"/>LAMENT</head><p TEIform="p">Impressed ~by a Sister who (prematurely) died at 28. —o— I reached this comma, in the
                            continuity of life, Ere it was noon. I could not longer hold the body to the strife. Hence,
                            left too soon. I had fondly hoped to reach earth life's fruition Full ripe with days; I feel
                            a sense of premature transition To life's second phase. My twenty-eight should be transposed
                            to eightytwo, Soul growth to gain ; My work is left for other hands to do — My earthly claim
                            ; My body poor, depleted— wan imagery of God — Served not the soul. My spirit, striving with
                            this broken rod, Fail'd of life's goal. When all of Nature's laws are rightly understood,
                            And well obeyed ; When life shall culminate in man or womanhood, N( r ills invade ; When the
                            ripe sheaf displays earth's full bequest, With noble deeds; When the developed spirit bids
                            the clay to rest, And from it speeds ; Then, casting back upon a well-till'd field, Full
                            fourscore years; Then will earth's fruitage, ripe, full harvest yield To higher spheres ;
                            Then shall the new earth effect a nobler generation For work in time ; Then the new heavens
                            will hail the transmutation To life divine. I once believed all angels of celestial birth
                            And all divine, My retrospection finds them first on earth, Mortals in time. When first I
                            learned their origin was human, Progressing higher, Then marvel'd I this compromise 'twixt
                            bird and woman, Which men admire. I long to see inherent laws redeem'd from degradation,
                            Bodies symmetrical and sound, And moral justice to abound, The intellect with wisdom
                            crown'd, Pure spirits hallowing all around, Proclaiming The Millennium's found—the new
                            creation. Then this depicture will not be in vain, If its portrayal count to human gain; For
                            naught but love's pure wreath can bind The human to the heavenly kind.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, Elijah" TEIform="persName"/>Elijah Myrick</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Save, lord!" TEIform="index"/>SAVE, LORD!</head><p TEIform="p">As Jesus was rock'd on the breast of the billow, And roused by the voice of despair from his
                            pillow, When fierce raging tempest left no hope to cherish, Came the entreating cry, " Save,
                            Lord, or we perish." At his word the wind ceased, and the storm was allay'd, Then the raging
                            sea, hush'd, in still calm was array'd, The faint-hearted marvel'd at his power of will, Who
                            stretch'd forth his hand with the mandate "Be still." While they stood around him, all
                            trembling and tearful, He gently reproved them with "Why are ye. fearful?" And look'd on
                            them with pity, and ask'd for their faith. Is not that the sure safeguard in life and in
                            death ? "Save, Lord, or we perish;" wild torrents are streaming, And o'er the dark waves the
                            red light, too, is gleaming. Lord, send forth thy Spirit, thy creatures to save, And rebuke
                            the destroyer abroad on the wave. O, save from the perils of passion now raging, For sin
                            unto mortals a great war is waging; O, impart to their hearts a new faith to cherish, And
                            teach them the prayer, "Save, Lord, or we perish!"</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Witham, Maria" TEIform="persName"/>Maria Witham, Enfield, Conn.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Aritficial stimulant" TEIform="index"/>ARTIFICIAL STIMULANT</head><p TEIform="p">I have a stimulant within, Which supersedes all other. It is not coffee, tea, or wine ; It is
                            to love each other. This love does stimulate the mind— Inspires to keep good order: In this
                            I daily comfort find ; My conscience the rewarder. I have a stimulant within. It is a living
                            spirit, Which shuns the ways of guilt and sin This blessing I inherit. Yea, I have food some
                            know not of,— Not always need of stuffing: I keep my conscience undefiled, And have no use
                            for puffing.* *The filthy, poisonous weed— Tobacco. Lord, stimulate me to do rightBe ever in
                            my duty ; Make thy commandments my delight: Thy ways are ways of beauty. I want this
                            stimulant within, And be alive in spirit; Not satisfied to live in sin ; That I thy care may
                            merit Be thou my guide in all I do ; O prosper and protect me, Until at length I travel
                            through ; And through my head direct me. This stimulant I'll still retain,— Be wide awake,
                            and stirring : True, and thy subject will remain, Nor be among the erring. Let me not be a
                            sleepy drone, Half dead whilst I am living : Nay! with the saints I will be one, And all I
                            have be giving. No artificial stimulant Is needed to enliven The soul who has forsaken all—
                            Who for the truth is striving.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Kulp, J. S." TEIform="persName"/>J. S. Kulp, Pleasant Hill, Ky.</byline></div2><div2 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is a fearful mistake to curtain and blind windows..." TEIform="index"/>It is a fearful mistake to curtain and blind windows...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">It is a fearful mistake to curtain and blind windows so closely for fear of injuring the
                            furniture by exposure to the sun's rays, that rooms positively gather disease by reason of
                            darkness.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tobacco-chewing habit" TEIform="index"/>Tobacco-chewing habit
                            </head><p TEIform="p">On Tuesday, Feb. 20th, 1873, Died, by the power of truth, and for the cause of Human
                                lledemption, at the Young Believers' Order, Mt. Lebanon, in the following much-beloved
                                Brethren, the TOBACCO-CHEWING HABIT, aged respectively, In D. S-, 51 years' duration. In
                                CM.,5T " In A. G., 15 " In T. S., 36 " In OLIVER PRENTISS, - 71 " In L. S., 45 " In H.
                                C, 53 In C. K., 12 No funeral ceremonies, no mourners, no graveyard ; but an honorable
                                record thereof made in 1 the Court above. Ed.</p></div3></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>