<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm0804" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title><editor role="editor" TEIform="editor"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/></editor></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">36</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">N. A. Briggs</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">8</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">4</biblScope><date value="18780401" TEIform="date">April 1878</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">78-102</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="8" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="4" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--                 <pb id="p1"/>
                        <p> APRIL. CO Cts. per Annum, POST PAID. THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. (OFFICIAL MONTHLY.) PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES.
                        1878. PUBLISHED AND PRINTED AT SHAKER VILLAGE, N. H. N. A. BRIGGS, Publisher. Vol. VIII. NO. 4. OUR HOME AT
                        WATERVLIET, N. Y. "GO PREACH THE KINGDOM OF GOD." <pb id="p2"/> CONTENTS. Shaker System . . . . 75 Is it consistent
                        for Christians to fight? . Teachings of the Shaker Manifesto 80 Indians No. 3. ..... 81 Materialization . ..._...
                        .8.0 What is, and what should be life . . 84 Such is Prayer .... 84 Good Morning ..... 90 Should all be Shakers? ...
                        92 Editorial Notes..... 93 Real Hells .... 95 For the Children .... 95 Slander ...... 85 j Farm & Garden
                        .... 98 Ann Lee . . . . . .86 Obituary......98 The Heaven & Hell of Universalists . 87 j Music......99
                        Soliloquy......88 ! Home Topics.....101 TERMS OF ADVERTISING. For one inch, one insertion $ 1. 00 " one half column,
                        " $ 3. 00 one " " " $ 6. 00 page, " " $ 12.00 Continued insertion for three months, 20 per ct. discount. " six " 25
                        " " " one year, 33£ " " Subscriptions, Sixty cents, per year. Address, N. A. Briggs, Shaker Village, Mer. Co., N. H.
                        Subscription ivill begin when order is received.—No back numbers.</p>--><pb n="78" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><p TEIform="p">THE SHAKER MAIIFESTO AN OFFICIAL MONTHLY. G. A. LOMAS Editor. Shakers, N. Y. VOL.
                        VIII.—APRIL. 1878.—No. IV. </p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker system" TEIform="index"/>SHAKER SYSTEM</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName">Elder F. W. Evans</persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> The first thought arising in my mind upon reading some well written editorials of recent
                            date assuming that the Shaker system, however good, would only reform man by exterminating
                            man, is, what is the Shaker system of ideas and principles? The world in which we live is a
                            large world, containing many nations, each nation many sects and peo- ple. Is it the Shaker
                            idea and faith that all of these should become ascetics— celibates—Shakers? It is not. What,
                            then, is the "Shaker system" that they, as religionists, would aim to inaugurate ? It is the
                            God system of sowing and reaping the human race. The harvest is the end of the world— and
                            the end of the world is the harvest of mankind. Two distinct and dissimilar operations—two
                            orders—result from the innate inevitable condition of humanity. The civil government of a
                            nation, which, according to Shaker religious faith, should be dual—male and female—to begin
                            with. Woman and man citizens, equal in wants, duties and functions, conjointly making the
                            laws, and unitedly administering them. But, as no two things can exist in one and the same
                            place at the same time— so neither can men and women occupy in two families—the private
                            family and the public family—at one and the same time. The man or woman who has a private
                            family to care for, cannot neglect that duty without being worse than an infidel—to some
                            false theology. They should not, while thus burdened, assume to care for, nor to rule the
                            na- tional family. He or she,.who is married, careth for husband or wife, how to serve and
                            please, and how best to conserve family interests. Let all such stay at home—not for one
                            year, as was the Jewish rule, to "comfort" wife or husband—but so long as that relation and
                            its duties exist. In short, when a people have progressed beyond a patriarchal family
                            relation, they sliould develop a class of intellectual celibates, who do not marry,
                            individually, but who marry the State, under the natural law of evolution that has hitherto
                            been overlooked, disregarded or ruinously violated. In all governments we have had man with
                            man, working, in governmental relations, what is unseemly and destructive to private and
                            public virtue—pass<pb n="79" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MLAJNTZFESTO. ing laws that are not
                            just—class legisla- tion—legal stealing—public sexual immorality—husbands and fathers being
                            away from their proper sphere—the family homestead. Hence result private vice, private
                            divorce, family quarrels, official robbery and public wars. What else could result—will not
                            a tree bring forth its appropriate fruit ? In the God element, in humanity, is the germ of a
                            new earth and new heaven—a new civil government—having no theology, no orthodox war-god,
                            Christ nor chaplain, but righteousness and peace in all the relations of human beings with
                            each other, and with, themselves individually. When society evolves a class of men and
                            women, as now in England, in whom, the Westminster Review declares, that the marrying
                            instinct has died out, these should fill the houses of parlia- ment and the halls of
                            legislation ; these should enact natural laws of righteousness. First, a law relieving ail
                            Avho have private families from public burdens. Second, a law oi citizenship, male and
                            female. Third, a law of property, giving the land of the nation to the people of the nation,
                            and securing its just distribution and possession by land limitation and inalienable
                            homestead laws. Fourth, a law of population, setting forth the physiology of reproduction,
                            its rule of right, with appropriate checks and restrictions, as did Mosaic LaAV— under which
                            marriage was used for offspring only, and children were nursed three years, during which
                            period the "woman was free.—Clark's Commentaries. Fifth, the law of digestion, or the
                            assimilation of food—the kind, quantity and quality that is scientifically right and best
                            for the individual and the nation. Sixth, the law of arbitration, under which no one should
                            live for himself nor herself, in family, society, nor nation— but each live for all. In each
                            family or society there should be a throne of judgment, unconditionally deferred to by the
                            unit or individual. This would end private feuds and strifes. Seventh, nations when
                            organized upon these principles of righteousness, can recognize a natural law of nations
                            that would be God's justice and right incarnate—a Supreme Court of arbitration— all the
                            nations beginning to be rational by universal disarmament. War creates war ; it begins with
                            warlike preparations. The girl with her doll-baby is learning the rudiments of maternity.
                            The boy with his toy fife, drum and gun, is a germinal warrior. Cease to think war. Learn to
                            think peace, and nothing but peace. Let the decision of parent, the majority of the court of
                            arbitration for nations, be as the fiat of the Almighty—the Persian Medo decree of humanity,
                            that a nation should no more revolt from the decisions of the grand Supreme Court of
                            nations, than the law-abiding Americans revolted from the revolting decision of the United
                            States Supreme Court, that "the black man has no rights that the white man is bound to
                            respect." It is the Shaker idea that the whole system of civil government should be so mrely
                            secular and materialistic that no sectarian of any of the world's religions could justly
                            complain of their children jeing taught, in the public schools, any hing but pure science
                            and pure morality. The civil government should claim and exercise the right of educating all
                            children up to fifteen years of age. VQ <pb n="80" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO.' 8O I
                            should as thoroughly indoctrinate every American child into the principles of secular
                            American republicanism, as the Roman Catholics indoctrinate their children into the faith
                            and principles of Church and State government. How is it possible for the American Republic
                            to perpetuate itself, if all parents, who choose so to do, exercise the right to educate
                            their children as enemies thereof? * As ignorance of scientific knowledge and morality lays
                            the foundation of criminals, that the State has to take the whole charge of, and bear all
                            the loss to life and property occasioned by their existence, is it unreasonable that it
                            should "see the evil afar off," and fore-stall it by national schools, into which all
                            parents should be obligated to place their children, or emigrate to some Church and State
                            country. Laws for the forced collection of debts should be repealed, and all debts become
                            debts of honor. They are generally paid. Let citizens settle their debts and theologies
                            amongst themselves, and the national government keep the peace amongst them while so doing.
                            Thus far, the new earth under the Shaker system. Shall we try it ? Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Teachings of the Shaker Manifesto" TEIform="index"/>Teachings Of The Shaker Manifesto</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName">ELDER GILES B. AVERY </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> The proper standard of character of our "Manifesto" should be above be- ing a receptacle for
                            mere trivial and light literature. It is desirable that articles should be well dressed,
                            their senti ments clearly manifest and free from redundance ; and, while they may be
                            various, and adapted to all grades of intellect eligible to its perusal, they should
                            generally be of a high tone of character and directed to the stupendous and magnanimous
                            object we have in view—the salvation and redemption of humanity from the mire of sin and its
                            darkening soul-cloud maze. . , What we should inculcate is, a religion free from human
                            sophistry, human creedism, pagan mythology, Pantheism, Materialism, infidelity to an
                            accessible God, manifest in some degree in all human souls who live the Christ life ; free
                            from infidelity to revealed truth ; infidelity to pure, soul spiritual ministrations of
                            angels. Free from priest-craft, which seeks to blind and befog the intelligences of men for
                            the sake of humiliating and debasing them for the advantages of power over them, and to bind
                            them for the sake of living at their ex- pense. Free from the mockery of laymen by a false
                            profession ; from sensual blindness ; self-conceit; free from the Old Orthodox
                            Heavens—happiness to be enjoyed by an elected few, without regard to their good works—and
                            from the equally inconsistent eternal hell for finite sins, as the vindictive punishment of
                            an avenging God. Free from antichristian righteousness that would teach salvation with a
                            Bible in one hand and a rifle in the other. Free from a Christian (so called,) righteousness
                            that is characterized by reliance on the merits of Jesus for salvation, by mere belief in
                            him. Our paper theologically, should be devoted to the manifestations of precepts upon, and
                            illustrations of the following subjects : <pb n="81" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 81 THE SHAKER M^LNTF'KSTO. 1.
                            The revelation of God as Father and Mother. 2. The knowledge of God by revelation through
                            mediatorial intelligences— the ministration of angels. 3. The precepts and elements of
                            Christianity as exemplified in the life of Jesus, unbiased by man-made creeds. • 4.
                            Salvation from sin—not simply from its consequences— the Christian salvation. 5. Self-denial
                            and virgin purity the harvest of the world. 6. The Harvest of the World the inauguration of
                            the Kingdom of Heaven upon earth. 7. Heavenly and earthly peace the fruit of righteousness
                            only. 8. War, the fruit of vain, worldly ambition, pride and lust for pleasure, power and
                            lordly dominion. 9. Abnormal death of the physical body not the providence of God, but the
                            result of violated laws of God. 10. The soul, a subject of mortality, the fruit of sin. 11.
                            The soul, a subject of immortality, the fruit of redemption from sin, and working
                            righteousness. 12. Incessant and interminable influx of spirit life the immortality of the
                            soul. 13. Conscious existence of man after death of the physical body. 14. Accessibility to
                            the ministration of angels the normal condition of righteous humanity. 15. Marriage an
                            institution for the worldly man. 16. Virgin celibacy an institution of the kingdom of
                            heaven. 17. Radical demonstrations of true spiritualism, the life and soul of the Christian
                            Church. 18. The soul, not the physical body, the subject of the Christian resurrection. 19.
                            The existence of hell a reality, but primarily, a state of the human soul as the result of
                            violated laws ; secondarily a, place, the society of the transgres- sors of God's laws. 20.
                            Heaven, a reality capable of being commenced on earth, the state of innocence and purity of
                            soul; and theplace of the society of the righteous whoobey the laws of God. " 21.
                            Information in general concerning that which constitutes a true Christian— a Shaker life,
                            its habits, economy ; theology, inspiration, prophecy, revelations,, anticipations and
                            needs. 22. The character of the subjects of Christ's Kingdom—as Kings and Priests unto God.
                            The field is boundless, but, we forbear. Our object is to key up the tone of our paper's
                            character to its proper level, and increase its intrinsic merits. We do not issue the
                            Manifesto as a specimen of erudition, nor as the fruit of pastime ; but as an angel
                            missionary of our everlasting Gospel Testimony to save and redeem humanity ; to make man a
                            new being ; a fit subject for the Kingdom of Heaven. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Indians, no. 3" TEIform="index"/>INDIANS NO. 3</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescott, James S." TEIform="persName">JAMES S. PRESCOTT </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> The question may be asked what have we to do with the Indians ? Answer : Nothing, at
                            present; but we have had much to do with them in the past, mostly in a disembodied state,
                            and it would not be strange if we should have something to do with them in the future. The
                            spiritual work of God on the earth s unlimited. It extends^o "all nations, <pb n="82" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER kindreds, tongues, tribes, and people," -and the Indians are
                            included. "The field is the world—the reapers are the angels"—including all, who are living
                            angel lives while in the form. "Ye are called in relation to all the rest of mankind. This
                            gospel will be freely offered to all souls. The time will come when souls will embrace it by
                            hun- dreds and by thousands !" Such was Mother Ann's prophecy. In the progress of the work
                            it will be said, "Lift up jour eyes and look on the fields, for they are white unto the
                            harvest." A moral evolution has to go before to prepare the way for a more radical testimony
                            which is to follow, and that work has already commenced. We have evidence to believe that
                            the Indians live more in accordance with the laws of na- ture, in the reproduction of their
                            race than do those of civilized nations. This being true it is easy to account why it is
                            that the Indians, are among the first to embrace the gospel in the spirit world, and become
                            powerful auxiliaries and ministering spirits sent forth to minister to those who shall be
                            "heirs of salvation." In my opinion, a redeemed Indian is as lovely in the sight of God and
                            holy angels, as a redeemed white man. "God is no respecter of persons ; but in «very nation,
                            he that feareth him and worketh righteousness is accepted with him." I once heard an
                            educated Indian preach in the first Presbyterian Church in Hartford, Conn. On entering the
                            church I saw two men in the pulpit who appeared so much alike in their costumes .and entire
                            physical organizations, that it was difficult to tell, which was the Indian and which was
                            Dr. Hawes the pastor of the church. But soon the way being opened, the Indian arose and
                            "spoke his piece," and it was a masterly effort, an eloquent appeal in behalf of his much
                            abused and down-trodden race. Closing with these words : ' 'And my country-men, who were the
                            original proprietors of America?" Ever since that time, 1823, my sym- pathies have been with
                            the Indians. I have never since doubted the ability of the Indian to plead his own cause and
                            vindicate his own rights if he had an equal chance with the white man, and his surroundings
                            were the same, any more than I have of the ability of an educated African, pleading his
                            rights in Congress to-day. My mind has never changed with regard to the injustice and the
                            advantage taken by the white man over the ignorance and simplicity of the red man of the
                            forest. No matter how many bad stories might be told and circulated against the Indians by
                            the more artful and cunning white man, and border ruffians, who, in nine cases out of ten
                            have been the aggressors. It is an impossibility for the Indians ever to have justice done
                            them, so long as their testimony is not allowed in our civil courts. We are told by an
                            ex-congress man who keeps himself well informed in government affairs at Washington, that
                            there are more applications for the Indian Agency, than for any other in the civil
                            Departments ! Why is this ? The reason is obvious. They want to continue the old game of
                            swindling the poor Indians out of the last dollar of money appropriated to them annually by
                            the U. 8. Government. And they are not willing to give it up, so long as they can keep the
                            Indian testimony suppressed, M^NTEF-ZESTO. S3 <pb n="83" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER and get border
                            ruffians to swear to a lie. But, it is said too that Secretary Schurz is determined upon a
                            reform. We hope he is, and that he will "not let one guilty man escape." This growing
                            iniquity has become a national sm, almost equal in magnitude to what African slavery was
                            before the emancipation act took place. And we protest against it with equal abhorrence. We
                            learn from official reports, the following facts, wThich we herewith extract verbatim: "The
                            shameful fact, that of all the appropriations made by Congress for their benefit, but a
                            small part ever reaches them." "No nation is more sensitive to the claims and obligations of
                            justice than our own; and we are sure that Avhen the true history of Indian's wrongs are
                            laid before our countrymen, their united voice will demand that the honor and interests of
                            the nation shall no longer be sacrificed to the insatiable lust and avarice of unscrupulous
                            men." Signed by more than twenty distinguished men in New York city, in their petition to
                            Congress in behalf of the Indians in 1868. See Report of the Commissioner of Indian Affairs.
                            Page 96. 1869. North Union, 0. </p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Materialization" TEIform="index"/>MATERIALIZATION</head><p TEIform="p"> Ed. Shaker Manifesto :—Returning from attending the Randolph Liberal League with Elder F. W.
                            Evans, I stopped at Utica, to witness "Spirit Materializations,"—William. Eddy, medium.
                            First Seance : About twenty persons present, more men than women. Saw about twenty spirits,
                            but none that I knew. Heard them talk and sing, saw them shake hands with members of circle,
                            etc. Meeting continued over one hour. The next day I went to Eddy's house, looked over the
                            building, talked with William and Webster, but could discover nothing to excite my
                            suspicion, or iaise a doubt. Second Seance : About same number in the circle, sexes nearly
                            equal this time. First Spirit out stepped into an adjoining room, where there was a lamp
                            burning and door wide open; nearly closed the door after it; struck its foot against a
                            stool, turned around, picked it up and placed it out of the way, stopped at cabinet-door and
                            gave us quite a long talk, expressing good sense. Another Spirit came out, shook hands with
                            one of the circle, stepped to the lamp on the mantel-shelf, raised the shade, so that we
                            could see its face plainly; it looked like an old woman seventy or eighty years of age. In
                            other respects the seance was very like the first. All things calmly and patiently
                            considered, I do the least violence to my senses and to my common sense, to accept what I
                            saw as being genuine spirit materialization. I am not of that number who can believe or
                            disbelieve, as they choose ; never say like Beecher in his speech on eternal damnation: "I
                            can't believe and I will not believe such horrible doctrine." </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Greaves, Chas" TEIform="persName">Chas. Greaves</persName></byline><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Canaan" TEIform="index"/>Canaan, N. Y. </dateline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Note from Elder F. W. Evans" TEIform="index"/>Note From Elder F. W. Evans</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName">Elder F. W. Evans</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">Ed. Shaker Manifesto :—Why do not Shakers have more materialization amongst them? The only
                            use of materializations, as now in process of development in the world, is to prove the
                            principle—create faith. The principle is proved, and the faith created <pb n="84" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/>
                            THE in many Believers. More evidence is not needed, would be only vain repetition, like
                            demonstrating our own existence. The use of the faith and the principle is protection. Not
                            long since, a brother—Emil Bretzner, with a company who were cutting evergreens, fell from a
                            tree thirty eight feet (by measurement) from the ground to his head. His experience is that
                            as soon as he fell from the tree, it was into the arms of a friend, who had recently passed
                            out of the body, whom we all know. He'felt, not frightened, but that he would not be hurt.
                            When he struck the ground the company kneeled together in thankfulness that he was not hurt.
                            He again ascended the tree. That is the kind of Spiritualism and Materialization that we
                            need all the time. It is the protection of God. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What is, and what shoud be life?" TEIform="index"/>What is, and what should be life?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, William" TEIform="persName">WM. PERKINS </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> It is to lie quite late of mornings, Then stretch and gape and go thro' yawnings ; Then hunt
                            the poor old trowsers' pockets,— Thrusting the hand into their sockets-— And chase the
                            precious crumbs to chew, To soothe the temper from its stew ! In honor of the green-horn
                            worm, Men love to eat the weed in turn. Then as they leave their filthy couch, Of grotesque
                            mien, both sad and slouch, They find, some easy place to sit, Drawling out words, of hit,
                            not wit; Feeling that Pope did well to write, "Whatever is, is surely right." Thus in this
                            lazy state of ease, Go well, go ill, all goes to please; And so they move with scarce a
                            strife, Till death engulphs their dolesome life. Should Darwin need more facts to show, That
                            men have come from things below, Just let him seize upon this class, Then see his notions
                            current pass. Others, there be of IshmaePs mind, Whose hands are turned against their kind,
                            By fraud and trade are robbing all, Worse than from Peter to pay Paul. Another class with
                            fiendish rattle Rush to the war in hellish battle; And thus in carnal, deadly strife,
                            Destroy the heavenly gift of life, And when they've vanquished all their foes, They sink
                            beneath their well earned woes. Life as it should be springs up early, Views the vast
                            heavens, bright and pearly; Sees the great sun in all his might, Pour out his flood of
                            glorious light; Dispelling every shade of night. With "hands to work and hearts to God," .
                            They seldom need his chastening rod; With noble philanthropic mind They're doing good to all
                            their kind; Too far above the vulgar strife To sacrifice the meanest life. With Cowper, they
                            would never tread Upon the poor worm's humble head, And all which they wish to receive, In
                            turn, they will to others give. Such are the lives of all the great; Not in the wars nor in
                            the state, But in the Kingdom ruled hy love, Gentle and pure as Noah's dove, Rise from this
                            life to that above. South Union, Ky. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Such is prayer" TEIform="index"/>SUCH IS PRAYER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Andrews, Watson" TEIform="persName">WATSON ANDREWS </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> Archimedes supposed, that if he only had support for his lever, he could move the planet
                            Earth ! Whenever I have carried out the Savior's injunction, "Pray without ceasing"
                            literally, I have found it an Archimedean lever, which supported by his life, practically,
                            can in- deed move "the idorld" aside, with all its loves, and its hatreds ; all its pride,
                            ambition and self-worship ; all envy ings, jealousies, suspicion, evil surmisings, slanders,
                            calumnies, and strife—the le- gitimate outgrowth of the world. At the first breath of deep,
                            fervent prayer, all these fly the thoughts, as chaff from the winnower ; nor can they
                            return, so long as the "very breath is rHB SHAKER MANTKESTO. 8 <pb n="85" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 85 THE
                            SHAKER MAJSTIFESTO. prayer." Verily, prayer is one of the most effective of means for
                            raising the human soul into the regions of eternal light and life. O ! the transcendent
                            power of prayer. "Ask what ye will, and it shall be given you," so you do not "ask amiss,
                            that ye may consume it on your lusts." It is asked, what is the philosophy of prayers ?
                            Simply this : That desire is the avenue through which mental conditions, spiritual afilata
                            inflow into the soul; and when intense, and directed to the holy and pure, beseeching a like
                            spirit, it is in the nature of things that such spirit should flow into the soul, and of
                            course while such a pure and holy spirit bears rule in the breast, the life will be
                            correspondingly pure. Iforth Union, Ohio. </p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Esteemed Editor : The following simple production came into my hand a few days since..." TEIform="index"/>Esteemed Editor : The following simple production came into my hand a few days since...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Correspondent" TEIform="persName">Correspondent</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">Esteemed Editor : The following simple production came into my hand a few days since, and on
                            perusing it I thought it might be of benefit to some of the numerous readers of our
                            Manifesto, and forward to you for insertion if you think proper.</p><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Slander" TEIform="index"/>SLANDER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hastings, M. E." TEIform="persName">M. E. Hastings </persName></byline><p TEIform="p">It is not the right of any person to judge the motives, sincerity or insincerity of
                                others, unless divinely appointed, and duly clothed with wisdom, and purity of thought
                                for the mission. Some remarks occasionally uttered by inexperienced persons professing
                                religious culture and sanctity, deserve criticism and censure. They are of this sort:
                                "People do'nt want religion in these days ; all they aim at, is a plenitude of 'creature
                                comforts'; give them these, and they are satisfied." Again: "They couldn't afford to
                                subscribe for a religious paper ; they would rather spend their money for knickknacks
                                and novels." Such judgings come from an unsanctified condition; none can minister the
                                regenerating gospel from that standpoint ; it is pharisaical, conceited. Other similar
                                inadvertent thrusts might be named, which always inflict pain to our spirit, when we
                                hear, or utter them, and lead us to soliloquize : Is that the way our Mother Ann Lee
                                enforced the living testimony of Jesus Christ with such pregnant results ? Did she
                                deride, slander, backbite, even when reviled ? Never ; her reproofs were from severely
                                in-wrought chastenings ; from a soul bleeding with compassion, suffused with
                                commiseration for other souls ; and though pointed against sin, yet tenderly humane to
                                the sinner. Her God-given accusations were to the sinner direct, rather than in his ab-
                                sence ; and in a way to effect their divine purpose. Her soul felt sorrow for the sinful
                                condition, and sought in humbleness and prayer to remove it. Censure is a dangerous
                                weapon in the hands of a Christian; it should never be used, unless to our own bruising.
                                We may torture our own mean, selfish propensities with perfect impunity,—even to
                                crucifixion ; but stay the battle there; exchange the sword for the plough, with this
                                manner of spirit: "Here my brother, is some fallow ground which needs breaking up, if
                                you would like, I will aid you in your toil, for I have had some experience in the work,
                                with a good degree of success. We will turn up the soil, and remove the <pb n="86" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 86 weeds, root and top,—every fibre—and cast them
                                into the fire to be burned." If we will learn to work, wish, and judge, with the love of
                                God for our armor, in humble dependence on divine guidance, we may be assured of more
                                grateful success in our efforts to do good, at home and abroad. Cast off the mantle of
                                haughty conceit ; and pray more earnestly that we may be clothed with the spirit of
                                divine wisdom, charity and love, and thus merit Heaven's kind parental care and
                                ministration, enabling us to work the work of our day and calling, which is grand,
                                beyond ordinary conception, and will assuredly ere long, bring forth glorious results.
                                May we all be workers together with God, and be found worthy reapers with the angels,
                                when they shall move us to "thrust in the sickle, for the harvest is ripe."</p></div3><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New Hampshire, Canterbury" TEIform="index"/>Canterbury, N. H. </dateline></div2><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ann Lee: her work, her people, and their critics, third paper" TEIform="index"/>ANN LEE Her
                            Work, her People, and their Critics Third Paper.</head><p TEIform="p"> All things being ready, as many as were able, paid their passage money at Liverpool, and
                            embarked May 19. 1774, on the ship Mariah, bound for New York. Besides Mother Ann, there
                            were eight others—nine in all— William Lee, James Whittaker, John Hocknell, Mary Partington,
                            Abraham Stanley, Richard Hocknell, James Shepard and Nancy Lee—a niece of Mother Ann's. It
                            is with curious feelings pervading us, that we go back in imagination to witness the
                            partings of this company, from those to whom they had become bound by more than the common
                            ties of consanguinity. Parting from necessity, because they could not live in England as
                            purely as did Jesus in Judea, and as purely as they were determined to do or die; leaving,
                            per force of circumstances, those too decrepit and poor to go with them, however strongly
                            desirous they were to do so—the Mother was to leave some helpless children, who were doomed
                            to suffer for more than merely the want of a Mother's presence. The testimony ceased in
                            England; and 'tis piteous to know, that during the same summer James and Jane Wardley
                            removed to the alms-house and died there shortly afterward! The others mostly fell back into
                            the common course of life after the manner of the world. The ship Mariah, had been condemned
                            as unseaworthy, and proved on this voyage, said to have been her last, to have been so weak,
                            that during a storm a plank started, and she nearly foundered. During the storm, this
                            company were having one of their meetings, which the captain had previously forbidden them
                            to engage in on the ship, threatening to throw them overboard if they continued to hold
                            them. It is positively asserted, that the captain was about putting his threat into
                            execution, when the ship sprung so badly aleak. Thus was the leak considered providential,
                            even as was the replacement of the plank, by the stroka of a wave after the captain had
                            declared they must all be lost, and after Mother Ann had said : "Fear not, captain, chere
                            shall not a hair of our heads perish, but we shall all arrive safely in America !" The
                            captain, afterwards declared to others than the Shakers, that "had not that people been on
                            board of his ship, she never would have reached land again !" No further remonstrance to
                            their worship was made; and regardless of their violent exercises, and unusual noises of
                            singing, shouting, shaking, etc., so little understood by the poor, annoyed captain and
                            crew, they were looked upon by these, with reverential awe, during the balance of the
                            voyage. They landed in New York on the 6th of August, the same year, the recurrence of which
                            day is still cherished in happy reflections of our people, as "Hail, the blessed sixth of
                            August— "Hail, the day, and hail the year— "When the messengers of Jesus, "With the gospel
                            did appear!" <pb n="87" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. After landing, they passed up Pearl
                            St. in a body; and seeing a woman standing in a doorway, Mother Ann told her that they had
                            been "sent to America to preach the everlasting gospel!" and to the surprise of Mother and
                            her company, the woman stated that having been warned in a visionary dream to pre- pare for
                            them, she had done so and bid them in, and cared for them until they found employment. Such
                            incidents, under such distressed circumstances, of strangers in a strange land, without
                            friends or means, are looked upon by us to this day as "providences" special or otherwise.
                            Finding employment, they were getting on well, when Abraham Stanley was taken dangerously
                            sick, causing Mother to leave her occupation to attend solely to his care and cure. Having
                            but'little means of her own, and John Hocknell, upon whose assistance they had almost
                            constantly relied, having returned to England to bring his family to America, she suffered
                            the direst poverty, while rendering the utmost care and kindness to the apparently dying
                            man. But, at length, Abraham became convalescent ; and before being able to return to his
                            occupation, resorted to houses of bad resort and ill fame, turning against his faith, and in
                            most ungodly and violent opposition to Ann, his former wife and benefactress. While
                            expressing herself ready, as ever, to do anything for him which justice, reason or humanity
                            required, she would never consent to live a worldly life with'him again, to thus violate her
                            known duty to God, by coming down from the cross upon which she had been crucified—to the
                            death of her worldly, fleshly life. After the worst possible abuse and contumely towards
                            Ann, Abraham left her, to resort with a lewd woman; and thus ended their relations. For this
                            period of Stanley's life, we hold him in utter contempt. Convinced as he was of the motive
                            power of Ann's testimony; having embraced it, and "tasted of the powers of the world to
                            come" by obedience to it; having been nursed in sickness, saved from death, and worse than
                            death by his whilom partner; conscious of her high and superior calling, and having nought
                            to complain of, but her unwillingness to descend from her angelhood, to be the merely animal
                            woman again, Stanley has our unmitigated willingness that he should receive his just deserts
                            as he undoubtedly did ! Sic semper brutalis. In September, 1775, the faithful remnant of
                            this little company, now numbering only five persons, passed through Albany, to the section
                            known then as Mskayuna, settling on a spot previously purchased by John Hocknell, where we
                            will find them in our next paper. (continued.) </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Heaven and Hell of Universalists" TEIform="index"/>The Heaven and Hell of Universalists</head><p TEIform="p"> It will be interesting to many, to know that Shaker doctrines concerning Heaven and hell are
                            at one with that of the Universalists; however different our methods of arriving at these
                            conditions. The following extracts, are from a sermon of Rev. James Gorton. They illustrate
                            the subjects well. We believe in heaven. We may be somewhat divided in opinion as to whether
                            heaven is any particular place in the universe fitted up as an abode for the just and holy
                            after they have left this world. We make no objection to that idea of heaven, but that would
                            be a very incomplete idea with us. To us holiness is heaven; and no place, however
                            beautiful, no condition of external comfort and grandeur, could be heaven without purity of
                            life, holiness of character. The good may go to heaven, but they can never go to heaven till
                            heaven has first come to them as an inward life of purity and righteousness. So Christ
                            represents heaven as within the soul—"Behold, the kingdom of God is within you." "The
                            kingdom of God is righteousness and peace and joy in the Holy Spirit." He does not teach us
                            to pray, "Lord, permit us to go to thy kingdom when we die," but to pray, "Thy kingdom come,
                            and thy will be done, on earth." To go to heaven in sin would be impossible, absurd, a
                            contradiction in terms, just as much so as to be dead and alive at the same time. To be
                            saved in sin is not merely impossible, but absurd and a contradiction. Salvation is
                            deliverance from sin. Whenever we ar« delivered, from the love and practice of holiness, we
                            are saved, whether in this world or the next. X7 <pb n="88" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE
                            M-AJNTEF'JSSTO. 88 Going to a local heaven in a future life is not salvation. We believe in
                            hell—not in a local hell in a future world where the wicked are herded together and
                            "tormented to all eternity. Sin makes hell. Wherever sin is, in this world or in any other,
                            there is hell. Hell is the opposite of heaven, and is a condition of interior life, a state
                            of character, rather than a place. Hell is in the soul that lives in sin, and is defiled
                            with hate, impurity, injustice and unrighteousness. Hell is in such a soul just as much here
                            as hereafter. Hell is that degradation and dishonor, that shame and misery which sin
                            produces in every soul that harbors it. We never can go to hell only just as we take hell
                            along with us. There is really no other hell than the hell of sin in the soul, and in the
                            life. The real heaven and the real hell are opposite states of life— are internal conditions
                            of the soul—not anything that is outward, local and material. A state of holiness is heaven;
                            a state of sin is hell. Holiness satisfies the spiritual nature; —brings peace, honor,
                            felicity. Sin gives dissatisfaction to the spiritual nature ; brings unrest, dishonor,
                            misery. To be holy now is to enter heaven now, or, better still, is to permit heaven to
                            enter you now, with all its beauty, peace and gladness. And just the contrary is true in
                            respect to what we call hell. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Soliloquy" TEIform="index"/>SOLILOQUY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Horton, Lewis" TEIform="persName">LEWIS HORTON </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> Have I a mansion there— Where on shining walls Hang fadeless flowers—symbolic emblems Of
                            earthly good, of victories won O'er sin and worldly strife ? Have I the love That shines in
                            all my Master's ways Peerless and sublime ? Blest Savior of my soul! O'er thee angelic
                            legions held controlEncompassed thee about in tenderness and care, Breathing forth—like
                            summer winds— Mercy, Love and Truth, from our Creator, God. O thou eternal Source of life!
                            Help me to walk the path that Jesus trod; Help me to know Thy will Till in my soul Christ's
                            kingdom comes And finds eternal dwelling. Enfield N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Is it consistent and right for Christians to fight?" TEIform="index"/>IS IT CONSISTENT AND
                            RIGHT FOR CHRISTIANS TO FIGHT?</head><p TEIform="p">To the Editor of the Cape Town Daily News. South Africa. snt,—I believe it is no more true
                            that the freedom of the press is the legitimate out- come of liberal governments than it is
                            that there is a general understanding among English-speaking people that editors are not to
                            be held responsible for the theories of their correspondents. Whenever the reasonableness of
                            this position is conceded, the way is open for the widest diversity of opinions and for the
                            agitation of thought which is the beginning of wisdom. But to the matter in hand. Since H.
                            M. Stanley, the brave, intrepid explorer, announces himself the hero of thirty recent
                            battles in Central Africa; since there is raging at the present time a terrible
                            Turko-Kussian war; and since there is an incessant wartalk in certain South African
                            journals, relating to the settling of frontier difficulties, it seems opportune to ask, if a
                            Christian, as a Christian, can fight? And is war, involving enmity, pillage, and the
                            destruction of human lives, in keeping with the letter and spirit of Christianity, as
                            enunciated and lived by Jesus Christ? It will not be denied by the student of history that
                            during the first three hundred years after Christ, an Israelite or a Pagan Soldier embracing
                            Christianity, refused to fight. If pressed by the Government to enlist, his ready reply was
                            "no." I have enlisted under the banner and am a follower of the Prince of Peace. I cannot
                            consistently fight; and can- not because I believe in Him who said, "My Kingdom is not of
                            this World, if it were, then would my servants fight." "We Christians are superior in this,"
                            said St. Jerome, "We do not fight with our enemies." The good St. Martin exclaimed: "I am a
                            Soldier of Jesus Christ, and therefore, I do not fight." Charles Sumner, the noblest of our
                            United States Senators said in the Congressional Session of 1849, "War is a damnable profes-
                            sion—a trade of barbarism!" It is expected that barbarians—that the wild animals of the
                            forest—will fight, because <pb n="89" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER they are animals. And the nearer
                            that tribes and nations approach the selfish animal planes of existence, the more do they
                            thirst for blood. All wars are anti-Christian. Jesus Christ subdued by love, and He was our
                            exemplar. Fighting is infectious breeding more fights. The sectarian soldier that fights, is
                            as brave as a dog. Few men are morally brave enough, and Christly enough, to run before they
                            will fight. Having recently travelled through Northern Ceylon, meeting and conversing daily
                            with Buddhist priests, I can assure you that the selfish tendencies, the drinking habits,
                            and the war practices, of Christian nations in the Occident, present the greatest obstacles
                            to the conversion of Buddhists to the pure and divine teachings of Jesus Christ. These
                            socalled heathen despise hypocrisy. And hence they say—why do you preach of the Prince of
                            Peace—why do you, oh Western Christians, profess love, charity, and forgiveness, and yet,
                            come into our midst with sword and rifle? It is becoming more and more a fixed conviction,
                            that since the reign of the Emperor Constantine, Christian nations have been no more honest,
                            temperate, and peaceful, than have the "heathen" nations of the East. Do not the heathen
                            know, and do"not we remember that 2,000,000 of lives were sacrificed during the ten
                            crusades—called "The Holy Wars ?" Do we not know that Catholics and Protestants persecuted
                            and killed each other in the past, declaring that the "interests of the Church" required it?
                            And have we not read of St. Bartholomew's eve, of the massacre of the Albigenses, and the
                            atrocious persecutions and murders of Jews by Christians, from the beginning of the 11th to
                            the middle of the 16th century? When the Abbot of Citeaux, on the sacking and destruction of
                            Beziers was inquired of, how they could distinguish between the heretics and the faithful
                            —"kill them all"— "kill them all," was the answer; "God will know his own !" During the late
                            Civil War in America over the Slavery question, there were six hundred battles fought and
                            more than 500,000 maimed for life or killed. The professed ministers of Him who
                            said-"blessed are the peacemakers" —preached in favour of war, and prayed for victories.
                            Bishop Polk, of Louisiana, laid aside robe, prayer-book, bible, and led one wing of the
                            Southern Army into the battlefield. General T. W. Jackson—called "Stonewall
                            Jackson"—maintained morning and evening prayers during all his campaigns. His negro servant
                            boy used to frequently say, "There's goen to be a big fight to-day, sartin —Masser's been
                            prayin for two hours." The Rev. Mr. Miller, commanding a battery in General Jackson's Corps,
                            had his church-bells melted down into cannon-balls, when the ordnance stores were low, to
                            shoot down the "Northern Yankees, bent on the overthrowing of slavery." The only people in
                            America, that as individuals and bodies, refused to engage in that fratricidal war were the
                            Shakers. They have about seventy communities, and count their numbers by thousands. Their
                            leading principles are purity of life, peace, and "all things in common" in imitation of the
                            early Apostolic Church. The cost of standing armies in Christian nations is absolutely
                            enormous. The annual expense of the war system in Europe, including the interest on the war
                            debt, ' 'far exceeds," say the statistics, "five hundred millions of pounds." The hard
                            times—the late strikes and mobs in America, are but the lean harvest sheaves of our late
                            civil war. There were 88,500 lives sacrificed upon the war-altar during the Franco-German
                            war. And the Emperor William, informing Augusta of the latest victory, and devoutly thanking
                            God, therefore, gave rise to the following inelegant lines :— "Ten thousand Frenchmen sent
                            below, Praise God from whom all blessings flow." But says one,—"How shall we do away with
                            war?" I answer: Become true and practical followers of Jesus Christ; arbitrate in the spirit
                            of confidence and charity; teach your children to overcome evil with good; oppose military
                            schools and standing armies; refuse to go into battle-fields to fight; and cease to praise
                            and glorify officers and military chieftains. If Jesus of Nazereth,with bared head, sandaled
                            feet, and coarse Oriental costume, should come personally to Cape Town, to how many could he
                            point and say, as of old, —" Ye are not of the world, even as I am VL^JSrrF-KlSTO. <pb n="90" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 9O not of the world?" And should he commence
                            preaching, as he did nearly 2,000 years since:— "Woe unto you ye blind guides. * * Woe unto
                            you scribes, pharisees, hypocrites ! for ye compass sea and land to make one prose- lyte ;
                            and when he is made, ye make him two-fold more the child of hell than yourselves."—Matt. 23
                            : 15. "Lay not up for yourselves treasures upon the earth, * * * but lay up for yourselves
                            treasures in heaven."—Matt, vi: 19, 20. "Verily I say unto you * * a rich man shall hardly
                            enter into the kingdom of heaven."—Matt. 19: 23. "If any man serve me, let him follow me."
                            —John 12: 26. "Whosoever he be of you that forsaketh not all that he hath, he cannot be my
                            disciple. * * * By this shall all men know that ye are my disciples, if ye have love one for
                            another."—Luke 14 : 33. I repeat, should the gentle Nazarene ap- pear bodily in this
                            flourishing city to teach his radical doctrines, and to accompany them by "laying hands on
                            the sick and healing them;" by making the "lame to walk and the deaf to hear," and by again
                            "discerning Spirits" as he discerned and talked with the Spirits of Moses and Elias upon the
                            mountain of transfiguration; he could not obtain entrance into any Church or Chapel in Cape
                            Town. But forsooth; He, Mr. Stanley comes with the echoing jingle of beer-bottles, and the
                            low far off wail of widows and orphans, resulting from thirty battles, and he is
                            feasted—lionized by the people—and nearly canonized by the Church! Such is the status of our
                            civilization—such is the nineteenth century Christianity! Is there no need of Spiritualism?
                            No necessity for the Spiritualizing of our humanity, and the quickening of the conscience of
                            Christendom? True, H. M. Stanley justifies his conduct, because acting in the interests of
                            geographical discoveries, and so James Mace, the prizepugilist of the world, exhibits his
                            championbelt, boasts of having pommelled and disfigured a goodly number of human faces—and
                            pleads justification that he is acting in the interests of muscle-culture and the "manly art
                            of self-defense." Love, charity, and goodwill to men have so yielded to the struggle for
                            existence, that men seemed to have renounced their higher natures, and ranged themselves on
                            the side of the carnivora, and, like them, rend and devour their prey. The coming man will
                            eat no meat. Pride, pleasure, sporting, pugilism, and war are so popular with the masses of
                            today, and apostacy from the Christ of the Gospels, and the simplicity of the Apostolic
                            Church, so nearly universal, that one is inclined to think we might quite as well expect to
                            boil water with Nova Zembla snow-balls, as to hope or expect that the fashionable,
                            policy-trimming, money-getting, pleasureseeking, wine-drinking, fighting Christiana of the
                            nineteenth century, can ever transform our poor erring humanity into the likeness of Christ.
                            Tennyson full of faith sweetly sings :— "Ring out the darkness of the land, Ring in the
                            Christ that is to be." The end of creeds, that cramp the soul's higher aspirations, and of
                            fossilized formalisms that sap faith and blight naturally religious natures, is at hand. The
                            seventh angel has sounded; the fig-tree has put forth its tender buds ; and He who said
                            "behold I make allthings new," is already in the clouds of Heaven with His holy angels and
                            minis- tering spirits.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Peebles, J. M." TEIform="persName">J. M. Peebles</persName></byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good morning" TEIform="index"/>GOOD MORNING</head><p TEIform="p"> Good Morning! though a simple gift, Has still a magic power ; 'Tis as a cup of water passed
                            One, in a needy hour. Good Morning! these two little words, When clothed with Christian
                            grace, Bring such a wreath of happy smiles Upon a friendly face. The sweetness lasts through
                            all the dayr When cheerful we begin; The light and shade along life's way, Are nicely woven
                            in. Perchance a cloud may rise at noon, And dim the morning light; Good Afternoon ! will
                            break the gloom And bring a sweet Good Night! Canterbury, N. H. </p></div2><pb n="91" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="figure" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="View of Shaker Village, at Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>View of Shaker Village, at
                            Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> We are indebted to The American Socialist for this picture. It is to i found in the new work
                            entitled "American Communities." The view is taken from the top of the North Family's be
                            great barn, looking southward. </p></div2><pb n="92" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Should we all be Shakers?" TEIform="index"/>SHOULD ALL BE SHAKERS?</head><p TEIform="p"> No question is more frequently asked by the caviling, than : "If all should be Shakers, what
                            then?" This question has been the foundation and cap-stone of nearly all the arguments in
                            opposition to our faith; because the only reasonable conclusion and answer thereto, is the
                            answer that "the world would run out.'" To relieve the plaints of those who admire our faith
                            from a distance, fearing it is the way, the truth, and the Christian life, we are led to the
                            following question : Should all be Shalcers ? We answer. They should not be, not only, but
                            that they cannot be! Proceed we now to state who should not be Shakers : Those who believe
                            that to pattern Jesus, the Christ, in our present lives, is like "feeding on skimmed milk,"
                            while all "the butter" is in the carnal indulgences of the flesh. Those, who cannot see,
                            that through the self-denials of the Shaker, the cream and butter of life are secured and
                            enjoyed. Those who cannot feel that our threshings and winnowings, separate the good grain,
                            leaving it to us, while blowing the useless out of our way of progress. Those should not be
                            Shakers, who believe it better to people the earth, with good or bad posterity, than to
                            populate the heavens, and similar heavens on earth, with characters patterned after Jesus'
                            life. Those who believe and realize more pleasure in self-indulgences than in self-denials,
                            are yet too low, to hear our gospel trumpet blow. None should attempt the life of a Shaker
                            who is satisfied that he needs not confess and forsake his sins; or who relies upon Jesus to
                            pay the debt for him. Who is not yet convinced, that there is more heaven in Christian
                            celibacy, than in the civil institutions of marriage, must be excused; also those who admire
                            husbands and wives, more than they do "brethren and sisters in Christ." As Jesus, the
                            Christ, was a virgin celibate, so those who will not, or cannot be such, cannot be a
                            Christian Shaker. Just so to those clinging to or longing after husband, wife, children,
                            houses, lands, private property of any kind, or living as selfishly as possible without
                            these, such cannot be Shakers. Those who love wars, contentions and the policies and
                            politics of the world, better than they do the peace, and seclusion found in Christ's life,
                            need not apply. Those who have, and do "make gods of their bellies," (see Phil. 3 : 19.) or
                            who are not yet resurrected above the mere worship of "the seven-loaves-and-two-fish"
                            principles —wanting the good of this life without a willingness to earn it; and those who
                            love themselves better than they do unselfish loves, must fail in the attempt at being
                            Shakers, and are warned therefrom. True, we have excluded, excused, denied and warned nearly
                            every one from being a Shaker! Then this should relieve us from the charge of bigotry and
                            unreasonable expectations. We believe Shakerism to be God's work with mankind; and that God
                            will gather to it those who want to be saved, from what Shakerism saves ; none others. None
                            will ever be forced into Shakerism against their convictions of what is right, or what is
                            happiness. The "whosoever will" is as active today as ever in the past; while "you must
                            believe or be damned," finds no more criers in genuine, Shaker hearts, than were exhaled
                            from the original Christ. One thing we have proved : Souls will ripen unto the harvest of
                            Jesus, the Christ; and by the spirit of his testimony be "cut off from earthly" practices,
                            and be resurrected into the life of Christ. These may be few or many, but such there will be
                            in this life, such there are now. Such there are, who, like berries have ripened unto the
                            plucking, from lives of generative lusts, into just such a resurrection as Jesus lived in;
                            who, sick of the unspirituality of the world's good and bad, seek relief from all that
                            constitutes it. Thus have many changed soul and body into the glorious resurrection of the
                            Christ; and through Shaker Christianity, realized truly, what the lifeblood of the Lamb can
                            do. Such can be, should be Shakers. We would not disparage any from the attempt to be a
                            Shaker. But a good Shaker will bear a full cross ; and by 93 <pb n="93" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 93 THE
                            SHAKER such only can the gospel be sustained in its genuine purity, and by such will its
                            godly aims be prosecuted. Only those can be Shakers whom the spirit of God calls upon so to
                            be. Such will know, their time to be a Shaker has come. Let such be faithful to their
                            consciences and to God. Should all be Shakers? Nay; only such as can and will bear the
                            Shaker's cross. Can all bear it who are willing to do so? Where there is a will strong
                            enough, there is always power enough accompanying Each shall get their pay according to the
                            degree of self-denial they exercise. If any one asks : "Should I be a Shaker?" We answer :
                            certainly, if you are "able." </p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>EDITORIAL NOTES</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Steady progress" TEIform="index"/>STEADY PROGRESS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> Mother Ann Lee once prophesied, during a period of some doubt among her followers, that
                                "souls will flock to your doors by hundreds and by thousands, like doves to their cots!"
                                Regardless of the charge upon us of adulatory adoration for our founder, take a look at
                                her belief and teachings one hundred, and more years ago, and compare them with the
                                present religious growth of the people : 1. She taught Jesus as an exampler, not as an
                                Atonement. How long will it be before Beecher, and "the rest of mankind" will so believe
                                ? What multitudes have since her day "flocked" to this idea ! 2. She taught the
                                Resurrection, as a soul work, in, as well as out of the body, in opposition to the mere
                                physical resurrection. What millions have already "flocked" to this door of escape from
                                error! 3. She taught and practiced, as have her followers ever since, intercommunication
                                between this and the spiritual world ! Since 1848, the number so believing, have
                                "flocked" to this truth from a few thousands to more than hvelve millions ! 4.
                                Concerning Hell and Heaven, Ann Lee even testified they were conditions, that merited
                                similar associations, here and hereafter ; and was ever pronounced in the truth of a
                                state of probation hereafter—to an unlimited extent. But having stated this much, and
                                viewing the millions now "flocking to this door," we will stop for the present, with the
                                re- mark, that we have more "doors" for more millions "to flock to," and the end is not
                                yet! </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Marriage" TEIform="index"/>MARRIAGE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> We have given up all hope of ever being able to set all the people right upon our
                                opinions of marriage. Several letters of recent date have been received at this office,
                                assuring us that we must have very wicked feelings towards this institution, or we would
                                practice it and its injunctions. But such is not the case. We have transcended the
                                sphere where marriage,, reproduction, private property, politics, etc.— are honorable ;
                                and are willing to view these as honorable in their proper sphere, among "the children
                                of this world." Being promoted into a higher sphere, needs not cause us to hate the
                                normal rudimentary conditions nor those in them, unless we find them cropping out in
                                ourselves, to the disturbance of the elements of the advanced sphere, among "the
                                children of the Resurrection"—of Christ, or Christians. In ourselves we may hate to have
                                them ; well knowing that Christians never did, never can practice them ; M^JSTIinESTO.
                                    <pb n="94" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKBfJ JVLAJSTIWttSTO. though many calling themselves so,
                                do practice them. Proposing still, and ever, to "follow" •Christ Jesus, we mean to do
                                with marriage, etc. just as he did with them— let them alone ; leave them with "the
                                •childreu of the world," until they get soul-sick of such practices ; yet all the while,
                                loving their souls, and desiring for them, even as for ourselves, an equal resurrection
                                into the advanced, higher, holier life-practices of Jesus, the Christ. </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bro. James M. Peebles" TEIform="index"/>BRO. JAMES M. PEEBLES.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> Our spiritualistic brethren, may or may not thank us, for proposing an organization of
                                Spiritualists under the leadership of Bro J. M. Peebles, a modern, and very superior
                                Paul! We see very many beautiful spirits in the body, casting about for a line, while
                                drifting unpleasantly and unwillingly towards Utopia. Bro. Peebles holds just the line,
                                which we think the millions of spiritually minded, would be most happy to attach their
                                barques unto ; and we are confident that by a strong attachment thereto, they will ever
                                after acknowledge that their "lines have fallen in pleasant places," and find themselves
                                being towed directly and expeditiously into conditions most desirable. Rev. Bro. Dr.
                                Elder Peebles, we lay our hands, in imposition upon you ! We anxiously await the effects
                                of the motion upon our friendly cotemporaries, The Banner of Light, The It. P. Journal,
                                Voice of Truth, Spiritual Scientist, Voice of Angels, etc. </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Credit to whom credit is due" TEIform="index"/>CREDIT TO "WHOM CREDIT IS DUE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> When we think there is no,t one minister of tiie Jonathan Edwards' school, that preaches
                                theology just as severely as he did ; no Presbyterian who is a complete copyist of
                                Calvin; that Luther could find no perfect imitator to-day, and that the entire religious
                                world is much more liberal now than ever before ; so much so, that there is scarcely one
                                who preaches to-day, but would have forfeited his life 150 years ago ; then can we well
                                afford to render to Thomas Paine some credit, for it is surely due. His crimes were a
                                disbelief in the Bible as a revelation from God—plenarily inspired; and he denied the
                                divinity of Jesus. Yet he said : "The world is my home ; to do good is my religion ;"
                                "No man should make a living by preach- ing;" "One good school-master is worth more than
                                a hundred priests!" He abjured shedding blood ; and hated any god that commanded it. His
                                opinion of Jesus was "that he was a sincere man ; that the morality which he practiced,
                                was of the most lofty and pure character, and that he had never been exceeded by any
                                mortal man!" Again: "Any system of religion that has anything in it, that shocks the
                                mind of a child, is not a true system." If Paine lived to-day, he would not be looked
                                upon, as we have been taught to think of his memory. Upon the points of the Bible's
                                plenary inspiration ; doing good being true religion ; preaching for hire ; the divinity
                                of Jesus ; his testimony against war; his opinion of Jesus, as far as he expressed it,
                                the Shaker system is at one with Paine. Yet these were his prominent 'faults in the eyes
                                of the world ! </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Read and think" TEIform="index"/> Read and Think</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> "Twenty Five millions of dollars are 94r <pb n="95" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER M-AJSTEHESTO.
                                spent for tobacco annually, by Christian professors ; while but little more than seven
                                millions are spent by these same professors for church and religious purposes !" (2?x.)
                                Of course, those engaged in this improper use of the large number of dollars, was not
                                intended to include the members of The Shaker Church! </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="One hundred and fifty years ago, magistrates..." TEIform="index"/>One hundred and fifty years ago, magistrates...
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> One hundred and fifty years ago, magistrates only performed the legal marriage service ;
                                it being then considered, as it now properly is, a civil rite ; and no honor, but the
                                contrary, rested on any priest who attempted the performance of the tie. To be sure, it
                                was called a Blue Law, but was it not consistent ? In Russia, and in some other coun-
                                tries, the highest church dignitaries are not permitted, because of the sacredness of
                                their offices, to perform nor attend marriage ceremonies. </p><p TEIform="p"> When the illustrious Shah, recently touring through Europe was in London, he exhibited a
                                ring, which for generations has been thought to possess talismanic influence ;
                                protecting the wearer or holder of it from all bodily harm, either from disease or
                                assassination, so long as he shall maintain his virginity. </p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Real hells: extracts from a letter" TEIform="index"/>REAL HELLS Extracts from a letter.</head><p TEIform="p">Spiritualism and Infidelity must be credited-with providing the people free nails, they
                                are a great blessing to a thinking people. If, like the volcanoes of earth, they throw
                                out, occasionally, fire, smoke and cinders ; do they not also give vent to internal
                                forces that would otherwise cause destructive explosions? New Haven has just voted the
                                Bible out of the Public Schools; and the Congregationalists, have, by a majority of 14,
                                voted hell out of their Churches ! They have? cast their theological "death and hell"
                                into a lake of logical fire, without the brimstone. If they will keep out of the real
                                hell and death, that came of evil doing, we will forgive them. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName">F. W. Evans </persName></byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head">For the Children</head><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Will you bear the cultivation?" TEIform="index"/>Will you bear the Cultivation?</head><p TEIform="p"> My Dear Children :—Do you know how many anxious friends are continually watching for a
                                growth of beautiful virtues in your little gardens ? Well, it is so. Your parents,
                                guardians and teachers, seek to protect you from many evils, which you cannot now see,
                                but which experience has revealed to them. The discipline and reproof which you
                                sometimes meet so unpleasantly, is but a manifestation of their love and interest in
                                your present and future welfare. Did you ever see a vine laden with full clusters of
                                rich grapes ? I will tell you the process of culture. The gardener desires some fine
                                fruit; he selects those branches which he knows will produce the best, and cuts off all
                                others, knowing that they will take the nourishment from the good branch; then he trains
                                them on a trellis in such a manner, as togive them plenty of sunshine and space for
                                growth. 95 <pb n="96" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE! 8HAKEE M-AJSTHPIESTO. After this, while they are
                                growing, he often repeats the process of nipping off the little useless branches which
                                keep shooting out here and there, which would take away the strength from the others,
                                and cause the fruit to be inferior. Now what I wish to say is this : The natural habits
                                of youth are like the uncultured vine, and the gardeners who wish some nice fruit,
                                represent your teachers and guardians, who, by good counsel, in a great many ways, nip
                                off the bad habits, and wrong inclinations, that the sunshine of truth, and the pure air
                                of heaven may give growth and expansion to the best feelings of your heart. The process
                                of pruning away the evils, is often painful to the careless, who do not fully know its
                                meaning ; but let me tell you, without it, you would be like the worthless, uncultured
                                vine; you might produce some fruit, but so inferior and sour, as to be undesired.
                                Remember this always, and aim to become like some good Christian friend whom you love.
                                Strive to be refined in your manners, and chaste in all your language. Make some
                                particular resolve every morning on rising, and pray for strength to live it through the
                                day ; then be very careful. If you follow this course, I am sure you will succeed, and
                                be surprised to see how fast you improve. Remember also, that your future happiness and
                                usefulness depend upon the good principles you now cultivate. Canterbury, N. H. </p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To keep back part of the truth may not always be wrong..." TEIform="index"/>To keep back part of the truth may not always be wrong...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">To keep back part of the truth may not always be wrong, since it is not everybody's
                                business to know everything. But to keep back part of the truth with an intention to
                                deceive, is falsehood, quite as much as an out-spoken lie. </p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Quondam sailor, chapter III" TEIform="index"/>QUONDAM SAILOR CHAP. III</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Libbey, William G." TEIform="persName">WILLIAM G. LIBBBY </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> After arising from our bed of leaves we continued our walk along the shore to the
                                eastward, our ship being in plain sight all the time, lying off and on. We never saw the
                                boats after we left them ; yet we think they came ashore the day following our landing,
                                and that our shipmates had a good time searching for us. I have never seen any of that
                                ship's company since we left them enjoying tropical scenery, on the pretty beach where
                                we first landed. As we traveled along, we found the shore very rough, where the pieces
                                of coral, weighing from one to twenty pounds, had been thrown up by the waves, into very
                                irregular heaps. The slabs of coral being mostly flat, and lying loosely upon each
                                other, made it very difficult to walk over them; then there were small indentations,
                                forming nice little bays very pretty to look at, but forcing us to make long detours in
                                our line of march along the shore. In one of these bays we saw the carcasses of a number
                                of porpoise, which had been driven over the reef into shoal water, where they had died
                                for want of sea room; at least, this was our conclusion from what we knew of their
                                habits. We have often helped catch a porpoise during our night watch on a whale ship,
                                and as we passed those in the little bay, we remarked that our prospect for oil when we
                                should become settled in our new home, was good. Although a part of the shore of the
                                island is like that we have described, it is not all so rough, as we found to our great
                                comfort; for about the middle of the day we came to a beautiful beach of fine, white,
                                coral sand, which we should judge was more than a mile in length. Although familiar with
                                tropical scenery of great beauty, yet I do not recollect of any place that has left such
                                a lasting impression upon my mind, as that coral beach, fringed on its inner edge with
                                pepperplant, and a forest of cocoa-nut trees in the back ground. 96 <pb n="97" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 97 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. Among these trees we remained a short time to refresh
                                ourselves on the nuts, which was the only food we ate during onr first day's stay on the
                                island. We could have obtained some fish, but were afraid to make a fire to cook them,
                                as the smoke could have been seen on board the ship, and might be the means of drawing
                                us into unpleasant proximity with our former shipmates. We continued our walk along the
                                beach to the eastward, and crossed over to the inner, or lagoon shore, and coming to a
                                very secluded creek or cove, that was mostly surrounded by trees, we ventured to make a
                                fire, and from this night we may date the commencement of our island life. We were now
                                in full possession of the island, with powers equal to Alexander Selkirk, on Juan
                                Fernandes, as described by the poet Cowper, in his beautiful poem on the Scotch sailor's
                                lonely island life; as with S elkirk, so with us, there were none to dispute our right
                                to authority, and as we had no political ax to grind, we agreed very well in the
                                government of ourselves and the seabirds. We built ourselves a better shelter than on
                                the previous night, made a good bed of palm leaves, and then went about preparing our
                                supper. We caught some eels—Congo eels I have heard them called—they seemed but little
                                different from a snake, for when hard pressed in the water they would take to the land
                                rery readily, and escape in the bushes. We had not learned all of their habits when we
                                made our first hearty meal of them, and were too hungry the second evening, to be very
                                fastidious. We had a good feast that night, using a piece of the petiole, or leaf stalk
                                of the cocoa-nut palm, to roast our fish with, there being no small sticks growing on
                                the island ¦where we then were, suitable for the purpose. We pointed the smaller end,
                                and inserting it into the fish, held it to the fire, until sufficiently roasted. Not
                                having the burden of table setting, being without cooking utensils,—if we except the
                                petiole—our manner of dining was very primitive; we simply roasted and ate, not waiting
                                to cook enough for a full meal, but sitting by the fire, each with a long piece of the
                                leaf stalk, roasting and eating until satisfied, which was not very quickly done I
                                assure you. As our cooking process was very slow, and our appetites keen at our first
                                feast, I think it was near midnight before we went to sleep, and then we did not sleep
                                long at a time, but arose several times before morning to replenish our fire, not to
                                supply warmth merely, but for the light, which gave to the tall palms a weird look, very
                                pleasant to the eye, and also that we might cook our breakfast; for depending as we did
                                upon our sun-glass, if our fire had gone out in the night, it would have been eight or
                                nine o'clock before the sun would have been high enough to light our fire from its rays.
                                On the morning after the feast described, we ate breakfast of cocoa-nuts and fish, and
                                then started on our return to the mouth of the lagoon. It took us until late in the
                                afternoon to reach the beach where we first landed. We found nothing to mark the visit
                                of our boats to the island, except the remains of a fire some of the men had kindled in
                                the dry palm leaves, which had burned over about an acre. There were two old huts near
                                where we first came ashore; in one of these we slept during our stay on the east side of
                                the tidal passage. We walked out to the seaside where we could have a clear view of the
                                great rolling Pacific; and as we gazed on its vast surface, a feeling of sadness came
                                over us, as we thought of our lonely condition. We could not then see how we could
                                obtain food sufficient to sustain us in good health, for the fish would not bite, hence
                                we had no fish that night for supper, and retired to rest feeling rather gloomy. But we
                                had no fears after the first evening, for the next morning when we came back to where we
                                left the boats, the tide was out and ,ve found plenty of small fish in the crevices of
                                the coral, where they had been left when the tide ebbed. We soon caught enough with our
                                hands for breakfast, without the aid of our fishing tackle. We did not stay but a few
                                days at the place where we first landed from our ship, for looking across the channel
                                through which we entered the lagoon, we could see She ruins of <pb n="98" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                                SHAKER 98 some huts ; and thinking we might chance to find something among them that
                                would assist us in house-keeping, we resolved to visit them. Being good swimmers we
                                could have easily swam across the channel in a few minutes : but seeing so many sharks
                                on our route we did not think it best to take passage with them. We accordingly started
                                by land with the circumference of the island before us ; and many a weary step we trod
                                over sharp coral, shingle beach, and through tangled thickets, before reaching those old
                                huts, just across the channel, within almost a stone's throw from where we started. We
                                traveled part of the time on the outer beach, although the distance was greater, to
                                avoid the almost impassable bushes, which were a species of dwarf palm, that in many
                                places grew to the water's edge of the lagoon. We built us a good shelter hut each night
                                of palm leaves, that would have kept us dry had it rained. We obtained the leaves from
                                groves, or wild nurseries of young cocoa-nut trees, that were to be found at short
                                intervals during our journey. (to be continued.) </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>FARM and GARDEN</head><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Farmers are kings" TEIform="index"/>Farmers are kings
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Farmers are Kings. A writer says that "when Roman virtue was the purest, the
                                        greatest generals cultivated their own farms. Industry and frugality were in
                                        high esteem. 'When our ancestors,' said Cato, 'wished highly to praise a man
                                        they called him a good farmer.' " Leckey tells us a censor deprived a citizen of
                                        his vote because his garden was negligently cultivated. Rome was the greatest of
                                        the old nations, and her history is the most replete with important lessons to
                                        us of the American republic. Before the commencement of her decline under
                                        luxury, King Pyrrhus sent a messenger to the Roman senate to treat for peace,
                                        and on his return the king asked him what he had seen? "I have seen," he
                                        replied, "a senate full of kings." Such were they who had been bred to
                                        agriculture and to arms. If all these kings did not cultivate their own farms
                                        with their own hands, they were occasionally compelled to call one from his plow
                                        to be dictator in a national emergency. Regulus, in the midst of his campaign in
                                        Carthage, asked to come home because his farm was uncultivated and his family
                                        would need bread. He was not permitted to come home; but the senate took charge
                                        of hiss farm. That was when the soldier served his country without pay. No
                                        wonder such a people conquered the world. Everything in history, nature and in
                                        phi- losophy, appeals to the farmer to cultivate an unbounded esteem for his
                                        occupation, and to exert himself, in co-operation with his fel- low farmers, in
                                        placing agriculture at the head of all pursuits in honor aud dignityThis would
                                        afford the surest guaranty to papular morality, public integrity and republican
                                        perpetuity.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Cincinnati enquirer" TEIform="index"/>Cincinnati Enquirer</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A French agricultural journal, the Basse Cour, describes..." TEIform="index"/>A French agricultural journal, the Basse Cour, describes...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A French agricultural journal, the Basse Cour, describes the result of some experiments
                                in potato growing recently conducted by scientific men in Germany, in which it is
                                demonstrated that the "eyes" at the top of the potato produce a much more vigorous
                                offspring than those in the lower part, and the consequence is that those agriculturists
                                who cut their potatoes in half before planting them are not well advised in cutting them
                                vertically, but should always divide them horizontally, planting the upper half, and
                                using the other as food for cattle. </p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Soot, scattered over Plum trees when..." TEIform="index"/>Soot, scattered over Plum trees when...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Soot, scattered over Plum trees when in ' full bloom, has proven very efficacious in.
                                checking the ravages of the curculio, with us. Add 8 qts. of salt to a tree. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hines, Elizabeth" TEIform="index"/>Elizabeth Hines
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> At Enfield, Ct., Feb. 22, <persName reg="Hines, Elizabeth" TEIform="persName">Elizabeth Hines</persName>,
                                aged 55 years. At Enfield, Ct., Feb. 27,</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Slack, Dyer" TEIform="index"/>Dyer Slack
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Slack, Dyer" TEIform="persName">Dyer Slack</persName>, aged 78 years and 10 months. </p></div3></div2><pb n="99" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Progression" TEIform="index"/>PROGRESSION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName">Abraham Perkins </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> Enfield, N. H. 1. I must live, must have my being; 2. Heaven invites me, conscience
                            prompts me, Faith Ev and conscience must be free: Deeper, wider, ery die tate of my soul
                            Urges onward, broader, higher, Every act and upward, heaven ward, Where pure inspi<pb n="100" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> feeling be. Creeds and forms do but oppress me, rations roll. Ope'
                            the golden portals wider, Burdens weighty adding more; Life alone, a Fuller explorations come; More to courtly living substance, All affliction bears me o'er,
                            chambers lead me, Where progressive laws are known. </p></div2><pb n="101" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>HOME TOPICS</head><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Indian chemical soap" TEIform="index"/>Indian Chemical Soap</head><p TEIform="p">To ten lbs. soft water, add two qts. of new rum, fourteen lbs. sal-soda, and you have
                                your soap. Said to be good for Tan, Freck- les, &amp;c. After application wash in
                                soft water. A good chance for the rum-seller to dispose of his rum profitably. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cement for wood and stone" TEIform="index"/>Cement for Wood and Stone</head><p TEIform="p">Take two parts ashes, three parts clay, and one of sand; this composition mixed with
                                Linseed Oil, resists the weather, and is as hard as marble. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lime water" TEIform="index"/>Lime Water</head><p TEIform="p">Two table spoonfuls of unslackcd Lime put into three quarts of boiling water, and well
                                stirred and settled, will give three qts. of clear lime water. It may be kept in stone
                                or glass vessels any length of time. </p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Potato custard pie" TEIform="index"/>Potato Custard Pie</head><p TEIform="p">Take good sized potatoes, either sweet or Irish, boil and as soon as done, remove the
                                skins and rub through a sieve ; add one-half dozen eggs; two teacupfuls of sugar; beat
                                well and add one quart of sweet milk, and flavor with lemon. This makes six pies. One
                                large sweet potato is allowed to each pie—Irish potatoes in proper proportion. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Advertisements" TEIform="index"/>[Advertisements]</head><p TEIform="p"> WE sell a First-Class Plan cheaper than any other house in Americn. Have no Agents, but sell
                            DIRECT TO FAMILIES AT FACTORY PRICfc, and warrant 5 years. Pianos sent for trial at our
                            expense. Illustrated Circular Free, giving full particulars, and names of over 2,000
                            Bankers, Merchants and Families using our Pianos in every State and Territory. Address, TT.
                            S. PIANO r.O., 810 Broadway, 2V". T. We do not accept the responsibility of any articles
                            inserted in The Shaker Manifesto. That department is under the management of the Editor—The
                            Advertisements and general business management is in charge of the Canterbury, N. H.
                            Publisher. We will insert the Cut of any family or society of Believers upon the title page
                            as per Watervliet and Canterbury, on receipt of an electrotype cut thereof! Publisher. A
                            Paper for Young People.—The Youth's Companion of Boston employs the same writers as the best
                            English and American magazines, and no other publication for the family furnishes so much
                            entertainment and instruction of a superior order for so low a price. Among its contributors
                            are Dinah Muloch Craik, Miss Yonge, J. T. Trow- bridge, Louisa M. Alcott, Henry W.
                            Longfellow, Wm. Cullen Bryant, John G. Whittier, and nearly fifty of the best story-writers.
                        </p></div2><pb n="102" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial Notes</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We are using a number of The Bickford Knitting Machines" TEIform="index"/>We are using a number of The Bickford Knitting Machines
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> We are using a number of The Bickford Knitting Machines; and they are very satisfactory
                                indeed, Being among "the wonders in this age" of machinery, their utility and expedition
                                in business should be expe- rienced by all, at so small cost. Material for Fences of
                                loood variety is getting scarce. We must soon accept the alternative of no fences, or
                                rely on the metal ones offered us by Washburn, Moen Co. Please read advertisement of
                                Wasson and Martin several times. They form an enterprising and reliable firm. A Useful
                                Apparatus : JohnBunyan said, that "an idle boy's or girl's head was the devil's
                                workshop." Get them the "Keystone Self-Inker" with complement of type. See Adv.
                                Oftentimes, we are led to regret, that there are unscrupulous persons, who, realizing
                                the solid benefits of judicious advertising, will use it most freely on some useless or
                                worse than useless articles, and soon retire with fortunes of ill-earned gains. But we
                                can still point to thousands who by a wholesome judicious judgment, have used
                                advertising to their exceedingprofit ! and to the most creditable advancement of useful
                                materials. Such, we believe our patrons to be. We have taken considerable and particular
                                pains to acquaint ourself with Dr. Frazier's remedies, and find from those using them,
                                only a good report. His Bit- ters are purely medicinal, and not an intoxicant beverage.
                                Elder James S. Prescott gives his endorsement of Dr. Frazier's Cough Remedy—and he is
                                good authority. . ' For thirty years, Mix, the jeweler and watchmaker, has stood high in
                                the estimation of honest people in these parts. Perry and Robinson's Adv. might have
                                included the famous Ovoid Beet, now being so largely sown for stock feeding. We find
                                Stinson and Co. very honorable in their dealing. Try them. None will regret wearing
                                Boots and Shoes from Schuster's shop. Send in your measure, please. Can we make the
                                Wheeler and Wilson Sewing Machine more famous than it is? It is doubtful. E. C. Koonz's
                                Adv. is a very modest showing, for such extensive and beautiful emporiums for Carpets
                                and Oil Cloths. We hope parties the world over, will send their patronage to this house.
                                We hope "everybody and his neighbor" will send us six cents for a copy of "Plain Talks;"
                                or ten cents, for two copies post paid. It is a pretty book. Please procure it and
                                present it to your friend. Look out for The Buckeye Mower! It is coming; and we give
                                this timely notice. For months, we have been witness of the workings of Coolet's
                                Creamer, and we know of many who endorse what we have inserted as their advertisement.
                                We are confident dairy people will inquire into the arrangement, and send for Circulars.
                                It will pay to do The U. S. Piano Co. enter a challenge to other manufacturers and
                                salesmen. We mean to make ourselves more acquainted with their instruments. People will
                                have Pianos, and they will look where to get them, ia The Shaker Manifesto. Every farmer
                                will yet be his own Miller ; grindingout his "religious bread" as Elder F. W. Evans
                                would say; then they will send for one of Sedgebeer's "Non- pareil." Send for a circular
                                now. We are at a loss to speak as yet, of the best Water Wheel ; but we are at no loss
                                to say that the firms of Leffel &amp; Co. and N. F. Burnham, who enter into friendly
                                competition in our columns, are both most honorable. By reference to our Bro. Philip
                                Smith's advertisement, it will be seen that Farmers, Gardeners, Amateurs, and "the rest
                                of mankind" can get genuine Shak- er Garden Seeds by mail, at the very lowest cash
                                prices. Try the seeds, coming immediately from the grower; it will pay you. The lion.
                                Clute Bros, of Schenectady, N. Y. present most excellent encouragements for parties
                                wishing Engines, Boilers, etc. We know, also, of the "Clute Plough" being the best
                                plough yet created, for all kinds of cross ploughing. </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Modesty" TEIform="index"/>MODESTY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Many persons seem to think that modestyconsists in retirement of manners, or assumed
                                bashfulness when in company. But no person can be truly modest without pure thoughts,
                                pure imaginations, and pure conversations. Let the would-be modest cultivate these virt-
                                ues both in public and in private life. </p></div3></div2><pb n="103" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><!-- 
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p> ATLANTIC WHITE LEAD LIISEED OIL CO. EOBT. COLGATE & Co., The Atlantic White Lead is warranted pure, and
                            is manufactured exclusively from the best selected refined leads and ground in refined Linseed Oil. It is packed
                            in, Casks of 200 and 1000 pounds. Kegs of 25, 50 & 100 pounds. Wooden Buckets (with handles) of 12.5 25
                            & 50 pounds. Also in Tin Pails (with handles) of 12.5 & 25 pounds Cans and carefully put up in
                            wooden cases 4 or 8 in a case— LINDSEED OIL WARRANTED PTJRE. RAW, BOILED AND REFINED, CASKS AJNJD BAEEELS. FOR
                            SALE BY ALL THE LARGE DEALERS. Geo. W. Prentiss & Co., HOLYOKE, MASS., MANDTACTTTKEKS OF IRON WIRE,
                            Orders solicited for TOOTED BROOM WIRE, quality guaranteed. MEDAL. MACHINES. NEW JOSS SIATE AGBICULTUBAL WOBiS.
                            WHEELER &; MELICK CO. MANUFACTURERS OF Threshing Machines, Horse Powers, Shingle Machine*, Horse Forks,
                            Sulkey Horse Rakes, &c. ALBANY., N. Y. 287 PEARL ST. ]V. Y. <pb/> AND OF EVBBY SIZE, -A3STID VABIBTV
                            MADE BY American Tack Co., Faibhaven, Mass. the AMERICAN TURBINE WATER WHEEL FRENCH BURR MILLSTONES, eral FLOUR,
                            MIIL.JL. and I»A JPEPt nvrilil^ Machinery. And full line of mill furnishing. The AMERICAN TURBINE WHEEL produces
                            the best average percentage of any Turbine ever known. Large illustrated catalogue sent free. ADDRESS, STOUT
                            MILLS & TEMPLE, DAYTON,OHIO. SHAKERSEEDS BY MAIL! GENUINE SHAKER GARDEN SEEDS. Farmers and Gardeners;
                            —Get your genuine Shaker Gabden Seeds directly from the grower. Send for Cat- alogue and Pbice List now ready.
                            We will send the Best Seeds of all kinds at very lowest cash prices, prepaid by mail. Attention, Farmers and
                            Gardeners! Try us,—Address PHILIP SMITH. Shakers, N. Y. Seedsman. $20 KNITTING MACHINE. The NEW BICETOBD FAMILY
                            KNITTING MACHINE all complete for $20. (former lowest Price $30-) Delivered at any Express office in the U. S.
                            or Canada Free, on Receipt of Retail Price. Send for New Descriptive Circular. A splendid chance for AGENTS, one
                            wanted in every Town, Exclusive Right of Sale given FREE. Address, BICKFORD KNITTING MACHINE MFG. CO.,
                            Brattlebobo, Vt. In ordering please mention the Shaker Manifesto. WHEELER & WILSON. PE ONOTJ 3STCEX3 THE
                            BEST IN" THE WOELD. HIGHEST AWARD AT THE CENTENNIAL. "Of all the Machines we tested, the Wheeler &
                            Wilson New Machine was the most completely successful, failing in nothing that was given it." FRED. A. PAGET.
                            One of the Centennial Judges of Sewing Machines. From his report to the English Government. HIGHEST AWARDS GIVEN
                            THIS A.T THE AMERICAN INSTITUTE FAIRS OF 1873,1874, 1875,1876 & 1877. At the close of the Exhibition of
                            1877. the Judges announced as their Unanimous Opinion that this machine has already received from the American
                            Institute all the awards and recognition under the rules possible to a Sewing Machine. We do not hesitate to
                            declare it the best Sewing Apparatus in the world. We recommend for it the highest recognition under the rules
                            that can be awarded— THE SPECIAL MEDAL OK1XXV7. AGENTS WANTED WHERE NOT NOW REPRESENTED OE3NTEiE.-A.Ij OFFICE,
                            44= U1VIO1V SQUARE, N. Y. BRANCHES 530 BROADWAY ALBANY, 454 FULTON St. TROY. <pb/> A NEW MONTHLY MAGAZINE, The
                            Primary Teacher DEVOTED TO THE Interests of Primary Instruction in America. ITS WRITERS Are selected from among
                            the most successful Teachers and Authors in the country. Its Discussions Cover the Departments, of Kindergarten,
                            Primary, and Intermediate. IT IS PUBLISHED On the 15th of each month, for ten months of each year (July and
                            August excepted.) ITS PRICE Is One Dollar per year, in advance. Specimen copies sent postpaid for 15 cents.
                            Agents Wanted. All correspondence should be addressed to Thos. W. BickneU, Ed. & T?xxb., 16 Hawley
                            Street, Boston. The Patrons HAEVEST HOME MAGAZINE Only $1.00 Per year! Three Copies $3,00, with Extra Copy to
                            Setter up of 0Mb!! POSTAGE PREPAID. Containing both Short and Continued Stories; Gems of Poetry; Agricultural
                            Department edited by a practical farmer; Scientific Articles; Household; Grange Articles; Children's Corner and
                            Teacher's Department. The Harvest Home is now in its Fifth Volume and the steadily increasing circulation and
                            many letters of commendation received from our readers furnish ample testimony of the worth of the Magazine. The
                            contents are varied to meet the wants of all. Sent in combination with any Paper or Magazine, the price of which
                            is $2.00 or upwards, at the regular price of such publication. Remit, by letter, at sender's risk, unless
                            Registered or P. O. Order. Sample number sent on receipt of ten cents. Address, W. E. DUNHAM, Publisher, Mt.
                            Washington, O. VICK'S FLOWER AND VEGETABLE GARDEN is the most beautiful work of the kind in the world. It
                            contains nearly 150 pages, hundreds of fine Illustrations, and six Chromo Plates of Flowers, beautifully drawn
                            and colored from nature. Price 50 cents in paper covers; $1.00 in elegant cloth. Printed in German and English.
                            Vick's Illustrated Monthly Magazine,—32 pages, flue Illustrations, and Colored Plate in every number. Price
                            $1.25 a year; Five copies for $5.00. Vick's Catalogue,—300 Illustrations, only 2 cents. Address, JAMES VICK,
                            Rochester, N. Y. OUR CORUNDUM POLISHER A Tool for Cutting, Leveling and Polishing Furrows in a Mill Stone. With
                            the use of this tool the miller can make a uniform, level and smooth furrow, and do the work in one-tenth the
                            time required to do it with a Mill Pick. It is acknowledged by millers using them to be the most practical and
                            labor-saving Tool for the miller's use. The frame is iron, with wood handle. The cutting face is a composition
                            of recently discovered mineral, the hardest and fastest cutting material known to the scientific world. One of
                            these tools will last, in an ordinary mill, from one to two years, andean be refilled at a cost of $2. By
                            sending amount you will save expense. PRICE $3. 50. Manufactured by WEED & Co. DAYTON, O. <pb/> lEFFEL
                            WATER WHEELS With recent improvements. Prices Greatly Reduced 7000 in successful operation. FINE NOT PAKPHLST
                            F02 1377. D Tree to those interested. James Leffei & Co, Sprirfgfield, O. 109 Liberty St., iN. Y. City.
                            J3000? XXX SHOE DBja.Zi^V^V3Et. J. SCHUSTER, Manufacturer of and Dealer in BOOTS, SHOES * RUBBERS, No. 16 South
                            Pearl Street JSJL.J*ANY, 1ST: Y. Particular Atteri&ctp. paiU to CUSTOM W0BJC For NINETY DAYS FROM DATE
                            Elegant Table Silverware Cm V secured hv all n compliance with the following conditions: The National Stiver
                            Plati g Com am 104 Cbeauiui Sue.i. fuiladciphia. manufacturers of Pure Coiu Btnuuftrd Silver-Fluted Ware, will
                            scud to »uj one wiio receives tins notice, a Set of Di.inile Kxtru-Plated Silver Spoons, and engrave on each
                            spoon any desired initial. You are required to cutout me loin.whig .Silverware Coupon uucl s. net it to tlie
                            i......e Oorapnnj, wit . your name and address, ami also to enclose with it 75 cents t.. p it all «ntii ges.
                            ine-uuiiiii; cost of eugraving initials, packing, boxing, and express cha ;«. Tin- Si-ooua will be Bent, liy ex,
                            risa lor mail, if you have uo express office), an.I delivered in your lianas without further oom. These Spo. us
                            are guaranteed to ba vr me i.est material, mni equal to tiie bell SllTei-FlaWd Ware made, as the following
                            letter fioni the « naiunt will H-MiT. : ilFFit ok SiTKiHiL Silvh Pi.atiso Co., 704 OlieKtnut St.. Philadelphia.
                            Pa. To whom it may Concern.—Tb« Spoons sent out un er tula anangement we gum antee tire ol b.st quality, Urst
                            heavily plated with pure nickel (the hardost wlnie iii.-tiil known), amt a double-extra plate or pure
                            Coin-Standard Silver added on top of the n okel. thu> rendering them th very Best Sllver-Plated Ware
                            manufaetnre i. \\'r will honor no o'er which A es not wniaiu the Silverware Coupon, aud we ¦will n......mor me
                            Coupon after ninety d»y« from the date of this paper, [Sigued] NATIONAL SILVER PLATING CO., *;04 Chestnut at.,
                            Fhiladi lphla. 81 LV EUWABE COUPON. On receipt Of this Coupon, together with 76 ot-nts to cover all chorees.
                            Including expn ss or niailiiiK enaruvin* and boxing wi: hereby agree to send to any address a set ol' uur pure
                            Coiu-Staudard double-extra plated SI LVER SPOONS, and nn each Spoon eoirrave any deatnid initial. All charge*
                            are to be prepaid hy ¦ hr 75 cents sent us, and the Spouus will be delivered at destination frue of an.i Goo i
                            for ninety days from dnte of thin paper, after which this flounnn Is Dull and void. LSignedJ NATIONAL SILVER
                            PIiATING CO., __________704 Chestnut, St., Philadelj hia. li»u i.r Uih SiX""in i.h |Xa.rm«ut of the following
                            oharges : Six »oltd atnel knives, bind*and luuidXXHMKXlfd piece, t.e.it iteel.douUa nickel and silver plated.
                            *'i : six forks, doui.le ni.kel and silver plated, 85 CM. If nil tbera rood* are dnolrwl, wlxxe tl.x totnl
                            clmreev. which will be 75 cts. rnr siumns, xi for knivns. mid 85 ot*. fof fork»—total, S8.70—thus ntourtnit for
                            $1.70 whn would oo i you munta mnre iu biiv ether way, H' member that each arijotn, except KniVi?8, will be
                            engraved with any initial desired willioat extra cost. IMPORTANT NOTICE. This lihernl offpr ho!d« good for onlr
                            ninety daj-s from date, therefore are notdtburad by remon of the. expiratloa of the time specified. All let-
                            ters orderiug 8ilr«rw»r« should be tiddreaKed direut to the KATIOXAI^ SILVER PT.ATING CO., No, 704 Chestnut
                            Street, PHILADELPHIA, PA. <pb/> Mt. Lebanon, Shaker Village, N. Y.( Sept. 3,1877. Vermont Farm Machine Co.,
                            Bellows Falls, Vt. Dear Sirs :—The two No. 3 Creameries I purchas ed of you have been in constant use for two
                            months The result has been very satisfactory. It answers fully to your guarantee in every particular. You have
                            not claimed one iota too much in your circular. With the submerged cans we have a decided increase o: cream, of
                            a quality far superior to any we have heretofore obtained by the old method of setting in common pans. The
                            butter produced from the cream is much sweeter and finer flavored, and fully sustains the name "Gilt Edge
                            Butter." Yours Respectfully, LEV! SHAW. Mt. Lebanon, Col. Co., N. Y., Sept. 21,1877. Vermont Farm Machine Co.
                            Bellows Falls, Vt. Respected Friends—We fully and gratefully endorse all the recommendations we have seen in
                            favor of Cooley's Creamery; believing it to be all that it purports to be in every particular. We feel confident
                            it is the greatest friend that has ever come to the reliet of the dairy. Our labors are lightened fully
                            one-half, and the results every way superior to all other known ways of setting milk. We would upon no
                            considera- tion go back to any of the old methods, but would consign them all with the antiquities of the past.
                            ANN OFFORD, RUTH BARRY, North Family Shakers. The silverware delivered by the National Silver-Plating Co., No.
                            704 Chestnut street, Philadelphia, is giving entire satisfaction. All orders are promptly filled, and no one
                            need hesitate about sending them money.— Lutheran Observer. For sewing machine supplies such as, Needles,
                            Tuckers, Hemmers, Eufflers, Shuttles &c. in fact, for all parts, and everything belonging to the above.
                            Send to C. P. BELL Telegraph Block, Nashua, N. H. Orders by mail or express promptly attended to. Also PIANOS
                            & ORGANS. Sold, rented or exchanged. No. 5 Beaver Block Cor. SOUTH PEARL & BEAVER Sts, ALBANY,
                            N. Y. A large assortment of Watches an i Spectacles constantly on hand. Repairing in all its branches. Parties
                            answering advertisements: Will you please mention The Shaker Manifesto? I ti tft CE 0 flper day at home. Samples
                            worth $5 free. 40 1U 4/U-A-ddress Stinson & Co., Portland, Me. J. SEDGEBEER'S PATENT NONPAREIL Self
                            Sharpening, Beversibla Motion Crushing and Grinding Farm, Bone and Drug Mills. 12 sizes. Send for free
                            illustrated descriptive Catalogues and Price-list. Address J. SEDGEBEER, Painesville. O. It aims to be a
                            favorite in every family—looked for eagerly by the young folks, and read with interest by the older. Its purpose
                            is to interest while it amuses; to be judicious, practical, sensible, and to have really permanent worth, while
                            it attracts for the hour. It is handsomely illustrated, and has for contributors some of the most attractive
                            writers in the coun- try. Among these are : J. T. Trowbridge, Dinah Muloch Craik, James T. Fields, J. G.
                            Whittier, Rebecca II. Davis, Louise C. Moulton, Mrs. A. II. Leonowens, C. A. Stephens. Edwakd Everett Hale,
                            Harriet P. Spofford, ¥m. Cullen Bryant, A. D. T. Whitney, Louisa M. Alcott. Its reading is adapted to the old
                            and young; is very comprehensive in its character. It gives Stories of AdvenStories of home ture, and School
                            Life, Letters of Travel, Tales, Poetry, Editorials upon Selections for DeCurrent Topics, clamation, Biograph'l
                            SketchAnecdotes, Puzes, zles, ReligiousArtiFacts and Incicles, dents. Subscription Price, $1 75, Specimen copies
                            sent Vee. Please mention in what paper you read this. PERRY MASON dfe OO., 41 Temple Place, Boston. <pb/>
                            BARNES' FOOT POWER MACHINERY. -j r~\ different machines with mJ which Builders, Cabinet I m (Makers, Wagon
                            Makers & _l_v_/Jobbers in miscellaneous work can compete as to QUALITY and PRICE with steam power
                            manufacturing; MACHINES SENT ON TRIAL. Say where you read this & send for catalogue & prices. W.
                            E. & John Barnes, Roekford, Winnebago Co., 111. Cfi PER CENT TO AGENTS, for the illustrated OU Monthly,
                            UNION IN OHEIST, 50 cents a year; also large cash commission or valuable premium to canvassers for THE LONDON
                            CHRISTIAN HERALD, an Illustrated Weekly, containing sermons of C. II. SPURGEON, DR. TALMADGE and D. L. MOODY,
                            interesting articles, serial story, etc. Three Months, 75 cents, $2, 50 a year, from IT. S. Branch Office. Write
                            now for sample copies and terms free, to II. A. KING. 17 Bible House, N. Y. City. THE NATIONAL AGRICULTURIST AND
                            WORKING FARMER, established 1847, a double quarto, 16 page, Illustrated Family Paper, devoted to Agriculture,
                            Stock-Raising, Bee-Culture, &c. Try it! 6 months for 55 cents, or with the ILLUSTRATED PRONOUNCING
                            DICTIONARY, 320 pages, 250 en- gravings, cloth, sent with the Paper a year, both postpaid, for only $1,30, Large
                            commissions or valuable premiums to Agents. Address WM. L. ALLISON, 128 Nassau St., New York. MATHEWS' CARRIAGE
                            MART CONCORD, N. H. Manufacturer of and Dealer in fine Carriages and Sleighs, secondhand Carriages and Sleighs
                            constantly on hand. J3GSt Bargains in the City. BURR STONE GRIST MILLS. THE CE NTE K5T1V I j*V.Ij Prize Medal
                            and Diploma, Eoaf tixx & iiiinui Bridgeport, Conn. TX. A. ItlEK.xxxxx, Shaker Village, N. H.—Agent. BY
                            Wm. A. HINDS. This book contains, in brief a succinct account of all the Communities now in America, and is a
                            valuable, almost invaluable accompaniment of the students of moral reform, and political economy. Price 60 cts
                            The Shaker Manifesto for 1878, and, American Communities §1.00 Such is the title of a Shaker Pamphlet, intending
                            to exhibit, in brief, Shaker Polity and Principles ; being answers to ever-recurring questions concerning The
                            Shakers ; also answering " What shall I do to be a Shaker?" Cost Price, Five Cents, postage One cent. Address,
                            The Editor of The Shaker Manifesto. BLANK BOOK MANUFACTURERS, Electrotypers, Stereotypers, EUNTGKRvWERS ON WOOD,
                            39 & 41 Columbia Street, ALBANY, N. Y. Printers to the Shakers. GOLD Any worker can make $12 a day at
                            home. Costly Outfit free. True & Co., Augusta. Mb. FOR THAT RHEUMATISM. Try Dr. Dean's Rheumatic Pills,
                            the old, popular standard and efficacious remedy. Ask for them at your Druggists. MAYNARD& NOYESAgts.
                            BOSTON. gigip-Answering advertisement: Please mention The Shaker Manifesto. <pb/> 4EgIt is so simple in
                            construction and runs so easily that a child can operate it. 0t" It has the straight, self-setting needle, our
                            improved shuttle, with a perfect tension, which does not change as the bobbin becomes exhausted. j@3=All the
                            wearing points are adjustable, and it combines every desirable improvement. J8x~ Every Machine is sent out ready
                            for use, after being thoroughly tested. Notwithstanding the GREAT REDUCTION I"N PRICES we continue to use the
                            best material and exercise the greatest care in their manufacture. VICTOU STATING MACHINE CO., Western Braael
                            Offloe, 381 West Madison St., Chicago, 111. PEIITCIPAL OJTIC3 and Manufactories, Uiddetowa, Coin. FAMILY SOAPS.
                            By C. BEBKLEY JOHNSON, Senior member of the late firm of E. A. & W. WINCHESTER. The character and
                            quality of E. A. & "W. Winchester's Soap is fully equal, in every respect, to its former Standard. Its
                            Style is plain. It is not garnished with Showy Labels. It recommends itself by its excellence. It is designed
                            for family use more than for trade. Trade generally demands something cheaper, consequently inferior. Address,
                            C. BERKLEY JOHNSON, 16 Chatham St. BOSTON, MASS. Established 1816. The Societies at Canterbury and Watervliet
                            have "used this INT^-for many years, and they unhesitatingly recommend it as a g"ood, reliable article; qf good
                            color, flows freely, ajid does not fade. Mia/yiiard «fc ]NToyesx Boston. Washburn & ffloen ManTg Cc,
                            WORCESTER, MASS. Sole ltauHifie*.ur«s East of Chicago, of A STEEL Thorn Hedge. No other Fencing so cheap or put
                            up so quickly. Never rusts, stains, decays, shrinks, nor warps. Unaffected by fire, wind, or flood. A complete
                            barrier to the most unruly stock. Impassable by man or beast. TWO THOUSAND TONS BOLD AND PUT UP DURING THE LAST
                            TEAR. For sale at the leading hardware stores, with Stretchers sad Staples. Scad for Ulnjnrated Paswhlet Also
                            Manufacturers of all hinds of IRON AND STEEL WIRE. A Speciality made of TINNED BEOOM WIRE. SCHElfECTADY, N. Y.
                            Builders of M~arine, Stationary and Portable Steam HJngines and "Boilers. Shaker Broom Handle Lathes, (the best
                            Lathe in Market.) Engines for Farm work, cutting and steaming feed, driving Threshing Machine^, tfc, from 1
                            horse, to 10 horse power. Send for Price List. <pb/> 8I»3E3CIA.Xi NOTICES. PRICELESS DISCOVERY. A SURE CURE FOR
                            PILES. A sure cure for the blind, bleeding, itching, and ulcerated piles has been discovered by Dr. William, (an
                            Indian remedy,) called Dr. William's Indian Ointment. A single box 'has cured the worst old chronic cases of
                            twenty-five and thirty 3Tears' standing. Xo one need suffer five minutes after applying this wonderful soothing
                            medicine. Lotions, instruments and electuaries do more harm than good. William's Ointment supports the tumors,
                            allays the intense itching (particularly at night after getting warm in bed), acts as a poultice, gives instant
                            and painless relief, and is prepared only for Piles and nothing else. Thousands of cured patients attest its
                            virtues, and physicians of all schools pronounce it the greatest contribution to medicine of the age. It matters
                            not how long or severely you have been suffering, you can be cured. . Mr. Joseph M. Ryder, Cleveland, Ohio,
                            writes: I suffered for years with Itching and Ulcerated Piles, tried remedy after remedy advertised, and
                            consulted physicians in Philadelphia", Louisville, Cincinnati, Indianapolis and this city; and spent hundreds of
                            dol- lars, but found no relief until I obtained a box of Dr. William's Indian Ointment some four months ago, and
                            it has cured me completely. I had a part of the box left which I gave to a friend of mine who had doctored with
                            many physicians, and as a last resort went to the noted Hot Springs, Arkansas, for treatment. He informs me that
                            the Indian Ointment has also cured him of the Piles. It is certainly a wonderful discovery and should be used by
                            the many thousands who are now suffering with that dread disease. 4ST$ 10.000 Reward will be paid for a more
                            certain remedy. Sold by all Druggists. Dr. G. W. Frazier, sole proprietor, Cleveland, 0. DON'T NEGLECT A COUCH.
                            or Cold, when 25 c'ts will binr a bottle of Dr. Frazier's Cough Syrup at any drug store. I't has wrought a
                            complete change in the Cough Medicines, is pleasant as honey and always cures. TO CONSUMPTIVES. 4E5="Dr.
                            Frazier's Cough Syrup used in connection with Dr. Frazier's Hoot Bitters will cuke consump- tion. Standard Steam
                            Laundry, Cleveland, O., Oct. 30,'76. Dr. Frazier. Dear Sir : I feel it a duty I owe to suffering humanity to
                            write you. For some time I was sorely afflicted with a cough, raising bad stuff, with every symptom of being a
                            confirmed consumptive. I tried different medicines and cures without finding relief; 1. also consulted three of
                            our most prominent Cleveland physicians, the last one of which pro- nounced my case serious, and informed me
                            that I could not live more than a few months. About this time, hearing of your wonderful success, I commenced
                            taking your Syrup in connection with your Root Bitters, and was at once benefited, and after using the medicine
                            some two months I find myself entirely cured. TORENOE DUNN. 4Qf"Mr. Dunn again writes, under date of Aug. 4,
                            1877,—Dr. Frazier, Dear Sir; I endorse your medi- cines more strongly than ever from the fact that it is now
                            nearly one year since I was cured. My lungs are to-day strong and sound, having no return of the disease. 4J=The
                            above Medicines speak for themselves. DR. G. W. FRAZIER, Proprietor, Cleveland, O. For sale by all Druggists.
                            8HAICER FLANNELS & KNIT GOODS, CORN BROOMS & BRUSHES. Address, 1ST. A. Hriggs Shaker Village,
                            3NT. H. The National Oragan or those laboring for the ACTUAL, VISIBLE UNITY OF EVANGELICAL BELIEVERS. PUBLISHED
                            WEEKLY AT No. 22 Beekham Street, New York. E. B. GRANNIS, Publisher. CONTRIBUTING EDITORS: JOSEPH T. D13RYEA,
                            D.D. HOWARD CROSBY, D.D. SAMUEL I). BURCHARD, D.D. J. HYATT SMITH, D.I). REV. THOMAS J. MELISH, REV. EDWARD P.
                            INGERSOLL. REV. ANSON G. CHESTER. Smith's Bible Dictionary. 1017 pp. Finely Illustrated. CONYBEARE &
                            IIOWSON'S Life and Epistles of St. Paul. Beautifully Illustrated, OVER 900 PAGES. These volumes are the result
                            of the finest scholarship, the deepest research and the most cultured piety of the present age. They have heen
                            particularly recommended as important aids to an understanding of Holy Scripture, by the. leading divines of
                            Every EVANGELICAL DENOMINATION. To the Pastor, Sunday School Teacher, and every careful student of the Bible,
                            they are indispensible. Each of these Books sells at Retail $4,50. OXJIt PBICE8. 'The paper alone, one year, .
                            $2.50 and either book. . . 4.00 " and both hooks, . . 5.50 Very Liberal Terms to Agents. Specimen Gopies of the
                            Ghurch Union Free. OIxTJXS HA^TJElS. We will send the CHURCH Union to clubs on the following terms : Five
                            copies, one year, for . . $X10.00 Ten copies, " * 18.00 Twenty copies, one year, for . 34.00 2fo premiums or
                            commissions to Clubs. BOOKS BY MAIL POSTPAID. 'Address, E. B. GRANNIS. Church Union, New York. <pb/> TET
                            SHAKER'S CORBETT'S SARSAPARILLA, For Purifying the Blood; best Medicine at all Seasons. Ask for it at your
                            Druggists. Maynard & Noyes, Boston. THE ALBANY WEEKLY TIMES Is in all respects a FIRST-CLASS FAMILY
                            JOURNAL Devoted to the promotion of the interests of the whole people. It is a large THIRTY-TWO COLUMN PAPEE,
                            Well filled with Choice Reading Matter, Literary, Scientific and Political. For its size and the amount of usual
                            reading matter, it is the Cheapest Paper in the Country! T E R M S : One copy one year......$1 50 Ten copies one
                            year......10 00 Twenty-one copies one year . . . . 20 00 Address THE TIMES COMPANY, 401 Broadway, Albany, N. Y.
                            JOHIV WHITELEY. Manufacturer of SHAKER BROOMS, Shirley Village, Mass. AG-ENl1 FOB "The Shaker"—monthly-60 cts.
                            per annum. "The Divine Afflatus"—10 cts. per copy. "The Shaker's Answer"—6 cts. per copy. "The Divinity of
                            Humanity"-3 cts. per copy. Illiberal cliscoixnt in qriaiitities. HENRY CUMMINGS, MANUFACTUREK & DEALER
                            IN SHAKER BROOMS, RAILS, TUBS; OLD GROWTH PAILS & TUBS a specialty. Also all grades of second growth
                            Pails, Tubs &c. HENRY CUMMINGS, Enfield, N. H. "Please send for price list &c. Nicer than Wise:
                            Those whose predjudice leads them to patronize the old monopolists when they can buy Five Ton Hay Scales for
                            $50. freight paid and no money asked till tested—The Lithograph and price list. Jones of Binghamton,
                            Binghampton, N. Y. A Practical Christmas Present. $2 Self-Inker Keystone Press, 100 Printing Letters, Roller,
                            Ink, Iieglets, Leads, Cards, Type, and Outside Case. All for $3. Stamp for Catalogue. W. G. Evans, 50 N. Ninth
                            St., Phila., Pa. | .JOH2ST GS-. KAULBACK, .Tr. Xfe CO. WHOLESALE DBALBB IN WEST INDIA GOODS AND GROCERIES of all
                            kinds, Of unexceptionable quality and low prices, AT 138 aiad 13O WATER St., Boston. Special attention paid to
                            Teas & Spices. DEALER IN TUBS tfe BROOMS Also, SHAKBE PAILS. k CC^1 week ill your own lown. Terms and $5
                            outfit )uDfruc. Address II. IIallettX Co..Portland,Mb. i^aaaEtify «fe kobiivson. —JOBBERS IX— FRUIT, ONIONS,
                            BEANS, CABBAGE, Agricultural Implements,&c. 41 & 43 WABEEN STREET, Syracuse, IN". "ST. Q-rowers
                            of all kinds of Fancy Peas. Aziel D. Perry. L. T. Robikson. </p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>