<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1111" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">11</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">11</biblScope><date value="18811101" TEIform="date">November 1881</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">241- 264</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="11" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="11" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--                     <pb id="p1"/>
                    <p>NOVEMBER, 1881. { 60 Cents Per Annum MANIFESTO. G. A. LOMAS, EDITOR, SHAKERS, N. Y. Published by the United
                        Societies. OUR HOME AT HARVARD, MASS. "And they shall turn to you for a testimony: " 4'Go preach the Kingdom of
                        God!" ADDRESS ALL COMMUNICATIONS TO "The Shaker Manifesto, Shakers, N.D." G. B. AVERY, PUBLISHER. 1881. Vol. XL No.
                        11. The Shaker </p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
--><pb n="241" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Love" TEIform="index"/>LOVE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p"> "By this shall all men know that ye are my disciples, if ye have love, one to another" —so
                            said Jesus. Unity, of ideas and opinions—oneness of sentiment is good. To see eye to eye in
                            doctrine is desirable—beautiful ; but to love and be loved is better than all else. Gates of
                            Hell.—If religious and doctrinal controversy be the Gates of Hell, it must be because the
                            Christ-Spirit has not, therein, a controlling power. Hatred is engendered where love should
                            have been created. Belief is held to be a matter of will, not a result of evidence;
                            consequently it is meritorious, while unbelief is a damnable sin to be censured.
                            Inquisitions grew out of this error. It is a poison Upas tree. Human sufferings, in the most
                            horrible forms, have come logically from those premises. And those who perpetrated
                            indescribable tortures, upon defenseless innocents, did it conscientiously, thinking they
                            were doing God good service. Independent impartiality is one of the characteristics of
                            Scripture writers. The evils of Pharaoh and his people are not more vividly described and
                            fearlessly condemned than are the errors of Moses and Miriam and the rebellious
                            stifFneckedness of the Israelites. The sins of the saint, prophets and martyrs are as
                            faithfully and impartially recorded as are their most prominent virtues. If these things
                            happened in the dry tree of external Mosaic law, what should we not look for under the
                            operation of the New Covenant where the Law is written in the heart and interpreted by the
                            conscience of each individual, the ChristSpirit being their inner life and motive power ?
                            Pains and Penalties.—To inflict these where argument fails to convince was the antichristian
                            method of Church and State organization, the inspiration, or investigation, coming from the
                            Babylon Priesthood. How good it was of God, by means of what the savage, bloody minded
                            priests, like Torquemada, called infidels, to give us a Civil Government, where neither
                            infidels, heretics nor saints can be tortured into uniformity that is not a reality. In as
                            much as the antichristian spirit that indorsed the premises above set forth, upon which all
                            inquisitional proceedings, dictating faith by authority and enforcing uniformity by the War
                            Power, are in the heart of each individual, and will never be eliminated therefrom only by
                            the Christ-Spirit producing PAGE.<pb n="242" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 242 THE SHAKEK MANIFESTO. soul
                            travail, how plain it is that agitation of thought is the beginning of wisdom. Father Joseph
                            is reported as saying : " Brethren, you have a thousand devils in you yet that have never
                            been _waked up." If sleep does not kill them, better wake them up. Agitation is better than
                            stagnation. The Catholic Church, in the day of her power, could maintain the unity of the
                            church by filling her underground inquisition dungeons, as Russia preserves political quiet
                            by working her Siberian mines with her original thinkers and would-be-reformers like
                            American revolutionists. It remains for the Shaker Church to not let the Gates of Hell
                            prevail against her, but to produce unity of thought by freedom of thought—uniformity of
                            doctrine, by spiritual unity—by such love of truth that gives her a fair field and a free
                            fight with error, in which, who ever knew her put to the worst ? Let brotherly love
                            continue, notwithstanding differences.ofidoctrinal ideas arising from constitutional or
                            educational conditions of body or mind. Impartial self examination and independent criticism
                            of each other is a blessed privilege indispensable to our utterance of the desires, or
                            prayers, " 0 do, good Lord, the giftie gie us, to see ourselves as others see us." My
                            confidence in God remains unshaken, that peace is a result of righteousness—that the
                            millennium is a possibility, when the within shall be as good as the without—the bottom of a
                            basket of fruit, equal to the top, and brothers and sisters can exchange ideas and reason
                            together, not like wild beasts who rend and devour, but as Christians in whom brotherly and
                            sisterly love still continues in full operation. Mount Lebanon, Columbia county, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Brave and honest man" TEIform="index"/>A BRAVE AND HONEST MAN</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whittier" TEIform="persName"/>Whittier</byline><p TEIform="p">Formed on the good old plan, A true, and brave, and downright honest man ! He blew no trumpet
                            in the market-place, Nor in the church, with hypocritic face, Supplied with cant the lack of
                            Christian grace; Loathing pretense, he did with cheerful will What others talked of, while
                            their hands were still. —</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thoughts concerning deity" TEIform="index"/>THOUGHTS CONCERNING DEITY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/>ANTOINETTE DOOLITTLE</byline><p TEIform="p"> Bible history informs us. that Tophar— whoever he might have been — in his reproof to Job —
                            whoever he may have been — in a satirical manner, said : " Canst thou by searching find out
                            God? Canst thou find out the Almighty to perfection?" The human mind is active, and it will
                            think and seek out knowledge in some direction ; and it is better to look up and reason
                            Godward, than to live, eat, and drink and die as do the brute creation. The searching
                            investigation still goes on, and the inquiry is made, Who is God? who and what the Christ?
                            The doctrine of the trinity has passed, or is fast passing away ; but yet, among the
                            multitude of church goers, there remain many who cling to the old Trinitarian idea of three
                            Gods conjoined in one ; and if asked to explain what we are to understand by that doctrine,
                            whether it is elementary, or a combination of persons who by some process are consolidated,
                            and made one, the answer would probably be, that it is presumption on our part, in our
                            limited capacity, to undertake to analyze or solve a problem so sacred, and so far beyond
                            our reach ; the wisest thing for us to do is to believe and let it alone. If we continue to
                            ask: What must we believe? the response would be, believe in the Father, Son and Holy Ghost,
                            three in one. Who is the Father, who the Son and who the Holy Ghost? Answer, first, second
                            and third persons in the God-head, but one and indivisible, working in harmony together. Not
                            feeling quite satisfied, again we query: Who is the Son? The answer comes, Jesus the Christ
                            was the only begotten Son of God, who dwelt in the bosom of the Father before the
                            foundations of the earth were laid, was his co-partner and co-worker, but subordinate of
                            course to the Father. Well what of the Holy Ghost ? Hesitatingly they answer, that is
                            somewhat a mystery; but we accept it as true, not because of evidence produced, but the
                            Bible speaks very plainly on that point, and it is the 'word of God, and we do not take
                            issue with the Bible. <pb n="243" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. 243 If Jesus was the
                            Christ, or Son of God, why does the same Bible tell us that he was born a Jew, and was
                            subject to temptation like his brethern in mortal form, and that God cannot be tempted? The
                            answer is, O! he was God in part and man in part; and proceed to explain the matter somewhat
                            in the following manner. The race of man had been so corrupt and wickedly depraved, that God
                            despaired of their ever becoming any better, and He grew angry and impatient with them and
                            concluded to annihilate, or destroy them all. The Son, being second in the God-head, did not
                            perhaps feel the full weight of the heinous crimes and transgressions of the peopled world,
                            as did the Father; and the Son saw much in the race that was good, and worth saving. He had
                            always been His Father's counselor, and he was so filled with pity and compassion for
                            humanity, that he reasoned with His Father, and devised a plan of compromise, and offered to
                            become sponsor for the great human family if the Father would sanction the effort. By taking
                            upon himself the form of humanity, and the temptation and weakness — if not entering into
                            their sinful lives practically — He was by His Father's consent clothed with flesh and blood
                            for a time, and lived and walked with men, until the wicked Jews killed him — which we
                            suppose was a part of the plan — then He ceased to be both human and divine, and returned in
                            a glorified form to the Father. A mystery sure enough! Leaving the Trinity and the Holy
                            Ghost as extremely mystical and false, and affirming that Jesus, according to our
                            perceptions, was not the Christ, only a man baptized with the Christ spirit, we are yet
                            anxious to get at some pivotal point, or central idea concerning God, to whom our thoughts
                            can ascend and revolve around, and unto whom we may direct our praise and prayer. The
                            subject does not, will not rest. People will think and investigate, and for the time being
                            may come to different conclusions, yet truth is bound to triumph in the end. By reasoning
                            from different standpoints, we get Atheists, Deists, Pantheists and Theists. All have their
                            reasons to give for their conclusions ; and it is not our purpose to question their
                            sincerity, if we deny their premises. If we reason intelligently Godward, we must have some
                            data to base our reasons upon. Are we to look to God as an organized Being, or only as
                            elementary? Perhaps none would deny that God is in the elements, but is He manifested in His
                            highest form and capacity through Nature and her laws ? We have not yet seen any better
                            exposition of who and what God is than the one given by Paul, the apostle of Jesus, who said
                            : "The invisible things of Him (God) are clearly seen, being understood by the things that
                            He has made, even His eternal power and God-head," so that we are left without excuse, if we
                            do not reason logically. Is not man and woman in an organized form, who possess intelligence
                            how to use the products of earth, and direct the elements, a higher form of creation than
                            the elements themselves? The Atheists may deny the existence of any supreme ruler of the
                            Universe, because they have no tangible evidence of such a being; have not seen him. The
                            Pantheist sees God diffused in all created things; in the great planetary system, hears Him
                            in the winds, and in the roaring cataract; and traces His handiwork from the loftiest tree
                            to the tiniest leaflet and flower. How can we reconcile the mind to a world of such order,
                            beauty and harmony, without an intelligent director? All of the elements possess force and
                            power, but not intelligence. Whence came man with the capacity to think, or the organ of
                            sight and hearing ? If at some period of time he was materialized from the elements, who
                            conceived the idea of such a formation, and who breathed into him life and gave him the
                            power of speech? Who formed the pattern? It could not have been incidental or accidental ;
                            there is too much method in it. Some persons say God is omnipresent. If this be so, He
                            cannot possess an organized form like man and woman; their sphere is limited. We answer,
                            God's spirit may be diffused throughout, animating all created things, and His care may
                            extend to all, but His closest communings are with the crowning work of His hands — man and
                            woman, who are the highest representatives of the <pb n="244" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 244 THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. Creator of which we have knowledge. Again the query arises, if God is an
                            organized being, where does He dwell? What are His proportions? Who can measure His height,
                            or fathom His depth ? Is He like man to be measured, that can have a garment fitted to His
                            size ? Can we not by the same process of reasoning ask who Jesus was, where he dwells and
                            what his size and measurement may be ? We have never seen Him ; yet we think of Him as an
                            organized being, possessing intelligence, and all the senses of hearing, seeing and feeling,
                            only in a more enlarged, refined, and superlative degree. And certainly, if Jesus was the
                            Christ, the Son of God, as many claim, then He must have been created in the image of the
                            Father, and would bear a marked resemblance to Him. Those who claim that God is not an
                            organized being should be able to point out the source of intelligence; who and what gave
                            creation birth, and how man and woman became possessed of reason ; and who formed the organs
                            of sight and sound. If produced from the elements, who conceived the idea? From nothing
                            comes nothing. What is the worth of prayer or praise if not directed to some source of
                            intelligence? If there are no ears to hear, no eyes to see, and no hearts to feel, how shall
                            we direct our thoughts and upon what shall we con-, centrate them ? Shall we pray to Jesus,
                            to the saints, to the sun, moon or stars, or to the trees, or to the land and sea ? If we
                            cannot "find out the Almighty to perfection," can we not find some germ of truth as a basis
                            from which to reason God-ward ? '' How can we reason but from what we know?" How can we come
                            to any other conclusion than that God is an intelligent being, male and female, with ears to
                            hear and an arm that can save ? Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A good Quaker, eighty-five years of age, whom no one had ever heard speak a cross word..." TEIform="index"/>A good Quaker, eighty-five years of age, whom no one had ever heard speak a cross word...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A good Quaker, eighty-five years of age, whom no one had ever heard speak a cross word.was
                            asked by a young man how he had been able through the trials and perplexities of a long life
                            to keep always so pleasant. He replied, " If thee never allows thy voice to rise, thee won't
                            ever be likely to get very angry."</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="World is what we make it" TEIform="index"/>THE WORLD IS WHAT WE MAKE IT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Manville, Helen A." TEIform="persName"/>Helen A. Manville</byline><p TEIform="p">I've seen some people in this life Who always are repining, Who never, never yet could see
                            The storm-cloud's silver lining, There always something is amiss, From sunrise to its
                            setting; That God's hand made their map of life, They seem the while forgetting. And I have
                            seen a blessed sight To sin-beclouded vision, Some people who, where'er they be, Make earth
                            seem an Elysian. They always see the brightest side — The direful shadows never — And keep
                            the flower of hope in bloom Within their hearts forever. The one can make the sunniest day
                            Seem wondrous sad and dreary ; The other smiles the clouds away, And makes a dark day
                            cheery. This life of ours is, after all, About as we shall make it. If we can vanquish grief
                            and care, Let's haste to undertake it. —</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bridegroom and bride" TEIform="index"/>BRIDEGROOM AND BRIDE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Eads, H. L." TEIform="persName"/>H. L. EADS</byline><p TEIform="p"> Delightful theme to think, talk and write about! Right glad am I to see the critique of my
                            article headed Heavenly Brideship, which appeared in the October number of our S. M. the
                            incongruous yet written so prettily. Its spirit is a model that I would gladly imitate were
                            I able to do so. It gives me the opportunity of more fully expressing my mind on the
                            subject—as well as to point out to the author what I deem to be his mistakes. He seems to be
                            new in the theological arena, hence could not be expected to be clear, logical and concise
                            in his positions and he will doubtless be pleased to have them pointed out. Mistake No. 1 is
                            found in the third paragraph, wherein he seems, unintentionally, to advocate the broad and
                            condemn the narrow way. Forgetting that " wide is the gate and broad is the way that leadeth
                            to destruction and many there be that go in thereat—because strait is the gate and narrow is
                            the way that leadeth unto life and few there be that find it," Matt. 7, 14, 15. <pb n="245" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEK MANIFESTO. 245 It reads thus : " The cause of the failures of
                            religious bodies seems to be that they restrict their ideas, beliefs and rewards to very
                            narrow circles- A few are chosen (although many are called), a few are saved [as Christ
                            truly said]. One man controls ; one set of men possesses authority to interpret all truth
                            especially, any new truth or idea. Exactly so. Christ says : "1 arn the way, the truth, and
                            the life ; no man cometh unto the Father but by me ;" (and whomsoever I send), John 16 : 6.
                            In this line only can any man be saved, and any other mode of salvation is as unnecessary as
                            it is impossible. Child-like obedience to this will save any soul, and who wants any thing
                            more than to be saved ? Again : "I am the door and he that entereth not by the door but
                            climbeth up some other way, the same is a thief and a robber," John 10: 1. Mistake No. 2
                            reads : " Every era seems to demand a change, new men, new thoughts etc." How change? Change
                            our foundation '? Change from one to many ? Change the certain for the uncertain ? Change
                            from the door to some other way ? Christ says : " \ xa.t\i.e truth" In him both'in his first
                            and second appearing "are hid .all the treasures of wisdom and knowledge," appertaining to
                            the redemption of our race, and " This I say lest any man beguile you with enticing words,"
                            Col. 2 : 3—4. If new men are needed it is those who will more vigorously prosecute the work
                            and more closely adhere to the life and teachings of our examplers, for ' no other
                            foundation can any man lrfy,', and all who attempt it will only lay stumbling stones in
                            their way and that of others. It was this very idea of changing, expanding and striving for
                            the world's greatness and applause that caused the downfall of the Apostolic church, which
                            can easily be shown by history. This should warn us to beware of changes and new departures.
                            Mistake No. 3. There can be no greater blunder than to suppose the "gospel of Christ takes
                            hold of and includes in its burdens generation, nutrition and property." Its hands are
                            defiled with none of these. It not only ignores them but calls us up and away from all the
                            generative brood and every thing pertainiup-'to the old Adamic life. Its domain is
                            spiritual. Neither Christ nor Ann ever taught any thing about generating. Their whole work
                            was regenerating. They call us away from the former, no more to touch the unclean thing in
                            thought or word or deed. It hence is not our call or business to try to make generating
                            respectable. In this regard '' ignorance is bliss." The less we know, think, feel, say or do
                            about it the better, only as duty may call teachers to condemn it. Believers and true
                            followers of Christ cannot touch the pitch even in thought without being denied. The best
                            way to proceed in this matter is : when we find our thoughts running in that direction check
                            them and turn them to something else ; almost any other line of thought is less dangerous or
                            injurious to spiritual life. In this, and this way only, can we have a successful growth in
                            angelhood. The same of nutrition and property, when they interfere with spiritual growth.
                            Our exemplars have advised us to eat whatsoever is set before us in thankfulness and no
                            grumbling. The spirit is always weak where there is much complaint about diet ; property is
                            also a cumbrous weight on the spirit, and not unfrequently clogs the wheels of spiritual
                            progress. Mistake No. 4. It does not follow that because " Israel walked by law and statute
                            in things appertaining to this life, the outcome being .Christ, that we must do the same to
                            produce a superior being to Christ. Israel was our type, tliey walked by statute for the
                            natural life, we walk by statute for the spirittial life. When this is attained another
                            higher life is impossible, hence we have no need of higher exemplars than Christ and Ann.
                            They are such now to the human race and ever will be time without end. It reads further : ¦'
                            If Jesus fulfilled the law how am I to escape fulfilling it, if I am his follower 1 " Ans :
                            Because we are not under the law; Jesus under the law was hot our exemplar. Were we to
                            follow him as he did Moses and as Moses did Adam, we should then introduce generation at
                            once, and come up as he and his parents did with our sacrificial doves for sin and then be
                            baptized with water as he was ! This question surprises me to come from any child of <pb n="246" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 246 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. the new creation. He, Jesus, was our
                            exemplar only after being baptized with the Holy Ghost and fire into a resurrected life.
                            After this the Mosaic law was null and void, nothing but a dead letter. The article speaks
                            truly in saying : " Obedience to the higher law abrogated the lower penal law; when the
                            greater was fulfilled the lesser ceased to exist." Very true. Whence then the necessity of
                            blending with that which is confessed to have no existence ? This is no play upon words but
                            stubborn facts. Mistake No. 5. It is a great blunder to mix law and gospel types and
                            antitypes, and then say they must stand or fall together (!) The types ended with John's
                            baptism; after which their fulfillment began. The types under Moses culminated in
                            circumcision. Must this stand or fall along with Christ's circumcision of the heart? Or must
                            any of the ceremonies of the dead law that ceased to exist with Christ continue with his
                            true followers ? All must say nay. Must the works of the law which were natural and the
                            works of the gospel which are spiritual blend and stand or fall together ? By no means. They
                            are distinct and cannot occupy the same plane. The Bridegroom and Bride are our exemplars,
                            our pole star, the foundation pillars of the spiritual temple. We are perfectly safe in
                            following them and " walking as they walked" but very unsafe in any divergence from the line
                            marked out by them. They attained the hig-hest maximum of all possibilities to any human,
                            born or unborn. Who can say more or wish to say more, than '' The prince of this world
                            cometh and findeth nothing in me ?" With this the longings of my soul would be perfectly
                            satisfied. Mistake No. 6. The work of preparation that culminated in Christ never did become
                            universal as stated, and it is not so now, and 'tho that if the Bridegroom and Bride may
                            fill the earth, it will remain the same. It will not change to something else, for the world
                            has no need of any thing else. No mortal nor angel should desire any thing else, but with it
                            be reconciled and satisfied. " I pray you in Christ's stead, be ye reconciled to God " in
                            his order, not out of his order but in it. Seek nothing else, for it is the highest, the
                            purest, most angelic, most holy and most God-like of all conceivable conditions. But further
                            it reads truly : " The bodily sufferings of Christ and Ann were not more than others," but
                            their soul agonies for their own and the redemption of the world exceeded any that ever
                            walked the footstool. It reads further : "Ann Lee reached beyond her [natural] condition and
                            claimed equality [as Bride] with Jesus. Why should her system reject His culture? Answer :
                            It did not do it, but accepted it in all its fulness. The reason why past progress is
                            ignored by their followers is because we have something better than it can offer. The "
                            grandeur and beauty of the promise that God should wipe away all tears from their eyes —
                            that there should be no more crying, sickness, death nor pain, and nothing to destroy in all
                            God's holy mountain " had no reference to the external body—for children will forever stump
                            their toes and bodies, cry for sugarplums, and old and young people sicken and die —but it
                            may be based on the spirtual fact that the " former life had passed away and all things
                            become new and all things of God." Now this thing of diet was agitated in Christ's day and
                            he settled it in few words, why should we not heed them ? One thing is certain — man is a
                            little cosmos which contains within himself a portion of all matter and all depends on the
                            quantity not the quality. Every thing is poisonous in too great quantity, and nothing is
                            poisonous with the proper quantity. What is considered the most virulent poison,
                            sufficiently diluted, becomes harmless. The whole world of science will not gainsay this
                            truth. Mistake No. 7. There would be indeed, as the article says, a great inconsistency in
                            advising Christ's followers to let generation alone and then say to them do as the Gentiles
                            do. " The Gentiles don't let it alone. This would be equal to advising Christ's followers to
                            let it alone and not let it alone." Not so, we mean to let it entirely alone and not do as
                            the Gentiles do, mix up flesh and spirit and then call it holy. Our business is to crucify
                            and put it to death—theirs to nourish and support it. Mistake No. 8. The article says: "
                            Because <pb n="247" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 247 the law was first does not
                            necessitate the assumption that the gospel was subordinate." But as was assumed that the law
                            was the Bridegroom and the gospel the Bride, this was making the gospel subordinate to the
                            law, which was justly com" plained of. By the gospel removing the flesh it did not, as
                            stated, " cause the law to become strong," but the reverse was the case. It thus showed the
                            weakness of the law, because the law supports the flesh while the gospel condemns it. The
                            two cannot be blended. So Christ's followers may leave off the old song of Moses, it is too
                            much of a lullaby and will take up the song of the Lamb and the Bride which inspires " that
                            love that casteth out fear and melts us all into one brotherhood and sisterhood in Christ."
                            South Union, Ky.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tribute of respect: A. C. Stickney" TEIform="index"/>TRIBUTE OF RESPECT: A. C, Stickney</head><p TEIform="p">Deceased at Shaker Village, Met. Co., N. H. Sept. 28, 1881, Michal Blake aged 82 yrs. gone!
                            Gone home at length, to that mighty Unseen Where so many cherished ones dwell. Gone
                            ;-----from our vision, and yet just between Our home and thine, hangs but a vail! Gone do we
                            say? while on memory's page Doth thy record of faithfulness live As a sacred memento for
                            youth, and for age As a legacy worthy to give ? A long life of usefulness reaching four
                            score Has come to an honorable end, For habits of prudence and temperance rare, Prolonged
                            the blest life of our friend. And what though no marble be destined to mark The place of the
                            casket's repose, A statelier column we see, of good works, Built up from life's dawn, to its
                            close. Dear mother, be comforted, many rejoice To greet you in your spirit home, For we
                            almost hear in one gladsome voice,— " You are welcome! " " Most welcome dear one!" Pray take
                            this, our tribute of filial regard To spirit friends where e'er you go: With our promise
                            renewed to earn the reward, Of their blessing and love, here below.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Soul travel, no. 3" TEIform="index"/>SOUL TRAVEL No. 3</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>Giles B. Avery</byline><p TEIform="p"> As previously stated, succeeding the age of pantheism in Greece (which once was typical of
                            the state of all Europe), commenced a belief in a Spirit God, and an age of inquiry set in,
                            because the simple Indian or Hindoo iaea of a " Great Spirit" God did not satisfy the
                            growing soul of humanity. In the earliest ages of this belief in a Spirit God the human
                            understanding (as if prophetically pointing out the sacrifice of the corrupted animal, or
                            carnal nature, in order to become affinitively united to the Divine Intelligence) projected
                            the idea of acceptable worship of their God by the sacrifices of animals for propitiation
                            for their sins, and to secure His blessing, and even men were thus used. Still their ideal
                            Spirit God was so far distant from man, that star worship was introduced, and as befitting
                            the gloomy state of the nightshrouded soul, dense forests and sacred groves constituted the
                            temples for worship, in those benighted ages : but in this, soul manifests instructive life
                            and reason viz.: that to become spiritually enlightened and enlivened, the mind and senses
                            must be withdrawn from the bustles and contentions of war, the strifes of worldly ambition
                            and selfishness, and often from even the cares of civic life, for a season. And, as if
                            prophetic of the millennial period, the priesthood of this age consisted of prophetesses as
                            well as prophets, who joined in the ceremonials of administrative duty. Now mankind began
                            seriously to inquire, What is the human soul? The animal senses alone are prone, ofttimes,
                            to deceive us, hence, the philosophic mind exclaims, Have we any criterion of truth? " The
                            moment a suspicion that we have not, we realize what may be truly termed intellectual
                            despair." But Pythagoras became almost deified by the Greeks, because he revealed to their
                            understandings the fact, that though through the senses the visible and audible may deceive
                            us, we may, nevertheless, find absolute truth in that which is alto- <pb n="248" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/>
                            THE SHAKEK MANIFESTO. gether separate from material nature, as for instance, in the
                            relations of members, as — two and two are four ; in the fact that the length of any two
                            sides of a triangle, taken together, are greater than a third side, etc., etc ; thus, though
                            beset with many deceptions of the senses, we are surrounded by a world of truth. Thus
                            reason, which has objects of her own, a world of her own, has guides to truth for man. . As
                            Sophists, the Athenians arrived at the conclusion that there is no conscience, no good nor
                            evil; no philosophy; no religion; no law ; no criterion of truth. But man, thus conditioned,
                            caunot live. If his speculations in nature give eim no reliable data of truth, he will seek
                            in other directions. "If he cannot prove, by physical arguments^the existence of God, he
                            will-like Socrates, accept that great fact as self-evident, needing no demonstration thus
                            instituting an age of unquestioning faith ; faith in a spirit, living God ! " In an ever
                            existing soul, whose happiness alone consists in the practice of virtue. ¦ But the changeful
                            and oscillating nature of man, which is ever inclined to extremes in life, next proceeds to
                            anticipate a fulness of Divine favor, by totally denying all the pleasures and comforts left
                            to man by the field of reason and substituting the fatal sophism of the necessity of
                            physical torture, almost to the extent of human endurance, as practiced by the stylites of
                            Syria, who with a view of separating themselves more completely from earth, took up their
                            abode on the tops of pillars, on which they remained, without ever descending to earth, and
                            exposed to all the variations of a Syrian climate. Also by the Anchorites of the third
                            century of the Christian Era, who fled to deserts and dens and caves of the earth, and
                            imposed on themselves tortures of body as a substitute for the glory of martyrdom for the
                            Christian cause. Thus, as though the acme of virtue consisted in the entire ^abnegation and
                            crucifixion of all the comforts and pleasures of the physical senses, in order to understand
                            and comprehend intrinsic truth, and please God, an order of extreme ascetics arose,
                            characterized by the example of one Diogenes, who lived in a tub, and Antithenes of Sinope,
                            who made virtue to consist in ignorance, a contempt of learning, of honor, of the possession
                            of property, and who enduring the suffering of the loss of all physical comforts prided
                            himself in ragged garments ! Much of the error of this course was manifested by the
                            admonition of Socrates to Antithines, thus — " 1 see your pride through the holes in your
                            cloak." Thus is presented to our view the oscillatting, repeating, re-repeating and
                            overlapping experiences of soul travel, and the struggles the human family has waded through
                            — the trials the soul has had, to become recognized as man's true and omniscient guide and
                            tutor ; and she is still a child, in the school of her Divine Parent and Tutor. " A review
                            of Grecian History presents: First, a legendary, prehistoric age; second, an age of
                            credulity; third, a succession of ages of speculative inquiry — faith, reason, etc.; and
                            fourth, an age of decrepitude." " The legendary age was closed by geographical discovery ;
                            the age of credulity by the criticism of sophists ; the age of faith by the doubts of the
                            skeptics ; that of reason by gradual decrepitude, introduced by the licentiousness of the
                            Roman Conquerors." These phases of national experience manifest in a considerable degree the
                            experience of myriads of individual souls in life's journey. It is said "there are four
                            grand topics in Greek philosophy. First, the existence and attributes of God; second, the
                            origin and destiny of the world; third, the nature of the human soul; and fourth, the
                            possibility of the criterion of truth." "The results the Greeks arrived at were, first, of
                            God. He is, and is All-powerfal, All-perfect, eternal, and is necessarily One God ! It is
                            conceivable that God can exist without the world " (this denies pantheism) "but
                            inconceivable that the world can exist without G-od." Notwithstanding this conclusion, they
                            eventually drifted into pantheism—that the universe itself is God, and that all animate and
                            inanimate things belong to His essence. Here was again repeated the Indo-European
                            experiences of untold ages before, viz. : 248 <pb n="249" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO.
                            249 " There is no God independent of nature !' But this conclusion does not meet and satisfy
                            the demands of the human soul, consequently cannot be a fixed idea in the understanding of
                            man; he presses his inquiry further to find an Eternal Parentage, mindfuj of his necessities
                            and ministering to his needs. Of the origin of the world, the Greek Alexandrian, Roman and
                            Christian ages all agreet hat the world is an emanation from God. The theology of Vedas also
                            centered in the same conclusion— "the universe is the thought of God, the shadow of God." Of
                            the soul, Greek philosophy determined it to be a portion of Deity Himself; it contemplated a
                            past eternity, a future of immortality. It is said the Greek and Indian Hindoo philosophy
                            agreed on this point; but the latter determined perfect happiness to consist in entire
                            passiveness and repose, or unconsciousness — '' nirvana " — absorption into God! Not in the
                            practice of goodness and the rewards of virtue. But the living, pulsating soul of man never
                            could rest in this conclusion, without every thing in life tending to decay and dissolution;
                            soul must have a heaven of continuous manifestations of ever-flowing bliss, catering to an
                            eternal consciousness of being. For a criterion of truth early philosophers^ as really as
                            those of modern date, discovered that it was not safe to rely on the senses of man, for
                            these were often deceptive. A straight stick thrust into water obliquely to a right line
                            from the eye looks crooked; a small substance rapidly rotated assumes, to the sense of
                            sight, a solid circular plane ; echo illustrates the possibility of deluding the sense of
                            hearing ; taste, touch and smell also practice their delusions upon us in mul titudinous and
                            varied forms. Thus philosophers from age to age have been baffled to find the immovable
                            fulcrum for the lever of abstract truth in facts mani fested by experience; thus the
                            fullness of abstract truth is only to be obtained by continuous search and revelation. And
                            the utmost degree of reason possessed by any one individual soul, or any number of souls in
                            any one given age of man, has not attained to the absolute measure of the fullness of
                            abstract truth. Thus the prospective future is full and aglow with prospective revelation of
                            truth and hope celestial, while the present, to those who regard and rely on the present
                            revelations of truth as steps in the ladder of progress for climbing to higher realms of its
                            mansions, is never cheerless. The human mind, trained by the experiences of past ages, is
                            expanding; the soul is traveling upward to higher and still higher altitudes of truth by the
                            revelation of God. Truth is a building that hath foundations eternal in the embraces of the
                            Infinite, and that which experience has once demonstrated as truth ever remains the same,
                            and all truths when fully comprehended harmonize as parts of one stupendous whole — one
                            glorious building of God — while the living soul of man is reaching out its feelers for
                            still more of truth and its harvests of supernal joys; but these are manifest alone to the
                            pure in heart and true in life, those who live in obedience to the laws of God to them
                            revealed, and the march of whose souls is in the pathway marked out by the hand of Him who
                            rules the destinies of universes by laws unchangeable, as well as those of worlds, or the
                            individual intelligent inhabitants thereof. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Funeral day" TEIform="index"/>FUNERAL DAY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. Anderson</byline><p TEIform="p">A tribute to the memory of President Oarfield. Ring myriad bells your requiem chimes to-day!
                            Ere unto dust our martyred dead we lay, Tell all the world before the sun departs A nation's
                            love, that flows from saddened hearts. Through air and sky, send forth the solemn peal, A
                            universal mourning to reveal! While all the people with united voice. Speak praise of him
                            who was their willing choice. The hum of busy marts is hushed and still, A hallowed spirit
                            steals o'er vale and hill. Earth yields in rarest gifts her latest bloom, To wreathe the
                            bier and lift the gathered gloom. <pb n="250" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 250 THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. Our great
                            souled chief! Ah! many tongues will tell How by the bold assassin's stroke he fell With
                            mortal wound, that care and skill defied, Which sapped the strength of manhood's flowing
                            tide. His wondrous fortitude and will sustain Through agonizing weeks of ceaseless pain, The
                            frame that feebler grew, till that brave soul The powers of life no longer could control.
                            The ocean moaned, the fair sun hid his face, A sable shadow veiled his resting place, O'er
                            trembling wires the last sad message sped Around the world ; " Our president is dead." And
                            quick response came like a throb of woe From kingly courts and e'en from stations low, One
                            feeling reigned, one impulse deeply thrilled, And kindly sorrow every kindred filled. Bright
                            omen of the blessed bye and bye. When love shall form the happy gordian tie That none can
                            break, when o'er the whole wide world. The star-gemmed flag of peace shall be unfurled. Did
                            not the silvery belt that gleamed on high, And spanned from west to east the evening sky,
                            Portend a meaning deeper than we drew, A bond twixt Continents both old and new? The
                            thronging millions of our own free land With heads uncovered by their altars stand And seal
                            their countless prayers with unfeigned praise, And bow in trust to " God's mysterious ways."
                            No North, no South, but one true family, Blend in one common flow of sympathy, Be this a
                            link these sacred hours shall weld So firm that hate forever shall be quelled. Who knows his
                            virtues best pcan on them dwell, His grandly rounded life shall history tell For loftly aims
                            inspired him from his youth His guiding motive was unsullied truth. The press and pulpit,
                            with each other vie In eulogies that place our martyr high, In all that gives to man a
                            lasting name, A niche of grandeur crowning mortal fame Bear gentle to the tomb the last
                            remains Of him whose broad career wears no dark stains. Whose private honors rest in hearts
                            of grief Where precious m emories britig sweet relief. Our prayers, our wishes are not
                            vainly lost Through all the trial, sacrifice and cost, The rod that chastens blooms with
                            life anew. A nation stricken shall be strong and true. God of our fathers! look on this our
                            land,"! For its salvation now stretch forth thy hand, Bless him,who steers the mighty ship
                            of State With sight to shun the sands and shoals of fate. May congresses of noble souls gone
                            forth. Send power and inspiration down to earth, That men may feel where sacred duty lies
                            And give our country counsels good and Purge fraud and selfishness from human laws Help
                            justice plead her rights in every cause, And haste the day when full equality Shall make all
                            nations from oppression free. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakeress on American institutions" TEIform="index"/>A SHAKERESS ON AMERICAN INSTITUTIONS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/>Antoinette Doolittle</byline><p TEIform="p">WHERE THEY ARE DEFECTIVE, AND THE REMEDY. To the Editor of the Brooklyn Eagle: America is a
                            great land, with her millions of inhabitants, her boundaries reaching from sea to sea, her
                            trade and traffic almost beyond the limit of computation, and her vast resources
                            inexhaustible. Her heavily laden ships of commerce are seen upon many waters. Her schools,
                            seminaries and colleges are numerous, and are yearly expanding and widening their doors to
                            admit more students ; and as fast as one class finish their course of studies, and vacate
                            their seats, others hasten to fill them. If lessons of real virtue and integrity should be
                            learned and accompany all upon their egress from the popular institutions of learning, our
                            country would be filled with'bright, intellectual stars, studding the moral universe. As it
                            is, thousands upon thousands emerge from the seats of learning, and launch out upon the
                            world with cultured intellect, and to them and to ncoming generations, the nation looks for
                                <pb n="251" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 251 perpetuity and the maintenance of her
                            free institutions. When we look over her large territories and compute the number of
                            inhabitants of home born and those of foreign birth who have vfound our shores, and taken
                            shelter under the American Government, and pledged allegiance thereto, the question is often
                            asked with profound and prayerful solicitude : " Shall the republic live, and her free
                            institutions be preserved ?" Her government machinery has already been amplified until it is
                            vast in proportions and moves as many wheels within wheels. If anything occurs to clog or
                            hinder the action of one of those wheels, the jar is felt, and causes agitation, if it does
                            not throw the whole machinery into disorder and confusion, and result in revolution. In the
                            past, as in the present, this momentous burden and weighty responsibility rests upon the
                            shoulders, and is intrusted to heads and hands of male rulers. The voice of woman is not
                            heard in legislative halls— only as a special favor upon certain occasions, and by special
                            request. Why this bondage and servitude on the part of woman ? Has she no heart to feel ? Is
                            she destitute of reasoning powers, and unable to plead her own cause and the cause of her
                            down trodden and oppressed sisters, who do not find redress from wrongs inflicted upon them
                            at the tribunals, where male rulers alone preside, judge and decide ? A change must and will
                            come in this respect. Woman possesses latent powers that need to be brought into action,
                            both for her own benefit and the good of humanity. Presidents and Government officials take
                            their wives with them to the Capitol of the United States, but when they enter the executive
                            chambers and legislative halls, it is more like gayly plumed show birds, to attract
                            attention, and to listen to a finely framed speech from the lips of some eloquent male
                            orator, than of feeling the weighty responsibility of helping to guard the nation's honor,
                            and of co-operating with her brother man in sustaining and framing just laws. When woman is
                            taken into the national councils and allowed to speak and fact her part, she will think more
                            of developing her mind than of decorating the outward orm. Virtue is said to be a plant of
                            slow growth. So we may think in regard to the rights of woman. Ever since Eden was despoiled
                            of its beauty and glory by transgression and man's confession of his weakness, " She gave
                            and I did eat," and a voice was heard saying : " He shall rule over thee," man has exercised
                            his power over woman to a marked degree. On the American Continent as dense forests have
                            been cleared and wildernesses turned into fruitful fields, and the march of civilization has
                            been onward and upward, and religious freedom proclaimed through the Declaration of
                            Independence, the iron chains which still bind and hold the female part of the population in
                            the basest ignorance and servitude in the far East have been melting away as the ice bound
                            streams yield to the rays of the sun in Springtime. What a notable change has been wrought
                            in this respect within the last two decades. At that time, with the exception of Shakers and
                            Quakers, it was of rare occurrence that woman's voice was heard, even from the freest
                            platform then erected. Now, women ecturers are passing from village to villages and from
                            city to city, and even to foreign lands, giving free expression to their houghts concerning
                            the problems of human life and its destiny, and are treated with courtesy. True, popular
                            theologians and ministers of the gospel, according to St. Paul, strictly adhering to his
                            opinion that woman's voice should not be heard in the churches, would not dare to allow a
                            woman to occupy their pulpits, even for a limited space of time while they go to the seaside
                            to recuperate, or to some hill or mountain to inhale the healthful breezes, and ward off
                            malaria, or other physical diseases. How would it answer, seeing such is the case, if the
                            female portion of the population who feel interested in the matter should withhold their
                            contributions from the renowned churches, and create a fund of their own, and build a few
                            small churches wherein they could feel at home and give expression to their own religious
                            views and convictions, if they have <pb n="252" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 252 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. any,
                            irrespective of the opinions or dictation of man ? Never mind if the steeple is omitted ;
                            perhaps the Lord will be as well pleased without the tall spire as He would be with it.
                            Mount Lebanon, M. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prentissiana: Shaker and Ism" TEIform="index"/>PRENTISSIANA: Shaker and Ism</head><p TEIform="p">Virginity and Community are the Shaker. Inherited and educational notions are the Ism, in
                            which novitiates are wont to enshrine the Shaker as the chestnut is enshrined in the bur, to
                            keep off squirrels. This procrustean bedstead Ism, however needful in humanity's
                            unprogressed condition, subsides in proportion to mental expansion. "We live in an age of
                            wonders. By the aid of unseen forces, the world moves as it never moved before. The day
                            dawns—the Day Star arises—The Shaker—the good, the true, the beautiful—will never be lost to
                            humanity. Truth loving souls are being prepared to shove the car of human progress, to
                            sublimer elevations. Creed. "1 believe in God, the Father Almighty, Maker of Heaven and
                            earth, and in Jesus Christ his only son, conceived by the Holy Ghost.'* The above is the
                            august commencement of the creed drilled into my juvenile cranium in St. Armand, P. Q., in
                            1807, by an old Scotch pedagogue. Creed, or no creed, 'tis manifest enough that somebody
                            must do the conceiving, as well as^the begetting. If we have a Father in Heaven, why not a
                            Mother in Heaven ? But, is Ghost the prettiest name for our Holy Eternal Mamma ? We
                            would'nt, for a common-sized world offend, but how would it do to moderize our creed thusly
                            ? We believe in God—Father and Mother— the vitalizing center of all vitality—and in all
                            their Sons and Daughters, who, by indomitable self-discipline, squaring their every act,
                            word, feeling and thought by their divinest ideal of the true dignity of man and womanhood,
                            come forth in the likeness of their Holy Eternal Parentage. We believe in the communion of
                            saints— better not have any sins—and in the resurrection of the body, clear above all
                            unphysiological — all indelicate appetites and indulgences—Amen.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., Oct. 12, '81" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., Oct. 12, '81</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Brainard, Jane M." TEIform="persName"/>Jane M. Brainard</byline><p TEIform="p"> Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., Oct. 12, '81 Respected Editor : — I have been impressed a number of
                                times of late to write; as often as the feeling would forcibly come, I would think our
                                little Manifesto is well filled by able writers that I consider far more capable than I
                                am, yet the feeling is icrite; if you should not approve I shall feel released and
                                perhaps your waste basket will hold it. While looking, and thinking of the condition of
                                my fellow beings, the feeling it brings seems overwhelming. I see them indulging in all
                                the follies that we that have been blest with the gift of God have been enabled to leave
                                ; spending their time trying to live on wTorse than husks, and seemingly know no better.
                                I think how can we who have received the words of eternal life, have proved their
                                efficacy., have been encompassed with the power of truth, sit supinely idle while so
                                many millions are suffering and wandering in the dark ways of desolation and death ? I
                                think, O that I had a trumpet that I could sound to the ends of the earth and encompass
                                it, endowed with power to cause them to see and realize their situation ! It seems to me
                                that every one that has a privilege and a home in Zion are called to do something — are
                                responsible ; from those that are in possession of five talents to the one that has but
                                one. If we can do no more let us pray that the fire of truth may be conveyed through our
                                little Manifesto. The inward feeling with me about true Christianity, and where
                                Christians were and are correlated I found was the Zion of God on earth where the sun
                                was outvied with <pb n="253" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. 253 splendor; knowledge
                                came by reading a book that I opened at random ; felt an envious sensation that passed
                                over me and left a feeling that I never had before, and have never wished to get rid of.
                                I turned to the title and saw it was written by the Shakers, and I do believe the
                                influence and inspiration therein was conveyed through the letter. I pray that holy
                                spirits may influence and move all that have been blest with the least spark of Gospel
                                life, to write as if their pens were dipped in Gospel fire — the fire of truth — that
                                every word may take effect. This is my earnest prayer. </p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mount Lebanon, Oct. 17, '81" TEIform="index"/>Mount Lebanon, Oct. 17, '81</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, A. G." TEIform="persName"/>A. G. Hollister</byline><p TEIform="p"> Mount Lebanon, Oct. 17, '81 Bro. Albert : — Grace and peace to you, and love from the
                                Father and Mother of Spirits, and may you have strength to go forward and complete the
                                work to which you are called The Shaker Manifesto does not abate in interest, but each
                                succeeding number comes to us freighted with good things. Long may it live to deal
                                spiritual bread to the hungry, and living waters of truth to the thirsty, who have no
                                other means of supply. " I see a light — a light on the distant horizen, its rays
                                illumine the path of the pure and betoken the coming morning. Take heart.take heart,
                                brave volunteers, the shades of night are dispelling : cast away all doubts, lay aside
                                all fears, this light God's truth is revealing." Yea it is even "here, and with you, and
                                in other places. Your brother in love, </p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ayer, Mass., Oct. 16, '81" TEIform="index"/>Ayer, Mass., Oct. 16, '81</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, Elijah" TEIform="persName"/>Elijah Myrick</byline><p TEIform="p">Ayer, Mass., Oct. 16, '81 Dear Bro. Albert : — As to the editor for which you advertise,
                                I vote with Elder J. B. V., and agree with him that such valuable "acquirements" should
                                still continue as in the past to be public property. The October Shaker Manifesto is par
                                excellent. I need not name contributors, who never fail to interest and instruct; but
                                permit a word of commendation of Bro. Thomas Smith's article, than which no sounder
                                sentiments have graced the columns of the Shaker Manifesto. And also Elder J. B. V-'s
                                article, I am with him and the writer to whom he refers as relates to worldliness and
                                fashion. The subject might receive much more attention with profit. A clean separation
                                from the world and its fashions is of more importance than all the theological
                                controversies that ever spoiled white paper or made brethren less brothers. * * * Dear
                                Albert: — Persevere in well doing. Please accept my love, and the love of all in our
                                humble home.</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="North Union, O., Oct. 16, 1881" TEIform="index"/>North Union, O., Oct. 16, 1881</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Andrews, Watson" TEIform="persName"/>Watson Andrews</byline><p TEIform="p">North Union, O., Oct. 16, 1881 Editor Manifesto : Dear Brother — This morning comes the
                                October number of our hopeful Manifesto of faith and principles ; and I might add,
                                consummate philosophy. Are we to fear the setting of this morning's sun, and if so, to
                                rise no more? Is this light, whose celestial rays can pierce the gloom of " nature^
                                darkness" and illumine the path of purity to the region of " Christian Rest; " is it to
                                be put out? We hope not, we pray not, at the same time we doubt not God's will will be
                                done. Dear readers, do but think of going back to the days when we had no such monthly
                                visitant! When this oft renewed, tangible assurance of general union was not! Look at
                                the last number ; starting out with the hint that we may be professing too much,
                                practicing too little of the Christ life; and proceeding to a complete portrayal of
                                "True Christian Rest." It might at first thought be considered a sufficient guide of
                                Christian travel; but it is not. This is an insidious thought. In activity only is there
                                life; fixity is death. Having attained to this glorious rest, or at least to such degree
                                of spiritual sight as to realize the correctness of the author's views upon true rest,
                                shall we sit down and fold our hands, as regards laboring for other souls ? content to
                                regard " the Summer over, and the harvest ended," since we are saved? On the contrary
                                let us <pb n="254" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 254 THE SHAKEK MANIFESTO. work harder, retrench more, and
                                contribute liberally to the support of our Manifesto op Light, in money and sympathy ;
                                and so very sparingly of criticism, that not only our truth-spangled banner, but its
                                poor overworked Editor may " still wave," is the prayer of many needy readers. P. S. The
                                inclosed money is $1 for postage, and $5 as a present for yourself, from our beloved
                                trustee, Eldress Lydia Cramer, in behalf of the sisters. With much love from all, Truly
                                yours,</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Desirable salvation" TEIform="index"/>THE DESIRABLE SALVATION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">In our day, when heretical opinions are too numerous and too widely circulated to be
                                compassed and commented upon by the pen—heresies concerning the truthfulness or
                                untruthfulness of early religious instructions—we can well afford to drop all the
                                dissensions of theological controversies, and ask, where, and in what is the most
                                desirable salvation ? In the word " salvation," we have the thought expressed, of the
                                act of being saved. The religious convert epitomizes all his or her efforts by saying :
                                " We want salvation." The simple question here presents itself—what do we want to be
                                saved from ? Is it from the participation in the pleasures of known sinfulness ? or do
                                we mean by the expression, that with all our participation in worldliness and
                                sinfulness, we desiro to be preserved from the penalties of such participations ? Too
                                frequently our real sorrow for sin comes not until we have surfeited ourselves by
                                engagements therein. Too frequently, we might truthfully express our desires for
                                salvation, as hopes to escape the just rewards of our doings—the consequences of known
                                evil practices. As truly as effects follow causes, so truly must we suffer or enjoy the
                                results of our conduct. There may be Saviours unto us, who can and will shield from us,
                                by an overwhelming sympathy, the full strokes following violated laws ; but at some
                                future time we must bear the full results for ourselves. We all love the name of
                                Saviour. We were all early taught to associate this qualifying term with Jesus the
                                Christ. We religiously look with hopefulness for a power radiating from Him, to baptize
                                us with the essences of salvation. Common sense, in religious matters, is fast taking
                                precedence of untruthful theologies, and is opening the eyes of millions to see wherein
                                Jesus Christ really was, and really is our Saviour. It is teaching us, that inasmuch as
                                He was saved from the commission of sin in that degree only ivas He saved from its
                                consequences. Common sense is teaching its disciples to know that so long as we will to
                                sin, no power on earth, Jesus, nor the God of Heaven, can save us from the rewards of
                                sin. The question again comes up : How much salvation do we want ? In all the ages past,
                                there have arisen reformers—godly men and women — teaching salvations in excess of the
                                past. Moses was a mighty saviour to his people; and inasmuch as the people regard Mosaic
                                instructions they are mightily saved. But Moses living, nor Moses ascended can save the
                                violators of the laws given through him from the stripes which must in%ditioixiut <pb n="255" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 255 evitably ensue. Neither can the lovely
                                Jesus Christ spirit prevent us from the consequences of unchristian lives. If we want
                                only the salvation obtained by the strict observance of Mosaic discipline, we can have
                                it only by such observances. But if we are desirous of the superior salvations from the
                                practices of unchristian lives, we can only have these by studying the rules of life
                                particularly practiced by Jesus, living by these rules ourselves and thus only be saved
                                from the punishment of unchristian sins, by a failure to engage in them. -^V</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Excelsior" TEIform="index"/>EXCELSIOR</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The special teachings of the Shaker church and its handmaiden The Manifesto are very
                                simple, very easily learned and understood, yet are comprehended, as yet, by but few
                                individuals. These special teachings have a constant reference to a higher life than
                                simply characterizes the moral civilian While admitting all the good that preceded
                                Jesus—while viewing the grand strides of progress made by humanity in civil and moral
                                life centuries before the Christian era began—yet the Shaker church comprehends a
                                grander step higher, heavenward, for humanity to take, in that, forsaking all the
                                pleasures of the lower, animal plane—all pleasures forsook by Jesus—and an ascension to
                                angelic spheres by unworldly, angelic, engagements. However good marriage and private
                                property, war and all worldly ambitions may have been and are, yet we teach of a life
                                still higher and better, more angelic, than is ever found where these are practiced. And
                                that such life example was and is witnessed in the founder of the Christian religion,
                                who renounced those worldly peculiarities, however good, to go up higher into the realms
                                of eternal virginity ; universal love ; ^eace and non-resistence ; and absolving himself
                                from all worldly ambitions, lived a life which all the truly Christian acknowledge as
                                worthy of the invitation " Follow Me," and which, compared with any previously or
                                subsequently different life, to be Excelsior, the highest and best. -¦</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our correspondence" TEIform="index"/>OUR CORRESPONDENCE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">EDITORIAL NOTES. Should we print one-half of the letters, referring with deepest regret
                                to the subject of suspending The Manifesto, we should have room for nothing else. While
                                we acknowledge with deep gratitude the appreciation of our own people as expressed to
                                us, yet we wish we could better acknowledge our high admiration for so many kind and
                                hopeful expressions that The Manifesto continue on its course, from so many individuals
                                in every part of our country, and some from foreign lands. We were quite unprepared for,
                                and truly affected by, so many messages of love and good will.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dr. Thomas' case" TEIform="index"/>DR. THOMAS' CASE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">As we feared, the Methodist church has done the very foolish thing of condemning Dr.
                                Thomas for daring to express a better religion than John Wesley knew of one hundred and
                                more years ago ; and for being true to <pb n="256" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 256 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO.
                                his conscientious convictions of God's goodness and mercy, though differing from the
                                steel-clad errors of a creed bound ""church. We agree with The Christian Union, that the
                                only effect of his expulsion " will be to add one more to the increasing number of
                                useful and influential independent ministers, and to give notice to young men who have
                                aspirations toward the ministerial profession that they enter it at the risk of
                                purchasing peace by the abnegation of their manhood, or liberty at the hazard of a
                                perpetual and bitter battle with their own brethren in Christ. Every such exclusion of
                                one earnest but independent thinker from the order of the ministry shuts out a score of
                                others whom the pulpit of to-day can ill afford to lose."</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>The Children's Grotto</head><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nothing to do" TEIform="index"/>NOTHING TO DO</head><p TEIform="p">"What are you going to do this afternoon, John? " inquired Mr. L-----, the merchant, of a
                                boy that was seated upon the steps of his store. " Oh, nothing!'" was the indolent
                                reply, and John Simmons looked as unconcerned as though there was no need of his ever
                                doing any thing. Mr. L-----said nothing until another boy came along, walking very fast
                                and whistling a merry tune. " Halloa, Harry, what are doing to-day ?" he inquired. " I
                                am going to the North Woods," the boy replied, scarcely stopping to answer Mr. L-----. "
                                But wait a moment. I want to talk with you," Mr. L-----said again. " I have not time
                                now. Can you not wait until I come back ? " Harry answered, half-impatiently. " You
                                see," he said, as he suddenly remembered that he was not treating Mr. L,-----with the
                                respect that was due him, " father gave me this afternoon for a half-holiday, and I am
                                going into the woods to have a regular good time with Dick andWill Benson, I'll call
                                to-night if you please Mr. L-----." " All right, Harry ; I want to hire you to help me
                                in the store when you are not in school," and Mr. L-----turned back into the store
                                again. So Harry hurried away as happy he could be, and John Simmons remained about the
                                village spending the bright Summer afternoon — wherever his fancy led him. The
                                difference between these two boys was, that Harry was a bright, active boy, always busy
                                about something, and cheerful and happy; while John Simmons was idle and spiritless, and
                                so, of course, he had " nothing to do." He could not well be any thing else but a "
                                loafer " when shut up in a filthy bar-room, with the fumes of liquor and tobacco all
                                about him. Two years have passed away since the above occurrence, and to-day Harry is a
                                clerk in Mr. L-----'s store, wearing the same cheerful face and happy smile ; John
                                Simmons is an idle vagabond, with degradation written all over his young face. Beware of
                                the boy that has " nothing to do," for it is very probable that the devil will have
                                something for him to do, if he is in this bad predicament. It is better to sometimes
                                have too much to do than "nothing to do." It is better to be thoroughly tired of real
                                hard work than to be weary of doing nothing. The devil always chooses Ms workers from
                                the " do-nothing" class, for others have no time to even listen to his suggestions. The
                                wide-awake, active boy, even though full ©f fun and frolic, stands a better chance of
                                keeping clear of the tempter than one who has "nothing to do."</p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prize essays" TEIform="index"/>PRIZE ESSAYS</head><p TEIform="p">In a certain town, some years ago, there was a large school, which had an excellent
                                master, and stood well as regards learning, but the conduct of the boys was any thing
                                but satisfactory. Lying and stealing were of frequent occurrence, and no punishment had
                                any effect. The master consulted Lord Shaftesbury. On inquiry he found that out of
                                school the boys were much given to tor- <pb n="257" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 257
                                ment animals, and that they were the terror of all the dogs and cats in the
                                neighborhood. " I think I can help you," said his lordship ; and then he announced that
                                he intended to give a prize for the best essay on the subject of kindness to animals.
                                The boys took to the idea ; they set to work at once ; their minds became interested;
                                they began to feel a regard for their creatures which were the subject of their
                                inquiries, and the result was that not only did one get the prize, but the whole school
                                profited.</p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good for evil" TEIform="index"/>GOOD FOR EVIL</head><p TEIform="p">For the purpose of illustrating the difference between Christianity and " mere
                                benevolence," as he called it, the late Elder Knapp used to releate that a man, tired of
                                keeping his great dog, tied one end of a rope around his neck and the other to a stone,
                                took him out upon a pond in his boat for the purpose of drowning him, and in throwing
                                his dog overboard he lost his balance and fell over also. The loop around the dog's neck
                                was large and slipped over his head, and he soon came to the surface, where he found his
                                master, unable to swim, struggling wildly, and just ready to perish. The dog, regardless
                                of his master's evil intent, and faithful unto death, seized hold of him, drew him
                                ashore, and saved his life.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Book Table</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="North American review" TEIform="index"/>North American Review</head><p TEIform="p">The North American Review : A most invaluable monthly. We purposed an extended notice of
                                the October number, but were unable to find space so to do. The November number is at
                                hand, filled with the choicest thoughts of deepest writers upon a great variety of
                                subjects. We would call attention of deep thinkers to this magazine. D. Appleton
                                &amp; Co., New York.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Illustrated Household Magazine" TEIform="index"/>Illustrated Household Magazine</head><p TEIform="p"> The Illustrated Household Magazine : We would call attention to the advertisement of the
                                same on our cover, and recommend all desirous of such a valuable and interesting paper
                                to take advantage of its beautiful and liberal terms. We do not know how the publishers
                                can afford it, but their presents are worth double the subscription price of the
                            paper.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>Agricultural</head><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Making and using manure" TEIform="index"/>Making And Using Manure</head><p TEIform="p"> .—No man is a truly successful farmer who allows his land to grow poor while he is
                                cultivating it. He may make money for the time and put it in his pocket ; but he does so
                                at the cost of his successors. He takes something from the soil and gives nothing in
                                return. This cannot be continued without beggary of both land and occupant. Writers and
                                speakers tell of the "inexhaustible" fertility of the West. I never hear that word
                                without being annoyed. We might as well say that we can consume a part and still have
                                the whole: not only that, but keep on doing so for an indefinite term of years, and
                                still have the whole remain to us. This mistaken idea of an inexhaustible soil has
                                already cost the West a great sum of money, and will inevitably cost many millions more.
                                Much has already been done to put an end to this ruinous system of forever taking from
                                the soil and putting nothing back. Much remains still to be done.— Tribune.</p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Those who own orchards..." TEIform="index"/>Those who own orchards...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Those who own orchards over twelve years or more of age will find a great advantage in
                                applying a moderate top-dressing of old or fresh manure. It seems to have an almost
                                magical effect upon the fruit. The trees will be more likely to bear every year; they
                                will give heavier crops, and the fruit will be finer. It will do as well, nearly if not
                                quite, to draw the manure out in the winter, and spread over the ground such manure as
                                accumulates from the animals in the stables and barn-yards. On the first thaw or rain
                                the earth will ab sorb all the soluble washed portions. The mistake should be avoided of
                                placing the manure in heaps at the foot of the treetrunks or in small circles about the
                                trees. Trees only twelve years old have already covered the whole ground with their
                                network of their roots beneath the surface. Wood ashes are always useful.—Dirigo
                            'Rural.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The man whose thoughts, motives, aspirations and feelings are all devoted to himself..." TEIform="index"/>The man whose thoughts, motives, aspirations and feelings are all devoted to himself...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The man whose thoughts, motives, aspirations and feelings are all devoted to himself is the
                            poorest of judges as to the effect of his own action on other men</p></div2><pb n="258" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>Home Topics</head><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="An attractive and economical tea cake..." TEIform="index"/>An attractive and economical tea cake...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">An attractive and economical tea cake, and oue which might appropriately be called
                                "children's delight," is made by taking enough white bread dough to make a small loaf ;
                                knead into it a tablespoonful of butter or lard, two tablespoonfuls of English currants
                                ; let it rise until it is very light, then bake in a moderately hot oven. If you have
                                any of the tin cans in whicli tomatoes are put up, use one of them for a baking tin, and
                                bake this cake in it. You will have a pretty round loaf, and the size and appearance of
                                the slices are also pleasing. Graham bread seems actually to taste better if baked in
                                one of these tins.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To soften putty and remove old paint" TEIform="index"/>To Soften Putty and Remove Old
                                Paint</head><p TEIform="p"> .— Take three pounds of quick stone lime, slack the lime in water, and then add one
                                pound of American pearl-ash. Apply this to both sides of the glass and let it remain for
                                twelve hours, when the putty will be softened, and the glass may be taken out without
                                being broken. To destroy paint apply it to the whole body of the work which is required
                                to be cleaned; use an old brush, as it will spoil a new one ; let it remain about twelve
                                or fourteen hours, and then the paint may be easily scraped off.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Useful plumb rule" TEIform="index"/>A Useful Plumb Rule</head><p TEIform="p">.—Get a good piece of board, a little larger than may be desired, and strike a circle on
                                its face at each end, taking care that they are both struck from the same centre. Plane
                                straight on the edge until the sides of the circle are touched on each side. When this
                                is done the piece of board will be of parallel breadth. Then a line drawn through the
                                centre, with a slit for the cord and an opening for the play of the bob, will complete
                                the plumb.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="For burns" TEIform="index"/>For Burns</head><p TEIform="p">.—When cooking, you often burn your fingers or arms, and there is not time to turn to tie
                                them up. Take a piece of hard soap, and dipping it in water, rub it over the spot.
                                Continue to do this two or three times until the surface is thoroughly covered. It will
                                be found to afford great relief. Or you may dip your burned hand in the soft-soap bucket
                                and hold it there a few moments, and you will experience the same relief. Aunt
                            Addie.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To weld cast steel without borax" TEIform="index"/>To Weld Cast Steel Without Borax</head><p TEIform="p">—Take copperas, 2 oz.; saltpetre, 1 oz.: common salt, 6 oz.; black oxide of manganese, 1
                                oz.; prussiate of potash, 1 oz. All should be pulverized and mixed with 3 lbs. of nice
                                welding sand. With this preparation welding can be done at a cherry heat.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="This also vanity?" TEIform="index"/>THIS ALSO VANITY?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pomeroy, Rachael" TEIform="persName"/>RACHAEL POMEROY</byline><p TEIform="p"> I spied two drops on a clover stem, Pale jewels loosely strung ; The sun god twinkled over
                            them, Twin spheres of flame they hung, And all the zeal of ardent day Was focused in each
                            globule gray. An errant breeze the clover shook — Each trembled toward its brother ; Or ever
                            I had time to look One slid into the other, And lo ! a single spark of dew, Where side by
                            side had glimmered two. I watched the traitorous, thirsty sun, Sucking the cordial up, Till
                            all its essence was undone, Till drained its crystal cup, And wind and cloud and blazing
                            sky, Knew better where it was than I. So have I seen chance comrades — say — Atomies on a
                            random spray, Idling the dewy hours away Some careless morning ; A solemn shaft of rosy
                            frame — Unfelt its sign,unfeared its name — Quick destiny to each it came — Without a
                            warning. The sun of love, it smote them through ; The wind of love, it blew ; it blew; They
                            shyly guessed — they surely knew What fate was doing ; No charm could will their lives
                            apart, Could sunder glowing heart from heart, Or chain the restless counterpart Its mate
                            pursuing. And yet— what if — tormenting fear ! Day were so bright and earth so dear, Breath
                            were so sweet and skies so clear, Only to snare them ? Grudging Eternity, go by. These want
                            to live — they would not die. More life—for that they pant, they cry — Good Death, oh, spare
                            them !</p></div2><pb n="259" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New sect" TEIform="index"/>A NEW SECT</head><p TEIform="p">THE DUNKERS ESTABLISH THEMSELVES IN ST. LOUIS—SOME OF THE PECULIARITIES OF THE BRETHREN. A
                            new sect—new to St. Louis—has lately been established in the city, that of the church of the
                            Brethren, or German Baptists, commonly known as Dunkers. Last night they held a meeting at
                            Sturgeon Market Hall, and had prayer and sacred song. The larger portion of the congregation
                            was composed of women, who all wore white lace caps and plain gowns or dresses of dark
                            stuff. Daniel Vaniman, of Virden, Illinois, presided. He is a tall, well-built, plain spoken
                            man, with heavy black beard—most of the brethren grow beards—full face and well developed
                            forehead. He was assisted by John Metzger, of Cerro Gordo, Illinois, a very old gentleman,
                            on whom infirmity had laid its heavy hand. Brother Vaniman briefly explained to a Globe
                            Democrat reporter the peculiarities of the church. They baptize only those who have come to
                            the use of reason and are capable of sin. Both the administrator and recipient of the rite
                            go down into the water, and the candidate, while kneeling, is immersed three times, as "Of
                            the Father, of the Son, and of the Holy Ghost" is said. The Brethren also lay hands on those
                            they baptize. They never go to war, nor to law with one another. Disputes are settled in the
                            church. If a member will not pay his just debts, when able, he is expelled by a majority
                            vote. They do not join secret, oath-bound societies, and will not lift the hand and swear in
                            court, simply affirming. " The brethren and sisters adorn themselves in plain and modest
                            apparel, and utterly repudiate the vain and ever changing fashions of the world,
                            comprehending ' the plaiting of the hair, the wearing of gold and of pearls, and of costly
                            array.' " In connection with the Lord's Supper and Communion—which is a literal supper,
                            including soup—they wash one another's feet. One brother rises, girds himself with a towl,
                            washes and wipes the feet of another, and this latter one does the same by the next, and so
                            on. The sisters perform the same ceremony on the other side of the house. They practice the
                            salutation of the holy kiss aud the elders anoint the sick members with oil. Each church is
                            under the supervision of an orerseer or bishop. Ministers of the first and second order are
                            elected by the church, each member, even the children, having a vote. Last night there were
                            instances of this. Brother Vaniman asked : " Does this suit you, brother Charles? And you,
                            sister Saxy ? And you ? And you ?" Besides, there are deacons, or overseers of the poor. The
                            church in St. Louis comprises fourteen members, many of them late soldiers in the Salvation
                            Army. To-day, at 2 p. m., Charles Funk is to be baptized, and, as he is sick, will be
                            carried in a wagon to the water. At 7 p. m., at the hall, the Lord's Supper, Communion, and
                            Feet-washing will take place. The Brethren are eager that every one should come and witness
                            these proceedings.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Brahmin" TEIform="index"/>THE BRAHMIN</head><p TEIform="p">The Brahmin, says Dr. Scudder, has intellectually no superior. No man can mingle much with
                            them and not have his wits sharpened. They are the learned men of the country. The Sanscrit,
                            " queen of languages," is their native tongue, and its vast literature has been their grand
                            field of mental training. The Brahmin is almost white, wonderfully neat, begins every day in
                            the water-tank, eats no animal food, believing that if he does he shall pass through as many
                            transmigrations after death as there are hairs on the animal of which he eats. Physically
                            these people are of splendid form, majestic heads, and carry themselves grandly.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="He who hates an enemy..." TEIform="index"/>He who hates an enemy...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> He who hates an enemy, gives him more reason for animosity; he who shuns him, creates the
                            suspicion that he hates him ; he who forgives him, always triumphs over him ; he who loves
                            him, makes him a means of good.</p></div2><pb n="260" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lines upon a caged lark" TEIform="index"/>Lines upon a caged lark
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">LINES UPON A CAGED LARK. A cruel deed It is, sweet bird, to cage thee up Prisoner
                                    for life, with just a cup And a box of seed, And sod to move on barely one foot
                                    square, Hung o'er dark street, midst foul and murky air. From freedom brought, And
                                    robbed of every chance of wing, Thou couldst have had no heart to sing, One would
                                    have thought. But though thy song is sung, men little know The yearning source from
                                    which those sweet notes flow. Poor little bird ! As often as I think of thee, ' And
                                    how thou longest to be free, My heart is stirred, And, were my strength but equal to
                                    my rage, Methinks thy eager would be in his cage. The selfish man ! To take thee
                                    from thy broader sphere, Where thousands- heard thy music clear On Nature's plan;
                                    And where the listening landscape far and wide Had joy, and thou thy liberty beside.
                                    A singing slave Made now ; with no return but food ; No mate to love, nor little
                                    brood To feed and save ; No cool and leafy haunts; the cruel wires Chafe thy young
                                    life and check thy just desires. Brave little bird 1 Still striving with thy
                                    sweetest song To melt the hearts that do the wrong, I give my word To stand with
                                    those who for their freedom fight, Who claim for thee that freedom as thy
                                right.</quote></cit><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Chambers' journal" TEIform="index"/> Chambers' Journal.</bibl></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wheel-barrow religion" TEIform="index"/>WHEEL-BARROW RELIGION</head><p TEIform="p">Richard Baxter said a good thing when he said of some one who lived in his day, that they had
                            a " wheel-barrow religion." They went when they were shoved. It would be hard to find a
                            better name for the religion of many who live now. Many people are like wheel-barrows, and
                            no Paddy up and down a steep incline has harder and more weary work than those whose duty it
                            is to push them. As often as not they are quite empty. They take what is put into them,
                            whether it is good or worthless. Whatever knowledge-feeling of duty they have, is proof of
                            some one else's work. They are easily upset or emptied, and they have no power or will to
                            get up again. They move as long as a firm hand grasps them and keeps them going. As soon as
                            they are left to themselves they stop, and are helpless and useless unless they are lifted.
                            When they move, it is up and down, backward and forward, never getting any further, or
                            showing any life of their own.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hints to the philanthropic" TEIform="index"/>HINTS TO THE PHILANTHROPIC</head><p TEIform="p">A lady in Roxbury, having little money but much time, told beggars who came to her door that
                            they must need more than she could give, but if they would leave their names and addresses
                            she would go to see them and make some arrangements for their relief. She did not succeed in
                            getting a single address, and finally no more beggars came, though her neighbors were still
                            called upon. At a house where tramps often came for breakfast or supper, it was decided that
                            each should be required to do some work —pulling up grass in the sidewalk, cutting grass,
                            sawing wood, or doing any of the minor things that always need to be done about a small
                            place. At once a change was perceptible, few tramps came,' and of those who called there was
                            seldom one unwilling to work for a meal. The unworthy knew the house and avoided it. In both
                            of these cases the beggars had not the false and frequent excuse that the societies to whom
                            they were sent would not or could not aid them; and both prove what the societies have
                            always claimed — that no beggar should be helped at the door even to food which he eats then
                            and there. Gifts in that way help to create the class of persons who live upon the
                            community. Mrs. Mumford of Philadelphia, in an excellent article on " Cold Pieces " (a form
                            of charity which argues much against our domestic economy), tells of a tramp who said : <pb n="261" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 261 " Why should I work? The women folks on my
                            route take good care of me. Some gives me my victuals, some gives me my clothes ; the city
                            furnishes free lodgings in winter and the country in summer; and why should I run my
                            constitution down with hard labor and get no thanks?" A child's plea for help touches most
                            of us at once, and the clothes or the money are freely given ; but ought we not to consider
                            that the child learns faster than her elders, and that she is storing up for her maturity a
                            lesson of dependence on strangers?</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Best thoughts of best authors" TEIform="index"/>BEST THOUGHTS OF BEST AUTHORS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Various" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> Among all the other virtues, humility, the loveliest, is pre-eminent. It is the safest
                            because it is always at anchor; and that man may truly be said to live the most content in
                            his calling who strives to live within compass of it. —Ricliter. While a man is stringing a
                            harp, he tries the strings, not for music but for construction. When it is finished it shall
                            be played for melodies. God is fashioning the human heart for future joy. He only sounds a
                            string here and there to see how far his work has progress. — Beecher. The sublime is the
                            temple-step of religion as the stars are of immeasurable space. When what is mighty appears
                            in nature, — a storm, thunder, the starry firmament, death,— then utter the word " God "
                            before the child. A great misfortune, a great blessing, a great crime, a noble action, are
                            building-sites for a child's church.— Riehter. Though thou see'st another openly offend, or
                            even commit some enormous sin, yet thou must not from thence take occasion to value thyself
                            for thy superior goodness ; for thou canst not tell how long thou wilt be able to persevere
                            in the narrow path of virtue. All men are frail, but thou shouldst reckon none so frail as
                            thyself.— Thomas a Kempis. Running water is sweet. It is your tight tank that gets slimy,
                            and putrid, and unwholesome. He who opens his eyes to see the wants and woes of other
                            people, and goes to work to relieve them, will somehow insensibly forget to make a fuss
                            about his own trifles. —(Jongregationalist.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Autumn" TEIform="index"/>Autumn
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">AUTUMN. Gently the autumn leaves are falling, And seem to retiring summer
                                    calling, Your time of blooming now is done ; You've acted nobly and pleased every
                                    one ; Even the little birds think it time To fly to some more pleasant clime ; The
                                    flowers droop and hang their head, And silently retire to their earthly bed ; And in
                                    quietness they dormant lay Till warm April showers seem to say, Awake ! robe
                                    yourself as soon as you can, And melt the frozen heart of man. As the birds homeward
                                    flying go It reminds us that we'll soon have snow ; Then only the snow birds fly
                                    around In search of food on the frozen ground. Autumn winds with their rude
                                    caresses, Disrobe summer of its verdant tresses : As its time in life is passing
                                    away, And soon it will leave it bare and. gray. Autumn seems to carelessly forget
                                    its vows, As it rustles the leaves from the boughs, Yet how thoughtful, for the
                                    winter's storm, Will not break its limbs, and be kept warm, Its feet, by the leaves
                                    profusely strewed, With their bright variegated colors hued. Soon we will have a
                                    destroying frost, Yet in nature's economy nothing is lost; Nature, as well as man,
                                    needs some rest; In spring it will burst forthwith vigor blest. The flowers will
                                    return, the birds all sing, And smiles of happiness to man it will bring. While the
                                    leaves are falling, remember, all, The future is prepared by the pleasant
                                fall.</quote></cit><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Reflector" TEIform="index"/>Reflector.</bibl></p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The pleasant inhabitants of Saxony..." TEIform="index"/>The pleasant inhabitants of Saxony...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The pleasant inhabitants of Saxony are perhaps the richest in the world. Want is scarcely
                            known among them. Once a year a fair is held by the farmers, at which the horses are
                            exhibited and a race called the flag race is held. The animals used are only plow horses,
                            and not trained for any such sport, and all sorts of comic scenes occur. — Small trees grow
                            at intervals on the race course, and the riders attempt to fell them as they pass. Whoever
                            succeeds first in this endeavor is the winner of the race, is presented with a flag, and
                            becomes the village hero on the spot. Man passeth away, but principles endure forever</p></div2><pb n="262" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Universal love" TEIform="index"/>UNIVERSAL LOVE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stickney, A. C." TEIform="persName"/>A. C. Stickney</byline><p TEIform="p"> Canterbury, N. H. 1. Blest be that 2. Be lifted 3. Its real universal love For up O virgin
                            throng With subjects, grandly rise Su— which the chris open hearts perior in tian aims:
                            embrace their sway Whose source in The princi— O'er earthly God pie loves is which and found
                            above purifies tendencies, All And In narrow el e— action, <pb n="263" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE
                            MANIFESTO. 263 human vates the word and claims race, way. As towers The love Then let the
                            which us lofty moun seeks the good join this noutaintop Above the distaut of all, In ev'ry
                            land and ble band And seek the joy, the sea, So clime, "Which hope; The stands the merits of
                            this vitalizes, cheers, for freedom which this love will love, In its gives, And ren bring,
                            Found al di ders ways vinity. life sublime. "Higher up."</p></div2><pb n="264" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Time" TEIform="index"/>Time
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">TIME. In the great square of a city, dreamily, a figure stands. With the water
                                    dimly flowing through its eyes and lips and hands, And the throngs that pass and
                                    ponder, tha weird masterpiece sublime Little think it is the picture of the solemn
                                    lapse of Time; Of the thoughtless lapse of Time, With its melancholy music and its-
                                    sad heart-broken rhyme. Oozing, trickling, bubbling, gleaming, Laughing, weeping,
                                    sobbing, streaming, Wailing, murmuring, sighing, dreaming, Flowing, flowing on. So,
                                    stand we that fountained statue, God, great masterpiece of art, And the lapse of
                                    time is flowing on thro' each oblivious heart; Seconds, minutes, meeting, fleeing
                                    into days, and months and years, Swell the rapids of the ages till at last Time
                                    disappears, With its flood of hopes and fears, Through life's dimly-lighted valley,
                                    thro' the valley of our tears. Tinkling, plashing, rippling, sleeping, Bounding,
                                    sparkling, dancing, leaping, Foaming, billowing, tumbling.sweeping, Gliding, gliding
                                    on.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Princetonian" TEIform="index"/>A Princetonian.</bibl>A Princetonian
                            </cit></p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Doing something for posterity" TEIform="index"/>DOING SOMETHING FOR POSTERITY</head><p TEIform="p">The movement to encourage the growth of trees continues. In New England many old farms are
                            being replanted or are growing up into forests. In many of the picturesque old villages
                            improvement associations are at work beautifying the local habitations with shrubs and what
                            will yet become noble trees. There is an astonishing amount of tree planting all over the
                            extreme west. Indeed, in the prairie countries groves and bits of wood have become a
                            necessity to protect the farm-house and barns from the fierce winds which occasionally visit
                            plains not intersected by mountain ranges. There is still much needless waste of wood, and
                            forest fires are altogether too frequent. Indeed, the day must come when the Federal
                            government will be empowered to protect our forests, as well as to give authority to replant
                            certain sections, so as to secure a supply of water for rivers which would dry up if the
                            feeders at their headwaters were removed. But until Congress is empowered to act, by a
                            change in the organic law, the disposition to plant trees by individuals and corporations
                            should be warmly commended. Some of the railroads are helping on the good work by offering
                            prizes for trees planted on either side of their tracks, and some of them have the good
                            sense to spend a little money in tree and shrub planting near the stations. Travelers on the
                            Union Pacific road will recall the tasteful surroundings at the stations where the travelers
                            stop for their meals. It would pay all the railroads to do as much for the traveling public
                            in every part of the country.—Demorest's Monthly. The author of " Home, Sweet Home," J. II.
                            Payne, a poor but genial-hearted man, says the London City Press, was walking with a friend
                            in London, and, pointing to one of the most aristocratic hauses in Mayfair, he said : "
                            Under those windows I composed the song of ' Home, Sweet Home,' as I wandered about without
                            food or a semblance of shelter I could call my own. Many a night since I wrote those words,
                            that issued out of my heart by absolute want of a home, have I passed and repassed in this
                            locality, and heard a siren voice coming from within those gilded walls, in the depth of a
                            dim, cold London winter, warbling ' Home, Sweet Home,' while I, the author of them, knew no
                            bed to call my own. I have been in the heart of Paris, Berlin, London or some other city,
                            and have heard people singing ' Home, Sweet Home,' without a penny to buy the next meal, or
                            a place to put my head in. The world has literally sung my song until every heart is
                            familiar with its melody. My country has turned me ruthlessly from office,and in my old age
                            I have to submit to humiliation for sread." I believe that virtue shows quite as well n rags
                            and patches as she does in purple and fine linen. I believe that she and every beautiful
                            object in external nature claims some sympathy in the breast of the poorest nan who breaks
                            his scanty loaf of daily bread.</p></div2><pb id="p29" TEIform="pb"/><!--                     <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>