<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ss0310" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">Shaker and Shakeress</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Society</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Mount Lebanon, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">3</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">10</biblScope><date value="18731001" TEIform="date">October 1873</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">73-80</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="3" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="73" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="10" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--  
                        <p>Vol. III. No. 10. PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETY. F W EVANS Editor/ ' Mt' ^e*>anon, Col. Co. N. Y. October,
                        1873</p>
                    --><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Judgement" TEIform="index"/>JUDGMENT</head><p TEIform="p">" The Lord will be a spirit of judgment to him that sitteth in judgment, and strength to them
                            that turn the battle from the gate " of entrance into his and her own soul — the inner
                            thought, the will. Through the will all good and all evil enters the citadel of our being,
                            our inmost desire, our prayer; for prayer is desire and will united to use the utmost power
                            of the person to accomplish the object desired and willed. Prayer is our wished-for
                            selfhood; and judgment is the light of the coming day shining upon the past history of the
                            individual— the truth as now revealed. Repentance — confession, and forsaking—is progress —
                            conformity to present abstract principle, regardless of the sacrifice of the old for the
                            new. A distiller, liquor dealer, or a drunkard, is convicted by a temperance preacher, and
                            drops the business, or ceases from the practice ; that is religion. A generative man or
                            woman hears the testimony of Jesus, obeys it, and becomes a Shaker. " Fear God, and worship
                            and give glory to Him, for the hour of his judgment is come," applies, first, individually,
                            then to a society composed of those individuals, and next to a nation. " Now is the judgment
                            of this world," when there is an influx of new truth (more light) upon abstract principles,
                            and the " still small voice" creating a whirlwind in the emotions, an earthquake in the
                            habits, and a fire of intense desire and an unconquerable and indomitable will in the soul.
                            The latent fire and abstract truth of one cycle is the practical truth and burning zeal of
                            the next that succeeds. When an individual is converted, or a society or a nation is
                            founded, there is always a reserve of the spirit of truth sufficient to reconvert, progress,
                            or explode by revolution, the cycle then inaugurated. The dreams of Abram and Joseph were
                            actualized. The vision of Moses and the bush redeemed one nation from the midst of another,
                            as a child proceeds from its mother. Israel was born into Egypt, and born again into the
                            land of Canaan — born of revelation and evolution. Judgment day followed judgment day to
                            Israel, always beginning at the house of God — the Temple — until the time of Augustus, when
                            a man arose who said : " For judgment I am come into this world." And, as Moses destroyed
                            Egypt, so did he destroy the Jewish nation ; and the Pentecostal Church was born from its
                            mother, the Jewish Church, as Israel was born of Egypt. This Pentecostal Church was absorbed
                            into, and diluted with, spiritual Babylon, just as the old Israel was absorbed into, and
                            diluted with, Babylonia of the Persians. Again, the Spirit said : " She shall go forth unto
                            Babylon, and there shall she be delivered. The second Christian, or Pentecostal Church, is
                            born of Christendom in Babylon. And, as Babylon is Church and State combined, so the Shaker
                            Order and the Republican Order of Civil Government were twins, born together; and they will
                            travel together hereafter as heretofore, until the earth, and the fullness thereof, shall be
                            the Lord's, even as Zion is the Temple. Then shall all nations and races be one nation, one
                            race, and one language. For confusion of tongues and interests shall cease, and a pure
                            language, expressive of pure, simple, natural, and true spiritual lives shall result. These
                            two distinctive Orders — spiritual and civil — of the United Society, and of the United
                            States, will run parallel, until they shall have subdued, by the truth, all the Churches and
                            all the kingdoms of the earth ; and it shall be Shaker dualism — a dual God and Christ, and
                            a dual Church of Christ, where man and woman shall be man and woman, just as Deity is man
                            and woman, in entire harmony, and perfect unity ; and the Civil Government shall be in its
                            image, and after its likeness ; male and female shall it be, in all its legislative and
                            judicial departments ; as also in all its religious and educational institutions ; dual —
                            male and female shall they forever be. These visions of the future are as the dreams of
                            Abram to the twelve sons of Jacob ; as the dreams of Joseph to the twelve tribes of Israel;
                            as the vision of Moses to his subsequent revelations, and of their products, the whole
                            history of Israel, down to Jesus, the Head of the Jewish Christian Pentecostal Church, which
                            was a seed of the Shaker Church. Seven cycles of progress are appointed to the American
                            Civil Government, before it will eliminate from itself all the elements of Church-and-State
                            Babylon, down to pure Materialism. The tendency to retain and incorporate some of the
                            theological or monarchical influences, antagonistic to pure Materialism and Republicanism,
                            will be equaled only by a like tendency on the part of the Spiritual Order of Shakers to
                            retain and absorb some of the " doctrines of devils" and their practices. Hence each cycle
                            will end in a day of judgment in both Orders. The United States Government has just passed
                            through its first day of judgment. Slavery, which was the antithesis of " all men free and
                            equal," is judged, condemned, and executed, by the latent reserved abstract truths of the
                            founders of the cycle. The Government repented, confessed, and forsook slavery; as it will
                            repent, confess, and forsake land monopoly, male government, war, prostitution, and poverty.
                            This is the vision for the future. " The seven thunders that uttered their voices" about the
                            steps of Progress of the Church of Christ's Second Appearing, were uttered and understood,
                            but not recorded ; so neither do I record them. " The measure that ye mete shall be measured
                            to you again," is now experienced by the South. As they had held millions of human beings as
                            chattel-slaves, disregarding all social family ties, and sexual covenants, and relations; so
                            did the war-spirit themselves had evoked, disregard all of their family ties, and social
                            sexual relations; and their fathers, and brothers, and sons, were forced into the army, as
                            they had forced away, by sale, the fathers, and brothers, and sons of the Negroes ; leaving
                            the females without protection, a prey to the debauched soldiery of both North and
                        South.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Singapore, Malay Peninsula, June 22, 1873" TEIform="index"/>Singapore, Malay Peninsula, June
                            22,1873</head><p TEIform="p">Elder F. W. Evans. — My dear friend, my heart swells with emotions of tenderness and sympathy
                            while heading this letter, inasmuch as it bears me on the wings of memory back to Mt.
                            Lebanon, to Albany, to Cleveland, and drops me down among brotherhoods and sisterhoods of
                            souls consecrated to human redemption. The distance, in miles, between Singapore (away down
                            here at the southern point of the Malay Peninsula, under the equator) and Mt. Lebanon is
                            great; but the moral distance is greater. Singapore is a city of eighty thousand souls,
                            sixty thousand of which are Chinamen; ten thousand are the indigenous Malays ; and the other
                            ten thousand are mixtures of Hindoos, Siamese, Javanese, Persians, and Arabs; and their
                            dresses are as complex as the blood mixtures. The heat is intense, and this is the third
                            week we have been waiting for a steamer in the opium trade to take us to Calcutta, where we
                            strike the regular route. They told us, positively, in Hong Kong, China, that we should
                            connect here with another line ; but, as the "fates" would have it, just as we were coming
                            into the bay, we met the out-going steamer. You can well imagine my disappointment. Why do
                            men lie so ? — to use the word falsify is too mild. But, left here., I made the best of it,
                            by writing up my Notes on China, and tramping about this country—the country of nutmegs,
                            pepper, cinnamon, cloves, cocoa-nuts, pine-apples, tapioca, durians, bread-fruit, and every
                            other fruit requiring perpetual summer. The foliage is magnificent, and the scenery crowning
                            the isles beautiful. At the same time the drawbacks are numerous. In my room, at the hotel,
                            are fleas, mosquitoes, beetles, and lizards. Only last night I saw four lizards <pb n="74" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 74= 8HAKEE J^ND crawling on the walls over my head, one of them nearly a foot
                            in length. Last week I went over to Johere, on the Malacca coast, to see the palace of the
                            Marah-Rajah, etc. One of his officials took us out into the country where we saw a young
                            tiger (a few years ago, one man a-day here was killed by tigers), an elephant, a boa
                            constrictor, fifteen feet in length on the limb of a tree, and monkeys in the jungle. Why
                            Europeans live in such a country is a marvel. Gold, gold tells the reason in a word. I
                            expect to get away for Calcutta, in about three days. In Singapore there are two hundred
                            Europeans and four hundred Americans. I am getting terribly behind in all American news.
                            You, dear brother, can hardly imagine how completely alone I am. At times it is quite a
                            trial. But all trials, to those who are loyal to duty and right, will end. My stay in India
                            and Egypt will be short, as the weather will be intensely hot. I have not given up going to
                            Palestine ; for really I do want to see the land where the Nazarene and the Apostles once
                            trod. I hope to get around to America by Christmas, God and the good Angels continuing my
                            health. This intense hot weather wears upon me I find. It is unnatural to a man born in
                            Vermont. I am getting anxious to be once more under the folds of the American flag, and am
                            very anxious to see you, venerable father, the family, and all. Give them my love, and
                            remember me in your prayers. Most affectionately thine,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Peebles, J. M." TEIform="persName"/>J. M. Peebles</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="26 Penton St., Pentonvile, London (N. C.), June 30, 1873" TEIform="index"/>26, Penton St.,
                            Pentonvixe, London (N. C), June 30,1873</head><p TEIform="p">My Dear Friend : — Your kind letter of the 5th of February I received while in the North of
                            England, and I have been so very busy since I have been back, that I have not had time to
                            sit down quietly and pen you a reply until to-day. We have had a very prosperous season, our
                            only difficulty being that workmen are scarce, many having emigrated, and very few boys
                            being apprenticed to the hand sewing department of our trade. But I will not trouble you
                            with business particulars, as I am sure they will not interest you so much as things of a
                            higher character. I have been very much troubled, for the last year or two, with a question
                            that, to me, is of the highest importance. Until I have settled that question, and can see
                            the truth of it one way or the other, I do not think I shall make much progress in spiritual
                            life ; for, as soon as I begin to think above the earth plane, this thought presents itself,
                            and I feel that I can get no further, until I can see clearly the real truth of the case. It
                            is this: Jesus Christ, was he human or Divine ! I was brought up from my childhood in the
                            Swedenborgian faith, which teaches that our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ was the only God ;
                            that he came to this earth in a glorified human form, to disperse the cloud of spiritual
                            darkness that prevailed upon it; that he accomplished, or rather finally completed, this
                            work by his death on the cross, and that the rending of the vail, separating the holy of
                            holies from the body of the church, was symbolical of his work being accomplished. Now, all
                            this is very beautiful, but I have long had, in my mind, grave doubts as to the truth of it.
                            One great thing is, we have no authority for it but Swedenborg ; and was not he as likely to
                            be wrong as any one else ? It seems to me that every one should settle it in his own mind as
                            to whether that doctrine be true or not. But, who is to be authority in the matter ? Perhaps
                            you can throw a little light on the subject; if you can, and will, I shall esteem it a great
                            favor. I have to thank you very much for the kind and prompt reply to my last letter, and
                            also for the " Shaker and Shakeress," which I receive every month, and am very pleased
                            therewith. I am convinced it will be the means of doing a great deal of good. With my
                            kindest regards and best wishes for the prosperity of all your undertakings, I remain, Yours
                            most respectfully, To Elder F. W. Evans.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Everitt, Frank" TEIform="persName"/>Frank Everitt</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York, July 24, 1873" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. U. S. A., July
                            24,1873</head><p TEIform="p">To Frank Everitt: My dear friend, your interesting letter of June 30th came to hand a week or
                            two ago. I am glad of your business prosperity during the past season. When I was in your
                            shop, I felt a good deal of sympathy, under an impression, that it was close work to make
                            the sales meet the expenses. The question that you propound is a very important one. In the
                            matter of a person learning geography, we begin with the outlines of the earth — the figure
                            of it. Now it is round; but, for thousands of years, if not ages, priest and people (and
                            even Jehovah, the God of the Jews included) believed it to be, not round, but flat. This
                            goes to prove the fact, that " the whole world " may '' lie" in geographical error, as well
                            as " in the wicked one." And how easily 1 could multiply the instances, like the circulation
                            of the blood, where all known human beings were under a mistaken conception of scientific
                            facts. Now the truth respecting them is everywhere known. It is the same with what are
                            called religious truths ; errors have preceded them. Ann Lee and Swedenborg were
                            cotemporary; and Ann called him her John the Baptist. Like Jesus, Ann was a human being — he
                            a man, she a woman. Like Jesus, she had her weaknesses and sins; and, while Jesus con-
                            fessed his sins to John the Baptist, Ann confessed hers to Jane and James Wardley. Then the
                            Christ Spirit descended upon her, as, after Jesus had confessed, the Christ Spirit, from the
                            Christ heavens, descended upon him. The Christ heavens bear, to the inhabitants of other
                            planets, the same relation that they bear to the inhabitants of earth. That is, when, on the
                            natural plane, the people of Jupiter shall have multiplied, until a prospect shall appear of
                            there being no more room (for wise people " see the evil afar off"), then the Christ Spirits
                            would begin to harvest that planet; that is, to resurrect the ripest natural men and women
                            above the plane of animal reproduction. Then the voice of Christ to them would be, just as
                            it was to and through Jesus, Forsake generation, and generative relation — father, mother,
                            brothers, sisters, children, wife, husband, and houses and land; and form "households of
                            faith," with property " in common," and relatives all spiritual, not natural. Under this
                            ruling, natural relatives may become spiritual relatives. It is the generative life that the
                            Christ Spirit will burn up ; not the person of father, mother, etc. " Let him that readeth
                            understand." Thus would numbers enough become Christians on the planet Jupiter to balance
                            population, without resort to disease, to the Malthus theory, to famine by poverty, to war,
                            to abortion, or to any other vice-checks of population. Can there be a moment's hesitation
                            in choosing between true Christianity and these infernal " inventions" of Christendom ? Or,
                            can there be a question raised, as to the literal fact that, however large a planet may be,
                            the population principle unchecked would fill it as China is now filled; where infanticide
                            is legalized, as the only means of preventing general starvation, even although the Chinese
                            are a long way from being where and what we hope the inhabitants of other globes are ¦—¦
                            pure, natural men and women — until called by the Christ Spirits to rise up and bless " the
                            wombs that never bear, and the paps which never gave suck ? " Mother Ann then was ignorant
                            of science, but was blessed with a Christ revelation, which enabled her to compass
                            Swedenborg, with all his learning. Now, you must consider that both Ann and Swedenborg were
                            brought up to believe in the Deity of Jesus ; to both of them, Jesus was God. Swedenborg
                            became simply a Spiritualist — not a religionist; he was scientific. Spiritualism is the
                            highest of the sciences; nothing more, nothing less. So that Swedenborg was not a Christian,
                            any more than was John the Baptist. The highest heaven that Swedenborg ascended into was a
                            generative — not a Christ, or resurrection — heaven. Himself testified of this, near the
                            close of his life, saying: " I see new heavens forming, and angels descending and ascending
                            from and to them, to the earth. I know not what they are." They were the resurrection
                            heavens, into which none had ever entered up to that time, not excepting Jesus and his
                            Apostles. They groaned in spirit, and waited, looking and hasting unto the coming of the
                            female Christ in a human female. Ann Lee was the " glory" of Jesus, in which he was to come
                            in his second appearing. The woman, we all know, " is the glory of the man." Now their
                            spiritual children — brethren and sisters — can live together in purity. Never before could
                            this have been done. Catholic monks and nuns have to be kept separate, or they would " fall
                            to the earth " — go back into generation. " A third part of these stars," of the first
                            Christian heavens have, in all ages, been drawn do"wn by the tail of the dragon—generation.
                            But " now," in the second manifestation, or appearing of the Christ Spirit, " has come
                            salvation and strength, the kingdom of our God, and the power of his Christ." And we can and
                            do live above the earth, as did Jesus. We have the Christ Spirit — not Jesus. He was the
                            "first-born of many brethren;" nothing more; as Ann was the first-born of many sisters.
                            Swedenborg would have to confess his sins to Ann, or to an Elder of her appointment, just as
                            John the Baptist would have to confess his sins to Jesus, in order to enter into his
                            kingdom. " Facts are stubborn things." And the facts are, that, while the Swedenborgians
                            are, in all respects, like all the other worldly Christians, ready to be of the world, to
                            fight, to marry, to hold private, selfish property, to <pb n="75" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKEEESS. 75 be
                            rich and poor, high and low, and generative male and female, just as are all who are in the
                            kingdom of the " beast," and in the kingdom of his " image"—the Catholic and Protestant
                            order: the Shakers are a distinct people, in every one of these respects — a new creation.
                            Is not this, then, the kingdom of heaven on earth, for which Catholic and Protestant have
                            alike been sixteen hundred years praying ? There, my friend, I have written the above as
                            fast as I could move the pen; and you may, at some seance, invite Resurrection Angels to
                            come and visit you. They will confirm what I have herein written ; and this Scripture will
                            be a medium by which they can come into the sphere of some one of your circles. You have no
                            medium for the manifestation of Christ Spirits. But, should they find access to \ou, they
                            would invite you to the Shakers as the proper mediums through whom for them to operate.
                            Remember that, while Swedenborg was the Angel of Spiritualistic communication, Ann was the
                            Angel of a Christ revelation. Believe me most respectfully your friend</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Elder Frederick" TEIform="index"/>Elder Frederick</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Brother, your letter, with its inclosed extracts, came safely to hand. You will please
                            accept our thanks for the same. In reference to your leader of the July number of the "
                            Shaker and Shakeress:" When about fifteen years of age, I was surprised to hear my father
                            remark, that the mission of Jesus (according to his own testimony), was national — exclusive
                            — in its character. In support of this view, the words of Jesus to the woman of Canaan were
                            quoted: " But he answered her not a word.... But he answered, and said, I am not sent but
                            unto the lost sheep of the house of Israel." How harsh his expression to the woman seems : "
                            It is not meet to take the children's bread, and cast it to the dogs!" (Matt, xiii.) God is
                            no respecter of persons. " He sendeth rain upon the just and the unjust, and is good to the
                            unthankful and the evil." That for her birth this woman was not accountable, must be
                            conceded ; and hence she was certainly entitled to receive from Jesus, for her daughter, the
                            healing power, which was given him by the Father to dispense to such as had need thereof.
                            There are quite a number of expressions recorded of Jesus, which seem to show that the
                            universality of his mission had not dawned upon him; and also that he expected the ushering
                            in of the latter day to take place within a short time. It seemed necessary that to Peter
                            should be given a vision, to convince him that God would accept others besides the Jews,
                            provided they were workers of good. Of the truth of your observation, in refer- ence to the
                            vacillation of the Apostles between Judaism and Christianity, it seems to me that the
                            Scriptures furnish abundant evidence. In putting aside the doctrines that " Jesus is very
                            God," and that " from his birth he was perfect," it seems difficult, for some, not to make
                            of him a sort of demi-god. The more mystery we attach to Jesus, the greater becomes the
                            difficulty we experience in striving to hold him up as a pattern to mankind. In proving that
                            he could not have sinned, we lower, instead of exalting, his character. In judging others,
                            we are often reminded of the wisdom of Father James, in saying, " I will henceforth know no
                            man by his words, but by his works." If the Scriptures give all the circumstances connected
                            with these seeming unwise acts of Jesus, then the inferences you draw are no doubt correct.
                            How difficult it is to meet and answer such questions as are necessarily put when any one
                            denies the Divinity of Jesus, in the sense in which it is im- plied by the old theology : —"
                            Was he man, or was he not 1 If not like other men, wherein was he different?" is asked.
                            Difficult for whom to answer ? Why, for those who, while claiming that the so-called
                            orthodox ideas in reference to Jesus are incorrect, would con- tend that no effort should be
                            made to clear away the mystery and make the matter plain. Of the character of Jesus, as a
                            medium and faithful leader — " Elder Brother " — I will speak but briefly. The greatest
                            proof of his surpassing Mediumship lies in the diversity of his revelations, and to their
                            applicability to the soul-wants of " those who hunger and thirst after righteousness." Many
                            as are the hearts that have been stirred by the revelations of Jesus, they are few in
                            comparison to the numbers that will yet awake and realize their truth and beauty. The
                            concluding part of your editorial I love It is the primitive faith in its purity : "
                            Whosoever receiveth you, receiveth me .... and him that sent me." The present of a work
                            which, by its Founders and Leaders, was declared to be a progressive one, is, and (to the
                            faithful), will always continue to be, superior to the past. He or she who lays hold of the
                            faith that " Christ is manifest in the flesh," and who renders to " Christ in the flesh "
                            obedience, can never be deceived, or fail of securing salvation. But, by referring to the
                            past as superior, and striving to disparage the present gift, we are not only standing in
                            our own light, but we are denying the truth of Jesus' and Ann's prophe- cies in reference to
                            the increase which should take place after their decease. Thanks from all for your love.
                            Please accept our love, and prayers for your prosperity. Grain all harvested and the greater
                            part threshed. Yield of wheat, averaged twenty bushels to the acre. Crops of corn not so
                            promising as we could wish. A great deal of rain.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Amery, George B." TEIform="persName"/>George B. Amery, Whitewater, O.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dual civil government" TEIform="index"/>DUAL CIVIL GOVERNMENT</head><p TEIform="p">The Times of July 28th says : " The Fantees are among the most interesting of the African
                            tribes. Many of their customs seem directly borrowed from the ancient Jews and Romans.
                            Murder is punished by the offender being sold into slavery. When the tribe, or rather the
                            aristocracy of the tribe, are tired of a king, a parrot's egg is brought and shown him. The
                            sight of this is the signal of death. They believe in one supreme Deity — the "Good Sjpirit
                            " — like the North American Indians. They have a priesthood which includes both sexes ; and
                            the honors, immunities, and property of this body are hereditary, just as they were with the
                            priesthood of Egypt. The superior priests are held to be immortal; and there is a village,
                            in a part of the country called Braffoe, in which a multitude of aged priests are said to
                            have lived from time immemorial.'" From all of which it appears: First, That capital
                            punishment does not exist. Second, That the monarchy is limited. Third, That they believe in
                            God as Spirit, and as dual— male and female. Fourth, That, consequentially, they have a dual
                            government — male and female. Fifth, That they believe in the immortality of the bodies of
                            the righteous.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New York, July 19, 1873" TEIform="index"/>New York, July 19,1873</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Evans : — I have been asked to procure a copy of " Ann Lee," which please send me. The
                            perusal of your books has proved profitable. It is, indeed, gratifying to me to find in the
                            " Shaker and Shakeress " interpretation of Scripture, the key to many passages between which
                            and myself there has long existed the relationship of novice on the one hand, and enigma on
                            the other. Nor has this been attended with little surprise either; surprise that a mode of
                            interpretation so simple and easy should have been overlooked or ignored, and so much " pain
                            of travail " taken by commentators to bring forth that which, except it should serve
                            sectarian ends, or to gratify mere personal vanity of research, can be of little use to any
                            one. Truly, there are men who, by a system of wordiness, would explain both the meaning and
                            the authority of the Scriptures entirely away! Should there be a surplus of funds you may
                            continue my feast of tlie " Shaker and Shakeress," by proportionally lengthening my
                            subscription. Believe me, dear sir, Very truly,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="D., C. H." TEIform="persName"/>C. H. D.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Camp meeting" TEIform="index"/>CAMP MEETING</head><p TEIform="p">During the camp meeting season, when it was known that Rev. Charles Pitman would preach, the
                            country for miles around would be on the move. Not unfrequently he would have five, six, or
                            even seven thousand persons to hear him on such occasions. His audiences were often chained
                            to the spot for two hours or more, forgetful of every thing but the great theme of
                            Redemption of a lost world, upon which he dwelt. While Agent for Dickinson College,
                            traveling in the discharge of his official duties, he came one day into the vicinity of a
                            camp meeting, and, like the war horse snuffing the battle from afar, hastened toward it. His
                            arrival was near the middle of the day. He said to the Presiding Elder, "I have come to your
                            meeting, and must leave this afternoon, but God has given me a message to this people. Will
                            you let me preach ?" The Elder replied, " There is a brother engaged to preach this
                            afternoon; if he will yield the appointment I shall be glad to have you." The ar- rangements
                            were made, and Pitman was to preach. At three o'clock, however, the sky was overcast with
                            dense black clouds ; fierce lightnings glared, and the thunders roared. All the indications
                            were that a fearful tempest would immediately burst upon them. But notwithstanding these
                            angry premonitions the preacher took the stand, and falling upon his knees, prayed in agony
                            of spirit, "OGod Almighty ! if thou hast sent me to preach to this people, hold back these
                            threatening clouds for at least one hour." This prayer was thrice repeated, each time with
                            increasing faith and fervor. It was a bold request — yet it was heard and the rain was
                            stayed. He then preached an hour and ten minutes like one newly commissioned from the skies,
                            and as if, when through, he must immediately return to report the manner in which-he had
                            performed his work. Men stood aghast, or feeling that the day of doom had come, fell
                            prostrate to the earth under the power of the convincing Spirit. Thousands were present at
                            the service, and as soon as he had finished, the clouds, no longer restrained, poured out
                            their contents in such ceaseless floods, that the multitudes fled to the tents for refuge.
                            The whole congregation, convinced by the power of truth, and now held captive by the storm,
                            were kept within the reach of religious effort. Prayermeetings were opened simultaneously
                            all over the ground, and such were the displays of Divine power amid the tempest, that five
                            hundred souls were reported among the saved on that memorable afternoon and evening.</p></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A Hoboken editor being challenged to fight a duel..." TEIform="index"/>A Hoboken editor being challenged to fight a duel...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A Hoboken editor being challenged to fight a duel, sent word in reply, " When I want to die,
                            I can shoot myself." </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vote of thanks" TEIform="index"/>VOTE OF THANKS.</head><p TEIform="p">The Editors propose a Vote of Thanks from all interested in the S. and S. to Brother William
                            Offord, for his invaluable services in copying and proof reading. —u— ALL are kindly
                            welcome. —AV. O.</p></div2><pb n="76" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Scotch correspondence" TEIform="index"/>SCOTCH CORRESPONDENCE</head><p TEIform="p">[Extract from a letter to D. P.] "I am fully of your opinion, that love must be the creative
                            and cementing element of every thing valuable in home. The primary, fundamental cause of so
                            much domestic infelicity, and so many divorces, is the lack of moral stamina, originating in
                            the utter absence of any effort to train the young, in this country, in that empress of all
                            virtues, selfcontrol. "It may seem absurd to speak of sugarsticks in this connection, but it
                            seems clear to me, that if a child is indulged in candy, without ever a hint to his
                            conscience, that there is any thing wrong in it, by and by a taste for tobacco and other
                            abominations is developed, and indulged in without a scruple of conscience. A flabbiness of
                            moral muscle, so to speak, is induced, and, when decidedly immoral appetites present
                            themselves for gratification, there is no power to resist. In he goes, and the result is
                            personal and domestic misery and mischief without limit, divorces included; the sugar stick,
                            the thin edge of the wedge, wrought the ruin. " Again, the wide-spread practice of raising
                            young women to nothing but a love of luxury and idleness, greatly aggravates the evil.
                            Parents who do not take all possible pains to train their daughters, in all the minutite of
                            domestic industry and thrift, are the enemies of these daughters and of all human kind; for
                            there is no source of happiness like a sense of genuine usefulness, and a consciousness of
                            duty quietly and well performed; nothing so attractive to those of the other sex, who are
                            sober minded; nothing so subduing to those who are not. Let us contrast the background of
                            solid worth, indicated by the knitting habits of Martha Washington and Maria Louisa Childs,
                            and the simple record of the New Testament Dorcas, with the flimsy accomplishments of the
                            'girl of the period;' and cease to wonder at the falling off of happy homes, in favor of
                            saloons with ' pretty waiter girls ;' and the prevalence of infelicity where real homes are
                            attempted. In Scotland, women work shoulder to shoulder with men in all rural industries.
                            This custom receives unfavorable comment from those who know only the outside of it. It has
                            its drawbacks, but the cannie prudence and sturdy independence begotten of it, may well
                            cover a multitude of minor evils, and be one of the causes of the greatness of our little
                            native land. " I am much pleased with the ideas em- bodied in the principles of the Shakers.
                            If I had remained at home in Scotland, it is not likely I ever should have married, for my
                            mother is still alive, and my sister likely to survive me. "I count Celibacy a wise
                            arrangement to those who can bear it; and, strictly and honestly carried out, it will
                            contribute largely to the permanency of the Shaker communities. I am not naturally disposed
                            to take a very rosecolored view of things that look dark on the surface; therefore, I am
                            gratified with your view of the destruction of slavery, as a prophecy of further moral
                            progress in the world; for that institution looked powerful enough on the very eve of its
                            fall. Taking the "whole sweep of human history, with many apparent interruptions and
                            retrogressions, progress is ever evident; but it is as evident that the moral has always
                            lagged behind the material, political, and intellectual. It is not likely that the letter of
                            republican institutions will soon be interfered with in this country ; but the state of
                            things which renders possible such careers as those of Tweed, Connolly &amp; Co., Fisk
                            and Gould, Vanderbilt, Drew and others, does not augur well for the spirit of these
                            institutions remaining long intact; yet, ' to hope the best is pious, brave, and wise.'
                        "</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dialogue" TEIform="index"/>DIALOGUE</head><p TEIform="p">Flesh-eater.— Were not all things made for our use 1 Vegetarian.—And man for mine, replied
                            the pampered goose. Flesh-eater.— What reasons have you for rejecting (as food) flesh, fish,
                            eggs, butter, cheese, and grease ? Vegetarian.— See Genesis, 1 : 29 ; and Numbers, 11:13 and
                            33, where it states that the Israelites lusted for flesh, and their punishment was, to have
                            their fill of it, till it turned into a great plague, and they died with it between their
                            teeth. The Prophet Isaiah (66 :3) said : " He that killeth an ox, is as if he slew a man." "
                            Gather up the fragments, and let nothing be lost" said the Saviour, after feeding the
                            multitude. No one, it is presumed, will question the prudence of the Saviour (in whom were
                            hid " the treasures of wisdom and knowledge"), because he let " the whole herd of swine run
                            down a steep place into the sea," and perish. Is it not reasonable to suppose that he knew
                            that the condition of the man, out of whom the legion was cast, was brought about by his
                            eating the flesh of that unclean animal ? and that the inhabitants of that region were much
                            addicted to it 1 See, likewise, Isaiah, 19 : 8-10. Why all the lamentation, mourning and
                            languishing, expressed therein, if it were not because the people would be vegetarians, and
                            would not buy the fish ? Flesh-eater.— Why don't you eat fine flour bread ? Vegetarian.— I
                            do eat some, when I think it is not (as Elder Frederick Evans says) poisoned with saleratus.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Frost, T." TEIform="persName"/>T. Frost</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="More church concessions" TEIform="index"/>MORE CHURCH CONCESSIONS</head><p TEIform="p">We scarcely read of the elaborate defense of the Anglican Church by the Primate of all
                            England, made through the columns of the press, in opposition to the disestablishing spirit
                            which is abroad in the United Kingdom, when we get a reminder nearer home, from the American
                            branch of the same Church, of the inroads which science is making into creeds, and of the
                            reluctant willingness of the clergy to accept a situation which they plainly see it is
                            impossible for them to withstand. Bishop Bedell, of Ohio, the coadjutor of the deceased
                            Bishop Mcllvaine, whose remains have reached his native shores within a week, in a
                            discourse, not long since, on " Heavenly Conversation," drew up a formal and elaborate
                            argument to prove what all believers in Spiritualism know without any argument whatever,
                            that in the future world we shall renew old friendships, feel interested in past events, and
                            daily increase in knowledge and love. And he proceeded to repudiate altogether the old time
                            belief in a heaven in which the saints are to stand around, perpetually singing praises to
                            God, or listening, in turn, to the songs of angelic choirs. He likewise scouted the idea
                            that the past would be forgotten and the future unthought of, while enjoying the ecstatic
                            bliss of the heavenly present. He believed that the immortal man would be but the mortal man
                            purified of his imperfections, and with an immensely enlarged and intensified in-
                            telligence. He will converse with his friends over the struggles and trials of the past, as
                            well as over its happiness, and will look forward with joy to the yet greater bliss of the
                            future. The Bishop pushed on with greater boldness still, and did not hesitate to renounce
                            the narrow creed that man, in his present state, on this insignificant vale of matter, is
                            the be-all and end-all of created intelligence. And furthermore, and more specifically
                            still, he declared that he did not hold the dispensation of the Fall and the Redemption to
                            be the only one in God's providence. The thousands of magnificent orbs that fill the
                            boundless space with activity and glory were not created merely for the use or amusement of
                            the dwellers on this, one of the smallest of all the orbs. Each probably has had, or will
                            have, its inhabitants and its peculiar dispensation. One of the joys of the future life will
                            perhaps be the reception of news from these myriad worlds, and the tracing out of the
                            workings of Divine Providence in their history. All this sounds very much like Swedenborg.
                            It is Spiritualism. The signs of the times are not easy to mistake in matters spiritual,
                            when the chiefs of the churches give such pronounced evidence of being weary of the
                            restrictions of their creeds, and show that their spirit yearn for a free flight among the
                            realities of the spiritual life, such as are known to those who hold the great truths of
                            Spiritualism. We refer to this demonstration of an Episcopal Bishop in this country with
                            unaffected satisfaction, because it shows that people are on the right track, and the
                            churches have got to follow them. The priests and preachers no longer lead and control the
                            public judgment or popular aspirations. The light is coming down everywhere in a welcome
                            flood.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good rules for emergencies" TEIform="index"/>GOOD RULES FOR EMERGENCIES</head><p TEIform="p">Professor Wilder, of Cornell University, gives these short rules of action in cases of ac-
                            cident. For dust in the eyes, avoid rubbing, dash water into them; remove cinders, etc.,
                            with round point of a pencil. Remove insect from the ear by tepid water; never put a hard
                            instrument into your ear. If any artery is cut, compress below. If choked, get upon all
                            fours and cough. Smother a fire with carpets, etc. Water will often spread burning oil, and
                            increase the danger. Before passing through smoke, take full breath, and then stoop low, but
                            if carbonic acid is suspected, walk erect. Suck poisoned wounds, or, cut out the part
                            without delay; hold the wounded part as long as can be borne to a hot coal or the end of a
                            cigar. In cases of poisoning, excite vomiting by tickling the throat, or by warm mustard.
                            For acid poisons, give alkalies ; for alkaline poisons, give acids ; white of an egg is good
                            in most cases. For apoplexy, raise the head and body ; for fainting, lie flat. If in the
                            water, float on the back, with the nose and mouth projecting. For slight burns, dip the part
                            in cold water ; if the skin is destroyed, cover with varnish.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Extract from Richard W. Pelham's letter of January 10, 1873" TEIform="index"/>Extract from
                            Richard W. Pelham's letter of Jan. 10th, 1873.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pelham, Richard W" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">And now as it is appointed for all men once to die, and whereas I being about seventy six
                            years of age, and weakened by disease, am approaching the end of my days on earth, I leave
                            this my dying testimony. To wit, That the Revelation of the Gospel of Jesus of Nazareth and
                            a second Revelation of the same Gospel through Ann of Manchester is the power of God unto
                            salvation from sin; that having lived according to this revelation over fifty-five years it
                            has saved me from sin — saved me from all criminal imperfection. It has given me power over
                            all flesh, all lust, all hatred, all anger ; over all that is of the world ; the lust of the
                            flesh, the lust of the eye and the pride of life ; over all murmuring and complaining, all
                            unreconciliation of spirit, and my soul is filled with peace, filled with gratitude and love
                            to God and to all humanity. Ho! every one that thirsteth come — come to the overflowing
                            fountain of God's impartial Love! Amen.</p></div2><div2 type="shaker-press" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers" TEIform="index"/>The Shakers.</head><p TEIform="p">The Troy Times does not believe the Shakers are dying outj and says : Regularly we hear or
                            read that the sect of Shakers is dying out. Every six months or so, a correspondent writes
                            to a newspaper that the Shakers are losing in numbers, wealth, and discipline, and every
                            other newspaper in the country reprints the letter. Already enough obituaries of this
                            peculiar people to serve for the funeral memoirs of all the eccentric religious communities
                            in the land have been written. The fact is, that the Shakers are to- day gaining in wrealth
                            and discipline, and holding their own in numbers. Their lands, which were bought for almost
                            nothing, have constantly gained in value, and now, owing to their location and
                            productiveness, they are as valuable for farming purposes as any we know of. For a dying
                            sect the Shakers have considerable vitality. In a late number of the New Haven Evening
                            Register, we find the following paragraph: It is said that there is not now living a single
                            descendant in the male line of Chaucer, Shakspeare, Spencer, Milton, Cowley, Butler, Dryden,
                            Tope, Cowper, Goldsmith, Scott, Byron, Moore, Sir Philip Sidney, Sir Walter Raleigh, Drake,
                            Cromwell, Hampden, Monk, Marlborough, Peterborough, Nelson, Stafford, Ormond, Clarenden,
                            Addison, Swift, Johnson, Walpole, Bollingbroke, Chatham, Pitt, Fox, Burke, Grattan, Canning,
                            Bacon, Locke, Newton, Davy, Hume, Gibbon, Macaulay, Hogarth, Sir Joshua Reynolds, David
                            Garrick, John Kemble or Edmund Kean. There is a law under which the procreative forces pass
                            from the back brain to the intellectual and turn from the intellectual to the spiritual
                            faculties.</p></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Longevity of the Jewish race" TEIform="index"/>Longevity of the Jewish Race</head><p TEIform="p"> The average duration of life among the Jews in France, is computed to be five years longer
                            than among Christians. M. Legoyt, a French author, in summing up the causes which lead to
                            this higher average, gives prominence to the following : The "sentiment of the family,"
                            fully developed among them, assures to these children and to their aged and infirm parents a
                            solicitude more active; to the new-born, the mother's nursing, and to the poor an assistance
                            more efficacious. "Their charity," he says, "is unequaled ; their morality is demonstrated
                            by judiciary statistics : firmness and serenity of spirit are the most marked traits of
                            their character, and proceed from a profound faith and an unalterable confidence in
                            Providence."</p></div2><pb n="77" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakeress: is there mystery in truth?" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERESS: IS THERE MYSTERY IN TRUTH
                            ?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">The human mind in all ages, has sought to understand the invisible Source of its existence ;
                            for belief in, or an intuitive sense of, the immortality of the soul, and of an over- ruling
                            Power, which guides and controls the destinies of individuals, and of nations, is in- herent
                            in every human soul. Much was said, in Apostolic days, concerning the " mystery of the
                            Gospel," " mystery of godliness," and also the " mystery of iniquity." The Revelator John,
                            who " bare record of the Word," while under a true spirit of prophecy reaching into the
                            future, foretold a day when the mystery of God would be finished. May we not reasonably
                            inquire into the source and origin of this mystery? If all the diversified opinions, and
                            theological discussions which have been written and expressed concerning it were gathered
                            and compiled in one volume, it would require a good mathematician to number its pages. But
                            we would ask, Is there mystery in truth, when unmixed with error ? Is there any mystery in
                            purity, or in unalloyed, unselfish love? If man and woman, on the natural plane of
                            existence, had kept their integrity, innocently carrying out the laws of their being in the
                            rudimental stage of life, using, and not abusing, the powers conferred upon them, would they
                            not, as a normal sequence, have progressed from the natural plane to the higher spiritual
                            life ? Then, where would have been the conflict, or mystery? Has not an interblending of the
                            true and false — a mixing of good and evil — been the cause of all the great mystery ? The
                            unperverted Natural Order is as true, in its time and season, as the Spiritual in its time
                            and season ; and must necessarily precede it. But every wise husbandman understands, that,
                            if he undertakes to sow the seed and reap a harvest at the same time, he will create
                            confusion and fail in the attempt. The Adamic or generative plane belongs to the seedsower ;
                            and spirits or angels who have passed out of the material form of existence into the lower
                            spheres of the heavens, watch over and guard those who are in that Order ; and, just in
                            proportion to their uprightness in carrying out the true intent and purpose of their exist-
                            ence in that Order, are they blest. But the Spiritual man or woman, who fills the Christian
                            character, must rise above the natural into the spiritual; and must come under the
                            ministration of spirits or angels who have themselves ascended into the resurrection heavens
                            where Christ is found; whence they are sent as angel reapers, to harvest souls from the
                            earthly generative life. If an enemy had not sown evil seeds — tares among the wheat — and
                            the earth and its inhabitants had grown and progressed like a beautiful healthy child under
                            the protection of its parents, from infancy to the strength and understanding of manhood,
                            can we not see that, successively, all would have ripened for the harvest ? and that the
                            Angel reapers would have gathered the mature grain into the spiritual garners of the Lord
                            for a higher use, leaving the field to be again occupied by the seed-sower? Then, where
                            would have been the " mystery," or inharmony ? In violated law, we opine, may be found the
                            cause of all the mystery and misery in the human family at all times. Sin blights and
                            destroys ! Virtue is a health restorer ! Man and woman are the agents by which the earth
                            must be redeemed; they are the mediums through which the Angels work ; and it would avail
                            but little for them to sound their trumpets, or for the thunders to utter their voices, if
                            there were not spiritually progressed, honest, earnest souls waiting upon the watchtowers of
                            Truth, listening to catch the first sound, and be ready to work with them. There is not so
                            much dependent upon what is said as upon what is done. One godly deed is better, and more
                            effective, than ten thousand words (if they are ever so good) coming from a deceitful,
                            unsanctified heart. As one said anciently, " One hour of equity is better than seventy years
                            of devotion," (without corresponding works). While there is so much reliance placed upon the
                            atoning blood of Jesus" and the pulpit eloquence of a hireling priesthood, the masses will
                            continue to sin and to sorrow, and the mystery of iniquity will continue to work." But we
                            rejoice in spirit exceedingly; for the beautiful star of Purity is rising in the spiritual
                            horizon, giving promise of a brighter and more perfect day. Thousands are beginning to
                            understand that those who " see God" and commune with Him, must be pure in heart and life ;
                            and only those who keep themselves chaste, can truly wait on Him, or the ministers whom He
                            sends ; and, like many of the ancient philosophers, they ascribe the highest place in the
                            heavens to those who live a pure, celibate life for conscience sake. And, while we
                            acknowledge God in the natural creation, and study his laws from the great book of Nature,
                            which is ever open before us, and from which we may learn important and instructive lessons
                            pertaining to our physical life, it may also be a medium through which we may study the
                            divine laws, which pertain to the inner spiritual life, and the boundaries of that world
                            which is to be our future home. The healthy spirit will draw sustenance from all God's
                            creation. And, as the rivers and running streamlets all converge toward the ocean, which is
                            never full, although constantly receiving new supplies ; so should all intelligent beings,
                            created as they are with the germs of an immortal life, direct their thoughts, and wend
                            their way, toward the great Source and Center of all Truth ; for there is the true home of
                            all souls.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beloved Eldress Antoinette:" TEIform="index"/>Beloved Eldress Antoinette :</head><p TEIform="p">Although our material forms are separated by hills and valleys, yet I am thankful that I
                                can commune with you in spirit; and, on this beautiful evening, I feel drawn to you by
                                the strong chords of Gospel affection; and there is a deep feeling of love and sympathy
                                welling up in my heart for you. You are ever ready to give freely to others from the
                                fountain of love that is treasured in your heart, and to impart knowledge that is much
                                needed; and I wish to express the great satisfaction that I find in reading the columns
                                of the " SJiaker and Shakeress." It seems to me that great good will result from the
                                circulation of such wholesome truths as are found in its pages. I often reflect upon the
                                wisdom and love of God ; and the more I study his Divine attributes, the more convinced
                                I am, that " His ways and thoughts " are not as the ways and thoughts of natural men and
                                women, who build cisterns according to their own plans, which do not contain waters of
                                life and salvation ; for the natural mind, when perverted, seeks pleasure in
                                unrighteousness, and drinks at the impure fountains of sinful indulgence, and finds
                                therein bitter disappointment, instead of true and lasting joy. They who thus spend
                                their lives and vital energies, are more to be pitied than envied. And those who have
                                not risen above the earthly, material plane of life, and have never sought happiness and
                                pleasure in doing God's will, often wonder how it is that the people called Shakers can
                                reconcile their feelings to (what seems to them) a dull round of duties ; for they
                                cannot realize that Wisdom's ways (which are always pure and peaceful) are filled with
                                good and pleasant things ; and that those who walk in her paths ever find joy that is
                                far more satisfying than earth-born pleasures, which at best are transient, and that the
                                spiritually-minded, whose aspirations are God-ward, feel the inflowings of life and love
                                from a never failing source. One reason why I thus express my feelings at this time is,
                                we have recently been enjoying a beautiful season with several companies of our dear
                                Gospel brethren and sisters who have been with us from other societies of Believers. We
                                have really enjoyed a feast of good things. Our heavenly meetings for worship, where we
                                felt the inspiration of the Holy Spirit which lifts the soul to Angel spheres, and gives
                                a foretaste of the joys of the redeemed, claim our best feelings. Then, in our social
                                feasts, where mind could respond to mind, as well as heart to heart, there was much
                                comfort. Again; as we walked through the cultivated fields and gardens which, in a
                                measure, have been redeemed from blight and beautified by consecrated labor, we really
                                felt that our Heavenly Father and Mother will not withhold any good thing from those who
                                love and do the truth; that the same kind hand that feeds the raven, and clothes the
                                lily, will continue to bestow every needful blessing upon those who seek the kingdom of
                                heaven and its righteousness in pre- ference to earthly riches, honors, or pleasures. We
                                visited the adjacent towns and villages and saw much in nature and art to admire ; but
                                as we saw costly palaces for the rich, and very humble cottages for the poor, and felt
                                the injustice existing between man and man, the poor who toil through weary days, and
                                fill the rich man's coffers by wearing their own lives away, receiving but a small
                                recompense in return ; we found a feeling of sadness gathering over our spirits ; for we
                                could not feel the peace and contentment there that pervades our Zion home, where self
                                is crucified, and where all toil together in Christian love ; thus, as in Apostolic
                                days, breaking our bread together as brethren and sisters in one spiritual household. I
                                thank God that there is a religion that can make the heart better, and change the whole
                                character of the natural man and woman ; and how mistaken are they who think there is no
                                real pleasure to be attained and enjoyed, except by traveling from place to place, and
                                mingling with the votaries of fashion, thus forming an excited and exciting crowd of <pb n="78" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 78 SHAKEE A.NE) pleasure-seekers. Happy are they who have so turned
                                their thoughts and affections Godward as to realize that all their joys center in truth
                                — in God.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Irving, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>Anna Irving, Enfield, Conn.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I am prompted by love..." TEIform="index"/>I am prompted by love...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">I am prompted by love to cast my mite into the Lord's treasury; and, in a true Christian
                                spirit, I would draw near to those who are not satisfied with their present condition,
                                and who desire more spiritual light, and conviction of sin, and to find the pathway that
                                leadeth unto eternal life; and, if by a word of solace, I could comfort one sin-bound,
                                sorrow-stricken soul, and help to disperse the dark clouds that have gathered around, it
                                would be a pleasure to me so to do. Dear friends, do we realize that we are hastening on
                                to the immortal shores ; that we must leave the things of time ; and that there is but
                                one straight way that will lead souls unto the rest of God in the realms of the blessed
                                ? Jesus our exemplar paved this way, and in kindly accents, he said, " Follow me." All
                                who accept the invitation, find in him a heavenly Guide ; and the Christ Spirit, with
                                which he was baptized, sheds light upon the narrow path of self-denial, and enables
                                those who are earnestly inquiring " what they shall do to inherit eternal life," to
                                understand their duty; and such find that the yoke of Christ is far easier than the yoke
                                of sin, and his burdens lighter than the bondage of a carnal life. And I would say to my
                                sorrowing sisters who are yet under that bondage, " There is a Heavenly Mother who is
                                able to extend sympathy and love, and to take earth's erring children by the hand, and
                                gently lead them through the cleansing waters of Jordan, (con- fession of sin and
                                repentance)/' and to bear them up through every trial and temptation, and to guard them
                                from all influences that would ensnare and lead them into darkness. We have a Father's
                                strength to uphold, and a Mother's love to cheer and encourage; and their united voice
                                is, " Whosoever will give up the carnal, sensual life for the Gospel of Christ, and rise
                                into the higher angelic spheres, shall find a life that is eternal." And bright
                                ministering Angels are sent to earth, to kindle the fires of truth that will cleanse the
                                temple (human hearts), and prepare a dwelling place for the holy dual Christ Spirit.
                                Even now, at the gates of cities, temples, and chapels, where God's name has been
                                profaned, through a false profession, Angels of Justice and Mercy are crying to the
                                massive throng as they pass, " Who will accept the way of life and salvation, and sell
                                all they possess that belongs to a worldly life, for the pearl of great price ? " Who
                                will listen to the goodly Shepherd's voice, saying, " Follow me ; I will lead you unto
                                living waters, where you may drink and thirst no more." Few are willing to hear and
                                obey, but choose rather to continue their course in the broad road of sinful pleasure.
                                It is not God's will that any soul should be lost. He patiently waits, and calls in
                                gentle tones, and pleads with souls to come to the truth and life, and that through the
                                cry in their hearts, " Lord what shall I do to be saved? " How shall I live to meet my
                                God in peace ? they may be brought to bow in humble submission and say, " Not my will,
                                but thine, O God, be done." Hold me in the hollow of thy hand; forgive my wanderings
                                from thee; and lead me to the higher life ; that I may dwell in thy temple forever.
                                Sweet would be the incense of such soul-breathings, when carried by Angels to the throne
                                of our Father and Mother in the Heavens. But we would ask, Is not the wickedness of the
                                present age, and especially of our great cities, equal to that described by the Prophet
                                Nahum ? Are not the cities full of blood, of lies, and robbery ; against which a woe was
                                pronounced? And does not crime as justly merit the indignation of a righteous God now,
                                as in days of yore ? People run to and fro ; knowledge is increased; and the wicked
                                continue in wickedness. It was said, " The chariots shall rage in the streets, and
                                jostle one against another in the broadways; they shall appear like torches as they run
                                like lightning." Have we not seen that prediction fulfilled in our time ? When we have
                                witnessed the rapid increase of knowledge in the land, O how much have we desired that
                                true wisdom, which leads souls to fear God and work righteousness, might also increase;
                                that there might be a true reformation in the lives of the people; and that those of
                                riper years and experience might, through the law of kindness and love, plant the germs
                                of purity and innocence in the hearts of youth and children, that they might honor God,
                                and become shining lights in the world, that wTould dispel the clouds of darkness which
                                sin and ignorance have formed. Such an influence could not fail to be a blessing to
                                humanity. It would lift the mind above sensual pleasure, vanity, and pride, which lead
                                to sorrow and death; and would turn it toward the Divine Source, whence all truth and
                                goodness radiate. Thus would be fulfilled that beautiful commandment which Jesus gave to
                                his disciples, " Love one another as I have loved you."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Adams, Hester A." TEIform="persName"/>Eldress Hester A. Adams, Gloucester, Me.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="For many years I have felt..." TEIform="index"/>For many years I have felt...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">For many years I have felt the saving influence and power of the Gospel of Christ in his
                                second appearing, which was preached in part by Jesus and his disciples, and for a time
                                was carried into practical effect in the Pentecostal Church They testified that they
                                only " saw and prophesied in part;:' and that, in the future, there would be a more
                                perfect manifestation of the work of God. This undoubtedly had reference to the time
                                when there should be a full manifestation of the Christ Spirit in both male and female ;
                                that as Jesus was baptized with the Spirit of the Father, which constituted him the
                                first-born of many sons — an elder brother, so also, in the fullness of time, a female
                                should be baptized with the Mother Spirit in Deity, which would fit her to be an elder
                                sister,— the firstborn of many daughters ; and that, under the power of the dual Christ
                                Spirit, they would co-operate together in the work of human redemption. I feel a deep
                                desire that others may be blessed as I have been, and I feel a lively interest in our
                                little periodical, the " Shaker and Shakeress; " for I believe it may be a means of
                                conveying much light and truth to honest inquirers. When I peruse its pages, my heart is
                                filled with joy ; it is a medium of the " living word" to souls, and of practical truths
                                so much needed at the present time. And while I feel an earnest desire that the Gospel
                                may spread far and wide among mankind, I also pray for an increase of the quickening
                                Spirit; the baptism of fire to sin, and of love to truth, within our Zion home ; that
                                all may be of one heart and mind — practical doers of good works ; and thus become God's
                                true witnesses and living ministers, to herald the glad tidings of peace and salvation
                                to other needy souls. I am thankful to know that this dual mes- senger finds its way
                                over the waters of the broad Atlantic, to old England's shores, the home of my
                                childhood, from whence I was brought by my parents in early life. I thank God that I was
                                preserved through a most perilous sea voyage to reach America. Once our ship was so near
                                being wrecked that for hours we were almost without hope of ever seeing land again. The
                                captain and second mate, with six others, were swept overboard and found a watery grave.
                                But we succeeded in putting back to Liverpool; and then took passage in another vessel;
                                but were obliged on account of severe gales, to put back into Liverpool the second time.
                                Again we started and by the good protecting powers above we finally reached the western
                                shore in safety. My thoughts often go back to the people of the land of my nativity;
                                and, in my prayers, I would call down God's blessing to rest upon them ; that they may
                                learn to do his will, and may feel the joy of knowing that they are owned and blest of
                                Him; and that, by being consecrated to his service, they may be quickened by his Spirit,
                                and nourished by his Word.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollingsworth, Betsey Ann" TEIform="persName"/>Betsey Ami Hollingsworth, Hancock,
                            Mass.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To the editress" TEIform="index"/>To the Editress</head><p TEIform="p">— I have not been accustomed, nor do I feel qualified, to write for the press ; yet I
                                possess so lively an interest in what I consider a living cause, of vital importance to
                                us, and to mankind at large, that I venture, in my feeble way, to make an effort to
                                sustain it; and therefore proffer a few thoughts for our Monthly, which, if of no higher
                                use, may drop into the much talked-of '' Basket," and there possibly serve as a " nest
                                egg," to attract something more interesting and valuable. The, Shakers, or Believers in
                                Christ's Second Appearing, have (in a measure) for many years, sealed up their testimony
                                among themselves, because it is so radical that none of the sects in Christendom, nor of
                                those who belong to what is termed Babylon, were prepared to hear it or live it. I am
                                thankful that the time has come for the vail to be removed, and the " cloud to be lifted
                                up;" and my prayer is, that the light of truth may shine so clearly, that many eyes may
                                behold the order of the true " Priesthood," who bear upon their shoulders the " Ark of
                                the Covenant." I bless the Shaker and Shakeress as a medium through which Sisters, as
                                well as Brethren, can present their views, and express their desires, and be heard.
                                Every one who has been blest with the saving influences of the Gospel, which is able to
                                redeem souls from sin, and to free them " from the bondage of the flesh," which is far
                                more grievous than was Egyptian servitude, cannot but rejoice in so glorious a work, and
                                feel a strong desire that others may also be blest, as they have been. I would gladly
                                blend my voice with that of the Spirit, which is calling: " Come up hither." Were
                                Gabriel's trumpet within my grasp, I would sound it aloud, and call my suffering sisters
                                away from the bondage of a <pb n="79" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> carnal life, and its consequent
                                sufferings, to enjoy the freedom of the true daughters of Zion, in the clean fold of
                                Christ. True, woman has suffered through her own volition, to a great degree ; for,
                                through either ignorance or weakness, she gave man power to rule over her; when, if they
                                had kept their rectitude on the procreative plane of life, they could have walked evenly
                                together; and then, in all the duties pertaining to that order, they would have been
                                one. It has seemed very strange to me, that so many females should willingly follow the
                                blind multitude, and yield to a life so fraught with pain and sorrow. But I suppose it
                                is easier to see the broad way, where the multitude — the " many" — throng, than the
                                narrow path, where the " few " are found. When we cast our eyes abroad over the land, we
                                see that crime stalks defiantly among all classes, from the lowest to the highest. And,
                                if we trace to their origin, national and household wars, and the heart-rending abuses
                                and cruelties inflicted upon females, do we not find them to be the fruits of wanton
                                lusts? As in the first Adam, all who sin as he sinned, die as he died; " so, in Christ,"
                                the second Adam, " shall all be made alive." By resisting every temptation to evil, as
                                did Jesus, we shall find our relation to him, who was the " first-born among many
                                brethren." Through the Christ Spirit, with which he was baptized, he was able to say, "
                                I have overcome the world." And, in the second appearing of the Christ Spirit, a female
                                has been baptized, to be a co-worker with Jesus, who now stands in a corresponding
                                relation to him as the first-born among many sisters. This we call the beginning of the
                                final Order of the work of God upon earth, which resembles the Order of heaven, where
                                dwells our dual God, with countless myriads of angels. The man Jesus, and the woman Ann,
                                are our Exemplars. He, by putting on Christ, became " the Lord our Righteousness." And,
                                by the same Spirit, " She shall be called The Lord our Righteousness." — (Jer. 23 : 6,
                                and 33 : 16.) I own this blessed Parentage in the New Creation, and rejoice with my
                                faithful brethren and sisters, who are living witnesses of the power and efficacy of
                                their mission ; and I will ever defend and uphold the testimony which they brought forth
                                against all sin. I have always loved my Shaker home; and, although I was only a small
                                child when placed under its guardianship, I have never had a desire to leave it. When I
                                grew to riper age, I had (of course) to make my own choice as to whether I would follow
                                the course of the world, and live in the generative order, or continue to live a pure
                                virgin life, as do the angels. I chose the latter, and have never regretted it; for I
                                can truly say, I love the name — character — of Shaker.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Potter, Hannah E." TEIform="persName"/>Hannah E. Potter, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Oneness of life" TEIform="index"/>ONENESS OF LIFE</head><p TEIform="p">In perusing the July number of the " Shaker and ShaJceress," so fraught with heavenly
                            treasures, I could not but pause, at the close of each article, to reflect upon their
                            oneness of feeling and sentiment; and knowing that near a thousand miles lie between many of
                            the contributors, and that they have never exchanged words, orally, or by pen, how strange
                            that they should speak and feel as though reared by the same Gospel Parents. What an
                            exemplification of the one great Spirit of truth and love that pervades the children of
                            Light! "As many as were of one heart and soul had all things common." These have come up
                            through deep waters of tribulation and are being transformed into pure virgins, for the
                            kingdom of heaven's sake." Here are truly kindred hearts ; those who suffer together for the
                            one great cause of human redemption, and who have plighted their souls to sleep with the
                            nameless martyrs of the past, with no proud monument erected to their memory ; these have
                            pictured truly an ensign of noble deeds, whose fame shall yet extend from pole to pole.
                            These shall ascend in glory and triumph, to their Eternal Parents, who gave them this
                            oneness of spirit. The proud and worldly-wise may scoff, Endeav'ring to afflict us ; But
                            patience doth possess our souls, And wisdom doth direct us. Although in numbers we may wane,
                            Progression's wheel is turning, And all earth's efforts would be vain, To keep Truth's lire
                            from burning, Now kindling on Mount Zion's height; Though few the flames are blowing, All
                            nations jret shall see the light, And taste the fruits we 're sowing. Take courage then,
                            dear kindred hearts, Most precious coins are fewest; And hearts that suffer just as one— The
                            noblest — are the truest. A dawning day I clearly see, "With many untold blessings, And
                            fraught with love and purity. For which are thousands pressing. I would not linger on the
                            brink Of doubt and desolation, Since Christ is here, and sayeth Drink The waters of
                            salvation ; O cleanse the soul from every sin, By sorrow and confession ; Forsake the world
                            that is within, Thus honor your profession.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Rupe, Polly M." TEIform="persName"/>Polly M. Rupe, P. Hill</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reflections upon mother's day" TEIform="index"/>REFLECTIONS UPON MOTHER'S DAY</head><p TEIform="p">The feminine or mother principle and element throughout sentient life, whether on the natural
                            or spiritual plane, is that which produces, develops, protects and cherishes. When, on the
                            natural plane, maternal functions are directed by wisdom and love, in conformity to natural
                            law ; the result is a wellformed healthy organism — a fit temple for the abode of an
                            immortal soul. The good physical mother may not be well qualified to mature and guide the
                            unfolding spirit, which, like the body, should be fed with food adapted to its needs, and
                            powers of assimilation. While man may claim supremacy in contending with, and subduing the
                            physical world, and.utilizing the elements and forces of external nature, looman's mission
                            is to contend with, discipline, and direct the strong current oftlife which flows through
                            the human soul, rippling its surface, or stirring its greatest depths. Her influence, though
                            it may be more silent in its operations, is ever acting on those around her, for good, or
                            for evil. The human form is an outgrowth from the mother; and her soul-life is infused into
                            it; and even the food which she prepares, and the clothing on which her hands and thoughts
                            are employed, bear her impress. She is the architect of Society, if she properly fulfills
                            her maternal duties. Man has his sphere of labor and duty, and may perform his part well, in
                            helping to 79 people the earth on the physical plane ; but he cannot fill the sphere
                            allotted to woman y and whenever he undertakes it, he mars her work. And on the higher,
                            spiritual plane woman has her sphere of action, and peculiar work, which man cannot do.
                            Therefore, if her life is consecrated to purity and goodness, and is under the guidance of
                            the Mother Spirit in Deity, then she becomes a co-worker with man in establishing the
                            kingdom of heaven on earth; and, through the love element (which is a stronger power than
                            argument), and her intuitional nature, which render her accessible to the higher sphere, she
                            becomes a medium to bear souls away from the earthly to the angelic life; and in that way
                            she helps to people the heavens with redeemed spirits, and reflects the image of the
                            Heavenly Maternity. The most sacred right, and the most glorious privilege, of a living
                            soul, is to grow ; and it should be woman's care to promote this growth, and to be a medium
                            through whom the expanding soul-powers may receive the genial sunshine, and refreshing dews,
                            from the Angel world. And, if we would be mediums through whom rays of divine light and
                            truth shall be transmitted to others, our lives must be free from blemish. The Orientalist,
                            in his address to Deity, said, " As shines the sunlight in a drop of dew, so doth thy Spirit
                            in my spirit shine." " Blessed are the pure in heart; for they shall see God." And truly a
                            blessing are they in whom God may be seen.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Broadway, Emeline" TEIform="persName"/>Emeline Broadway, Union Village, Ohio</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thankful heart" TEIform="index"/>THANKFUL HEART</head><p TEIform="p">Oliver W. Holmes wrote the following oft-to-be remembered comparison. " If any one should
                            give me a dish of sand, and tell me there were particles of iron in it, I might look for
                            them with my eyes, and search for them with my clumsy fingers, and be unable to detect them;
                            but let me take a magnet and sweep through it, and it would draw to itself the almost
                            invisible particles, by the mere power of attraction. " The unthankful heart, like my
                            fingers in the sand, discovers no mercies; but let the thankful heart sweep through the day;
                            and, as the magnet finds the iron, so it will find, in every hour, some heavenly blessings;
                            only, the iron in God's sand is gold." The same thought is applicable to our little paper,
                            the Shaker and Shakeress. Let the vain, the worldly, or the sensual person look upon its
                            pages, and they appear barren as the desert wastes. But let truth-loving, truthseeking
                            souls, whose desires are unfulfilled, behold the same pages, and they bloom like a garden in
                            spring ; they blossom the promises of immortal fruit; they gleam with unpolished jewels; and
                            they hold the " pearl of great price"—the virgin pearl. They speak with the voice of home
                            love — the home and the love whose foundations are deeply laid, and whose perfection shall
                            be the blessing of eternity. Fast and far may our dual sheet speed to the hearts that aspire
                            to be pure; for they shall see the work of God wherever it is wrought.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Devyr, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/>Cecelia Devyr, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If the glory of this world wanes, we see another glory ..." TEIform="index"/>If the glory of this world wanes, we see another glory...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">If the glory of this world wanes, we see another glory pertaining to a world, of which this
                            is but a shadow, rising and becoming visible to our spiritual senses. Sorrows will cease in
                            the good time coming, when light shall comprehend or banish all works of darkness from human
                            souls ; remove the cause, and the effect will cease. Then pain, hatred and strife will give
                            place to the pleasure that flows from pure love. May we realize the importance of giving our
                            thoughts to God : For surely " it shall be well with the righteous, and ill with those who
                            transgress God's laws."</p><byline TEIform="byline">— <persName reg="B., Charlotte" TEIform="persName"/>Cliarlotte B.</byline></div2><pb n="80" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Progression" TEIform="index"/>PROGRESSION</head><p TEIform="p">1. Be firm our endeavor to follow the right, Though many our purpose oppose, 3. The hill of
                            redemption with courage we'll climb, Though rugged our pathway and steep, 3. The darkness of
                            doubt that be clouded our way, Fades far in the distance from sight, The weapons we wield
                            are untarnish'd and bright, And mighty to vanquish our foes, We will join the victorious
                            army of truth Unflinching 'mid trials and dangers of time, Still sunward our course we will
                            keep, For a sweet sound of triumph floats down from the spheres We press for the glory of
                            eternal day, Where lingers no shadow or blight, We will swell the grand chorus with heaven's
                            bright throng Whose vanguard before us have gone, They traverse the land of perpetual youth,
                            All grown'd with the laurels they' ve won. There's joy in the conqueror's song, With hope
                            all inspiring with gladness it cheers, And hastens our journey a long. The blessing of
                            victory see, The conquest of self over error and wrong, The life that remains for the
                        free.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Woman's reign" TEIform="index"/>WOMAN'S REIGN</head><p TEIform="p">When error's cloud o'erhung the sky, And superstition fill'd the land, The life of Woman knew
                            a blight, And cower'd neath sin's stern demand. She was down-trodden and oppress'd — A slave
                            to Man's ignoble reign: Her will — her strength — to his must bend, Whate'er the loss,
                            whate'er the pain. Yet through the struggling tide of years, The cause of reason claim'd the
                            day, And bade her trusting spirit wait Till truth should sweep the wrong away. And, through
                            the heat and wave of strife, She cherished still her lofty aim— To be a bright and guiding
                            star, And thus the sinful heart reclaim. The powers above in earnest strove To form on earth
                            a home of love, And woman was the temple sought For the white-breasted, spotless dove. The
                            angels bore unto her soul The power to lift the fallen race ; They cloth'd her with the gift
                            of God, And in the truth gave her a place. A Mother in her sphere she rules, Unbias'd by
                            inferior power ; And nobles own her life — her love — And seek it as an angel dower. Her
                            worth unto mankind is known; Her inspiration has been felt; She leads the wand'ring to the
                            truth, With penitence the heart to melt. Unto her Order thousands bend, To feel her touch of
                            holiness, And prove, with her, that Virtue's cause Is full of joy and blessedness. Her name
                            shall spread throughout the earth, Till all shall know her influence true ; And, through a
                            Mother's strength of love, Their life in God and Christ renew.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Byrdsall, Charlotte" TEIform="persName"/>Charlotte Byrdsall, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Heavenly treasures" TEIform="index"/>HEAVENLY TREASURES</head><p TEIform="p">O lay up your treasures in heaven above! For purity reigns in those mansions of love, Where
                            peace like a river the righteous enjoy, While heaven-born pleasures their time doth em-
                            ploy. The treasures of heaven are fadeless and pure ; No earthly enjoyment can like them
                            endure : O then let your hearts for these treasures aspire, Let nothing inferior claim your
                            desire. The bubbles of time, with their shining display, Leave sad disappointment as time
                            wears away; Then seek for the fruits that from righteousness grow; Press onward, the life of
                            the Spirit to know : For those who are seeking those treasures to find, Who labor sincerely
                            with heart, soul, and mind, Shall swiftly the path of redemption pursue ; And Wisdom will
                            guide them in all that they do. Their treasured enjoyments are those that will last, An
                            enduring substance when all else is past. But earth's richest gift can abide but a day: They
                            vanish like dew in the summer sun's ray.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Patrick, Marion" TEIform="persName"/>Marion Patrick, Enfield, Ct.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hard and bitter words" TEIform="index"/>Hard and Bitter Words</head><p TEIform="p">—We all speak and write too many hard and bitter words. We try to break, not to mend the
                            bruised reed. While we strive to be s trong in faith, let us not despise the faith of the
                            weakest; for there will come a day to all of us when, in the giving way of the powers of
                            nature, and the pouring in of the great water-floods, we may grasp at something which may
                            hold, up and carry us over. And then, not how much we have searched out and know, not how
                            much we have disputed and prevailed, will help us, but how much we have lived on Christ and
                            imbibed his Spirit.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Alford, Dean" TEIform="persName"/>Dean Alford. — Ex.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pelham, Richard W." TEIform="index"/>Richard W. Pelham
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Pelham, Richard W." TEIform="persName">Richard W. Pelham</persName>, aged 76, Union Village,
                                O., July.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="McCue, Michael" TEIform="index"/>Michael McCue
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="McCue, Michael" TEIform="persName">Michael McCue</persName>, aged 49, Tyringham, Mass., Aug.
                                1st.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rude, Hiram" TEIform="index"/>Hiram Rude
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Rude, Hiram" TEIform="persName">Hiram Rude</persName>, aged 71, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., Aug.
                                4th.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Atherton, Nancy" TEIform="index"/>Nancy Atherton
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Atherton, Nancy" TEIform="persName">Nancy Atherton</persName>, aged 76, Shirley, Mass., Aug.
                                23d.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nutting, Jonas" TEIform="index"/>Elder Jonas Nutting
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Nutting, Jonas" TEIform="persName">Elder Jonas Nutting</persName>, aged 71, Shirley, Mass.,
                                Aug. 26th.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Eades, Robinson" TEIform="index"/>Elder Robinson Eades
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Eades, Robinson" TEIform="persName">Elder Robinson Eades</persName>, aged 69, South Union,
                                Ky., Aug. 28th.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Plain Talks upon Practical Religion, being Candid Answers to Earnest Inquirers" TEIform="index"/>Plain Talks upon Practical Religion, being Candid Answers to Earnest Inquirers
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"Plain Talks upon Practical Religion, being Candid Answers to Earnest Inquirers." — This is a
                            pamphlet of twenty-four pages, containing, among other interesting matter, " What shall I do
                            to be a Shaker? " by Elder G. A. Lomas. For single copies or larger quantities address this
                            office, or the author, Shaker's, Albany N. Y. Price, 8 cents single; $5.00 per hundred.</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker and Shakeress. Addresses of the Local Editors and Publishers" TEIform="index"/>
                            SHAKER AND SHAKERESS. Addresses of the Local Editors and Publishers</head><p TEIform="p">Elder F. W. Evans, Mt. Lebanon, Col. Co. N. Y. G. A. Lomas, Albany, N. Y. Shakers. Calvin G.
                            Reed, Sonyea, Living'n Co. N. Y. Simon Mabee, West Pittsfield, Mass. H. S. Kellogg,
                            Thompsonville, Conn. Shakers. Albert Battles, Tyringham, Berkshire Co. Mass. Wm. Leonard,
                            Ayer, Mass. Shakers. John Whiteing, Shirley Village, Middlesex Co. Mass. B. H. Smith, Shaker
                            Village, Merrimack Co. N. H. Henry Cummings, Enfield, Graf ton Co. N. H. John B. Vance,
                            Alfred, York Co. Maine Shakers. Nehemiah Trull, West Gloucester, Cumberland Co. Me. Shakers.
                            Charles Clapp, Union Village, Warren Co. O. Shakers. Ezra Sherman, Preston, Hamilton Co.,
                            Ohio Shakers. Stephen Ball, Dayton, Ohio Shakers. Jacob Kulp, Pleasant Hill, Mercer Co., Ky.
                            J. R. Eades, South Union, Logan Co., Ky. J. S. Prescott, Cleveland, Ohio Shakers.</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>