<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2511" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">28</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">East Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">25</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">11</biblScope><date value="18951101" TEIform="date">November 1895</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">243-266</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="25" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="11" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
NOVEMBER.
MANIFESTO
PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES.
VOL. XXV.
" Cast thy bread upon the waters ; for thou shalt find it after. many days.'
Eccl. XI: i.
East Canterbury, N. H.
1895.
THE
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
CONTENTS.
PageSheaves of Experience, - - - -     243
Tribute to Mother Ann Lee,   -     .       -          245
Elder John Lyon,......      247
Letter,John Whiteley,           ...         250
"   ,F. Silsby Tripp,                                  251
Double Dealing,......         252
Old Age,........      255
Music,Soul Awakening,         -       -       -         256
Notes About Home,.....      257
Sanitary,.......         263
In Memory of Caroline Downs,         -       26JS,  265
A boy who laughed at other people,   -         264
Exchanges,.......        "
Deaths,........         205
Books & Papers,      -      -      -      -      -      -       266
WANTED SALESMEN
     t.wn rtnnr> TWRTNT in pn.p.li nmmtv
We
want
one or
two GOOD MEN in each County to take
orders for a Choice line of NURSERY
STOCK or SEED POTATOES Stock and
Seed guaranteed. We can give you Steady
Employment with Regular Pay. It will
cost you nothing to give it a trial. State when
writing which yor prefer to sell.   Address
The Hawks Nursery Co.,
Rochester, N. Y.
cMATSJRADEMMs
COPYRIGHTS.
CAN I OBTATN A PATENT? Fora
prompt answer and an honest opinion, write to
MUNN & CO., who have had nearly fifty years'
experience in the patent business. Communications strictly confidential. A Handbook of Information concerning Patents and how to obtain them sent free. Also a catalogue of mechanical and scientific books sent free.
Patents taken through Mum & Co. receive
special notice in the Scientific American, and
thus are brought widely before the public without cost to the inventor. This splendid paper,
issued weekly, elegantly illustrated, has by far the
largest circulation of any scientific work in the
world.  $3 a year.   Sample copies sent free.
Building Edition monthly, $2.50 a year. Single
copies, tiS cents. Every number contains beautiful plates, in colors, and photographs of new
houses, with plans, enabling builders to show the
latest designs and secure contracts.   Address
MUNN & CO., New York, 361 Broadway.
THE DIVINE AFFLATUS,
A
FOECE IN HISTORY.
Price, 10 cts.
AGENTS    WANTED
Salary or commission to good men.
Fast selling Imported Specinlties.
Stoci failing to lire replace! free.
Also Pure Seed Potato Stock our Leader
"Lincoln," (480 bu, per acre past season
Address   R. D. LUTCHFORD &   CO.,
(Letterspromptly answered.)   ROCHESTER,  N. Y.
WANTED
Good reliable men, to sell
our Choice and Hardy
Nursery Stock such as Fruit
Trees, Roses Shrubs and Ornamentals. Ladle* make this business a success. Easy work, pleasant, light and profitable. OtJTi'iT Free. A pply at once, with references, and secure choice, of territory.
:E\   US".   M^Y   COJMPANY,
Nurserymen  ant!   Seedsmen,   Rochester, nsr. y.
THE   ALTRUIST.
Is a monthly paper, paitly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is published by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all
their property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing
officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. 50 cents a year;
specimen copy free. Address A. Longley.
Higbee,   Mo.
HUMAN NATURE
is an illustrated Monthly, now only 50 cts.
per    year,    devoted   to   PHRENOLOGY,
PHYSIOGNOMY,  HEALTH,   MEDICAL
& SOCIAL EEP0KM.
Would you like a copy?
Send 5 cts. for Sample to Prof. Haddock,
Phrenologist, 1016 Market St.,
San Francisco, Cal.--><pb n="243" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sheaves of experience" TEIform="index"/>SHEAVES OF EXPERIENCE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, Oliver C." TEIform="persName"/>By Oliver C. Hampton.</byline><p TEIform="p">FINITE means that which is limited. Infinite is that which is unlimited. Yet the former is
                            included in the latter, must be, else the latter would be limiied and then it would not be
                            Infinite. The mass of Being called Man, taken in its entirety may be an infinite categoy or
                            series, but individual man is a finite being and limited in many ways and dependent for his
                            existrncj and happiness upon his fellow man and the other facts of Ins environment. "God
                            never made an independent man. 'Twould mar the concord of his general plan." Herein I feel
                            certain the Christian Scientists have grievously erred. They teach not only the generic
                            independence of individual man, but that it is his duty to ignore all authority of his
                            fellow man to dictate to him any policy, or allow himself to be led by any influence
                            whatever, one side of the suggestions of his own shallow mind and his own sweet will. The
                            salutary experiences of his predecessors for millions of years, must all go for nothing. No
                            authority, no book, no experience, nay not even a suggestion outside of, or foreign to, the
                            individual's own natural sagacity or intuition must be entertained for a moment, lest it
                            interfere with the integrity of his or her independence by which alone they must "root pig
                            or die." No obedience to any other influence no odds how assisting or salutary, no odds if
                            it come from heaven, earth or hell beneath, must be allowed to modify in the least degree
                            that little egotistic idol of almost latent intuition and self-assertion which they have set
                            up in themselves for adoration and worship. One thing about this would be laughable were it
                            not so utterly contemptible. That is, that while ignoring all authority and exhorting all
                            others t do the same they proceed to palm their doctrines, experiences, inspirations, etc.,
                            upon others with an authority and superciliousness that would seem ludicrous enough if it
                            were not so tiresome and disgusting. <pb n="244" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 244 THE MANIFESTO. I have not so
                            learned Christ. "He spoke with authority and not us the Scribes." Yet he had no right to,
                            only because he was wiser and better than other men. This constitutes all authority. The
                            systematic use of this authority in all organizations and communities of men lo realize the
                            bl -ssings of that great law of the universe enunciated by St. Paul, "Without all
                            contradiction the less is blest of the better," Heb. vii., 7, is philosophical, reasonable
                            and justifiable. It is only another way of stating the great problem of evolution through
                            whose instrumentality all things are moving to higher and higher perfection. The whole
                            Universe is the direct effect of Love and Wisdom acting in the systematic order of parental
                            government in that direction alone by which the less are blest of the better. The authority
                            proceeds naturally and legitimately from the law and claims obedience from the nature of
                            things. Jesus indirectly claimed this authority wh^n the Pharisees a-ke 1 him by whit
                            authority he proceeded, and he would not tell them. He not only had the authority but
                            delegated the same to his apostles and the result was the Peniecostal Church. This church
                            was systematically organized with reference 1st. To the law of the less being blessed of the
                            better. 2nd. To securing the greatest benefit to the greatest number. 3rd. To securing the
                            mos&gt;t perfect conditions of altruism or vmselfi-hness. So the Savior and his followers did
                            not marry nor have any thin i to do with amativmess or fleshly indulgence either social or
                            solitary. Why? Uecause that is the most selfish proclivity in man. And what had they to do
                            with any old charnel house of legalized or unlegaiized "lu.^t of the flesh, hist of the eye
                            or pr'.d.; of life." They had all things in common. Why? Because this secuivd the greatest
                            good to the greatest number. They had leaders and directors. Why? Because a systematic
                            organization of the energies of a people are a thousand times more efficient than any
                            isolated effort, or even the efforts of many persons working in separate directions and
                            often to cross purposes, defeating the result of the greatest good to the greatest number.
                            The Shakers have lived to this Pentecostal arrangement ever since their establishment as a
                            Church, now about one hundred and twenty years. They have all reason to be satisfied with
                            it. From long experience it has proved to be the only really successful Christian
                            Institution attempted since the days of Jesus Christ upon the earth. For while hundreds and
                            hundreds of efforts have been made on other than Pentecostal lines, they have all failed,
                            and most of them have been long since relegated to the limbo of worthless and worn out
                            systems. This pentecostal arrangement of the primitive church of Christ was the direct
                            result of the word that was made flesh and dwelt with men, rendering them saviors, fathers,
                            mothers, directors, apostles on whom Christ bestowed <pb n="245" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MAN [FES TO.
                            245 the authority to lead an 1 guide the church in wisdom and parental authority and
                            soiicitu.l &gt;, and continued till destroyed by the selfishness, lust and ambition of a
                            corrupt and unscrupulous hierarchy of secular priests, bishops, and popes. Mother Ann again
                            revived, revitalized and reorganized this pentecostal system with all its authority,
                            spiritual power and saving efficacy. We close by saying that the authority of a parental
                            government is not only legitimate and justifiable, worthy of existence, regard, obedience;
                            not only the one preach &gt;d and lived by Jesus, but the only one in heaven or earth which
                            will ever be proposed and succeed for the present and future benefit and happiness of
                            mankind here or hereafter. Now therefore, "the Spirit and the Bride say, Come, and let him
                            that heareth say, Come, and let him that is athirst say, Come, and whosoever will, let him
                            take the water of life freely." Rev. xxii., 17. Union Village, O.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tribute to the memory of mother Ann Lee" TEIform="index"/>A TRIBUTE to the Memory of Mother
                            Ann Lee.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Vinneo, Cora C." TEIform="persName"/>By Cora C. Vinneo.</byline><p TEIform="p">How strange it seems across the years to look, The rounding years of brightness and of shade,
                            And read them like the chapters of a book That fate has made. How near it seems and yet so
                            far away, Since she who was inspired beyond her time, Led by tin? hand that never leads
                            astray bought out this clime. The nation's hand was red with patriot's blood, The nation's
                            air was thick with battle smoke, And tribulation like a plunging flood, Upon it broke. But
                            freedom never yet was easy won, What is not worth a struggle dies with thought, 'Tis only by
                            the mighty action done, That good is wrought. She came, our Mother, with a heart of steel,
                            Bringing a courage worthy of the strife, And with a soul baptized with love and zeal She
                            gave her life. Gave it in suffering for the nation's good, Gave it a ransom for her people's
                            weal, <pb n="246" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 246 TEE MANIFESTO. In that strong fortitude which is subdued By
                            what we feel. Above the baneful battle cloud she saw The white winged messengers- of rich
                            inc. ease, Saw Mercy temper Justice, through the iaw Of holy peace, She saw the nation's
                            victory sure though slow,, She saw her mission prosper wheiv 'twas sent, And saw God's
                            promise like a sunset glow Of good intent. Her church was. reared amid the smoke and Hi me
                            That made the land of freedom that we prize, Together they must cherish freedom's name, Must
                            sink or rise. Shall we turn cowards where her heart was strong, When work increasing calls
                            us to the field? Nay, though self-love the struggle may prolong; We must not yield. In every
                            motive by the Spirit led., She builded wiser than the mortal knew, And in the light of
                            inspiration read The future through. In all the soul's deep vales and solitudes, She walked
                            with unshod feet in solemn trust, At home with duty in its sternest moods., And wise and
                            just. Let us give honor where the debt is due, Rememb'ring all the blessings that she
                            brought, Clean was her soul and pure her hand, and true The life she taught. Ah, who shall
                            fail to count these mercies o'er Nor let them scattered be like falling leaves, Should he
                            who gathers grain forget to store The golden sheaves? Shall we who reap the harvest sown in
                            pain Grow weak in purpose through neglect or haste ? Nay, better never see the precious
                            grain Than let it waste. A Mother's blessing clothed in white and gold, Conies down the
                            shaded vista of the past, <pb n="247" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 247 And on life's rugged
                            mountain ways behold A light is cast. Our path is smoother, for the brightness shed Around
                            the dangerous places that she trod, Makes us avoid the pitialls and the dread Dark road from
                            God. Teach us oh Father, how to rightly prize The wisdom that is perfect from above, Teach
                            us oh Mother, how to realize Thy tender love. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Elder John Lyon, third paper" TEIform="index"/>ELDER JOHN LYON. Third Paper.</head><p TEIform="p">STOOD filled with wonder and lifted my eyes toward the East and saw a bright light as fine as
                            a hair. It stood perpendicularly and appeared about eight feet in length. Then a voice was
                            heard to say, "Go to that light." I was very anxious to do so. As I looked towards the
                            light, I saw a vast, deep gulf, with almost perpendicular banks, and some timber extended
                            across in the form of abridge, though it seemed to extend a considerable distance right and
                            left. This timber was partially covered with planks, thrown on in a promiscuous manner and
                            some of the planks were badly decayed, so that I thought it was a dangerous place and
                            required the greatest carefulness to cover it. In obedience to the voice, I moved toward
                            this streak of light. Just as I reached the edge of the gulf, I was enveloped in darkness.
                            Every vestige of light was withdrawn exc -pt that little streak toward which I was moving.
                            Then I b^gan to look around and to feel for something firm upon which to place my feet. Not
                            finding anything I remained quiet and looked for the little ray of light, but it was gone. O
                            the sorrow I was in ! enveloped in darkness and fearing to move, tongue can not express the
                            anxiety of my soul. At length, I thought I would try to find the light and if I should
                            succeed, there was hope, if not, I was lost. I moved to the right and left, and finally
                            discovered the bright light. Oh, how happy I felt, when I saw it once more, but alas, I did
                            not yet know how I lost it, nor how to keep it. I had no other way left for me, than to try
                            to move forward toward the light, for I had no hope in trying to get back: so I turned
                            directly toward the light, and moved on, still trying to look about in the dark with all
                            attention, feeling my way with my feet, lest I should get into some hole. I again thought I
                            would look for the light, and see which way I was groping. When I looked, behold it was
                            gone, and I could discern nothing of it. With what horror I was struck! I knew not <pb n="248" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 248 THE MANIFESTO. which way to move. I had learned that a little
                            deviation would cause me to lose the light. I knew that my first work must be to find the
                            ray of light. I moved a little, not knowing which way I moved on my course. It seemed a long
                            time that I was struggling in distress of mind to find the light again. I felt much worse
                            than I did the first time that I lost sight of the light. After struggling in this manner,
                            resolving to do all I could to keep it, I caught the sight. O how rejoiced I was at this new
                            privilege. Then I was filled with fear, lest I should lose it again for I did not know how
                            to retain it. Yet, there was no way for me but to try to move on as well as I could in the
                            dark as before. Again, when I lifted up my eyes to look for the light, I could see nothing
                            of it. My whole soul was filled with despair, I not only despaired of finding the light
                            again, but also of keeping sight of it. I thought that I had as well give up to die where I
                            was ; I could not think of trying to get back, and to go forward was impossible; but all
                            these thoughts of mine did not mitigate my distress. I began to cry and beg that if there
                            was any help for me that I might have it and also know why it was that I did not or could
                            not keep sight of the light when I had it. I was told with energy "You have not asked simply
                            for instruction and have not determined to obey it when you are instructed." This cut me to
                            the heart; 1 thought 1 had done as well as I could, and if I could be directed how to escape
                            from this terrible situation, I would follow the direction through life. Then it was said to
                            my understanding, "You have proved darkness and have found that you could do nothing without
                            light. Here lies the whole mystery of your case. When you discerned the light, you turned
                            your sense from it, and followed your own way, and was led by your own judgment till you
                            found yrurself enveloped in darkness and then you would begin to search for the light. Thus
                            you have done from time to time, but you did not consider that all you had to do was to
                            follow the light which God has placed before you and not in you. Now if you would be
                            released from the distressed situation you are in, place yourself in view of the light, with
                            your eyes fixed on it and go straight forward then you will not find any impediment in the
                            way where this light shmes." After receiving this instruction, I said, "I will, this shall
                            be my course now and forever." Accordingly my first effort was to find the streak of light
                            and to place myself in the direction of it. I moved in every direction, as I had done
                            before, only with this difference, I thought of nothing but the light. I did not try to look
                            about in the dark, nor to feel my way with my feet, but moved about as rapidly as I could,
                            and presently I discovered the light with an inexpressible ray of joy. It seemed brighter
                            than it did before ; although it appeared so unspeakably bright, it did not illuminate the
                            region where I was, but left it in profound darkness. Having placed my eyes directly on <pb n="249" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 249 the light, I was determined to reaph it and pay no
                            attention to any other object. With this determination I moved on without any difficulty
                            find arrived at the point from which the light came, only to find a wall which I could not
                            pass; it was so dark that I could not discern of what it was composed. There were two
                            pillars inserted in the wall, and placed as near as possible to each other without touching.
                            It was from between the pillars the light came. The pillars were like polished silver and
                            were eight inches square, by eight feet long, and were so constructed, that by placing my
                            eye close to the joint between the pillars, I could look through and see a hemisphere of
                            light and such brightness as nothing on earth can describe. It was brighter than the sun,
                            yet my sight was such that I could look on it without my eyes being dazzled. It was the most
                            delightful scene that I had ever beheld and I wished that I might look upon it forever.
                            Accordingly I knelt down* and placed my head against the pillars where I had full view of
                            the light. How long I was in this situation, I do not know, but after an interval of time, I
                            heard the same voice, which I had heard before, as it came rolling through the heavens. Thus
                            closed my vision, and I found myself on my knees, while a space of some twelve inches in
                            diameter was wet with tears. I returned to the house and found that I had been in this
                            trance about four hours. A strange change was wrought in me, during this season. I awoke to
                            find myself released from all past trouble, and all I had to do was to walk in the light of
                            God's love and by his appointed Order, to fix my eyes on this light and go straight forward.
                            I learned that God had appointed but one way, to lead the soul from nature's darkness, and
                            at this time I determined to build upon this principle. It will be seen, as before stated,
                            that I fully believed that my Elders were the witnesses of God, when I went before them for
                            confession. I was shown however that if I would become one of the sons of God, I must be led
                            by the spirit of God, .and that his will must become my will, and his judgment become my
                            judgment. 1 have been helped into four principles of Godliness by supernatural agency. One
                            in childhood, two in youth and one after reaching manhood. My faith has been fully
                            established from the day I had them revealed to me, and I have acted according to them in
                            the decisions of my after life. I can not close without stating the difference between the
                            state I was in before I received these manifestations, (especially the two last,) and my
                            subsequent situation. Before these things were made known to me, not having come to judgment
                            myself, but being my own judge, I could easily judge others. When I thought that they did
                            not do quite right, even in such things as did not in the least concern me, it would provoke
                            me, to think that they were unwilling to do as I thought they ought. Thus having my own
                            nature <pb n="250" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 250 TEE MANIFESTO. to dictate me and so many others to judge
                            and rectify, it kept me in continual perplexity. After I received these manifestations the
                            scene changed, all I had to do was to give myself to God. From this time, I set myself at
                            work to comply with what was made known to me; instead of vexation, I found peace, instead
                            of perplexity and trouble, I found comfort and consolation. From one who loves the spiritual
                            New Creation. Enfield, N. H. (The End.)</p></div2><div2 type="Section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="E. I. Lindh, Secretary United Christian Association..." TEIform="index"/>
                                E. I. Lindh, Secretary United Christian Association...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Massachusetts, Shirley, August 6, 1895" TEIform="index"/>Shirley, Mass., Aug. 6,
                                1895.</dateline><p TEIform="p">E. I. Lindh, Secretary United Christian Association, Cambridge, Mass., Dear Friend :After
                                reading the reports of the Ayer Conference of July 30, I much- regretted that I had not
                                arranged to be there, so that I could have enjoyed the pleasant interchange of thought.
                                We know that it is the expressed wish of Jesus that his disciples should be one, not
                                two, much less that they should be divided into hundreds of organizations, and it does
                                seem lamentable there should be such diversity, even if those organizations were at
                                perfect oneness within themselves. Still, if there is an assurance of growth toward a
                                divine oneness, as would seem to be the case, there is reason for hope and encouragement
                                to work for so desirable a result, individually and collectively. Few, very few, if any,
                                have attained that growth of perfection that would justify them in arrogating to
                                themselves the right to dictate a standard for others. Nor is there any need of it, for
                                what other foundation can any man lay than is laid in the life and testimony of Jesus
                                the Christ, and its everlasting increase. I rejoice, as every true disciple will, in
                                every manifestation of growth or endeavor toward this increase, wherever found. There is
                                much to be done, and a blessing will come to every true-hearted worker. We find no
                                antagonism in Christ, except against wrong in whatever form it may be found; and that
                                antagonism will find its most fruitful labor in the warfare against the wrong in each
                                one's own heart. Then, in union with those like minded a power for good will be
                                developed that will be effectual, for they will love each other dearly, whatever their
                                other ideas may be, of God in his Oneness, a Trinity, or as God the Father and Mother of
                                all. There is no disunion in God. United with Christ we shall be one with God. Let us
                                strive for this union first, then all will be well. Yours very truly,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whiteley, John" TEIform="persName"/>John Whiteley.</byline></div3><pb n="251" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It was said by Nordhoff..." TEIform="index"/>It was said by Nordhoff...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Kentucky, Pleasant Hill, August 1895" TEIform="index"/>Pleasant Hill, Ky., Arc;.
                                189o.</dateline><p TEIform="p">IT was said by Nordhoff in his book upon ''American Communism" that "to look upon the
                                members of the Shaker brotherhood, revealed to him an appearance as of something
                                wanting,the semblance of a life that had been lived in vain." This sentiment, though
                                possibly penned in more homely words than were used by this eminent writer, made upon me
                                an impression that has ever been before me in reading the literary work of authors on
                                Shaker Communism, not of the faith of the United Society of Believers. The introduction
                                to old age one receives among the Shaker people, is one of the most pleasing meetings
                                that is accorded a kindly inquirer. It presents to you a life that has long since
                                relegated its walks of busy usefulness, (as is spoken of the active career of the
                                brother or sister in the full discharge of family life) to the quiet of meditation, and
                                review of the career that has been safely passed through, and now presents the beautiful
                                picture of the reward of an earthly life well lived. There are some, and the writer has
                                personally observed them, who, at this period of life, will bewail and moan over their
                                fate; speaking of themselves as being set aside upon the human shelf, worn out and
                                useless, an incumbrance upon the busy hive of workers. They speak of themselves as hav
                                ing lived too long. Oh ! this is sad. But many are seen whose proud delight it is to
                                recount and narrate every detail of a past that has lived to become eighty or ninety
                                years of ripe and natural existence. It will be found, in reviewing the past, every joy
                                accounted for, every grief made whole, every debt and obligation paid. It is a pleasing
                                sight and is an incentive to live the better life. It speaks well, too, of the, virgin
                                life of the true Believers, those who accepted the higher example of Christ, and who in
                                the Shaker Church followed in the teachings of Mother Ann Lee. She was an inspired
                                woinau of the faith in the second appearing of Christ, to the United Society of
                                Believers, as the Shakers now address themselves. This is a life of toil, of faith, of
                                charity, of celibacy, and preparation for the eternal salvation. The brotherhood and
                                sisterhood of this religious sect, are a long lived people, those whose respect for
                                their covenant has been of paramount consideration. It is a successful life, when you
                                can approach and ask, "Is it well?" And you receive the response, "I would live it all
                                over again, were it granted."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Tripp, F. Silsby" TEIform="persName"/>F. Silsby Tripp.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The grand panorama of life..." TEIform="index"/>The grand panorama of life...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The grand panorama of life is continually passing before us. The forces of nature move in
                            endless procession. To learn their meaning is to understand ourselves.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, C." TEIform="persName"/>C. Allen.</byline></div2><pb n="252" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Double dealing" TEIform="index"/>DOUBLE DEALING</head><p TEIform="p">AMONG the many profitabl lessons of the Scriptures that hav been preservd for our reproof and
                            instruction in righteousness, is the one found in the ninth chapter of Joshua. The incident
                            has in it much that pictures the real traits of human nature of three thousand years ago and
                            quite like that which is found in the race at the present time. Whatever the Gibeonites may
                            hav been at an earlier date, they forfeited, thru this stratagem all their rights and
                            privileges and became the wiling slaves of their Jewish masters. We do not suppose that they
                            could foresee all that would transpire in their case, but they made a venture which ended
                            disastrously. It was an attempt to do sumthing smart, but they faild thru their low
                            craftiness and being detected they suffered the penalty of their foolishness. In the third
                            chapter of second Timothy it says,"All Scripture is given by inspiration of God," which wil
                            of course include this story of the Gibeonites. It did not require an inspiration much above
                            the low cunning of human nature to develop and to act just such a scene as that found in the
                            book of Joshua. We do think, however, that the great military captain was a litl obtuse in
                            not being better informed about the several tribes that were at so short a distance from his
                            camp. On meeting Joshua this cunning company said to him, "Thy servants hav cum from a far
                            cuntry. We hav herd of the fame of the L^rd thy God, and all that he did in Egypt. And what
                            he did to the Amorites, and to Sihon beyond Jordan. And our people said to us, "Take food
                            and go meet the Israelites and form a league with them and say,We ar your humble servants."
                            So far there was one sprinkling of truth and two sprinklings of falsehood in their deceptiv
                            story. It was what they calld in that day, craftiness or subtlety, but we denounce it as
                            deception or a white lie. Then they enlarge the story as follows,"We took this bread from
                            the oven, while it was hot and now it is dry and mouldy. These skins of wine were new but
                            now they ar old and broken. Our shoes hav worn out on the journey and our garments that were
                            new ar ruined from the hardship that we hav experienced." The whole of the closing statement
                            was utterly false and was made use of to deceive Joshua, and to obtain a promise from him
                            that he would not destroy their nation. Their bread was mouldy when they put it into the
                            bags. The wine skins were old and broken when they DEALING-. <pb n="253" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. 253 left home to go on this journey of two or three days, and their shoes which
                            they said were new on leaving home were proved to be those which had been thrown away, but
                            gathered again for this special occasion. This singular tribe must have presented a sorry
                            appearance on the morning of their deception and especially after it was ascertaind that
                            their very long march was only about forty or fifty miles. As Joshua had made peace with
                            them to let them live he now informed them that for their deception, he would make them
                            hewers of wood and drawers of water. In this case it did not pay to practice such deception.
                            It never pays. Those who do it give themselvs into a slavery far worse than that experienced
                            by the Gibeonites. From the first instance in the history of man we hav learnd that the way
                            of the transgressor is hard. It wil always be hard to live where dishonesty and double
                            dealing is allowd to prevail. Had this been a solitary instance left for us we might hav
                            lookt upon a past age with greater pleasure. Marvelous things ar said to hav occurrd in that
                            day which may never take place again so long as man exists. Angels dwelt among men, and they
                            tell us that the voice of God was heard in their camp as a man speaking face to face with
                            his friend. Such privileges ar not conferred upon us, and yet we think we ar living in a
                            better age than was ever known at a previous date and indeed we ar, for "The world is
                            growing better Every year." More men and women ar at work making the Lord's paths straight
                            and the rough places smooth. Light is abroad in the world and the thousands ar walking by
                            it. Mercy and charity abound, and these precious blessings ar scatterd on every hand with a
                            wonderful liberality. Every thing may not be just right but the march is onward. If a man or
                            a family or even a nation return to ignorance and to barbarism it may be bad for the
                            individual and for the nation, but the mass of mankind is not that way. Great care however
                            should be taken with children and youth and with mature manhood, teaching at all times as
                            did Jesus that the truth shall make us free. Those who think of leading a religious life wil
                            find that everything that pertains to the moral and spiritual development of the mind
                            demands a careful attention. It is line upon line and precept upon precept, and this thru an
                            honest self-examination. The faithful and honorable sons and daughters of our God can only
                            reach their place of protection as did Jesus our heavenly pattern, by <pb n="254" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/>
                            254 THE MANIFESTO. years and years of watchfulness and prayer. On the other hand
                            lukewarmness and a growing indifference wil lead to ruin and like those who visited Joshua,
                            choose rather to fall into slavery than to speak the truth. Such premeditated falsifying had
                            been nurtured, no doubt, in their homes for years and this was only the culmination. Men may
                            do wrong. Cases may arise where one man, or may be three or four men will agree to falsify
                            their word, but it would be hard to find a whole tribe like the Gibeonites who had traveled
                            fifty weary miles and held a lie unchanged for three days. Even at this early date mankind
                            had received sum excellent lessons in morality and wel knew the fearful penalty that was
                            sure to follow a wilful transgression, yet such was their cupidity that the horrors of an
                            inquisition could not hold them within the bounds of propriety. Where was the blame to be
                            laid? Burning, as every Jew did, with a dominant spirit to rule the wh )le earth, his
                            education being in the midst of the crime of slavery and the fierce unrelenting spirit of
                            war, what better thing could we expect of him? And what better is an uneducated,
                            undisciplind man of to-day? What can be a clearer representativ of a hideous savage or of a
                            wild beast than the brutal work of an ignorant mob ? Then the beast in man predominates, and
                            lost to all reason the mob would tear a person limb from limb, or burn him to death by slow
                            torture. In the case that was enacted in Texas but a few years since the religious and the
                            irreligious acted in concert to brutalize a human being. And yet we hav good and wholesum
                            laws. The Israelites also had good and wholesum laws and the penalty they inflicted
                            harmonized with the age in which they lived. Our second Bible story or lesson for "reproof
                            and for instruction in righteousness," is of the same character as the first and peculiarly
                            interesting. If such a case could be brought before us to-day it would be sad in the
                            extreme. It is a matter of congratulation, however, that we were born at a later date. Achan
                            knew better than to steal that wedge of gold or that Babylonish garment. As beautiful as the
                            garment may hav been he knew quite wel that he could never wear it, and on this account he
                            hid it in the earth. The whole transaction is characteristic of the man, and in fact, of all
                            men who wil steal. Hiding their goods and lying about them fills up the measure. His guilt
                            was discovered, however. Not by his own honesty but by a long, tedious process of casting
                            lots to ascertain the tribe and then the family, and at last the guilty man. A forced
                            confession was made and the fearful penalty soon followed. It is a long but an interesting
                            and in- <pb n="255" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 255 structiv inspirational story. Read it in
                            the seventh chapter of Joshua, and then you may believe the New Testament doctrine, that the
                            penalty of sin is death. Achan may have been an honest litl boy. He may hav heard the law
                            read Sabbath after Sabbath by the Jewish priests. The commandments may have been one of his
                            lessons for recitation and among these he had lernd, "Thou shalt not steal." As plainly as
                            though he was before us we know that he grew to be a selfish, deceitful and penurious man.
                            He coveted what did not belong to him. He could see his friends destroyed before his enemies
                            and the honor of his cuntry ruined, if by this means he could secure his ill-gotten
                            treasure. This poor Israelite had many foolish followers, and the Achanites are not yet all
                            dead. After three thousand years of preaching and of religious experience the same old story
                            of distorted human nature stil continues. Lessons ar being learned, however, and
                            righteousness enjoys a better place in the minds of men and there is a prospect that the
                            future wil present a better record. The time is coming when "the. knowledge of the Lord wil
                            cover the earth as the waters cover the sea." Peacemakers wil rule and the kingdoms of this
                            world wil becum the kingdoms of our Lord.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/>H. C. Blinn.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Old age" TEIform="index"/>OLD AGE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>By Martha J. Anderson.</byline><p TEIform="p">I would not couple age with weary care, Or closely link it unto sorrow's load Which, lowly
                            bowed on time's long dreary road Must lonely walk in silence and despair. Ah, nay! 'tis
                            day's decline all bright and fair, The genial rest that nature has bestowed; No heated
                            strife life's waning powers to goad, But tranquil peace diffusing everywhere, Not like the
                            gilded morn of childhood's gaze, Not like the glowing day of youth so bright, But softened
                            with the kindly mellowed rays That temper the full beams of glowing light, And robe the
                            distant hills with purpling haze Ere falls the shadowy curtain of the night. And hides the
                            mortal traveler from sight. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><pb n="256" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Soul awakening" TEIform="index"/>SOUL AWAKENING.</head><p TEIform="p">"O send out thy light and thy truth: let them lead me." Psalms, xliii., 3. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.
                            1. Awake, O soul, arise With faith and prayer, Cast 2. The angels circling, will With gifts
                            reiine, And 3. Tread not the vale of woe Where shadow lies, When 4. Array thyself, O soul,
                            In virgin white, Put ev'ry sin aside God's light to share. Go teach the holy laws Of life
                            divine. Ope heights thou mayest scale 'Neath truth's fair skies. When on the jeweled crown
                            Of dimless light. Work forth with firm desire, With trust and love, To wide thine avenues,
                            Thy courts make pure. That pearly mansions shine, For thee a home, A with the power that
                            works Triumphantly, Joined meet thee good will come From heav'n above. Christ may live and
                            reign In thee secure, bide not where the floods Of evil come, to the heavenly host Then thou
                            wilt be.</p></div2><pb n="257" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. NOVEMBER, 1895. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is published by the
                            "United Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued
                            regularly by the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the
                            religious views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. All
                            communications should be addressed to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer, Co., N. H. .75
                            .40 One copy per year, postage paid " six months, " "</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. September. Thermometer. Bain. 1894. 64.1 5 in. 1895.
                                62.89 3.15 in. Highest Temp, during this mo. 90 above 0 Lowest " " " " 32 " " Number of
                                rainy days " " 6 " " clear " " " 17 " " cloudy " " " 7 C. G. Heed. Oct. 1895. The golden
                                days of Autumn, remind us that the growing time, for our locality, is passed. Nature
                                will soon nestle under her white counterpane, for a season of rest. And rest it should
                                be, for she has dealt bountifully with us. From early spring until now the brown earth
                                has been producing, O such a variety of fruits and vegetables. We begin to realize that
                                there is no place so sure of a good crop of something, as our hillsides. Thirty kinds of
                                fruit and vegetables have been grown in our large garden this season. Potatoes weighing
                                two pounds, and tomatoes one and a half pounds, prove that the farm is not useless yet.
                                We feared that the severe cold of last winter, had injured the peach trees, but not so;
                                every tree has done its prettiest. Three bushels of as nice peaches as can be found,
                                have just been gathered from one late tree. Our village school, which for the past
                                century (I think) has been the burden of the two families comprising the Church, now
                                passes into the hands of efficient teachers from the North family. Carpenters and
                                painters have made the school buildings and environments look very attractive, and we
                                trust that the extra tax on the district to meet the demands will make the words of a
                                noted educator true. "The school tax is the best tax." We have just been reviewing the
                                latest book issued by our Society; "Mt. Lebanon Cedar Boughs," a collection of choice
                                and beautiful poems original with the sisterhood of the North family. Surely it makes
                                one feel the influence of the inner court to peruse it. Amelia J. Calrer.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>West Pittsfield, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">Oct. 1895. Since last we occupied a place in the "Home Corner," the buds of spring have
                                opened, under the summer's sun, and ripened with the cooling wind of autumn, and now we
                                are realizing the benefit of a bountiful harvest. Apples and pears very plentiful.
                                Perhaps our pen might find a valuable lesson, from the busy works of nature and fill
                                each month with records of duties performed. During the past summer our Office has been
                                remodeled, and the sound of the hammer has been heard almost daily though the land.
                                Still the results will, TERMS. <pb n="258" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 258 THE MANIFESTO. we think, well
                                compensate for any inecnvenience, as more space of rooms and freer admission of light
                                has betn obtained. Our street also, not to be left in the background in the striiv for
                                improvement, has asserted its lawful rights, and as a consequence we now have a mile of
                                state I road east of us, while another mile west, lias just been commenced. This renders
                                traveling much easier, and as yet we have heard, ''none speak of it but to praise." Last
                                Sunday, the 30th ult., we attended singing-school at the Center family, Mt. Lebanon. We
                                were welcomed very cordially, and and enjoyed a pleasant season with our friends there.
                                Our afternoon's pleasure was dampened slightly by a shower occurring during our ride
                                home. Twice during the summer we have had the pleasure of visiting our friends, from
                                other Societies. Sister Isabella White and Louie Bussel, of Watervliet, were the first
                                to call, and later, Brother Daniel Orcutt, Sisters Caroline Tait, Mabel Thompson and
                                Kobina Page, of Enfield, Conn. We enjoy such seasons for communion with those whose
                                desires and purposes are similar to our own, helps to strengthen us, and binds us more
                                closely to each other forming a more united Community. On two occasions has the Death
                                Angel visited us and taken from our midst a loved father and mother. Elder Albert
                                Battles and Sister Elvira Hulet. We miss them from the home circle, in many ways and it
                                will be long before we cease to remember them in affection. Fidelia Estabroolc.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Oct. 1895. The kind words expressed for The Manifesto by the "World's Advance Thought,"
                                are reciprocal. Speaking from experience and with no disparagement to the many worthy
                                publications, the "Advance Thought" is a jewel of the first water and the principles
                                taught by it are worthy of a foremost place in human society. We enjoy the blessed
                                seasons of spiritual communion in our weekly Society meetings, and we could not but pity
                                those who should lose tluir interest in these seasons; they are of great benefit in the
                                development of a harmonious life. We have been asked how we liked the new method of
                                spelling that is largely used by The Manifesto. We can say that it certainly simplifies
                                the old method, and after the novelty passes away, its superiority over the old method
                                is apparent, At the date of writing, Oct. 6th, we have not on the uplands had any
                                damaging frosts, but on the lowlands around us are frosts that destroyed tender
                                vegetation, on the 15th of Sept. The weather still continues dry. Hamilton DeGraw. A
                                EEFEBENCE to the advanced form of spelling made by Br. Hamilton is quite suggestive.
                                Those who asked the question should know that this change has been moving on from an
                                early age, and while they are astonished at the present slight variation they may be
                                interested to compare it with that of their fathers of only a few generations in the
                                past. See Matt, viii., "Forsothe, when Jhesu hadde comen doun fro the liil, many
                                cumpanyes folewiden hym. And loo! a leprouse man cummynge worshipide hym, saying: Lord
                                yif thou wolt, thou maistmake me clene." Webster's Dictionary. A great many people even
                                at the present date do not spell according to Webster or Worcester, and any new rules
                                will not disturb their form of orthography. We will write a few examples of the spelling
                                of 1895 which are not uncommon. About aboute And annd Access akses Book boc Bones bons
                                Cross croos Contrary conterary Color colour City cytee <pb n="259" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                                MANIFESTO. 259 Entered entride Faults folts Steady- stidey Soul soal Shut shet Fervent
                                farvent Sensibly sencibelly Firm farm Grief greaf Ri vers ryveres Great grete Writers
                                for The Manifesto need have no anxiety about the form of spelling till they obtain a
                                Standard Dictionary. //. C. minn.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">North Family. Oct. 1895. As we sowed, so have we been reaping. Rich harvests have
                                rewarded the laborer's care. Corn-stalks heavy in fruitage reared their tasseled crests
                                ten or fourteen feet above ground. Occasional showers have saved the crops but most of
                                the springs have long since been dry, and we are now without water force for laundry,
                                sewingmachines or other purposes. The endurance of Brethren and of teams is well tested
                                by frequent journeys over the mountain with fruits and vegetables. The small return for
                                so much labor brings us into some degree of sympathy with the struggling masses whose
                                labor is so ill requited. Unlike a large proportion of the world's producers our homes
                                and lands are not as yet mortgaged and our communistic relations, even on the small
                                scale which we have thus far realized, give us some advantages. The probabilites are
                                that ere long our necessities will compel us to adopt a co-operative system between
                                families and societies. We should ever bear in mind that Communism with us, as with the
                                primitive Christians was not a plan but an outgrowth from the divine life in which
                                selfish ties and interests were renounced. As a people should we not earnestly seek a
                                re-baptism of Pentecostal power which will cause us to feel that the spirit of
                                brotherhood and of sisterhood and our spiritual interests generally are paramount to any
                                earthly gain? In the Oct Arena an orthodox Reverend boldly sets forth the slavery of the
                                churches to the money power and their consequent decline. As a part of the great body of
                                humanity do we not share its infirmities? Are we fulfilling our call as leaders in the
                                religious thought of the world by boldly proclaiming against the causes which have
                                produced the present conditions of our civilization? or do we indifferently allow the
                                Sacred Flame to pass to other altars and the testimony committed to us, which should
                                search to the very foundations of sin, find such oracles as B. O. Flower and many other
                                brave prophets and teachers whose souls find voice through the "Arena," a magazine which
                                we believe to be the grandest educator in the country, and which we are happy to say
                                will, the coming year, find its way to every family of Mt. Lebanon, also to kindred over
                                the mountain. This p. m. our meeting was made richer and fuller by the presence of our
                                beloved Canaan friends. The gist of the exhortations were, that we so discern between
                                principles and customs that we may be ready to discard the husk that no longer contains
                                a vital germ;that we look well to our foundations, holding fast to that which is good
                                while reaching forward for the increase of which the lives and teachings of our founders
                                were a continual prophecy. Love abundant to all workers for truth. Catherine Allen.
                                South Family. Oct. 1895. The present month reminds us that time demands the sounding of
                                new Notes, but what the music shall be, the singers must decide. We agree with other
                                contributors of The Manifesto, that God h;is been merciful unto us and caused his face
                                to shine upon us. <pb n="260" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 260 THE MANIFESTO. The party from Enfield,
                                Conn, who visited here during August was one of the summer's sunny features. We hope
                                when Br. Daniel Orcutt and company come again, they will stay longer, Orcut not thtir
                                visit so brief. The fruits of the vineyard have been lich in quality and generous in
                                quantity; no better results of the grape culture can be found in all the region round
                                about Columbia. Of apples a bountiful harvest is being gathered for the coming winter
                                when snow shall cover the earth as the waters cover the sea. The nutting season is
                                greatly enjoyed by our juvenile members. Many bushels of butternuts have been secured
                                for converting into sweetmeats or nut candy which is in daily demand by lovers of all
                                things saccharine. Through the absence of rain flowing streams have become a thing of
                                the past, and a drouth is one of the plagues of the day. May the Lord of the harvest
                                Send showers of rain, To refreshen the earth On mountain and plain. Genevieve DeGraiv.
                                Oct. 1895. Ekdejb Henry :This is a beautiful day in October, but soon the winds and
                                storms of winter will gather us more closely into our homes to enjoy the fruits of our
                                labors, spiritually and temporally. Much has been accomplished the past season and many
                                good things garnered into our treasury. Foolish, indeed, we would be if it were not so.
                                Consecrated hands could not do it all, but the laborer is worthy of his hire. If all do
                                not come in and accept the cross of Christ, we must be thankful for those who are
                                willing and obedient, and therewith be content. We love our comrades who are true and
                                loyal,those who are aged&gt; and no less our beloved companions, and also the dear children
                                for whom we ever pray. In our day we receive from every nation, kindred and tongue.
                                Ministers, Professors and Doctors must all have their day,for so God wills it. We must
                                "advance or we must stand aside and not hinder the progress of others." In obtaining our
                                merchandise we must pay for that which is wrought out by hired labor, not only in our
                                own but foreign lands. As individuals we can do much good. We should praise God and
                                render thanks to Him for the health and strength we have received. We should make good
                                use of these blessings and of all the powers that are conferred upon us. To a certain
                                extent we might wish to be independent, even if not wholly so; but with all that we can
                                do there are multiplied duties that we can not even find time to do. We are now thanking
                                the carpenters for the houses so substantially built: and some of these were made by
                                consecrated hands. Let us give a universal blessing, as those who are shoe-makers, must
                                make the shoes,those who are weavers must weave the cloth, while those who are sowers
                                and reapers must continue faithful in their duty. Let the dentist be a dentist if that
                                is his mission, and we will wish him eminent success. Those who work as refiners of
                                sugar and syrup should know and understand their business as well as those who delve in
                                the earth for coal and oil, and all should be faithful in duty. The beautiful crockery
                                that we have, we certainly, could not make, but we can see that it is kept in the best
                                of order. Our consecrated property is used in obtaining and in protecting all these
                                things. If we are faithful in the duty into which we are called, God and his people will
                                bless us, and our souls and our bodies will be correspondingly rewarded. How often we
                                sing,"I would be a blessing while I tarry here below;" and let us spend our time in
                                doing all the good we can; for God is good, and through Him and his order comes our
                                salvation. "With his loving hand to guide, let the clouds above us roll, and the billows
                                in their fury dash around us,we can brave the wildest storms with his glory in our
                                souls,we can sing amidst the tempest, Praise the Lord." Sarah Collins.</p></div3><pb n="261" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station, Ct.</head><p TEIform="p">Oct. 1895. "Let us be happy while we can, For life is but a little span." Mental,
                                physical and spiritual activity is the source of happiness. We should fill the hours
                                with some noble object, for they seem to fly as if on the wings of the wind. Let us
                                discipline ourselves to take what each moment brings of duty or of privilege. Let us
                                perform the duty of the hour now passing, for if we grasp well the little fragment of
                                time present, and perform the duty that this hour brings, we shall do that which will
                                please God and perfect our own character. Duty is the watch-word. The secret of success
                                in the self-denying life is to be patient, persevering and untiring. Each day we are
                                rearing for ourselves a structure no one else can lay claim to, our individual
                                character. What is the influence of that character on those around us? This is the
                                question each on should often ask of himself as the days flit by. "The largest loaves of
                                bread baked in the world are those of France and Italy. The bread in Italy is baked in
                                loaves two and three feet long, while in France the loaves are made in the shape of very
                                long rolls four and five feet long and in many cases even six feet." "Eighty-two million
                                acres of corn in this country this year; the largest breadth ever planted." ******* Hens
                                will not lay in the winter unless they finish moulting before December. Milk, meat and
                                bone are the best egg making material. Daniel Orcutt. South Family. Oct. 1895. We can
                                but feel deeply interested in our Manifesto and its valuable teachings, embracing so
                                much truth; and we gladly offer the few items of interest we may for those who read it.
                                The blessings from our heavenly Parents' hand are abundant, and as we look over the
                                works of creation we may continually stop to admire the beauty and system which
                                indicates the benevolence which we can not fail to understand. The weather the past
                                month has been unusually pleasant, with but little rain or wind to interfere with the
                                work on the new green-house which is nearly completed and will be put in operation as
                                soon as finished. The fall work has been prospered and the potato yield is very good.
                                Apples are harvested and quite abundant. The late sweet corn is excellent, producing a
                                good supply for the table, which is a new feature at this late date with us. Ploughing
                                is going on and everything goes forward prosperously. Two new houses for hens and
                                chickens are built and one repaired. Thrashing of oats also finished. So the diligent
                                hand maketh rich, and overcomes all obstacles; and "Sufficient unto the day shall thy
                                strength be." Maria Witham.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harvard, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Harvard, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">Oct. 1895. "The harvest is past, and the summer is ended," and all are saved who work in
                                faith to that end. Nature has donned her gayest attire, a prelude to her long sleep
                                beneath her beautiful white pall, an emblem of purity. We also are making preparations
                                for the long inclement season by ploughing, pruning and harvesting roots and winter
                                vegetables. About 35 tons of ensilage are nicely packed in the silo; 300 bushels of corn
                                and 30 bu. of beans are garnered in good order. While gathered in our comfortable homes,
                                enjoying the fruits of our labors, it would be well to remember the poor who are not so
                                bountifully blest. Marola M. Hullurd.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Alfred, Maine" TEIform="index"/>-Alfred., Me.</head><p TEIform="p">Oct. 1895. The chilly mornings and evenings remind us that summer is pa&gt;t and another
                                winter is close at hand. The first killing <pb n="262" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 262 THE MANIFESTO.
                                frost did n&gt;&gt;t reach us until the 8th inst. ;i fortnight later than last year. As was
                                expected, our silos were lilled full, and more than full, of the best ensilage we evej:
                                had. Elder John says it is superior to the Canterbury seed and grows considerably taller
                                although that was excellent. It had as many, or more ears^ which by the by, goes into
                                the silos as our cows would "strike" if cheated out of the corn. Two years ago less than
                                a quart of seed was sent from Washington and from that was raised five and one half bu.
                                last year? furnishing seed for this year. It is called "Improved Learning." The Brethren
                                are gathering the few apples left us. They report the quality poor and no more than a
                                tenth of last year's crop. Still we have every cause to be thankful. Our blessings are
                                innumerable both temporal and spiritual. The body must have food, clothing and shelter:
                                this is necessary and proper, but our greatest anxiety and care is for our spiritual
                                welfare. The spirit must be fed and unless we are laying up heavenly treasures we shall
                                surely famish and die,spiritually. Fannie Cttxey. [Notes taken from a letter written by
                                the friends in Florida to a Brother in N. H. Ed.] Narcoossee, Fla. Aug. 1805. Dear
                                Brother:Once a month I read with great interest the "Home Notes" from gospel friends,
                                and none interest me more, than those from the old Granite state. It calls to mind the
                                delightful season that I spent with you almost three years ago, at the time of your "One
                                Hundredth Anniversary" of the Community at Enfield. But I am now at a great distance
                                from you, and may be you have learned something about us. We are situated quite as well
                                as could be expected for the time we have been in our new home. I am now sitting in our
                                little cabin, in an upper south west room and looking at the beautiful li! tie lake, not
                                far distant. It may not be as large as your lovely Mascoma, but it lies so quietly,not a
                                ripple to mar its beauty, while the sunshine makes it almost a mirror. When we grow
                                wear/ of extracting the roots of the old palmetto, we take a sail upon the lake an*l
                                secure a small quantity of fish for our table. By this you will see that we are not
                                fully committed to the vegetarian order, but still cling to some things that belong down
                                in old Egypt. (What a pity. Ed.) Our vegetable garden will be ready fcr planting in
                                Oct., and this we call our winter crop. In Feb. and March we shall be ready to plant
                                again for a summer crop. In this you will see the advantage we have over those who live
                                in a more northern climate. We have also set out 1000 very nice pine apple plants. One
                                hundred banana plants, together with peaches, plums, persimmons, oranges and guavas.
                                (May the dear Lord bless every plant. Ed.) Elder Joseph and other dear friends are
                                praying for our success in our new home, and we are no less anxious for its peace and
                                prosperity. We ask a remembrance in your prayers, and of all our dear gospel friends.
                                Andrew Barrett.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Oct. 1895. To everything in nature's vast field of materiality, man has given a name.
                                Thus distinguishable are the different species of the mineral, vegetable and animal
                                world. Not so with the understanding of the elements governing human life, for minds,
                                like temperaments, differ; consequently, ideas of Christianity, science and morality are
                                as varied as the colors of the floral kingdom that dot the universe. The important work
                                of man is first to know himself and then to "study the creation of souls." And will not
                                such a knowledge help us in our work of human reformation? Should not the Christ church
                                be as broad and <pb n="263" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 263 generous in sentiment as the
                                noble spirited philanthropist? Surely, for its functions are love and service toward
                                huraaniyThe month of September gave us another delightful season of inter-Society
                                communion in the presence of six Sisters, of the Church family at Canterbury, N. H. We
                                esteem such seasons of enduring worth to our souls. Preserving of fruits for winter
                                consumption is an active industry. Our annual supply of fifty gross of Shaker Anodyne
                                has been filled, and fifteen hundredweight of lovage root prepared for market. The
                                filling of an order for twenty-four doz. sweaters are now making much work for busy
                                hands. Thus we toil on realizing that as true as the silver pencilings of the lightning
                                purify the atmosphere, so does the law of cause and effect, yield to each soul its
                                respective portion of good or ill as sowu in daily life. If as a walled motto we keep
                                before us the incentive prompter, "Love thy neigh. bor, in honor preferring one
                                another", we become in truth joined to the Christ element which furthers the cause of
                                holiness* and glorifies life. Our herdsmau, Br. Thomas Steadman, has two silos of some
                                thirty tons each, and these have been filled with the best of ensilage. The corn
                                averaged some twelve ft. in height, and both rooms were filled from about two and one
                                half acres. An excellent crop of potatoes has furnished uswith seven hundred and fifty
                                bushels. George H. Baxter.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Downs, Caroline" TEIform="index"/>To the Memory of our Sister,
                            Caroline Downs.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bartlett, Abbie F." TEIform="persName"/>By Abbie F. Bartlett.</byline><p TEIform="p">There's a bright, bright star, In the heavens above, That alone is shining for you, Beyond is
                            a pearly harvest, A harvest for the good and true. Oh faithful Mother in Zion, That star is
                            your beautiful life, Adherence to truth and to principles pure, Un-wavering ever in strife.
                            So firm thy purpose to walk in the right, ISTo weakness nor turning is there; I know thy
                            victories oft have been gained, Through deep tribulation and prayer. And even at the first,
                            opposition we meet, In the path our Savior trod; And the fiercest strife in our earthly
                            life, Is met on our way toward God. Oh beautiful spirit, thou hast shown to us What a
                            Mother's love cun do; [There," We need not wait till we meet "Over The Christian life to
                            pursue. Thou hast strewn thy blessings everywhere, They have sunk in the hearts you love;
                            May it guide and cheer their youthful lives Till you meet in the home above. Oh sweet
                            affection that rests with us, Though our lives be long or brief; [home, At last the death
                            Angel has gathered thee As a ripe and golden sheaf. Farewell dear one to your angel hone,
                            Where nothing can blight or mar; But leave Oh Mother, just leave for us, "The Beautiful
                            Gates Ajar." Shakers, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary.</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cows that are fed upon hot slops..." TEIform="index"/>Cows that are fed upon hot slops...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Cows that are fed upon hot slops, in our cities, lose their teeth, as do human beings who
                                use much hot food.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Shrew, Joel" TEIform="persName"/>Joel Shrew, M. D.</byline></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is proved by bills of mortality..." TEIform="index"/>It is proved by bills of mortality...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">It is proved by bills of mortality, that half who are born die under ten years of age.
                                Half of mankind are said to die of fevers of one kind or another. Are fevers natural?</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Alcott" TEIform="persName"/>Dr. Alcott.</byline></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Do you know what causes round shoulders..." TEIform="index"/>Do you know what causes round shoulders...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Do you know what causes round shoulders, particularly in the young? Much depends, no
                                doubt, on sitting a long time, from day to day, in a bad position. God <pb n="264" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 264 THE MANIFESTO. has kindly given to each of us a pair of shoulder
                                braces, 1 mean of course, the collar bones. Naturally we need no artificials of this
                                sort, though many use them. Nature's own are about six inches long in an adult. In
                                children and youth both ends of each of these bones are soft. It is not till we come to
                                maturity that these are completely ossified or changed to bone. If while we are young,
                                we sit a great portion of our time with the shoulders thrown forward too far, we
                                compress the soft cartilaginous ends of these bones and the cartilages gradually yield
                                and are absorbed, as it is called, so that the braces become too short, and the
                                shoulders remain too far forward. Thus we are made round shouldered.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Alcott" TEIform="persName"/>Dr. Alcott.</byline></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tea, coffee and tobacco" TEIform="index"/>TEA, COFFEE AND TOBACCO.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Tne eminent Dr. Bock, of Leipsic, writes as follows respecting the influence
                                        of tea and coffee upon the character: "The nervousness and peevishness of our
                                        times are chiefly attributable to tea and coffee; the digestive organs of tea
                                        and coffee drinkers are in a state of chronic derangement, which reacts on the
                                        brain, producing fretful and lachrymose moods. Fine ladies addicted to strong
                                        coffee have a characteristic temper, which I might describe as a mania for
                                        acting the persecuted saint,The snappish, petulent temper of the Chinese can
                                        certainly be ascribed to their immoderate fondness for tea." Although Wood gives
                                        it as his opinion that chewing is the worst form of using tobacco, yet Dr. Geo.
                                        P. Hall says in the International Medical Magazine that the use of cigarettes is
                                        certainly the most objectionable. He says the effects of tobacco when past the
                                        physical limit are very wide and far reaching, and may fall in some degree on
                                        any one or more of the nerves or nerve centers of sensation. Dr Hall then
                                        relates four cases of tobacco omblyopia as proof of the serious effect of this
                                        drug on the eyes. He quotes Bosworth as stating that tobacco is not sim ply a
                                        cardiac poison, it is also an arterial poison. Its ill effects are shown in
                                        cerebro-spinal irritations, headaches, vomiting, morning fatigue, impairment of
                                        memory, physical irritation, inaptitude for work, and even transitory aphasia.
                                        Mackintoshes and Rubber Clothing large commissions can be earned by retailing to
                                        users. Samples free. Manufacturer, P. O. 1371 New York.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Temple of Health" TEIform="index"/>.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Boy who laughed at other people" TEIform="index"/>A BOY WHO LAUGHED AT OTHER PEOPLE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ashton, Leon J." TEIform="persName"/>By Leon J. Ashton.</byline><p TEIform="p">(14 years old.) Charlie was the son of a poor farmer. One day Charlie's father had to go to
                            the city and he told Charlie to pick apples. Charlie said to himself:"To-day I will have
                            some fun." So after breakfast he went out with his ladder and had just begun to pick when an
                            old man came along: his hair was white and one of his arms was gone. "Ha ha," laughed
                            Charlie, "I will throw an apple at him." He saw a nice one a little way from his ladder and
                            he put out his hand to get it but just then a gust of wind blew, and poor Charlie was blown
                            off. He was picked up as dead. The doctor came and found that his right arm was broken;
                            Charlie was in bed for a month, but it was a great lesson to him. He is a man now but he has
                            never laughed at the aged and infirm since. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>EXCHANGES.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Church monitor" TEIform="index"/>The Church Monitor
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Church Monitor is a four page monthly. Edited by G. T. Welcome, of Union Mills, Ind.
                                Its doctrinal points are obscure, but as it presents the paper"Our Hope and Life in
                                Christ" as the best family paper published in the west, we conclude The Monitor must be
                                a Second Advent paper. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="American tramp" TEIform="index"/>The American Tramp
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The American Tramp is a National Weekly and published in the
                                interest of humanity and common good of all. Edited by W. B. Emerson of Atlantic, Iowa.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Salvator scientist" TEIform="index"/>Salvator Scientist
                            </head><p TEIform="p">
                                Salvator Scientist, is an Evangel of Koreshanity. Edited by TJ. G. Morrow of Alleghany,
                                Pa.</p></div3></div2><pb n="265" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In memoriam sister Caroline Downs" TEIform="index"/>In Memoriam Sister Caroline Downs.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Beaver, Orren" TEIform="persName"/>By Orren Beaver.</byline><p TEIform="p">Another brave spirit has laid aside the garments of mortality to join the ranks of the pure
                            in heart. Our Sister has spent a long life of devoted toil and consecration, to sustain the
                            cause she loved so well. The many cheerful testimonies of loving friends in whose hearts her
                            bright example will ever remain enshrined will attest her true worth far more than the
                            costliest monument. For more than ninety-one years she had resided in our beautiful valley
                            home, giving her whole being to the cause without reserve. Many years of her early life were
                            spent at the North family and in the order of Elders. Sister Caroline entered the work with
                            full purpose of heart, bravely to endure all crosses she might meet on the way. How well she
                            kept those early vows is best known to those who had the pleasure of an acquaintance with
                            her gentle, lovicg ^piiit and in tie pnhig of wise counsel to those who were young in the
                            faith ministering to the sick and needy, charitable in all her dealings, sowing the seeds of
                            purity and Christian virtue in all her intercourse with others. She was truly a mother in
                            Israel. Angel choirs will chant the glad refr.tin through the shining corridors of heaven;
                            Welcome, thrica welcome, to thy future home above. Shakers, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Downs, Caroline" TEIform="index"/>Caroline Downs
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Caroline Downs, at Shakers, N. Y. Aug. 4, 1895. Age 92 years and 15 days. O B. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Patterson, Clarissa" TEIform="index"/>Clarissa
                                Patterson
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Clarissa
                                Patterson, at Union Village, O. Sept. 27, 1895. Age 94 years, 0 mo. and 15 days. She has
                                lived among Believers ninety years. She has been truly faithful and zealous to maintain
                                the Gospel by words and by works. She occupied almost every position of care and burden
                                in the Society with great honor and success and always with the most scrupulous regard
                                to justice, uprightness and sincerity. She has left in the family a sweet savor of good
                                deeds, which will long remain to bless those who may choose to follow in her footsteps,
                                righteousness and true holiness. O. C. H. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Battles, Albert J." TEIform="index"/>Elder Albert J. Battles
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Elder Albert J. Battles, at West Pittsfield,
                                Mass. Oct. 2, 1895. Age 84 years, 11 mo. and 12 days. Elder Albert has spent his life
                                from early childhood among Believers. Formerly he resided at Tyrinrham, Mass., but when
                                the members of that Society, moved to the other Societies in the same Bishopric, he went
                                to live at Enfield, Conn. After the death of Elder Thomas Damon in 18S0 he was chosen to
                                fill the place of first in the Ministerial Order at Hancock, Mass., and Enfield, Conn.,
                                where he remained till June 18, 1893. At tl is time the Order of Ministry at Hancock,
                                Mass., and Enfield, C'nn., was dissolved, and the tw &gt; Societies were taken under the
                                immediate charge of the Ministry of Mt. Lebanon. Since that time Elder Albert has lived
                                at Hancock in the brick house, with the Church family, a beloved member, father, brother
                                and friend. A good man who has kept his Covenant and was prepared to praise the Lord
                                with his whole heart, he has gone to receive his reward. Peace to his memory now and
                                forever. I. K. L. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="March, Harriet" TEIform="index"/>Harriet March
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Harriet March, fit East Canterbury, N. H. Oct. 18, 1895. Age 68 years
                                2 mo. and 7 days.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prouty, Abagail" TEIform="index"/>Abagail Prouty
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Abagail Prouty, at Shirley, Mass. Oct. 18, 1895. Age 77 years 2 mo.
                                Lived in the Society since early childhood and has been a faithful worker in places of
                                trust for many years. J. W.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="All little aims..." TEIform="index"/>All little aims...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">All little aims slip from me as I reach my yearning soul toward the Infinite.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wilcox, Ella Wheeler" TEIform="persName"/>Ella Wheeler Wilcox,</byline></div2><pb n="266" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Successward; a young man's book for young men" TEIform="index"/>
                                Successward; A Young Man's Book lor Young Men
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Edward Bok, the editor of The Ladies' Home Journal, has written a book for young men
                                Oilieu "Successward; A Young Man's Book lor Young Men," which the Reyells will pub lish
                                in a fortnight. The book aims to cover all the important phases of a young man's life:
                                his business lite, social life, his amusements, religious lift1, (tress, his attitude
                                toward women ami the question of his marriage. This is Mr. Bok's first book. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pleasant hours for boys and girls" TEIform="index"/>
                                Pleasant Hours for Boys and Girls
                            </head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Word and works" TEIform="index"/>
                                Word and Works
                            </head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Popular monthly" TEIform="index"/>
                                Popular Monthly
                            </head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bible triumphant" TEIform="index"/>
                                The Bible Triumphant
                            </head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">A new
                                monthly illustrated magazine for young people has just been started by Frank Leslie's
                                Publishing House. It is called FKANk Leslie's Pleasant Houks ior Boys and Girls, ami is
                                in every way equal to the best publications of its kind, although the price is but 10
                                cents. The first number (October) contains the opening chapters of a serial story for
                                boys by Edward S. Ellis, and one for girls by Jeannette H. Walworth, There are short
                                stories by Oliver Optic and Rebecca HardingDavis; a football story by Henry E. Haydock;
                                bicycle stories by Max I. Harvey and A. L. Millet; an article giving "Hints on
                                Trapping," by F. L. Oswald; a paper telling how to turn a heap of rubbish into pretty
                                ornaments, by Adele Beard; several illustrated poems and practical descriptions of novel
                                tricks, games and puzzles. The editor of the new magazine is Fiank Lee Farnell, who has
                                been connected with Fraak Leslie's Publishing House for a number of years, and who
                                thoroughly understands what will please and interest the young people. HICK'S GREAT
                                WORKS. Rev. Irl R. Hicks, the celebrated storm prophet, of St. Louis, is now a household
                                name in nearly every home in America. His wonderful Almanac predicts the weather for a
                                year ahead more correctly and accurately than any other publication or any other system.
                                The testimony of a large number of careful observers is that 99 per cent of Hicks'
                                predictions are fulfilled to the letter. Mis series of annual Almanacs are now well anil
                                favorably known in all parts of this country and in foreign lands. The new Almanac for
                                18H6 is the most practical ami instructive as well as the prettiest of this splendid
                                series. It contains 100 pages, printed on fine book paper, with covers elegantly printed
                                in colors. The matter, although scientific, is written in popular style, there being
                                nothing difficult to understand about it. It is also finely illustrated. Don't confound
                                this with some patent medicine pamphlet. It is nothing of the kind, but is a line book,
                                which sells at all news stands for '25c. This fine Almanac is given as a premium to
                                every yearly subscription to the Rev. Irl R. Hick's well-known and deservedly popular
                                paper, Wokd and Works. This unique journal is a peerless educator of the masses, and is
                                fast becoming a household guardian and necessity in the homes of America. Those who want
                                to keep up with the advanced thought of the age, in science, religion and all social,
                                commercial, intellectual and domestic subjects, should subscribe for Word and Works.
                                Subscription only $1.00 a year. You can send for both direct to Wort, and Works
                                Publishing Co., St. Louis, Mo Single copies of Word and Works, 10 cents. The Cotton
                                States and International Expo- -ition nt Atlanta, which takes rank among .he most
                                brilliant lairs ever organized on the \ meiican Continent, conies in for conspicuous
                                attention, both pictorial and liturary, in the November number of Frank Leslies Popular
                                Monthly. The lending article on this subject i from the authoritative pen of Walter G. i
                                ooper, the energetic chief of the Department of Publicity and Promotion. James L. Ford,
                                the now celebrated author of 'The Literary Shop" and "Hypnotic Tales," xmtributes a
                                delicious example of his satiri3al humor in a paper upon "Our Exotic Nobiltjs" which is
                                charmingly illustrated by Warren B. Davis. Mrs. Leicester-Addis discusses the traditions
                                and customs of Allhalltide. Some interesting glimpses of the "Immortals" of the French
                                Academy are given in a gossipy paper, accompanied by the latest portraits of such
                                contemporaneous celebreties as Paul Bourget, Pierre Loti, Francois Coppee, Dumas,
                                ShiyIou, Jules Claretie, Jules Lemaitre, Brunetiere and others. Other illustrated
                                articles of special interest are: "The Suburban Riding and Driving Club of New York;"
                                "The Scenic Panorama of Sew York State," and The Boomerang." Among the notable short
                                stories is "The Railway Signal," by the famous Russian writer, Garshine. The
                                frontispiece is an admirable reproduction in water colors of a characteristic "New
                                England Thanksgiving Dinner. Altogether, the improved Frank Leslie's Popular Monthly is
                                a brilliant success. The Bible Triumphant. This is a beautiful book in cloth binding of
                                one hundred and sixty pages. The author Mrs. H. V. Heed is a Hebrew and Gieek scholar,
                                and her study of the Bible has enabled her to refute no less than twelve dozen skeptical
                                arguments. How fully she may have carried this to a successful issue, must be determined
                                by those who follow her carefully through this extended list of triumphant solutions.
                                The work is prefaced with words of wisdom from the pen of that able advocate Br. H. L.
                                Hastings, and this every one will be interested to read. The same book also contains
                                nearly fifty pages under the head of "Infidel Testimony concerning the Truth of the
                                Bible." This exhibition in parallel columns of ancient inscriptions with quotations from
                                the Scriptures form a very interesting feature of the work, and may be studied with
                                immense profit by those who are anxious to be well informed on the subject. The book is
                                nicely and substantially bound, and is well worthy a place in any Library. Published by
                                H. L. Hastings, 47 Cornhill, Boston, Mass.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How calm the mind..." TEIform="index"/>How calm the mind...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"How calm the mind, how composed the affections, how serene the countenance, how melodious
                            the voice, how sweet the sleep, how contentful the whole life is of him that neither
                            deviseth mischief against others nor suspects any to be contrived against himself! And,
                            contrariwise, how ungrateful and loathsome a thing it is to abide in a state of enmity,
                            wrath, dissension, having the thought distracted with solicitous care, anxious suspicion,
                            and envious regret!''</p></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p27"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
THE   CLIMAX.
This  is an American   Stem-windeP,   up to date.    It represents  the  most important step taken in watch evolution in many  years.    It  describes  a line beyond
which nothing radical will pass for years, not only in the matter of price, but quality
Two styles.   Gilt and nickel,   Snap  Tbaclc, BeveJ crystal,
Stem Set.   Fully timed and regulated.
For $2.00 we will  send the Watch, an(i ^so & copy of The Manifesto for one
year, to any address in the U. S.          AddressThe   Manifesto.
EAST    CANTERBURY,    N. H.
AUTHORIZED RULES
THE   SHAKER   COMMUNITY,
The religious basis of the Order must
be a foundation resting on the principle of
righteousness, which principle is God.
This should rule the life of the  individ
ual for the protection of his own soul, for
the peace of the family and as an evidence
of his upright standing before the world.
Price, 10 cts.
BRIEF EXPOSITION
OF  THE
Principles and Regulations
of the
SOCIETY   OF   BELIEVERS.
Price, 10 cts.
"INTERPRETING PROPHECY"
AND   THE
"Appearing of Christ,"
is the title of a neat little pamphlet of
some forty pages, just sent out by A. G.
Hollister of Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.
The many at the present time who are
interested in the fulfillment of prophecy
and in its mathematical calculation, will
find themselves by the side of the good
old prophet Daniel, and with him illus
trating the Coming of Christ so clearly
that no occasion can arise for the least
doubt.                             Price, 10 cts.
<pb n="" id="p28"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure.
A cre.-im of tartar baking powder.
Highest of all in leavening strength.
Latest United States Government
Food report.
Eoyal Baking Powder Oo.
106 Wall St., N. Y.
POUR
By Pressing the Lid.
Tea and Coffee Pots that pour by tho lid w ithout lifting or tipping.     Simple beyond belief.
Practical and artistic.   Send for pamphlet.
THE ASBURY=PAINE MFG. CO., Phlla., Pa.
This is a good thingEd.
i American Bee Journal,
(Established 1861.)
IS Oldest, Largest, Best,
Cheapest and the Only
weekly Bee-Paper in all
America.  32 pages, 81.00
a year.   Send for Free Sample.
$1.00 BEE-BOOK FREE
w. W. YORK & CO., 199 Randolph St., Chicago, 111.
A Visit to the
of EAST CANTERBURY,   N. H.
 . CHANDIiER.lJ. S 3T
Liberally Illustrated with half tone
pictures of persons and places.
The Village of EAST CANTERBURY
is situated in one of the lovliest spots of
New Hampshire, and is high enough to
overlook the surrounding country.
Price  15 cts.
 SUMMARY VIEW
 CHURCH,
OB
"United   Society    of    Believers"
It treats of the Bise and Progress of the
Society, together with the general Principles of the Faith and Testimony.
Price 50 cts.
OF  THE
A
MILLENNIAL.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>