<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0108" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Mount Lebanon Bishopric</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Albany, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">1</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">8</biblScope><date value="18710801" TEIform="date">August 1871</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">57-64</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="1" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="57" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="8" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">I WILL SHAKE ALL NATIONS, AND THE BESIRK OF ALL NATIONS SHALL COME; AND I WILL FILL THIS HOUSE
                        WITH GLORY, SAITH THE LORD." Published Monthly, by, and under tfcfl direction of the Mt, Lebanon
                        Bishopric. Vol. L SHAKERS, ALBANY GO., N. Y. AUGUST, 1871. No. 8,</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian success" TEIform="index"/>Christian Success</head><p TEIform="p">Christ's mission to the world was the salvation of souls—to save sculs from the transgression
                            of God's laws, and consequently from the punishment of sin. The mission is a success.
                            Whoever looks to Christianity for salvation from the punishment of sin, while living in sin,
                            mistakes the mission of the Christ spirit, and is doomed either to a change of opinion and
                            life, or to the sorest disappointment,— Whoso cemmits €m, does not experience Christian
                            success. We believe "Christ to have appeared, just as we firmly believe in the existence of
                            gold; but until we experience the value of gold, by real possession and the benefits of its
                            exchange, of how much worth is our belief? Until we experience the salvation from the
                            commission of sin, which Christ's mission promised, of what avail is Christianity to us? "
                            He shall save his people from their sins," by teaching a life that is free from sin. Christ
                            teaches freedom from war—a Christian peace. Christians never did, never can fight.
                            Christians are peacemakers, and realize that there never was a Christian cause worth
                            fighting for with weapons that kill the body or hurt the soul! Thh Christianity will exclude
                            the majority of professing Christians. Christ taught a a virgin life, pure and chaste as the
                            angels. Jesus practiced virginity; so did his immediate disciples ; so practice all who
                            attain to a Christian success. Paul lived like the author of Christianity, but permitted a
                            license to the heathen that finds no sanction in the life and teachings of Christ; whoso
                            indulges in any practice of life, heathen to Christianity, can lay no claim to Christian
                            success. The Christ spirit organized the most beautiful church-pattern among the primitive
                            Christians. To this, genuine Christians gathered, gave up their selfish individualities, and
                            laid down at the apostles' feet their wealth and their poverty, their burdens and their
                            indifferences, and with these the apostles built up a successful Christian Church. The
                            wealthy became less wealthy in worldly goods; the poor were elevated by the condescension of
                            the rich; all enjoyed a comfortable equality as brethren and sisters. Whoso would attach to
                            this church any mutual or social relations, not comprehended by the terms brethren and
                            sisters in Christ, aims at the prostitution of the true church into a community of ill-fame.
                            We find human nature, undisciplined by the Christ spirit, opposed to the demands of
                            Christianity. However loud its professions of love for Christ, it prefers, that spirit would
                            not press too closely the subject of self-denial. Under the Christian name it prefers to
                            live worse than the Jews, and whoever would restrict it is made the object of persecution
                            and crucifixion. It wants, and will have, the pleasures of the flesh, of private property
                            and war, unless converted to the Christ life. It marries and then transcends, to beastly
                            extent, the boundaries of Jewish discipline, screening itself behind the name of Christ from
                            the mortifying penances and purifications that Jewish laws demanded. Christ was the end of
                            the law of generation and of the u unfruitful works of darkness]" and who would achieve
                            success in a Christian life must discontinue these, seeking an excuse and refuge in Christ!
                            "If this is Christianity," cries the majority of professing Christians, " then we. prefer
                            not to be Christians." Regardless of their preferences, the truth stands alto relievo, and
                            will not down at the bidding of popular desires. Refusing the discipline of the law, all cut
                            themselves off from the enjoyment of its advantages ; and by practicing that which the life
                            of Christ will not sanction, but condemns, such cannot have the gospel, nor attain to a
                            genuine Christian profession. " The Shakers," says a noted writer, " have certainly struck
                            at the root of all evil; but, in our opinion, they have struck a little too deeply." The
                            Shakers, we say, experience genuine Christian success, when obedient to the voice of their
                            principles, and this demands our striking at the root of evil very much deeper than our
                            eotemporaries have; yet none too deeply to experience salvation from the ills our
                            eotemporaries suffer. We know what it is to experience Christian success— salvation from
                            sin. Our success has not been in the congregation of vast numbers; never will be; at least
                            we do not look for this. There has been, as may occur again and again, a falling away from
                            the purity of our principles, which inevitably degrades the individualities so falling—as "
                            the stars of heaven falling to earth ;" but this in no manner affects our Christian success.
                            Our numbers are not so large, as in periods that are past; we fearlessly admit this fact;
                            but our principles are firmer than ever, in our faithful hearts, and in the estimation of
                            'the truly religious minds of the day. We mean to maintain these principles inviolate, while
                            living in happy anticipation of the approach of a blessed season, when mankind will become
                            convicted of the need of Christian success, and gather to the principles that alone can
                            satisfy the demand. " For the love of the primitive Christians," says one who is not far
                            from the kingdom of heaven, " we need not expect to find in the churches of Brooklyn nor in
                            surrounding cities; but in a community life, where so much selfdenial is in exercise, that
                            but few individuals will be willing to submit to its demands." *</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian communism" TEIform="index"/>Christian Communism</head><p TEIform="p">Is nothing more nor less than li the Kingdom of Heaven," of which so much has been pro-
                            phesied. And that kingdom is described by the simile of a net, which fishermen had cast into
                            the sea, and drawn, filled with (not all good fish that would answer the expectation of the
                            fishermen, but) a promiscuous multitude of such as the sea contains. Well trained, ex-
                            perienced fishermen know where to go, and in what waters to ply their vocation, to secure
                            the greatest proportion of the fish they want, and the fewest and least dangerous of those
                            which are of no profit. And as often as the net is cast, follows the selecting, separating
                            process, which returns back into the sea the notwanted, undesirable result of the haul. The
                            best of fish are unfit for use until death has occurred, and a cleansing process has been
                            passed through, after which, their former life in the ocean is an impossibility ; they are
                            on land, and landsmen appropriate and use them up. They at least will never again multiply,
                            nor replenish the waste waters of the great sea, in which they had their origin, and wherein
                            they experienced their former life. Signs of life in the fish, upon a supper table, would be
                            no more horrible and disgusting to the invited guests, than are manifestations of <pb n="58" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 58 THE SHAKER generative life in young, or old men and women in a Christian
                            Community. Whilst, " blessed are the pure in heart who therein see God." Much as the
                            moreprogressed minds of the world desire community life, having failed to actualize it in
                            severity-sis attempts during the last fifty years (see Noyea), there is "no form or
                            comeliness in a Christian Community that they should desire ft." It excludes and takes the
                            life of the natural, procreative man and woman, which they find in 1 the waters, or sea,
                            where the whore sitteth, and which are peoples, and multitudes, and nations and
                            tongues,"—all the human inhabitants of this earth being by the Spirit included under one
                            gigantic figure. There is latent in the soul of every man and woman a spiritual or angel man
                            or woman. Like Paul, the whole race, as a race, have been pressing on, " if by any means
                            they might attain to the Resurrection" from the " dead sea" of generation; and ever and anon
                            this spiritual yearning has cropped out a Reformer, a Philosopher, a Prophet or Prophetess,
                            with their dream of a "good time coming" in the distant future, their felicitous Arcadia, or
                            unattainable Utopia, or their vision of a Millenium; indistinct and undefined glimpses of a
                            spiritual state and life on this earth—the Resurrection Order as an answer to the
                            God-inspired prayer of "Thy kingdom come," wherein their daily bread and water would " be
                            sure," without the daily drudgery and degradation to which the great mass of humanity are
                            subject, and only to be escaped by self-denial in the new life to be attained in " Christian
                            Communities," as schools, which are educating immortal souls for a life that is eternal.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Labor is worship" TEIform="index"/>Labor is Worship</head><p TEIform="p">Pakt First. It is supposed by many who seem to be superficial readers of the New Testament,
                            that the founders of the Order introduced hand labor as something new into the Christian
                            Church as a principle of duty for all. Others believe that we carry out rigidly for worldly
                            gain, members being subjects of toil and leaders standing exempt. We will endeavor to show
                            that in diligence we strictly follow the example of Jesus, the Apostles and the Primitive
                            Church, who established the principle, that work is Christian worship. The argument is to be
                            scriptural and nothing more. The Parents of Jesus were laboring Jews. When he was entering
                            the field of labor as an inspired teacher, the inquiry was raised by those who heard him, "
                            Is not this the carpenter's son ? " &amp;c. Jesus required by law to learn a trade.
                            Under the statute of Moses, tradition says, every father rich, or poor, was required to see
                            that his sons learned a trade. After the affair with the doctors at the temple, " He came to
                            Nazareth and was subject to his parents," til thirty years of age; in which time Joseph evi
                            dently instructed Jesus in his own occupation for when he began to preach they inquired "Is
                            not this the carpenter?" &amp;c. TTie habitation of Jesus. The day after John baptized
                            him, he was jassing, and the Baptist exclaimed: " Behold the Lamb of God!" &amp;c.
                            Again, the next day he stood with two of his disciples, and calling their attention to him,
                            uttered the same sentiment, and the two followed him. He turned and asked " What seek ye ? "
                            They isked, "Where dwellest thou?" He answered, " Come and see." They obeyed and bl-lowed
                            him and abode with him that day. Others were invited to his dwelling, who jecame his
                            disciples. Here evidently Nicodenus came to him by night. Now, by what means was this simple
                            home supplied with its daily needs ? This was the starting of the first Christian community;
                            the outgrowth from it was the calling of the twelve, the gathering at Pentecost, the Church,
                            at Jerusalem and ;hose among the Gentiles. So the latter Church started under Mother Ann. A
                            powerful inspiration attracted deeply religious inquirers to her; the outgrowths from this
                            are the present Churches in America. The Disciples when called were working men. Their
                            industries were fishing, gathering taxes and other labors. A Church that is to live by its
                            own industry should have such pioneers to start with. For the scriptures show positively
                            that this requirement was laid upon all the Christian ministers, even upon Paul, who was
                            brought up at the feet of Gamaliel the most learned of the Apostles. The first American
                            believers in this Order were out of just such society. All ordained Apostles required to
                            labor for their daily bread. After the crucifixion, Jesus appeared to them at the sea of
                            Gallilee while toiling at their nets. After they had advanced far into their min- istry,
                            Paul declared, " God hath set forth us the Apostles (he excepts none) a spectacle to the
                            world, angels and men. Even to this present hour we hunger, thirst, have no eertain dwelling
                            place, and labor, ivorking with our hands," &amp;c. He does not say that they chose this
                            condition, nor that povertydrove them to it, but that God (through Jesus) laid it upon them,
                            that as a pattern, they might be set forth a spectacle to be looked upon by the heavenly
                            orders, the Church and the world. The same life of honest toil was exacted of all ministers,
                            elders and people in gathering and starting the Church of Christ's Second Appearing, Mother
                            Ann setting the example, living up to her own motto at all times—" hands to work and hearts
                            to God." They required the same of their Churches. Paul held it as a principle and proved it
                            by his works, that he who opposed honest labor was an enemy to the Christian faith. He says,
                            "When we were among you, we commanded if any would not work neither should he eat. Neither
                            did we eat any man's bread for nought, but wrought with labor and travail night and day that
                            we might not be chargeable to any of you : not because we had not power, but to make
                            ourselves an example to you to follow us.' How could Paul preach down indolence and ease to
                            others, if he refused to labor himself ? They had affectionate brethren and sisters, quite
                            wealthy, which they could lean upon and could receive donations for support, but they prized
                            a Christ-like example above all this. Like their Master they never required of others what
                            they were unwilling to do themselves. Notice the reproof of Jesus to the Jewish Priesthood
                            against shirking the duties of life ;hey well understood. He said: " The Scribes and
                            Pharisees sit in Moses' seat; they bind leavy burdens upon men's shoulders, grievous to be
                            borne, which they will not move themselves with one of their fingers." Paul ai.d ;he twelve
                            had seen and heard this. Now would Jesus cry out against an evil which he oracticed himself?
                            From the time that this Church was established our leaders have taught members to follow
                            them as they followed the leaders of both dispensations of the gospel, in honest labor. Hand
                            labor introduced into the Gentile Churches. When Paul came to Corinth he was impressed to
                            tarry there, sow the seed of faith and reap a harvest of souls. It was not his first
                            business to seek out some place of ease in some metropolitan hotel, but true to his faith he
                            sought some humble workshop where he could go to work with his hands. " When Paul came to
                            Corinth he found a certain Jew named Aquila, with his wife Priscilla, and he came to them;
                            and because he was of the. same craft, he abode with them and worked, for by occupation they
                            were tent makers." Paul had now entered his field of labor right, and could pray for others;
                            he toiled on through the week, "and reasoned in the Synagogue every Sabbath day." " Being in
                            the way, the Lord blessed him and delivered him from persecution. He converted Crispus, the
                            chief ruler of the Synagogue, with all his house, and many of the Corinthians hearing,
                            believed." All came out true, "For he continued there a year and six months." By following
                            strictly the example of Jesus, Paul was clothed with great power to control and admonish his
                            followers. He found they were wealthy and worldy, sunk deeply in the sins of the Gentiles,
                            and he walked among them with great self-denial, charity and circumspection. When his labors
                            in the spirit became so extended that his own hands failed to supply his wants he said: "
                            When I was with you and wanted, I was chargeable to no man, for that which was lacking the
                            brethren from Macedonia supplied." Thus in times of need Ministers of Christ divided the
                            proceeds of their labor with each other. The first Believers in Shaker faith provided a home
                            to which others gathered: they preached to them the gospel, and united with them in toil and
                            labor, and imparted to them their substance. Gentile Churches follow the example of the
                            Church at Jerusalem in hand labor. When the Apostles established the Church at Jerusalem,
                            they followed strictly the teachings and example of Jesus, that when the gos<pb n="59" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE. 59 pel spread among the Gentiles, they could present to them his
                            true life and doctrines. In exhorting the Thessalonians to a strict Christian course, Paul
                            says: " Ye remember, breth- ren, our travail; we would not be chargeable to any of you. Ye
                            become the followers of the Churches, which in Judea are in Christ Jesus." Thus the Apostles
                            appeared among them as Christian teachers, toiling for their daily bread just as they did in
                            the Churches at Jerusalem, and these stood in the very life and testimony of Christ Jesus.
                            It has been so with the Shaker Church from the beginning. When their Missionaries have
                            planted other Churches, the same spirit of honest toil which exists in the Church at New
                            Lebanon has ever been required of all, as an important part of the Christian faith.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leonard, William" TEIform="persName"/>Wm. Leonard</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Progress" TEIform="index"/>Progress</head><p TEIform="p">With old and young, the questions often arise: What constitutes a state of blessedness ? What
                            character is the most acceptable to the Great Originator of human souls, and the most con-
                            ducive to the happiness of sentient beings endowed with intelligence, and possessing the
                            germs of an immortal life ? The Apostle Paul gave many wholesome instructions, some
                            commandments, and some permissions. His mission was to the people; and he strove to meet all
                            classes—the Jew under the law, and those who were without law; to the weak he adapted his
                            teachings, fed them with milk; for they could not digest the strong meat which he gave to
                            those who were more spiritually progressed; his object was to benefit all. Shall we be
                            willing to take our place with the weak, and hide beneath the permissions which the Apostle
                            gave to the Gentile Christians of his day, instead of girding ourselves about with every
                            truth, and making haste in the upward path of progression, though it may take us away from
                            every earthly idol ? Progress is stamped upon everything ; knowledge is constantly
                            increasing in things pertaining to the earth-life. If we possess an innate power to add to
                            our knowledge in natural science, why should there be a limit to spiritual growth and
                            development ? Why is it that so many give tacit assent to the stereotyped proprietor of the
                            pulpit, and unmistakable support to the style of architecture expressed in steeples? to the
                            artistically-stained glass through which to dimly light the Church ? indicating the status
                            of those who say, Lord, Lord, but whose soul language is, " Subdue the light; let it not
                            shine too vividly for the weak vision, and let the Word be tempered with scholastic
                            platitude, and fall on us as the snow-flake on the running water-stream, so as not to
                            interrupt our course in securing earthly emoluments and delight;" though, oft, deep tones
                            from each neighboring cemetery are heard, How short lived! how corruptible 2 But few minds,
                            comparatively, have been exercised upon the subject of Regeneration versus Perpetuity of the
                            Kace. The generative plane, when under the guidance of wisdom, and subject to the highest
                            reason, may be viewed as the rudimental, or natural, having in view its use—replenishing the
                            earth. But, as J. M. Peebles has said, " There should be a mount of ascension—a spiritual
                            birth to each brainorgan—a heavenly polarity—before physical death." //. W. Beecher says,
                            "It is better to be born right the first time, than to depend upon some spasmodic revival—an
                            occasional wave of spiritual life, for the better regulation of the being, feeble, and often
                            transient, in its descent." And, as the Swedenborgian, Dr. Giles, says, " Try to work
                            through the misty, shadowy veil of the flesh." Malthus, by mathematical and geometrical
                            conclusions, makes out, that "it is impossible for the earth always to contain and afford
                            subsistence to its inhabitants, if they so abnormally continue to increase." And many are
                            brought to look favorably, and even kindly on war, disease, infanticide, etc., as means by
                            which an ungodly race may continue to exist, and find room to come to, and go from the
                            surface of mother earth. A. J. Davis says " procreation is not compatible with
                            spirituality." From his high, intellectual stand-point, the progressive spirit would become
                            absorbed and incorporated with an element of light and knowledge wherein the animal or
                            procreative life could not exist; and he invites men and women to " come out of their little
                            enclosures of pigs, potatoes, progeny and pence, and take a flight to the mount or summit
                            wherefrom they could behold the harmony and beauty of God's creation, which in a lower
                            altitude can not be seen. The knowledge of this higher life will test the stamina of all
                            applicants for progress. Should this process prevail, the earth will cease to satisfy or
                            supply the spirits thereon. Doubtless, millions of years may roll by, ere this condition
                            will become universal; but, as progressionists, we should approximate thereto; for we are
                            destined to exist in another sphere; therefore, let that sphere be one of superior delights
                            and loves. Let us, from this exalted position, aim for the higher life, where the sphere is
                            more universal, and the element more genial; where we can behold the passing away of the
                            sublunary orb itself, which will cease to exist as a separate body in the planetary system
                            actually passing away ; attracted to and by stronger bodies, it will ultimately be ab-
                            sorbed and incorporated into another system, and in a way and manner not understood by the
                            orthodox theologian. Earth shall be no more! " " Science, by the aid of revelation from the
                            spirit spheres, has opened a more philosophical and peaceable way of disposing of and
                            settling this matter, than the old oft-repeated pitiless story of burning and annihilation;
                            thus exterminating mother earth and her inhabitants." " The spiritual aspirations, and soul
                            wants of the age, call for a broader, a more liberal view of Heaven; a more expansive and
                            profound idea of intelligences above and around us, and of their mission to the earth
                            sphere." Such are the thoughts of many; and we are happy to announce to them, that there is
                            a heavenly order established on earth—a second Pentecostal Church—where the character of
                            Jesus is not only admired, but imitated. As he was holy, harmless and undefiled, so are they
                            in the Second Christian Church who follow him in the regeneration. White-robed Angels are
                            again seen on the mountain of purity, and again is heard, in accents of love, " Come up
                            higher." Angelic beings, male and female, sound forth the heavenly invitation from the
                            immortal spheres, " Come all who will: the wine, milk and honey are free. Come and buy
                            unalloyed, pure gold without money and without price."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Knight, Jane D." TEIform="persName"/>Jane D. Knight</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Do good" TEIform="index"/>Do Good</head><p TEIform="p">This should be the aim of every human being—to make the world better for their having lived.
                            No one can be a reformer unless they first become reformed—made better. Jesus struggled to
                            make life principles effective in himself, rather than to proclaim new theo- ries. He never
                            urged the acceptance of his principles until, by a living illustration, he proved them
                            efficacious. With weighty truths in his possession, he yet was humble; accept- ing neither
                            the kingly crown, nor the purple robe. Baptized by the power of redemption, drinking deeply
                            at the springs of eternal life, he imparted the same to others. In lonely places he would
                            gather the afflicted —tell them of the heavenly joys of the Divine life. A few honest
                            fishermen heard his teachings, and made their lives conformably to them, gather- ing others
                            to the beautiful way of the cross. The "few" who laid the foundations of the Shaker Church
                            were equally zealous in disciplining their lives according to their honest convictions of
                            right. Under the most scorching testimony against pride, lust, war, etc., they stood firm.
                            They incurred the hatred and envy of those whom they sought to improve, while giving
                            expressions of the most Christian love—laying down a life of sinful pleasure in behalf of
                            the souls of their neighbors. They were poor, but willingly shared their all with sin-sick
                            souls, wherever met. They were rich in spiritual things, and from their abundance built the
                            structure that is a beacon to the afflicted of all nations, having come out and separated
                            themselves from the works of darkness into the glorious light and life of Christ—they
                            stripped themselves of any base disguise, showed their past deeds, and earnestly began a
                            life of true repentance, leaving off what they confessed as wrong. In struggling for their
                            salvation they used extreme measures to meet their cases. The heads of families would
                            sometimes, under the deepest conviction for their sins, and of their responsibility as
                            parents, call their children around them and impress upon them the necessity of a godly
                            life, hot by the relation of mythical stories of fire and brimstone, but, givingexpression
                            to their sorrow for their own missteps in life, warn their children to flee from the same
                            condemnation; and with such fervor were these communications made, that the stony hearts of
                            their children melted, and, as the baptized parents baptized their children into the newness
                            of life, society received a force of the. proper material for the maintenance of the true
                            gospel of Christ. May the same truths enter the hearts of many natural parents, while we all
                            sing the song*, "We Live to do Good."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bullard, Harriet" TEIform="persName"/>Harriet Bullard</byline></div2><pb n="60" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Biographical: testimony of John Farrington" TEIform="index"/>BIOGRAPHICAL. Testimony of John
                            Farrington</head><p TEIform="p">As vre have received the most authentic records of Jesus from the writings of his daily
                            companions, we would give evidence of Ann Lee's life and character from those who knew her
                            personally, and suffered with her in the promulgation of her unpopular faith. —En. In
                            consequence of an extraordinary revival of religion, which took place at New Lebanon in the
                            summer of 1779, and extended through the neighboring towns, I was brought into a deep labor
                            of mind concerning my own salvation . In this revival I diligently attended the meetings,
                            and was much engaged in religious exercises, By which I was greatly awakened to pray
                            earnestly to God for deliverance from sin, and from the nature of evil; but no deliverance
                            could I find'. I closely observed the operations of this revival, but could not find that it
                            wrought any abiding effect upon its subjects. I therefore diligently searched the
                            scriptures, prayed to God, and confessed my sins to Him alone in secret places. But all this
                            produced no abiding comfort, for I found that in all my labors and struggles I could not
                            obtain any victory over sin, nor could I see any among the subjects of the revival that
                            appeared in any better situation, as to religion, than myself. Notwithstanding all my
                            experience in the illuminations of the Divine spirit, and all' the flattering encouragements
                            of many old professors, who earnestly endeavored to persuade me that I was a Christian, and
                            an heir of salvation, my feelings were not satisfied. I felt mysetf unworthy o\ the name of
                            a Christian, and had no confidence in making a public profession of religion, unless-1 could
                            live according to my profession; and therefore determined net to name the name of Christ
                            till I could1 depart from iniquity, nor call myself a Christian without being convincecf
                            that I was such in realty. In the spring of the year 1780, I received intelligence of a
                            singular sect of Christians who bad! come from England, and lived near "Albany, asd who-
                            attracted much attention on Account of the singularity of their religion, and the remarkable
                            power and operations which attended it. This intelligencemade rare very anxious to see the
                            people for my own satisfaction, feeling myself fully prepared by my late Experience and my
                            knowledge of the scriptures, :to receive an understanding, and to jodge of ilWi virtue and
                            efficacy of their religion. In ¦agreement with my parents I went to see them i(feeing then
                            in the 20th year of my age), and "%as among the first in this country who Visited these
                            remarkable strangers. I found -them indeed a very singular people, and after critical
                            inquiry and observation, I had sufficient evidence to satisfy me that they possessed the
                            power of God beyond any other people I had ever seen. Instead of asking me to tell my
                            religious experience, and Inviting me to join the Church, as my former teachers had done,
                            Mother Ann Lee, the leader of this little community, taught me the necessity of confessing
                            my sins in the presence of God's witnesses, and showed me the propriety of bringing my deeds
                            to the light, and of being joined to the Lord in one spirit. I saw and acknowledged this to
                            be right. I tarried several days, and saw with much admiration the wonderful displays of
                            Divine power among these people. When I was about to take my leave of them, to return home,
                            Mother Ann told me I might confess my sins if I desired, before I returned home. I said I
                            believed it to be right to confess my sins, but I had thought to return home and labor for a
                            deeper sense of sin, and try to mend my life a little. Mother replied, " That is very good,
                            but you can gain a deeper sense of sin after you have confessed them than before, and be
                            better able to mend your life." Being fully convinced by what I had heard and seen that this
                            was the real requirement of God, I undertook it, and made as honest a confession as I was
                            able at that time. Afterward, Mother said, " You have done well so far, but you have not
                            confessed all." She then told me of a number of secret sins that I had committed, which I
                            had not recollected, and which I well knew was before unknown to any living mortal but
                            myself: and I was fully convinced that she could not have known these things but by the
                            revelation of God. I therefore felt able to return home and say, as the woman of Samaria did
                            of Jesus Christ, /have seen a woman icho was able'to tell me all that lever did in my life.
                            Here I received that holy unction from Christ, through1 Mother Ann, that fully enabled me to
                            cease from sin. Here I found boldness and confidence before God and all men, and felt my
                            adoption into the family of Christ, and among the sons of God. Here I found an entrance into
                            the pure and peaceable Kingdom of Christ, and felt my soul united to the invisible, heavenly
                            host, and filled with the quickening power of God, which gave me strength to resist all
                            evil, and to keep every sinful propensity in subjection to the law of Christ. And I felt a
                            full assurance that by continuing in obedience to the testimony I had then embraced, I shouM
                            gain a complete dominion over the powers of darkness, and reign triumphant with Christ in
                            purity and holiness. In this I have not been deceived, for I have found my faith fully
                            rerified. Indeed, it is impossible it should be otherwise, for the testimony that I
                            received, and with which I united, was like a two-edged sword against all ungodliness and
                            every appearance of evil; therefore all who are obedient to it must certainly be saved from
                            all uwgodliness. This grace I have obtained, and this power I have received, through the
                            special ministration of Mother Ann Lee, whose piercing testimony awakened the inmost
                            feelings of my soul, and roused the sleeping faculties of my mind, which had loag been
                            boundin nature's darkness. Thus did my soul receive a special manifestation of the healing
                            power of God, as really as the impotent man at the beautiful gate of the temple received the
                            miraeolous cure from Peter and John. I can testify before all men that it was through faith
                            in Mother Ann, whom God raised up and endowed with the spirit of Christ, that I was healed
                            of the infirmities of my spirit; even through Christ manifested in that woman, who was
                            shamefully persecuted, abused and slandered by a lawless and wicked generation, because she
                            zealously maintained the principles of purity and holiness, and bold! j testified, by
                            precept and example, against all the abominations of the wicked. It must appear evident to
                            every reasonable mind that had she not possessed the spirit and power of Christ she could
                            not have communicated it to others. And had she been laden with iniquity, and fraught with
                            evil and unclean spirits, she could not have purged those things from other souls. The
                            nature of evil is directly opposed to godliness, and if ever subdued it must be done by the
                            spirit and power of goodness, or it never can be done at all. And had not Mother Ann brought
                            forth the genuine fruits of righteousness in her own life and example, she never could have
                            wrought in souls such convistion of sin, and turned so many from the ways of iniquity into
                            the pure paths of peace and righteousness as she has done; and that this was truly the fruit
                            of her labors, many living witnesses can testify from their own personal knowledge and
                            experience. I was well acquainted with Mother Ann, and had many opportunities with her
                            during her ministration in this country. Being a free man, and feeling a powerful religious
                            attachment to her and the elders with her, I embraced every suitable opportunity to visit
                            them, and to be in their company at the different places where they ministered the gospel. I
                            often visited them at Watervliet, and was with them in prison at Albany—I was with them at
                            Harvard, Shirley, Woburn, Ashfield, Richmond and Hancock, in Massachusetts, at Enfield in
                            Connecticut, and at New Lebanon. I have seen and heard them in many meetings, and was
                            knowing to their deportment in public and private, and was well acquainted with their
                            manners at home and abroad, and, therefore, feel fully able to give a true statement of
                            their lives and characters. And I feel it justly my duty to contradict the false reports
                            which have Been spread abroad by the tongue of slander concerning them: for in all my
                            acquaintance with them, I have ever obesrved the same uniform example of temperance,
                            ehastitj^, righteousness and every gospel virtue. Their lives and characters were in strict
                            conformity to the doctrine and example of Christ; and they constantly taught the same to
                            others. Although many malicious and abusive charges have been published abroad in the world,
                            for the purpose of criminating Che character of this Society and its first founders,yet all
                            that can be said in the spirit of slander, is unworthy of the credit or attention of any
                            rational person. Those who nave little or no acquaintance with the Society, are not
                            qualified to give any correct information concerning it. Many unfaithful members have vainly
                            pretended to hold relation for a season ; but their ungodliness has justly brought them
                            under reproof; and instead of reforming, they have thereby taken occasion to indulge
                            themselves in resentment and falsehood, and to deny the faith whieh they had once embraced,
                            and become as traitors to those who honestly maintain the cross of Christ. Such apostates
                            have often palmed upon the Society and its leaders the crimes which they themselves had
                            committed, while pretending to hold relation with us. I can truly testify, from my own
                            personal <pb n="61" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. 61 acquaintance, that the character and example of
                            Mother and the elders were altogether the reverse of any excess, and that they invariably
                            taught the same sobriety and temperance to others. I have been a witness of many instances
                            in which Mother admonished intemperance in those whom she taught; but in no way did she do
                            it more effectually than by the godly example which she continually displayed, during the
                            whole of her life, among us. Ever faithful in good works, she often deprived herself of
                            comforts, that she might be able to comfort others. She spared not her life in promoting the
                            cause of God, in strengthening the feeble, comforting the afflicted, reproving the careless,
                            correcting disorders, purging out sin, and zealously striving, at all times, to build up
                            righteousness and peace in all who embraced her testimony. I once was young but now I am
                            old, and through my life have been an attentive observer of the ways and actions of men, but
                            I have never seen the persecutor prosper, nor the vile slanderer rise to honor. When the
                            gospel first opened in New Lebanon, the little despised flock who first embraced it, were
                            mostly people of small property, and in low circumstances ; many among us were indeed very
                            poor; and all of us, like the rest of mankind, were bound in sin and iniquity, possessing
                            our full share of all the evil propensities of a fallen nature, and sunk in slothfulness,
                            filthiness, intemperance and a multitude of other evil habits. These were our inward enemies
                            with which we had to contend; while without we had the prejudices, jealousies, slanders and
                            persecutions of an unbelieving world to encounter, who spared no pains in trying to impede
                            the work of God among us, and discourage us in our undertaking, crying out, delusion !
                            fanaticism! witchcraft! the work of the devil! But what has been the result ? I bless the
                            God of Heaven that I have lived to see the fulfillment of those blessed promises, given us
                            by the faithful messengers of truth, who first administered the gospel to us, " That if we
                            would yield a faithful obedience to the law of Christ, now made manifest, wre should be
                            blessed in our outgoings and incomings—in our basket and in our store; and above all that we
                            should enjoy the blessings of peace and salvation, which Christ had promised to the
                            faithful." As the fruits of their precepts and examples of industry, neatness, prudence,
                            temperance and godliness, I have seen a Society of people spring up. and grow and increase
                            in order, beauty and harmony, till it is, in my view, the glory of the earth—a city of
                            reflige—a shining light and a tree of life to the nations. On the other hand, I have seen
                            the false accuser, the vile slanderer and proud persecutor, who gladly would have trampled
                            under foot the meek and lowly followers of Christ, either left to become a shame and a
                            reproach to civil society, outcasts among men and vagabonds in the earth; or if their rank
                            and standing in society has preserved them from these disgraces, they have not escaped the
                            stains of dishonor, nor the stings of a guilty conscience. Numbers have lingered out their
                            days under evident guilt and condemnation, and left this mortal stage with " a fearful
                            looking," knowing that the day of reckoning must come. What became of those proud and
                            malicious persecutors who vainly strove against the work of God in New Lebanon and its
                            vicinity, in the early days of our faith ? Behold, they were scattered to the four winds!
                            But few remained in this town as the sad relics of a dishonored gang—a once haughty,
                            riotous, cruel and unfeeling band of intolerant persecutors. Many of them were swept from
                            the earth by untimely deaths and retributive judgments, till nothing but an empty name is
                            left to their forlorn remembrance. They have received the reward of their doings, and shared
                            the fate of persecutors in every age of the world. Hence it is a point of wisdom for all who
                            know not this gospel to beware how they treat it; for whether they believe it or not, it is
                            a serious reality, that the God of Heaven has laid the foundation ; Christ has set up a
                            kingdom on earth which shall never have an end. And those who bless this work will be
                            blessed, and those who curse it will be cursed. Knowing and feeling a sense of these things,
                            and standing in the fear of God, I solemnly warn all to be careful that they touch not the
                            Lord's anointed, and do his people no harm. Remember the counsel of Gamaliel to the Jewish
                            high priest and his council: " Refrain from these men and let them alone: for if this
                            counsel or this work be of men, it will come to nought; but if it be of God, ye cannot
                            overthrow it; lest haply ye be found even to fight against God."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Farrington, John" TEIform="persName"/>John Farrington</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Branches or root?" TEIform="index"/>Branches or Boot?</head><p TEIform="p">A short time since, in a religious and scientific magazine, we observed this or a similar
                            expression: " Have we not been at work on branches, and neglected to strike the axe at the
                            root of evil ?" Surely this imputation cannot be laid to the little " Shaker," which has
                            "dealt such vigorous and persistent blows at the very root of all existing evils. One
                            benevolent-hearted class of people hack away most industriously at the giant sin of
                            intemperance, but with little headway, for when they verily believed it dead, life from the
                            root and trunk sends forth more branches, and in another form the work must be repeated
                            again and again. And so of every evil: all have their mortal enemies in humanity who nobly
                            work at their destruction, but still the tree of evil holds its head aloft, and seems not
                            likely to succumb. When Jesus commenced his mission, he said, now is the axe laid at the
                            root of the tree. The now seems to be the remarkable word in the expression, and to
                            inaugurate a new mode of attack. The prunings and trimmings were to be exchanged for a work
                            more effectual. If the farmer would rid himself of an obnoxious tree, he puts his energies
                            at the destruction of the root and trunk, by cutting it down at once, not by cutting off any
                            prominent limbs or branches, however much they may have seeded his garden or otherwise
                            annoyed him. The Apostle said, " from whence come wars and fightings ? come they not hence
                            of your lusts which war in your members ?" Then to rid the earth of wars, and all the
                            consequent evils, the most effectual way would be to destroy the selfish and sensual
                            principle in each human being which " craves that it may consume upon its lusts." Christ
                            commenced on the new plan, ignoring marriage, private property, rank and title, war and
                            retaliation; and declared that the tree that bore the evil fruit was to be hewn down and
                            cast into the fire—the fire of truth and selfdenial. Fire is a purifier as well as a
                            destroyer. " Who can dwell with devouring flames," etc. ? "He that hath clean hands and a
                            pure heart."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webster, Elizabeth H." TEIform="persName"/>Elizabeth H. Webster</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To the afflicted" TEIform="index"/>To the Afflicted</head><p TEIform="p">Child of adversity ! we who are saved from the miseries and uncertainties of the outer life,
                            would speak to you words of hope; would say to you, " Fear not the rough surge which bears
                            your frail bark along the dark waters of sorrow ! Every stormy tide, and every sterile path
                            over which you journey has some fertile margins on which may grow a few plants of virtue.
                            There is some good in every heart, and that good the angels will never forsake. Look for it,
                            cherish it, and in its measure it will be like the arm of God to sustain you. Friends may
                            depart to join the invisible host; you are not bereft; they still guard you. Loved ones may
                            turn traitors, yet blessed is the heart that can say in the spirit of true forgiveness, '
                            They were not always false; it is human to err. I am not perfect.' " The soul that thus
                            receives sorrow is not blighted, but chastened; its tears are drawn from the pool of
                            humility, whose waters are purifying; and that soul will not waste the daivn of the day in
                            recalling the night-dream of grief; but it will awake to hope and energy. Its wounds will be
                            healed, and beauties will appear instead of scars. Thus God helps those wrho help
                            themselves. The sorrowing are not forgotten; their afflictions are known, their prayers are
                            heard, and relief is sent most directly through their own co-operation with the ministering
                            powers. It is never too late for effort. The change that we call death, which is certain to
                            every human being, will afford opportunity to finish whatever may be left undone here, or to
                            turn into a new course. However winding may be the stream of adversity, it has its source in
                            sin ; and sin is only abolished by self-denial. Sin is the element of Babylon, and the voice
                            of the spirit is constantly calling to all suffering hearts that are seeking truth, " Come
                            out of her, my people, that ye be not contaminated with her wickedness, and that ye receive
                            not of her punishments!" and your days of bitterness will end in bliss, for there is no
                            adversity in Heaven.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Agnew, H. R." TEIform="persName"/>H. R. Agnew</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Those who fix their eyes on the sermon on the Mount..." TEIform="index"/>Those who fix their eyes on the sermon on the Mount...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"Those who fix their eyes on the sermon on the Mount, or rather on the naked propositions it
                            contains, and disregard Christ's life, his cross and his resurrection, commit the same
                            mistake in studying Christianity, that the student of Socratic philosophy would commit if he
                            studied only the dramatic story of his death. Both Socrates and Christ uttered remarkable
                            thoughts and lived remarkable lives. But Socrates holds his place in history by his thoughts
                            and not by his life ; Christ, by his life, rather than by his thoughts."—Ecce Homo.</p></div2><pb n="62" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Future existence and eternal happiness" TEIform="index"/>Future Existence and Eternal
                            Happiness</head><p TEIform="p">As mankind in this life have a real existence without enjoying perfect happiness, so, in the
                            future world, man will find himself in the same condition. Future existence, therefore, does
                            not imply future happiness; this is attained by a certain process, and man, being a free
                            agent, is left to determine for himself how long he will put off that process which leads to
                            eternal life and happiness. Man's present and future, then, is dependent on his own agency.;
                            but this future existence is the feat of God. Dunlavy observes, that " God's decrees are to
                            be known by His works of creation and providence." When God purposed or decreed to create
                            animated beings, such as inhabit our globe, he also decreed that they should all require
                            sustenance for bodily support, and formed every one of them with appetites and a digestive
                            apparatus. After thus decreeing and thus forming them, if he had left them all without food
                            adapted to their appetites and digestive organs—without anything to sustain their lives—and
                            so left them to linger and perish with hunger, would any intelligent being fail to see that
                            such a being was either malignant or impotent and shortsighted? On the contrary, when we see
                            that ample provision is made for food, and all the means of subsistence for the thousands of
                            varied wants and appetites, all exactly adapted to each and every species of being, we see
                            not only infinite wisdom, but a boundless munificence displayed; and thus nature teaches us
                            that God is infinitety wise and good. Does she teach us truth ? Shall we rely on her
                            testimony ? Among the vast variety of these creatures there is one species called man, of
                            which there are more than a billion of individuals now on the globe. These all have the
                            common wants of other animals with regard to food, and possess in common with them an
                            appetite and digestive organs, and, like the rest, the Creator has made ample provision,
                            adapted to all their bodily wants of food, clothing and shelter. But this species of being
                            have also intelligent spirits, which have their peculiar wants, among which is an intense
                            desire for future and immortal existence. Yet, notwithstanding this, some of this species
                            say that the Creator has made no provision to satisfy this craving appetite of the
                            intelligent spirit, but that every individual of the race is doomed to perish and become
                            extinct, because no means exist to supply this life-long innate cravings of the soul. Nature
                            contradicts the ungenerous charge against this, a munificent Creator, and testifies that
                            there exists a provision for this want as well as others, because God the great Author of
                            nature cannot be inconsistent, providing for all minor wants, even those of insects, and
                            neglecting any provision for the most important of all. .Revelation harmonizes with nature
                            and declares that the God arid Father of all, who provides for " sparrows," will surely,
                            therefore, provide for the spiritual, as well as the physical, wants of his rational
                            creatures. But in the case of our temporal wants, God does not cook our food, make our
                            garments, nor build our houses, but furnishes us with the material and the faculties to do
                            it ourselves— "reaching," as one says, " these necessaries to us through our own hands."
                            This makes labor and toil a necessity in providing for our bodily wants; so with the wants
                            of our spiritual nature, God furnishes the knowledge and necessary means, but requires us to
                            " work out our salvation." " Seek and ye shall find." " Ask, ye shall receive." Strive
                            [agonisthe'] agonize, exert every nerve that ye may enter into life. Thus it is made quite
                            as necessary that we should exert our own faculties to gain spiritual sustenence and life,
                            as it is to labor for our temporal wants. It may be observed here that the word life is
                            often used in scripture in contrast, not with extinction, but with distinction and want; the
                            same as was used by the Romans, "l)um vivimvs vivamus"—While we live, let us live; that is,
                            let us enjoy ourselves. Thus it is said to those who had improved their talents—"Enter into
                            the joy of thy Lord"— into the enjoyment of his glorious and heavenly life. " Narrow is the
                            way that leadeth to life"—to true enjoyment—" and few there be that find it" in this state
                            of existence. Yet it exists and can be found—is found—and those few who have it proclaim, "
                            Ho i every one that thirsteth, come! come, for all things are ready ! "</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pelham, Richard W." TEIform="persName"/>Richard W. Pelham</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Regeneration" TEIform="index"/>Regeneration</head><p TEIform="p">Progress, as applied to man, is a movement from a lower to a higher, from a bad to a better
                            condition. As to the manner or means by which progress is effected, there is perhaps some
                            difference of opinion. One class of persons, for instance, supposes that in order to
                            progress to a higher and better condition, it is necessary to kill and utterly annihilate
                            certain inherent qualities, passions and powers of the human mind and body, so that what
                            remains may be pure and good. This presupposes the aforesaid qualities and passions to have
                            been evil, and a necessity for their destruction. Another class thinks that every faculty of
                            man is eternal; that no part of his nature can be annihilated, only at the risk of
                            destroying his identity, and endangering his future existence in the ratio of such
                            destruction. I belong to this class. I think the progress of man consists, not in accretions
                            from without, but by a process of eternal refinement from within of all that can be refined
                            as it stands; and a transmutation into higher uses of all that can not be thus refined:
                            viz., all those fugitive passions and powers, whose uses are apparent only in this
                            rudimental state, and mainly subservient thereto. Amongtjiesepassions,powers, &amp;c,
                            are anger, the productive principle, acquisitiveness, &amp;c. Let us consider the
                            procreative faculty alone, as from the treatment of this one faculty, with reference to the
                            point at issue, the theory, as applicable to all the others, may easily be inferred.
                            Procreation, a word embodying a sufficient definition, requires for its successful
                            fulfilment certain secretions from the blood, deposited and secreted by the wonderful
                            economy of the physical system. If the laws of this economy had never been violated, how
                            might the whole creation of man have been blest, and universal peace, purity and personal
                            righteousness might have sweetly smiled over the silent gloom of the fearful past! But by
                            sin, misdirection, ignorance, or whatever name you may call it, the integrity of this
                            physical law of procreation is almost completely lost; most ruthlessly and devilishly
                            violated in this our day, till there is scarcely one in a hundred thousand who is not
                            unnaturally or precociously developed in animal lust; and we are constantly driven to hear
                            the recital of such orgies of social or solitary amativeness as often to make us writhe in
                            sickness and horror. This being the case, many in all ages have chosen to renounce all
                            relation in life to this powerful passion, and to live pure celibate lives. The Shakers of
                            the present day have even adopted the celibate life as the most important tenet of their
                            doctrine, without which, as they believe, their community and their theological system would
                            both fail. The question, then, is: How are we free from the imputation of destroying and
                            crushing out certain faculties and proclivities furnished us by our Creator for beneficial
                            purposes, thereby blaspheming the Great and All-Wise Power which has bestowed them? This
                            question would come with a better grace from those not of our Order, if there was now, or
                            ever had been a time in man's history when the abuse of this faculty did not produce a
                            hundred thousand fold more misery and ruin of soul and body than its total disuse. We
                            believe that the Evangels of Jesus and Ann were predicated principally upon the terrible
                            fact that the human race were fast nearing the awful maelstrom of irrecoverable ruin, mainly
                            through the instrumentality of sexual abuse, and there was need of an institution into which
                            could enter those who desired an asylum of perfect seclusion and protection from " the lusts
                            of the flesh ;" and which would also be a standing rebuke and perpetual testimony against
                            the frightful orgies of crime, carried on through the abuse of the sexual principle. Now, as
                            before stated, the pabulum creating secretions necessary for procreation, if not used in
                            that way, is by no means wasted, but re-absorbed by the blood, and goes to form the yery
                            best material for the vitalization of the brain, and consequent evolution of the purest
                            material for thought, and the most transparent medium through which to transmit the highest
                            inspirations from Heaven. In this sublime and heavenly condition we feel drawn out in love
                            towards the whole world, and would gladly propagate them through our faith and living
                            inspirations from the flesh into the spirit, from the power of lower, baser influences, to
                            the higher and holier! This, as we understand it, when fully acquiesced in and seconded by
                            those on whom it is brought to bear, is the true regeneration; and when faithfully and
                            understandingly entered upon, with a full determination never to yield the struggle, must
                            inevitably eventuate in " the second birth." And we have learned by long experience that so
                            sure as " he that soweth to the flesh, shall of the flesh reap corruption," so sure will "he
                            that soweth to the spirit reap life everlasting;" yea, and peace beyond all power of human
                            language to express. But this high ground is not to be gained with62 <pb n="63" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/>
                            THE SHA.KER. 63 out a struggle. Indeed, to come into and through this regeneration and new
                            birth, and completely rise into this halcyon newness of life, everything below it, all
                            former elements, have to be melted with fervent heat, and the whole re-cast in the crucible
                            of deep sorrow and tribulation, until the spiritual transmutation is effected. This requires
                            days, months, and years, and great wisdom and vigilance are requisite, that collateral
                            agencies be not allowed so far to affect the results as to distort and mutilate the whole
                            character and features of the child of God that is to be! If, for instance, a person holds a
                            constant check upon one mean proclivity, say lust, and yet indulges all the time in the use
                            of spirits, opium, tea, coffee, tobacco, pork, &amp;c, he may possibly attain to a
                            regenerate state on that one line; but, alas, what a distorted, swollen, ill-natured child
                            of God he must inevitably come out! Another regenerating process will be necessary to make
                            him presentable, under any circumstances. This is not the worst. Every atom of nervous force
                            he allows to be wasted, in the pleasurable excitements of the aforesaid animal indulgences
                            and intoxications, subtract directly from that unreplenishable stamina of body and mind by
                            which he is to effect his final exaltation to a higher plane. Davis, and many other eminent
                            writers, even declare that "opium and tobacco stimulate the sexual propensities, and
                            generate unhealthy desires." Therefore, would any man or woman set out on the solemn journey
                            to eternal peace with God, let him, or her, if they have felt a Divine call from their
                            interior consciousness, and conviction thereto, abandon at once and forever all indulgence
                            of the "flesh with the affections and lusts;" all anger and ill-will against all fellow
                            beings; all use of tobacco, tea, coffee, spirits, opium, etc., and commence immediately the
                            development of regeneration. When you have made the most earnest and persevering struggles
                            in this new life, and find yourselves overcome in spite of your best efforts, until you are
                            in utter despair, then come, if unwilling to before, to the Shakers; confess every known sin
                            ever committed, yield yourselves in unequivocal obedience to their instruction, and if you
                            are ever after faithful to your convictions, you cannot fail of the mansions of peace,
                            eternal in the heavens, and a crown of everlasting joy and glory, " where the wicked cease
                            from troubling, and the weary are at rest!" We know this to be true; we have tried it from
                            ten to seventy years, yea, even to eighty years, and it has never failed in a single
                            instance. The reasons why you will succeed better here than in isolated conditions of the
                            world may be easily understood. For the amount of love, sympathy and affection which you as
                            an individual may be able to bestow, you receive back the love, sympathy and affection, and
                            consequent moral and spiritual strength of hundreds of your dear brethren and sisters,
                            laborers in the same good cause. This advantage is possible in a Community only, and this is
                            the reason you will be far more liable to succeed among the Shakers.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="H., O. C." TEIform="persName"/>O. C. H., Union Tillage, 0.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Unity, the bond of peace" TEIform="index"/>Unity, the Bond of Peace</head><p TEIform="p">We'll cling to each other in friendship. In purity, peace, and true love ; We'll imitate
                            Jesus' example, And live like the angels above. Jesus said, " Ye must love one another, By
                            this your discipleship's known;" So all other tokens are useless, Where this blessed mark is
                            not shown. We'll move ever onward and upward, Away, far away from the earth, Together seek
                            heavenly treasures Of eternal substance and worth. The spirit is calling us loudly, To work
                            with more earnest desire; True action is living to purpose. And draws us to God ever nigher.
                            We'll live—live by love and good actions, The cross, self-denial and right; Time is
                            fleeting, earth's joys are transient, But heaven hath endless delight. 'Tis only the
                            faithful are crowned, So let us work on with a zeal, Not weary, but labor in earnest, And
                            God will His treasures reveal. (Hancock.)</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="J." TEIform="persName"/>J.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Light" TEIform="index"/>Light</head><p TEIform="p">Father of Light, in thee we trust. From thee all blessings flow; Thy ways are ever true and
                            just, A nd thou all hearts doth know. O, may we walk with humble fear, Each day within thy
                            sight; And may our constant, fervent prayer Be, "Father, give us light!" O, grant to us thy
                            mercy, Lord, To save us from our loss; Thy power, and thy quickening word, With faith to
                            bear the cross,— O, leave us not, when storms arise, Dark clouds heave up in sight; But
                            guide us in thy way so wise, To light, more perfect light. If we should err, or go astray,
                            Or thy least law forget, O, point us to the narrow way, Thy truth hath wisely set. Then, in
                            thy temple, while we've breath, We'll praise thee with delight; That thou hast raised our
                            souls from death, To light, effulgent light.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lewis, Polly" TEIform="persName"/>Polly Lewis, Mt L.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Happiness is a very common plant..." TEIform="index"/>Happiness is a very common plant...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Happiness is a very common plant, a native of every soil, yet, some skill is required in
                            gathering it; for many poisonous weeds look like it, and deceive the unwary to their ruin.
                            Amid the tears of grief, peace keeps her silent place like the rainbow upon the spray of the
                            cataract; noi can it be disturbed so long as Jehovah's sunshine rests upon the soul. Duties
                            lazily and lifelessly performed ; half-heartec prayers ; a deportment blameless enough,
                            perhaps but tame and unexpressive, and therefore not influen tial; words wrell and wisely
                            spoken, perhaps, but without depth and intensity, therefore without weight These are things
                            which God cannot tolerate in a saint In judging of others, let us always think the best, and
                            employ the spirit of charity and candor; but in judging of ourselves we ought to be exact
                            and severe He that cannot live well to-day, will be less qualified to live well to-morrow.
                            To be wise in our own eyes, in the opinion of the world, and in the sight of our Creator,
                            are three things so very different as rarely to coincide. Charity, like the sun, brightens
                            every object on which it shines. Christianity did not come from heaven to be the amusement
                            of an idle hour; to be the food of mere imagination; to be as a very lovely song of one tha
                            hath a pleasant voice. It is intended to be the guide the companion of all our hours, the
                            serious occupation of our whole existence. Enfield, Conn. It is pleasing to us, when those
                            not of our order neourage us in disseminating our doctrinal views; ind when we receive words
                            of cheer, as the following jespeak, we are reminded that we toil not in vain.— Ed.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Adam, the first, was created..." TEIform="index"/>Adam, the first, was created...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">" Adam, the first, was created a natural man of the earth. Adam, the second, was jorn a
                            spiritual man from the heavens." Here we have two distinct orders of beings, each belonging
                            to its respective head or parentage. As it is written: " That which is first was not
                            spiritual, but natural, and afterward that which was spiritual," it is reasonable to
                            suppose, had not Adam transgressed and fallen m his generative order, there would have been
                            a necessity for him to have progressed into a spiritual order; and it is fair to suppose
                            that, as a natural, rational being, the transition from a generative to a regenerative life
                            would have been easj to what it is now, as a poor, blinded, fallen being. Then, if there was
                            a necessity for man, before the fall, to progress to a higher state of manhood, out of one
                            order to another, how much greater necessity now that man is unnatural, irrational and
                            fallen. " You must be born again," is the language of Christ to Nicodemus, and " you must be
                            born again," is the language of fallen humanity repeated to itself daily, as it wallows in
                            its own corrupt blood, or lingers in constant pain. Then Christian regeneration, as we
                            understand it, is the coming out of the old generative order —putting off the old man with
                            his deeds, which are ever corrupt after the flesh, and by putting on the new man who is
                            spiritual—even the Christ from the heavens. Jesus calls all men to follow him (not Adam, nor
                            Moses), in the regeneration, and become new creatures, by the washing or cleansing process
                            of a Christian life, as it is in Himself, the Christ—the Lord from heaven.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bushnell, E." TEIform="persName"/>E. Bushnell, Calhoun, Mo.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I feel the Divine hand has guided my way..." TEIform="index"/>I feel the Divine hand has guided my way...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">" I feel the Divine hand has guided my way; and though the full hour has not arrived for the
                            opening of your door to me, yet some day it will open, and angel hands will guide the way,
                            and Mother Ann will lead me in the paths of wisdom and love. ... 'The Shaker' blesses me ; I
                            rejoice in its advent to the world; it will do good, for those who read it cannot fail of
                            feeling its heavenly mission."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="L., C. S." TEIform="persName"/>C. S. L., Ohio.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How can I better praise my God than by loving him with a heart sincere?..." TEIform="index"/>How can I better praise my God than by loving him with a heart sincere?...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">How can I better praise my God than by loving him with a heart sincere ? How better can I
                            show it, than by giving love to those who need his love through me ? In gentle words, in
                            kindly acts, in pleasant smiles or sympathetic tears, as the occasion best requires.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whiteley, J." TEIform="persName"/>J. Whiteley</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="As each particle of gold possesses every one of the chemical properties of all the gold on                                 earth..." TEIform="index"/>As each particle of gold...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"As each particle of gold possesses every one of the chemical properties of all the gold on
                            earth, so does each human being possess all the elements and properties of humanity in
                            aggregate. The same process thaOvould separate the dross from one ounce of gold, would also
                            separate the dross from all the gold in existence.'"</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="E., F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. E.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Every Christian should begin to doubt himself..." TEIform="index"/>Every Christian should begin to doubt himself...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"Every Christian should begin to doubt himself, if he finds after ten years, that self-denial
                            is as hard in the same things as it was at first." "Yon are to accept as a Christian every
                            one whose life and disposition are Christ-like, no matter how heretical the denomination may
                            be to which he belonga''—Beecher.</p></div2><pb n="64" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="According to your works" TEIform="index"/>"According to Your Works."</head><p TEIform="p">In the " Book of Common Prayer," we read, at the close of the " Lord's Prayer," the fol-
                            lowing addendum :—Minister : " 0 Lord, deal not with us according to our sins !" Congre-
                            gation : " Neither reward us according to our iniquities !" This is a first class
                            representation of the lesson human nature has learned from the text, " Thou shalt not surely
                            die." Pleasure, regardless of its character, depraved human nature will have; but the just
                            reward of iniquitous doings it shrinks from; to escape pay-day is very desirable. Rather,
                            slay the Lamb, use his skin, or character, for a covering ; his blood for an atonement; and
                            thus disguised, run the gauntlet of justice, and look for the reward of heaven, unearned,
                            gratuitously! Poor human nature! "Behold, I come quickly." * * * * Should we, in the employ
                            of one government, look to another for our compensation ? Why should we look to God for
                            reward, if our services have been engaged in the works of the Devil ? If we have the reward
                            of the righteous, we must live the life of the righteous. If we sin, we shall reap the
                            reward of sin—death. If we sow to the flesh, we shall reap the opposite of peace, purity;
                            and our abode here, and hereafter, will be where those who " sow to the spirit, and walk not
                            after the flesh with its affections and lusts," would not, could not dwell. May the good God
                            not depart from the holiness of his promise, but " reward us according to our works ;" and
                            may we so live as to expect, and joyfully meet the consequences. The best way to escape the
                            punishment of sin, is to stop sinning.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anstatt, Isaac" TEIform="persName"/>Isaac Anstatt</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><p TEIform="p">Mt. Lebanon stands improved by an ornamental iron fence on either side of the road passing
                            through the Church family. New roofs are noticed on some of the buildings. "The "North" are
                            testifying their love for future adherents by repainting all their buildings. One of the
                            most beautiful and affecting seasons was at the farewell gathering to bid adieu to Elder F.
                            W. Evans.</p><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>[Obituary]</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hinckley, Dwight" TEIform="index"/>Dwight Hinckley...
                                </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Hinckley, Dwight" TEIform="persName">Dwight Hinckley</persName>. a most worthy and
                                    estimable brother, dropped dead while at work on the Church's fence, on Monday, 3rd
                                    July. He was brother of Barnabas, who. in the height of his career as a surgeon,
                                    dropped dead a few years ago in the same family.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harwood, Mercy" TEIform="index"/>Watervliet chronicles one death recently...
                                </head><p TEIform="p">Watervliet chronicles one death recently—<persName reg="Harwood, Mercy" TEIform="persName">Mercy
                                    Harwood</persName>, of the " Church,'1 aged nearly 79. Immense crowds are attendant
                                    on Sabbath services, and of a very intelligent and appreciative type. Groveland
                                    reports "no great loss without some small gain." by rebuilding liner buildings than
                                    those destroyed by fire. Hancock has been improving her Meeting House. No deaths,
                                    but general health reported. Fruit a failure here. Tyringham: Crops looking well,
                                    corn excepted. Grass, nearly a medium crop. General health.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Barrett, Maria" TEIform="index"/>Harvard reports one death...
                                </head><p TEIform="p">Harvard reports one death, <persName reg="Barrett, Maria" TEIform="persName">Maria Barrett</persName>,
                                    aged 88. A large and commodious barn has been built at the " North." "If we have any
                                    monotony, it is broken once a month by the appearance of the ever-welcome '
                                    Shaker.''" Shirley reports many deaths of prominent individuals in their vicinity,
                                    but have not been afflicted themselves. The substitution of cement aqueduct for the
                                    lead pipes of old, has much improved the quality of their water. The Hospital took
                                    fire from a defect in the chimney ; damage slight; but now the same stands greatly
                                    improved. Union Village, O., is enjoying a refreshing season of spiritual things in
                                    some portions of its domain, the effect of sincere prayer ou the part of its good
                                    people. The New Creation is a new monthly, published at Omaha. We are unable, as
                                    yet, to know its true intent, but, judging from its remarks upon the Shaker Church,
                                    in the July No., we are inclined to believe that it means to experience what
                                    persecution is, by upholding the true issues of life; by despising the shame of the
                                    popular masses, and inculcating the necessity of a purer life than orthodox
                                    Christians, socalled, now live. Its life is useless unless it strikes deeply. " We
                                    declare as by the spirit of the Lord, among the seven representative churches of
                                    Asia, which are made manifest at Christ's second coming in the hearts of his elect,
                                    all of which the spirit rebuked for their sins, while commending their graces, save
                                    tioo. one of Which was called the "Church of Philadelphia," that the order of
                                    Shakers represents this church, which by name signifies (Phila-Delphi) the love of
                                    brother, or brotherly love, as distinguished from sexual love or the love of
                                    kindred, of which Christ demanded a full and complete sacrifice. We declare that the
                                    Shakers alone have fulfilled as an order or church, in the lead of woman, t\\\sfull
                                    condition, fulfilling the words of Christ, "Who is my mother and who are my brethren
                                    ? He that doeth the will of my Father in Heaven, the same is my mother, my sister
                                    and my brother." They have left houses 'ami lands, fathers and mothers, brothers,
                                    sisters and children, husbands and wives, for the kingdom of heaven's sake. They
                                    alone us an order have laid the ax at the root of sexual corruptions, or at the
                                    roots of the corrupt trees which have sprung therefrom. They alone have sacrificed
                                    the strongest impulses of a corrupt and lustful nature, as did their mother Ann.
                                    They have made themselves a sign to this lustful and adulterous gene- ration, the
                                    generation of the flesh, sacrificing fleshly love and taking in its place brotherly
                                    love. They alone have therefore gained the character of the Church of Brotherly
                                    Love, the Church of Philadelphia."—New Creation.</p></div4></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="publication" TEIform="index"/>[Publications]
                        </head><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notices of the press" TEIform="index"/>NOTICES OF THE PRESS.</head><p TEIform="p">The Shaker is the name of a new monthly, issued by and devoted to these faithful and
                                honest devotees of their Christ. The first number issued for January, 1871, is a well
                                got up and well filled sheet of respectable size, and cheap at fifty cents a year, and
                                issued in Albany, N. Y., and edited by G. A. Lomas. We are glad these good people are
                                now speaking to the public for themselves, and hope their paper will be largely
                                patronized, that they may be better known and more appreciated thereby. They certainly
                                have many virtues not common to Christians, and not appreciated as they deserve to be by
                                other societies. It is not strange that there should be much sympathy with them among
                                Spiritualists, since they had much of phenomenal Spiritualism among them, and most of
                                them became convinced that spirits communicate before it gained much popularity among
                                Infidels and other Christians.—Banner of Light. The Shaker, published at Albany, N. Y.,
                                is a monthly sheet, filled with words of love and wisdom. Its weapons of warfare are
                                spiritual and mighty.— New Era, Cleveland. </p></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Universal test" TEIform="index"/>"The Universal Test."</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">It falls in the way of the little paper called The Shaker, to define its ism
                                        in a nut-shell; and it says, " the kernel when reached is: Confess and forsake
                                        sin; live purely, and you are a Shaker without knowing it, regardless of your
                                        theology.'' How unerringly all sincere religionists of every name and nation
                                        come to this one result at last! The great end and aim of the truly religious
                                        man is to '' live purely *'—to throw off the yoke of sin. The attainment of this
                                        is the Great Salvation. The best religion is that which, tried by its results,
                                        is best adapted to this end. Ought not this self-evident truth to disci-edit the
                                        prevalent a priori tests by which we are ever trying our respective theologies ?
                                        And does it not suggest, too, the cheering thought, that inasmuch as we have the
                                        Divine assurance that '' in every nation, he that feareth him and worketh
                                        righteousness is accepted of him;" the field of God's mercy is wider than our
                                        fears have allowed ? That wherever (even among the heathen) the sincere effort
                                        is put forth, however mistakenly as to means, for the attainment of holiness,
                                        the Divine Love shall surely, one day, bring the consummation so devoutly wished
                                        ? Blessed are they that hunger and thirst after righteousness, for they shall be
                                        filled.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Christian union, New York" TEIform="index"/>Christian Union, N. Y.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="However pleasing it may be at present to follow our inclinations..." TEIform="index"/>However pleasing it may be at present to follow our inclinations...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> However pleasing it may be at present to follow our inclinations, nothing will give
                                peace in the end but righteousness; and nothing is righteous but to deny ourselves and
                                do the will of God. </p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If our gratitude keeps pace with the blessings we receive..." TEIform="index"/>If our gratitude keeps pace with the blessings we receive...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> If our gratitude keeps pace with the blessings we receive from God, we must begin very
                                early in the morning to exercise it; for His protecting care and tender love is extended
                                to us all the time we are sleeping. </p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Defend the character of the absent..." TEIform="index"/>Defend the character of the absent...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Defend the character of the absent, even of those that are bad. as far as truth Will
                                permit; the rest conceal, unless duty requires its exposure. </p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Every love is impure in proportion..." TEIform="index"/>Every love is impure in proportion...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Every love is impure in proportion as it has self for its end, and dangerous in the
                                degree that it ministers impure gratification. </p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="O, how foolish is he who defiles his spirit..." TEIform="index"/>O, how foolish is he who defiles his spirit...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> O, how foolish is he who defiles his spirit, sacrifices a pure conscience, and the love
                                of God, for the sake of gaining the love of creatures. </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Private and internal devotion improves the affections; reading and reflection                                     the understanding" TEIform="index"/>Private and internal devotion improves the affections...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Private and internal devotion improves the affections; reading and reflection the
                                understanding. </p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="And should my brother me offend..." TEIform="index"/>And should my brother me offend...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> And should my brother me offend, Seventy-times-seven in a day, I will forgive him at the
                                end, And for his reformation pray. I seek not selfish ends, but greatly desire the end
                                of self.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pelham, R. W." TEIform="persName"/>R. W. Pelham </byline></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Societies not mentioned in the 'Record,'..." TEIform="index"/>Societies not mentioned in the 'Record,'...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Societies not mentioned in the "Record," have not reported in time for notice. * </p></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker, monthly journal, devoted to the exposition of religion, acording to Shaker                                     theology" TEIform="index"/>THE SHAKER. MONTHLY JOURNAL, DEVOTED TO THE EXPOSITION OF RELIGION, ACCORDING TO
                                SHAKER THEOLOGY.</head><p TEIform="p">Fifty Cents, Per Annum, in Advance. G. A. Lomas, Resident Editor, Shakers, Albany Co., N.
                                Y. </p></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Members of society" TEIform="index"/>MEMBERS OF SOCIETY</head><p TEIform="p">Appointed to answer Correspondents, among whom are the Board of Editors. PUBLICATIONS.
                                Christ's First and Second Appearing Dnnlavy's Manifesto Millennial Church Compendium of
                                Shakerism ... Three Discourses ou United Interests Tracts free, where postage is paid.
                                SI 25 1 25 1 00 0 50 0 50 Elder F. W. Evans, Mt Lebanon, Columbia Co., N. Y. " Issachar
                                Bates, Shakers, N. Y. " Calvin G. Reed, Mt. Morris, Livingston Co., N. Y. " Simon Mabee,
                                West Pittsfield, Mass. " Stoughton Kellogg, Thompsonville, Conn., Shakers. " Albert
                                Battles, Tyringham, Berkshire Co., Mass. " Wm. Leonard, Ayer, Mass., Shakers. " John
                                Whiteley, Shirley Village, Middlesex Co., Mass. " Xehemiah Trull, Shaker Village,
                                Merrimack Co., N. H. " Henry Cummings, Enfield, Grafton Co., N. H. " John B. Vance,
                                Alfred, Shakers, York Co., Me. " Alonzo Gilman, West Gloucester, Cumberland Co., Me.,
                                Shakers. " Chas. Clapp, Union Village, Warren Co., O., Shakers. " Ezra Sherman, Preston,
                                Hamilton Co., Ohio, Shakers. " Stephen Ball, Dayton, Shakers, Ohio. " Jacob Kulp,
                                Pleasant Hill, Mercer Co., Ky. 11 J. R. Eades, South Union, Logan Co., Ky. " J. S.
                                Prescott, Cleveland, Ohio, Shakers. 64</p></div3></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>