<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm0909" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title><editor role="editor" TEIform="editor"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/></editor></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">9</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">9</biblScope><date value="18790901" TEIform="date">September 1879</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">193-216</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="9" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="9" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                     <pb id="p1"/>
                     <p> SEPTEMBER, 1879. MANIFESTO, (OFFICIAL MONTHLY.) G. A. LOMAS, Editoe. Published by the United Societies. OUR HOME AT
                        CANTERBURY, N. H. "And they shall turn to you for a testimony:" '' Go preach the Kingdom of God/" ADDRESS ALL
                        COMMUNICATIONS TO " The Shaker Manifesto, Shakers, N.D." G. B. AVERY, PUBLISHER. 1879. Vol. IX | No. 9. 60 Cents I
                        Per Annum. The Shaker</p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
--><pb n="193" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Justice is God's throne" TEIform="index"/>JUSTICE IS GOD'S THRONE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/>ANTOINETTE DOOLITTLE</byline><p TEIform="p">When wo see the inequality of the rich and poor, of individuals who by inheritance or stealth
                            hold within their grasp hundreds of millions of dollars, and who spend their unearned wealth
                            in profligate habits, luxuriating on costly wines and extravagant dinners—which stimulate
                            animal passions and lead to gross sensuality—the language of our heart is " God is not
                            there; " neither will " wisdom, whose dwelling place is with prudence," consort with
                            gluttons and wine bibbers. We turn to the poverty stricken and oppressed, who perhaps
                            through want are driven into crime, and the haunts of vice and woe, there to drag out a
                            brief but miserable existence. Again we say, " God is not there," except as a reprover—for
                            He does not dwell in unclean temples filled with idols, and idol worshipers. If "wisdom is
                            justified of her children," who are her children, and where is she to be found ? Will it be
                            considered an untenable position or sacrilegious if we affirm that God never made man a
                            millionaire nor a pauper; neither a murderer nor a sensualist ? Can man, or any number of
                            men, by an enactment of law, under any pretext whatever, make right what in principle is
                            wrong? One man cannot accumulate millions of dollars in a life-time, even in a century of
                            years, and be a truly just and honest man ; for by the toil of his own hands, if ever so
                            industrious, and the wl sweat of his own brow " he cannot earn that amount. By brain work,
                            he may heap up gold and silver in large sums, taking by might not right, from his weaker
                            brother his just dues for labor performed, which rightly named, is "legalized theft;" and he
                            is honored and sustained by public opinion and the spirit of the times. The poor man, who
                            has been robbed of the fruits of hard-earned toil, if he steals five dollars, is condemned
                            at what is termed the " bar of justice " as having committed a criminal act and is tried,
                            fined and placed for a limited time, longer or shorter, within the walls of a cold,
                            cheerless prison to atone for the penal offense. Again, rulers and law givers justify
                            bloodshed and slaughter, when it is done in a prescribed manner. If there be what is termed
                            a national insult, or violation of international law unredressed, then if thousands under
                            their " National Banner," uprise in a war spirit to avenge the wrong by slaying multitudes
                            of innocent but helpless human beings, it is sanctioned by public eclat, honored by
                            political prefer- <pb n="194" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 194 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. merit, and rewarded by
                            large drafts upon the public treasury ; when, if for an individual wrong or insult, a murder
                            is perpetrated, then it becomes a heinous crime, and the law passes the rigorous sentence: "
                            An eye for an eye, life for life." So in regard to sensuality, if legalized and hid under a
                            cloak of marriage, it is sanctioned by public consent, and not a dissenting voice is heard
                            from pulpit nor press. But they who sell their chastity for profit or pleasure, not having
                            taken shelter behind the matrimonial screen, must bear the odium of public scorn, and become
                            outcasts, not worthy a place in respectable society. " The Lord seeth not as man seeth ; "
                            He looks at the heart, and judges justly. Heaven is not formed of nor for millionaires,
                            military chieftains, nor legalized adulterers ; and we do not go beyond the bounds of
                            prudence when we assert, that there are neither millionaires nor paupers, warriors nor
                            adulterers in heaven. Christ, the redeeming spirit, must work to uplift, purge and purify
                            them from the spirit of monopoly—of war and sensual appetites and desires, regardless of
                            names or professions, before they can be at peace with God, and enjoy the full communion of
                            saints, without which there can be no heaven. God's ministers may plead, angels may weep and
                            pity, but without co-operation with the redeeming spirit, and suffering upon the cross, and
                            dying to all that is selfish, unjust and unholy, there can be no heaven formed in this nor
                            any other sphere of existence. Justice is God's law, where he sits enthroned.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Eden" TEIform="index"/>EDEN</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p">The writer possesses a microscopic copy of the _ZV. Y. Tribune a few inches square. In size
                            it bears about the same relation to the common Tribune that the Eden of our theological
                            childhood bears to the true Eden, as it once existed upon earth, and to the millennium, as
                            it will hereafter exist. In Eden there were no diseases. In the coming millennium there will
                            be no one who can say I am sick. If the first act of sin in Eden was erroneous eating, will
                            not the first act of salvation in the millennial order be that of eating righteously ? Will
                            not revelation and science determine to exactitude, what food and drink shall be taken, and
                            in what quantities, to maintain in perfect health, the physical bodies of human beings, with
                            the most perfect mentality ? Obedience to such knowledge will be justification—salvation—
                            even as disobedience thereto, either through willfulness or ignorance, was the original sin
                            of Eden. Was the lust of eating the first, or the second sin ? I incline to put it first, in
                            point of time— second in point of importance, even as the continuance of the race is of more
                            importance than that of any one individual. The perverted uses of the reproductive powers —
                            the corruptions that are in the world through lust—have wrought the ills that now afflict
                            humanity. All the diseases of the Egyptians are upon Christians. They also inherit the War
                            God of the Jews, with his bloody sacrifices, filling the earth with slaughter, turning all
                            church and State governments into engines of blood, having even a theology as bloody as
                            Mars, the Heathen God of War, could devise or desire. By the lust of eating evils are
                            multiplied in the individual. And by the lust of generation, they are perpetuated and
                            increased in the whole race—priest and people. The government of Hayti has set apart an
                            Island in the Pacific for the exclusive use of Lepers, of which there are some 35,000.
                            Should these Lepers be cut off from Hayti and the rest of the world, so entirely and so <pb n="195" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 195 long as to lose knowledge of it, any
                            physical regeneration must originate among themselves and their leprous posterity. May not
                            such have been the case with the primal pair of Eden? Are we, their descendants, any thing
                            but the outcasts of some former millennial race of people ? Was not Eden a State, rather
                            than a location? a state of innocence and bliss that countless millions of beings had
                            attained unto by travail of soul, and who had an existence as real as do the inhabitants of
                            Hayti ? Adam and Eve were thrown out from amongst them, as lepers, for their own
                            transgressions—the lusts of the flesh and mind. Having lost knowledge of the community from
                            which their sins had expelled them, they have lived in their posterity down to the present
                            time, with a childish recollection of Eden, and a child hope of the millennium. The original
                            faithful Eden people, having passed into the Spirit World, are a heaven to the generation of
                            sinners left upon earth. Spiritualism is bringing them into intercommunication with each
                            other, and religion excites them to blend, by love, into one people. Condescension on one
                            side, and aspiration and inspiration on the other, effect the mutually desired union.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Weary not, o Christian pilgrim" TEIform="index"/>"WEARY NOT, 0 CHRISTIAN PILGRIM."</head><head TEIform="head"><persName reg="Fletcher, Richard" TEIform="persName"/>RICHARD FLETCHER</head><p TEIform="p">Who says the Christian pilgrim wearies ? Surely not in spirit, in this bright day ! One may
                            be so weary in body, from zealous temporal labor, that the best affections are robbed of
                            their share of the richest elements, and droop earthward, instead of climbing God-ward. Does
                            scarcity of numbers dishearten 1 What are numbers, when the weight of the spiritual universe
                            is on one's side ? The census of the innumerable throng would add a long string of ciphers
                            to the right hand side of our present figures. No earthly statistics have as yet found room
                            for the count. Let those weary who dissipate in building hopes of happiness on selfish
                            pursuits, on the sands of trashy amusements. It belongs to the bubbles, on the surface of
                            the stream of life, to weary of circling round and round in the frothy scum until they
                            vanish. Let the bubbles whirl and sparkle at the foot of every little brookfalls, to amuse
                            the eyes and lull the drowsy ears of idlers. Yet we all know the useful under-current of the
                            stream is the hope of the miller, as it quietly throws off the glittering bubbles and
                            hastens on. Happy are they who can see the nobility of living like the Christ; they receive
                            a rich, hundred-fold reward in return for the sacrifice of a life of a transient pleasure
                            and animal sensations. It is well worth the labor to be so consecrated as not to be even
                            tempted to waste a moment in sighs for the bubbles and trash of life. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Saviour on the mount" TEIform="index"/>THE SAVIOUR ON THE MOUNT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>MARTHA J. ANDERSON</byline><p TEIform="p">Pressed by the multitudes that thronged his way, And clamored for a miracle or test, Who
                            sought the things that lasted but a day, Nor cared for truth his inner life had blessed. The
                            lowty Jesus went his way apart, And his disciples followed him apace ; They knew the springs
                            that welled within his heart Would flow to them in streams of living grace. His steps were
                            bent unto the favored spot, Where he was wont to seek a calm retreat, While cares and trials
                            all, his soul forgot; Where heaven and earth in close communion meet. The sunny beams upon
                            the mountain broke; The Olive-trees with glistening dews were sweet; Among their branches
                            gentle murmurs woke, And snowy blossoms fell before his feet. Fair emblems of the precious
                            words that came Unsullied from the lips of him who spake To those who loved to hear, and
                            name the name, That bore the power the slumbering soul to wake. Beneath the Olive's shade,
                            whose glossy leaves <pb n="196" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 196 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. Droop peacefully above
                            his Christ like brow — The golden threads of life divine he weaves, In which beatitudes
                            refulgent glow. The shimmering gleams that 'lumed the shady bower Were faint, compared with
                            truth's bright piercing darts, That God had placed within the archer's power, To slay the
                            foes that lurk in human hearts. He sat not there, with pharisaic mien, Propounding logic of
                            a mystic creed ; But, with a spirit self-subdued, and clean, He ministered according to
                            their needs. A flood of inspiration thrilled his soul, And thought expanding found
                            expression free; The Christ-anointing held supreme control, And gave his spirit heavenly
                            liberty. Before all men, O let your light shine forth ' That they may see your works are
                            just and true, And glorify the Father, who hath wrought, A work which will create all things
                            anew. He came, not to destroy the written law. But one more perfect to impress within ; When
                            good for evil wrong would overawe, And righteousness would take the place of sin. He gave to
                            them the simple, golden rule ; More potent than the conquering Roman state, The fires of
                            passion to assuage and cool, And love its motor, to subdue all hate. They bowed their hearts
                            in sacred reverence, While he in simple faith taught them to pray ; A prayer so full of
                            trust, yet so intense, 'Twas like the glory of a new-born day. Fair lilies of the valley
                            robed in white, Knew not the cankering care of mortal needs ; Yet he who trusting, dwells
                            within His light, Our heavenly Father blesses, clothes and feeds. And thus he crystallized
                            the gems of worth, In illustrative parable outwrought; While mighty principles which move
                            the earth, Were to the understanding clearly taught. Some marvelled at the doctrine, strange
                            and new, That Jesus taught the people day by day ; His wondrous system rose before their
                            view, And all their old traditions swept away. The Messianic kingdom they had planned Came
                            not in regal pomp, nor glittering show ; The Prince of Peace went forth through Judea's
                            land, The seeds of everlasting life to sow. He healed the sick, the lame and blind made
                            whole ; Demoniac spirits from his presence fled ; Superior forces acting through his soul,
                            Restored to living consciousness, the dead. How beautiful upon the mountain's hight The
                            Master in his earnestness appears ! All crowned with haloes of prophetic light, That circle
                            'round the centuries of years. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Consecrated discipline" TEIform="index"/>CONSECRATED DISCIPLINE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="McLaughlin, Josephine" TEIform="persName"/>JOSEPHINE MC LAUGHLIN</byline><p TEIform="p">I feel impressed with the necessity of maintaining a cheerful spirit at all times — a spirit
                            of thankfulness. Outward circumstances of disquiet unquestionably have the power to mar the
                            peace of the best; but we should school ourselves to look on the bright side, and having
                            faith in God, labor to be able to find some good in everybody and in every thing. Of course
                            it requires strong faith in God to live this life in cheerful acquiescence to the duties
                            allotted us. But every Shaker or Christian (they are synonyms) must have a faith to be as
                            clay in the potter's hands. This is the faith which the Bible everywhere enjoins ; the faith
                            which was so emphatically taught and exemplified by Christ himself. Some might ask : Is it
                            possible in this age of doubt and unbelief to live such a life of faith ? the answer is,
                            many true disciples have lived it in the past, many are living it to-day, and sufficient
                            unto our day will be our strength. The blessings of God will descend on those who are
                            obedient to His will through his order, and such will become the possessors of that peace
                            that passeth all understanding. Yea, a peace that broad acres and elegant mansions with
                            exclusive ownership can never give—but comes alone from a conscience j ustified by the daily
                            crucifixion of all the evils that belong to a fallen nature. If we are in this labor we will
                            be able to do great good to others, and honor the religion we <pb n="197" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            SHAKER MANIFESTO. 197 profess. Let us carry the sunshine of a cheerful face and a glad heart
                            wherever we go. Let us have an encouraging word for every one we meet. Let us make our home
                            an Eden to the extent of our ability, by shedding over it the atmosphere of contentment, the
                            fragrance of love, the sweet influences of all kind and gentle attentions. We should avoid
                            even the appearance of evil. Conquer and subdue ourselves, so that we will not be slaves to
                            appetite, neither to passion nor ambition. Sever every partial, selfish tie, and. cultivate
                            a broad, universal love instead. We as Christ's followers are invited to do this. Do not let
                            us deceive ourselves with the thought that we can retrace our steps at any time; but rather
                            let us keep in the narrow way, and the power to restrain the evil, and to cultivate the good
                            then lies within ourselves. Let us ever listen to the quiet mentor who will not lead astray
                            and obey each better impulse until we gain complete supremacy over evil. Bouih Union,
                        Ky.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Valley of silence" TEIform="index"/>THE VALLEY OF SILENCE</head><p TEIform="p">I walk down the Valley of Silence, Down the dim, voiceless valley alone, And I hear not the
                            sound of a footstep Around me, but God's and my own ; And the hush of my heart is as holy As
                            hovers where angels have flown. Long ago was I weary of voices Whose music my soul could not
                            win ; Long ago was I weary of noises That fretted my soul with their din ; Long ago was I
                            weary of places Where I met but the human and sin. I walked in the world with the worldly,
                            Yet I craved what the world never gave ; And I said, in the world each ideal That shines
                            like a star on life's wave, Is toned on the shores of the real, And sleeps like a dream in
                            the grave. And still did I pine for the perfect, And still found the false with the true ; I
                            sought 'mid the human of Heaven, And caught a mere glimpse of its blue ; And I sighed when
                            the clouds of the mortal Veiled even that glimpse from my view. And I toiled on, heart-tired
                            of the human, And groaned 'mid the masses of men ; Till I knelt long ago at an altar, And
                            heard a voice call me. Since then I walked down the Valley of Silence That lies far beyond
                            human ken. Do you ask what I found in the Valley ? 'Tis my trysting-place with the Divine ;
                            And I fell at the feet of the Holy, And around me a voice said, '' Be Mine ! " Then arose
                            from the depths of my soul An echo, " My heart shall be Thine." Do you ask how I live in the
                            Valley ? I weep and I dream and I pray; But my tears are as sweet as the dew-drops That fall
                            on the roses in May; And my prayers like a perfume from censer, Ascend eth to God night and
                            day. In the hush of the Valley of Silence I hear all the songs that I sing ; And the music
                            floats down the dim Valley Till each finds a word for a wing ; That to men like the doves of
                            the deluge The message of peace they may bring. But far on the deep there are billows That
                            never shall break on the beach, And I have heard songs in the silence That never shall float
                            into speech, And I have had dreams in the Valley Too lofty for language to reach. And I have
                            seen thoughts in the Valley— Ah, me ! how my spirit was stirred ! They wear holy veils on
                            their faces; Their footsteps can scarcely be heard; They pass down the Valley like virgins,
                            Too pure for the touch of a word. Do you ask me the place of this Valley, To hearts that are
                            harrowed by care ? It lieth afar between mountains, And God and his angels are there; And
                            one is the dark mount of sorrow, And one bright mountain of prayer.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ryan, [Father]" TEIform="persName"/>Father Ryan, of Mobile</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Unpardonable sin" TEIform="index"/>UNPARDONABLE SIN</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p">Sin against law is one thing; there is the letter in black and white, and there is the
                            penalty. When the penalty is paid the sin is forgiven. Sin against conscience—religious
                            conviction—is another thing, and is not to be condoned or forgiven by law-makers in this
                            world, nor in the next world by the same law-makers. It is a sin against the holy spirit of
                            truth itself. Death to, in separation from the sinning spirit—change of heart producing <pb n="198" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 198 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. change of character—can alone free the soul
                            from its blighting effect. Then the unpardonable sin goes with the old man, who with his
                            ungodly deeds has been put off.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How shall Sunday be used?" TEIform="index"/>HOW SHALL SUNDAY BE USED?</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Simply as a day of rest it meets a most imperative want. Our American life is at
                                    the best too hurried and feverish. We waste our strength in over-exertion. We burn
                                    the candle at both ends and in the middle, and reap our reward in such a harvest of
                                    nervous disorders as was never known elsewhere. From the too eager strain and stress
                                    of the week Sunday offers a blessed relief. Its rest is incomplete unless the wanted
                                    current of ideas, as well as occupations, is interrupted. A. first and obvious
                                    principle therefore to get away from the habitual activities of the other six days,
                                    however good they may be in themselves. A teacher, for example, should as a general
                                    thing not teach on Sunday, but let the mind relax wholly from the attitude of
                                    instruction. So, a man who works his brain all the week can rarely afford to listen
                                    on Sunday to a sermon which keenly stimulates thought, though a service of beautiful
                                    and hearty worship may rest and refresh him. To say that no general rules can be
                                    laid down in such matters is obvious ; the harder and more important thing is for
                                    each one to recognize that for him there is a good rule attainable, dependent on his
                                    character and circumstances, and that it is his business first to find it out and
                                    then to be faithful to it. Most people are very willing to take Sunday as a day of
                                    rest, and resent any encroachment on their own rest. But the day has a higher
                                    function. It ought to give moral guidance and impulse to the week. It is the time to
                                    take a large and calm view of one's life ; to see what its real objects are ; what
                                    are its temper and spirit. Much of the time we are so absorbed in the details of
                                    living that we forget to ask whether it is all tending. The fault of most lives is
                                    not that they are consciously directed to bad or low ends, but that they have no
                                    distinct end in view ; they are merely drifting. We do a thing to-day because we did
                                    it yesterday. We earn our bread because otherwise we should go hungry or starve. We
                                    live from hand to mouth. Now, it is good that we should often stop a little while —
                                    once in seven days is seldom enough — and ask ourselves, " What real gain am I
                                    making ? Am I growing in true worth, in manhood, in sincerity, in sweetness of
                                    temper ? Am I getting the better of sensuality, of indolence, of surliness, of
                                    whatever is the worse part of me ? What am I adding to the community ; what other
                                    lives are brighter because of mine ? " It is good to look at our own life in its
                                    serious and noble aspect; to be humble before its deficiencies ; to set our firmest
                                    will toward better living ; to take a deep and thankful and trustful sense of a
                                    higher power helping us in our infirmities. Such hours as this, if they are
                                    habitual, will shape the course of our lives. True, we constantly fall short of our
                                    own aspiration and purpose. But to have the aspiration and purpose to hold to it, to
                                    constantly recur to it — this is every thing. What we really want to be, what we
                                    seek to be, that we shall be. Jesus said, not only " Blessed are the pure in heart,
                                    the merciful, the peace-makers," but " Blessed are they that do hunger and thirst
                                    after righteousness "— Tightness of life — " for they shall be filled." Paul wrote :
                                    " Whatsoever things are true, honest, just, pure, lovely, of good report — think on
                                    these things." To think on them, to long for them, will bring us to seek and find
                                    them.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Springfield republican" TEIform="index"/>Springfield Republican.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bible reading" TEIform="index"/>BIBLE READING</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lamson, William" TEIform="persName"/>REV. WILLIAM LAMSON, D. D.</byline><p TEIform="p">One of the most interesting and hopeful features of the present revival work is the attention
                            that is given to the Bible. Public Bible-readings are a new and blessed means employed. God
                            honors those who put honor on His Word. But let us for a little turn attention to private,
                            personal reading of the Scriptures. How, where the Scriptures are not wholly neglected, are
                            they used ? It is the practice with some to take the Bible at some time every day and read
                            one or more chapters wherever it chances to open. Sup- <pb n="199" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. 199 pose the student of any other text-book thus to treat it. One wishes to
                            become acquaint ed with the history of the United States" and having furnished himself with
                            Ban" croft's History, he takes an hour every day to devote to it, and having taken up one of
                            its volumes he lets it open where it will, and then reads so many pages as a task, pursuing
                            this course from the first to the last day of the year. How much will he have learned of the
                            history of his country in that way ? Others make a practice of reading the entire Bible
                            through every year, beginning with the first chapter of Genesis on the first day of January,
                            and closing the book of Revela. tion on the last day of December. I read recently of one who
                            for years readjust thirty chapters every day in his Bible. For all the purposes of biblical
                            knowledge he might probably just as well have read thirty pages in Webster's Dictionary. But
                            how shall we use the Bible ? That is, how shall the ordinary Christian, merchant or mechanic
                            use his Bible, so as to be profited by it ? Mr. Moody has preached a sermon on this topic,
                            and it lias been published as a tract. It contains some useful hints and lessons, and we
                            wish it might be extensively read. One important suggestion is that the Bible be studied
                            topically. Take, for instance, the topic of prayer. With a good Concordance or with only a
                            reference Bible, let one sit down to learn the Bible teaching on prayer. He would not
                            exhaust the sub ject at one sitting. But when he had completed the search, what a f and of
                            most precious knowledge he will have acquired. More valuable information he would get by
                            this one study than by reading the Bible through yearly for three-score years. Or take
                            heaven as a topic, and go through the Bible gather, ing all its teaching on that topic. And
                            so of forgiveness, love, faith, the topics are numerous and every one precious. A good
                            reference Bible is invaluable to one who would " search the Scriptures." A number of years
                            since an intelligent lad among my people thought he had become a Christian. In talking with
                            him on his evidences, I said, " Do you love prayer ? " " O yes," was the prompt reply. " Do
                            you love the Bible ? " He hesitated, and then said, " I do not think I do." I loved his
                            frankness. " But," said I, " how do you read the Bible?" It was near the beginning of the
                            year, and with the new year he began to read the Bible in course, and he had then reached
                            Leviticus, and was conscientiously reading so many chapters every day, and vexing his soul
                            because he found no enjoyment in it. Because he found more pleasure in reading Harper's
                            MontMy than in reading the record of Jewish statutes, he doubted his piety.— The
                        Watchman.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New ways in religion" TEIform="index"/>THE NEW WAYS IN RELIGION</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Lombard, I. K." TEIform="persName"/>I. K. LOMBARD</byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">To-day I've been to meeting, John, To hear the parson preach, But how they've
                                    changed since we were young In all they do and teach. They say that we're old
                                    fashioned, John, And don't care what we say ; But my old heart can see and feel
                                    Whene'er they change God's way. When we were young the world was gay, And loved to
                                    make a show ; But Christians walked the narrow way, We could not with them go ; But
                                    oh, how things have changed since then, The two ways are but one ; They all go in
                                    together now, And say they've " lots of fun." When we were young and used to meet In
                                    our old kitchen room, And sometimes in the school-house near, If many chanced to
                                    come ; And Elder B-----, that good old man,— I'll ne'er forget his voice,— How
                                    faithfully he dealt with sin, And how the saints rejoiced. But now they meet in
                                    palaces, So gorgeous, rich and nice ; And every thing that draws the crowd, They'll
                                    have at any price ; With cushioned seats and carpetings, And everything so gay, The
                                    poor can hardly gather there,— They've not the scrip to pay, The minister, like some
                                    vain fop, Stands up and reads his prayers ; And how it pained my heart to-day To see
                                    him " put on airs." He did not preach, he only read An essay in Christ's voice ; No
                                    heart was touched, no tears were shed, And not a soul rejoiced. <pb n="200" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 200 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. He thought Christ's voice was musical, Melodious, rich
                                    and clear. And thus it sounded pleasantly Upon the listening ear. I heard some say
                                    as they passed out, " Wasn't that a splendid thing ? " And another said, " That
                                    can't be beat By even Dr. Tyng." 0 can it be that such vain fops Are called to speak
                                    for God, Who feed the Church on worldly slops, But never preach his Word ? 1 thought
                                    if Christ himself were there, We'd see some sighs and tears ; "Ye Pharisees and
                                    hypocrites," Would thunder in their ears, I thought of our old kitchen times, When
                                    servants sent by God Would warn us all so faithfully To love and keep his Word. They
                                    did not wink at worldliness, As ministers now do ; O give me back the olden ways, I
                                    do not like the new. A hoarse machine now grinds their tunes, A godless choir joins
                                    in, But neither one can tell of joys That come from pardoned sin. They sang God's
                                    praise when we were young Because their hearts were blest ; A well-paid choir now
                                    chants their songs, And so the Church has rest. My heart was pained to see the show
                                    They tried to make in dress, All nnified from top to toe, And some look like
                                    distress. With frills and flounces, tucks and crimps, They seemed almost deformed;
                                    And many had the Grecian bend, With camel's hump all formed. They noticed my plain
                                    calico, And thought my bonnet '• odd ; " And frequently they smiled, I know, But I
                                    had peace with God. I thought of times when we were young, When all the proud and
                                    gay Would make the Christian's dress their song, And jest them every way. 'Tis sad,
                                    when all the world runs mad In foolish, vain display, To see the Church so fast and
                                    glad To ape them every way. The Church has changed since former days In all they say
                                    and do ; But give me back the olden ways, I do not like the new. They're strangely
                                    bent on pleasure now ; They meet most every week To have some sort of lively spree,
                                    That worldlings love and seek. But whether 'tis a festival, Or sociable, or fair. Or
                                    Christmas tree, or other scrape, The Church will all be there. With lotteries and
                                    grab-bags, And other tricks and games, They make God's house a den of thieves,
                                    Without a blush of shame ! Lord of the temple, come with zeal, As thou didst come of
                                    yore, With scourge in hand to make them feel, Before their day is o'er. They all
                                    attend such gatherings, But when they meet to pray, There are but few who venture
                                    out, And they've not much to say. They lightly speak of former days, When Christian
                                    men were true ; But give me back the olden ways, I do not like the new. What means
                                    this strange departure, John, And when will they amend ? God's day of wrath is
                                    hastening on, When all earth's shams will end. That awful hour is drawing near ; Its
                                    signs are gathering fast ; The judge of all will soon be here, To scrutinize the
                                    past. Our record then will be made known, Our habits, thoughts and aims ; And some
                                    must hear from God's own throne " You've brought my cause to shame." Ah! then what
                                    grief and sore regret Will reach them in that day, Because they've chosen
                                    worldliness, And scoffed at God's old way.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Yates County chronicle" TEIform="index"/>Yates County Chronicle.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Influence of religion" TEIform="index"/>THE INFLUENCE OF RELIGION</head><p TEIform="p">People talk about religion being a restraint upon men. In some senses, it is a restraint. But
                            this is not its chief idea. There are in men certain destructive tendencies,— passions,
                            appetites and inordinate affections which need the curb; and religion operates as a curb
                            upon these and reins them in. But it has other and larger uses than this. Feters and cords
                            and gags do not represent it. It plants more than it uproots. When the work of correction is
                            ended, it has only just Degun its operations in the soul — operations which will continue in
                            force eternally. Negatives do not express religious duty. We ove to think that religious
                            life means the <pb n="201" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 201 growth of all the faculties,
                            and not a slowstrangulation of them. Religion no more cramps a man than wings do a bird, or
                            fins do a fish. Piety is not a ship at anchor on a level sea ; it is a ship in motion, with
                            every sail set and swelling with wind and the waters around it crested with white.
                            Christianity makes a man active, vibrant, intense. Great injury has been done religion by
                            teaching people to regard it as a mild form of slavery, in which people consent to be tied
                            up that they may not hurt themselves nor others. But there is no such religion as this, at
                            least in the New Testament. The gospel Christ taught, is a gospel of liberty. It is a
                            stimulant to man's energies, not a narcotic. It makes him a doer, not a hearer.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="William Penn's words of truth and soberness" TEIform="index"/>WILLIAM PENN'S WORDS OF TRUTH
                            AND SOBERNESS</head><p TEIform="p">Sin is of one nature all the world over ; for though a liar is not a drunkard, nor swearer a
                            thief, nor either properly a murderer; yet they are all of a church; all branches of the one
                            wicked root; all of kin. They have but one father, the devil, as Christ said to the
                            professing Jews, the visible church of that age. He slighted their pretensions to Abraham
                            and Moses, and plainly told them, he that committed sin, was the servant of sin. They did
                            the devil's work, and therefore were the devil's children. The argument will always hold
                            upon the same reasons, and therefore is good still. " His servants you are," saith Paul,
                            "whom you obey;" and, saith John to the church of old : " Let no man deceive you; he that
                            committeth sin, is of the devil." Was Judas a better Christian for crying, Hail, Master !
                            and kissing Christ ? By no means. These words were the signal of his treachery ; the token
                            given by which the bloody Jews should know and take Him. He called Him Master, but betrayed
                            Him. He kissed, but sold Him to be killed. This is the upshot of the false Christians'
                            religion. If a man ask them, Is Christ your Lord? they will cry: "God forbid else. Yes, He
                            is our Lord." " Very well; but do you keep His commandments?" " No, how should we ? " " How
                            then are you His disciples ?" " It is impossible," say they. "What! would you have us to
                            keep His commandments ? No man can." Indeed ! is it impossible to do that, without which
                            Christ hath made it impossible to be a Christian ? Is Christ unreasonable ? Does He reap
                            where He has not bowd ; require where He has not enabled t Let no man deceive his own soul ;
                            " grapes are not gathered of thorns, nor figs of thistles : " a wolf is not a sheep, nor is
                            a vulture a dove. Whatever form, people, or church thou art of, it is the truth of God to
                            mankind, that they who have the form of godliness, but by their unmortified lives deny the
                            power thereof, make not the true, hut the false church : which, though she entitle herself
                            the Lamb's bride, or Church of Christ, is in very deed that mystery of Babylon, fitly called
                            by the Holy Ghost, " the mother of harlots, and all abominations." True it is, they that are
                            born of the flesh, hate and persecute them that are born of the Spirit, who are the
                            circumcision in heart. They cannot own nor worship God after Babylon's inventions, methods
                            and prescriptions, nor receive for doctrine her vain traditions, any more than they can
                            comply with her corrupt fashions and customs in their conversation. The case being thus, the
                            false church becomes a persecutor of the true church. It is not enough that Babylon, or the
                            false church, declines from ancient purity ; others must do so too. She will give those no
                            rest, who will not partake with her in that degeneracy, or receive her mark. * * * * So that
                            though the unrighteous latitude of their lives be matter of lamentation, as it is of
                            destruction to themselves, yet the false notion, that they are the children of God, while in
                            a state of disobedience to His holy commandments, and disciples of Jesus, though they revolt
                            from His cross, and members of His true church, which is without spot or wrinkle,
                            notwithstanding their lives are full of spots and wrinkles—this sad notion I say is, of all
                            deceptions upon themselves, the most pernicious to their eternal condition. For they are at
                            peace in sin, and under a security in their transgression. Their vain hope silences their
                            convictions, and overlays <pb n="202" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 202 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. all tender
                            motions to repentance: so that their mistake about their duty to God is as mischievous as
                            their rebellion against Him.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cruel libel" TEIform="index"/>A CRUEL LIBEL</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Devyr, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/>CECELIA DEVYR</byline><p TEIform="p">Perhaps the newspapers we should forgive— They need much charity on slander's score— And
                            we're persuaded that subscribers live On just such product as their columns store; But
                            there's one slander that disturbs and harrows — It came to us on bitter wintry air — It was
                            a libel on our friendly sparrows, 'Twas unprovoked, uncivil and unfair. It was a bold and
                            merciless assertion, That sparrows killed or banished birds of song ; It filled the land
                            with ignorant aversion, And who will trace the workings of that wrong! Of honest character
                            such defamation Put forth in malice, or but done in sport, Should rouse the justice of a
                            liberal nation, And have a hearing in the Highest Court. But we recall that once was
                            judgment given, That made us all that Court's decree suspect ; It was about a race that
                            prayed to heaven, That had no rights that Christians need respect ! Well, then there was a
                            wondrous change of benches, Although the people did not go to Court, But took themselves to
                            gunboats and to trenches, And then to capturing citadel and fort. It always seemed like
                            madness to the Shakers, That they so many thousand men must kill. To teach officials they
                            were not law-makers, Nor had they rights above the people's will, And now it seems to us a
                            wondrous pity. Its heights and depths cannot be drawn in words, That goose-quills nurtured
                            only in a city, With sharpened points should scrawl about the birds. What can they know ?
                            The ancient hissing gander In whose tough pinions they were far from loose, Was hatched out
                            in a town whose air was slander, And by a mother, known to be a goose. But in our home the
                            libel soon was ended, And from experience praise could fill the theme, The twittering tribe
                            that we mid storm befriended, Most worthy of our kindly love we deem. They came to us as
                            shivering, hungry strangers, Of bad report, and yet we took them in. And from that day these
                            outlawed little rangers, Have never ceased our confidence to win. The spring and summer had
                            their old-time singing. The door-yard trees their quaint and quiet nests; While brilliant
                            birds their joyous flight were winging. All unmolested by our russet guests. They took a
                            birds-eye view with this conclusion; " Earth's the Lord's, and so to us is free, We'll own
                            our houses — that will save confusion, And for our living all work faithfully," So we refute
                            the charge of goose Quill's making And do espouse the humble sparrows' cause, We would be
                            sure millennial day was breaking If men were governed by such righteous laws. Mt. Lebanon,
                            N. F.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True religion! what is it? no. 1" TEIform="index"/>TRUE RELIGION! WHAT IS IT? No. 1</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, G. B." TEIform="persName"/>G. B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p">James, the Apostle of Jesus, said,"pure religion, and undefiled before God the Father is
                            this, to visit the widow and fatherless, and keep one's self unspotted from the world." To
                            do something, not merely to believe something, not simply to believe that Jesus did all the
                            work of salvation for sinners ! Thus, salvation from sin, by living as Jesus lived, is made
                            to mean expiation for sin, by believing that Jesus did good things ! How is such salvation
                            possibly compatible with the kind of salvation Jesus came to institute, if souls continue to
                            sin while professedly believing in Jesus? for, it is written, " His name shall be called
                            Jesus, i. e., Saviour, for he shall save his people from their sins." " If any man be in
                            Christ, he is a newcreature ; old things are done away and all things are become new, and
                            all things of God." Here is the fruit of spiritual toil, something done ! "No man having
                            drunken old wine straightway desireth new, for he saith the old is better," said Jesus, but,
                            in religion, or religious belief, men would keep <pb n="203" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. 203 on drinking the old wine ; that is, in the present time, taking precepts for
                            a guide of life which belonged to dispensations done away, when Jesus introduced the Kingdom
                            of Heaven on earth. " When that which is perfect is come, then that which is in part (only)
                            shall he done away." But, mankind substitute conventional institutions — the creeds and
                            dogmas made by councils—for religion, and call things by wrong names,— Salvation from sin,
                            is made to mean expiation or apology for sin. Religion, is made to mean belief in what Jesus
                            did, instead of doing the works he did ! Love is made to mean a mere heat of the blood — a
                            passional, animal attraction to an individual of opposite sex. True loie is a holy soul
                            flame pure as sunlight, and reaches out to all humanity. Affection is made to mean the mere
                            operations of the nerves,—the elimination of attachment which passion institutes ; but, true
                            affection is that soul-felt interest in the well-being of another, which is ready to
                            sacrifice self-interest, ease, pleasure and gain, for another's happiness, and unwilling to
                            mar that happiness by any means. "If within the sophisticated man there is not an
                            unsophisticated one he is simply one of Satan's emissaries."</p></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Can we object to competition?" TEIform="index"/>CAN WE OBJECT TO THE COMPETITION?</head><p TEIform="p">It is amusing to see the tables turned in this way, as described by the New York Tribune : "
                            The heathen are organizing foreign missions for the conversion of Christians. The Hindus of
                            the sacred city of Benares have founded a society for the propagation of Brahminism among
                            the Christians of Australia. An eminent Brahmin of the name of Suradschi, a man of great
                            authority, has recently been visiting some of the English colonies, and while traveling in
                            Australia, was appalled and grieved at the fearful prevalence of drunkenness among the
                            Christians. On returning to India he called together a number of thoughtful Brahmins, to
                            whom he communicated his glowing zeal to do something for the salvation of their degraded
                            fellow-men and fellow-subjects in Australia. The only perfect remedy, he considered, would
                            be the conversion of these Christians to a better and purer faith. A large sum was collected
                            for the pious and benevolent enterprise, and some of the Brahmins declared their willingness
                            to devote themselves to the work, and to spend and be spent in this humane and holy cause.
                            Suradschi is now engaged in translating fitting passages from the Vedas into the English
                            tongue, for the use of the missionaries."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Socrates' faith" TEIform="index"/>SOCRATES' FAITH</head><p TEIform="p">This grand man had abiding faith in immortality. In a conversation shortly before his death
                            he said : " Then Cebes, beyond question, the soul is immortal and imperishable and our souls
                            will truly exist in another world ? (Plato : Phcedo, 106.) Other expressions of Socrates
                            mainly from the same conversation, are not less emphatic and significant : * * * When death
                            attacks a man the mortal portion of him may be supposed to die, but the immortal goes out of
                            the way of death and is preserved safe and sound. (Plato: Phcedo, 107.) * * * But then, O my
                            friends, if the soul is really immortal, what care should be taken of her, not only in
                            respect of the portion of time which is called life, but of eternity! (Plato: Phcedo, 107.)
                            And can we suppose that the soul being invisible and on her way to a place like herself
                            invisible and pure, a world worthy indeed the name of the Unseen, there to dwell with the
                            good and wise God — whether, if God please, my soul must soon go * * * will, when released
                            from the body, be instantly scattered to the wind and destroyed, as the mass of men assert
                            1" (Plato: Phoedo, 81.) If, upon her release, the soul be found pure and free from all that
                            appertains to the body * * * she goes to the world which is invisible like herself ; to the
                            world divine and immortal and full of thought; there set free from error, folly, fears and
                            the fierce passions and other evils of humanity, her lot is a happy one indeed * * * but if,
                                <pb n="204" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 204 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. on her release, she be found unclean
                            and polluted by her intercourse with the body * * * do you think that a soul in this
                            condition will be found pure and uncontaminated when she is set free? " (Phcedo, 81.)</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Abominable headgears" TEIform="index"/>"ABOMINABLE HEADGEARS."</head><p TEIform="p">The abominable style of dresses and headgears now worn by women are too immodest to mention,
                            yet professing Christians run after them with the zeal of a turkey after a grasshopper. If
                            an angel from heaven, dressed in plain white, without ruffles, flounces, trails, and
                            ornamented head-cover, was suddenly to drop among some Christian congregations nine-tenths
                            would vote for its speedy ejectment, because it is not in the fashion. Very well, anangel
                            will thrust in the sickle of death some of these times, and then these devoted
                            clothes-worshippers will send up a wail of despair too fearful for mortal ears. We class
                            this clothes religion with drunkenness and all other pernicious vices. It is tolerated
                            simply because popular. It is sin, and we have no patience with sin.—Brethren at Work.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Inquisition" TEIform="index"/>THE INQUISITION</head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Massachusetts, Ayer, August 14, 1879" TEIform="index"/>Ayer, Mass., Aug. 14, 1879</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Brother and Editor : Thoughts of the priestly invasion of American's boasted freedom
                            gave me a restless night. We now realize that we have the inquisition restored with all the
                            rigors that our attained civilization will permit. We have nothing better to expect of the
                            clergy — the God-in-the-constitution advocates. They challenge a man's right to doubt,but to
                            believe, every falsehood that ever cursed the earth and man, that is a virtue though it
                            prove a curse to both soul and body. It is not the " faithful believers " that have advanced
                            the world. History tells us it is to the doubters — the "infidels"— that the world owes the
                            greatest debt of gratitude. They never persecute nor kill, nor trample upon,but uplift
                            the.fallen; give sight to the blind, whose eyes are filled with the dust of tradition, and
                            whose minds are warped, and dwarfed by creeds and professions of faith. We had hoped
                            something better than a subsided president bowing reverently to the dictum of church
                            authority. So much at random. Now for what I intended to say when I took pen in hand. Can
                            you see Bennett and say a kind and sympathetic word to him ? How do the warden and officers
                            treat him ? Influence them if possible, to treat him kindly, as a noble human being which he
                            is. Who knows but some of us will be behind the bars ?</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, E." TEIform="persName"/>E. Myrick</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To-day" TEIform="index"/>TO-DAY</head><p TEIform="p">We are living, we are dwelling In a grand and awful time, In an age on ages telling To be
                            living is sublime. Hark ! the waking up of nations, Gog and Magog to the fray. Hark ! what
                            soundeth ? Is creation Groaning for her latter day ? Will ye play, then, will ye dally, With
                            your music and your wine ? Up ! it is Jehovah's rally, God's own arm hath need of thine.
                            Hark ! the onset! will ye fold your Faith-clad arms in lazy lock ? Up, O, up ! thou drowsy
                            soldier, Worlds are charging to the shock. Worlds are charging — heaven beholding, Thou hast
                            but an hour to fight; Now the blazoned cross unfolding, On, right onward, to the right; On !
                            let all the soul within you For the truth's sake go abroad! Strike ! let every nerve and
                            sinew Tell on ages — tell for God!</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Union" TEIform="index"/>UNION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prentiss, Oliver" TEIform="persName"/>OLIVER PRENTISS</byline><p TEIform="p">" Our union is our strength," is one of the sage maxims of the early believers in the gospel
                            of our mother Ann Lee. When, on the 6th of April, 1820, I found the Shakers—all new to me—I
                            said to them, I have come some out of my way and would like to know what you are about iere.
                            They gave me to understand that they de- <pb n="205" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 205
                            nied the flesh in all its ramifications; as sister and brother lived pure virgin lives, and
                            had all things in common. The sayings surprised me. I said: But where do you get the power ?
                            other folk can't live so. In a quiet way they informed me that where many minds combine
                            together, for a certain purpose, like a galvanic battery, they form a strong current,
                            supporting each other." " Our union is our strength." No need to tell me that, for union,
                            and in union, we must revolve around a common centre, with as much fidelity as planets in
                            general. "Love is all the gospel treasure that our , souls can ever find— This is given
                            without measure, if in love we are combined." Let us have union in the gospel treasurer —at
                            any—at all sacrifice—Amen.</p></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gospel wit, but truths, nevertheless" TEIform="index"/>GOSPEL WIT, BUT TRUTHS, NEVERTHELESS</head><p TEIform="p">Shop girls recognize a lady by her manners and not by her dress. It has been remarked that,
                            however hard the times, " the wages of sin" have never been cut down. Bob Ingersoll ^hinks
                            that if there should happen to be such a place, the tormentors of the poor Southern negroes
                            will have the hottest corner of it. " Don't show my letters," wrote a young man to a young
                            lady. " Don't be afraid," was the reply ; " I am just as much ashamed of them as you are."
                            An agricultural paper advises the farmer to count his sheep every day. If it comes to that
                            we should advise the farmer to move into a better neighborhood. " Bub, did you ever stop to
                            think," said a grocer recently, as he measured out half a peck of potatoes, "that these
                            potatoes contain sugar, water and starch?" " Noa, I didn't," replied the boy, " but I heard
                            mother say you put peas and beans in your coffee and about a pint of water in every quart of
                            milk you sold." The subject of natural philosophy was dropped right there. We have no
                            confidence in cross Christianity. It is not the Christianity of the cross ; and it denies
                            the Master as openly and effectually as did Peter when he said, " I know not the man."
                            Paupers suffer less than mizers do — the man who don't kno whar he iz going to get hiz next
                            dinner, suffers less than the one who iz anxious to kno how much it iz going to kost him. —
                            Billings. Some robbers, having broken into a gentleman's house, went to the bed of the
                            servant, and told him if he moved he was a dead man. " That's a falsehood," said he, '* for
                            if I move, I'm sure that I'm alive." A touching story is told of a little New Haven child,
                            who, having received a " reward of merit card " from her teacher, held it up toward the sky
                            all the way home that her dead father might see how good she had been. A young candidate for
                            admission to one of our colleges was severely taken to task by his father for failing in the
                            previous examination, to whom he replied that he gave a correct answer to every question. It
                            turned out that his answer to every question was, "i don't know." Rev. Mr. Hubbell was
                            riding on the New Haven road with a brother clergyman. On the train passing through Milford,
                            the brother clergyman observed: "I used to preach in that place. That was sometime ago. I
                            learn that the church is now used for an onion depot." " In which case it probably sheds
                            more tears than it did then," solemnly suggested the Danbury pastor. The brother clergyman
                            sank into a profound reverie.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Key to church unions" TEIform="index"/>The Key to Church Unions</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Beecher, Thomas K." TEIform="persName"/>The Rev. Thomas K. Beecher</byline><p TEIform="p">writes : "I have noted that theories, philosophies, theologies' and even sciences change.
                            Churches, rituals and usages change. But I detect one fact and one testimony that never has
                            changed and never will. I believe in the Lord Jesus Christ, and am at rest. Nothing shall
                            separate me from the love of God, which is in Christ Jesus, my Lord.</p></div2><pb n="206" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Exactions of true Christianity" TEIform="index"/>EXACTIONS OF TRUE CHRISTIANITY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Eadical Christianity, while granting to every individual the rights of free agency—to
                                choose to be Christians or to refuse so to be—is yet full of aggressions upon the
                                worldly affections of those who accept of and obey its radical commands. True, it
                                teaches non-resistance to those who profess it; yet it demands of them resistance, even
                                to violence, against temptations toward worldly inclinations. It sets its adherents at
                                variance with worldly institutions and relations ; and is a sword, to the severing from
                                true Christian lives, the dearest relations that a worldly mind can imagine. It requires
                                a constant warfare with inclinations, that are however good after a worldly estimation,
                                or however affectionate to the heart unchastened by Christian law; and bids a denial to
                                the most sacred and honored of worldly associations. Its demands are significant of an
                                entire relinquishment of personal property or individual gains, and of a complete
                                self-consecration to the most unselfish employments. To those .just starting in life,
                                full of hopes, aspirations, and determinations to have and enjoy a surfeit of this
                                world's pleasure, even after the most approved dictation of the moral laws, radical
                                Christianity says, if they would be its disciples, they must forsake all these, and
                                follow the Master. To every young man and woman who hears its voice, and makes it a
                                practical profession, it speaks today, as plainly and significantly, as did Jesus to the
                                young Jew of old : " Gro sell all that thou hast, then come and follow me /" To them it
                                sends out invitations to deny themselves of the relations of marriage—of being husbands
                                and wives, fathers and mothers, having children, and private property to sustain
                                these—and to choose rather, the virgin estate of Jesus, the Christ! To them it says:
                                "Deny yourselves of an entrance upon the arena of worldly indulgences, and choose rather
                                a life of superior spirituality, as far apart from all selfish loves and lusts as was
                                the Christ's." To those who have been and are entangled in the maelstrom and snares of
                                generative, fleshly, selfpleasing and self-seeking associations, radical Christianity
                                demands as credentials of fellowship, a dissolution of even the appearance of these, and
                                offers as a substitute the angelic relations of the superior world, where they "neither
                                marry nor are given in marriage," where heavenly, and the purest of virgin loves and
                                lives are engaged in. It offers as a superior inducement to selfish loves, and1
                                exertions for earthly emoluments and property for self, an opportunity to die unto
                                selfishness by working from a love of nobler principles and pure philanthropy, and from
                                an affection for the fruits of selfdenial, for the best interests and most exalted
                                conditions of all humanity. However radical Christianity is and has ever been, and it is
                                very radical if it is the religion of Jesus—no excuses in it for selfish loves nor
                                relations —no pandering in it to the fleshly indulgences to which humanity is prone —yet
                                it forces itself upon no one. It gives license to any and all to sow just what they
                                please, and then makes them welcome to reap the rewards of the %ftitoxinl. <pb n="207" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 207 sowing. But it' disowns and denies the commonly
                                implied hope, that souls may sow to the flesh and to selfish loves and lusts, and that
                                Jesus or any other will or can relieve or excuse them from the consequences. It does
                                however contain exactions that are peremptory upon those who would be really and truly
                                followers after the life of the Master, Jesus, the Christ. It does say: " You may marry,
                                be husbands and wives, fathers and mothers, have property, go to war, and otherwise be
                                children of the world; but in none of these are you Christians, nor followers after
                                Christ. And if you would be Christians deny yourselves of all these, then come and
                                follow Christ." Radical Christianity admits that the order of life lived by the children
                                of the world may be, and properly lived, is good. Yet it presents the letter and the
                                best as superior substitutes for all it asks any to forsake. It does ask for many
                                denials to selfishness—it does not propose suppressions—but it invariably supplants this
                                with something superior every time. The vast majority have determined for themselves
                                that it is asking too much of them, when invited to be followers of
                                Christ—Christians—-by living his life, and a mere profession of faith covers all their
                                obligations, while their worldly associations, lives, and aspirations for the future,
                                find no similarity nor sympathy with Christ's life. And they are not Christians. "
                                Unless men and women deny themselves as I have denied myself" said the Christian Leader,
                                Christ Jesus, " they are not Christians—they cannot be my disciples ! " Such is the
                                kindness of Christianity that it says: " Whosoever will be my disciple, let him ; " and
                                such is its decisive conclusion, that whosoever wills not to be a disciple, nor live the
                                self-denying life of Jesus, they are welcome to their choice, their reward; but they are
                                not Christians, and can have no part with them. Christianity is aggressive ; but only to
                                the worldly loves and lives of those who, having named the name of Christ, should
                                therefore depart from all iniquity.</p></div3><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>NOTES</head><div4 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sensation about Hebrews" TEIform="index"/>THE SENSATION ABOUT HEBREWS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">" Grod is no respecter of persons; " but He is of characters, and in His dealings
                                    with humanity will make this thoroughly understood. For any human being in this
                                    intelligent age to attempt to stir up a spirit of caste, merely and solely upon the
                                    grounds of nationalities or religious persuasions, is worse than foolish, and very
                                    reasonably merits the censure, odium, and disgust, of all fair-minded humanity who
                                    have the least milk of human kindness yet remaining in their souls. Such was the
                                    opinion of the grand majority, when, last year, the very inferior, puerile Hilton
                                    refused human civilities to a noble Jew ; and now another miserable, rich man named
                                    Oorbin, is making a very disgusting historical record, by a similar persecution of
                                    those who, as a class, are very much better than he is. He will be severely punished
                                    by the good sense of a right-thinking humanity. Jesus, who became the Christ of His
                                    day, was a Jew; and yet we scarcely ever think of His Hebrew lineage in our extreme
                                    admiration of His beauti- <pb n="208" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> ful character. Had he been an
                                    Irishman, or even an American, it certainly would make no difference to us, so that
                                    He was such an unequaled model of chastity and heavenly nobility.</p></div4><div4 type="shaker-press" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="That 'Midsummer holiday' story" TEIform="index"/>THAT " MIDSUMMER HOLIDAY " STORY</head><p TEIform="p">We hope our people will not be too deeply stirred by the ridiculous, sarcastic and
                                    scurrilous stories that every now and then find their way into type among the trashy
                                    literature of our day. The latest, in a "midsummer monthly," can do but little harm
                                    among those who, having brains, are willing to accord to us even a modicum of common
                                    sense and common courtesy. It will be readily recollected that Dr. J. G. Holland,
                                    the editor of the last scurvy tale, once wrote, that "/ really believe God loves the
                                    Shakers, but I do not think He admires them!" and with such imperfect logic, we can
                                    comfortably conclude that if God only loves us very well, we can risk His
                                    admiration, and endure the unpretty thrusts of Timothy Titcomb and his unscrupulous
                                    lackeys.</p></div4></div3></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Honor where honor is due" TEIform="index"/>"HONOR WHERE HONOR IS DUE."</head><p TEIform="p">We are in very common, and constantly happy receipt, of eulogistic and complimentary letters
                            thanking us for our unselfish labors in behalf of The Manifesto. We want all our own people
                            to know that there is a most energetic and talented sister in our household, whose unselfish
                            and most kind attentions to the details of The Manifesto are deserving of unmeasured praise,
                            and much more. Were it not for her untiring zeal, for her unequaled love for and interest in
                            The Manifesto, neither editor nor publisher would receive the credit we now get from every
                            quarter. It is no easy task to keep the mailing lists all in correct order; nor to direct so
                            perfectly the thousands of copies proceeding from this office. Then there is much copying to
                            be done, and many details too numerous and small to be mentioned, and these are all and
                            faithfully attended to, gratuitously, and during hours that might be used for recreation, by
                            one who chooses to be nameless here ; and yet without such devotion, The Manifesto would not
                            be even what it is in excellence. That our dear friends may know hereafter who to praise and
                            send gifts both earthly and heavenly we will whisper</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Neal, Sarah Ann" TEIform="persName"/>Sarah Ann Neal, Shakers, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="shaker-press" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kind words for us" TEIform="index"/>Kind Words of us</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The Shaker Manifesto for August is a pretty vigorous exponent of Shaker thinking
                                    and doing. It is well for persons of opposite views to acquaint themselves with each
                                    others' thoughts ; and no one can read these earn-, est, eloquent and
                                    self-respectful essays without receiving a wholesome conviction that his particular
                                    " doxy " has not a monopoly of culture and intelligence. However much he may differ
                                    from the opinions expressed., he must admit that they are well expressed. In their
                                    liberality toward women they are in advance of many older societies. The Shaker
                                    Manifesto, Shakers, New York. Sixty cents per annum.</quote></cit><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Woman's words" TEIform="index"/>Woman's Words.</bibl></p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tyndall's champion" TEIform="index"/>Tyndall's Champion.</head><p TEIform="p"> At a late assembly of ministers in Scotland, a proposition was made to pray for Prof.
                            Tyndall. One aged clergyman arose to his feet and exclaimed : " How dare you pray for Prof.
                            Tyndall, whose shoe latches you are unworthy to unloose?" "He is an infidel," cried one. The
                            aged man continued: "I dare not pray for a man whose whole life has been devoted to doing
                            good without a selfish thought, without hope of reward. I dare not pray for one so much
                            better than I am." That old man had caught the spirit of the age — the spirit of the new
                            religion. Tyndall has fired the heaviest shot at the ancient system of selfish and
                            superstitious Christianity; he believes in nothing but what his mind can discern and
                            elucidate from solid principles, and hence — he is an infidel. Let us have more of them. He
                            has done his age more good than this whole generation of clergymen who tell the story of the
                            crucifixion in a way to melt the tender to tears, but have nothing in aid of the trouble and
                            sorrow in their midst.</p></div2><pb n="209" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>The Children's Grotto</head><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ahmo; or, 'there's no such word as fail'" TEIform="index"/>AHMO; OR, "THERE'S NO SUCH
                                WORD AS FAIL" A Chinese Story.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sproat, Grenville T." TEIform="persName"/>Grenville T. Sproat</byline><p TEIform="p">The following story was communicated to the writer by Ah Sing, an intelligent Chinaman of
                                San Francisco, in reply to the request : " Will you give me a specimen of child-lore
                                among the Chinese ? " Little Ahmo lived in Hong Kong, in China. His home was a little
                                hut in the suburbs of the city, overlooking the beautiful bay covered with junks, with
                                dark mountains frowning in the distance. He was a watercarrier, and might be seen every
                                day trudging through the dusty streets of the city, with a pole across his shoulders,
                                from the ends of which dangled two buckets filled with water to sell. Sometimes he would
                                go all day, calling at every house; but nobody wanted to buy, and little Ahmo would not
                                earn a penny to buy his supper that night, and would have to go to bed tired and hungry.
                                One evening, after walking all day through the streets of Hong Kong, and not selling a
                                single penny's worth of water, he came to his hut sad and weary, and sat with his head
                                resting on his knees — when his fosterfather came to the door and looked in upon him. "
                                Why art thou so sad, my son ? " said his foster-father. " Are the birds all flown from
                                the celestial kingdom, and are there no flowers for thee to gather ? Up with thee, and
                                be no longer a loiterer and sluggard! Thou must climb the mountain if thou wouldst reach
                                paradise !" " Father," said little Ahmo, " I am sick and weary of this way of life. All
                                day long have I trod the burning streets of the city, trying to sell a little water. But
                                no one would buy of poor Ahmo! Is there no country on the globe, out of the celestial
                                empire, where one will not have to labor so hard, and fare so ill ? Oh! I would go many
                                miles to reach such a country ! " "Wouldst thou?" said his foster-father. I can tell
                                thee of such a country ; but thou will have to travel far, and climb high to reach it. ¦
                                It is far distant — far beyond the tallest mountains that skirt the celestial kingdom."
                                ¦' Tell me not of its distance! " said Ahmo; " or of the weary miles I must travel to
                                reach it. Show me where it is — direct me on the way, and I will climb rocks and
                                precipices, and scale huge cliffs where the goats never climb, and where the eagle
                                scarcely dares build her nest! Tell me where it is, and I will reach it, though
                                mountains lie between ! " "Come to my hut," said his foster-father; " Come early
                                to-morrow morning, aad I will show thee the way to that beautiful country." Little Ahmo
                                hardly slept a wink that night, thinking of his journey, and the way he should travel on
                                it. "I have never failed yet," he said, " in all I have undertaken, save in this water
                                business of mine ; and that was no fault of mine, seeing that others would not buy. I
                                never failed yet, nor will I. ' There's no such word as fail! ' " So, early the next
                                morning, he was up by the first streak of dawn, and off to his foster-father's house.
                                The old man was ready, and waiting for him, and had prepared a nice basket of rice, and
                                some fruit, for the journey. "Follow me," he said; "thou hast far to go, and thy legs
                                will be weary. Follow me, and I will show thee the country better than this, which is
                                thine by birthright." So away he hastened, and little Ahmo followed him, and he had to
                                walk very fast, for his legs were short, and his foster-father was a great traveler.
                                Away over hills and plains, and through valleys and villages, and across rivers, till
                                they came to the foot of a very tall mountain. " This mountain is high," said his
                                fosterfather ; " the top reaches above the clouds ; wilt thou essay to ascend it ? " " I
                                will do any thing," said Ahmo, " any thing that one like myself has done." " Bravo ! "
                                said his foster-father ; " come on! " Up the mountain they went — up over rocks, and
                                cliffs, and steep precipices, that "gixt ©Mttotx's Cgr0tt0. <pb n="210" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 210
                                THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. seemed walled to heaven —- up, beyond where the goats were
                                feeding, and where they seemed to look upon them with amaze ment—- up, beyond where the
                                eagle built her nest. Sometimes Ahmo's brain grew dizzy, and he thought he must fall;
                                but he clung to the vines on the rocks, and clambered still higher, all the time saying:
                                " There's no such word as fail! " At last they reached the summit of the great mountain,
                                and Ahmo sat down to rest, and his foster-father was seated beside him. " Thou hast done
                                bravely," said his foster-father ; " one trial more and the work is done. Seest thou
                                that cloud resting on the summit of the mountain ? " " I see it," said Ahmo. "Just above
                                that cloud is a beautiful plain ; thou must break the way through it and ascend, and
                                thou wilt come to the country that I told thee of — a country far better and richer than
                                this. But see that thy foot stands firm; for if it slips thou losest thy labor, and thou
                                wilt have to toil still farther." Ahmo ascended the summit, and had his hand on the
                                cloud. He sprang forward to break his way through it; but his foot slipped, and he
                                rolled very far down the mountain. "Certes," said he, getting up and rubbing Ms bruised
                                limbs, " Ahmo, thy name should be called ' Luckless !' Here I am, bruised and sadly
                                lamed, and the worst of it is I must climb all those rugged rocks again. But 'tis no use
                                to fret;" and he started again up the mountain, whistling and singing as he went, "
                                There's no such word as fail! " " Bravo ! " said his foster-father, as he saw him
                                ascending to the top. " Bravo ! " By slip and fall We're wiser all. " Thou wilt reach
                                the beautiful country, I do believe, at last, Bravo ! " Ahmo rested a while, and then
                                the second time he ascended the summit. This time his foot did not slip; but his hand
                                lost its hold, and away he went, toppling over, and down against the rugged sides of the
                                mountain. He was more bruised and lamed than before, and he said, with a wry face, "
                                'Tis a sorry task ! I did not mean to get discouraged, though I broke every bone in my
                                shin ! Yea, it is a very sorry task ! But, cheer up, Ahmo! better luck next time. Only
                                they who strive can win — Winners only wear the crown ; Brave hearts never are cast
                                down." " Ha! not dead yet!" said his fosterfather, as he saw him ascending the mountain
                                the third time. " Thou hast a brave heart, and thou well deservest a rest in the
                                beautiful kingdom. Come with me. Thou needest to make but one more trial, and thou wilt
                                succeed." Ahmo ascended to the summit, the third time ; but now the sky gave way before
                                his hand, and he ascended to a beautiful place the other side of the cloud, where were
                                vineyards, and orange groves, and palaces, and rivers of water, and abundance of fruit.
                                None were poor, tired, nor hungry, neither bending with heavy burdens, as in the dusty
                                Hong Kong streets. And Ahmo became a prince, and was much loved by the lord of the
                                country, and he gave him a kingly robe, and on the robe was written this motto —
                                "There's no such word as fail." Canaan, N. Y.</p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Solomon Ray" TEIform="index"/>SOLOMON RAY</head><p TEIform="p">A hard, close man was Soloman Ray, Nothing of value he gave away ; He hoarded and saved,
                                He pinched and shaved, And the more he had the more he craved. The hard-earned dollar he
                                tried to gain Brought him little but care and pain ; For little he spent, And all he
                                lent He made it bring him twenty per cent. Such was the life of Solomon Ray ; The years
                                went by, and his hair grew gray ; His cheeks grew thin, And his soul within Grew hard as
                                the dollar he worked to win. But he died one day, as all men must, For life is fleeting
                                and men but dust ; The heirs were gay That laid him away, And that was the end of
                                Solomon Ray. They quarreled now who had little cared For Solomon Ray while his life was
                                spared ; His land was sold, And his hard-earned gold All went to the lawyers, I am told.
                                Yet men will cheat and pinch and save, Nor carry their treasures beyond the grave ; All
                                their gold some day Will melt away Like the selfish savings of Solomon Ray.</p></div3></div2><pb n="211" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>DEATHS</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Doxy, James" TEIform="index"/>James Doxy
                                </head><p TEIform="p">At Union Village, Aug. 7, 1879, <persName reg="Doxy, James" TEIform="persName">James Doxy</persName>,
                                    aged 70 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sherman, Ellery" TEIform="index"/>Ellery Sherman
                                </head><p TEIform="p">At Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., Aug. 14,1879,<persName reg="Sherman, Ellery" TEIform="persName">Ellery
                                    Sherman</persName>, aged 26 years.</p></div4></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Unusual phenomenon occurred at Union Village" TEIform="index"/>Unusual phenomenon occurred at Union Village
                            </head><p TEIform="p">An unusual phenomenon occurred at Union Village, O., on Aug. 10. The Thermometer
                                indicated 44 deg. When we think of the time of the year,and that the village is in
                                latitude 39, we may well be surprised. At Shakers, N. Y. (Lat. 42.5°) same day it was
                                40° higher. Eec'd from Caroline Whitcher, Aug.9, $10 00 " " Otis Sawyer " 12, 5 10 "
                                Pleasant Hill, Ky. " 20, ----" Enfield, N. H. ' " 20, ----" Shakers, N. Y. " 20, —— "
                                Groveland, N. Y. " 20, ----" "' Harvard, Mass. " 20,----For all we have received, Lord
                                make us truly thankful. Amen.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>THOUGHTS FOR TO-DAY</head><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christ is coming" TEIform="index"/>Christ is coming
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Christ is Coming. — Frances E. Willard exclaims: "Truly, Christ is coming, coming all the
                                time, like sunrise from the east, or summer from the south, or heaven to hearts that
                                love and look for His appearing. Happy are they who help to hasten, by a little, even,
                                the day when He shall reign King of nations as He now reigns King of saints!" </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Some kindly deeds done" TEIform="index"/>Some kindly deeds done
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Some Kindly Deeds Done. — Let every dawn of morning be to you as the beginning of life,
                                and every setting sun be to you its close ; then let every one of these short lives
                                leave its record of some kindly thing done for others, some godly strength or knowledge
                                gained for yourself.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Immortality" TEIform="index"/>Immortality
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Immortality. — The door between the two worlds has been constantly opening since the
                                advent of man upon the earth, and the hour is at hand when it will be possible for the
                                sons of men to view distinctly what is beyond. The only obstacle now in the way is the
                                dull materiality by which man fetters himself to the earth, his painstaking devotion to
                                stupidity, his self-stultification, his persistent wallowing in the slough of permanent
                                errors, and the resolute sealing of his spiritual capacities to the light which is
                                constantly beaming down upon him. Oh! when will 5man open his eyes to the divine
                                capacities of his being? When will he take the same pains to know and to do the will of
                                our Father in heaven, that he now takes to know and do foolishness? and when will he
                                arise and take possession of that heritage which is placed at his disposal through the
                                countless ages of the everlasting? </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Golden thoughts" TEIform="index"/>Golden thoughts
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Golden Thoughts. — Buddha said: "A man who foolishly does me wrong (or regards me as
                                being or doing wrong), I will return to him the protection of my ungrudging love. The
                                more evil goes from him, the more good shall go from me; the fragrance of these good
                                actions always redounding to me, the harm of the slanderous words returning to him."</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Be a good man, papa" TEIform="index"/>Be a good man, papa
                            </head><p TEIform="p">"Be a Good Man, Papa." — Leaving home this morning for the office, we kissed our little
                                four-year-old good-bye, saying to him, " Be a good boy to-day." He somewhat surprised us
                                by replying, " I will. Be a good man, papa." Sure enough, we thought. We need the
                                exhortation more than he. And who could give it more effectually than this guileless
                                prattler? The words of the little preacher have been ringing in our ears all day, and
                                whether we wrote letters or editorials, pacified an irate correspondent whose effusion
                                we could not publish, or pruned down a too lengthy report, we seemed to hear the sweet
                                childvoice, saying, " Be a good man, papa." If the exhortation had been by Paul or
                                Peter, would it have had more force than coming from this little apostle of innocence ?
                                We think not, at least to our heart. Oh, how many little children if not in words, yet
                                by the helplessness of their lives and the trustfulness of their little hearts, are
                                pleading most eloquently, " Papa, be a good man!" May their tender admonition be blessed
                                of God to the rescuing of many precious souls from the wreck and ruin of sinful lives !—
                                Christian.</p></div3></div2><pb n="212" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Book Table</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker sermons: Scripto-rationale" TEIform="index"/>Shaker sermons: Scripto-rationale
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Eads, H. L." TEIform="persName"/>Elder H.L. Eads</byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">Shaker Sermons.— Scripto- Rationale ; Containing the Substance of Shaker Theology
                                together with replies and criticisms logically and clearly set forth. By Elder H. L.
                                Eads, Bishop of South Union, Ky. Such is the title of one of the most valuable
                                collections of Shaker Theology that it has been our good fortune to review and enjoy
                                perusal of. Its author is well known in the west as one of the most indefatigable
                                individuals ever born there. Like his cousin, of Mississippi jetty fame, whatever he has
                                put his hands to do, he has done with all his might, and in his projects has been
                                philosophically ] successful. The Am. Socialist lately paid him this tribute. " Capt.
                                Eads, of jetty fame, is a cousin of the Minister of the South Union (Ky.) Society of
                                Shakers, who is trying to do his part in removing obstructions of quite another kind
                                than those found at the mouth of the Father of Waters." Now let us give our side of his
                                history, for it is worth giving, and he being past three-score and ten years will not be
                                vain in our expose. Elder H. L. Eads was born in a log cabin near So. Union, Ky., April
                                28, 1807. Joined the Society in his mother's arms (!) at its first gathering on the 17th
                                day of the November following. Was " given up to the Lord," and placed in the children's
                                order before he was one year old, poor little fellow ! All he is, or has, the Shakers
                                made and gave him, after obtaining his existence. He continued to live in a little log
                                cabin until he was 15 years old. After four years of age, attended school three months
                                each year, learned to read, spell, write, "and'tis said, could cipher too " as far as
                                rule of three and vulgar fractions. All else (and he is the best read scholar, writer
                                and logician ever reared among the Shakers) he has " picked up " at spare moments. After
                                he was 6 or 8 years of age he worked sedulously at some manual labor for nine months
                                each year. Learned the shoemaker's trade by four years' active service ; was a teamster
                                two years ; a seed grower for eight years. Was next elevated to the ministry (1836) with
                                Elder B. S. Youngs (the first missionary sent from the mother society to the west) and
                                now " paid his way" by learning and working at the tailor and book-binding trades. In
                                1844 was suddenly called to Ohio ! Was then informed of his releaseinent from the
                                capacity of a bishop, and requested to make his home at U. Village Society. This he did
                                without ever inquiring the reasons for his displacement, and to this day he is ignorant
                                of the cause ! In Ohio he learned and worked two years at wool-carding and spinning,
                                also at the tin and sheet-iron works. Was appointed the Novitiate Elder at U. Village,
                                O., in 1846, remaining at the same twelve years, there learning the Dentistry, Printing,
                                Painting, and the Hat trades. Was relieved from the eldership in 1858, and worked as a
                                common laborer for two full years, when he was again appointed the elder of a senior
                                family. At this, as well as at the Novitiate family, he was very successful in his
                                undertakings. At the opening of the (un)civil war, was sent back to Kentucky to assume
                                the position he so suddenly vacated in 1844—the junior Bishop in the Society, having
                                been absent more than eighteen years. Next became one of the Bishops in the consolidated
                                Ministry of the two Kentucky Societies. In 1872 this consolidation was dissolved, and he
                                became and has remained acting head of South Union Society. After reading such a
                                biographical sketch, nearly every one will want to know the outgrowths of philosophy,
                                experience and religion from such a genial and good man. If on reading his book he
                                appears bigoted, charge this to his enthusiasm and deep sincerity. We promise the reader
                                a rich treat and a logical consistency all through the book. His criticisms of Beecher,
                                Tyndall, Talmadge, Dr. McCosh and others, are exceedingly good. His logic in " Types of
                                Christ" has nowhere been equaled in printer's types. His arraignment of false
                                theologians may appear severe ; but it is the severity of the scalpel—a demanded
                                severity. To those wishing the steel-plate engraving of the old man, pretty and
                                eloquent, in conjunction with book, send One Dollar for the book to The Shaker gatfk
                                gaftlje*</p></div3><pb n="213" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tribute to the memory of his brother Ebon" TEIform="index"/></head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ingersoll, R. G." TEIform="persName"/>Col. R.G. Ingersoll</byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Overthrow of papacy" TEIform="index"/></head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fulton, Justin D." TEIform="persName"/>Justine D Fulton</byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reply to Colonel Ingersoll" TEIform="index"/></head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leech, S. V." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> Manifesto, Shakers, N. Y. It will have a large sale. G. A. Lomas. Tribute to the Memory
                                of his Brother, Ebon, by Col. R. GL Ingersoll, has been put in beautiful form by C. P.
                                Farrell, 1417 Gf. St., Washington, D. C. Just as a reading exercise, it has few
                                superiors in any selections for that purpose that we know of. We do not know its price,
                                but a card to the publisher will meet with prompt reply. Facts about Tobacco is a
                                pamphlet of " stubborn things," as facts commonly are. Who uses tobacco and wishes to
                                know the real effects physiologically and spiritually upon him, had better send 25 cents
                                for this book. We are unwilling to make any disgusted with himself, and shall we say her
                                self ? but if there is any thing of a moral courage remaining this book will come as a
                                god-send to the eternal exclusion of tobacco. Issued by the Religious Newspaper Agency,
                                21 Barclay St., New York. The Overthrow of Papacy, by Justin D. Fulton, issued by the
                                same firm, is a scholarly piece of bombast, which reads like a boy eloquently scolding
                                his mother until he thinks he sees her stagger. To us who are familiarly acquainted with
                                the antecedents of Baptist churches, there is but little in this bitter harangue we can
                                recommend. Its price to those who wish it, 20 cents. Reply to Col Ingersoll, by Rev. S.
                                V Leech, is a talented and ingeniously arranged discourse, which gives us the other side
                                with some vengeance attached. As to its being a reply, we hesitate to affirin. We
                                believe Religion and reason have kissed each other, and Col. Ingersoll shows us many
                                good results of their reunion. Same firms 10 cents. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The pope has sold the last ship of his navy..." TEIform="index"/>The pope has sold the last ship of his navy...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The Pope has sold the last ship of his navy. Sensible ! What does the head of the church want
                            of a ship of war ? St. Peter, from whom he claims descent, was a fisherman, not an
                        admiral.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>Agricultural</head><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Birds and agriculture" TEIform="index"/>THE BIRDS AND AGRICULTURE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p">It is true, the Sparrows have done us only good. It is pleasant in winter to see and hear
                                them about, when every other bird has disappeared. From earliest childhood, in England,
                                I was cotemporary with Sparrows. That they drive off singing birds is not true. I more
                                think they attract them. In Worcestershire, they were to be seen in flocks, and singing
                                birds of every kind, from the Linnet to the Skylark — from the Robin to the Nightingale
                                — were in full force. We have more of other birds than the Sparrows. I am glad to see
                                the United States government waking up to the necessity of protecting the birds. In the
                                Report upon Foresting — 1878 — there is much valuable information, and many invaluable
                                suggestions relative to birds in Europe and America. The Grasshopper plague of the West
                                is clearly attributable to the wanton, selfish destruction of Wild Pigeons, Turkeys,
                                Prairie hens, Grouse, Quails, and many birds that multiplied according to the food
                                nature so bountifully provided for them in the form of insects, such as Grasshoppers,
                                Beetles, etc., etc. The Birds being destroyed, as amateur huntsmen are destroying the
                                Deer and Buffalo of the West, the balance of force in nature is destroyed, and human
                                beings are punished by the food they would not let the birds eat — a righteous
                                infliction. France, legislating in favor of its Agricultural friends, says: "Birds are
                                the natural guardians of our harvests, and the most precious aids to the farmer, yet are
                                they, almost everywhere, treated as enemies. The husbandman, overlooking the constant
                                services they render him, sees only the damage they may do. Children pursue them to
                                their extermination, taking them with snares, and destroying their nests. Teachers
                                should make children understand that they thus injure themselves." "The truth is," says
                                the Journal de Agriculture, " small birds are disappearing more and more, and
                                ^QXitUltUXKl. <pb n="214" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/> 214 THE SHAKES MANIFESTO. races are becoming
                                extinct. A dozen Blackbirds could not be killed in the Gironde. It is truly alarming to
                                see sack full of little birds, which afford but a trifling amount of food for man,
                                brought into our cities. Birds of passage are taken by thousands as they come weary with
                                their flight over the sea. In Lanquedoc, 20,000 Quails are taken in April and May." I
                                expect Sparrows, if encouraged, to exterminate the Potato Beetle. Poultry do it
                                effectually. Keep Poultry in Gardens and Orchards. Painting, where limbs are cut off,
                                with Coal Tar, is a French practice. Woodman, Spare that Tree. Gunners Spare the
                                Sparrows.</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A Connecticut farmer mixes a teaspoon of cayenne..." TEIform="index"/>A Connecticut farmer mixes a teaspoon of cayenne...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A Connecticut farmer mixes a teaspoonf ul of cayenne or red pepper with the food of his
                                hens, which causes them to lay more eggs. In six months a flock of twenty-six hens laid
                                2,025 eggs, or an average of 111-6 per day. On two occasions when by the omission of
                                pepper the daily product was 9, the use of that spice brought up the number to 13 or
                                more a day. The fowls were fed on corn-meal in the morning and oats at night. </p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Care of calves and sheep" TEIform="index"/>Care of Calves and Sheep</head><p TEIform="p">Lard and kerosene are good to keep lice from calves ; sulphur mixed with salt is good to
                                drive ticks from sheep. Calves, like all animals, should be kept growing from youth to
                                maturity. Here is one place where the profits come in. There is always a loss of time
                                and feed, and more, by allowing young animals to "stand still" for six months or more of
                                the year. Sheep are well clothed, and need shelter from snow or rain, and perhaps from
                                the very strongest winds, but cold agrees with them. Feed them well ; give them plenty
                                of water, in small flocks ; keep them dry, and they may stay out in the cold and thrive.
                                A close, dark pen is a poor place for sheep. </p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Straw for horses" TEIform="index"/>Straw for Horses</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A small quantity of straw might be fed to working horses without injury.
                                        Straw fed only once a day to a working horse is an entirely different thing from
                                        straw morning, noon and night. And it is the same with fattening animals. I have
                                        known straw to be fed to those in small quantities with some advantage. With
                                        milch cows it is different, and they may be fed considerable quantity of straw
                                        and not affect the flow of milk. The most important thing, and something that is
                                        usually neglected, is to keep the appetite of the stock always good. This is
                                        easily accomplished by judiciously feeding straw and hay together. I think a
                                        greater quantity of hay and straw can be fed together than of either alone. It
                                        is a serious mistake to give cattle a surfeit of straw, and, indeed, of any
                                        thing else.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Country gentleman" TEIform="index"/>Country Gentleman</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Poultry versus Swine" TEIform="index"/>Poultry versus Swine</head><p TEIform="p"> An enthusiastic breeder of poultry says : " Farmers will feed a bushel of corn to
                                produce six pounds of pork, while the same amount of corn will keep a good laying hen
                                one year, and she will produce at least twelve dozen eggs, averaging 18 cents per dozen,
                                which would equal $2.16; in adddition she would rear a brood of chickens worth as much
                                more, making a total of nearly $5, against six pounds of pork at 10 cents, equaling 60
                                cents, or, in other words, the hen will yield seven times as much as the pig on the same
                                quantity of food."</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Check rein" TEIform="index"/>The Check Rein</head><p TEIform="p">Whipping and overworking do not torture like the check rein. When you compel a horse to
                                contract the muscles just under the top of the collar, in order to sustain the head a
                                foot, more or less, above its natural place, and then hold them thus contracted, the
                                strain on those muscles soon produces great harm. If you don't believe it, watch the
                                animal, look at his eyes and ears ! I am sure you can't misunderstand that face. See him
                                carry his head around on one side, and then away round on the other side. Now in a
                                moment you will see him throw his nose up in front as high as he can, three or four
                                times. That struggle for relief he continues all the day long. When you take off the
                                check, he will hang down his head low, and show in his face a sense of relief which I am
                                sure you cannot misunderstand. The long strain wastes his muscles, and produces that
                                ugly hollow which is now so common just under the ollar. <pb n="215" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                                SHAKER MANIFESTO. 215 The London Horse Book says : "'The check rein is a useless and
                                painful incumbrance, introduced by vanity and retained by thoughtlessness amounting to
                                cruelty." Prof. Pritchard of the Royal Veterinary College (London) says : "To sum up in
                                a word, the check rein lessens the horse's strength, brings on disease, keeps him in
                                pain, frets and injures his mouth, and spoils his temper." Dr. Flemming, Veterinary
                                Surgeon of the Royal Engineers (London) says : "Nothing can be more absurd than the
                                check rein. It is extremely cruel. It is not only the head and neck that suffer, but
                                from his head to his tail, from his shoulder to his hoof, he suffers more or less." The
                                eminent John Adam McBride, Professor of Veterinary Medicine and Surgery in the Royal
                                Agricultural College, exclaims : "Could these speechless sufferers answer the inquiries
                                : Why do you continually toss your heads while standing in the harness ? Why do you
                                stretch open your mouths, shake your heads and gnash your teeth ? Why do you turn your
                                heads back toward your sides ? They would answer : All this is done to get relief from
                                the agony we are enduring by having our heads kept erect and our necks bent by tight
                                bridles and galling bits." The author of that excellent and able work The Horse in
                                Health and Disease, after discussing at length the mischief done by the check rein
                                closes with these words; " To sum up the consequences of the gag bearing rein — it
                                inflicts intense agony on the horse, impedes the action of his muscles, and by making
                                him fractious and miserable spoils his temper."</p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="White Pine for Barren Fields" TEIform="index"/>White Pine for Barren Fields
                            </head><p TEIform="p">White Pine for Barren Fields. [We enjoy a personal pleasure in noticing that the Boston
                                Post, Philadelphia Ledger, and other papers are giving demonstrations of approval to the
                                enterprise and good judgment of our Bro. Pease. We have the greater pleasure in
                                reproducing the following types, because Bro. 0. Pease has been foremost and liberal in
                                sustaining The Manifesto.—Ed.] <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">We call the Shakers a peculiar people, and perhaps we do them no injustice,
                                        but like many other classes and societies, with all of whose ways we do not
                                        sympathize, they are capable of giving us profitable ideas if we will only
                                        accept them. The Shakers do not bestow much thought upon art, but they work in
                                        admirable harmony with nature. Their splendid avenues of trees, their farms
                                        under almost perfect cultivation, show that they do not slight the gifts with
                                        which they have been intrusted. A writer in a New Haven paper says that "
                                        probably no man in all New England has done more in a certain line for the
                                        benefit of posterity than Elder Omar Pease, of the North Family at the Shaker
                                        settlement at Enfield. He has sown in the last thirty years over 200 acres of
                                        white pines, and to-day from the hill east of his residence can overlook their
                                        dark, dense growths, their various heights, indicating their different ages. He
                                        says that only once in about three years do the white pine seeds ripen. Four
                                        quarts of seeds well distributed will stock an acre. His best success has been
                                        after buckwheat and without harrowing. Pines grow where the land is poor^ and a
                                        man who has 200 acres of comely growing trees rising annually to his memory in
                                        this world leaves a monument better than marble." All of this is true, and we
                                        wish it might not be simply abstract truth. There are thousands of acres in New
                                        England now bearing nothing better than mullein and sorrel that might be treated
                                        to the white pine remedy and become richly paying territory. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Boston post" TEIform="index"/>Boston Post</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The honey In flowers" TEIform="index"/>The Honey In Flowers</head><p TEIform="p">The wonderful magnitude of the least operations in nature is illustrated by the quantity
                                of honey that can be gathered from flowers. Two hundred thousand pounds have been taken
                                from bees kept within an area of ten miles, and on this basis it is plain that our
                                continent might be made to produce thousands of tons yearly, and the honey crop outdo
                                the sugar crop.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="No man has come to true greatness who has not felt in some degree that his life belongs to his race..." TEIform="index"/>No man has come to true greatness who has not felt in some degree that his life belongs to his race...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">No man has come to true greatness who has not felt in some degree that his life belongs to
                            his race, and that what God gives him he gives him for mankind. The different degrees of
                            this consciousness are really what makes the different degrees of greatness in men.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Brooks, Phillips" TEIform="persName"/>Phillips Brooks</byline></div2><pb n="216" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>Home Topics</head><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Unleavened loaf bread" TEIform="index"/>Unleavened Loaf Bread</head><p TEIform="p">The Shakers claim to make the best unleavened loaf bread from pure Graham flour. Here is
                                another recipe which makes a very nice composition bread: Mix the best of rye and Indian
                                meal in equal proportions into a soft dough, with cold water in hot weather, but warm
                                water in cold weather. Mix and knead it with the hands until light, and lay it softly,
                                so as not to press out the air confined in it, in deep tin pans. Now smooth over the top
                                with the moistened hand so as to give it a neat appearance. Let it stand over night,
                                then bake it in an oven, hot at first, but gradually cooling. If it could be made late
                                enough in the evening to be allowed to remain in the oven over night, it would make a
                                very nice breakfast bread. — Laws of Life. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mixture for cleaning paint" TEIform="index"/>Mixture for Cleaning Paint</head><p TEIform="p">Dissolve two ounces of soda in a quart of hot water, which will make a ready and useful
                                solution for cleaning old painted work preparatory to repainting. The mixture, in the
                                above proportions, should be used when warm, and the woodwork afterward washed with
                                water to remove the remains of the soda. A hint for the laundry : Linen may be glazed by
                                adding a teaspoonful of salt and one of finely-scraped soap to a pint of starch. </p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tomato butter" TEIform="index"/>Tomato Butter</head><p TEIform="p">To seven pounds of very ripe tomatoes, take three pounds light brown sugar, half a pint
                                of vinegar, and half an ounce of cinnamon; boil slowly for five or six hours. It may
                                then be put into jars. A spoonful of this added to almost any soup or sauce gives it a
                                most delicious flavor. </p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Scrambled eggs" TEIform="index"/>Scrambled Eggs</head><p TEIform="p">Six eggs, one coffeecup of milk, one teaspoonful of butter, one teaspoonful of flour, and
                                salt. Beat the eggs very light, rub the butter and flour together, add this to the milk
                                after it has been placed on the stove, and becomes a little warm. Salt to taste. Add the
                                eggs, and cook until the whites are cooked, and serve while hot, or with toast. </p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="For burns" TEIform="index"/>For Burns</head><p TEIform="p">Strong, fresh, clear lime water, mixed with as much linseed oil as it will cut; shake the
                                bottle before applying; wrap the burn in cotton wadding saturated with the lotion ; wet
                                as often as it appears dry, without removing cotton from burn for nine days, when new
                                skin will probably have formed. </p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Corn griddle-cakes" TEIform="index"/>Corn Griddle-Cakes</head><p TEIform="p">To one quart of sour milk add one teaspoonful of soda, the same of salt, and one egg,
                                one-half cup of wheat flour; add corn-meal sufficient to make a batter thick enough to
                                bake on hot griddles. </p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Scalloped tomatoes" TEIform="index"/>Scalloped Tomatoes</head><p TEIform="p">Pare and slice fine ripe tomatoes ; put into a bake-dish with alternate layers of
                                buttered breadcrumbs ; season each stratum of tomato with pepper and salt. Bake covered
                                until very hot, then brown. The upper layer should be of crumbs. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Whitewashing" TEIform="index"/>Whitewashing</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Good whitewash, well applied to fences, rough siding, and the walls and
                                        ceilings of buildings, has a highly sanitary influence, as well as being in the
                                        highest degree preservative in its effects. To be durable, whitewash should be
                                        prepared in the following manner: Take the very best stone-lime, and slack it in
                                        a close tub, covered with a cloth to preserve the steam. Salt — as much as can
                                        be dissolved in water used for slacking and reducing the lime — should be
                                        applied, and the whole mass carefully strained and thickened with a small
                                        quantity of sand, the purer and finer, the better. A few pounds of wheat flour
                                        mixed as paste may be added, and will give greater durability to the mass,
                                        especially when applied to the exterior surface of buildings. With pure lime,
                                        properly slacked and mixed with twice its weight of fine sand and sifted
                                        wood-ashes, in equal proportions, almost any color may be made by the addition
                                        of pigments. Granite, slate, freestone and other shades may be imitated, and
                                        without any detriment to the durability of the wash. The covering is very often
                                        applied and with good effect, to underpinning, stone fences, roof, and the walls
                                        of barns and other out-buildings. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Germantown telegraph" TEIform="index"/>Germantown Telegraph</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><!--
                    <pb id="p29"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>