<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm1705" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">23</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">17</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">05</biblScope><date value="18870501" TEIform="date">May 1887</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">97-120</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="17" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="05" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!-- 
<pb id="p1"/>
MAY.
THE
MANIFESTO
Published by the United Societies.,
"Every plant which my heavenly Father bath not planted shall be rooted
up."- -Matt, xv.,  13.
Canterbury, N. H.
1887.

<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
CONTENTS.
| Gospel Testimony, No. 14,
IJestiny of our Race,
The Mission of Life,
Prayer,              Again,           ....
Friendship,
Influences,
Future Probation,
Unto you it is given, &c,
Truth,       -          -          Faith and Works,
Faith,        ....
Prayer in May,
War,          -          Strife,            ....
Temperance,        -          Thought,         -          Practical Religion,
Juvenile Theology,
JSTotes-Non-Essentials or Essentials,
A Plea for Temperance,
Letter-Harriet Bullard,
My Shaker Childhood,
Christian Communism, No. 2,
Hoe your own Row,
Books and Papers,
Deaths,            ....
97
100
102
103
104
105
108
109
110
111
112
113
116
117
119
120
$/5fSAMONTH   and BOARD Guaranteed
^J %jf 3 y oung Men or Ladies in each country,
and highest commission paid (often $150
a month)    MEW BOOK already on
TIDAL WAVE fTr^^TFT ^ W "H T1 "P - -i
OF SUCCESS  Ik33    Tf wJH JJ- -irWfe>
in North and South America, at the Ice-Bound
Poles, over the lands of the Midnight Sun, under the
Equator, through the Dark Continent, among the Old
Temples of India, in the Flowery Kingdoms of China
and Japan, amid the ruins of Incas, Aztecs and Zuni, within Canons, Cliff Buildings, and Gardens of
the Gods, on the Isles of the Sea, and in all parts of
the globe. 300 engravings, Low Price. Quick Sales.
Send for Circular, p, W. Ziegler, & Co,, 720 Chestnut St. Philadelphia, Pa,
AGENTS WANTED to sell "KEMINISCENCES"
of 60 TEAKS in the  NATIONAL METROPOLIS,
1TBEN PERLEY POORE
Illustrating the Wit, Humor, and Eccentricities of
noted celebrities. A. richly illustrated treat of inner Society History, from " ye
olden time " to the wedding of Cleveland. Wonderfully Poimlar. Agents report rapid
sales. Address for circular and terms.
HVBBARB BROS., Pub's, Boston, Mass.
BLEY'S
SEND "SsnUuWid CATALOGUE
Vegetable, Flower, Field - - gj" g- - - - |"%C
Plants, Bulbs. Implem'ts. v& E. Ei.U'- -
C O ET ET  toT mail on application.
- -    W% In Sm  Don't neglect writing for it.
HIRAM SIBLEY & CO.
ROCHESTER, N. Y.
322-326 E. Main St.
CHICAGO, ILL.
12-11 N. Clark St.
After Forty years'
experience in th- -
preparation of more
than One Hundred
Thousand applications for patents in
the United States and Foreign countries, the publishers of the Scientific
American continue to act as solicitors
for patents, caveats, trade-marks, copy- - rights, etc., for the United States, and
to obtain patents in Canada, England, France,
Germany, and all other countries Their experience is unequaled and their facilities ara unsurpassed.
Drawings and specifications prepared and filed
in the Patent Office on short notice. Terms very
reasonable. No charge for examination of models
or drawings.    Advice by mail free.
Patents obtainedthrough Munn&Oo.arenoticed
inthe SCIENTIFIC AMERICAN,which has
the largest circulation and is the most influential
newspaper of its kind published in the world.
The advantages of such a notice every patentee
understands.
This large and splendidly illustrated newspaper
is published WEEKLY n!, $3.00 a year, and is
admitted to be the best paper devoted to science,
mechanics, inventions, engineering works, and
other departments of industrial progress, publisned in any country. It contains the names of
all patentees and title of every invention patented
each week. Try it four months for one dollar.
Sold by all newsdealers.
If you have an invention to  patent write to
Munn & Co., publishers of Scientific American,
361 Broadway, New York.
Handbook about patents mailed free.
The Church Union is Edited and Published by Mrs. E. B. Grannis. 33 East 22d
St. N. Y. City. It is the National Organ
of those laboring for the actual Visible Unity of Evangelical Believers.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
Vol. XVII.
MAY,  1887.
No. 5. --><pb n="97" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gospel testimony of Mother Ann Lee and the elders, William Lee and James Whittaker no. 14" TEIform="index"/> The Gospel Testimony of Mother Ann Lee and the Elders, William Lee and James Whittaker.
                            No. 14.</head><p TEIform="p"> Published expressly for the several Communities of Believers in IS 16. Re-written by Henry
                            C. Blinn. Some of the Believers attempted to address the crowd, but were soon admonished, to
                            hold their peace, as some ruffian would deal them a severe blow with a whip or a cane. One
                            hour was allowed the Believers in which to make preparations for their journey. The time was
                            very limited in which to do the many needful duties, especially when we consider that more
                            than a hundred people, of all ages, were in the place, and many of them fifty or more miles
                            from home. At the expiration of the hour the Believers were ordered to march. The Sisters
                            were permitted to ride in a carriage or on horseback, but the Brethren were forbidden this
                            privilege, although many of them had horses. About one half of the mob formed the advance
                            guard. Next came the Believers, while the remainder of the mob brought up the rear. The
                            Brethren who lived in the town of Harvard were determined to follow their Brethren and
                            Sisters, although forbidden by the leaders of the mob. As this large body of religious
                            persecutors were nearly all on horseback, they obliged the Believers to move along with
                            considerable speed. The infirm and tliOoe advanced in age who did not walk so fast as their
                            inhuman drivers thought proper, were rudely and cruelly admonished by a severe stroke of a
                            whip or some other instrument of torture. If any one attempted to admonish these persecutors
                            for their cruelty, a blow from a lash or stick, on his head or face soon convinced him of
                            the danger of reasoning with an unprincipled mob, whose loving kindness is bitter and whose
                            tender mercies are cruel. Several of the Believers, on that day, found by sad experience,
                            that it was in vain, to attempt to moderate the cruelty of such savage hearts. Quite soon
                            after the procession had started, one of the Believers attempted to repeat a prayer, but a
                            number of cruel blows over the head and face, forbid his proceeding. Prayers were not
                            allowed. When the company reached the dwelling of Jeremiah Willard, two of the Brethren from
                            his place came out to .*peak to their friends. As Abijah Worcester was shaking hands with
                                one<pb n="98" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/>in the ranks, a man by the name of Houghton rode up and struck
                            Abijah a severe blow on the head with a goad. Abijah was then placed under guard, ordered
                            into the ranks and marched along with the company. At Still River the whole body were
                            ordered to halt. They had marched three miles. "Now we will have a little diversion," said
                            one of the leaders, and orders were given that James Shepard should be soundly whipped.f A
                            ring was soon formed and sticks cut from the bushes, preparatory to the whipping. Several
                            persons were appointed to the work and directed to give the prisoner a certain number of
                            strokes. James was ordered to take off his coat and vest. He then kneeled and prayed, "Be of
                            good cheer, Brethren, for it is your Heavenly Father's good pleasure to give you the
                            kingdom. " On hearing these words one man, Isaiah Whitney without waiting for orders, gave
                            James several severe strokes with his horsewhip. Eleazer Rand and Jonathan Slosson arrived
                            at the time of the whipping. Eleazer immediately placed himself between James and his
                            persecutors. This act of Christian kindness so enraged the mob that they beat him with their
                            clubs, canes and whips most unmercifully. Others of the Brethren followed the example of
                            Eleazer till the confusion of the scene brought this act of cruelty to an end. William Morey
                            did not hesitate to reprove Farnsworth, the captain of the mob, for permitting such acts of
                            inhumanity, such abusive conduct, and - -f James was the only person in the company, that
                            came with the Believers from England and as they liad been disappointed in not finding
                            pother Ann and the Elders, their enmity was turned toward this poor man, and they resolved
                            to whip him for all the orthers. such shocking cruelty. Farnsworth was so enraged at this
                            reproof that he struck William in the face with great violence and broke out several of his
                            teeth. This scene over, the Believers were again placed in marching order and driven with
                            greater speed than before for a distance of three more miles which brought them to the line
                            between Harvard and Bolton. At this place the Brethren from Harvard called at the house of
                            Zacheus Stevens, which was near the boundary line. Several Sisters came to the door and
                            begged of the Brethren not to leave their gospel friends, so long as they were driven by
                            those cruel persecutors. It was a word in due season, and the response came, "We will go
                            with our gospel friends, as far as the mob goes. " At the town line a strong guard was
                            placed to prevent the Brethren from Harvard from advancing. They were sternly forbid from
                            passing over the line. These Brethren however, claimed a perfect right to travel on the
                            highway, and were determined to proceed. Being opposed by the mob they cried out, "Are you
                            highway robbers?" "We will go as far as you go, and will not leave our Brethren and Sisters
                            in your merciless hands." '' If you attempt to cross the boundary line of the town," said
                            the captain, "we will spill your blood in the sand." Regardless of the threats, the Brethren
                            from Harvard proceeded, but were inhumanly beaten with clubs, by the captain and his guards.
                            Eleazer, at this time received a blow that broke his arm. Frightened at their own cruel
                            deeds, the guards fled and the Harvard Brethren went on and joined the body of Believers.
                                <pb n="99" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> From the place where the mob halted to whip James Shepard, to the
                            town of Lancaster was one continued scene of cruelty and abuse. Horsewhipping, pounding,
                            beating with clubs, collaring, pushing off from bridges into the water, frightening the
                            horses that were guided by the Sisters, and every kind of abuse that their malicious minds
                            could invent, without the taking of life. Indeed it seemed miraculous that none lost their
                            lives while subjected to such cruel and continued persecutions. One of the Brethren,
                            Jonathan Bridges, for neglect to march at their required speed was whipped nearly every step
                            for the distance of a quarter of a mile. Jonathan at last became so faint that he fell by
                            the side of the road. As Eleazer Hand was repeating the words,- -"0 Lord," a man named
                            Priest seized him by the collar, shook him severely and commanded him to hold his tongue. "
                            I have the right and I will pray, " said Eleazer. Eleazer was now cruelly pushed for a rod
                            or more and then hurled against a Stone wall. '' Did you stop the dog from praying, " said
                            Houghton. "No, " said Priest, "I could not unless I had killed him." If any of the aged
                            Brethren attempted to mount a horse, to obtain some relief while on this wearisome journey,
                            some one from the persecutor's ranks would immediately ride up to him and with the butt of
                            his whip-stock, soon force him to dismount. At Lancaster the leaders of the mob held
                            consultation, and then dismissed the Believers with this injunction, "If any of you shall
                            ever be seen again in Harvard, any person of this party present, shall have full power to
                            tie you up and whip you, without judge or jury," and then added, "We now have a farther work
                            to do with these Harvard Shakers." After this dismissal the Believers found a resting place
                            under the shade of a large, beautiful elm, and once more having the divine right to breathe
                            freely, they expressed their gratitude and thankfulness by uniting in prayer, and giving
                            thanks to God that they were counted worthy to suffer persecution for the testimony of the
                            gospel. It was the outpouring of a thankful spirit from many honest hearts, after having
                            suffered such cruel persecutions, from the hands of those who denominated themselves the
                            followers of Christ and advocates of religious liberty. Perhaps they were too soou in their
                            demonstrations of thankfulness. The mob heard the prayers. These were piercing reproofs to
                            guilty consciences. The mob was provoked, and again rushed upon the Believers and commenced
                            another inhuman scene of cruelty. Neither age nor sex was regarded in this indiscriminate
                            lashing and beating. It was done, seemingly, with as little regard for the feelings of men
                            and women as though it had been a herd of swine. After this burst of fury had been exhausted
                            the mob retired from the place. Once more the Believers were permitted to breathe freely,
                            and yet they were not quite sure that the blessed relief was more than a momentary blessing.
                            They could now hold communion with the apostle, when he said, "We are troubled on every
                            side, yet not distressed ; we are perplexed, but not altogether without help or means.
                                Per-<pb n="100" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> secuted, but not forsaken ; cast down, but not destroyed." The
                            Harvard Brethren now bade their gospel friends an affectionate farewell, and the wish, " God
                            bless you, " went up from every heart as the parties began their journeys toward their own
                            homes. Those returning to Harvard were beaten more or less, by the mob, while on their way
                            home. An aged brother, Jonathan Clark, was struck several times with the butt of a loaded
                            whipstock, by a man named Houghton. On entering the town of Harvard, the mob stopped at
                            Captain Pollard's and formed a ring. Up to this time they had kept Abijah Worcester under
                            guard. He was now charged with going about and breaking up families and churches, and it was
                            declared that he should be whipped. By vote of the mob, Jonathan Houghton and Elijah Priest
                            were appointed to be the whippers, after several nominations. It was decided by vote that he
                            should receive twenty lashes. He was immediately stripped to the waist and tied to a tree,
                            when Houghton laid on his ten strokes. Suddenly, a respectable and humane citizen, James
                            Haskell, rode to the place and seeing this case of cruelty, dismounted from his horse, and
                            throwing off his coat and vest, cried out, "Here! here!! If there are any more stripes to be
                            given let me take the rest. " On hearing these words from Haskell the mob did not dare to
                            proceed, and Abijah was immediately set free. Having put on his garments, he began to sing,
                            which he continued to do till he reached the house of Zacheus Stevens. There were persons in
                            the company, who made no profession of a religious faith, that were so affected with the
                            sufferings of Abijah that they could not refrain from weeping. At this place the mob
                            dispersed and were not seen again. Many of the citizens of the town of Harvard were much
                            displeased with the proceedings of this churchal persecution. Not only in Harvard but
                            through the whole course of the seven miles, which the Believers were driven, many were
                            greatly dissatisfied with the abusive conduct of the mob. Some ventured to remonstrate
                            against the cruelty, but were generally answered by curses and a reminder that they might
                            possibly be served in the same manner. It will be well to remark that the conduct and
                            testimony of some of the young Believers, while on the road had a tendency to exasperate the
                            mob to greater acts of cruelty than they probably, would have committed, had strict silence
                            been maintained. Many of them had accepted the faith but a few months, and were full of
                            zeal, and being divested of all fear of man, they would sing, and shout and pray, and praise
                            God that they were counted worthy to suffer for Christ's sake and the gospel. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Condition and destiny of our race" TEIform="index"/> Condition and Destiny of our Race.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>GILES B. AVERY.</byline><p TEIform="p"> The age in which we live, in all civilized society of the human family, is rife with action
                            ; progress is the motor that is prompting and propelling human destiny ; unrest appears to
                            characterize the substratum of human character, in the present phase of human history. This
                            spirit is propelling the inquisitive element in mankind to seek to know the<pb n="101" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> truth, the undeniable reality of all the multiform fruits of the tree of
                            knowledge, in every lineament of human capacity, physical, mental and psychical. The avenues
                            of both mental and psychical communion are opened to the perceptions and understandings of
                            human beings to a degree, as we believe, never before experienced by our race ; and, from
                            the tomes of the history of human progress consigned to the inhabitants of our age, that
                            have survived the ravages of time, together with the light and truth revealed to man in the
                            present era, by ministering angels of intelligence on errands of love from the shrine of
                            Wisdom, there are brilliant orbs of light and truth shedding their lustre of life and power
                            upon the human family, and urging it on a march of truthful improvement, unknown, as we
                            believe, in all the cycles of past ages. The vital question of the hour is, How near
                            heaven's appointed course is the ark of human destiny now sailing by the winds and waves of
                            power operating upon our race ? Apostolic light perceived humanity's life progress ''first,
                            in that which is natural, afterwards that which is spiritual." Following this wake on life's
                            ocean, we observe that the immense progress of science and art attained by man during the
                            last half century is without a parallel in human history in the knowledge of the present
                            generation. A knowledge of man's physical constituency has, it appears, almost reached the
                            pinnacle of wisdom. Mental researches have unearthed the mines of knowledge, brought out and
                            coined, in the mint of philosophy, the treasures of science and art applicable to the needs
                            of man's material existence in labor-saving machinery, and in the quick transmission of
                            ideas to great distances,- -which, were it husbanded for the benefit of all classes of human
                            society, would so much lessen human toil for support as to allow a great amount of time for
                            the enlightenment of the minds of the masses of society, promoting intelligence calculated
                            to bless and happify our race. It has been estimated that the labor-saving machinery of the
                            State of Massachusetts alone is equal to the manual labor of one half the inhabitants of the
                            globe. But to such an extent have the cupidity and selfishness of mankind been extended,
                            that, comparatively speaking, the great mass of the human race are but very moderately
                            elevated and blessed thereby. Many of the necessaries of life are now produced so cheaply
                            that, were the benefits justly shared by the human family, earth might become a Paradise.
                            But, it is most sorrowful, tli3 great mass of mankind have not yet discovered the value of
                            reciprocity and communion of interests, and that those only are truly wealthy who can
                            measure their stores by their ability and determination to contribute to the benefit of
                            other beings, after the precept of the Golden Rule : " Whatsoever ye would that men should
                            do unto you, do you even so to them." The iron rule of selfishness puts manacles on the
                            hands of charity, and locks with clasps of steel the purses of benevolence ! Thus the golden
                            bowl of love is broken at the fountain, and the rivulets of blessings are sapped and dried
                            up at the springs. Consequently, bitter water of cursing are poured out of rancorous lips,
                            while famished tabernacles of palsied souls are groping in melancholy ravines<pb n="102" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> and desolate valleys of want and woe. The God-given Mosaic key, "Thou shalt
                            love thy neighbor as thjself," is not used to unlock the doors of humanity's hoarded pelf
                            and distribute to the needy: and that Christian love that would lay down one's life for his
                            friend's is seldom to be witnessed ; though the example of Jesus is adored in speech and
                            admired in thought, but esteemed as a virtue of an impracticable age even by those who call
                            themselves most honorable Christians ! But, as it hath been said by him whose life was
                            manifestly a consecration to the happiness of mankind, by an effort to save the race from
                            sin, the cause of all human sorrow, "Man shall not live by bread alone, but by every Avord
                            that proceedeth out of the mouth of God." And the Prophetic Age is at hand, when heavenly
                            messengers are descending to earth to teach mankind a more just, better, and happier life,
                            to harvest man from the fields of sin, yea, even from the low animal plane- -the old stock
                            of narrow, selfish families- -" the clusters of the vine of the earth," (see John the
                            lievclator,~) and make him a guest in the chambers of the great family of Christ, who
                            inherit "the city that hath (eternal) foundations, whose builder and maker is God." This
                            "i'M,e of the earth" is the power and work of generation. One of the angels, seen by the
                            Revelator John, told another angel, who held a sharp sickle, to "thrust in his sickle and
                            gather the clusters of the vine of the earth, for her grapes are fully ripe." These clusters
                            are natural families ; and the work of the day that is now dawning upon human society is a
                            time when harvesting angels from the spirit world, and those souls in the mortal body who
                            follow Christ in the regeneration, are about to reap souls who are seeking for a higher life
                            than the low, degraded state of militant selfish man, swallowed up in sensuality, and the
                            lusts of a perverted life, and garner them into the heavenly mansions of souls who are saved
                            from sin and being redeemed from its nature of temptation, thence to live a virgin celibate
                            life in a community of saintly souls who are overcoming the world, and shaking loose from
                            its every shackle of sinful nature. " These are they who follow the Lamb (of God the Christ)
                            whithersoever he goeth." He is the first Great Shaker who opened up the way of salvation and
                            redemption to man, thus beginning the fulfillment of that most gracious and merciful
                            prophecy from the God of heaven. "Yet once it is a little while, and I will shake the
                            heavens and the earth, the sea and the dry land, and I will shake all the nations, and the
                            desires of all nations shall come, and I will fill this house with glory, saith the Lord of
                            hosts." (Hag. ii., 6, 7.) This house is the tabernacle of the souls who have "washed their
                            robes white in the blood (life) of the Lamb"- -that is, by living the life as Christ did-
                            -by overcoming the world in himself. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mission of angelic life" TEIform="index"/> THE MISSION OF ANGELIC LIFE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL FRASER.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Gratification without reference to use, stands athwart the path of those who seek to
                            establish "the Divine order of human society" in the midst of the confusions and antagonisms
                            of the earth life. In going forth to do that great<pb n="103" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> work of human
                            continuity, there are some leading facts to be kept in view. Gratification without reference
                            to use, leads first, to bodily disease. Second, to social troubles. These carried to a
                            certain extent, create an all pervading atmosphere of selfish unreasonableness. Violations
                            of the laws of health, and of social adjustments, are the factors in the formation of human
                            hells. Bodily disease, hell, and social disturbances, form a oneness. Hell may be defined as
                            an assemblage of human spirits having no common center, seeking gratification to the injury
                            of themselves and others. Each spirit setting itself up to be an independent center of
                            influence- - to be a god. Whether spirits are in or out of the body, the antagonisms of such
                            a life, shows the necessity of a Divine central spirit to gravitate to, revolve around, and
                            to maintain harmony with ; otherwise, each spirit will be a center of discord. Hence the
                            first efforts, in beginning to establish divine life,- -heaven in the hells of earth, or in
                            those of the spirit laud- -will be directed to manifest a center of love and goodwill to all
                            spirits. To preach a gospel of right living and of right doing. And of, not only justice,
                            but beneficence to the poor and oppressed, to heal the broken-hearted, give deliverance to
                            the captive, and comfort to the sorrowing. This class of spirits are the first to be cared
                            for. Those who have broken human hearts, made captives of, and abused their fellows, can
                            only be released by, and through the good-will and mercy of those who have been abused and
                            trampled upon. "Whatever measure ye mete unto men, will be measured to you again." The laws
                            of the moral universe are as invariable, omnipotent and harmonious, as are those of the
                            material world. With such a mission, you cannot at all times lind an entrance into the
                            hells. There are spiritual times and seasons. When these are favorable, and "the spirit of
                            the Lord is upon you," theu go forth and declare the iife and the principles that put an end
                            to human hatreds, oppressions, war and strife. Most assuredly, the words of the prophets
                            will be fulfilled. " None shall say I am sick." "Death and hell shall be swallowed up in
                            victory." "Violence shall no more be heard in thy land, wasting nor destruction within thy
                            borders ; thy walls shall be salvation, and thy gates praise. Thy people shall all be
                            righteous, a little one shall become a thousand, and a small one a strong nation. I the Lord
                            will hasten it in his time." Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prayer" TEIform="index"/> PRAYER.</head><p TEIform="p"> [Contributed by C. Jacobs. | " More things are wrought by prayer Than this world dreams of.
                            Wherefore, let thy voiceRise like a fountain for me night and day. For what are men better
                            than sheep or goats, That nourish a blind life within the brain, If, knowing God, they lift
                            not hands of pra3rer, Both for themselves and those who call them Mend?' For so, the whole
                            round earth is every way Bound by gold chains about the feet of God.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Tennyson" TEIform="persName"/>Tennyson.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Again" TEIform="index"/> AGAIN.</head><p TEIform="p"> 'Tis all for lack of sacrifice That souls are stinted in their growth Our God is just and
                            makes returns For all we give in greater worth : But he who holds his selfish life And will
                            not render time and pains Eor others good is: of tlie earth Arid in the world that soul
                            remains. Canterbury, N. H. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W.</byline></div2><pb n="104" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Friendship" TEIform="index"/>FRIENDSHIP
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Case, F. A." TEIform="persName"/>F. A. Case
                        </byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> From heaven's garden God did take One of his choicest
                                    flowers, To plant it in the heart of man, And happier make his hours. Yet rarer
                                    flower can now be found, For choked and overgrown By thorns and weeds of selfishness
                                    That Satan's hands hath sown. God plants it first, in infant's heart, When pure and
                                    white as snow, Unspotted by the soot of sin Or tracks of human woe. When youthful
                                    days its life entwine. Deception's dirt ne'er chokes ; Its growth is like the Ivy
                                    vines That wind about the oaks. It lifts the fallen from disgrace, And makes their
                                    life anew. It heals the broken-heart and makes Its sorrow bid adieu. It hath great
                                    power to shape the end Of men, and nations too. Its scepter is of purest love. Its
                                    motto is "be true. " Yet oft like Judas' kiss it's used To gain one's selfish part,
                                    With sweetest nectar on the lips But a dagger in the heart.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Georgetown College magazine" TEIform="index"/>Georgetown College Magazine.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Surrounding influences" TEIform="index"/> SURROUNDING INFLUENCES.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Thomas, Ida A." TEIform="persName"/>IDA A. THOMAS. </byline><p TEIform="p">Let me gather to the true and noble of heart; those who are willing and ready to sacrifice
                            life itself, for the pure and holy principles of Christianity. It is any sincere desire to
                            ever feel the beautiful influences of such, that they may strengthen me in my struggles. I
                            feel without these pure influences around me, my own efforts are but feeble. It is the true
                            aim of my life to live and learn to do well, so as to be a help to any that I could help in
                            my feeble way. I have enjoyed a privilege among Believers over three years, and in that time
                            I feel that I have gained many and lasting friends. Of my dear Elders I cannot speak too
                            well; tongue cannot express the love and gratitude I feel for their untiriog patience in my
                            behalf. Do you wish to keep near God? then be true with your faith. Do you wish to keep from
                            a worldly influence? then shun every thing that would tend to it. This I will strive to do,
                            to shun every thing that would carry my thoughts from my gospel home out to the bewildering
                            and dazzling influences of the world. I know I have a strong and worldly nature which needs
                            subjection and restraint ; this is chiefly my object in living here, to learn to govern and
                            subject my spirit, that I may receive to my soul's understanding. Many complain of the
                            cross, thinking oft-times this thing or that is unnecessary ; to such I would say, why do
                            you live in such a way ? what is your motive ? Not half, but the whole must be given ; a
                            full and complete sacrifice is required, and now is the appointed time. I am thankful that I
                            have been blest with faith, and also that I have had strength to be guided by it, and I pray
                            that I may receive more and more daily, a substance for my soul to feed on, that I may grow
                            firm and strong, and be a valiant servant in the great cause of redemption. Mt. Lebanon, N.
                            Y. </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Self forgetfulness bridges the turged stream..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Self forgetfulness bridges the turged stream...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Self forgetfulness bridges the turgid stream of discontent, and unbars the gates of
                            Paradise.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. A. </byline></div2><pb n="105" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Future probation" TEIform="index"/> FUTURE PROBATION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dibble, Chauncy" TEIform="persName"/> CHAUNCY DIBBLE. </byline><p TEIform="p">Observing in the New York Witness of December 23rd., a notice on Probation 1 will express a
                            few thoughts thereon. It sterns the only theory that explains consistently the dealings of
                            Providence with man. God as Father and Mother of all souls, is the fountain of intelligence
                            and has imparted a portion of this attribute to mortals. Also He has bestowed the gift of
                            free agency as a lasting inheritance to man, so far as the use of his faculties extend,
                            either for good or ill, virtue or vice. Yet he must reap the fruits of his doings. The law
                            of compensation he cannot escape in the final test, yet who but an all-wise judge can
                            measure truth and mercy? Character, uot reputation, is based upon the same immutable law of
                            merit in spirit life, as here. The same all-wise Parent of love administers justice and
                            mercy to his children through his divine agencies. Yesterday, to-day and forever the same
                            rewards of virtue and punishments of vice is the law throughout the realm of intelligences.
                            Those who have died without the knowledge of Christ's gospel, as nearly all mankind have,
                            may come to a knowledge of its saving power in spirit life and be redeemed from their
                            natural depravity by compliance with its principles. I am not an advocate for Purgatory,
                            neither do 1 suppose the spirit world is a void space with one place of endless torment and
                            another of ineffable bliss, for this idea if carried out, would destroy heaven anywhere.
                            God's character and government has been falsely represented by Jewish tradition. No such
                            warlike nature is attributed to Him by Jesus. Throughout his Sermon on the Mount the spirit
                            of mercy predominates towards the penitent. Not a sparrow forgotten. Not a thief on the
                            cross condemned. He exhorted to forgive men their trespasses. Judge not lest ye be judged.
                            Let him that is perfect cast the first stone. Christ after his resurrection went and
                            preached to the spirits on whom the long suffering of God waited in the days of Noah. 1st
                            Peter, iii., 20, also iv., 6. Future probation was commonly taught in early ages of
                            Christianity ; but those parts of Scripture which advocate it were carefully rejected by
                            church authorized compilers of Scripture. The spirit life is not dark and mysterious. In God
                            is no shadow of turning, and through his instrumentalities He will gather the prodigals home
                            until the last of the flock be restored. Watervliet, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Unto you it is given to know..." TEIform="index"/>Unto you it is given to know...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Preter, Charles Julius" TEIform="persName"/>CHARLES JULIUS PRETER.</byline><p TEIform="p"> " Unto you it is given to know the mysteries of the kingdom of God, but to others in
                            parables; that seeing they might not see, and hearing they might not understand. " Luke
                            i&gt;iii., Most all sects and denominations in the world are looking for and expecting
                            the kingdom of God, the New Jerusalem on earth in a future tense, therefore they are greatly
                            surprised when they are told that it has already come, and all true Believers are its
                            inmates. Whenever God had a divine manifestation on earth, it came always contrary to the
                            common expectations of men, and why not at the present time of Christ's second appearing in
                            the female, the Bride?<pb n="106" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/>Rev. xii., 17. To get a right knowledge of this
                            all important subject, we must first get a right understanding of God. It is plain and
                            evident, the Deity is not, a Trinity but a Duality. Rons. i., 20. "For the invisible things
                            of Him from the creation of the world, are clearly seen by the things th- -xt are made even
                            his eternal Power and Godhead. " Jesus was not God, but a created being. His soul did
                            emanate and came forth from God, the same way that all other souls did. Acts xvii., 28. "We
                            are also his offspring. " Eccl. xii.,7. "Then shall the dust (body) return to the earth as
                            it was, and the spirit shall return unto God who gave it." St. Paul wrote 1st. Cor. i., 28,
                            "We preach Christ, the Power of God and the Wisdom of God." Jesus received this Christ
                            spirit or anointing, when he was thirty years old, at the time of his baptism in the river
                            Jordan. John i., 12. "As many as received him, to them gave he power to become the sons of
                            God." 1st. John III., 2. "Beloved, now we are the sons of God." Obadiah, 21. " Saviors shall
                            come up on mount Zion, to judge the mount of Esau. " By this it is plainly seen, that God
                            has many sons and daughters, as well as a number of saviors beside Jesus, who was the first
                            begotten from the dead, our first brother, for all before him were in a spiritual sense
                            dead. " Death reigned from Adam to Christ," who came to restore to life all who were "dead
                            in trespasses and sins." Gen. v., 1, 2. God created man in his own image, male and female,
                            not three, but two persons. This anti-christian doctrine of a Trinity was first concocted
                            and introduced into the church at the council of Nice in Bithynia, in the year 325, by
                            corrupt priests and bishops, after much disputation and violent opposition. Learned men in
                            Rome, who have carefully examined the ancient paintings and monuments in the catacombs,
                            where the earliest records of Christianity were found, have ascertained without a shadow of
                            doubt, that the Deity was always represented as Father and Mother, and not as a Trinity,
                            during the first three hundred years. Even among the ancient Egyptians the duality of the
                            Deity was acknowledged. Isis and Osiris, Father and Mother, and Horus the offspring. Also
                            among the Hindoos there was Brahma and Vishnu, Father and Mother, and Siva, offspring, which
                            was in the course of time finally worshiped the same as the person of Jesus was. (It must be
                            remarked here that it was the Christ spirit, the anointing, or power aud wisdom of God,
                            which was the proper object of worship, but not the man Jesus.) In all ancient accounts of
                            their Vedas among the Hindoos, there is nothing which proves the doctrine of a Trinity. In
                            all the heathen mythology could not be found such a monstrous doctrine as a three male God,
                            he the Father, he the Sou, aud he the Holy Ghost. It was through the subtleness of Satan, to
                            subvert the true work of God, by ignoring all agencies of woman, or a female spirit in the
                            existence of Deity, as well as the redemption of man. 1st. Cor. xi., 7. "The woman is the
                            glory of the man." Therefore it is plain and evident, if Christ promised to come again in
                            his glory, he has to come in a woman. This we declare to all mankind has found place in the
                            person of Ann Lee. Her name is mentioned in the sacred Scriptures the same as the name of
                            Jesus. Zech. iv., 7. "Who art thou, O<pb n="107" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> great mountain ? before
                            Zerubbabel thou shalt become a plain, and he shall bring forth the headstone thereof, which
                            shall be called Ann, Ann Lee." (Those last three words are falsely translated "grace grace
                            to it.") Our gospel brother, Wm. Bussell, found this out some time ago, and it is fully
                            endorsed by Prof. Bush, teacher of Hebrew in the university of New York. Zech. iv., 14. ''
                            These are the two anointed ones that stand by the Lord of the whole earth. " 2nd. Esdras
                            vii., 26. "Behold the time shall come, that these tokens which i have told thee shall come
                            to pass, and the Bride shall appear, and she coming forth shall be seen, that now is
                            withdrawn from the earth. " Now we leave it to all intelligent men and women to judge, if
                            "Adam was a figure of him to come," should it seem to be incredible in this 19th. century
                            and enlightened age, if "Eve was a figure of her to come?" Rom. v., 14. Micah iv., 8. "And
                            thou O tower of the flock, the strong hold of the daughter of Zion, unto thee shall it come,
                            even the first dominion ; the kingdom shall come to the daughter of Jerusalem." Exod. xxv.,
                            18. "Two cherubims (a male and female angel, according to ancient traditions) were placed
                            over the ark and mercy seat. We find in verse 22, "And I will commune with thee from above
                            the mercy seat, from between the two cherubims." Dan. xii.. 5. " Then I Daniel looked, and
                            behold there stood other two, the one on this side of the river, and the other on that side
                            of the bank of the river. " Showing the waters of life to flow forth from between them. John
                            vii., 38. He that believeth on me, out of his belly shall flow rivers of living water." Rev.
                            xii., 12. "On either side of the river was there the tree of life." Prov. xi., 30, and xv.,
                            4. "The fruit of the righteous is a tree of life." " A wholesome tongue is a tree of life. "
                            It is also very remarkable, when we reflect that, according to Josephus, on one side of the
                            double door of the temple was written Father, and on the other side, Mother. The two pillars
                            which stood before the entrance of the temple, are also plainly pointing out to the two
                            anointed ones, Jesus and Ann Lee, and their successors in the work of God. One was called
                            Jachin, which denotes "he that established," referring to Christ's first appearing, and the
                            other was called Boaz, which denotes "in strength," referring to Christ's second appearing.
                            For we read that the glory of the second temple shall be greater than the first. Urim and
                            Thummim written on the breastplate of the high priest, was also in a remarkable manner
                            referring to the two gospel dispensations. Urim denotes light, alluding to Christ's first
                            appearing, and Thummim denotes perfection, alluding to Christ's second appearing. In
                            Christ's first appearing they saw as through a glass darkly, but in his second appearing,
                            "when that which is perfect has come, they shall see eye to eye, and face to face, when the
                            comforter, the spirit of truth, shall lead us into all truth. " Jesus had figuratively to
                            lay the corner stone of the spiritual temple. He revealed the eternal Father. In his time
                            souls were only begotten of God, they were merely a true pattern of the kingdom of God on
                            earth, which Jesus taught them to pray for; "Thy kingdom come." But Mother Ann revealed the
                            eternal Mother ; her work was to lay the cap or<pb n="108" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> headstone on this
                            sacred temple. And as in the course of nature no children could be born without the mother,
                            so no souls could ever be spiritually born, without the co-operation of spiritual parents.
                            We invite all who are willing to live righteously, godly and soberly, to confess and forsake
                            their sins, and live a pure, holy and chaste life to come. "The Spirit and the Bride say,
                            Come. Let him that heareth say, Come. Let him that is athirst Come, and whosoev. er will,
                            let him take the water of Life freely." Rev. xxii., 17. Union Village, 0.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Truth" TEIform="index"/> TRUTH.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bushnell, Richard" TEIform="persName"/>RICHARD BUSHNELL.</byline><p TEIform="p"> [Contributed by F. W. Evans.]The truth must be understanding^ and willingly received,
                            sincerely believed and cordially obeyed or man cannot be spiritually regenerated, nor can
                            the spirit of God's moral attributes be begotten in the soul. For God, in infinite wisdom,
                            goodness and power, has so constituted things that it is impossible for this result to be
                            effected by any oth. er means or in any other way. Consequently, the notion that the spirit
                            of God can, as it were, like the electric or magnetic fluid, enter into man and by its own
                            absolute power effect his spiritual regeneration, at any moment, without the instrumentality
                            of truth, without the exercise of man's moral agency in heartily believing, loving and
                            obeying the truth, is a dark delusive, anti-christian and superstitious doctrine. Truth is
                            the foundation of virtue ; an habitual regard for it is necessary. He who walks by the light
                            of it has the advantage of the noonday sun. He who would spurn it, goes forth amid clouds
                            and darkness. There is no way in which a man strengthens his own judgment, and acquires
                            respect, in society so surely as by a scrupulous regard for the truth. The course of such an
                            individual is right on, straight on. He is no changeling, saying one thing to-day and
                            another to-morrow. Truth to him, is like a mountain land-mark to the pilot, he fixes his
                            eyes upon a point that does not move, and he enters the harbor in safety. On the contrary,
                            one who despises it and loves falsehood is like a pilot who takes a piece of driftwood for
                            his land-mark, which changes with every changing wave, on this he fixes his attention, and
                            being insensibly led from his course, strikes upon some hidden reef, and sinks to rise no
                            more. Truth brings success in our gospel travail, and yields peace to the. soul; falsehood
                            results in ruin, misery and contempt. Therefore, truth is to be adored and obeyed, in all
                            things. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Faith and works" TEIform="index"/> FAITH AND WORKS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Butler, J. F." TEIform="persName"/> J. F. BUTLER.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Faith is not a confidence of our own making, but it is God that works it in a contrite and
                            repenting heart. This faith as Luther in his preface to the epistle to the Romans observes,
                            purifies the heart, destroys the old Adam, overcomes the world, engenders us anew, and
                            changes us in heart, mind, and all the powers and faculties of the soul. If we but think and
                            say I believe, such faith profits us nothing, for faith without works is dead. All true
                            believers have received it under a sense of holy contrition and godly sorrow for sin, and by
                            this we must test <pb n="109" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> our faith, if we feel something of this and apply
                            to Christ by prayer for faith and grace, we have a sure mark for faith already; for if we do
                            not believe, we would not pray. But true repentance goes before faith, by which the heart is
                            not only convinced of sin, and filled with godly sorrow, but changed, so as to hate and
                            abandon all sin ; it is not enough to cleave off some of our sins, or be outwardly reformed,
                            but it must be au inward and thorough change of the whole mind ; for if one sin he reigning,
                            we cannot be said to have repented, and received that faith and power of God which overcomes
                            the world and sin, therefore repent and believe the gospel, Marki., 15. Even so faith, if it
                            hath not works is dead, being alone. James ii., 17. The faith that does not produce works of
                            charity and mercy, is without the living principle which animates all true faith, that is,
                            love t- - God love to man, verse 18th. Show me thy faith without thy works, (that is)
                            pretending to have faith, while we have no works of charity or mercy, is utterly vain ; for
                            as faith, which, is a principle in the mind, cannot be discerned but by the effects, that is
                            good works; he, who has no good works, has no faith. I will show thee my faith by my works
                            of charity and mercy ; will show that I have faith, and that it is the living tree, whose
                            root is love to God and man ; and whose fruit is the good works here contended for. God
                            acknowledges no faith as the operation of his spirit, that is not active or obedient: but
                            the principle of all obedience to God, and beneficence to man is love. Love to God produces
                            obedience to his will; love to man, worketh no ill; but on the contrary, every act of
                            kindness. This humble, holy, operative, obedient love, is the grand touch-stone of all human
                            creeds, and confessions ot faith. Faith without this, has neither soul nor operation; but
                            faith which worketh by love is potent to save. Alfred, Me.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Faith" TEIform="index"/>FAITH
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">With constant faith surpassing doubt I stand and watch the tide go out- -
                                    That 'twill come back I say to you I do not know, and yet I do. At eventide I see
                                    the day Put night on guard and go away Will morning come the mists to woo? I do not
                                    know, and yet I do. I see the sere that autumns bring. Will verdure come with waking
                                    spring? My faith alone can answer true- - I do not know, and yet I do. We see our
                                    loved ones droop and die. Hath Heaven a brighter life on high- - Is death the vale
                                    that leads thereto? 1 do not know, and yet I do.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Chicago news" TEIform="index"/>Chicago News.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prayer in May" TEIform="index"/> PRAYER IN MAY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Shepard, Arabella" TEIform="persName"/> ARABELLA 8HEPARD.</byline><p TEIform="p"> I wander forth and pensive stray, This pleasant morn of lovely May, And O may Angels deign
                            to meet To pour out inspiration sweet. Away from every earthly care, I bend my soul in
                            fervent prayer, And wilt thou answer when I pray And chase all gloomy clouds away? Here I
                            can feel the sighing breeze, That whispers softly through the trees, And I can feel a holy
                            calm That's like a sweet and heavenly balm. Help me to trust my all with Thee, Prom every
                            sinful thing be free; And when life's journey hath an end, My Father, Mother be my Friend.
                            North Union, Ohio.</p></div2><pb n="110" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="War" TEIform="index"/>WAR
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Beattie, Charles J." TEIform="persName"/> BY CHABLES J. BEATTIE
                        </byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">  War is man's masterpiece in crime, - - The scourge
                                    of every age and clime; It sweeps the fertile fields of grain, Destroys the city,
                                    wastes the plain, With battle storm and sulphur rain, While broken drums and
                                    battered shields Are trophies of its battle-fields Alike in every land. War's
                                    ministers of lust and hate Subvert the law, o'erthrow the state, Annihilate the
                                    church and school. Bring anarchy, with iron rule ; Murder their code, Mammon their
                                    tool; Pushing their carnival of gore, Sweeping the wide world o'er and o'er With
                                    fiery glare and brand. Down the dark cycles of the world War's shaft of rage and
                                    malice hurled; On land and sea, in sanguine strife, With fire and sword, with spear
                                    and knife, Preying on human peace and life. Its fields with dead and dying strewn,
                                    Soldier and steed together thrown In one dark charnel grave. Its hireling panders,
                                    trained in fight, Cast on the world war's vicious blight; By its dread mandate,
                                    madly given, The patriot from his home is driven And all the ties of kindred riven ;
                                    The orphans' sighs for loved sires slain, The widow's tears, that fall like rain,
                                    Fail to restore the brave. Its mail-clad hosts have left their scar In every land
                                    e'er cursed with war. Gaunt famine brooded o'er the land : Rank plague, with the
                                    destroyer's wand, And pestilence went hand in hand ; Stern desolation swept the
                                    track [black Where war's wild clouds rolled fierce and Above the battle's din. It is
                                    from chariots rolled in blood, Have crushed the gentle, pure and good; Industry
                                    vanished, morals died, Sweet charity was crucified, And all the streams of mercy
                                    dried, While headless trunk and sightless eyes Attest the glory of the prize, War's
                                    minions ever win. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Chicago, Inter-ocean" TEIform="index"/>Chicago, Liter-Ocean. </bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Strife" TEIform="index"/> STRIFE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hohman, Leopold" TEIform="persName"/> LEOPOLD HOHMAN.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Strife: has been the rule of ages. Pound in all historic pages. Wounds are made, the pain
                            assuages Grief and bliss commingled rages. The right and wrong do oft collide And men for
                            both have often died. Defined, the strife on either side Is always easy to decide. But where
                            both are mixed, confusing Neither gaining ground, but losingAll that's good is not amusing,
                            But to death of both conducing You give the world be-dazzled Youth " An eye for eye a tooth
                            for tooth " Where actions gives them thoughts uncouth They think they know it all forsooth.
                            Aged seniors truth preserving From which there should be no swerving Empty forms and rites
                            conserving Only harm the undeserving. They each in each their place should take And from
                            their lethargy awake To close the strife, firm friends to make, A good to build, an evil
                            shake. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A statement having reference to the use of Alcoholic drink..." TEIform="index"/>
                            A statement having reference to the use of Alcoholic drink...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> [A Statement having reference to the use of Alcoholic drink, made by Eliab Harlow and Garret
                            K. Lawrence of New Lebanon, Sept. 15, 1828. These physicians were good advocates for the
                            temperance cause, even at this early date. Ed.] '' We use alcohol in tinctures and syrups
                            when we think it necessary and in no other case whatever, unless the stimulus of ardent
                            spirits is indispensable. We find that medicine without spirits is far more efficacious,
                            than when given in combination with it, in the majority of stomach complaints. In cases
                            where alkalies, such as Soda or Salts of Tartar are indicated, we add these to syrups which
                            preserves them from souring without the addition of spirits. No definite rule can be given,
                            but it is our firm purpose never to make a free use of alcohol under the cloak of medicines.
                            "</p></div2><pb n="111" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thought" TEIform="index"/> THOUGHT
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">There are blanket sheets with millions of money behind them, and with
                                    but a commercial value that all told do notgive so much thought that is good and
                                    valuable as is contained in this gem from the sparkling, living, glowing pages of
                                    Helen William's little paper, THE WOMAN'S WORLD, published in Chicago for three
                                    cents a copy and $1.00 a year, and the type of which is set by her daughter's hands.
                                    "And the world's thinkers, what of them ? Soul captains; men who lead battalions of
                                    souls in opposition to the hosts of ignorance, and conquer; obliterating their very
                                    memory from the face of the world ; are these not the valiant heroes of earth, whose
                                    conquests shall endure when the conquests of those other captains who have led
                                    bodies only shall have passed as a dieam? I say yes I say that the things which we
                                    see not are mightier than the things which are seen. I say that thought is the one
                                    universal conqueror whose mission is constructive, not destructive, and to whose
                                    care is committed every work that will endure. It is because there are a thousand
                                    non-thinkers to where there is one thinker that the great bulk of the race lies in
                                    chains of the basest servitude. A servitude that no extraneous force- - neither of
                                    organization nor of dynamite, can break ; nothing but the lifting and the lightening
                                    power of thought can reach it. Millions of thoughts from millions of thinkers;
                                    thought individualized ; each thought the seed germ of a life, generating more life-
                                    -this is the lever by which humanity can be raised. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The spirit of truth dwelleth in meekness" TEIform="index"/>The spirit of truth dwelleth in meekness
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> The spirit of truth dwelleth in meekness.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Practical religion" TEIform="index"/> PRACTICAL RELIGION.</head><p TEIform="p">A good lady employed a deacon of one of our Baptist churches to do some carpenter's work
                            which amounted to quite a large sum of money ; and she said, when speaking of the job, " I
                            would just as soon hear Deacon- - - -pray now as I would have before he did that piece of
                            work for me." That's it! We want deacons and all other members of the churches to do in all
                            business relations just that which is right. We believe in a practical religion. Spurgeon
                            asked a young girl, who served as a domestic in one of his families, when she presented
                            herself for membership in his church, what evidence she could give of having become a
                            Christian, and she meekly answered, k-1 now sweep under the mats." And the renowned preacher
                            said it was good evidence, and we agree with him. Real religion leads one to do work
                            thoroughly.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Presbyterian" TEIform="persName"/> The Presbyterian.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile theology" TEIform="index"/>JUVENILE THEOLOGY
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> The Christian Union relates an anecdote the moral of which it
                                    thinks is sufficiently plain. A little girl belonging to a Presbyterian Sunday
                                    school came home from church one day quite indignant because her teacher had said
                                    that Jesus was a Jew. " He wasn't, was he, mother .'"she exclaimed. "Why, yes, my
                                    dear, I suppose he was," the mother replied. " But I thought he was the son of God."
                                    "So he was, try dear." "Well, I don't see, then. " said the little sectarian, " how
                                    he could be a Jew, for God is a Presbyterian. "</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Be not a spider..." TEIform="index"/>Be not a spider...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Be not a spider to select The poison, and the good neglect, But like a bee collect the sweet
                            From every little tiower you meet.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="C., A. J." TEIform="persName"/>A. J. C</byline></div2><div2 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p"> Truth never fears rigid examination.</p></div2><pb n="112" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>NOTES. </head><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> THE MANIFESTO. Office of publication. The Manifesto is published at Shaker Village, Mer.
                                Co. N. H. All articles for publication should be addressed to Henry C. BLINN, and all
                                letters on financial business to A. Y. Cochran. .75 .40 One copy per year, postage paid,
                                " six months, " " Send for specimen copy, free. </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Non-essentials or essentials" TEIform="index"/> NON-ESSENTIALS or ESSENTIALS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> It is not an uncommon thing to have our attention called to the non-essentials in
                                religion. The idea is conveyed to the mind, that in this enlightened age, very little is
                                needed to remind one of his duty to God, and on this account the rites and ceremonies of
                                the church or churches are only so much of superstition or form as has been preserved to
                                us from the religions of an earlier date. MuchN&gt;f this may be quite true, and
                                possibly we may be holding on to some things which have no vitality as a saving grace.
                                We review the past and readily observe in ignorant and semisavage races, that many of
                                the ceremonies of religion were phases of atonement, and brought forward as a
                                propitiation for that which they held to be sins against God. _ Jesus understood this so
                                well that he did] not hesitate to inform his disciples that the time would come when
                                intense cruelty would be inflicted u rrman, by those who through ignorance believed
                                their religion demanded it. Men shall kill you, said Jesus, and think they are doing
                                God's service. With this outburst of their own savage natures, agreeing so well with
                                their dominant ideas of might as right, they enter upon the sanguinary action under
                                solemn vows, wi'h the cause of churchal religion welling up in the heart. It may be
                                quite true that in the religious world, might becomes right much oftener than the spirit
                                of righteousness becomes right. From the earliest ages we have the record that one part
                                of the race has been enslaved by the other. Sometimes these captives have been held in
                                loathsome dungeons, manacled with heavy iron chains, and beaten and abused even unto
                                death, while at the same time the inhuman masters would be offering up prayers to God or
                                singiug psalms of praise. Wars of devastation have been engaged in and immediately
                                religion is appealed to for aid and for victory. In connection with all this, churchal
                                ceremonies are instituted and the faithful give thanks that they are not as other men.
                                In the midst of schisms and wars the church has moved along from age to age, and even
                                now in these times of plenteousness and peace, is more or less trammeled with those
                                obstacles that have been handed down through superstition and fear. It is not strange
                                that many of these observances are looked upon by thinking minds as among the
                                non-esseatials of a religious life, and can have no intrinsic value in the establishment
                                of righteousness in the heart. Neither is it strange that the prophet should introduce
                                his religious exercise with this peculiar remark. "I am a man of unclean lips, TERMS.
                                MAY, 1887.<pb n="113" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> and I dwell amidst a people of unclean lips." It might
                                seem quite difficult to reconcile the statement, that a religious body could be one of
                                unclean lip's, or of an impure language. Perhaps they had grown to claim that
                                inheritance as a sacred right, not to be disputed, and had the credit of much,
                                seemingly, religious talk, of drawing near to God with their self-righteous speeches,
                                even to the honoring of his name, but at the same time it was a ceremony of the lips, as
                                their hearts were far from Him. All that they did as solemn reverence was what they had
                                learned from the traditions of men. This fitting rebuke may not be out of place among
                                the thousands of pious church going people of to-day. Observe, said. Jesus, what the
                                Scribes and Pharisees bid you, but do not after their works, for they say and do not. If
                                men teach for honor, or for gold and silver, these emoluments become the essential
                                feature in their lives. They soon learn the theological path in which they must walk,
                                and that creedal forms and ceremonies take the precedence of an unspotted life, or a
                                practical self-denial. By whatever name a Christian body may be designated, if they
                                become the children of God, they must be led and governed by the spirit of God. The
                                Prince of Peace must be the director and everything be ruled by this system of
                                discipline. Holy wars and religious persecutions belong to a barbarous and dominant age,
                                where force ruled, and are destitute of the first elements of Christianity. It has been
                                learned that a merciful man exercises mercy even toward a beast, and certainly it is far
                                more essential that he should show mercy to his fellow men. The one special feature of
                                the religion of Jesus teaches us that it entered into the very life of his chosen
                                followers and made of them, new creatures. Instead of becoming selfish, and designing
                                and bending everything to his own will, he is now to study the lessons of a peacemaker
                                and through the manifestation of love for all souls learn to become a child of God. He
                                then receives the wisdom that comes from above, which is first pure, then peaceable,
                                gentle and easy to be entreated, full of mercy and good fruits, without variance,
                                without hypocrisy. This testimony of the Son of God and of his disciples stands first as
                                an essential qualification to form a foundation upon which to build a Christian
                                character, that will reflect honor upon the name of Christ. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Plea for temperance" TEIform="index"/>A PLEA FOR TEMPERANCE
                        </head><p TEIform="p">[Contributed by Harriet Shepard.] <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> The chief event which distinguished the Kansas Governor
                                    St. John's administration was the passage of the Constitutional Amendment in 1880.
                                    As to the beneficial results of that change there is indisputable evidence. An
                                    official return of the State prisons for the first nine months of the following year
                                    shows that one hundred and fourteen prisoners were sent to the penitentiary, while
                                    two hundred and twenty-six, or nearly double the number, were incarcerated during
                                    the corresponding period of 1880. Gloomy predictions. During the campaign there were
                                    not wanting politicians who urged that prohibition would impoverish the State, and
                                    would also prevent immigrants settling<pb n="114" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> there, and especially
                                    that German immigrants would never be persuaded to make their homes in a State where
                                    lager could not be procured. Governor St. John, (The Hon. John P. St. John, the
                                    Prohibition candidate for the Presidency,) in an often quoted speech, thus
                                    criticised those predictions in the light of events which have followed the
                                    prohibition law. " Let us see if we are losing business: Take the Santa Fe road for
                                    instance, which earned in June, 1881, $438,998 more than it did in June, 1880.
                                    Business is increasing everywhere ; our State never was so prosperous ; let us see
                                    whether we are losing in dollars and cents or not. I find that in the year 1876 we
                                    commenced the biennial system of assessing real property. In 1877 there was no
                                    valuation on real property, and consequently the increase was on personal property
                                    alone ; it amounted to $364,821,352 ; in 1879 the increase on personal property was
                                    $623,146,871, and in 1881 the increase on personal property reached $1,024,361,159.
                                    Can't we stand that kind of ruination ? WHERE WE LOSE. "The population of the
                                    penitentiary, December 30, 1880. was 725. July 1, 1881, it was only 659 ; thus it
                                    will be seen that in one spot, and one only, are we losing population, and I think
                                    we can stand it. We were told that we should get no German immigration. I went down
                                    the Santa Fe road not Jong since, and had to ride on the rear platform of the
                                    sleeper on a camp-stool, because there was no room in the inside of the train, and
                                    when I finally got in the front car I found it full of Germans. I supposed, of
                                    course, that they were going to New Mexico or Colorado, where they could get whiskey
                                    and beer, but discovered that they were really going to Kansas. " A gentleman said
                                    to a man, who seemed to be acting as interpreter for them. ' Whfere are these people
                                    going?' and was informed, ' To Kansas;' 'Why,' said he, 'they can get no beer
                                    there.' The interpreter repeated the assertion to one who seemed to be a leader,
                                    then turned to the gentleman who addressed him, and said, 'They say they are not
                                    going to Kansas for beer ; that they go to secure a home for themselves and families
                                    ; that a home gives more true happiness than all the beer manufactured.' I said to
                                    myself, they are on the right platform. They are coming to Kansas for a legitimate
                                    purpose, and we welcome them with all our hearts. We are having a better class of
                                    immigration this year than ever before." Governor St. John is an effective orator,
                                    enviably successful in the principal test of a public speaker- -viz., securing and
                                    holding the attention of his audience. He speaks slowly, correctly, and distinctly,
                                    showing no hesitancy and using no rhetorical device. There is, therefore, everything
                                    in his manner to add to the impressiveness of his subject and of his felicitous
                                    style of treating it. He knows the value of illustration to add to the weight of
                                    argument, but while his memory is stocked with apt anecdotes, he never tells one for
                                    its own sake, or to help him out of a failure in his speech. When delivering an
                                    address in the Cooper Union, New York, he related the following incident, which had
                                    occurred in connection with his own official duties, and it produced a sensation in
                                    the crowded assembly. A heart-broken woman came into my office with a babe in her<pb n="115" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/>arms to beg the pardon of her husband, who was under sentence
                                    of ten years imprisonment in the penitentiary for homicide. She showed papers
                                    recommending the pardon from the judge who tried the man, the prosecuting attorney,
                                    and other prominent men. After closely examining the papers, I said, ' If I were to
                                    consult my personal feelings, I should gladly let your husband go ; but I am bound
                                    by my official duty and that forbids it.' '' The woman fell at my feet in a paroxysm
                                    of weeping. ' Then hear me' she cried, till I tell you how he came to be where he
                                    is. We were married seven years ago ; we went to a town (mentioning the place,) and
                                    there in our little village we were happy. My husband was sober, industrious, and
                                    thrifty. By great exertion and self-denial we finally got our home paid for. But in
                                    an evil day the State licensed a saloon, and let it plant itself right between my
                                    husband's shop and our house. He was prospering so well that he could leave his
                                    business in other hands and lose an hour or two without feeling it. He was solicited
                                    to enter this saloon, and weakly yielded. Hour after hour he spent there, playing
                                    cards. One day lie became embroiled in a drunken quarrel, and, fired by drink,
                                    struck a man and killed him. He was tried and sent to the penitentiary for ten
                                    years, and I had nothing to live on. Bye and bye the sheriff turned us out of our
                                    comfortable home into a rough shanty, neither lathed nor plastered. The cold wind
                                    came in through the walls and ceiling. My oldest boy took sick and dkd. Then little
                                    Tommy, my next fell sick and died. Now this babe in my arms is sick, and I have
                                    nowhere to take it. The State licensed that saloon ; the State murdered my children
                                    ; and now in God's name I want you to set my husband free.' I said I would- -and I
                                    did." Innumerable instances are related of men who have been induced by Governor St.
                                    John's appeals, in public and in private, to quit drunken habits and lead sober
                                    lives. Fully occupied as he necessarily is with official duties, an opportunity to
                                    talk to a poor drunkard is one he has never been known to neglect, and there are few
                                    Sundays on which lie is not preaching gospel temperance in some city or village in
                                    his State. Somewhat above middle height, St. John is a fine specimen of physical
                                    manhood ; robust, active, energetic, decisive in all his movements, he gives those
                                    with whom he comes in contact the impression of being vigorous in work, prompt in
                                    action, and unswerving in purpose ; yet with all his manly qualities, those who have
                                    seen him listening to a tale of distress or urgiug a dissipated man to forsake his
                                    evil ways, carry away a deeper impression of his delicacy, sympathetic kindness, and
                                    sensibility, for which other aspects of his character had not prepared them. It is
                                    not surprising that such a character should have aroused the unbounded enthusiasm of
                                    those citizens of Kansas whose views are in harmony with his own, or that he should
                                    have won a regard more devoted than is usually given to a mere politician. How
                                    fervent that affection is, is manifested when the name of St. John is mentioned to a
                                    citizen of the State, one of whom, in a letter we received during his Governorship,
                                    naively said, '- - We almost worship our Governor. Is it a sin?"- -An abstract from </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Christian herald and signs of our times" TEIform="index"/> The Christian Herald and
                                    Signs of Our Times,</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="116" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My dear little S.- Your very pretty letter is..." TEIform="index"/>My dear little S.- Your very pretty letter is...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon" TEIform="index"/> Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> My Dear Little S.- -Your very pretty letter is before me. I can rejoice with you that you
                            have experienced that soul cleansing work of a Believer and that your twelfth birthday was
                            the day you sought the holy baptism of the fire of truth which will consume sin, rather than
                            the pleasures of an earthly character. How much more real and substantial are the things of
                            the spirit, than are earthly riches which are but shadows, they perish with the using. If
                            you hold on to the good you have received in the effort to consecrate your little self to a
                            life of the Virgin Order, you will grow in all those lovely virtues which you can see in
                            those who are older, and spend many happy years in living a good life. You will be able to
                            pluck up the wild weeds of nature which grow without cultivation and in their stead grow the
                            rare plants of beauty which need so much care, viz., purity, peace, humility, love and all
                            the gospel graces which adorn the true followers of Christ and Mother Ann. As you grow older
                            you will often need the same holy power which you felt on that memorable day, and if you are
                            faithful and obedient, you will be able to call to your assistance help from the same
                            heavenly source. As you have felt happy in taking up this cross, the like experience will be
                            felt in future days. Every building must have a foundation to stand upon, some are solid and
                            firm, some very poor and unsubstantial, so with souls in the gospel work, those who dig deep
                            and uproot all the wrongs aud evils of their hearts, will lay their foundation on the rock
                            of truth, they will be firm. Such we expect our dear little S. to be and on that twelfth
                            birthday we hope you laid the corner stone for a true and noble structure, a good life. Our
                            prayers and blessing shall be for our good child. Please give our kind and best love to your
                            dear teacher and all your little companions. Lovingly and truly, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bullard, Harriet" TEIform="persName"/>Harriet Bullard.</byline></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reminiscenses of my Shaker childhood" TEIform="index"/> REMINISCENSES OF MY SHAKER CHILDHOOD.</head><p TEIform="p"> SPRING. After the long dreary winter we were generally prepared to give the Spring a hearty
                            welcome and eagerly we began to look for the first blades of grass or the pussy willows
                            which came out by the ponds where we were sure to find the first. Then would follow the
                            tender leaves and the lovely Spring flowers, for never have I since seen such beds of
                            violets as those that used to spring up at Canterbury. Before these came, however, farmers
                            had begun to gather the sap from the sugar maples, and make the never-to-be-forgotten maple
                            sugar. How we looked forward to those days spent in the Sugar Camp. Indeed, they almost
                            seemed to me like visits to fairy land, such entire freedom from unnecessary restraint as we
                            thought, while the marvelous gymnastics we there performed would hardly be credited to us
                            when seen on duty elsewhere. We sometimes fancied ourselves the wild Indians about which we
                            had read, and sometimes would almost attempt to fly through the fields rather than run, or
                            perch in the dark spruce trees to collect the succulent gum which exuded therefrom and
                            meantime relate stories that were quite amazing to our listening playmates. It was there,
                            also, when seated on hard board benches we ate the best lunches off roughest tables, or
                            quietly seated upon the ground would pluck the winter-green berries too busy to be noisy
                            even. All these incidents formed part and parcel of the delightful clay. <pb n="117" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/>As the time for returning home drew near we would hover around the open
                            fire-place and sing those lovely songs which can never be forgotten. Ah! Such delightful
                            hours as those were, too rare not to be appreciated and remembered by the participants and
                            when at last we reached home one would hardly recognize in this subdued band the noisy
                            children who left it in early morning. Soon to rest we went to live over the day in dreams
                            if not too weary. Anon we began to have out of doors work to do, for when the grass began to
                            start, the door-yard must be made tidy so that it should cover all the ground. After helping
                            to carry in the wood we would pick up the chips and rake up the remaining debris. The fresh
                            glad sunshine the soft winds and the happy twitter of the birds could not fail to make us
                            healthy, happy and hearty, and so we were still busy and bright in spite of the winter's
                            confinement which was useful discipline and the best kind of training for us. Then the
                            flowers came in abundance and fragrant beauty and soon after the early fruit. I remember one
                            year I had a small bed of flowers all by myself which in those days was an uncommon
                            privilege; perhaps these good friends saw that I needed the fresh outside air, and so took
                            this way to give it to me, so I was allowed to assist the sisters in the Garden house and we
                            spent many long days among the flowers, plants, etc. I was as happy and busy as the bees
                            which seemed to think the flowers were made for them alone and often gave us a sharp
                            reminder of their opinion. What a garden that was, with Elder Eli s orchard on one side and
                            the Garden house on the other while between the branches of the trees you could see the
                            Sisters' Shop and the old kitchen house now gone to decay. I have had many a happy day-dream
                            there, breathing in the perfume of the flowers and listening to the drowsy hum of the
                            toiling bees or the patient voice of the sisters who gave me useful talks on Botany and also
                            a desire to acquire more of the knowledge which these delightful surroundings began to teach
                            me. Healthy labor promotes rest and here we could enjoy both. As the weather began to get
                            warmer the summer term of school approached, and how anxiously I used to search through my
                            memory for the remains of last year's harvest and set them in order, for immediate use.
                            These first days were always very trying to me for I wished so ardently to excel in this
                            part of my education if possible, for I loved the occupation itself and beside I earnestly
                            desired to please my dearly loved teacher. Now I find myself back to the point from which I
                            began the reminiscences. Should they seem imperfect to some of you who read them, remember
                            that it is a quarter of a century since these events occurred during which time owing to a
                            change of residence and circumstances beyond my control, I have been completely severed from
                            these scenes, and the dear friends of my youth. For those who have known and cared for me in
                            my wayward, careless childhood, I have written these papers to prove my grateful recognition
                            of their untiring devotion. "Should old acquaintance be forgot And never brought to mind?- -
                            Should old acquaintance be lorgot In the days of Auld Lang syne ? </p><byline TEIform="byline"><index level1="Carll, Anna P." TEIform="index"/>Anna P. Carll. Providence 11. I.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian communism no. 2" TEIform="index"/> CHRISTIAN COMMUNISM. NO. 2.</head><p TEIform="p">TAKEN FROM THE CINCINNATI POST. A Shaker Interior strikingly pictured. Everything moves with
                            the cheerful punctuality of an Old Fashioned Cloclc. It was just before noon of a blustering
                            day last week that our sociable little train on the Cincinnati, Lebanon and Northern narrow
                            gauge ambled into Lebanon and we scattered. I sought the comfortable fire of the hotel and
                            the additional comfort of a hot dinner, both unusually comforting to me that day, because in
                            my rush to catch the train in Cincinnati I had neglected to change my frock coat for my
                            "reefer. " "How far to the Shakers'?" "Four miles. The 'bus leaves here about 2. 80. That
                            will take you over. It goes right by there." "No. I'll walk. "<pb n="118" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> From
                            Lebanon it is up hill to the ridge on which " Union Village, " as the Shaker settlement is
                            called, is located. The first mile was a pretty cold walk in the face of a raw wind, and I
                            did not by any means despise the philosophy of a youngster by the roadside who had dropped
                            down almost out of sight in a post hole his red-faced, overcoated and mittened father had
                            just dug. But a mile's sharp walking and a run or two up hill turned a good blast into my
                            internal furnace and made me "warm as toast, " and " red as a boiled lobster. " WINTER
                            SCENERY. The road passes through some beautiful woods of those deciduous species and
                            varieties for which the Ohio valley is famous. All were bare save the birches, whose skirts
                            were still brown with persistent foliage, though their ambitious tops were bare. They stood
                            like Amazons bared to the waist to contend with old Boreas. I noticed a good deal of "down
                            timber" in the woods, going to waste, there being little demand for it in these days of
                            cheap coal. A couple of miles out from Lebanon I met a Shaker brother and two sisters clad
                            in their plain woolen clothes and riding contentedly to town in a carry-all behind an
                            unambitious horse. Two miles further on I turned off onto the Franklin pike, and in a
                            quarter of a mile had passed the big, four-story, substantial building and barns, sheds and
                            shops of one of the Shaker " families, " and had come to another fine building on the
                            opposite side of the road, which building is called " The Office. " This is a large
                            three-story frame, built 70 years ago, of oak and black walnut, and still as stanch and
                            strong as when first erected. It is painted an unobtrusive slate color. Across from it is
                            the big, plain, two-story white frame church, its lower windows closed by broad shutters.
                            Its gable ends look up and down the pike, which makes one - -of its sides front the pike. In
                            the side, thus made a front are two doors. "The Ministry " of two Elders and two Eldresses
                            live in a building back of the church. Steepleless and shuttered, I took the church for a
                            very neat and commodious storehouse. Beyond "the office"" is the very fine pressed-brick,
                            slate-roofed new building of the " Church Family, " built, says a block inset near the roof,
                            in 1844. To me, coming from the sooty houses and buildings of Cincinnati, it looked as if it
                            had been built a year or two. Across the street are the "old building" of the " Chuich
                            family, " the steam laundry, the corn-drying house, the blacksmith shop, the infirmary, and
                            several other buildings. Entering the front hall of "the office" through the wide and very
                            heavy black walnut front door, whose rubber weatherstrip drew a long and noisy breath as it
                            swe-e-e-pt along the polished hard-wood floor, I found no one there. The hall was wide,
                            clean as the floor of the sky, and in the middle distance stood a tall wooden pump. An
                            oldfashioned Connecticut wooden clock ticked slowly and sedately against the wall. Strips of
                            ingrain carpet laid neatly on the polished floor invited me onward, and I was advancing down
                            the hall when I met a Shaker sister, who told me that "Elder Charles" was "in there,"
                            pointing to a room she had just left, leaving the door open. Entering I Avas cordially
                            received by a white-haired, pleasant-faced old man who was rocking in an old-fashioned
                            straightback rocking chair comfortably cushioned. I took its mate and there we chatted for a
                            few minutes while another Shaker sister in glistening, satiny brown dress and cape busied
                            herself tidying up the room, and wiping dust from the mantel and chest of drawers. In a few
                            minutes "Elder Charles" (known to the world as Charles C. Clapp) and I adjourned to the
                            postoffice "not to disturb the sister with our conversation." The postoffice is a room in
                            the same building and serves the mailing needs of all the families and of some neighbors
                            outside. Elder Charles is nearly eighty, but has the spry step of young manhood. He was a
                            merchant and a Presbyterian way back when this century was in the thirties, and went off in
                            the great Millerite excitement. Upon the collapse of that movement he joined the Shakers and
                            has been with them ever since. He is a sort of spiritual and theological authority in the
                                "familv."<pb n="119" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> From him I learned that there are about 18 societies of
                            Shakers in the United States, located in New York, Mass., Conn., Ohio, Ivy., N. H., and Me.
                            These contain over fifty families and about 2000 members. SHAKER GOVERNMENT. Here at Union
                            Village resides a " ministry " composed of Matthew B. Carter, Oliver C Hampton, Louisa
                            Farnham and Adeline Wells. These have oversight not only of the Union Village Society, but
                            also one near Harrison, Hamilton county, O., one near Dayton, another near Cleveland and two
                            in the "Bluegrass region" of Kentucky. Each family is governed by Elders and Eldresses.
                            Those of the first or Church family are Charles C. Clapp, Leopold Goepper, Ellen lloss and
                            Julia O'Connell. Those - -of the North family are Isaac Beals, Amos Babbitt, Matilda Butler,
                            and Sarah Cochran. Those of the West family are Ruth Siebenthal and Wm. Dynes. In addition
                            to the " Ministry, " who have spiritual oversight and an advisory power in all temporal
                            matters, and the Elders who lead the family, there are deacons and deaconesses, and
                            "caretakers," (overseers or foremen) and an "agent" who transacts business with the world.
                            All these offices are appointive, and the appointing power is in the "Ministry." Four or
                            five Brethren and Sisters reside in "the office" to care for and conduct it. Sister Emily W.
                            Hampton is in charge. Visitors and hired hands are lodged and boarded in "the office."
                            New-comers who want to make experiment of Shaker life with a view to joining, are housed and
                            fed at what is called "the gathering family, " on the Lebanon pike. here's pure comfort.
                            While Elder Charles was explaining these things to me, Sister Emily was preparing my room.
                            When conducted to it, I found a very comfortable apartment on the first floor front. A rag
                            carpet laid down in overlapping breadths covered the floor. A brisk wood fire in the close
                            stove sang its low, cheerful monody. In one corner stood the cot bed, roomy and comfort
                            promising, with its fat feather-tick and ample blankets and "comforts." Behind the stove was
                            neatly riled a good supply of wood, which so long as I stayed Elder Charles kept well
                            replenished. Near the stove hung the shovel, poker, wisp-broom and dust-pan, to inculcate
                            and facilitate cleanliness and tidiness. Against the wall in another part of the room hung
                            an honest broom, the only kind the Shakers make. A chest of drawers, a wardrobe, a leaf
                            hinged to the wall like a table-leaf to serve as a writing-desk, two plain chairs and a
                            straight-backed, armed, feather-cushioned rocking-chair, which I found to be the acme of
                            comfort, completed the furniture of the room. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hoe your own row" TEIform="index"/>HOE YOUR OWN ROW
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cary, Alice" TEIform="persName"/>BY ALICE CART
                        </byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> I think there are some maxims Under the sun,
                                    Scarce worth preservation; But here, boys, is one So sound and so simple 'Tis worth
                                    while to know ; And all in the single line, Hoe your own row ! If you want to have
                                    riches And want to have friends, Don't trample the means down And look for the ends
                                    ; But always remember Wherever you go, The wisdom of practicing, Hoe your own row !
                                    Don't just sit and pray For increase of your store, But work, who will help himself,
                                    Heaven helps more. The weeds while you're sleeping Will come up and grow, But if you
                                    would have the Full ear, you must hoe ! Nor will it do only To hoe out the weeds,
                                    You must make your ground mellow And put in the seeds, And when the young blade
                                    Pushes through you must know There is nothing will strengthen Its growth like the
                                        hoe!<pb n="120" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/> There is no use of saying What will be, will be; Once
                                    try it my lack-brain, And see what you'll see ! Why, just small potatoes, And few in
                                    a row, You'd better take hold then, And honestly hoe! A good many workers I've known
                                    in my time Some builders of houses, Some builders of rhyme, And they that were
                                    prospered, Were prospered, I know, By the intent and meaning of Hoe your own row !
                                    I've known too, a good many Idlers, who said, I've right to my living, The world
                                    owes me bread ; A right! lazy lubber ! A thousand times No ! 'Tis his, and his only
                                    Who hoes his own row.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected,</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Stick to the truth..." TEIform="index"/>Stick to the truth...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Stick to the truth.- -Motto of Lord De Blctquiere. </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I would rather be at peace..." TEIform="index"/>I would rather be at peace...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> I would rather be at peace with conscience than possess the world.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. A.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers
                        </head><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/>Hall's Journal of Health</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>Phrenological Journal and
                                Science of Health</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Herald of health" TEIform="index"/>Herald of Health</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> Hall's Journal of Health. April, Contents : The Occult Forces; Injurious and Adulterated
                                Beverages; The Prayer Cure practically applied; Quinine; Food Adulterations; Hygiene,
                                Its Agency in Therapeutics; Drugs and Medicines; Dental Surgery; Rheumatism; etc., etc.
                                Office 206 Broadway, N. Y. Phrenological Journal and Science of Health. April, Contents:
                                Rev. J. Hyatt Smith; Familiar Talks with our Young Readers; Heredity and its
                                Limitations; Primitive people of the Colorado; Jacob Melton; The backwood's preacher;
                                Jules Verne; Decay of Negro Element in Civilization; Notes from a Teacher's Diary;
                                Decline of population in Rural Mass., No. 3. Animal Magnetism as a Curative Agent;
                                Cancer; Notes on Science and Industry; Poetry, etc., etc. Fowler &amp; Wells Co. 753
                                Broadway, N. Y. Herald of Health. April, Contents: Health and Working Habits of the
                                German Emperor; Rev. II. W. Beecher on Physical Exercise; Artificial Sleep as a Curative
                                Agency; Spring Food, Clothing, Bathing, etc. Women and the Household, etc., etc. Herald
                                of Health Co. 13 Laight St. N. Y. A</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Providence of God..." TEIform="index"/>Providence of God...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Providence of God Lies near to every one The way that we have trod, The travel yet to come.
                            Let us pursue with care, And meet with humble mind Whate'er is ours to bear, In this, true
                            peace we find.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Truth never was indebted to a lie" TEIform="index"/>Truth never was indebted to a lie
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Truth never was indebted to a lie.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Young" TEIform="persName"/>- - Young. </byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.
                        </head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pease, Martha" TEIform="index"/>Martha Pease</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="G., A." TEIform="persName"/>A. G.</byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bloomberg, Johanah" TEIform="index"/>Johanah Bloomberg</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., N." TEIform="persName"/>N. B.</byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Persons, Leander A." TEIform="index"/>Leander A. Persons</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">He had lived with the society since the time he was four years of age. He had
                                        prepared to unite in the morning worship last Sabbath, but just before the time,
                                        fainting, fell on his bed, and suffered from intense pain in his stomach and
                                        bowels, till death came to relieve him. His funeral occured Wednesday afternoon,
                                        a goodly deputation from Harvard society attended. "Very impressive and
                                        interesting addresses were made by many of those present, all of whom seemed
                                        thankful to be there, both of those from outside friends and the Brethren and
                                        Sisters. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Turner's public spirit" TEIform="index"/> Turner's Public Spirit</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Parkhurst, Hannah" TEIform="index"/>Hannah Parkhurst</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> Martha Pease, at North Family, Enfield, Conn Apr. 2, 1887. Age 81 yrs. 10 mo. and 10
                                days. Another faithful soldier of the cross or Christ has been called home. One who was
                                much beloved, a trustworthy member and a burden bearer in our Community for more than
                                sixty years. A. G. Johanah Bloomberg, at Center Family, Pleasant Hill, Ky., Apr. 10,
                                1887. Age 59 yrs. 10 mo. and 10 days. She occupied the position of an associate Eldress
                                at the time of her death. Johanah was born in Astrunda Co., Westmoreland State, Sweden.
                                Came to the U. S. in 1847. United with the Believers in 1855 and has been an upright and
                                faithful member. N. B. Leander A Persons, at Shirley, Mass., Apr. 12, 1887. Age 75 yrs.
                                6 mo. and 27 days. - - Turner's Public Spirit. Hannah Parkhurst. at Enfield, N. H., r.
                                15, 1887. Age 74 yrs. G mo. and 4 clays.</p></div3></div2><pb n="121" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><!--  
THE MANIFESTO.
Perlet's Reminiscences op sixty tears in
the National Metropolis : By Ben : Perley Poore. Published in two volumes of
544 pages each, by Hubbajd & Bros, of Boston, Mass., and sold only by subscription.
The work is printed on excellent paper,
profusely illustrated and substantially and
tastefully bound. This interesting history
introduces us, at first to the sixth President
of the United States,- -John Quincy Adams.
It informs us that "President Adams took
great interest in arboriculture. He planted
in the grounds of the White House the
acorns of the Cork oak, black walnuts, peach
plum and cherry stones, apple and pear
seeds, and he watched their germination and
growth with great interest. A botanic garden was established under his patronage and
naval officers were instructed to bring home
for distribution, the seeds of such grains and
vegetables as might be desirable to naturalize."
The author then very pleasantly takes us
through all the succeeding administrations of
our honorable and honored Presidents, and
illustrates, graphically, the official and social
life of the Senators, Representatives and
other dignitaries who walk in advance of the
American Republic.
Passing through these years of extended
public care we have many instances of the
mannerly and mirthful side of life, which
might be made a chapter of "peace on earth
and good will to man, " but the shadow of
this comes in the rough language, the coarse
actions and the cruel and vindictive spirit
which too often ruled the minds of those
great men.
The work brings us to the present date,
and closes after a few brief notices of our
present chief Magistrate,- -G-rover Cleveland.
The busy, participant life of the writer and
his keen observation of men and their manners before the public has afforded him
abundant resources, from which to present
to the world, this period of Congressional
history in all its. varied and vivid qualities,
that with a slight stretch of the imagination
we find ourselves looking upon those scenes
of years gone by as though they were transpiring to-day.
The work contains hundreds  of excellent
illustrations, including the portraits of the
men who have officiated in the government
of the United States, as Presidents, Cabinet
officers, Senators, Representatives, arid officers of the Army and Navy. Also of many
noted characters who have visited the Capitol- -of many of the public buildings that
beautify the Governmental city and of many
interesting incidents that have transpired
from time to time.
Once opened the book will be reluctantly
laid aside, till the last chapter is reached and
the last page perused.
MEDAL   MACHINES.
HEW YOEK STATE AGEIOULTUSAL WOSZS,
1st. Premiums at all Competitive  Trials
Railway, Chain andLeverHonePowera, Threshers and Cleaners, Threshers
&, Shakers, Clover Hullers, feed Cutters, Wheel Morse Rakes, Morse Pitchforks* Shingle Machines, Straw Preserving- Rye Threshers, Portable Steam-J2ng-ines, Ciller and Wine Mills and Presses,
Dog; and Pony Powers, Disc Marrows
& Springy Tooth   Harrows.     "Robinson's Hay Press, of four sizes- Will
work as easy with one horse, as
others with two. Made with Steel
Gearing which can not be broken."
WHEELER & MELICK Co.,
Send stamp for Circular and report of Centennial
trial.
CHEAP Reading.     "-5ST.
back numbers of THE HOME COMPANION, no two alike, filled with good
reading for  all homes.           Address,
The Home Companion,
Troy, N. H.
IPCHTC llfAMTim to canvass for one of
Autil I b WAN I fcU the largest, oldestestablished, best-known N urseries in the country. Most liberal terms; Unequaled facilities.
Prices low. Geneva Nursery. Established
184- -.   W. tfc T. SMITH, Geneva. N. Y.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
Mt. Lebanon,  N. Y.,
<pb n="" id="p"/>
 --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>