<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm1702" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">23</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">17</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">02</biblScope><date value="18870201" TEIform="date">February 1887</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">25-48</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="17" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="02" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!-- 
<pb id="p1"/>
FEBRUARY.
THE
MANIFESTO.
Published by the United Societies,
" Every plant which my heavenly Father hath not planted shall be rooted
up." - - Matt. XV, 13.
Shaker Village, n. H.
1887.

<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
CONTENTS.
The Gospel Testimony,
Duty First,
Fridge and Thanksgiving,
Christian Virtues,
Note,       Not Far,         -          ...
Letter from Elder F. W. E.    The First Command,
Testimony   of Prudence  Hammond,
The Cloud  Lifted,
Letter from A. C. S.
Liberty enlightening the World,   In Remembrance,
Rules for Holy Living,
Notes.    Cease to do Evil,
Rheumatism and Diet,
Imagination and Disease,
Is man a fallen being?
A Heavenly Transition,
My Shaker Childhood,
Letter from Martha Carr,
From the Littie Children,
The River of Life,       -                    Books and  Papers,
Deaths,              30
32
86
38
39
40
42
43
-1,1
45
it;
41
The Cosmopolitan
The handsomest, most entertaining, low price,
illustrated family magazine in the world.
($2.50 per year, with a $2.25 premium
free.) Sixty-four beautifully printed pages in
each number, filled with short stories, sketches,
travels, adventures, bright and brief scientific
and literary articles, by distinguished American
and foreign writers, such as Julian-Hawthorne,
Harriet Prescott Spofford, George Parsons
Lathrop, Louise Chandler Moulton, J. Macdonald Oxley, Ella Wheeler Wilcox, H. H.
Boyesen, Catherine Owen, Rev. R. Heber
Newton, Alphonse Daudet, Paul Hevse, Count
Tolstoi, Th. Dostoivsky, William Westall and
many others. Also entertaining JUVENILiE
and invaluable HOUSEHOLD departments.
One or more illustrated articles and several fullpage engravings in every number.
A Shannon   Letter and
Bill File or a Shannon
Sheet-Music Binder
Free   to   every
Subscriber.
These premiums sell
everywhere for $2.25
each. The File is the most
perfect device ever invented for the preservation and
classification (alphabetically and according to date)
of all letters, bills, etc.
Any paper can be referred
to, taken out and put back
without disturbing the
others. With the Binder
one can insert or take out
any piece of music without
disturbing any other sheet.
Get SAMPLE COPY at NEWS STAND or
send 20 Cents to publishers.
ACCENTS WANTED. Blfl COMMISSIONS PAID.
Schlicht & Field Co., Rochester, N. Y.
- -2.25.
EED
SEND ron^T Illustrated CATALOGUE
Vegetable. Flower, Kield g* gj> - -r* |- -^<^
Flams, Bulbs Implem'is. %9 &- - &,B^55
C* Oi ffiT C   "y m^il on- application.
I    If CL   Don't neglect writing for it.
HIRAM SIBLEY & CO.
ROCHESTER, U. Y.         CHICAGO, ILL.
322-326 E.
 12-H H. Clark St.
SEWING-MACHINE
HAS NO EQUAL.
PERFECT SATISFACTION
New Home Sewini MacMne Co.
- -ORANGE, MASS.- -
30 Union Square, N. Y.   Chicago, 111.   St. Louis, Mo.
A'tJanta, Ga.   Dallas, Tex.   San Francisco, Cal.
FOR   SALE   BY
26
28
IS
<pb n="" id="p"/>
Vol. XVII.
FEBRUARY,  1887.
No. 2. --><pb n="25" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gospel testimony of Mother Ann Lee and the elders, William Lee and James Whittaker no. 11" TEIform="index"/> The Gospel Testimony of Mother Ann Lee and the Elders, William Lee and James Whittaker.
                            No. 11.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> Published expressly for ike several Communities of Believers in 1S16. Re-written by Henry C.
                            Blinn. Mother Ann and the Elders, return to Harvard. Soon after the sad termination of the
                            visit to the town of Petersham, Mother Ann and the Elders returned to Harvard for their
                            home, and from that place made occasional visits to the Believers in Shirley, Woburn and
                            other places, confirming them in their most holy faith. The opposition in and about Harvard
                            continued to manifest itself and frequently brought severe sufferings upon the Believers.
                            Threats were made by secret as well as by open enemies and individuals were subjected to
                            abuse, such as stoning, pilfering, cheating, mocking and other acts of meanness, nod yet no
                            general persecution had been experienced. As the gospel increased and the testimony of truth
                            prevailed, those who were opposed began to be more and more alarmed. Auti-christ could not
                            endure a religion which threatened thedestruction of the foundation of his kingdom. He could
                            not allow so many of bis subjects to pass from darkness to light, by converting them from
                            the error of their ways. As the Believers were averse to wars and fightings, and as this
                            principle had been inculcated by Mother Ann and the Elders, it was conspicuously brought
                            forward as a suspicious evidence of their hostility against the -best interests of the
                            public. Through pretence of fear for the safety of the country this was made the foundation
                            for a general alarm, and measures were taken to prevent the apprehended danger. The worldly
                            wise men finally decided that Mother Ann and the Elders must be driven from the town of
                            Harvard. Arrangements were accordingly made and in January 1782... a captain of the militia
                            with a company of men presented themselves before the residence of the Believers, and there
                            received orders to drive the Shakers from the town unless they would promise to leave by a
                            specified time. On the arrival of this lawless gang, the Believers were assembled for
                            worship in the Square House. The militia were stationed around the dwelling, with clubs
                            poised on their shoulders after the man-<pb n="26" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> ner of muskets, evidently
                            thinking that ^bj this maneuver they could frighten the Believers. The captain at once
                            obtained peaceful admittance into the house, and with a show of authority, requested Mother
                            Ann and the Elders to leave the, town. Mother Ann replied, "I expect to go to-morrow, if it
                            is God's will. " "Very well," said the captain, "if you are going so soon as that, I shall
                            ilet you alone." Soon after this, while taking his leave, he again promised not to molest
                            her, as she was going away to-morrow. " Yea, " said Mother, "I expect to go to-morrow, if it
                            is God's will, and I shall return the next day, if it is God's will." The captain left the
                            house to join his - -company. During this interview, several of the soldiers had entered the
                            room where the family were engaged in worship. Some of them manifested an unbecoming
                            rudeness by entering the .apartments where they were not welcomed. The Brethren zealously
                            defended their home as best they could from the advances of such a lawless class of men.
                            Daniel Wood who stood guard, before one of the doors, was abusively treated hj a violent man
                            in the company. He was beaten over the head with a club and left helpless and bleeding
                            profusely. The captain on seeing this made inquiries into the cause, " One of your men did
                            it, " replied Daniel- The captain ordered his men to leave the house fimmediately. They soon
                            passed out and the whole company left the place without offering any further abuse at this
                            time. The next day Mother and the Elders went from Harvard, but returned again in a few days
                            to see the Believers at the Square House. As they had been so unkindly threatened for some
                            time and disturbed with mobs, and feeling that their way was nearly hedged up for usefulness
                            in Harvard, they were brought under severe suffering of soul. Through the ministration of
                            the spirit they were warned of God to leave their home in Harvard, and at once assembled the
                            Believers, and encouraged them to remain steadfast aud faithful to the cross of Christ. This
                            was a day of deep tribulatiou. Strong hearts were bowed in sorrow. Men who for years had
                            bravely battled with carnal weapons against the enemies of their country, and who gloried in
                            the salvation which their own arms had wrought for the nation, had now laid aside all their
                            weapons of war that they might " put on the whole armor of God, and be able to fight against
                            the powers of darkness." They were learning a Christian experience. "My kingdom," said
                            Jesus, "is not of this world, therefore my soldiers will not fight." The assembly were all
                            on their knees in fervent prayer for protection. Mother Ann was in prayer with her children.
                            " I should be willing to die," said she, "and go to our Lord aud Christ, if you could do
                            without me." All well knew that she was called of God to preserve her life that she might do
                            good to the whole household of faith. This Avas an effecting and sad season for all, and
                            many of the Believers, at this time, consecrated aneAv their lives to God. After the last
                            farewell was spoken. Mother Ann aud the Elders aud Mary Partington journeved as far as the
                                resi-<pb n="27" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> dence of Zacheus Stevens. Early the following morning the mob
                            came to the Square House and were sadly disappointed, in not finding Mother Ann and the
                            Elders. The leader of the company ordered a barrel to be placed by the door of the dwelling,
                            upon which he called the Brethren and Sisters, one at a time, for examination, that he might
                            be able to gain some information concerning the Believers who had left Harvard. The mob then
                            proceeded to the home of Isaac Willard and began to search his premises. Isaac did not stand
                            in fear of this lawless crowd and forbid them to open a door in his house, or they should
                            suffer the full penalty of the law. They quite well understood the man with whom they were
                            dealing and soon dispersed. Mother Ann and the Elders proceeded to Enfield, Conn., and
                            arrived at the residence of David Meacham, on the first of March. At this place they were
                            obliged to pass through new scenes of suffering. Many Believers called to see them, and also
                            many strangers. The ministration of the Elders was for the encouragement of all who had
                            received faith in the gospel work. While this word of God was being received with joy and
                            zeal by the Believers, it did not fail to awaken the jealous fears and arouse the
                            persecuting spirit of the workers of unrighteousness. By a preconceited plan a mob of two
                            hundred men and boys stood before the house of David Meacham, under the direction of a
                            militia captain by the name of Bush, and a lieutenant named Terry. The captain ordered
                            Mother Ann i'nd the Elders to leave the town within one hour or they would be carried out by
                            force. Elder James Whittaker addressed the company as follows, "We came to this place
                            peaceably, to visit the Brethren and Sisters, but since you have judged yourselves unworthy
                            of the gospel of Christ, we will go to some other place." As it was considered prudent to
                            leave Enfield, the Believers passed on to the ferry, some eight miles distant, followed
                            closely by the mob. On their way to the ferry, Mother Ann and her companions realized that
                            they were surrounded by a host of angels, which so encouraged them, that they broke forth in
                            songs of praise and thanksgiving, Avhile their wicked persecutors followed on in gloomy
                            silence. As they were passing through a village near the ferry, a noisy rabble gathered and
                            mingled with the mob, using very threatening and abusive language. At this instant a young
                            American officer who was on the main street, observed the mob and on inquiry was informed
                            that they were driving the k'elect lady" and her followers out of the town. The officer was
                            well armed, and mounted on a spirited horse. He was an entire stranger to the Believers, but
                            he Maw that they were peaceable and were patiently enduring the insulting language of the
                            mob without making any reply. He immediately rode to the side of Mother Ann's carriage, and
                            accompaned her to the ferry. He seemed to have no fear of the mob, and after speaking to
                            Mother Ann very kindly couducted her to the boat, assuring her that she should not be
                            harmed. The wonder-struck mob who had a short time before been so libsral with their<pb n="28" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> threats, were suddenly, as quiet as though they had been paralyzed. As
                            the boat was pushing from the shore, the bravado spirit welling up in the breast of one man
                            he relieved himself by this speech. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Duty first, pleasure afterward" TEIform="index"/> Duty First, Pleasure Afterward."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="White, Anna" TEIform="persName"/> ANNA WHITE.</byline><p TEIform="p"> The above quotation is frequently given as an incentive to labor. And were it not for the
                            relation the one bears to the other, it might seem too imperative and demanding. If " there
                            is a time for everything under the sun," that is good and true, then is there a suitable
                            time for every employment and for recreation, and for the expansion of every faculty of mind
                            and body, as well as for the development of those higher faculties that tend to mifold the
                            spiritual part of our being. If we in our researches after truth "seek first the kingdom of
                            heaven and its righteousness," and find it, then are we sure of a home that is eternal as
                            the heavens, we are sure that our souls' needs will be amply supplied, and sure of the added
                            promise of shelter, food and raiment, those creature comforts of which the Father knoweth
                            and provideth. By a strict adherence to Christian principles, which include the daily cross
                            aud self-denial over the inbred passions and propensities of nature, duty becomes sternly
                            requisite, and to the natural instincts there seems no beauty or comeliness iu it. Viewed
                            from this standpoint, the way of righteousness is not only narrow but rough and cragged.
                            Mountains high surround us, vallies low must be traversed, rivers deep and currents rapid we
                            must ford, until the feet become sore, the hands heavy, the head weary and the heart faint.
                            Where then, may be asked, is the pleasure aud the satisfaction derived by the observance of
                            a principle that involves such rigid discipline? We answer. The first and most essential
                            thing, is to secure a relationship to God- -the fountain of all truth and goodness- - whence
                            alone permanent happiness proceeds ; or in other Avords, find our heavenly Father and Mother
                            from whom we have wandered, and against whom we have sinned. And as there is an innate
                            desire iu every human soul for something spiritual, and a general belief iu immortality and
                            eternal life, the return to God will eventually succeed. And as reconciliation ensues,
                            through confession and repentance of sin, so happiness follows in its wake, peace flows like
                            a river, joy springs up iu the soul, light breaks forth as the morning, while purity and
                            love shed their hallowed and saving influence. When this condition is attained, the duties
                            of life yield pleasure be they light or tarduous ; the one being so interblended with the
                            ether, that it is difficult to separate them. It would be well to heed the injunction of the
                            wise Preacher of olden times to w'Fear God and keep his commandments, for this is the
                            whole'duty of man." And in connection with the above, to likewise remember the apostles
                            reproof, " She that liveth in pleasure is dead while she liveth." Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Unless the Lord is with you..." TEIform="index"/>Unless the Lord is with you...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Unless the Lord is with you all your efforts are vain. </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head">Do not reckon anything your own...</head><p TEIform="p"> Do not reckon anything your own that can be given away.</p></div2><pb n="29" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Praise and thanksgiving" TEIform="index"/> PRAISE AND THANKSGIVING.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Shepard, R. A." TEIform="persName"/> R. A. SHEPARD.</byline><p TEIform="p"> "Praise ye the Lord. Praise, O ye servants of the Lord, praise the name of the Lord." Psalm,
                            cxiii. Is it not meet, that we give praise to the "Giver of every good and perfect gift?" To
                            whom, we owe everything, "in whom we live, and move, and have our being?" Ah yea, it is
                            meet, that we should do this. We were " made a little lower than the angels ; " having power
                            to reason ; gifted with superior intelligence, above all created things on earth. Shall we
                            silently pass on our way, receiving all these gracious gifts as though they were our right?
                            0 nay, shall we not rather give praise, and thanks, for the countless blessings bestowed
                            upon us? Surely, praise and thanksgiving, shall go hand in hand Avith our petitions for
                            still moreible.ssing. Our hearts are continually desiring protection, and care. But, ore we
                            as ready to give thanks for the mercies daily received from the "Great AllFather?" Will not
                            the truly thankful heart, sometimes, overflow in praise, and give thanks to God? "Bless the
                            Lord, O, my soul," for all His benefits ; yea, bless Him. Humbly bowing before the throne of
                            grace ; grateful for the manifold mercies vouchsafed to us. Not only the blessings of every
                            day, but also for the merciful preservation, from the wages of war, and pestilence, the fury
                            of the elements ; the dreadful calamities which have filled the laud with death, sorrow and
                            destruction. O may avc walk softly, humbly, before Thee, our God ; and bless Thy holy name,
                            for all Thy loving-kindness, Canterbury, N. H, </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian virtues" TEIform="index"/> CHRISTIAN VIRTUES.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Burger, Sarah J." TEIform="persName"/>SARAH J. BURGER.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Truth to the heart in love reveals The way from error's night, And gilds the life with noble
                            deeds, Cho'ice gems of heavenly light. Hope lifts the curtain of the mind, Till virtue's
                            dawn is seen; Her glow is like the morning sun Upon the meadows green. Love is the
                            light-house to the soul, 'Lumed with the lamp of Peace, Where joy and lasting happiness Bid
                            gloom and sorrow cease. Mercy her purple clusters yield A harvest rich and rare, Inviting
                            souls to drink the wine Of life abounding there. Humility where art thou found? Close by
                            some lowly stream, Where fancy ne'er would hie for rest, Or cast a shadowy dream. And
                            Meekness by her side is found, With Charity and Prayer, And these combined will stay the
                            hand Of sordid want and care. Uniting these with Faith and works, What noble gifts appear
                            Wkhin the temple of the soul, Ripe fruit of toiling years ; And cherished in the heart for
                            good, They'll bear the victor's palm, While angel joy shall flood the soul, And heaven's
                            holy calm. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Note" TEIform="index"/> NOTE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescott, James S." TEIform="persName"/> JAMES S. PRESCOTT.</byline><p TEIform="p"> What a sweeping declaration that was for an apostle to make, " We know that we are of God,
                            and the whole world lieth in wickedness." 2 John v., 19. Why? Because he abstained from that
                            forbidden "tree" which in the beginning God commanded, "not to touch " until further orders
                            ; and which the whole world is most eager to grasp, consequently is now suffering under its
                            penalties. North Union, Ohio.</p></div2><pb n="30" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Not far" TEIform="index"/> NOT FAR.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Newton, Agnes E." TEIform="persName"/> AGNES E. NEWTON.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Not far from the soil of sin Though white thy robes to-day; Not far from the daiig'rous path
                            Where the feet of many stray. Not far from Virtue's dwelling The snares of sin are set; And
                            near the peaceful harbor Fierce tempests may be met. Not far from light the darkness
                            Obscures the Christian's sky ; Not far from good the evil Is ever lurking nigh. Not far O
                            Christian traveler The goal thou long hast sought; Not far the priceless treasure Which
                            ne'er with gold is bought. Not far is Heaven's portal Its pearly gates ajar ; Near is thy
                            home immortal Its glories not afar. Not far the song of triumph 1 The world I've overcome ;
                            " If thou wilt all surrender To-day, is vict'ry won. Not far the good nor evil The broad or
                            narrow way; But near is strength and courage Our safety, watch and pray. Not far 0 Christ
                            our Savior Be from each struggling soul; Thy cross shall be our refuge Thy law, our lives
                            control. Canterbury, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The following letter was written to a..." TEIform="index"/> [The following letter was written
                            to a Lancashire friend in England, in Oct. 1886, and published in the Manchester, England
                            Guardian. Ed.]</head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon" TEIform="index"/> Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Friend :- -Your welcome letter was received. Undoubtedly you are, like myself, full to
                            overflowing, doing all the good you can. I suppose we must all be content when we arc, doing
                            our best, whatever the result. We can write and speak the word of truth given us for the
                            time being. If it be only as a grain of sand, we know that the whole mountain of truth is
                            composed of an aggregate of such sands. Hepworth Dixon warned me that the English people
                            could not be moved like Americans. Yet they would have filled two St George's Halls- -the
                            Spirit helped us. I was well satisfied with my reception. When in Manchester I saw the stone
                            prison in which Mother Ann is said to have been imprisoned for Sabbath breaking- -disturbing
                            a National Church-audState religious meeting. I have no doubt but that they acted with
                            strict legality, as she did not fail to give them just occasion. She was a Breaker and a
                            Shaker, and she accepted the consequences as opposing a system, not the ministers of a
                            system. The progress which has been made in England in vegetarianism since I was there is, I
                            think, marvelous. There was then not a restaurant where you could procure a Christian meal.
                            Now I am informed by an English friend who with his family have just closed a four week's
                            visit at the North Family there are vegetarian restaurants in the cities and towns of
                            England. There is not an equal of that in America. Yet a very great change is going on
                            slowly in this country. At almost any first-class hotel you can get oatmeal and what they
                            call brownbread- -Graham bread, &amp;c,- -but I do not know of a place in America where
                            you could procure a loaf of genuine whole wheaten flour bread, unleavened, except in the
                            North Family at Mt. Lebanon, Shaker Village, where I reside. Between the bread we make and
                            what the hotels furnish there is as much difference as between English Christianity, <pb n="31" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> with its marriages, private properly, and war, and Primitive
                            Christianity, with its celibacy, community of goods, and non-resistance. On the date of this
                            letter I will be seventy-eight years of age. I write this without glasses. I have been in
                            this village fifty-six years, and fifty-six years of that time I have been a strict
                            vegetarian except that I have used eggs and milk sparingly. I hope to finish my course on
                            earth harmless and undefiled by unclean animal food. When I come to England I hope to find
                            some who are prepared to found our ;order there permanently, and to establish the second of
                            the seven cycles of Shakerism, adding to the faith of the first cycle the virtues of land
                            limitation- -not owning any more land than the members can cultivate without hiring ;
                            vegetarianism- -not keeping any more animals than are absolutely necessary ; and physiology
                            and hygiene- -their food being their medicine, sickness and disease being relegated to the
                            outside order, death being the simple process of eternal sleep to the body. Wlien I do go to
                            the spirit land it will be to help to prepare a place for my friends. All men and women who
                            are working for the good of others according to the degree of light with which they are
                            blessed- -all such are my friends ; and in my Father's and Mother's house- - the spirit
                            world- -there are many mansions- -spheres- -enough to accommodate every degree of human
                            travail. It is a ladder whose rounds reach from the hells to the heavens, on which the angel
                            messengers descend and ascend continually. David was a "man of blood." If a man "after God's
                            own heart," was it not the heart of the "God of Israel" the Lord of Hosts of fighting men
                            and women. "- - Even David hath not ascended into the heavens"- -the Christ heavens. Do you
                            not think when such men of blood as David and Joshua, Cyrus, Alexander, Caesar, Alfred,
                            William the Conqueror, Cromwell, Nelson, Wellington, Napoleon, Washington, Grant, and their
                            fellow-criminals, their Marshals, are waked up to see that they have been great on earth-
                            -great murderers- -that they will call upon the rocks and mountains to hide them from the
                            face of Quakers and Shakers- -nonresistants? When unier conviction for sin they desire to
                            find a relation to the; Prince ot Peace- -Jesus- -and to the peaceable kingdom of the
                            Branch- -Ann Lee- -to the first and the second appearing of Christianity upon earth, these
                            once mighty men will be mightily tormented, and they will seek to undo what: they have done.
                            They are the powers of the world to come, they fouudetl alii the nations and governments of
                            earth ia blood, in and by force, in the divine; right of kings and a birthright aristocracy.
                            The American revolution was an earthquake to all human governments:: its au.hors and
                            instigators proclaimed Right in place of Force. Paine, Jefferson, Franklin, Washington,
                            &amp;c, opened a new epoch when they declared that human beings were born "free and
                            equal- -endowed with inalienable rights,'' most of which rights the misnamed Republic has
                            deprived the people of up tothis time. All women are disfranchised to begin with. But the
                            Fathers said "the American Government was not a Christian Government. " That was a good
                            deal. The Church was got rid of. Then they said, "The people are sovereign ; they are the
                            source of all power.""' <pb n="32" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/>In the eud the American Government will be kia
                            new earth," the Shaker Order "a new heaven.'' Then "thou sbalt not kill" will be the First
                            Commandment. Hitherto American statesmeea have killed and eaten animals. Therefore they have
                            not ceased to kill and destroy each other. You are inspired by those men from the spirit
                            world to begin at the beginning- -to cease to kill and eat animals. If the landlords of
                            England should become vegetarians they would restore the laud to its owners- -the people.
                            They would desire to raise and nurture human beings in place - -of rearing wild beasts aid
                            birds. Ill fares the hind, to hastening ills a prey Where beasts are nourished and the men
                            decay. I sat down to write a few lines when I began, and I am covering two or three -
                            -sheets. Please excuse my runaway thoughts and the multiplication of many words.- -In much
                            love.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="First command" TEIform="index"/> THE FIRST COMMAND.</head><p TEIform="p"> As far back in the history of this country as 1850, a class of persons at the North who were
                            very anxious to -soothe the slaveholders of the South and save the Union, could find no- -to
                            them- -stronger and better way to do it thaaa by taking as authority the Bible, and from its
                            pages attempting to prove the !God-given foundation of slavery ; and to do it they selected
                            these words ; "'cursed be Canaan : a servant of servants shall he be. " They did not turn
                            the pages of the book and read, ''Undo the heavy burdens, and let the oppressed go free and
                            break every yoke." And to further fulfil their constitutional obligations, thev insisted
                            that in accordance with New Testament teachings fugitive slaves should be returned to their
                            masters, or rather, owners, and cited Paul's example in sending back Onesimus to Philemon.
                            Rut they did not quote Paul's words "not now as a servant, but above a servant a brother
                            beloved." In shoit. they used such portions of the Bible as to them seemed to sustain their
                            position, never for a moment looking at the other side of the case. Indeed, to them there
                            was no other side. Somewhat analogous it seems to me is the position of those who criticise
                            the Shakers on the " letting the world run out" subject. They tell us that the "first
                            command" given to man was to "multiply and replenish the earth," and they forgot to add,
                            "and subdue it." Taking it for granted that the record is correct who was that command given
                            to? Adam. When? After he had become corrupt and fallen from his high estate, hid condition
                            of purity? Nay! it was given, if at all, when he was in his iunocency, and it meant
                            obedience to law. Replenish the earth in compliance with law, bring perfect beings into this
                            world, those who having been lawfully begotten have the right to their inheritance. Did Adam
                            obey ? Nay, not till lie had become corrupt and then he- -like our modern Adams-
                            -multiplied, and when he brought his work to fruition his first sou became a criminal by
                            murdering the second. Is bringing law-breakers into existence complying with the first
                            command? What did the " subdue it" mean ? Would it be unreasonable to say that it meant
                            subdue all and every tendency in yourselves to use your procreative powers except in
                            compliance with law, subdue that part of your nature which may be dormant but which
                            nevertheless is Hid<pb n="33" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> within you, and having subdued it and being fitted
                            by that experience to obey the command, do it in order and consistently. How willing people
                            are to comply with law when it suits their own purposes ! How anxious to comply with it as
                            they understand it; and they understand it as their selfish, lower, animal instincts would
                            have them understand it. Is it to be presumed that men and women marry so that they may
                            yield obedience to what they designate as the "first command?" Not at all. They marry
                            because they can legally do what if they did not go through a marriage ceremony would be
                            criminal in the view of human enactments. For the higher law they have but faint regard.
                            Marriage as a rule is simply a thin veil of legality thrown over the indulgence of lust; and
                            when that is satiated the parties tire of each other, and the most trivial means are used to
                            give employment to lawyers and the divorce courts. 1 would like to have any candid person
                            say how many out of every 1000 marriages are contracted for the purpose of solely complying
                            with "the first command. " I think if he struck off the three ciphers and used the remaining
                            numeral for his reply he would be nearly correct. Indeed a large proportion of persons who
                            marry (so results show) seem to aim at the avoidance of obedience to the "first command. "
                            How many of the fifty-five millions of people in the United States to-day came into
                            existence in compliance with law? The number is incontrovertably small, and the millions are
                            here to-day as the result of violated law. Lust brought them into existence, and thus
                            drunkenness, robbery, murder, licentiousness, dishonor and corruption in all its hydraheaded
                            forms fill the land. When men and women marry solely for the purpose of complying with the "
                            first command " and bring a pure, elevated, untainted race into the world, a race that will
                            ennoble life, and cease to marry for the reason that Paul'wrote, that "it is better to marry
                            than to burn," then and not till then let them criticise the Shakers for advocating and
                            living a life which to the benighted and contracted vision of the worldling means only
                            "letting the Avorld run out." When mankind become honest, temperate, unselfish, chaste ;
                            when men "cease to do evil, and learn to do well," in short when all men turn into and walk
                            in the Shakers' path, which is the path that Jesus trod, then if utterance is given to the
                            thought that the human race will die out, it will be time enough to frame a fitting reply.
                            A. Canterbury, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Testimony of Prudence Hammond" TEIform="index"/> Testimony of PRUDENCE HAMMOND.</head><p TEIform="p"> In my youthful days I often felt greatly exercised in mind about a future state. The
                            exercises of my mind were more than I could express to any one. I knew I daily lived in sin,
                            and could find no way out. I often prayed to God as well as I knew how, but found no
                            releasement. These exercises increased upon me as I grew older, so that at the age of
                            nineteen, which was the time of the great revival in New Lebanon, I was exceedingly wrought
                            upon; but I could find no way out of sin, nor could I find any one that could help me or
                            show me the way out. I could not even find one in whom I could place confidence as a
                            Christian leader, because I did not see any one who manifested by<pb n="34" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/>the
                            works of righteousness that the spirit of Christ was formed within, which I believed really
                            necessary in order to be a Christian. I kept house for my father at that time, and though he
                            was a professor of religion, I could find no help from him. Some would tell me I was
                            converted and born of God, and try to persuade me to be baptized and join the church ; but
                            all this availed nothing ; it would not ease my troubled conscience. I felt myself a child
                            of wrath, and greatly feared the judgments of God. I had been in this troubled state of mind
                            about three years when I first saw Mother Ann and the Elders. I visited them in June, 1780,
                            being then twenty years of age. Mother asked me if I was sick of sin I told her I saw no way
                            out of sin. She repeated the question, "Are you sick of sin?" I knew not what to say. She
                            turned to some who were present and said, "This young woman is sick of sin." Then turning to
                            me, she said, "You can find no way out of sin till you confess your sins." She then told me
                            of some circumstances and mentioned a number of the transactions of my childhood and youth,
                            which I knew it impossible for her to know but by divine inspiration. I said within myself,
                            "Is not this the anointed?" Here I felt that I had found somebody that could help me, and
                            show me the way out of sin ; and truly it proved so. I found no deception nor witchcraft
                            here- -nothing but the plain and honest truth, and my conscience bore witness to it. Here I
                            found, for the first time, the image of Christ displayed in his followers ; a people who
                            manifested true godliness in all their deportment. Here I was taught to confess and forsake
                            all my sins, as the fruits of the only true repentance which is acceptable in the sight of
                            God; and to take up a full cross against every carnal indulgence, and deny myself of all
                            ungodliness and every worldly lust, and live a pure and chaste life. I confessed my sins,
                            and felt as though I was confessing them to God iu the presence of his witnesses ; and I
                            found great releasement of soul by it. Mother bid me take faith in the power of God, that my
                            life might be according to my faith. She said "If you will be faithful and obedient, you
                            will never want for bread ;" not natural bread, said she, "I mean the bread of life. "
                            Ireturned home with full confidence in her testimony, and a settled determination to
                            maintain it. My health was restored. At another time I visited them at Watervliet, when
                            Mother told me the state of my own mind and feelings, just as they were, without any
                            information from me whatever. These things were, at that early age of my faith, a sufficient
                            confirmation to me of her spiritual sight and discernment, if I had never received any
                            further evidence: but I have since felt too much evidence in my own soul, and had too great
                            experience of such divine manifestations ever to have a moment's doubt. Mother was always
                            meek and harmless in her manners, and manifested a pure and unspotted life in all her
                            movements. I visited Mother at AshfieM, at a time when there was a great concourse of people
                            there, from various parts of the country, and much work to be done, especially on the part
                            of the sisters. A little time before this I had the bone of one of my fingers broken, and it
                            was very much swelled, so that I could not use that hand. I mentioned this cir<pb n="35" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> cumstance to Mother and she sent word that if I had faith in the power of
                            God, I might be healed. I immediately unbound my hand without any inconvenience. My hand was
                            well and remained so. - - When Mother was taken from the house of George Darrow by the mob
                            and so cruelly abused, I was there. By her direction I kept by the side of the carriage all
                            the way to Grant's. Some of the wicked men tried to beat me off, but were not able. Mother
                            often encouraged me to keep up, and not let my faith fail, and said, " You will not be hurt.
                            " When she arrived at the house of Eleazer Grant, the mob crowded around her. She requested
                            them to stand off, but they refused. One man in particular was very rude and insolent.
                            Hannah Kendall, who was with Mother, from a sudden impulse of feeling spoke with
                            considerable energy, and said, "Go off- -you are a" thief and a robber." This greatly
                            offended the man, and he swore she should prove it. Mother instantly called out, "Where is
                            Prudence ?" I stepped up to her- -"He?e," said she, "Hannah has called this man a thief and
                            a robber, and he says she shall prove it." I replied, " It is the truth of God, Mother- -he
                            broke into my father's house, and stole a large sum of money." This I spoke from the
                            immediate impulse of my feelings, for I did not know the man. But he was highly offended and
                            struck me; and I found him to be the very man who, some time before, actually broke into my
                            father's house, one night, and took a considerable sum of money ; but was soon after
                            detected and brought to justice. His comrades, who knew the truth of this charge, laughed at
                            him on the spot; and the guilty culprit soon sneaked off, and we saw him no more. Through
                            all the violent and abusive transactions of this day, Mother remained firm and composed ;
                            and though she was shamefully abused, and treated with savage cruelty, she bore it with
                            patience. During the ministration of Mother Ann I had opportunities of seeing her, and being
                            with her a great deal. A little before she left this world I was with her most of the time,
                            day and night, for a number of weeks ; and I can testify before all people, that she was the
                            most godly person I ever saw, in all her manners and deportmen1;. She bore a powerful and
                            swift testimony against all pride, lust, covetousness, idleness, extravagance, intemperance,
                            drunkenness, and every kind of excess. She taught us that all these things, and evil of
                            every kind must be done away ; that nothing could be saved but what was of God; and she
                            always confirmed her precepts by her own example in all things. And I can truly say, I never
                            saw anything in her conversation and conduct, from the first day I saw her till she left
                            this world, but what bore witness that she was led and governed by a spirit of pure
                            godliuess. One might as well try to convince me that there is no day nor night, as to alter
                            my faith concerning Mother Ann. I know of a truth that Christ was manifested in her ;
                            because I know that I received the spirit of Christ through her ministration. I have obeyed
                            her testimony and I have ever found the same spirit in all her successors, down to the
                            present day. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God assisting there is nothing to be feared" TEIform="index"/>God assisting there is nothing to be feared
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> God assisting there is nothing to be feared.</p></div2><pb n="36" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cloud lifted" TEIform="index"/> THE CLOUD LIFTED.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Johnston, Mary" TEIform="persName"/> MARY JOHNSTON.</byline><p TEIform="p"> How very forcibly has the writer experienced the above phrase in numerous and various ways.
                            Though young it is true in this life's journey, yet beingblest with a good degree of
                            experience in the ups and downs of Christian war- j fare, and realizing the blessings of a
                            living and true faith, that God our Father and Creator, will help us through every trial, I
                            have learned the lesson of trust and reliance upon his mercy and love. How many the
                            obstacles that often surround us, and environ the unwary in the tangling mesfces of
                            worldliness and discouragement, leaving us in doubt, almost to despair of ever again seeing
                            the silver lining, that never fails to break through the darkest cloud and illuminate the
                            dreariest day. Instinct teaches us to look to a higher Power for aid and guidance in all
                            circumstances of life. But I sometimes think we are prone to seek some other source of
                            relief, and are thereby too easily influenced by what other people may say, to insure any of
                            the real, true substance and blessings that are awarded to all, who are diligently seeking
                            to be under the protection of Heaven's love. If we have received a right faith in the
                            knowledge of God's plan for complete salvation and redemption, we shall never experience a
                            doubt as to the validity of his word. Although we are submerged in deep waters of oppression
                            and tribulation, let us not be likened to a certain Irish chieftain, who Avas receiving
                            baptism of a worthy Baptist elder. On being plunged beneath the rolling torrent, he held up
                            his right arm, and when questioned why he did so, replied, "I reserve this to fight my
                            battles with;" thus putting to naught God's promise, "that he will sustain the faithful,"
                            and imploring his mercy at the same time. However we shall all learn sooner or later that "a
                            little reserve and thou'lt fail surely, " will prove to be true in our experience. Every
                            cloud has a silver lining and so has every sorrow, and if we submit ourselves to the Divine
                            Order and direction placed in Zion, aud there* lay the weary burden down, we shall feel at
                            once the happy consciousness of peace and rest. What a breaking away of clouds and
                            dispersing in the distance we shall experience ; leaving a way clear for the bright
                            effulgent rays of Divine love. What a glorious transformation that soul realizes who has
                            "turned from darkness into light." I feel thankful to God that I have been called to the
                            great privilege of living this life of Christ here on earth ; aud may it ever be my earnest
                            endeavor to persevere in keeping my feet firmly planted on the rock of this everlasting
                            gospel, which will bring a sure reward to all those who will try the self-denying process.
                            God grant a living spirit, May ever with me dwell; Thy favor Lord, to merit, And loud thy
                            praises swell. Pleasant Hill, Ky. </p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear eldress J.; This morning I suggested..." TEIform="index"/>Dear eldress J.; This morning I suggested...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New Hampshire, Shaker Village, November 1886" TEIform="index"/> Shaker Village, N. H., Nov.
                            1886.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Dear Eldkp:ss J. ;- -This morning I suggested to Ida, who is sitting near me, to write a
                            good letter to some one, today, with eyes open, while I would write one to your address with
                            eyes closed. So we commenced to perform the wonderful feat. After writing two <pb n="37" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> pages in utter darkness I found that if 1 continued this project I might have
                            to go hunting for the stray verbs,,which I discovered on opening the eyes, had so wandered
                            from their respective nominatives that there could be no telling what special nouns and
                            verbs ought to dwell together; meantime some of the adjectives seemed leaping over the keeu
                            edge of the sheet in pursuit of the nouns which it was their duty to cl scribe, and thus I
                            revoked my promise ;tud wrote the remainder with eyelids ajar. Permit me to say that last,
                            evening one special text from the Gospel came vividly before me. it was this. ''Let your
                            communications be yea, yea and nay, nay, for whatsoever is more than these cometh of evil. "
                            So vividly did this appear that 1 fancied I could hear the glorious voice of the divine
                            Counselor who uttered the same upon the Sacred Mount more than eighteen hundred years ago.
                            As the fanciful vision faded I began to recall and compare my own habits of speech
                            therewith, in words, sentences, common remarks, and in daily converse With others. While
                            thus occupied the text seemed to grow into limitless proportions, and as it grew assumed a
                            significance more positive, more autboratative than I had ever be'fore realized. I mentally
                            exclaimed, why, what" a reformation might have gone through every Christian nation, ere
                            this, had this one sacred injunction been regarded. If my inference is correct, it is
                            enjoined upon every professed follower of Christ to be careful to speak the exact truth on
                            all occasions, about every circumstance or incident with which they are connected. That no
                            conversation, however common place, mirthful or serious, grave or gay, can be right
                            according to this standard- -unless true. No exaggerated statements about persons or things,
                            no overdrawn comparisons though clothed in language however select, can find admittance
                            within the limits of this text, for whatsoever is more than truth, cometh of evil. Adherence
                            to this would soon rule out all vulgarisms in speech, all slang phrases, all idle words, all
                            careless expressions. No grammar nor dictionary could so efficiently chasten our utterances
                            as the spirit of truth which still breathes its divine inspiration upon the reverential
                            heart. What would become of slander, exaggeration, frivolous thoughts and imaginings,
                            careless hints relative to A. B. or C. if in every Christian household this text was taken
                            as a standard? "Let your communication be yea, yea and nay, nay, for whatsoever is more than
                            these cometh of evil. " Now, dear J., if I have not rendered the biblical saying correctly
                            or according to your understanding will you not refer it to those who are well versed in the
                            scriptures, and set me right. You will please accept a universal tribute of love from every
                            one at home. Ida has kept her part of our morningagreement very faithfully, and has written
                            a good letter to Eldress A. C. whom she remembers very pleasantly. I need not apologize to
                            you for this letter as I intended that it should seem just like home without any
                            qualification or polish whatever. It is just six o'clock P. M. and I must bid you a kind
                            adieu. Lovingly ever, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stickney, Asenath C." TEIform="persName"/>Asenath C. Stickney.</byline></div2><pb n="38" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Liberty enlightening the world" TEIform="index"/> Liberty Enlightening the World.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bowers, Lucy S." TEIform="persName"/>LUCY S. BOWERS. </byline><p TEIform="p">Jt is the mission of Liberty to enlighten the world, to bear aloft her blazing torch,
                            piercing through the darkness of error, leading the nations from shadows of ignorance to the
                            perfect glory of righteousness and truth ; and well may the people of these latter days, who
                            have felt the inspiration of her presence, and shared the benefits of her blessings, jcin
                            hands even over the great waters, to raise an illumined statue in her honor, an emblem of
                            the future fraternity and peace of the nations. But let us see, in part, in what our liberty
                            consists. America has been justly eulogized "the land of the free and the home of the brave.
                            " It is true, we live in a free country, wrested from Monarchial powers and released from
                            despotism, in a glorious Republic formed and maintained by the people, and all the laws of
                            the land passed and executed by the same ; we say, by the people, not absolutely so ;
                            Liberty has not done her perfect work so long as half of the population are deprived the
                            right of suffrage ; there have been many queens in the Orient, but no woman has occupied a
                            corresponding position with the President in the New World; but thanks be to Progress the
                            work is advancing, steadily and surely. We have a wonderful Free Press, truly the world's
                            liberal educator; but the terrible immorality of the matter which often passes through it,
                            is greatly to be regretted, the tendency of which is not to elevate in truth, but to enslave
                            to evil. When will be uplifted a higher standard in literature by which all will abide ? not
                            until there is universal goodness in the hearts of the people. We have no chattel slaves
                            since the Emancipation Proclamation ; but as a writer lately stated, when that great deed
                            was done, the work of emancipating was but half performed, since woman remained all but
                            universally man's subordinate and slave, and by him considered to be little else but the
                            playmate of ignorance, at most, only capable of running the continuous round of domestic
                            fife: not much longer will she hold her peace with these things; now is Liberty lighting her
                            through the dungeon bars and releasing her from imprisonment. But woman is a voluntary
                            votary to Fashion, a ready listener to her ceaseless calls ; subject to vanity and folly;
                            not until she emancipates herself through her reason and common sense will she be able to
                            rise and breathe the free air of divine truth. When man gives her justice, instead of
                            flattery she will see the need of turning from these things to better ways of life. - - We
                            have no Fuedal System of lords and serfs,as in the tenth century ; but we have the
                            millionaire and niauy poor, the landlord and tenant; not until the giant god Mammon is slain
                            shall we have justice and equity ruling in the land. We are free from God in the
                            Constitution ; free fro'm the Inquisition, free from fanatical bigots who propagate new
                            faiths by the sword ; but alas ! we are as far from right when in our independence we skip
                            the bounds of conscience ; too many irreverent, irreligious and infidel run the broad open
                            road of wickedness, to ruin. Oh that God might reign in the soul and His laws be written in
                            the hearts of His people S<pb n="39" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/>We have no curfew that tolls the knell of
                            parting day, making retirement at that time absolute ; but left to individual choice, we
                            have allowed ourselves to be the slaves of pleasure, and to revel in midnight orgies
                            regardless O1" consequences to life and health. We are free from present civil strife, but
                            not from standing armies, who only wait for the summons to action-; but still the voice of
                            Peace is in the land constantly entreating the nations to learn war no more. From one thing
                            we can boast but little freedom, and that is the dire curse of drunkenness; morbid appetite
                            insatiate has usurped control, and disease, quacks, poverty and death have followed in its
                            wake ; but behold the grand and noble army of Prohibitionists, they will yet conquer this
                            terrible enemy. 0 Liberty, lift still higher thy immortal light, shine abroad over the whole
                            earth ; let thy rays enter the dark places of voluptuous sin and habitations of evil ;
                            illume the hearts of the people, and relieve from the shackles of false living and
                            consequent care and crime ; go to high places and destroy the insidious foes of God and
                            goodness ; shine on, reign eternal O beautiful Goddess through the long twilight; nor will
                            thy perfect work be finished before the dawning of the bright Millennial day when all will
                            be free indeed and in truth. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In remembrance of eldress Julia Johnson" TEIform="index"/> lu Remembrance of Eldress Julia
                            Johnson.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sweet, Julia L." TEIform="persName"/> JULIA L. SWEET.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Unto this sacred place we come With saddened hearts, and sore To render the last solemn
                            rites To one whose short life's o'er. Whose Golden Sun in sky is set All Silver-starred and
                            fair, While radiant gloamings ling'rin- - yet. Bespeak a beauty rare. The beauty of a life
                            well spent In service unto God, Of Heavenly peace and sweet content Though smitten by the
                            rod, Affliction's rod, which robbed her life Of earthly bliss and health, And made existence
                            but a strife Despoiled of this great wealth. Still did she ne'er repine nor grieve, But
                            strove with noble aim The bitter chast'ning to receive And meekly bear the same. Though
                            sorely tortured day and night. No murm'rings ever came, And her chaste soul enrobed in
                            white, Has won the victor's fame. Hancock., Mass. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Brief rules for holy living" TEIform="index"/>BRIEF RULES FOR HOLY LIVING
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Rev. William Wisnee of Ithaca, N. Y., about fifty
                                    years ago, drew up a set of rules for Holy Living, to be adopted by the families of
                                    his parish. We will strive to keep our minds free from every thought which we
                                    believe will be offensive to God. We will not spend our time in foolish jesting or
                                    unprofitable conversation, but will consider the very moments precious, and endeavor
                                    to fill them up with usefulness to ourselves and others. We will not indulge
                                    ourselves, or countenance others, in speaking of the faults of any one, unless it be
                                    with a view to do good. We will endeavor to educate our children in such a manner as
                                    may make them most useful in the world. We will not suffer any person, not belonging
                                    to our family, to reside under our roof, unless he will refrain from all unclean
                                    language, from Sabbath breaking, intemperance and all outward wickedness. We will
                                    devote a portion cf every day to prayer, to reading the scriptures, and to de vout
                                    meditation.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="40" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>NOTES.</head><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> THE MANIFESTO. Office of publication. The Manifesto is published at Shaker Village, Mer.
                                Co. N. H. All articles for publication should be addressed to Henry C. Buns, and all
                                letters on financial business to A. Y. Cochran. TERMS. One copy per year, postage paid,
                                " " six months, " Send for specimen copy, free. .75 .40 </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cease to do evil. Learn to do well" TEIform="index"/> Cease to do evil. Learn to do
                                well.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> The loving invitation which Jesus extended to those who were privileged to hear him
                                speak, is a beautiful representation of his humanity in that he felt a care for the poor
                                and oppressed. His familiar acquaintance with all the burdens imposed by the ordinances
                                of the law, as well the spirit of domination which found a place in the heart of man,
                                allowed him to speak with the spirit and with the understanding. "Come unto me," said
                                he, "all ye that labor and are heavy laden, and I Avill give you rest. Take my yoke upon
                                you and learn of me, for my yoke is easy and my burden is light." Learn of me ! Learn
                                what? To be meek ; to be merciful; to be pure in heart. The law had been particularly
                                careful in teaching its own form of religious life, and yet Moses under the clearest
                                light of the Divine Presence had not yet seen the forgiving spirit that was manifested
                                iu the life of Jesus. Take my yoke upon you. You have worn the yoke of the oppressor. It
                                has multiplied to you burdens of sorrow. You have borne the yoke of the law with its
                                sacrifices and commandme/nts and all of it has not given you a power to love your
                                enemies. If you will take upon you my yoke, you will find that it is easy, and that my
                                burden will be light. With this the disciple can live as a friend to man and be able to
                                work for the establishing of righteousness on the earth. It was the mission of Jesus to
                                cultivate a confidence in the mind of man, to assure him that he was able to maintain a
                                self-government, and to build up a kingdom of God among men. He did not preach to them a
                                religion of ease and indifference, but a religion full of spiritual activity. "Seek and
                                you shall find, knock and it shall be opened unto you." It was a gospel of good news
                                because of its universal adaptation. It was also a gospel that demanded the whole man.
                                "All that a man hath." To be industrious with his hands, and at the same time to give
                                the heart in prayer to God, is certainly the Christian's rule for a successful journey
                                to the abode of peace. All work would make a man, a mere creature of the earth, low,
                                groveling and selfish. The affairs of the soul, and those of the body are so closely
                                conjoined that the relationship cannot be severed without unpleasant results. A man
                                filled with prayers and psalm singing, and yet slothful and negligent of his earthly
                                duties would make a. sorry Christian. In his pious idleness he would fail to establish
                                the new earth, or to promote the spirit of righteousness. The tendency of man is
                                strongly toward the earth, and to the fruits of that FEBRUARY, 1887.<pb n="41" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> order of life. Instead of learning the value of the peaceful spirit of Christ, man
                                readily falls into that state where human life, even, is not of much value, and cruelty,
                                oppression and sanguinary wars become the ruling power. The Israelites show very plainly
                                to what excesses such things may be carried. The destruction of everything that
                                breathed, and then the habitations burned to the ground. Napoleon in his wars in Europe,
                                cut men down as the machine cuts down the grass. Life was poured out with as little
                                feeling as water would be poured from a cask. Our puritan fathers made it a matter of
                                business to kill all the Indians that they consistently could. The puritans denominated
                                them heathens, and concluded that God had fore ordained the redskins for destruction.
                                All this seems quite different from the spirit which Jesus manifested, or the doctrine
                                which he taught. It seems the more strange when we iind that much of tkis cruel work was
                                done by the Christians, a class of people professing to be the followers of the great
                                Peace-maker. To these, in an especial manner, we now direct our attention. The infidel
                                who does not accept the teachings of the Christ, iias of course the right to stand
                                aside. He may be an honest man and one to be respected in Society, but the writings of
                                the New Testament have a more direct reference to the professor of Christianity. It is
                                fortunate, however, that everybody does not go to the bad at the same time. A. thousand
                                years before the advent of Christ, a man who had experienced some of the changes of
                                life, left a testimony that has no uncertain sound. He had shared in the honors and
                                glory of this world, had been wonderfully blessed with the spirit of God and then most
                                foolishly wasted it away. In his old age, however, he became more thoughtful and while
                                the greater part of his life he denominated a vexation, he left this warning to those
                                who were young. "Fear God and keep his commandments." A course that he had neglected to
                                adopt, and for the neglect was made to receive the just retribution. He farther remarks
                                that " to fear God and keep his commandments is the whole duty of man, for God shall
                                bring every work into judgment with every secret thing, whether it be good or whether it
                                be evil." With this light and understanding at such an early age, we learn that there
                                existed good and true witnesses. _ All our deeds, good and evil, are to be brought up
                                for judgment. Few would object to the inspection of that which was good, even if it was
                                written upon the Avails, but the evil deeds might prove objectionable. It would, indeed,
                                be a sorry sight it every man was obliged to carry his evil deeds upon his back as did
                                Bunyan's Pilgrim. If the Christians are as one of the divines represen'ed them to be,
                                they are to be pitied. "Many of those who profess religion are weak in their morals ;
                                the taking of that which does not belong to them is becoming very common." These are
                                Christians passing from their prayers to rob their neighbors. They are in pursuit of the
                                god of this world. Get an education, said the father to his son, but be sure and get
                                wealth, get it, by fair means if you can. but don't fail to get it. .K'Siis gives us
                                advice and a remedy<pb n="42" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> for all these ills. "If any man will come after
                                me, let him deny himself and take up his cross and follow me." Of what shall lie deny
                                himself? Had not Moses demanded more or less of this same self-denial,- and wherein was
                                this requirement which Jesus made peculiar? Well, a man might deny himself of that which
                                he knew would lead to wrong doing. The man that informed Jesus of his intention to
                                become a Christian, professed wealth. Jesus understood the fact and informed him that in
                                the first place he must sell his house and farm and all his stock and then give the
                                proceeds to the poor. After this he might come and be a disciple ; but the record says
                                that the young man went away quite sorrowful. Another man came to .Jesus and this was a
                                man given to visiting. He was of a social nature and wanted to have all his friends feel
                                well. lie informed Jesus that lie would like to be a disciple, but before he settled
                                down as a member of the order, lie would like to run around among his neighbors and hid
                                them farewell. Jesus had no sympathy with this style of dealing. It was yea, yea and
                                nay, nay, any prevarication was evil. The man said he wanted to be a disciple. Did he
                                mean what he said? Jesus informed him that when a man put his hands to the plough, if he
                                looked back, he was not lit for the kingdom of God. Instead of visiting his worldly
                                relations and wasting away his precious moments, in that foolish way, Jesus said to him,
                                "Go, preach the kingdom of God." Make this a matter of the first importance, and let
                                every other consideration fall into the back ground. In this we find the plain testimony
                                of Jesus Christ. It is the yea and amen of the gospel work. It makes of man a new
                                creature ; separates him from the world ; establishes him upon au immovable foundation,
                                and makes of him a self-sacrificing disciple of the Divine Teacher. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary. </head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rheumatism and diet" TEIform="index"/>RHEUMATISM AND DIET
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Rheumatism is, as often as not, caused by over-eating,
                                        and especially over-indulgence in meat, which is certain to cause an excess of
                                        uric acid, and render the body liable, on exposure to wet or cold, U&gt; an
                                        attack. We know that old people are proverbially liable to rheumatism. The
                                        reasons for tin's are not far to seek. One is that joints and ligaments are
                                        harder and stifFer, and very often contain a deposit- -urate of soda. Another is
                                        that, as a rule, people up in years eat more than is necessary to support life,
                                        under the mistaken notion that they want a deal of nourishment to keep them up.
                                        I say that, on the contrary, the wear and tear of tissue is trifling compared to
                                        what it is in earlier manhood, and that far less food is required. Therefore, if
                                        an elderly person would live long, and be free of aches and pains, and be calm
                                        in mind- -for that is a great desideratum- -he or she must live abstemiously,
                                        more or less.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Cassell's magazine" TEIform="index"/>Cassell's Magazine.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Imagination and disease" TEIform="index"/>IMAGINATION AND DISEASE
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Few people arc aware of the power of imagination
                                        over the body. The Arabs have a legend concerning the plague and the
                                        remonstrance of a man with the destroying angel for killing one hundred thousand
                                        people with this fearful disease. The angel replied that he had only killed
                                        twenty thousand people, as he was commissioned to do- -"the rest." said he,
                                        "died from fright!" Let a person imagine that some part of the body is diseased
                                        and it causes a determination of blood to that part, and if persisted
                                            inproduc-<pb n="43" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> es more or less inflammation and in time
                                        degeneration ! This is especially true of the throat or lungs. If a person
                                        imagines these organs are diseased he will cough or hem three times where lie
                                        should once, until he actually induces a chronic disease, which might have been
                                        avoided. If so-called "Christian scientists" would confine their efforts to
                                        imaginary ailments, leaving out their theological blasphemies and nonsense and
                                        their attempts to treat all diseases as myths, they might meet a long-felt want
                                        in the healing art. Imagination lias a terrible power over persons of a nervous
                                        temperament conjoined to a, feeble bodily organization. Such people should
                                        especially guard themselves in this direction. It is said that even intelligent
                                        and healthy physicians in the beginning of their studies or even practice are
                                        liable to become morbid and imagine themselves victims to various ailments until
                                        experience proves that their fears are groundless. How many people will soberly
                                        tell us that they expect to die of a special disease because some of tlieir
                                        family have passed over the river in that particular way. Of course hereditary
                                        tendencies are not to be ignored. Neither should they be exaggerated till a
                                        person induces a given dreaded disease mainly by the imaginary process. If your
                                        father or great-grandmother died from some disease that you fear, use reasonable
                                        precautions against it, and resolve and expect, by the help of Heaven, that you
                                        will die of something else when your " appointed time " shall come. Imagination
                                        uncontrolled by the reasoning faculties is simple insanity. Some peovtle are
                                        sane on every subject but tlieir health. They have so dwelt on and
                                        exaggeratedevery morbid symptom as to have become to that extent monomaniacs.
                                        Physicians can do untold good or ::;ischief by the way in which they deal with
                                        such patients. An intelligent doctor of divinity told the writer that many years
                                        since he had some trouble with his throat or lungs, and after awhile imagined
                                        that he was past help. He kept his room most of the time and was unable to put
                                        on his coat alone. At length he consulted a wise physician, who told him that
                                        his lungs were sound and that he whs dying from fear! lie at once pulled on his
                                        overcoat, without help, went out doors and in a few days was in his usual
                                        health. Let wise consultation, self-reasoning and will power guide you instead
                                        of the ignis fatuus of a morbid imagination, that "your days may be prolonged in
                                        the land which the Lord God giveth you. " .</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Boston journal" TEIform="index"/>Boston Journal. T. P. B. </bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Is man a fallen being?" TEIform="index"/> IS MAN A FALLEN BEING?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Severance, George" TEIform="persName"/>GEORGE SEVERANCE.</byline><p TEIform="p"> The doctrine of the fall of man as taught by the eld scholastic divines is known more as a
                            thing of the past than as a living dogma of the present. Since the theory of evolution has
                            obtained the strong foot-hold that characterizes this view, instead of the Adamic fall, the
                            current theory teaches that man began extremely low in the scale of being and all the way
                            along he lias gradually been rising to higher conditions. In what I have to say in this
                            article, I do not propose to affirm or deny the doctrine of evolution. I propose simply to
                            inquire, "Is man a fallen being?" We know the individual can fall from a higher to a lower
                            condition. This we see in the wrecks of humanity all around us. In passing from man to the
                            strictly animal kingdom, it would seem as it the different grades of animals are in a more
                            normal condition than is the human race, said to be the crowning work of God in the earthly
                            sense. The devastating evils of sexual excesses and drunkenness, seem to be confined to the
                            human species. In short they are most emphatically human sinsWas man created a drunkard? Is
                            the lecherous condition of society in the gross a normal condition, or is it abnormal? To
                            say nothing in extenuation of man's faults, is it not a matter of most sober and serious
                            thought that woman should devote h ',r life to prostitution, selling her body for hire? Is
                            there anything in animal life below the human plane that bears any comparison? Statisticians
                            tell us there are more than twenty-thousand professional prostitutes in N. York city. Among
                            these are many of excellent natural abilities. Were these twenty-thousand persons to parade
                            the streets 4a<pb n="44" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> in a body, walking two by two what a long procession
                            they would make. If we turn to men of high and low degree who are still baser, if anything,
                            what shall we say of the degradation of our kind? Look at these terrible diseases that eat
                            away the human form divine, by piece meal and what stronger proof can we have that our race
                            is a fallen race? How could the Divine Mind have given plainer utterance to the terrible
                            penalties of his broken laws ? What means the long list of human complaints, if in part the
                            sins of fathers and mothers are not visited on those of the third and fourth generation.
                            What means the general prevalence of scrofulous and cancerous ailments, if the race in any
                            tolerable degree has maintained its integrity? We have it on good authority that these
                            maladies spring largely from syphilitic sources. Did the Author of nature in the beginning
                            fi'l the human system with the seeds of these baneful diseases, or is man in a really fallen
                            condition? If animals we ea.t were as badly diseased bodily as are the human kind should we
                            not abstain from flesh eating? Causes work out their natural results; and there are natural
                            causes for what we should all most seriously deplore. If the fault lies in ourselves does it
                            not behoove us to understand these causes ; and if possible apply the remedy. When* we come
                            to the consumption of intoxicating drinks the figures are most startling. On the authority
                            of the London Times the drink bill of Great Britain is annually $027,380,375. The Christian
                            Union by careful figuring makes the United Slates annual drink bill .$1)00,000,000 with an
                            increase the last fiscal year in consumption of 1,600,000 gals., of distilled liquors. New
                            York city liquor bill per annum is put at $60,000,000 averaging - -49.70 cts., per head for
                            its people. The money raised for religious purposes in the United States does not very much
                            exceed this sum. Are the demands for these intoxicants the results of a primal law of our
                            nature, or are they the effect of artificial heredity and acquirement? Is not all
                            viciousness a perversion, not a natural outflow? Report says in our cities it is not
                            uncommon for milliners and salt's women to treat their lady customers. A man beastly drunk!
                            Can we conceive of a condition more degrading? Even women sometimes become intoxicated. Can
                            these allegations be true ! Man the lord of this lower creation, can it be he is thus
                            debased? What myriads can in truth repeat, "We are diseased from the crown of the head to
                            the sole of the feet there is no soundness in us. " Looking at the world as moralists, we
                            can but exclnim, " Wide is the gate'and broad is the way that leadeth to destruction and
                            many there be which go in thereat; because strait is the gate and narrow is the way which
                            leadeth unto life and few there be that find it. " If morally and physically mankind are as
                            highly progressed as anti-supernaturalists maintain the proof should be palpable to all. The
                            facts cf human history are not flattering to our pride and vanity. We need restoring or
                            re-instating to a condition superior to our present state. There is an ample field for the
                            saviors and redeemers of the sinful and degraded. One of our inspirational poets very aptly
                            diagnosis the sinsick condition of our boasted humanity. " O world ! somewhat I have to say
                            to thee O sin sick, heart sick, soul sick, love sick world ! So ailing art thou both in part
                            and particle, That solid truth thy stomach ill digests. " Ho. RoyaUon, Vi</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Heavenly transition" TEIform="index"/> A HEAVENLY TRANSITION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="White, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>ANNA WHITE.</byline><p TEIform="p"> The close of a long, useful and eventful life. At Mt. Lebanon, Col. Co., N. Y., on the
                            evening of December 31st. at 15 minutes past eight o'clock, our beloved Mother in Israel,
                            Eldress Mary Antoinette Doolittlo, of North Family, passed peacefully and painlessly to her
                            beautiful spirit home the angels had prepared for her. She was 7G years of age the 8th of
                            September 1886. Very few, if any, have passed beyond the confines of earth bearing with them
                            such sterling traits of character as were<pb n="45" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/>exemplified in the life of our
                            dear Mother. As a natural woman she was endowed with remarkable faculties, and possessed
                            qualities well adapted to the important and responsible station, which during her life, she
                            was ordained to occupy. Blest with a strong and robust constitution, with physical endurance
                            almost without limit, she met the stern realities of life unflinchingly, and no circumstance
                            could deter her when, and wheresoever duty called. For nearly fifty years she bore a heavy
                            burden in both temporal and spiritual things ; indeed her whole life was devoted to the holy
                            cause she so courageously espoused in early youth. In temporal matters, prudence and economy
                            were always considered. She thought to " use the things of this world righteously as not
                            abusing them." When away from home she was particularly conscientious and self-denying, many
                            times walking miles t ml going without needed food to save extra expense, nor for anything
                            personal claimed a single dollar, feeling th .t she had no right to use for selfish
                            purposes, the consecrated property held by her in trust. As a spiritual Guide and Instructor
                            where could be found her equal? In our home she shone as a bright beacon light, and many are
                            the feet she has turned from the broad paths of sin, and led step by step up the highway of
                            holiness, tenderly feeding them with the bread and waters of life. The testimony of the
                            Gospel of Christ she maintained regardless of the approval or disapproval of the people.
                            Just and true in all her dealings with souls ; discreet and cautious lest she should hurt
                            the oil and the wine, she held with loving embrace while chastening with her words, and
                            after the rod, would anoint with healing balm. But ah ! to the designedly wicked and
                            rebellious, she was like a flaming herald of truth, whose fire could not be quenched until
                            through baptism, confession and repentance they became subjected and united to the gift of
                            God. When weighed in the balance of justice and truth she will not be found wanting. For
                            nearly a quarter of a century the writer has been a close associate with Eldress Antoinette,
                            and can testify from acquaintance and experience to the truth honor and glory of her life,
                            as set forth in the above brief sketch. Her many dear children ''rise up and call her
                            blessed," and with numerous friends sadly mourn the absence of her visible presence from
                            their midst. "Sing, 0 barren, thou that didst not bear ; break forth into singing, and cry
                            aloud, thou that didst not travail with child ; for more are the children of the barren than
                            the children of the married woman, saith the Lord." Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reminiscenses of my Shaker childhood" TEIform="index"/> REMINISCENSES OF MY SHAKER CHILDHOOD.
                            WINTER.</head><p TEIform="p"> "Let not ambition mock their useful toil Their homely joys and destiny obscure. " When at
                            length winter had fairly set in we began our regular work and were soon as happy as when we
                            had more time for play. At first I was taught to knit and so many were the pairs of socks we
                            knit that sometimes I used to wonder in a childish way where they all went to for to my mind
                            wre furnished enough to supply all the world including Central Africa and Farther India. The
                            weary work however, did me much good for I learned that time and patience which is said to
                            make the mulberry tree into silk.. <pb n="46" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> would also make the sheep's coat
                            into comfortable socks, and also that this same patience was a virtue which I sadly needed
                            and I seemed in a fair way to attain to it. Now, although the cold must have been intense I
                            can't remember that I ever suffered from it, for there was such life giving power in the
                            crisp air that sent the warm blood dancing through my veins, and why should not my feet
                            dance too. At any rate they did trip over the smooth crust which formed over the top of the
                            snow, as did many others besides mine. Who among us can forget the glorious slides we used
                            to have on the sparkling surface before breakfast under the morning stars; and such exciting
                            races where the victor won instead of the laurel wreath, roses, whose brilliancy outrivaled
                            any that ever grew on bushes. "We would sometimes meet with mishaps the worst of which was
                            the running into a wall a sled loaded with little ones, and even then there was but one nose
                            turned wrong, and that has long since come so straight that if the owner follows it she will
                            never be found in crooked ways. So where's the harm ? As I grew a little older I was taught
                            to weave shaker bonnets which was a task I delighted in, for the stir and motion of the loom
                            suited me much better than the continuous knitting. Here I could exercise my fancy in color
                            somewhat, and that always gave me pleasure. Table mats and trimming engaged much of the
                            time, and the knittinghour then seemed more like rest than work, for it came only in the
                            evening. Such good home meetings we used to have and how full of good resolutions we were,
                            and the inclement weather without seemed to draw us together. Every one of my companions are
                            as clear in my memory as though we had met within the year. One face that I used to see more
                            than the others, for we faced each other as we worked, comes up before me as I write. The
                            mirthful twinkle in the eyes is an ever present memory when I think of those by-gone days.
                            Though seemingly merry, careless girls we were gaining for ourselves golden grains to store
                            for future use, and many a time and oft they have Veen like water to the thirsty soul. I
                            remember that I used to form good resolutions and when I found myself in danger would flee
                            rather than succumb as I feared I might do, and so doing discovered that ': Discretion was
                            the better part of valor. " I have tender memories and grateful affection toward all who
                            were thus associated with me then and my recollections retain nothing but hearty kindness
                            and earnest regard. And in the years that have intervened I have found strength to withstand
                            and grace to overcome through their wise counsel. Winter. What cared we for it: had we not
                            warm homes and warmer hearts that protected us from wintry weather without and foes within?
                            Toward all such I shall always feel, Pleasant memories softly stealing' Echoing thoughts of
                            former 3 ears, Faces of the past revealing Bathed in memory's silent tears. Anna P. Carll.
                            Providence, K. I. </p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear children: Our good Enfield brother..." TEIform="index"/>Dear children: Our good Enfield brother...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Massachusetts, Ayer, November 1886" TEIform="index"/> Ayer, Mass., Nov. 1880.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Dear Children:- -Our good Enfield brother has given you rich and valuable advice. To this I
                            will add a few words. " Order is Heaven's first law. " It is wisely written, " Have a place
                            for everything, and everything in its place. " We hear it said, " Where there is no order,
                            there is no God. " Having the privilege, at one time, in a short call, of looking upon your
                            pleasant faces, in your own beautiful home, I thought I would send this to you. You may rest
                            assured, dear children, that nothing can so greatly enhance your happiness, as well as that
                            of others, like this beautiful gift. It is a bright, guiding star, at whatever post of labor
                            you may be called. In possession of this, I will insure success in all your efforts. While I
                            make all due allowance for others who have not been blessed, like myself, in the days of
                            childhood, I rejoice that I learned obedience. Nothing will so beautify the soul for time
                            and eternity as obedience in righteousness. Your sister,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Carr, Martha A." TEIform="persName"/>Martha A. Carr.</byline></div2><pb n="47" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/> From the Little Children. </head><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Winter is here again with..." TEIform="index"/>Winter is here again with...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Wintek is liere again with its snow and ice, I would like it if I did not get so cold. I
                                like spring best. I love to see the trees budding and the flowers blooming and the
                                pretty green grass. In the spring 1 love to go down on the cliffs and see the wild
                                flowers and watch the waterfalls. In the fall the leaves on the cliffs are very pretty
                                so many colors together. When I stand upon the cliffs I can see the river, it looks like
                                it was standing still, yet I know it is running as fast as it can into another river
                                which runs to the ocean. The dear Manifestos come every month and we girls like to read
                                them, we find some pretty verses which we memorize. We all want it to come another year. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Montgomery, Alice" TEIform="persName"/>Alice Montgomery, age 8yrs. Pleasant //ill, Ktj. .
                            </byline></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Manners at table" TEIform="index"/> MANNERS AT TABLE.</head><p TEIform="p"> The face and hands should be washed and the hair should be brushed and combed nice, ly.
                                We should eat with our fork and use 6ur knives to prepare our food. We should not gaze
                                at other people when they are eat ing. We should bend slightly forward. When we take our
                                chairs, we should move them as quietly as possible. We should take soup from the side of
                                the spoon. When any one meets with an accident it is impolite and unkind to laugh or
                                gaze at them. We should not fill a cup more than two thirds full. We should not drink
                                out of the saucer. Before and after taking our food we should ask, with a thankful
                                heart, the blessing of our heavenly Father.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="White, Jennie L." TEIform="persName"/> Jennie L. White. </byline></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rabbits" TEIform="index"/> RABBITS</head><p TEIform="p"> The rabbit is a beautiful little creature with long ears and soft fur. They are very
                                timid and are startled at the first sound. They look like the woodchuck in some ways but
                                are smaller. They make their hole underground and it is so deep that you cannot get them
                                out. There are different kinds of rabbits. There are the wild rabbits and tame ones. I
                                like the wild ones best because they look so pretty running about so wild and free. I
                                always thought that animals were much happier when they were free as God made them than
                                they would be if they were caught and tamed. Babbits are of various colors, black,
                                white, red and gray. I think the white rabbits are the prettiest. The white rabbits have
                                pink eyes and the rest have gray ones. Wild rabbits are good to eat. I have had some two
                                or three times and I thought them very nice. The rabbit is like the hare but is much
                                smaller and has shorter legs and ears. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Shepard, Lizzie" TEIform="persName"/>Lizzie Shepard. </byline></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Trees" TEIform="index"/>TREES. </head><p TEIform="p"> [The following article was copied from a blackboard ^i one of our district schools. It
                                was dictated by as many pupils as it has sentences, and written upon the board by one of
                                the teachers. It was a very pleasant and commendable exercise.] Thehe are several kinds
                                of trees. Trees are valuable for lumber and some for fruits. The mountain ash has little
                                red berries. They grow in clusters. There is another which is called the aspen tree. The
                                leaves are always in motion. The evergreen stays green all the year round. The red maple
                                has red blossoms. There are three kinds of maple. The red maple, the rock maple and the
                                white maple. Maple trees are very useful. We get sap from the maple tree, and boil it
                                down to sugar. Without trees our home M'ould not be as beautiful as it is now. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="River of light" TEIform="index"/> THE RIVER OF LIGHT.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Horton, Louis" TEIform="persName"/> LOUIS HORTON.</byline><p TEIform="p"> " Though I walk fhrovgh the valley of the shadow of death, 1 will fear no evil, for Thou art
                            with me, Thy rod and Thy staff they comfort me." Psalm, xxiii., 4. I've heard it called by a
                            different name, This river so deep and wide, And voices that over its waters came, Were lost
                            in a whirling tide. 'Twas the Tliver of Death ; and a boatman With sorrow and grief and
                            fear- - [pale. And the worn out theme of an old, old tale, liehearsed 'mid floods of
                                tears.<pb n="48" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/> But times have changed and the dark cold Throws off its
                            mantle cf night, [stream From shore to shore like a beautiful dream, Behold a River of
                            Light. And white robed souls in radiant throngs, Across bright waters sail, While shouts of
                            joy and heavenly songs Are borne on the balmy gale. These have walked through the shadowy
                            vale, That spans our River of Light, Singing loud Hozanna's, Hail, all Hail! 0 Land of pure
                            delight. The "boatman" now is an angel fair, And waits by the "gates ajar," To show the
                            pilgrim entering there, Where heavenly mansions are. E- Sornercillc, Mass. </p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers.
                        </head><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>Phrenological Journal and
                                Science of Health</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/>Hall's Journal of Health</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Herald of health" TEIform="index"/>Herald of Health</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hood's calendar" TEIform="index"/>Hood's Calendar</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Scientific American" TEIform="index"/>Scientific American</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Columbia bicycle calendar for 1887" TEIform="index"/>Columbia Bicycle Calendar for 1887</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prayer of the president" TEIform="index"/>Prayer of the President</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> Phrenological Joubnal and Science of Health. January. Contents: Seven New Governors;
                                Mass., Penn., S. C, N. J., Tom., and Del., Illustrated. The Outer and the Inner Man;
                                Familiar talks with our Young Headers; Pa llagfjelleu; On the High Mountains; Colorado
                                Canyons; Evolution and Religion; A. Hundred Years Ago; The Face in Diagnosis;
                                Erysipelas, or St. Anthony's Fire; Poisoning the Blood; Woolen Clothing; Relations of
                                Sanitary Science to the Profession; A dangerous dnig; ?\otes in Science and Industry;
                                Poetry, Wisdom, etc., etc. Fowler &amp; Wells Co., 758 Broadway, N. Y. $2 pr. year.
                                Hall's Journal or Health. January, Contents : The New Year; The Electric Light; Doctors
                                Disagree; Oxygen, Its agency in Therapeutics; God and the Robin; Electricity; Care of
                                the Teeth; How to retain Health; etc. Office 206 Broadway, N. Y. $1 pr. year. Hebaid OF
                                HEALTH. January. Contents: Health Habits of II. M. Stanley, the. Explorer; Malaria, Its
                                prevention ; Woman and the Household ; Mothers and the Nursery; Health Inventions;
                                Questions and Answers, etc., etc. Herald of Health Co. 13 Laight St. N. Y. $1 a year.
                                The wonderful popularity attained by Hood's Calendar last year, will be repeated by
                                Hood's Household Calendar-Almanac for 1887, just published. A happier combination of
                                calendar and almanac, of beauty and utility, of art and advertising, has seldom been
                                produced. The lovely child's head lithographed in many deiicate colors, will be welcome
                                anywhere, while the pad is a wonder of condensed, useful information. Copies may be
                                obtained of the druggists, or by sending six cents in stamps for one copy, or ten cents
                                for two, to C. I. Hood &amp; Co., Lowell, Mass. The Scientific American, published
                                by Munn &amp; Co., New York, during forty years, is, beyond all question, the
                                leading paper relating to science, mechanics and inventions published on this continent.
                                Each weekly issue presents the latest scientific topics in an interesting and reliable
                                manner, accompanied with engravings prepared expressly to demonstrate the subjects. The
                                Scientific American is invaluable to every person desiring to keep pace with the
                                inventions and discoveries of the day. The Columbia Bicycle Calendar for 1887. The
                                Columbia Bicycle Calendar for "87, just issued by the Pope Manufacturing Co., of Boston,
                                is a truly artistic and elegant work in ehroino-lithography and the letterpress. Each
                                day of the year appears upon a separate slip with a quotation pertaining to 'c3"cling
                                from leading publications and prominent personages. The notable 'cycling events are
                                given; and concise opinions of the highest medical authorities; words from practical
                                wheelmen, including clergymen and other professional gentlemen; the rights of 'cyclers
                                upon the roads; general wheeling statistics; the benefits of tricycling for ladies;
                                extracts from 'cycling poems; and much information interesting alike to the 'cycler and
                                to the general reader. Jn fact it is in miniature a virtual encyclopaedia upon this
                                universally utilized modern steed. The calendar proper is mounted upon a back of heavy
                                board, upon which is exquisitely executed in oil color effect, by G. H. Buck, of New
                                York, an allegorical scene representing the earth resting among the clouds, with Thomas
                                Stevens, in heroicsize, mounted upon his Columbia bicycle, cireuinbicycliug the globe.
                                The atmospheric lights and shades of sunlight and moonshine are charmiugl3vivid, yet
                                artistically toned and softened. A smaller g portion of the board is devoted to a
                                picture of amounted la ly tricycler, speeding over a pleasant country road. As a work of
                                convenient art, the Columbia Calendar is worthy of a place in office, library or parlor.
                                The Prayer of the President. Address Ge- -. E. Littlefleld, 67 Cornhili, Boston, and
                                enclose five two-cent stamps. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.
                        </head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Davis, Eliza" TEIform="index"/>Eliza Davis</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="index"/>Antoinette Doolittle</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gould, Sarah" TEIform="index"/>Sarah Gould</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Clapp, Harriet" TEIform="index"/>Harriet Clapp</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> Eliza Davis, at Poland, Me., Nov. 21, 1886. Age 78 yrs. Eldress Antoinette, Doolittle at
                                North Family, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. Dee. 31, 188G. Age 7G yrs. .'5 mo. 23 days. Sarah
                                Gould, at Shaker Village, N. H., Jan. 4th 1887. Age 73 yrs. 1) mo. and 16 fays. Harriet
                                Clapp, at Kent. Ohio, Jan. 4th 1887. Age 73 yrs. 7 mo. and 28 days.</p></div3></div2><pb n="49" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><!--  
THE  MANIFESTO.
*   HISTORY of the CONQ UEHT of MEXICO.   With a Preliminary
9 View of the Ancient Mexican Civilization, and the Life of the Conqueror,
Hernando Cortes. Illustrated Iiibrary Edition, in two volumes, small octavo. Price. $2.25.
Popular Edition, two volume? in one, without  illustrations, $1.25.    Noiv ready.
rf*^ amum! ^w EL* * The expiration of
COpyrflght, copyright enables
me now to present this great work to American readers at a popular price, yet in form
worthy of the author, and worthy of the finest
library. Its mechanical qualities are fairly
equal to those of my best edition of '' Guizot's
History of France."
- -a# |_ * __ -_ I _ the noted essayist and
w w 81 I - -J JJBCj critic, says : "A history
possessing the unity, variety, and interest of a
magnificent poem. It deals with a series of
facts and exhibits a gallery of characters, which
to have invented would place its creator by the
side of Homer ; and which to realize and represent in the mode Mr. Prescoti has done, re-'
quired a rare degree of historical imagination."
Rni//>iH ALL PRAISE.   "This
Dvjf W \t I %M announcement is all that is
needed. The work itself long ago passed beyond
all praise. The thousands of people who were
unable to secure it at former prices will be glad
to avail themselves of the opportunity of doing
so at a reduced rate."- - -Interior, Chicago, 111.
"'The work itself occupies too high a place
among historical writings to need commendation."- - The Mail. Toronto. Ontario.
Ts a-ftrft jo, I - -f      " The enterprising Mr. Ali 11815! V e    den has chosen a most timely occasion for the reissue of this valuable work,
and its excellent and convenient library form,
its cheapness, and the widespread interest in
Mexican matters that exists at j>resent, will
doubtless combine to give it an appreciative
reception. "- -The Week, Toronto, Ontario.
"The volume before us is a very creditable
piece of work mechanically, and puts Prescott's
charming histories within the reach cf the average pocket book."'- -Evangelist, St. Louis, Mo.
 "This history
 g hasafascinating interest, and is so well known as to need no
praise."- -Christian Secretary, Hartford, Conn.
"Especially interesting at this time. Is published in two handsome volumes, and like all
Mr. Alden'a publications is sold at an astonishingly low price."- -Advertiser, Detroit. Mich.
n judiciously
9 planned
and admirably executed: rich with the spoils of
learning easily and gracefully worn: imbued
everywhere with a conscientious love of the
truth, and controlled by that unerring good
sense without which genius leads astray with its
false lights, and learning encumbers with its
heavy panoply. It will win the literary voluptuary to its pages by the attractiveness of its
subject and the flowing ease of its style: and the
historical student will do honor to the extent
and variety of the research which it displays. . .
It will take its place among those enduring productions of the human mind which age cannot
stale and custom cannot wither.- - G.S.Htllakd.
AND    ISABELLA.     HISTORY of the RJEIGN oi
Ferdinand and Isabella, the Catholic. By William H. Prescott.
Illustrated Library Edition,, in two volumes, small octavo, including portraits and other illustrations. Fine heavy paper, line cloth, gilt tops. Price, $2.25. Popular Edition, from the same
plates, but without illustrations, the two volumes in one.   Price, $1.2,5.   Now ready.
" Prescott had the genius to invest the dry
facts of history with the charms of fiction; and
yet he never sacrifices truth to the graces of
style."- -Westlakb .
" It is one of the most pleasing as well as most
valuable contributions that have been made to
modern history; it is the only one that gives us
a faithful and sufficient picture of a period so
momentous as the latter half of the fifteenth
century."- -London Athenaeum.
" One of the finest histories of modern times,
written by an author of rare felicity of diction,
fervor of imagination, accuracy of statement.
and exquisite beauty of style. Every one who
reads at all should read Prescott."- -Presbyterian. Philadelphia, Pa.
ILLUSTRATED CATALOGUE of Choice Books, 132 pages, 4 cents; Condensed Catalogue, free.    The best literature of the world at the lowest prices ever known.    Address,
JOHNB. ALDEN, Publisher, 393 Pearl St., New York.
The Alden Book Co.: Clark and Adams Sts., Chicago ; 120 Yonge St., Toronto.
^>A*a           "%               At the office of ui'| - - *%       &
Clubs - -i This
^^ ^^ ^- -'- -   i^^ rir   jn combination     ^^   **^*.^*-r*zr
PAPER a copy of the work above
be seen, auditor any of Aiden'S
tions J||ay be had on extremely
either as Premiums for Cltibs, or
i combination   "*"*- - ^^- -^- -^^ with   the   paper.    "A  book   worth
reading    is                               worth owning."   Alden has placed
the best literature of the world within the reach of every home; send for our attractive term-..
FERDINAND
A NobleWork
Fascinating
<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
MEDAL   MACHINES.
YOBE STATE AGBICULTUaAL WOSES,
1st. Premiums at all Competitive Trials
Railway, Chain and I- -r- -rllor- -e Powera, Threshers and Clrauvi'H, Thresher*
& Shaken, Clover Hullei-M, Feed Cutters, Wlieel Horse Itakcs, Horse I- -itchforkD, Mliinifle 371a- -liim- -  ,
                    Straw Preserving- Itye TSiresIiers, Portable Sieam-Eiig-ine- -, Cider i.ibsI WinvJIills and Presses, Do^ and Four
                    Powers, "BJisc Iliirronw & Springy Kootli Harrows. "Robinson's Hay Press, of four sizes- Will work as easy with
                    one horse, as others with two. Made with Steel Gearing which can not be broken." WHEELER & IELICK Co., AVONTH
                    and BOARD Guaranteed 3 1 oung Men or Ladies in each country, and hifi'icst commission paid (often $150 a month) Mff HOOK
                    alrn.dy on tidal wave of success in North and South America, at ilie Ice-Bound PoleSj over the lands of the Midnight
                    Sun, under the Equator, through the Dark Continent, among the Old Temples of India, in the Flowery Kingdoms of China and
                    Japan, amid the ruins of Incas, Aztecs and Zuni, within Canons, Cliff Buildings, and Gardens of the Gods, on the Isles
                    of the Sea, and in all parts of the globe. 300 engravings, Low Price. Quick Hales. Send for Circular, p, W. Ziegler,
                    & Co., 720 Chestnut St, Philadelphia) Pa, Send stamp for Circular and report of Centennial trial. MANUFACTURERS
                    OF SLACK WRITING INK. COPYING and MARKING INK CARMINE, RED and BLUE INK, WRITING FLUID, INK POWDER &c. BOSTON
                    MAYNARD & NOYES. MASS<pb n="" id="p"/> --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>