<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2209" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">28</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">22</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">09</biblScope><date value="18920901" TEIform="date">September 1892</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">193-216</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="22" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="09" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
SEPTEMBER.
THE
Published by the United Societies.
VOL. XXII.
MANIFESTO
'For what is a man profited, if he shall gain the whole world, and
lose his own soul ? or what shall a man give in exchange for
his soul."Matt. XVI., 26.
Canterbury, N. H.
1891
<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
CONTENTS.
Page.
The Early Shakers,            -         -         -         193
Blessings in Disguise,             -         -         -    194
Perfect through Suffering,          -         -         195
The Dispensations,        ....
The Three Rules,                 -         -         -             200
Perpetuity of Human Institutions,
-An Appeal,                 ....          202
Love is the first of all,
The Web of Life,                                               203
Editorial,               -          -          -          -          -   204
Notes About Home,           -         -         -           205
Inquiry, No. 7,      - - - - -     212
Scripture Text,         ....             
The Bible,.....       
Kind Words,                                                                   214
Deaths,       - -....
Music;Looking Upward,          -         -           215
Books & Papers,          -         -         -         -       216
H
A Normal Course f?
for Teachers.     J
20   Complete   Courses $
 for   Student and    Teacher.     All instruc tion   by mail. Send stamp for  catalogue.
 American    CorresPondence      College,
 S. Dansvillk, New York.
AGENTS "WANTED
MAEE TEOM
1  UJCZU working for WOlUPS COLITitf:_____..
A YILLFx POSITION ILLffSTEATED; authentic organ of the World's Fair. Most beautiful, interesting and popular publication issued. Sells
at sight. Send 15 c. in stamps for full particulars and sample copy containing COLOEBD LITE
OOSAPEIC VIEWS of EXPOSITION BUILDINGS. J. B.
Campbell, Pres., 218 LaSalle St., Chicago, 111.
THE  ALTRUIST.
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetie
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is published by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all
their property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing
officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. 50 cents a year;
specimen copy free. Address A. Longley.
901 Olive St.,  St. Louis, Mo
WRO i*. WMOO A MONTH can be
|/9i W j)i9Vi made working for us.
Persons preferred who can furnish a horse
and give their whole time to the business.
Spare moments may be profitably employed
also. A few vacancies in towns and cities.
B. T. JOHNSON & CO., 26th. and Main St.,
Eichmond, Va.
GOOD AGENTS WANTED FOR
Onward Christian
By MARY LOWE DICKINSON, Q%l#li#%i<*
Gen'lSecretary " King's X 111 jl IU j V
Daughters and Sons." WUIUIUI O
A Full Account of " The Epworth League," by the
Rev. J. F. Berry) " Christian Endeavor," by the
JRev. Francis E. Clark;" Baptist Young People's
Union," by Rev. J. M.Coon; "Woman'sChristian
Temperance Union," by Frances J. Barnes; and
"Chautauqua Circles," by RateF. Kimball.13
Books in One.-Profusely Illustrated.-Portraits of Leaders.-Handsome Illuminated
Cover. AGENTS ARE COINING MONEY.
Second Edition Now ix Press.
.. Great Offer for the Next Thirty Dnys . .
Prospectus FreeKSe*S Bet {uicK
Write for Confidential Terms to
The Brodix Publ'ng Co., Washington, D. C.
Tbt Celebrated
Stratton
BAND INSTRUMENTS,
Srutre and Bass' Orums. Fifes,   pioooios. Clarionet*. Cy
baisand all othar instruments ps'taining toBrass Bands and Drum Corps.
*JOHIV F. STRATTON &. 8OIV,
*3  *  *5 WalUer  Street   NEW  YORK.
It tOO  CASIKTT GET TRXM O>  TO
THE CBUVIlfK       tjocjtj,   pxalkBB,   IT*   WBJ.   FUI aOMX
WAT   09 RUPn.iIKO  09 ltl TBS
STRATTON
RUSSIAN GUT
VIOLIN STRINGS.
 M Lto.
 STRATTOM & SON.
*. Musical Merchandise.
t                            *1 VOB1L
If so, send your name and address for a Free
Sample of the A2EERICA3T BEE JOUBNAX
Weekly22 pasresOne l>ollar a year. ~
GEORGE W, YORK, & CO.,
199 Randolph Street, CHICAGO, ILL.
IF you wish  to   advertise   anything anywhere at any time, write to GEO. P.
EOWELL & CO., No. 10 Spruce St., N. Y.
ome study
do you keep bees
Vol. XXII.
SEPTEMBER, 1892.
No. 9.--><pb n="193" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Early shakers in Manchester" TEIform="index"/> THE EARLY SHAKERS IN MANCHESTER.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Axon, William E. A." TEIform="persName"/> By William E. A. Axon. F. R. S. L.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Vice President and Hon. Secretary of the Vegetarian Society. In my Annals of Manchester and
                            in my Lancashire gleanings I have given some particulars as to the rise of the Shakers in
                            Manchester in the last century. When Elder F. W. Evans visited the city where Ann Lee was
                            born I showed him in Chetham's Library an old discolored newspaper, Manchester Mercury,
                            which records the apprehension of several Shakers.* Some further particulars have come to
                            light and may be of interest. The Corporation of Manchester have recently printed the
                            accounts kept by the Constables of what was then a comparatively small, though busy and
                            wealthy town. The following are the entries that refer to the persecution of "the Manchester
                            Prophetess" and her associates : July 14, 1772. To apprehending 5 Shakers on Sunday last, 24
                            persons 6d each, for Assistants 12s. To John Moss for expenses on this and other such like
                            sundry times 6s 8d. To the day after attending them all day when two were committed to the
                            House of Correction, four persons each Is 6d conveying them Is......7s. To ale for 24
                            Persons about apprehending the Shakers 5s 6d. July 15. To Mrs. Hulme for drink when the
                            Shakers were brought before the Justice Is 6d. July 23. To the Jurors Bailiff on prosecuting
                            John Lee and his daughter Ann Is 6d. To the Cryer's fees 2s 6d. To four women witnesses
                            attending each three days 12s. To four men witnesses attending each same time 18s. To meat
                            and drink for each at 6d a day 12s. To other expenses amongst them during the sessions when
                            both received sentence of commitment 7s. July 20. To a bill of expenses at the Mule when
                            Justice Mainwaring attended to examine the Shakers 2s 7%d. Oct. 3. To widow Shepley for
                            ironwork when the Shakers were apprehended 2s 6d. To sundry persons and expenses quelling a
                            mob who were beginning to pull dj&gt;wn the house of John Townly a Shaker 5s 6d. Oct. 19. To
                            repairs making good the breaches at Lee's in Toadlane in order to apprehend a gang of
                            Shakers lock't up there 5s 2d. May 30, 1773. To Ann Lee a Shaker apprehended for disturbing
                            the Congregation in the old Church <pb n="194" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> detaining her i n the Prison room
                            two days 2s maintaining her with meat and drink and her attendant 2s 3d. wages 2s 6s 3d.
                            July 28. To attending Ann Lee two whole nights 3s. The justice mentioned under date, July
                            30, 1772, was Peter Mainwaring a well known medical man long resident in the town and who
                            was in the commission of the peace. There seems to have been an ingenious system for
                            combining the secular consumption of ale with the sacred joy of harrying the sturdy
                            protestants who like the earlier Quakers did not hesitate to bear their testimony even in
                            the face of the assembled congregation of the parish church.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Blessings in disguise" TEIform="index"/> BLESSINGS IN DISGUISE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Barrett, A. D." TEIform="persName"/> A. D. Barrett.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Why not keep heart in adversity as well as in prosperity? If the times are a little dark,
                            bear in mind;"It is a long lane that has no turning." "God helps those who help themselves."
                            "All things work together for good to those who love the Lord." And not only love the Lord,
                            but love our Brethren and Sisters who are one with us on the journey up the hili of life.
                            There is no greater criterion of Christian character than a strong manifestation of love
                            under adverse circumstances. It is very easy to be loving when everything moves smoothly and
                            when nothing comes to ruffle the daily pathway. But the test comes when the opposite spirit
                            presses itself upon you. Nothing but a thorough baptism into the spirit of Christ is able to
                            meet these emergencies. "Dislike," says Victor Hugo, "is always a prejudice." This is worthy
                            of a much wider application, for surely the great majority of all our dislikes spring from
                            our ignorance of the objects considered and are, hence, the children of prejudice.
                            Sometimes, we criticise our friends very harshly, and forget to be charitable, because we
                            are ignorant of that great truth from which the gift of charity springs. If we should place
                            ourselves in their circumstances, with their surroundings, we might err as they err. There
                            is no disputing this truth ; that our greatest trials come from want of investigation or
                            from looking into the motive or intention of the individual, whom we think has caused these
                            great trials. With a second thought and a little more reasonable care we might be better
                            able to discover where we could exercise mercy as wrell as justice. There are times when we
                            may be spoken to harshly : or in plainer words, may be insulted. Our nature is suddenly
                            aroused and the first impulse is to retaliate, and like beligerent spirits in time of war,
                            we send out our long guns and the battle has commenced. Shall we be able to stop before the
                            powder and shot are all exhausted? As foolish as were the two Knights before the shield.
                            Passion is a monster ! In it we break our union, and repentance only can bring a
                            restoration. We have heard this condition compared to the growing of the willow by the side
                            of the highway. While it was <pb n="195" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> young it could easily be protected, even
                            during a tempest, but after several years of growth, it so obstructed the daily travel that
                            it was forced to be removed. So much for a story. Let us prove ourselves to be faithful
                            soldiers of Christ, by having a good supply of self-control, dictated by good common sense,
                            and then in times of trial we may be able to meet them in the spirit of our divine Teacher.
                            Among good Believers a cheerful, loving spirit, breathes forth at every step and gives
                            courage to the weak, and added strength to the strong. Let us cultivate that spirit which
                            makes a cheerful home, and form the habit of looking on the sunny side of life. We want the
                            inspiration of gladness that comes from God, that pleasantly and peacefully assists us on
                            our heavenward journey. Ayer, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Perfect through suffering" TEIform="index"/> PERFECT THROUGH SUFFERING.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stephens, Annie R." TEIform="persName"/> Annie R. Stephens.</byline><p TEIform="p"> A cloud o'er-hangs my way, I cannot see, A darkening trial fills my soul with dread, And
                            every doubting step my feet must tread, Leads but to Labyrinths,uncertainty, Where
                            weird-like shadows flit unceasingly. O faithless heart! O blinded sight that's led Where
                            phantom shapes their ghostly presence shed, Anoint thine eyes with faith and thou shalt see.
                            Shalt see the cloud fringed with hope's radiance bright; Shalt see thy woe an angel
                            sanctified, That gently leads thee on through sorrow's night, If thou but calmly trust,in
                            faith abide. Ope wide thy soullet in the holy light, And lo! thy innermost is glorified. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dispensations" TEIform="index"/> THE DISPENSATIONS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leonard, William" TEIform="persName"/> William Leonard.</byline><p TEIform="p"> The idea of four dispensations, is as old as our existence as a Church. And these four
                            epochs had each their own heaven and hell. Then, as now, obedience to God's lawr produced
                            the state of righteousness, and acceptance, that the IShakers call and know to be heaven ;
                            disobedience produced the unrighteous, unaccepted, and condemned state, that the counterfeit
                            professor with true faith, knows and feels to be hell. The spirit must be ruled by the
                            higher powers to stand right, and the body must be ruled by laws that correspond with the
                            natural elements, of which it is composed to stand right. Hence, we find, beginning with
                            Adam, both were to be regulated by God's laws, which were the first heaven and earth laws,
                            ever given to man. The first was to teach him what to eat; "And God said, behold I have
                            given you every herb bearing seed, which is upon the face of all the earth, and every tree
                            in which is the fruit of a tree yielding seed, to you it shall be for meat." The green herb
                            was for the cattle, but every herb seeding seed, was for man. Here was, evidently, a plain
                            vegetable diet, laid out for the earthly body of man, and under the first covenant, when man
                            stood in his rectitude. This seems to have been Adam's first kw, to regulate his appetites.
                            Then comes the second.Gen., ii, 16, 18. "Of the tree of the knowledge of good and evil, thou
                            shalt not eat of it, for in the day that thou eatest thereof, thou shalt surely die." To
                            simplify it; this was <pb n="196" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> the first earth, that should have been the solid
                            foundation, for the patriarchal fathers to have stood on, with all attached to them, till
                            the call of Abraham. This was his earth. His heaven would have been in the keeping of God's
                            laws. Simple vegetables regulated by law was intended for his use. This would make pure
                            blood and shut out all disease. It would have kept his mind on his God, and his duty. When
                            the second Covenant was made with Noah, he stood at the head of the race. The covenant to
                            regulate eating, shows a depraved state of the appetites which men had fallen into. Gen.,
                            ix, 14. "Every moving thing that liveth, shall be meat for you, even as the green herb, have
                            I given you all things. But flesh with the life thereof which is the blood thereof, shall ye
                            not eat." This is what one would call getting pretty well down from God's original law. Some
                            like a man starting with harmless appetites first tasting spirit, then tippling, then
                            drinking, then staggering, then falling to the ground. Certainly no good spirit wrould have
                            invited man into this depraved condition. It was a step backward, for him to be eating wild
                            animals, reptiles and creeping things, and every thing in earth, ocean, and air, which was
                            afterwards cut off by the law. They evidently ate all these things in the blood, or it would
                            not have been so positively forbidden. In the second Dispensation, Moses gave an earth law,
                            to regulate the Jews. It lifted all the descendants of Abraham, w^hile they wTalked in
                            obedience, from the lawless, diseased state into winch the old Gentile would have fallen.
                            Again they were placed in a high state of rectitude and health, compared with all others.
                            When the Jews came out of Egypt, they were lawless in their habits of eating and were
                            afflicted with the diseases of the Egyptians. They passed forty years in the wilderness
                            under forced abstinence and temperance laws Those who entered Canaan did so with greatly
                            subdued appetites, and a higher degree of health, than their fathers ever enjoyed. Among
                            this people, the great spirit by his agents, established a second earth and heaven order.
                            Isaiah alludes to this when he says, Isa., xxxiv, 4. "And all the host of heaven shall be
                            dissolved, and shall be rolled together as a scroll." Again, Isa., lv, 17. "Behold I create
                            new heavens and a new earth, and the former shall not be remembered." This was the most
                            remarkable earth order, ever established in any nation. It laid out their lands in a sort of
                            community, and no involvement of ancestors, could deprive heirs of their inheritance, but
                            for a short period. No inheritance was allowed to exceed twenty acres. Their washings,
                            cleansings, and sin offerings, were intended to show up plainly the offence in Eden. The law
                            stated what animals, fish and birds might be eaten and indeed the parts to be saved and the
                            parts to be rejected. It regulated in a great measure, the preparing of bread, vegetables
                            and garments. It taught under what circumstances to engage in wTar; how to till the soil, to
                            labor ; to deal justly, and even how long a journey one might take on the Jewish Sabbath.
                                <pb n="197" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> In their rudimental heaven order, they were strictly required to
                            believe iu the word of God through inspired Mediators", and to receive no revelation one
                            side of Levitical and prophetic leaders, who ruled for God at the Jewish altar. They were to
                            rest in faith on the promises of God. In the third dispensation, Jesus again established and
                            taught, a heaven order and an earth order. He fulfilled or kept the law of Moses and made it
                            honorable; as men fulfill the laws of temperance, by total abstinence, so Jesus kept certain
                            requirements under the law. He lived a virgin life. With the disciples, Jesus established
                            the first Christian United Inheritance ; thus he kept the Jewish law on property, by
                            superceding the necessity of such a law. By non-resistance, he rose above the defense of
                            human rights by wars of resistance. By simple language, yea, and nay, he left beneath all
                            oaths and vows to be fulfilled at the Jewish altar. In this new life he rose into a heavenly
                            element that Moses never knew; and bound this life upon his Jewish, Christian followers at
                            Jerusalem. This new life gave them higher, holier power. It gave them a more spiritual,
                            refined, consistant inspiration. This was their- heaven, but it rested on an earthly order
                            like the two former epochs. The primitive Christians, had not only to keep the spirits in
                            order, but they had living earth forms also to keep in order. The law that ruled their
                            bodies to keep them in health, must correspond to their spiritual condition. Jesus
                            says,"Think not that I have come to destroy the law, (of Moses) I came not to destroy, but
                            to fulfill."Matt., v. 17-20. "Whosoever, (among Christians,) shall break one of the least of
                            these commandments, and shall teach men so, shall be called the least in the kingdom of
                            heaven. But whosoever shall do and teach them shall be called great in the kingdom of
                            heaven." The Jewish priests, Scribes and Pharisees, to favor their own sensuality,
                            intemperance and voluptuousness, had misinterpreted and altered the punctuation of the law,
                            and by being false guides, had plunged the Jews into darkness by teaching for law, what was
                            never written by Moses. Jesus took it honestly, in its original form, just as it was given
                            to Moses; kept it himself, and then bound it upon his disciples to keep it. He warned them
                            in the above Scripture not to do as Jewish teachers had done. If they did as he enjoined,
                            they would stand highly honored ; if they did not they would stand disgraced in his heavenly
                            kingdom. Did not the primitive Christians require law to regulate them in what to eat and
                            drink, and how to prepare it to insure health of body as much as did the Jews ? Did they not
                            need instruction what to wear, and how to make it? Did they not need teachingrespecting
                            property, how to use it and divide it, even if they took higher property ground? Most
                            certainly, and to Moses was given laws to regulate all these matters. In our light and life
                            spiritually, we understand the original spirit life of Jesus, and by the above plain
                            requirements as recorded by Matthew, we <pb n="198" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> may understand the earth laws
                            which the primitive Church lived under, that brought their bodies into harmony with the laws
                            of nature. Here they obtained power to stand up in health of body, and justification of
                            spirit. How beautifully this opens to view the power that Jesus stood in, as a preacher of
                            righteousness, and the first Christian healing medium. His whole salvation and power in the
                            outward and inner man, was derived by living to the physiological law, and the selfrestraint
                            of the gospel. By earth law given of God, he mastered every appetite of the animal man, and
                            stood firmly, a perfect model of health. By gospel light, he ruled down all affections and
                            lusts of body and mind. What a medium and leader is presented to us. How gloriously he
                            fought his way to lay a permanent foundation for the heaven and earth of the third
                            dispensation. Jesus stood free from infirmities and the physical sins that engendered them.
                            The spirit of Christ could dwell in a law-abiding body and spirit, and could use him as a
                            medium to raise others to the state in which he stood. The primitive Church at Jerusalem, in
                            their united order of interest and spirit power, stood far ahead of anything that ever
                            existed under the order of Moses. Then property and earthly blessings were one wide step
                            nearer to the outward order of the Church of the latter day. All the leading apostles and
                            elders were like their Lord, healers of the sick. They ministered what they lived for, a
                            physical and spiritual salvation. Sick Christians were not very desirable company in that
                            Church. If a member had committed a physical sin and was taken sick, it was a sacred matter
                            to get him healed. "Is any sick among you, let him c-all for the Elders of the Church, and
                            let them pray over him, and the prayer of faith shall save the sick, and the Lord shall
                            raise him up." James, v., 1416. "Confess your faults one to another and pray one for another
                            that ye may be healed." They seemed to have obtained their gifts of healing in the manner
                            spoken of, and then must keep healed by living in harmony with God's laws. Paul who was
                            called to take his station as first Minister to the Gentiles, whatever his advantages by
                            healthy, orderly parents, had from his infant days been a rigid observer of moral and
                            physiological law under Moses. Of himself he says, "My manner of life from my youth which
                            was at first among my own nation at Jerusalem, know all the Jews which knew me from the
                            beginning, that after the straightest sect of our religion I lived a Pharisee."Acts, xxvi.,
                            45. Paul declares, that from his earliest years, he was so strict to live to moral and
                            physiological law, that this regular and abstemious life was publicly known to many of the
                            Jews. Undoubtedly, there were those within the sound of his voice that knew it, and when
                            striving to reclaim the Gentiles from eating and drinking unhealthy and unhallowed things,
                            he could present himself as their pattern, by declaring, "Touching the righteousness of the
                            law, I was blameless."Phil, iii., 6. We certainly have the foundation principles of a new
                            heavenly <pb n="199" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> order and a new earthly order, but in both do we not need to
                            progress a few steps? We certainly do spiritually, and howr is it physically ? Are we yet up
                            to the manifests laid down by our Lord, that were to rule the primitive Church ? Has the
                            beautiful earth order or a newer one been revealed to us yet? Jesus declared that till
                            heaven and earth pass, those simple requirements pertaining to diet, and all the rules of
                            physiological life would stand as God's law to Christians. In the first earth order diet was
                            first laid out for man. In the second earth order, I conclude that the Jews in the
                            wilderness thought that their diet was to be regulated first. In the third earth order
                            beginning under John the Baptist, it seems clear that it wras so there. But we are Gentiles
                            by birth, Gentiles in living, and the gospel so found us and has dealt with us as Gentiles.
                            The judgment order came to us first, the earth consecration next, and our health regulations
                            are yet to come. Here again is something new, and it seems quite consistent. The great
                            Spirit works with us like a good and skillful Architect. Do we so live that wTe may stand as
                            a pattern of health to the nations ? We shall all be likely to conclude not. But many begin
                            to feel that in the next general opening or out-pouring of the spirit in Zion, laws to
                            govern appetites rule bodies more consistently, and set apart the very food and show the way
                            to prepare it to produce health, will be revealed in order. We need new rules to regulate
                            our outer life and to have them regarded strictly, to raise us up into a glorious physical
                            resurrection. This would sweep awray a host of disorders, unnecessary labors, needless
                            expense, murmurings, intemperance, relieve many sufferers, give us clean conceptions of holy
                            things, bring us into closer connections with the heavens, and let in a flood of light and
                            power, at which this Church will yet be astonished. We should as a people or as individuals,
                            shake off many indulgences, and be preparing ourselves, by living to our present light,
                            physiologically ; as our physical condition as a people, imperatively demands it. Do, or did
                            we ever come up to the primitive Church as healing mediums ? Historians say that powrer
                            remained with them for a long course of years, and continued in a greater or less degree
                            among the witnesses. Did we ever hold it as a permanent profession, as did our Lord and
                            Teacher and the early Christians? As a body it seems to me that we are just such mediums, as
                            spirits do not want to use for the purpose, and could not successfully use, if they wanted
                            us. We do not know how to live to produce true physical health in ourselves, and how can we
                            administer what wre have not received? Can we instruct individuals how to live to keep
                            healed, after they were healed by good spirits ? I think not. As the Lord liveth, and as the
                            gospel will increase, new rays of light or physical life will break upon us, inspiring our
                            spirits and reviving health, then the inhabitants of Zion will not say I am sick Harvard,
                            Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Live for to-day" TEIform="index"/>Live for to-day
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Live for to-day.</p><pb n="200" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Three rules" TEIform="index"/> THE THREE RULES.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bowers, Lucy S." TEIform="persName"/> Lucy S. Bowers.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Iron Bule, Evil for Evil. The iron rule the passions well obey, It is the rule for rendering
                            hate for hate, Regardless reason, yea regardless fate. Strife meets with strife in bitterest
                            array. Sin over evil seeks to rule the day. "Tis hard and cold revenge insatiate Felt for
                            injuries small, as well as great; Tooth for a tooth, eye for an eye to pay. Selfishness and
                            pain in like coin returned, Mete for measure, flame for fire that burned, [earned.
                            Eecompense of wrong, just and justly 'Tis back to back, no Christian brotherhood, Feeling by
                            animals scarce understood, 'Tis sin of double sin, all void of good/ Silver Bule, Good for
                            Good. The silver rule, the rule of right for right, In better ways all human feeling leads,
                            Which finds expression in good kindly deeds. 'Tis love for love, a measure of delight, And
                            mercy which like mercy may requite. 'Tis sympathy which in its turn succeeds, 'Tis pity
                            ministered, when pity heeds, And joy bequeathed, when other joys incite It is but good for
                            good, no more, no less, No overflow, no added power to bless, 'Tis not, indeed, exceeding
                            righteousness, In this the publicans do even so, But Christ has come to teach, that we may
                            know The sweetness of life's perfectness below. Golden Bule, Good for Evil. The golden rule,
                            the highest rule of thought, In Christ-like action lovingly expressed, Best guide by which
                            the soul is surely blessed. By which the happy ways of peace are taught, [sought. Through
                            which the blessedness of life is The power of Christ by kindly hearts possessed [distressed,
                            Will help the spirit when with wrong And sweet forgiveness is the gift outwrought. The
                            God-like soul to greater gain aspires Than wrong for wrong, or good for good requires, The
                            fulness of the highest law it most desires. Be unto others ever just and true As you would
                            have them be to you; E'en more than this God willeth you to do. Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Perpetuity of human institutions" TEIform="index"/> THE PERPETUITY OF HUMAN INSTITUTIONS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="DeGraw, Hamilton" TEIform="persName"/> Hamilton DeGraw.</byline><p TEIform="p"> "Creeds, empires, systems, rot with age." The objective point in the establishment of
                            organizations in human society wkether religious, social or political is a desire for the
                            betterment of life's conditions. For that purpose men break from their old moorings,
                            reorganize in striving for the goal of their ambition. The subjective is, how long shall
                            these present associations last? All finite entities contain within themselves the elements
                            of progress and decay. Complying with the conditions that are in harmony with the former,
                            will ensure life, neglect these and decay is certain. When the vitalizing spirit that
                            animated and gave life at the beginninghas spent its force, or in other words, any
                            organization that has performed its mission, the most proper thing to do is to make its last
                            will and testament and go into dissolution. A failure to do so produces a respectable ( ?)
                            fossil. A witness thereof can be seen in the many antiquated forms in the religious and
                            political world. "O consistency, thou art a jewel." But in what does consistency consist?
                                <pb n="201" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> Emerson says, "obey the highest light revealed to-day, if it
                            upsets and destroys all of the preconcieved ideas of yesterday. The law of change that is
                            written on all human institutions, is the propelling power that is forcing onward toward a
                            higher destiny, the ever restless spirit of man. The continuity of an organization depends
                            upon its adaptability to the wants and needs of its supporters. The difference between life
                            and mere existence is apparent. The one is the energetic, active, dominant force seen in all
                            progressive associations. The other, the passiveness resulting from arriving at the boundary
                            of its environment. While its adherents believe that it is the highest embodiment of their
                            ideal it holds its former position ; when convinced that its boundary has been reached and
                            its work accomplished, then it is shelved to make room for advanced thought. The
                            conservative element in life that clings to the old, fearing to launch out into unknown
                            seas, and "opposing the new moon out of respect for the old," is the balancing power that
                            keeps in check the radical element that without proper restraint would overthrow all
                            organization and hurl society into inextricable confusion. The proper adjustment of these
                            forces produces a healthy growth, conserving the old as long as it is conducive to the
                            welfare of the body ; and when not, is removed to make way for newer and better conditions.
                            The inharmonious adjustment of the centripetal and centrifugal forces in life is the cause
                            of the discordant notes that are sounded upon the keys of human experience. When these are
                            properly balanced, the unfolding of life will proceed with a regularity not now apparent. To
                            the superficial observer, the structure is hid by the scaffolding used in its erection,
                            which is to be removed when the necessity for it ceases. When mankind progress out of the
                            artificial environment they have placed around themselves and accept nature as their teacher
                            and guide, the longevity of human life and human institutions will be increased. Place a
                            pyramid upon its apex and it needs many stays to prevent it from toppling over, but on its
                            base it is its own support. The operation of that ceaseless law that is changing the thought
                            of the age, is but the legitimate operation of those forces that when left to their normal
                            action will lead through pleasant pathways, unfolding to the mind higher conceptions of life
                            as its development enables it to comprehend those higher truths. The nineteenth century is
                            in advance of the preceding ones because the revelations of advance thought have been
                            accepted. "Give us this day our daily bread" is applicable in more senses than something
                            fresh to sustain the corporeal system. Truth only is eternal and its continuity cannot be
                            questioned, but there must be new revelations of it to supply the growing needs of a
                            progressive life. As the whole is greater than a part, the success of the great human body
                            or humanity in its entirety does not depend upon the perpetual existence of any one separate
                            part which can be <pb n="202" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> dispensed with and the body perform its normal
                            functions as long as the vital principle, the soul life remains intact. In all of the great
                            religions that mark the growth of spiritual life in the race, there is a principle that is
                            as eternal as the infinite because it is an emanation from that fountain ; but the
                            materialistic cloak that has enshrouded them showing marked differences to the outer sense
                            is fast being removed, showing the attonement that exists between them. When this work has
                            been accomplished, names and sects and parties will not exist, "as the knowledge of the Lord
                            will cover the earth as the waters cover the sea." Then the prophetic announcement will be
                            fulfilled,;'I will shake all nations and the desire of all nations shall come and I will
                            fill this house (the human soul) with glory, saith the Lord." Sonyea, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Appeal" TEIform="index"/> AN APPEAL.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wayne, Sophia" TEIform="persName"/> Sophia Wayne.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Christian awake! discard all earthly creeds, Adopt a holier faith, Seek for the light,
                            fulfill all noble deeds, Banish all fears of death. Look upward to the glorious worlds above
                            Formed by the Master's hand; Choose for thy watchword one of peace and love, Hope for the
                            promised land. What but the all-wise Infinite's commands Brought these bright worlds in
                            view, Speaking to us of fairer, better lands, Formed for the good and true. Turn not from
                            virtue's pure and lovely path, Walk ever in the light, Remove all deeds of evil, hate and
                            wrath, Learn always to do right. Then with our friends ascended, For victories sought and
                            won, And hear the blessed loving Master's voice, "Servant, thou hast well done." Ballston
                            Spa, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="And love is the first of all" TEIform="index"/> "AND LOVE IS THE FIRST OF ALL."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pick, Ernest" TEIform="persName"/> Ernest Pick.</byline><p TEIform="p"> One morning, there were several things to be done, apparently, at once, and trying to
                            arrange them in order, the question arose, "What shall be done first?" I stopped to listen,
                            for the voice of my innermost spoke: "Love your fellow men." And there was light; I knew the
                            beginning, without which I could not possibly accomplish the least wrork to the honor and
                            glory of my Master. "Love your fellow men." This was the first thing of all, before crossing
                            the threshhold of the house, to go to my daily work. Without it, I felt I should be void of
                            strength, without hands for my work, without heart for my Lord's interest. The importance of
                            this first step seemed to me so great, the desire of starting right so strong, that my heart
                            was filled to overflowing. For a moment a flash of light illumined the horizon of my mind so
                            far and wide, so deep and broad, as my eyes never have seen beforea new thought; at the same
                            time my soul enjoyed an unequalled communion with all that is noble, good and just, true,
                            loving and heavenly a new feeling. "Love your fellow men." Not until this shall be the
                            universal language of all tribes, peoples, and nations will man's work be begun to the
                            pleasure of his Creator. <pb n="203" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> Not before this becomes the universal
                            currency of all mankind, stamped on each coin and printed on each bill, will cease the
                            eternal warfare wherein a brother slays another, the son his father, the daughter her own
                            mother. "Love your fellow men" must be graven on all the boundary-stones of states and
                            empires, carved upon every gate leading into a city, inscribed upon the altars of all
                            churches, verily be set as a mark on every man's forehead, before he will be ready to appear
                            in the presence of the Lord and to re-enter into the Paradise, his birth-place and his
                            abiding home. Return then, ye fugitives and prodigals through the dark abyss of shame and
                            vice, up to the valley of repentance, upon the mountains of truth and virtue, overtopping
                            all else in creation, and upon the summits ascending and boldly reaching into the very
                            heavens of joy, peace and love. Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Web of life" TEIform="index"/> THE WEB OF LIFE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Swain, Edith L." TEIform="persName"/> By Edith L. Swain.</byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> [Contributed by Eldress J. J. Kaiine.] Weaving, weaving, weaving, weaving, Still
                                    the living shuttles fly, While the Master, never sleeping, Holds the pattern o'er us
                                    high. Holds the pattern and unrolls it Thread by thread, and day by day Blue and
                                    golden tints and carmine, Mixed with weary lengths of gray. Fain the weavers are to
                                    linger, Fain to scan the pattern o'er; But they know not till they weave it What the
                                    future holds in store. Flash the golden threads of sunlight, Gleam the purple tints
                                    of fame, As the weavers' gliding fingers Kich and beauteous figures frame.
                                    Throbbing, throbbing, throbbing, throbbing, Beating fast and beating slow, Never
                                    pausing, never resting, On the busy shuttles go. Now the threads are dark and
                                    sombre, Dim the weavers' eyes with tears, Trembling to the pattern looks he, Numb
                                    the halting hand with fears. Now the threads are black and broken, Tangled,
                                    intricate and crossed; Figures rambling, weird, unlovely, And the Master's thought
                                    seems lost. Sick at heart and worn and weary, Toils the weaver at his task; For the
                                    web must e'en be finished Ere he rest or respite ask. Weaving, weaving, weaving,
                                    weaving, Slow the shuttle works its will; Throbbing, throbbing, throbbing,
                                    throbbing, Faintly beating,and is still. Happy now the patient weaver Who the
                                    Master's plan hath wrought, Tracing carefully the pattern, Marring nor neglecting
                                    aught. For the web the Master turneth, And before his dazzled eyes, Shining in its
                                    wondrous beauty, All the thought completed lies; And the weaver joyful learneth That
                                    the wrong side was his own Till the beating, throbbing shuttle All its faithful work
                                    had done.</quote></cit><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Christian register" TEIform="index"/> Christian Register.</bibl></p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How many of us have been driven to the mercy-seat..." TEIform="index"/>
                            How many of us have been driven to the mercy-seat...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">' 'How many of us have been driven to the mercy-seat by our trials? Without them we should
                            often neglect the throne of grace." "He who casts his care upon God will be cared for." "God
                            has marked each sorrowing day And numbered every secret tear, And Heaven's long years of
                            bliss shall pay For all his children suffer here." ' 'I have always been fed and warmed and
                            clothed, and should I not bear constant testimony to God's faithfulness?"</p><pb n="204" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p"> THE MANIFESTO. SEPTEMBER, 1892. TERMS. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is published by
                            the "United Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued
                            regularly by the Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the
                            religious views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. All
                            communications should be addressed to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. One
                            copy per year, postage paid, .75 " " six months, " " .40 Send for sample copy, free. Entered
                            at the Post Office at East Canterbury, N. H., as second-class matter.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial.</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="And why not become established upon a good..." TEIform="index"/>
                                And why not become established upon a good...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> And why not become established upon a good and permanent foundation? The temporal and
                                spiritual interests of every individual imperatively demand this care. No order of
                                business could be successfully conducted without a well-digested plan of procedure which
                                would afford adequate stability to the enterprise that was under contemplation. And can
                                it be expected that the spiritual interests of a Community will warrant success by any
                                less effort? When men of mind attempt to raise a superstructure, they arrange with great
                                care, the foundation upon which they are to build, as they know quite well that upon
                                this depends their ultimate success. The good man of New Testament times who exercised
                                so much worldly wisdom as to build his house upon a rock, an immovable foundation, had
                                the great pleasure of finding it securely fixed after the tempest and the flood had
                                exerted their forces upon it and passed on. And for this work so thoroughly accomplished
                                he received the commendation of the divine Teacher. To make this lesson of life more
                                vivid and to force its acceptance into the minds of the more or less indifferent
                                hearers, he placed it in contrast with a workman of an easy and shiftless disposition
                                who built his house upon the sand ; utterly ignoring the necessity of preparing any form
                                of foundation, and the story goes on to say that this house was subjected to a
                                corresponding test. The tempest and the flood came against it, in full force, and the
                                careless builder saw all his property, suddenly destroyed. Every such lesson in life
                                should be studied with great care for a future guidance in our journey through time, and
                                as a necessary admonition while building our home that is to be eternal in the heavens.
                                Too much interest and care cannot be expended upon this spiritual work, which is to be
                                wrought out on the foundation which God has laid. <pb n="205" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> The apostle in
                                his exhortation to the brethren of Corinth, placed this lesson before them in its full
                                force, that he might impress upon them the necessity of a "faithful continuance in
                                well-doing." He presents the beautiful figure of God's building, and of the foundation
                                that is laid ; which foundation is Christ. Neither gold nor silver nor even precious
                                stones are worthy to be mentioned in connection with this work of the heavens. For these
                                perishable treasures men may become the slaves of an earth life,suffer all forms of
                                privation,risk every hazardous enterprise, and willingly forget God in their wild
                                pursuit after a shadow. In the building of a religious Community, which is made to
                                include the new earth and the new heavens wherein shall dwell righteousness, comes the
                                spiritual consecration. In this building of God,in this home of God, and more
                                particularly in this Community of God, how very necessary it is for those who accept it,
                                that they should dig deep and lay a foundation in God's love which cannot be moved.
                                There are lessons through the whole history of man that are valuable for meditation, and
                                especially so in the ministrations of Jesus and his immediate followers. On the
                                maintenance of this testimony of eternal life, largely depends the temporal and
                                spiritual prosperity of our gospel home. In this home, consecrated to God, a sure
                                foundation has been laid, upon which we must build. There need be no doubt, no mystery.
                                "He that soweth to the flesh, shall of the flesh reap corruption; but he that soweth to
                                the spirit, shall of the spirit reap life everlasting."</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mount Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mount Lebanon, New York
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Average of Weather at Mount Lebanon. July. Thermometer. Bain. 1891. 60.83 4.875 in.
                                1892. 70.05 7.875 in. Highest Temp, during this mo. 94. Lowest " " " " 46. Total
                                Rainfall " " " 7% in. Number of rainy days " " 9 C. G. R. Aug. 11. 1892. We purpose to
                                give Home Notes a vacation this month for the time is mostly employed trying to "keep
                                cool," and dodge the so-called electric storms, of which we have such an abundance. The
                                old-fashioned thunder-storm coming directly from the northwest, lasting about three
                                quarters of an hour, then passing on leaving the air clear and cool, is a rarity. Now
                                they come from every and any point in the heavens, two from different directions at once
                                with the wind changing every few minutes; and under such conditions they are like some
                                people; they do not know when to take their leave, or say the last word. The most
                                threatening looking storms are quite apt to pass us by, while those of a seemingly
                                milder type develop into the simply terrific. To those who delight in the "awful" the
                                electric displays are "grand." Lightning of every hue, and shape. Chains, forks, arches,
                                plaids, branches are to be seen; and if it would only come a little slower, milder and
                                not be so uncertainly mischievous wTe should all delight in it, as we would in gazing
                                    <pb n="206" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> upon man-made pyrotechnics. If this year thus far, is what we
                                may expect during the maximum period of the sun spots, then perhaps during the eleven
                                years, we may become used to it. But these storms are of the earth, earthy, even of the
                                mud, muddy, and we will endeavor not to let them enter the spiritual realm, where we can
                                always find a calm. Even the clouds there have a silver lining, and how blessed a
                                retreat where we can enjoy together the well-earned fruits of the spirit. Into this
                                realm, we shall always love to invite such dear friends as lately visited us from
                                Groveland. Eldress Polly Lee and Sister Lavina Dutcher. We would that they were nearer
                                us, when we could joy in their joy and sorrow in their sorrow in other ways besides
                                words. Strength of body, mind, purpose and cause, lies in concentration. We are learning
                                this lesson, but when shall we know it? Our beloved ex-ministry, Elder Daniel and
                                Eldress Ann, are still with the living, soul and body. They are practicing their
                                life-long lesson of active goodness, proving how long and strong that spirit can last
                                which has always lived for other's good. This is not vacation time after all, but next
                                month will do just as well. A. J. C. North Family. Aug. 11. 1892. In the last month we
                                have witnessed some very magnificent electrical displays; they were awfully grand. On
                                the afternoon of the ninth inst. one of our neighbors had his barn struck by lightning
                                and with its contents entirely consumed. Hay harness, tools, etc. There were four
                                persons in the barn at the time: the owner, his two sons and a hired man. The eldest of
                                the two sons was standing in the door-way, and was killed instantly; the other three
                                escaped unharmed. Here is another instance in proof of the danger of being in the open
                                door-way during a thunder-storm. About two years ago the barn that stood in the same
                                place was struck and entirely destroyed. Some twenty-five years ago this farm was owned
                                by the North Family. Oat harvest is progressing as fast as the weather will permit. We
                                are now engaged preparing a room at our cow-barn in which to put a separator; we have
                                tested it in our laundry, to our entire satisfaction. Shall put a motor in the room, and
                                drive it with water power. Are in hopes that it will somewhat reduce the dairy labor,
                                and yield a better article of cream and butter. I trust that before we reach the next
                                century-post, there will be a Christian people on the earth who will have learned to
                                prepare food in far greater perfection without the products of the dairy, or henyard
                                than is now done with them. The time was, and that within the memory of those living,
                                when it was thought to be impractical to get along in the kitchen without the hog. Now,
                                we look upon that as disgusting. Undoubtedly, in the not far off future there will be
                                those who will look upon the productions of the cow and hen with greater disgust, and
                                will exclude them from their dietary entirely. The subject is worthy the consideration
                                of all who are striving to live according to the "Golden Rule," and the Law of Love.
                                Peace on earth and good-will exercised toward all, will never be realized till the diet
                                of the people is changed. When humanity of the past, was in Eden, fruits and grains were
                                their portion. When Eden is restored, will it not be the same? D. O.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/> Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> Second Family. We had a few days in July that made us think the old version expressed
                                the heat best, it seemed as if the very ground would burn up. We have finished haying
                                and trying to get in' the oats and if it will only stop raining long enough, we shall
                                succeed. The Sisters say, if we do not know as much as we should, we do know beans, and
                                how to can them. We are now engaged canning string-beans for sale and <pb n="207" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> home use. The Society have put up several hundred doz. cans; expect to
                                put up several hundred more, before the season is over. We had a pleasant visit on the
                                18th. ult. with our good friends from Groveland, Elder Alexander Work, Eldress Polly Lee
                                and Sr. Lavina Dutcher. We believe them to be worthy, cross-bearing souls, true
                                followers of Christ and Mother. We have also been privileged to enjoy a visit with our
                                dearly-loved mother, Eldress Ann. We were over-joyed to see her among us as of yore,
                                with her even, inimitable grace of mind and person. She seemed an angel of goodness with
                                her pleasant smile and kindly word for all. Dear precious, Eldress Ann, you know we
                                deeply, truly love you, and it must be a comfort and consolation to you in your
                                declining years to know how much you are loved and honored by those to whom you have
                                always been such a wise counselor and friend. We have all shared of your love and
                                goodness of heart, and may we be worthy children. We thank the dear Sister who wrote the
                                beautiful tribute of love to our mother. We believe it expresses the feelings of all
                                Zion's sons and daughters. Here is an example of practical Christianity. For what end
                                the gospel of Jesus Christ, if not to make us more like the Divine. Let n% so live while
                                on the earth, that we may honor our cause, be a blessing to our Brethren and Sisters,
                                writing in their memory an epitaph, by the doing of kind deeds, for if we do not live so
                                as to merit the blessing of the faithful and consecrated, here, we cannot expect to win
                                it in the world to come.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/> West Pittsfield, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p"> Aug. 10, 1892. Deab Exdeb Henby:Our gospel messenger, the good little Manifesto, always
                                comes promptly on its errand of love and soul-enlightenment, and is very welcome.
                                Weather through July was extremely warm, and August promises to be as sultry. We have
                                not made such heat welcome, but like some other things, it stays. Health of family at
                                present, is quite good. We are continually giving thanks for Br. Ira's preservation to
                                us. He is in better health now than for many months past. There is some repairing of
                                buildings being done, in the way of shingling and mending of roofs to keep out the
                                water, which however pleasant it may be to the parched earth, does not prove so when it
                                comes dripping down within four walls. Quite a work is just completed at the East
                                Family; a well has been dug, and water carried by means of a windmill to the top of the
                                house, and modern conveniences put in on each floor. Within three weeks we have had
                                several hard thunder-storms. During one a valuable ox belonging to the East Family was
                                struck by lightning and killed and in two successive storms, the telephone box in the
                                Trustee's office was shivered into many pieces. Such severe storms have not been known
                                for some years in this vicinity. We feel no cause for complaint, as life and buildings
                                were spared, but renewed gratitude to our loving Father who is truly a "Eock of defense"
                                to all who trust in Him. Eldress Polly Lee and Sister Lavina Dutcher came to us on July
                                27th. We enjoyed a very pleasant visit with them. They will surely be enrolled among the
                                good and true. To-day we have enjoyed a similar privilege with Br. Washington Jones, and
                                Sisters, Corinne Bishop and Esther Gill from the Center Family, Mount Lebanon. Such
                                opportunities for interchange of love and good-will are too few and far between. It has
                                been truly said that "Believers are one great family," no matter how far separated. If
                                so, should we not call on each other whenever the privilege offers? We were reminded by
                                Elder Louie, in our meeting of Aug. 6th., that it was the one hundred and eighteenth
                                anniversary of the arrival of Mother Ann in this country, with her little band of
                                followers. We feel incited to keep the gospel free and unspotted, which has cost us so
                                much, but <pb n="208" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> which has come to us, "Without money and without
                                price." The fall term of school opened on Monday, the 15th. E. B.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mount Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/> Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> Center Family. Aug. 1892. Our haying is done and we have had an unusually large crop.
                                Our grain is nearly harvested. We have had excellent early potatoes for over a week
                                past, while cucumbers, squashes and string beans have appeared on our table. Pears are
                                just beginning to ripen. The early apples are scarce. The Sisters have spent several
                                days picking huckleberries, which are quite plentiful this season. People keep in usual
                                good health. We have warm days and cool nights, plenty of rain and abundance of sunshine
                                both inside and out, These are beautiful days for farmer and pleasure seeker alike.
                                Society meetings are spirit quickening and soul satisfying. Praise and thanks to the
                                Great First Cause from whom all blessings flow, peace, love and joy to all his people.
                                Beloved Elder Henry:Accept our thanks, many and kind, for the Editorial in the August
                                Manifesto. The theme is excellent; every word is good and true. Hope all who run may
                                read. We have long, wished to pen just such an article, but are minus the talent to
                                condense and yet portray the subject, as we now have it. Had we passed to the home "over
                                there," we might think we had come again to the home over here, and inspired the writing
                                of that well-written epistle. This, from the pen of one who for seventy years has been a
                                scholar in the school of Christ; conforming to the precepts and following the example of
                                our divine Teacher. My experience in this blessed school has been fraught with peace,
                                joy and heavenly comfort; seasoned at intervals with tribulation, sorrow and repentance.
                                No discouragement nor weakness is found in souls free from sin. Amid the darkest hours
                                of life, the kingdom of peace reigns within. To those who may chance to read these
                                lines, be it known that through our life we have put forth our best efforts to honor
                                this highest school of Christian love. Go thou and do far better than we have done; God
                                will reward you with a righteous reward and our most excellent Teacher will give you a
                                glorious certificate. Now good Editor, please accept our best love and impart freely to
                                the inmates of your beautiful home, with whom we had the pleasure of spending most happy
                                hours in days gone by. May heaven bless all those who contribute to our little paper,
                                and may God bless and prosper its worthy Editor. Your Sister, H. R. Agnew.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/> Shaker Station, Conn.</head><p TEIform="p"> "Whosoever shall give a cup of water in Christ's name, he shall not lose his reward."
                                There are many needy travelers on the journey of life who are fainting for the cup of
                                cold water that we might give. It is a little thing to do, and there are none who have
                                not some opportunity of giving it. Are we always ready to do some good deed? The cup of
                                water, the word of sympathy, the many little ways in which we can do good if we have the
                                love of the Master in our hearts, may reach some struggling soul and help him to conquer
                                a sinful life. The word in season, well chosen and fitted in at the right moment, may
                                make an impression never to be effaced, and sinking deeper and deeper, may turn the
                                heart that has received it to walk in the way of eternal life. I only wish to call
                                attention to those little things we consider trifles, but which mean so much to those in
                                trouble, or to "the stranger within the gates." Let us be up and doing while our day
                                lasts. There are calls for help in every direction. We have a work to do, and if we do
                                it well and hear the blessing pronounced, "Well done good and faithful servant," will
                                not <pb n="209" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> that be sufficient reward for all our suffering? Business in
                                poultry keeping should start small and work up. Get good poultry and learn from
                                observation and experience. Chickens make the best growth on whole wheat with no sloppy
                                food. To make poultry business profitable requires calculation. This is required in any
                                business. Eggs represent cash. Our largest hen's egg for July weighed five ounces. Very
                                acceptable. 3921 spaces of cream were sold in July. D. Orcutt.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ayer, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/> Ayer, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p"> Aug. 1892. Dear Editor:The drouth has finally ended. For three long weeks, Old Sol
                                poured down his rays with double intensity. Our supply of water which has seldom been
                                known to fail during a term of forty years, has been proven to its extremity this time,
                                and had not nature blest us with a refreshing shower, to-day, before the week had ended,
                                we could have told you a long story of our wonderful spring. However, our crops are
                                looking quite well. More hay, and that of a better quality, has been cut this year, than
                                during any of the last ten years. Potatoes bid fair for a good crop. Indian and ensilage
                                corn are growing finely, and a stalk has been brought to the house that measured in
                                height, more than nine feet. A. D. B.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shirley, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/> Shirley, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p"> Aug. 15. 1892. Beloved Elder Hestey :We have recently had a short visit from Elder Geo.
                                Wilcox. These occasional reunions are very comforting indeed. They are flnone too
                                frequent, however. We have finished our hay harvest which is not so large as we have
                                had, but of a good quality. Eye, very good, the threshing of which is one of present
                                occupations. The straw being called for as fast as we can get it to market. It is no
                                news to tell of hot weather; we have reason to think all have had a full share. Corn
                                promises well, as a consequence. How fast the seasons roll on, and how much food for
                                thought they yield. I have been much interested in the articles in the Manufacturer and
                                Builder. They would make a very interesting book. We still keep up fervent desires for a
                                breaking away of the darkness, and the ushering in of the more perfect day. J. W.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/> Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p"> Dear A. J. C:Your earnest appeal, and wise declarations in the August No., clearly prove
                                that brain waves move in a direct line from New York to New Hampshire, for our thoughts
                                have lately been on the same subject. Thanks for their utterance. If "Agitation is the
                                beginning of reform," no good effort is ever lost, but causes an advance toward the
                                desired goal, whether among us, or elsewhere. Our first Elder Brother Ezekiel Morrill,
                                said to the little company who had gathered into communal relations, "Ye are in the
                                world, yet ye are not of the world." This should be true of us, his professed followers,
                                and yet we are forced to acknowledge that we move, more or less, with the ebb and flow
                                of the mighty tide governing the masses of humanity; hence the divergencies from the
                                true covenantal consecration. It is an open question, worthy of study, why a people who
                                dress plainly, who do not live to eat, but rather eat that they may have strength to do
                                good while upon the earth, who have not as yet been seized with the traveling mania,
                                should not have both time and means for the healthful development of the physical,
                                mental and spiritual interests. We can see with our Sister the need of rising out of old
                                ruts, of various kinds, which in time must come, as we believe our Father and Mother
                                God, are at the helm, and that nothing will be suffered to supplant the purity and
                                beauty of our communal homes while guarded by loyal members. The old Church has not been
                                opened this summer. Society service in the <pb n="210" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> Chapel, has been
                                attended by some large companies, who could not, nor should they be turned away empty.
                                Why should we close our doors to all save our own members! echo answers, why? Electrical
                                storms have been frequent, and such heat! 120 degrees seems too hot to believe, but that
                                was the report, July 29th. We were sorry to learn that the strawberries failed at
                                Canaan, for our gospel friends are worthy of success, perhaps they did too luuch. It is
                                said that over civilization is causing a loss of natural vitality among humans and it
                                may be so with the petteu strawberry. Ours were nice and quite plenty. The currant
                                bushes were a pretty sight so heavily laden. An abundance for our own use, and some to
                                go abroad. Some one or ones knew just when to apply a solution of hellebore, and destroy
                                the destroyers. M. E. B.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Alfred, Maine" TEIform="index"/> Alfred, Me.</head><p TEIform="p"> Aug. 12. 1892. Beloved Elder Henry:No wonder the fear of a hotter climate should have
                                proved a means of grace with so many in past ages. After experiencing the hot nights,
                                and hotter days of July and Aug. one might well dread a more torrid location. The
                                weather has proved favorable for curing hay, and now that the rains have come, corn and
                                potatoes will be glad. Our ensilage corn, of which we have ten acres is already eight
                                feet in the air, and like the youth whose motto was Excelsior, is still climbing.
                                Potatoes planted on sandy soil, the rain came too late to save, but unless the excessive
                                rain and heat shall cause decay we shall have a good crop. Upland hay fell off 35 per
                                cent. If, as some claim, sickness is caused by sin,(Whose sin?) I fear we are not as
                                good as we hoped we were. A kind of epidemic much like whooping-cough visited us some
                                weeks ago and is inclined to remain much longer than it is welcome. We would call it
                                whooping-cough except that those who should be exempt from that disease have to share
                                with the rest. We are expecting some visitors from Harvard, the last of the month. Hope
                                by that time the unwelcome visitor will have left us. We are striving to keep the gospel
                                in its purity and simplicity. F. C.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sonyea, New York" TEIform="index"/> Sonyea, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> The fertile soil and genial climate of Sonyea has produced fruits rich in quality and
                                generous in quantity; it is the land of fruit and flowers, poetry and song, and thrice
                                blessed are they who can claim as their own, a few acres in this modern "Garden of
                                Eden." The heat is intense. During a fierce thunder-storm the large barn at the West
                                Farm was struck by lightning. Fortunately the damage was small, only a post was
                                splintered. The absence of fire prevented the destruction of the building. Thanks to
                                Providence that we escaped the terrible scene. G. D. G.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Canaan, New York" TEIform="index"/> Canaan, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> Aug. 5., 1892. Hoav rapidly time speeds along. Here is at hand the ninth month of 1892.
                                The seasons in their order come and go, bringing the duties and cares which must
                                necessarily be attended to, each in its proper time, or we lose the blessing of the
                                faithful laborer. Our Brethren finished haying July 21st. The rye and winter wheat also
                                have been zealously and carefully stored awTay in the barn. The spring wheat was cut
                                yesterday. Our two oldest boys have reaped the grain while our faithful aged Br. Andrew
                                Wise, with the help of two or three little boys have followed the reaper and bound as
                                fast as it was cut. We have not been fortunate enough, as yet, to have an attached
                                reaper and binder, but hope we may in the near future. The Sisters have been striving to
                                obey Mother's injunction to put their hands to work and give their hearts in prayer to
                                    <pb n="211" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> God. True Brethren and Sisters are the life and light of
                                Zion. Bless God for them. We have been engaged in painting 27% rods of picket fence in
                                front of the buildings, also continue painting windows, besides attending to a great
                                many other duties pertaining to the welfare of a home. On the 25th. of July we had the
                                pleasure of enjoying a beautiful visit with our two gospel Sisters from Sonyea, Eldress
                                Polly Lee and Sr. Lavina Dutcher. We highly appreciate such privileges, because they
                                serve to strengthen the bonds of gospel love. On Aug. 1st. and 2nd. a company of twenty
                                turned out to have a general merry berry bee; it being a very good year for
                                whortleberries;we gathered nine"and one half bushels. Expect to enjoy some good
                                whortleberry pies when the winds are blowing and the snow is falling. A. B.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="South Union, Kentucky" TEIform="index"/> South Union, Ky.</head><p TEIform="p"> Aug. 11. 1892. Elder Hesby Blinn:Please accept this little contribution, which I want
                                used for the distribution of the Manifesto, wherever you may think best. I think the
                                Manifesto is the best exponent that we have through which to disseminate our doctrines,
                                and I want to help you, as we help ourselves to do this very thing. I am interested that
                                this gospel of salvation should be spread broadcast through our land of freedom. We have
                                been greatly blest in the harvesting of our crops, for which I feel very thankful, and
                                therefore send you a few dollars as a present to help us to be placed more fully before
                                the world. Our hay crop was good. Wheat excellent. The East Family harvested 2200 bu.
                                while the whole Society had 7500 bushels. This was an average of 20 bu. to the acre.
                                Corn promises a fair yield. Fruit is plentiful, especially peaches and apples. Should we
                                not be very thankful. With kindest love, and a hope that you may be blest in your
                                efforts for good, I am your Brother. J. W. P.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/> East Canterbury, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p"> Weather Record, for July, 1892. Highest Temp, during the mo. 92. Lowest " " " " 51. Mean
                                " " " " 70.S Total rainfall " " " 1.95in. Number of days in which .01 of an inch fell,
                                (5. X. A. Bkiggs. Aug. 1892. "All things work for good to those who love the Lord;" and
                                indeed. we are all interested to have what we may do, work for good. The heat and cold,
                                the sunshine and storm, are just beyond our power of control, and we can do no better
                                than to let them come and go, while we are faithfully engaged in our duty. The barns are
                                now filled with the best quality of hay, and with good hay and good stock the farmers
                                can sit cross-legged and sing. This makes the winter months grow shorter, and the storms
                                genfy fade away. Very few blueberries have been gathered this season. Several barriers
                                stood in the way and by the time they were fully removed, the sweet, little blueberries
                                had left their bushy homes. The blackberries may not so easily escape, as interested
                                parties of Sisters are busy from day to day gathering the black caps for winter use.
                                With a good supply of fruit we need have but little fear. August has been a month for
                                camp meetings at the Weirs and thousands have made their way thither to preach and sing
                                and pray. Baptists, Methodists, Unitirians and UmVers tlists. While there were so many
                                good men and women, it would be a nice point to designate the sainted Christian from his
                                equally fortunate finning Christian. Two Sisters visited the Unitarian Grove Meeting and
                                were on the grounds more than two weeks, conversing upon the good things of God,
                                distributing tracts, and comforting the hundivds who did not attend the meetings, they
                                s:d small packages of Lovage and sugared flag. Who knows but that even this may be the
                                means of leading some to grace. While the Universalists were preaching from the
                                Methodist stand, and sitting in <pb n="212" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> Methodist seats, and occasionally
                                singing a Methodist hymn, two Brethren and two Sisters made a trip to the Camp ground,
                                on the shore of the Wimiepesaukee Lake. Although the Indian name of this beautiful lake,
                                is "The smile of the Great Spirit," it might be questionable if this heavenly smile was
                                apparent through all that was said during this mixture of theology from such
                                antagonistic systems of belief. However, we concluded that God's smile on the Lake would
                                in the wonderful bye and bye, chase away all the man-made dogmas, and all the unloveable
                                features of each class and make them to be as Brothers and Sisters in their work for God
                                and for humanity. Summer boarders abound. They are in every valley and on every
                                mountain. If they can find rest to their weary souls and bodies, they are indeed
                                fortunate. Not less than thirty of these wandering sons and daughters were admitted into
                                our dwelling to listen to the voice of song. It is said that their hearts were made
                                glad, and may be the inner life was brought into closer harmony with the spirit of all
                                Good. On the Sabbath the Novitiate Order permitted some eighteen or twenty to sit with
                                them during the hour of worship. They al so may have been blest, in common with their
                                Christian friends, and in this way humanity is made better, and God, our Father and
                                Mother is praised of men. H.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Inquiry. no. 7" TEIform="index"/> INQUIRY. No. 7.</head><p TEIform="p"> What is the fee of admission to a Shaker Society? No fee of -admission is demanded of any
                            one. No considerations of property are ever made use of to induce a person to enter the
                            Society, nor to prevent any one from leaving it. Having for its basis a well-ordered,
                            religious life, with its principles of consecrated interest and separation from the life of
                            the world, it teaches the Father and Motherhood of God, and the Brother and Sisterhood of
                            mankind.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Scripture text" TEIform="index"/> SCRIPTURE TEXT.</head><p TEIform="p"> The 8th. verse of the 3rd. chapter of John. The wind bloweth where it listetn, and thou
                            nearest the sound thereof,' but canst not tell whence it cometh, and whither it goeth : so
                            is every one that is born of the Spirit. A great many interpretations have been given to
                            this passage of Scripture and yet the worldly wise-men have not confidence in their own
                            illustrations. The rendering in the Diaglott gives us a better form,' 'The Spirit breathes
                            where it will and thou nearest its voice." The breathing or the outpouring of the Spirit of
                            God awakens new life in the soul, and to accept this new life is to keep unspotted from the
                            world. To be born of the Spirit is to grow in goodness, and a close communion with the
                            testimony of Jesus affords a protecting influence over evil and assures us that he "that is
                            begotten of God keepeth himself and the wicked one toucheth him not."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bible" TEIform="index"/> THE BIBLE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Eads, H. L." TEIform="persName"/> H. L. EADS.</byline><p TEIform="p"> ' 'For no other foundation can man lay than that is laid, which is Jesus Christ."1 Cor. Hi.,
                            11. There is no text within the lids of the Bible truer or more important than the one I
                            have chosen; but there <pb n="213" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> seems to be a quivering on the waters and a
                            brooding uncertainty arising in the minds of some as to its true value, which I hope and
                            trust I may be able in some good measure to remove. "No other foundation can man lay than is
                            laid, which is Jesus Christ." This truth I will in brief attempt to demonstrate. "Honest
                            persons can not fail to agree in their conclusions if they sufficiently define the terms
                            they use." This is evidently true. People who are careless are liable to use, and often do
                            use, a word to mean one thing, and afterward use the same word to mean another thing,
                            without knowing they involve themselves in a contradiction. The God-anointed man, Jesus,
                            became the Christ or the Messiahwhile the Christ-anointed disciples became
                            Christ-i&amp;ns, not Messiahs, but simply his Christian followers ; this and nothing
                            more, Jesus alone being the Christ of prophecy. His disciples and followers never were, nor
                            never can be Christs either in this or the angel world. To speak, as has been done, of a
                            "universal Christ, projecting entities throughout the world," is using words without a
                            meaning, and to use the term anointing to mean Christ, is doing the same thing. Also, the
                            term Word is used by many in the same careless way. It may be correctly used in various
                            ways, but it really signifies that which conveys an idea to the mind, either spoken or
                            written, or by sign or symbol; but it should never be used to mean an entity, as some have
                            done. "We should never take words for things, nor suppose them to stand for real entities."
                            The Bible, wrhile it contains both God's and man's written words, is ridiculed and set at
                            naught by some as \mworthy of perusal; but this is done mostly by those who read it least. I
                            am asked this question :Who can tell which is God's and which is man's wrord? I find but
                            little difficulty in distinguishing between them for myself. All that encourages
                            licentiousness and sin, or any violation of God's law therein recorded, or anything which is
                            impossible to be made clear to the understanding of the rational mind, either literally,
                            figuratively or metaphorically, may be considered the jumbling work of man ; but with it all
                            I would say that there is not, even in the Old Testament, one twentieth part of this
                            character, while we can claim for God nineteen-twentieths as valuable food for the under
                            world ; and the person who would throw all the good away for this little consideration would
                            be as simple and foolish as the person who would throw awray a good-fitting garment because
                            the skirts had become fa trifle soiled. I would say of the New Testament, take it as it is,
                            the whole book exceeds all others in divine inspiration, sublimity of thought and diction,
                            high poetic effusion, similitude, beautiful allegory, parable and metaphor, and its gold
                            should never be cast aside because of its spurious metal. The Old Testament not only
                            foreshadows the New, but it is a foundation and guide for the generative world, while the
                            New is the foundation of the regenerative. Right here I should define what is meant by the
                            term "foundation." It is not a sound or word <pb n="214" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> conveying an idea
                            revealed or unrevealed ; but it is a basis on which to build a super-structure. For the New
                            Heaven's Christ and his recorded word are the basis on which the new structure is reared,
                            and no other foundation can any man lay. A text also is a foundation for a discourse. The
                            prophets pointed to Zion's foundation : "Behold, I lay in Zion a precious corner-stone, a
                            sure foundation."Isa. xxii., 16. No other can man lay. This foundation is God-laid. He will
                            not lay a different one for the new heavens and earth. He is unchangeable. If we think to
                            find a different one to build on by some future revelation, we build on expectancyon
                            nothing, not even sand. Christ's saying (John iv., 12.) "He thatbelieveth on me shall do
                            greater works," does not mean he should build on a different foundation, but that the same
                            work should be more extensive. If any climb up another way, the same are thieves and
                            robbers. That it is unalterable is shown from the fact that no more sacrifice can be made
                            than is now required, and no greater reward can be given than that which is promised for the
                            sacrifice. (to be continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good health should be secured by correct living..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Good health should be secured by correct living...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Good health should be secured by correct living. Oatmeal can be used in a variety
                                    of ways, as oatmeal is too often drowned in too much milk, sugar and butter, f or
                                    good digestion; is swallowed so easily that it helps lead to overeating and its bad
                                    results.</quote></cit><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/>Halls Journal of Health.</bibl></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religion needs no ornaments to make it beautiful..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Religion needs no ornaments to make it beautiful...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"Religion needs no ornaments to make it beautiful. When unadorned it is adorned the
                        most."</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>KIND WORDS.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Every one who reads the Manifesto month after month..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Every one who reads the Manifesto month after month...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Connecticut, Shaker Station, August 1892" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station, Conn.
                                Aug. 1892.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Every one who reads the Manifesto month after month, knows well the rich store of
                                pleasure and good that it contains. This same pleasure and good influence might reach
                                other homes if those having the Manifesto would send it to these other homes and give it
                                the word of praise it so justly deserves.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, D." TEIform="persName"/>D. Orcutt</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Look on the bright side..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Look on the bright side...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">[Contributed by D.C. Brainard.] "Look on the bright side" said one to a friend who was
                            lamenting the misfortune that seemed to attend his every undertaking"Oh!" sighed the friend
                            "there is no bright side." "Then polish up the dark one" was the prompt reply.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We should eat to live, and not live to eat..." TEIform="index"/>
                            We should eat to live, and not live to eat...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">We should eat to live, and not live to eat. Decide what and how much you as an
                                    individual, need, and take that and nothing more. Put your bodily desires under the
                                    direction of the spirit, which should always hold the mastery if you hope to have
                                    health or happiness</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/>Hall's Journal of Health.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths. </head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cantrell, Henry" TEIform="index"/>Henry Cantrell
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Henry Cantrell, at Mount Lebanon, N. Y. July 22, 1892. Age 87 yrs. In 1844 his whole
                                family, consisting of his companion and four children were gathered to Believers. Nearly
                                half a century of consecrated labor spent in the fields of our Zion home. "Glory to the
                                righteous." D. O. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miner, Samuel" TEIform="index"/>Samuel Miner
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Samuel Miner, at Watervliet, Ohio., Aug. 6, 1892. Age TO yrs. 5 mo.
                                and 4 days. He was admitted into the Society at North Union, May 12, 1839. He was moved
                                from North Union to Watervliet, Ohio, October 1889. He has lived among Believers over 53
                                years. Was Elder at Watervliet for two years and Elder at North Union for a good many
                                years, He has been a faithful servant to the good cause. H. W. F.</p></div3><pb n="215" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Looking upward" TEIform="index"/> LOOKING UPWARD.</head><p TEIform="p"> Mount Lebanon, N. Y. 1. I long in my heart for the truth, For something divine, Oh 2.
                            Temptations so often allure, And evils assail, Whence 3. The pow'r of salvation I seek, And
                            love's perfect light, Some 4. Thro' struggle is victory won, If holy the strife, Oh where
                            shall I look for that grace, I know should be mine ? cometh that pow'r that will cause, The
                            good to prevail? spirit to strengthen the faith, That leads in the right, give me a fullness
                            in Christ, The truth and the life. rit. rit. My soul reaches upward in pray'r, O Lord, unto
                            Thee, Thou Chorus. cres. m rit.f ores. m. wilt in Thy mercy appear, Yea, even to me, Yea,
                            even to me. rit.f</p><pb n="216" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers
                        </head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>
                                The Phrenological
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Phrenological.A sketch of some features of the Columbian Exposition in the August
                                number of the I'hkknoldi.k al Jouknal includes a portrait of Columbus and the supposed
                                place of his birth in Genoa. A notable article, entitled "Mental Causes and Physical
                                Effects," follows. It is a powerful .appeal to society for the higher moral culture. Mr.
                                Luther C. Bateman, a talented lecturer of Maine, is given a place among the short
                                biographies, and evidently deserves the notice he gets. "What Phrenology did for one
                                poor boy" appears to be a personal narrative of the writer. "Vacation Time Suggestions,"
                                Our Children's Deformities from Dress and Improper Education. A Barbaric Fashion makes
                                "Child Culture" piquant and serviceable. Of the brief contributions to phrenological
                                biography. Alexander Campbell, the Distinguished founder of the Church of the Disciples
                                forms the larger part. The old style portrait gives him Roman sturdiness in face and
                                pose. The Health department is specially full of practical information. What is
                                Vitality? The Hygienic Treatment of Piles (worth a hundred dollars itself to any
                                sufferer from these torments), Some Summer Talk, and Sponging out a Headache are gems.
                                The scientific reader will enjoy the Anthropological Notes, we are certain! and the
                                Editor's pithy comments on very relevant topics. Price 15c, or $1.50 a year; offered "on
                                trial" six months for only 50c. Address Fowler &amp; Wells Co., 25 East Twenty-first
                                street, New York. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="World's Columbian exposition illustrated" TEIform="index"/>
                                THE WORLD'S COLUMBIAN EXPOSITION ILLUSTRATED
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> THE WORLD'S COLUMBIAN EXPOSITION ILLUSTRATED FOR AUGUST. At the first
                                glance of this number one is strongly impressed with its great worth and beauty. A mong
                                its literary featuresVe notice several well written articles of unusual interest. Among
                                these we mention: "Born of Patriotism," in which the advantages to each country
                                participating in the Exposition are forcibly presented, and the loss to any country
                                failing to take part in "this grand" opportunity to improve its conditions" is well
                                told. There is an article "Sunday Opening," cogent with arguments for the affirmative
                                side of the question. But especially interesting is the article "A visit to the World's
                                Columbian Exposition." In about two columns is embodied a description of the entire
                                Exposition as it will appear when thrown open to the world, and from it can be gained a
                                more perfect understanding of the scope, grandeur and worth of this "great interchange
                                of practical thought" than could be had by reading volume after volume of the
                                disconnected accounts appearing in the daily press. Among the artistic features we
                                notice a full page engraving of II. N. Higinbotbam, first vice-president of the board of
                                directors, and several full-page engravings of statuary, including five of the eight
                                groups that will adorn the Administration building, viz : statues representing "Art,"
                                "Blacksmith," "Abundance," "Commerce" and "Tradition." Great praise must be given the
                                publisher for the execution of the engravings of these beautiful works of art. But one
                                is struck with the large space given to the account of the National Catholic Educational
                                Exhibit, and to the biographies and the portraits of its principal promoters. But this
                                is easily understood when we recall the fact that Christopher Columbus was himself a
                                Catholic, and that the good king and queen, Ferdinand and Isabella, who assisted him in
                                making the voyage of discovery, thereby rendering it possible for a Columbian
                                Exposition, were also devout Catholics. There is a fullpage engraving of his Holiness,
                                Pope Leo xiii., and two letters, one to Mrs. Potter Palmer and the other an autograph
                                letter to Commissioner Bryan, published by his consent, and accompanied by English
                                translations. There is a full-page engraving of his Eminence, Cardinal Gibbons, large
                                engravings of all the American, archbishops, of Bishop Spaulding, president of the
                                National Catholic Educational Exhibit, and Rev. Maurelian, secretary and manager. Each
                                is accompanied by a brief yet complete biographical sketch by the versatile pen of Rev.
                                Maurelian, secretary and Manager of the Catholic Educational Exhibit. The generous space
                                given to the promoters of this great enterprise is a fitting compliment to the great
                                Catholic Church, and its faithful workers everywhere. Although this number is a worthy
                                successor to the seventeen illustrious numbers hereto, fore published. When completed
                                they willin the language of Vice-President Gage of the Exposition, "furnish a most
                                valuable history of that event," or in the language of Benjamin Butterworth,
                                ex-secretary and solicitor general and director of the Exposition, "prove very valuable
                                as the years go by." The publishers announce their "Special Great Offer" which includes
                                all copies from July, 1892, to January, 1893, ten in all, for only $1.50. This is about
                                half-price. Single copies 25 cents. There will be 60 copies from first to last,
                                subscription price, $12.00. Early in the Fall it will be published semi-monthly and
                                during the Exposition, weekly. In September this great work will be issued
                                simultaneously in English, German, French and Spanish. J. B. Campbell, Publisher. 159
                                &amp; 161 Adams St., Chicago, 111., U. S. A. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Evangeline" TEIform="index"/>Evangeline
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A PRETTY SURPRISE. A beautifully
                                illustrated and charmingly bound edition of Longfellow's "Evangeline," the most popular
                                long poem ever published by an American author, and one of the most famous poems in the
                                language, just published, is a pretty surprise for tbook-lovers. It is in large type,
                                numerous and excellent illustrations, very fine and heavy paper, gilt edges, remarkably
                                handsome cloth binding, with gilt title and ornaments. No illustrated edition has ever
                                before been published at less cost than $1.50, and that is about what you might "guess"
                                the price of this to be, but it isn'tit is only 1 cents! plus 6 cents for postage, if by
                                mail. This covers only about the actual cost of manufacture by the 100,000, the
                                publisher's Object being, not profit but to show the book-loving millions what he can
                                do. His publications are not sold by dealers, but only direct; catalogue, over
                                100-pages, a literary curiosity in its way, is sent for a 2-ct. stamp. Every home in the
                                landoughtto have a copy of this Evangeline, so charmingly beautiful, as a poem, as a
                                collection of artistic illustrations, and as a product of the book-making art. Address,
                                John B. Alden, Publisher, 57 Rose St., N. Y. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New England magazine" TEIform="index"/>New England
                                Magazine
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Joseph Kirkland writes in the New England
                                Magazine by far the best account of the great Chicago Fire that has found its way into
                                print. He gives a straight, connected story of the progress of the fire, like a good
                                newspaper man who knows how to group his facts into a telling, vivid and consecutive
                                story. The article is fully illustrated from photographs furnished by Major Kirkland's
                                Western publishers, who possess the best collection of the kind in the country. </p></div3></div2><!--<pb n="217" id="p"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
THE FUMING SWORD
A Radical, Rational  and Racy
Reform Paper.
The bitter foe of every form of social abuse
in church and state, the expositor of Koreshanlty, which is primitive Christianity revived, and the promulgator of an equitable
system of exchange which is destined to revolutionize commercial methods and
Orush the Iniquitous  Money Power
SAMPLE    COPY    FREE.
Tie Gniiing Star Pnl. House.
3619 Cottage Grove Avenue.
CHICAGO, ILL.
The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy. July.
Contents. Treatment of the Sick; The Secret
of Health; Krodhagara; Anti-Vaccination;
Cause and Effect of Heredity; What is the object of this life? If you would keep cool, etc.,
etc.   Dr. T. V. Gifford & Co., Kokomo, Ind.
A Literary Find.
Mr. Bok has succeeded in unearthing a
quantity of unpublished material by Henry
Ward Beecher, which will shortly be published
as a series of articles in The Ladies' Home Journal. The material is especially valuable since
it deals with a range of topics both varied and
timely, and will advance, for the first time in
print, the great preacher's views on a number
of such interesting questions as marriage,
home government, woman in public and private life, politics, etc., etc. Mr. Bok has secured the co-operation of Mrs. Beecher and
Professor Ellinwood, Mr. Beecher's private
reporter, in the editing of the material.
Hall's Journal of Health. Aug. Contents. Talks with Dr. Mandeville; The Liver;
Russian Lepers; The Wonders of your Watch ;
Overwork and Disease; Tired People; The
Proper Way to Sit; Glycerine in the House;
Cooking and Digestion; Hints for the Bath,
etc., etc.   Office 340 West 59th. St., New York.
Scientific American
Agency for
CAVEATS,
I  TRADE MARKS,
DESIGN PATENTS
COPYRIGHTS, etc
For Information and free Handbook write to
MUNN & CO.. 361 Broadway, New York.
Oldest bureau for securing patents in America.
Every patent taken out by us is brought before
the public by a notice given free of charge in the
Largest circulation of any scientific paper in the
world. Splendidly illustrated. No intelligent
man should be without it. Weekly, $3.00 a
year; $1.50 six months. Address MUNN & CO.,
Publishers, 361 Broadway, New York.
THE DIVINE AFFLATUS,
A
FORCE IN HISTORY.
Price, 10 cts.
 We want one in every town
 to handle the
JACK FROST FREEZER.
DEALERS
Makes
A Scientific Machine made on a Scientific Principle. Save
their cost a dozen times a year. It is not mussy or sloppy.
A child can operate it. Sells at Bight. Send for prices and
discounts.
29   Murray St.,   NEW   YORK.
 Ice   Cream    in   3O   Seconds.
TIMELSTRENGTH )      By     j BUSY WORK
AKD PATIENCE j   Using   | Jj SERIES.
A copy, FREE, ofNoraial Instructor, tSie best educational
paper in America,will give full particulars. Dansville, K.\7.
save
AGENTS
<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure.
A cream of tartar baking Powder."   Highest of   all   in  leavening  strength.Latest
Untied States Government Food Report,
Ro ya l B A icing FOWDKit Co., 106 Wall St., N. Y.
JOHN   F.   STRA7TON   &   SON'8
CELEBEATED
Importerioftnd WholajUDcaIriin 11 kinds of
MUSICAL   .MERCHANDISE,
Vichnt, Guitars, Banjos, Mandolines, AccordeoM,
Harmonicas, skc., all kinds of Strings, etc.etc.
43 A 45 Walker St.,                  SEW YORK.
"HTERPEETM PROPHECY"
AND  THE
"Appearing of Christ,"
is the title of a neat little pamphlet of
some forty pages, just sent out by A. G.
Hoixister of Mount Lebanon, N. Y.
The many at the present time who are
interested in the fulfillment of prophecy
and in its mathematical calculation, will
find themselves by the side of the good
old prophet Daniel, and with him illustrating the Coming of Christ so clearly
that no occasion can arise for the least
doubt.                             Price, 10 ctsThe Life and Gospel   Experience of
Mother Ann Lee.                  Price 10 eta.
Address H. 0. Blinn, East Canterbury, If. H,
E. C. Morris & Co,
64 Sudbury St.,  Boston, Mass.
FffiE AND BUEGLAB-PEOOF SAFES.
Bank Safes, Bank Vaults, Bank Vault
Doors, and. Deposit Work of all kinds.
The Best Safe in the World.   160,000 in use.
Always preserve their contents
150 sold in Lynn, Mass., since that great lire
where 50 of our safes were subject to intense
heat, preserving their contents.
Champion Record also in the Great Chi'
cago Fire in 1871, in the Great Boston Fir* in
1872, and in all the great fires since. Send
for circulars.        Agents "Wanted.
JOHN F. STEATT01? & SOff,
43 & 45 Walker St.             N EW YORK.
Importers of all  kinds oMUSICAL   MERCHANDISE,
Violins,  Guitars,   Banjos,
Accordeons, Harmonicas, &c.
All kinds of STRINGS, etc., etc.
HYMNS AND ANTHEMS
FOR   THE
H0UH of WORSHIP.
The above is on the title page of a beautiful book of 144 pages just issued from
the press at East Canterbury, N. H.
Containing as it does some of the inspirational thought of the gospel of Christ,
it will be in direct harmony with those
who love to do good.
Price, 50 cts. & 7 cts. postage.
Address, H. C. Blinn, East Canterbury,   N. H.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>