<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2908" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">20</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">East Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">29</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">8</biblScope><date value="18990801" TEIform="date">August 1899</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">113-128</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="29" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="8" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
MANIFESTO
WONDERFUL strange REVELATIONS.
DANIEL'S & STJOHNS
PROPHECIES.
48 page pamphlet.     Price 10 cts.
13 for $1.00.
Address,    H. B. Bear, Preston, Ohio.
A SUMMARY VIEW
OF  THE
MILLENNIAL   CHURCH,
OF
''United   Society   of Believers"
It treats of the Bise and Progress of the
Society, together with the general Principles of the Faith and Testimony.
Price, 50 els.
Sketches of Shakers and Shakerism. A synopsis of the United Society., of Believers in Christ's Second
Appearing. Illustrated. By Giles
B. Avery.    Price 15 cts. |
BRIEF EXPOSITION
or the
Principles and Regulations
of the
SOCIETY   OK1   BELIEVERS.
Price, 10 cts.
THE ALTRUIST.
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is publisht by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all their
property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. It now has 5,000
acres of land in Southeast Missouri on
which it offers a home and employment
for life to all acceptable persons who may
wish to join it.            50  cents a year;
specimen copy free.    Address A. Longley, 2819 Olive St. St. Louis, Mo.
THE
AUGUST,   1899.
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
The July number of Donahoe's Magazine
contains many excellent features.   The illustrated article on Nicaragua is particularly
timely, and imparts much information relative to the route of the new canal.    Rev. J. T.
Roche contributes a second paper on Belief
and Unbelief; and the Rev. Jas. H. Cotter
writes in warm approval of  Macbeth as
Shakespeare's master-piece.   Some Gaelic
Scholars; is the caption of an article that will
find many readers.   It is illustrated with
fine portraits of the leaders, Bishop O'Donnell, Douglas Hyde, Rev. Eugene O'Growney,
Rev. Richard Henebry, and Rev. Michael
Hickey.   The finely illustrated paper on
Augustin Daly's Life and work sets forth the
personal character of the man, his achievements as a dramatist, his business career, and
his influence in remodelling and elevating
life on the stage.   No-truer or more sympathetic estimate has been publisht.   The fiction
of the number is excellent and varied.    The
Golden Harvest; runs through some very entertaining chapters, and there are several
bright short stories.   A Plaything of Fate; a
serial by Anna C. Minogue, the well known
Southern writer, begins in this issue.   It is
the story of a young girl's struggle against
adverse circumstances, and is a strong picture of the triumph of character.    Rev. J. M.
Harrington writes entertainingly of Pagan
Ruins in the Orkneys, and Susan L. Emery
analyzes the poetic work of Francis Thompson.   There are many fine engravings and
poems, and a miscellany of interesting department matter,
With its infinite variety of excellences, the
July Ladies' Home Journal appeals to every
taste and touches every interest.   It opens
with The Most Famous Little Town in America;   which pictures many interesting spots in
historic and literary Concord.   There is a delightful view of social life in the Colonial
days in When Washington was Married;
which brings to light many new, interesting
facts.   A series of almost incredible narratives in The Moonlight King; tells of the follies and eccentricities of Ludwig II of Bavaria.   The gifts to our Government from foreign Powers are described in Presents That
Have Come to Uncle Sam.   Ian Maclaren discusses the pulpit and the pew in an article on
How to Make the Most of Your Minister; and
Katharine Roich writes of The College-Bred
Woman in Her Home.   The fiction of the July
Journal includes a continuation of Anthony
Hope's serial, Captain Dieppe; the conclusion
of A College Courtship; the second of 0)
Peckham's Opinions; and a humorous portrayal of The Valor of Brinley, by John Kendrick Bangs.   Entertaining in the Country;
How to be Pretty Though Plain; What it
Means to be a Dressmaker; Birthday Parties;
A Boy's Club-House on the Water; are some
of the seasonable, practical features.   Mrs.
S. T. Rorer writes on Hasty Eating and Hurried Meals; and Cooking Over All Sorts of
Fuel; and Maria Parloa describes and pictures new and effective labor-saving devices
for the home.   The Gossip of a New York
Girl; details the very newest fancies in feminine attire, and Pretty Stuffs for Midsummer
Frocks; are described.   Two pages are devoted to Floral Porches and Vine-Clad Cottages;
an attractive feature filled with suggestions
for every homekeeper.   By The Curtis Publishing Co., Phil.   Ten cents per copy, one
dollar per year.
The Midsummer Fiction-Art number of
Frank Leslie's Popular Monthly, publisht
July 20th, bids fair to be the most brilliant of
the season.   Within an artistic cover by Wenzell, will be gathered such contributions as:
An illustrated poem by W. D. Howells;   short
stories by Ruth McEnery Stuart, Joel Chandler Harris, Edgar Fawcett, Etta W. Pierce
and Larkin J. Mead; a golfing extravaganza,
by Van Tassel Sutphen ; A Day of President
McKinley's Life; by Mrs. John A. Logan;
and reproductions of four of F. Hopkinson
Smith's most beautiful water-color paintings,
with comment by Perriton Maxwell.     The
fiction features in the above enumeration are
illustrated by the following well known artists; Albert B. Wenzell, Howard Chandler
Christy, F. Luis Mora, W. Granville Smith,
Clifford Carleton, Hugh M. Eaton, Charles
Grunwald, H. C. Edwards, Frank Adams and
George R. Brill.
Why we need a knowledge of Phrenology is
broadly illustrated in the June issue of The
Journal of Htgeio-Therapt.   Papers on
the Science of Life, by the Editor; Where it
is most Needed, by Elsie Cassell Smith; and
Woman and her Needs, by Madame L. D.
Windsor are especially praise-worthy.   Price
75 cts. per annum, single nos. 10 cts.   Published monthly by Dr. T. V. Gifford & Co.,
Kokomo, Ind.
Word and Works for July, 1899 is at hand
with timely forecasts for July.    Readers always take an interest in this good paper.
Subscription $1.00 single copy 10 cts.   Word
and Works, St. Louis, Mo.
AND
SHAKERISM.
By Giles B. Aveby.
Price,  loots.--><pb n="113" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Old inheritance" TEIform="index"/>THE OLD INHERITANCE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>By Elder Henry C. Blinn.</byline><p TEIform="p">THE holy bond of matrimony," as it is sometimes called, brings for ward a subject which has
                            more or less direct influence upon every religious Order, and well it might, as it is the
                            foundation upon which the order of the world stands. On the inspirational strength of the
                            following passage, as well as from the animal passions to which it strongly appeals,. this
                            has become a favorite text in the Christian church,"And God blessed them and said unto them,
                            Be fruitful and multiply and replenish the earth." The first chapter of Genesis is very full
                            and explicit in the commands which God gave to the several orders of his creative work. All
                            the vegetable and animal creation are under the same common law. All are created male and
                            female and assigned to a special duty which should ultimately replenish the earth. Man, who
                            is said to have been formed in the image of God, receives the same law as does the animal.
                            Nothing in this part of the sacred record places him above the beasts of the field, in the
                            work of generation. The law of reproduction becomes the law of God and receives from the
                            Creator the divine benediction "very good." We next find that Adam had a companion to assist
                            him. The Bible says, "God brought her to the man." This forms the first marriage ceremony.
                            Admitting that the ceremony was performed by such high authority did not, in the least,
                            change the animal relations of the man and woman, any more <pb n="114" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 114 THE
                            MANIFESTO. than it did that of the beasts of the field or the fishes of the sea, as they had
                            the same command to multiply. Under no consideration could this law be ignored, and the
                            anticipated success attend the creative work. This same direct interest followed the race
                            from generation to generation, and became so marked in its results that those who maintained
                            it were denominated the sons of God, and those who ignored the law were called the sons of
                            Belial. The same regard for the race was manifested through all the Judges and Prophets, and
                            culminated in the mysterious birth of Jesus. In accepting the divine mission, Jesus is said
                            to have sanctioned what God had so carefully arranged in the garden of Eden, by his presence
                            at the marriage at Cana and by contributing to the enjoyment of the guests. He accepts the
                            hospitality of Peter, who is a married man, and finall}7 makes him a bishop of the church,
                            which agrees remarkably with the Apostle Paul, who says that a bishop must be blameless, and
                            the husband of one wife. Jesus blesses the little children that come out to meet him, which
                            may be accepted as an evidence that he approved of the generative life. Bible readers will
                            readily find that the sacred volume has more advocates in favor of generation than it has of
                            a virgin order. That the meekest man, the wisest man, the prophet, the high priest and even
                            the man after God's own heart, were married, and more than this, some of them were decidedly
                            strong advocates for polygamy. Now with this Biblical and churchal education, we need not
                            wonder that the Christians are so enthusiastic over what they call God's great command. The
                            cause in which one enlists all his energies must necessarily absorb his life. The man who
                            lias become a life member of the Generation Society who reads and writes about it and
                            strongly advocates it in public and private, might be expected to render a decision like
                            this Rio gentleman :"How remarkable it is that whenever an enthusiast in religion gets new
                            light and adopts what he considers advanced views, he almost invariably begins to tamper
                            with marriage. In this tampering he always betrays the charlatan and sufficiently warns all
                            who attempt to follow him, to beware of him." When this Rev. Mr. Worldly Wise Man had
                            relieved himself of this decision, he must have been relieved, but possibly may have
                            forgotten that others, as well as himself, could read the Bible, and at the same time have
                            the divine right to understand it from their own religious standpoint. It is very natural
                            that the children of this world should think it right for them to enter the marital
                            relations. It belongs, as they do, to a civil institution, and to an order of life which
                            becomes a matter of worldly interest. It is the forming.of a co-partnership for the mutual
                            benefit of those who engage in it. All the laws concerning the marriage covenant are under
                            the control of the civil government. This determines who may, and who may not be <pb n="115" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 115 married ; who may, and who may not be divorced, and
                            attaches fines and penalties to every deviation. We do not dispute the point that those who
                            get new light on the subject of the Christ life invariably find themselves at variance with
                            the advocates of generation. And why not? Jesus says, "The children of this world, (not his
                            followers) marry and are given in marriage," and this the much-married Rev. Dr. calls
                            tampering with the marriage relation. On this point "Let every man be fully persuaded in his
                            own mind." Jesus taught a new and living way. He received advanced ideas, because an
                            enthusiast on the subject of the kingdom of God. As proper as the natural order of
                            generation may have been for Adam and the Rev. and their followers, it was not encouraged in
                            the ministration of Jesus. Peter may have been a married man, but that no more prevented him
                            from becoming a disciple, than because he was a fisherman. Jesus said, "Except a man forsake
                            all that he hath (and Peter had a wife) he can not be my disciple." St. Paul was another
                            enthusiast who, like Jesus, advanced religious ideas, and he also began to tamper with the
                            marriage question, to the evident disgust of the Rev. Dr. St. Paul was an unmarried man, as
                            was Jesus, and he wrote to the churches, "I would that all men were even as I." Human nature
                            is about the same now, as in the days of the apostles, and all may easily learn,"To be
                            spiritually minded is life and peace, but to be carnally minded is death." East Canterbury,
                            N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reviewal" TEIform="index"/>REVIEWAL.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="White, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>By Eldress Anna White.</byline><p TEIform="p">~T~ IKE the fulness of the approaching harvest comes our little Harbinger I 1 of peace and
                            good-will for July. Each article teems with fruit of the new lifea life hid with Christ in
                            Goda life as beautiful as a rose in its unfoldment, when sought arightan eternal life, found
                            in the acceptance of eternal principles, and found in each lovely Zion home where the
                            standard of Virgin Purity rears aloft its snowy banner. "Why Not Think," stops us at once
                            from all other pursuits and we go to thinking; as we think, we reason, and as we reason we
                            act, as far as power to do so in us lies. But, the reasoning must spring from pure motives
                            based upon the fundamental principles of truth, or we may be led away by carnal reasonings,
                            not having our thoughts sufficiently purified. We are glad our dear Sister has favored us
                            with her "Soliloquy." How many good thoughts are ofttimes kept concealed; by withholding
                            them we miss the opportunity of sowing the seed of the kingdom come. Let us enter her
                            garden, not merely to enjoy the sight and the fragrance of the flowers <pb n="116" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/>
                            116 THE MANIFESTO. there growing, but for the purpose of securing rare plants for
                            transference and seeds for sowing, that we too may grow a garden, and in cultivating it, we
                            ourselves may become the flowers of earth and the glory of heaven. "Unerring Principle"
                            should be placed alongside of B. Fay Mill's article "Between the Animal and the Angel," in
                            the July "Arena." The one claims absolute independence of every other one, while the other
                            claims naught but dependence and a following after lest by any means they attain unto the
                            resurrection of life. The one gives what is called the new thought of the day, just what is
                            needed to stir and awaken the masses, but this thought, old of itself, does not tell you how
                            to destroy a single atom of the old life, that is left to be told by a simple Shaker. Elder
                            Oliver has done it. I repeat what he has said after an experience of fifty years in a life
                            which is continually growing brighter and newer as the years go by, that the "happiest,
                            purest and most harmonious organization that was ever on earth is a Shaker Community." "The
                            Mission of Disciples of Christ" is aptly and clearly depicted after the same manner. The
                            disciples were to provide for the journey that they might learn dependence and trust in
                            Divine guidance. "I have chosen you." "Follow thou me." "Cycles and Magnets" is an article
                            as interesting as is the writer. There is a ring of practical Christianity chiming through
                            it. It brings us down to the era which George Fox initiated, and carried still further by
                            Mother Ann Lee when she insisted upon the right of woman to her own body, which really
                            insures all the other God-given rights and makes her the Comforter of souls. Last, but not
                            least, we find "God's Promises" concisely and interestingly reviewed by our beloved Editor.
                            We go back upon them without taking one backward step. If not one jot or tittle of the law
                            shall pass away until all be fulfilled, then do we not need to stop and reflect, and find
                            out our bearings ? Elder F. W. Evans was a prophet in his daywas a follower of this
                            school-master Mosesa believer in his law as being God's law. An article from his pen is so
                            in unison with the one referred to, and so in keeping with the times that we are sure the
                            readers of The Manifesto will be interested and find food for reflection in its perusal.
                            "They sang the Song of Moses, the servant of God, and the Song of the Lamb in the morning
                            and again in the twilight hour." "We call ourselves Christians, and claim Jesus as our
                            Savior. But Jesus was a Jewthe son of David, of the tribe of Judah. There were two laws, the
                            law of God, which was pure and holy, being a reflex of the law of nature on the animal
                            plane, and the penal law, which was added because of the transgression of the original and
                            universal law of nature, by mankind. By that law wras the knowledge of sin and its
                            punishment. <pb n="117" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 117 The twelve tribes of Israel, Moses
                            brought up out of the land of Egypt, where they had been immersed in all the sins of Egypt,
                            and were possessed of all the diseases of the Egyptians, which those sins had created. The
                            property laws of Egypt had produced poverty and riches, as in Christendom to-day. Capital
                            and labor were as antagonistic then as now. Joseph, as primeminister of Egypt, had used his
                            spiritualistic power to speculate and transfer all the property of the inhabitants of the
                            land into the hands of Pharaoh. The continuous violation of dietetic laws had made the
                            Israelites a band of invalidspatients ; a catalogue of their diseases and maladies was
                            fearful; and the sexual relations were in confusion, and had caused the firstborn in each
                            household to be slain, while all the male children born to Israel were doomed to
                            destruction. The land was filled with mummies and dead people waiting to be embalmed, and
                            with sorrow and mourning. Moses used his spiritualistic power to deliver Israel from the
                            grasp of the Egyptians, the greatest military power on the face of the earth. Then, by the
                            same power he fed the whole nation on mannaa vegetable production for forty years. This diet
                            as food, and the pure water from the rock to drink cured the people of the diseases of
                            Egypt, of which the Israelites were sorely afraid. In obedience, no one could say, I am
                            sick! and neither were there any poor. There were no rich or poor; no sickness or disease ;
                            no noxious, destructive insects as are now over-running the kingdom of
                            Antichrist-Christendom. In Canaan, all the people, male and female, were freeholders,
                            vegetarians, and chaste, using marriage only for offspring, as George Fox taught and Moses
                            enjoined. Jesus was without sin, when he abstained from marriage, from private property, and
                            from flesh-meat, or animal food. After confessing his sins to John the Baptist, the Christ
                            spirit came to him as guardian Spirit. The God of Israel was a tutelary divinity, not deity.
                            The Scriptures are not the word of God, but a record of the religious experience, history
                            and literature of the Jews. And Jesus was no more the Christ than was Ann Lee ; they were
                            both baptized with Christ spirits. The Christ heavens are above all heavens, it is the
                            heaven of heavens. God is not a trinity, but a dualitya father and mother. The natural
                            world, with all that there is therein, shows forth the true order of Deityof the God-head.
                            There was the law, and the prophets, who prophesied of the coming of the Messiah, and of a
                            great work of God in the latter days. John the Baptist preceded the Messiah, and prepared a
                            goodly number of people in Judea, for the first Christian dispensation which was founded at
                            the day of Pentecost. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A Christian life is a life..." TEIform="index"/>A Christian life is a life...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A Christian life is a life hid with Christ in God, every power of mind and body in the
                            service of godliness.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="E., J." TEIform="persName"/>J. E.</byline></div2><pb n="118" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wanted" TEIform="index"/>WANTED.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, Jessie" TEIform="persName"/>By Jessie Evans.</byline><p TEIform="p">HOW much rushes into thought waves as we scan the wide sweep of horizon inscribed by one
                            brief word ! Wanted ! What is not wanted in this wonderful, wide world of ours ? Everything
                            that presents itself to the human eye has its definite purpose, else it would not have found
                            its way into the vast creation of Gad. The great, unerring Law-giver has put into operation
                            so perfect a plan that somehow, somewhere, sometime every individual life will fulfill its
                            end in the divine mind, That we are so strangely and sadly distanced from this desirable
                            millennial condition, to-day, after a human history covering a period of perhaps six
                            thousand years, is part of the inexplicable system of salvation toward which evolution is
                            steadily though slowly lessening the distance. Of theorizing on this broad, perhaps vague,
                            subject, the flesh wearies and the heart faints; yet faith firmly anchors the mind to the
                            assurance that in God's good time, and in ways perhaps mysterious to the speculative mind of
                            the skeptic all the glorious prophecies of the ancients will be fulfilled. But what of
                            to-day? We have only the vital needs of one day to consider, to meet, to supply. The eternal
                            future will come to us one day at a time. God's wisdom has so mercifully adapted his
                            stupendous laws to our littleness that from morning till night is our only term of service.
                            The Voice says to us, "Go work to-day in my vineyard," and, by way of hushing the undue
                            anxiety so natural to the material mind, adds, "Take no thought for the morrow, for the
                            morrow shall take thought for the things of itself," while the great Teacher instructs us to
                            pray after this manner: "Give us this day our daily bread." In this one brief sentence, so
                            deeply studded with faith in God's knowledge of our needs and his liberality toward our
                            great necessities, we seem to be drawn with our hungering and thirsting in sight of the
                            green pastures and the still waters of the divine landscape. Our needs lie open ever to the
                            gaze of the Infinite. "Your Father knoweth what things ye have need of before ye ask him,"
                            yet only by asking have we the promise of receiving. The heart of the Christian Church seems
                            burdened with the keen, deepseated tribulation foretold by the Savior in connection with the
                            hundred-fold blessing. Never yet did an individual or corporate life rise in defence of the
                            unpopular principles of true Christian integrity without feeling the bitterness of opposing
                            forces. This conflict is not limited to one section or to one denomination. Indeed whatever
                            finds its way into the great arterial system of religious thought in this day of quick
                            transmission is felt for good or ill more or less strongly in every church. The present
                            burden is a universal one and represents the vital need of our day. What is the trouble in
                            the socalled Christian Church ? What is expected of it ? How can this be fulfilled ? <pb n="119" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 119 These are the burning questions that face us from
                            day to day with alarming vividness. I. Christ said, "By their fruits ye shall know them,"
                            and the Apostle adds, "The fruit of the spirit is love, joy, peace, long-suffering,
                            gentleness, goodness, faith, meekness, temperance ; and in the light of this criterion we
                            are able to discern the presence or the absence of the spirit which characterized the first
                            true Christian Church. Read the second chapter of Acts, and mark the baptismal work which
                            resulted in the conversion of three thousand souls, who "continued steadfastly in the
                            apostles' doctrine and fellowship," then turn to the church of these latter days whose
                            corner-stone is imbedded in those principles. Where is it? Why? The truth leads the
                            questioning, bitter though our replies may be, and loath as we may be to utter them :Have we
                            not lowered the primitive Christ standard to our human weakness instead of reaching up with
                            our deficiencies to its divine strength? Have we upheld the enforcers of our laws? How easy
                            to blunt the keen-edged truths of the gospel that they may fall agreeably upon the ear of
                            the natural man ! When the divine message struck a chord in opposition to the selfish will,
                            were we "offended because of the word?" It is human to screen from its inevitable
                            condemnation" the sin that doth so easily beset," but no divine benediction can follow where
                            the name of Christ is upon the lip but the worship of self in the heart. Only the simple
                            mourn that the fruits of the spirit result not from sowing to the flesh, and that grapes
                            grow not from thorns. Above our foolishness, God's truth through the Apostle stands
                            inexorable; "Other foundation can no man lay than that is laid, which is Jesus Christ. Now
                            if any man build upon this foundation gold, silver, precious stones, wood, hay, stubble ;
                            Every man's work shall be made manifest; for the day shall declare it, because it shall be
                            revealed by fire; and the fire shall try every man's work of what sort it is. If any man's
                            work abide which he hath built thereupon, he shall receive a reward. If any man's work shall
                            be burned, he shall suffer loss; but he himself shall be saved; yet so as by fire." Without
                            doubt this is the day of the fire test. Upon the altar of the church the shekinah of truth
                            has never been extinguished, but by the compelling forces of our times our life work is put
                            to the flame as never before. Here we see the glory of the righteous who put only gold to
                            the fire, their virtue returns to them the more resplendent for the refining. Many of us,
                            however, stand and watch the smoke of our hay, wood and stubble, over which we have invested
                            so much careful planning in the vain hope of passing it as the genuine sacrifice. But, thank
                            God, we ourselves shall be saved, not a faculty is injured by the crucial test. God's mercy
                            permits us a new-born day, with the hope of life in its sunrise, and we may begin anew the
                            work of consecration, this time with the sweet, sad experience of the past to nerve us to
                            holier sacrifice. This is a blessed day to those who are studying the signs <pb n="120" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 120 THE MANIFESTO. of the times spiritually. While it records the obituary of
                            selfish hopes, man made creeds, earthly fears, and human calculations, it heralds the birth
                            of clearer insight into gospel truth, broader conceptions of God's dealings, and a
                            strengthening resolution to rise upon the "stepping-stones of our dead selves to higher
                            things." II. What is expected of the true Christian Church? That it shall be Christian in
                            the full sense of the word. Jesus said to Peter, in this connection, "Upon this rock
                            (revelation from the Father) I will build my church, and the gates of hell shall not prevail
                            against it." The Apostle refers to the "glorious church, not having spot, or wrinkle, or any
                            such thing." The Church of Christ is expected to teach, as did Jesus, the answer to the
                            universal question : "What shall I do that I may inherit eternal life ?" Spiritual life is
                            an obtainable possession, more real than the tangible surroundings of our earthly existence,
                            and the creed of the church, if creed there be, should be worded, the testimony outlined,
                            the ceremony guided, the socials conducted, the minister emboldened, the community
                            instructed, on lines bearing directly toward this power of God. III. How can this be
                            fulfilled? Only by a positive maintenance of the Pentecostal standard. Human methods may
                            vary, the principles of God are "from everlasting to everlasting." Plant the testimony of
                            Christ in the soil of honest hearts and its fruit-bearing is certain. Hide the leaven of
                            true Christianity in any community and its penetrating properties make themselves felt and
                            known. But"Beware of the leaven of the Pharisees which is hypocrisy." Wantedthe Church that
                            will meet this stirring call! Wantedthe ministry that will not reserve one jot or tittle of
                            God's searching truths! Wantedthey who will "hear the word and receive it, and bring forth
                            fruit, some thirty-fold, some sixty, and some an hundred.\ "He that hath an ear, let him
                            hear what the Spirit saith unto the churches." East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Experience" TEIform="index"/>EXPERIENCE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName"/>By Elder Abraham Perkins.</byline><p TEIform="p">rTIHE Lord is my Shepherd, I shall not want. From my early years he - -L has made me "to lie
                            down in green pastures," and led me "beside the still waters." In such a degree as light and
                            gospel travel have given growth hath "my soul been restored," and "in the path of
                            righteousness" have I been led. Yea, all the days of my life I have received the tender
                            mercies of the Lord, and for all these benefits my soul doth praise the Lord, and with all
                            my powers it is my delight to serve Thee. Yet, having thy continual blessing and care, thy
                            hand giving me strength to walk in justification, however great my blessing, I realize my
                            humanity, my inherited infirmities and weaknesses, consciously or unconsciously cultivated,
                            so clear has been my <pb n="121" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 121 vision, that egotism is
                            obliterated and positive knowledge has been both evoked and impelled, evincing the truth,
                            that the power of protection, spiritual baptism, salvation of soul and peace of mind are
                            gifts from above, not begotten of humanity, but from within, and only as we sacrifice self
                            for their possession do we obtain these gifts. From personal experience, and the reading of
                            my own book of life, I have learned that the possession of the Spirit and progress in the
                            paths of Wisdom I have attained has been wrought by Spirit influence, and as my mind
                            expanded and became capable of receiving increasing truths, they have not been withheld, but
                            kindly and graciously transmitted, thus gradually working salvation. Hence, the annihilation
                            of self, and the breaking down of pride, arrogance and worldly principles is the stern work
                            to be done by our individual efforts and labor, which alone are the means of victory. In my
                            soul, many, many times do I cry,Who then is to be redeemed ! Who, 0 Lord, is to abide in thy
                            tabernacle and dwell in thy holy hill? David, the psalmist, explicitly solves the problem
                            :"He that walketh uprightly and worketh righteousness , and speaketh truth in his heart: he
                            that backbiteth not with his tongue nor doeth evil to his neighbor, nor taketli up a
                            reproach against his neighbor. He that doeth these things shall never be moved."Psalms, xv.
                            East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Love" TEIform="index"/>LOVE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Gillett, E. B." TEIform="persName"/>By E. B. Gillett.</byline><p TEIform="p">Love, turns defeat to victory, And keeps the colors flying; And in the soldier's heart
                            re-lights The embers almost dying. Love turns the tide, and rifts the cloud, And cheers the
                            lonely sailor; And fills the sails with merry gales, And calms the stormy weather. Love
                            warms the cold, and cools the heat, . And makes a blessing of defeat; It turns the blackest
                            night to day, And leads us, in a wondrous way. Olive Branch, Fla.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nothing can long delight him..." TEIform="index"/>Nothing can long delight him...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Nothing can long delight him who delighteth not above all things in God.</p></div2><pb n="122" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. AUGUST, 1899. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is publisht by the "United
                            Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued regularly by
                            the Shakes Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the religious
                            views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. Address all communications
                            to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. One copy one year, postage paid. .50 A
                            cross in the margin will show that your subscription has closed. \ Remittances for
                            subscription by Money Order should be on the Post Office at Concord, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">June. Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. Thermometer. Rain. 1898. 68.33 5.265 in 1899.
                                69.84 3.375 " Highest Temp, during this mo. 90 above 0. Lowest " " " " 50 " Number of
                                rainy days " " 5 " clear " " " 9 " " cloudy" " " 16 July, 1899. June has been a month of
                                moods. The first half was very dry. There were frequent indications of rain, but for
                                more than three quarters of the month the rains parted, a portion going north, and the
                                remaining portion going south, leaving us only the lightning, thunder and drought. On
                                Saturday, the 24th inst. we had a variety storm which seemingly shook the heavens and
                                the earth. Lightning and thunder, rain and hail poured upon us in torrents without
                                respect for persons, and apparently for property. We had 1% inches of rain in a short
                                time, interblended with hail. The hail did no good and not much harm. The lightning shot
                                a bolt into a locust tree injuring it severely. This year we have taken 74 bu. of
                                asparagus from the bed. 33^2 bu. of strawberries have been gathered from ten rows.
                                Cherry picking at present engages the attention. Grass, a light crop, for want of a
                                suitable amount of rain. What has grown is being harvested. The new State Road is
                                receiving its coating of gravel. The health of our Community is generally good. A few of
                                us are somewhat drooping. Our Ministry leave on July 5, for Watervliet. Calvin G. Reed.
                                North Family. July, 1899. Haying, hoeing and cherry picking about cover our activities
                                this month. With regard to the first, owing to the nature of our soil, we have not
                                suffered much from drought and expect as soon as the present reverse of droughty weather
                                lets us, to get in a very fair crop both in quantity and quality. It is during this
                                month that a garden usually begins to look like a garden. We have suffered but little
                                from the lack of rain, and assisted by our friends things keep growing along nicely.
                                These friends are very willing to help, and one or the other draws the cultivator along:
                                in fact they are horses. Sour cherries, as usual, have been very abundant and we have
                                picked a good many bushels for sale, but of sweet ones we have had only enough for very
                                limited TERMS. <pb n="123" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 123 home use. Next year is their
                                year of plenty. Brother Daniel Offord, ever busy where pipes are concerned, has been
                                putting a new iron aqueduct into our saw-mill, the old one, in use many years being
                                leaky. While pouring some lead into a hole in a stone in which he intended to fasten a
                                bolt, the boiling liquid sputtered up into his face and splashed the glasses he was
                                wearing. Some water had got into the hole unknown to him. To say that we are thankful
                                that he was wearing those glasses is putting it rather feebly. As it is, he was somewhat
                                burnt, but what the consequences would have been if he had not had his spectacles on is
                                something we would rather not think about. Sufficient unto this particular day, most
                                certainly, was the good thereof. Frederic McKechnie. South Family. July, 1899.
                                Independence Day has come and gone, yet we are as independent and dependent as before.
                                The ever-glorious Fourth proved a fair day. The elements conspired to perfect perfect
                                weather. Fully appreciating the unseen efforts, a party from here, in company with our
                                nearest neighbors, the Second family, celebrated the Fourth at Queechy Lake, in the town
                                of Canaan. It is a beautiful, pacific lake, formed by nature and surrounded by pretty
                                groves, with pretty cottages and a pavilion where ramblers can hide should a tempest and
                                a storm arise. At 12 o'clock we were seated to a rich repast of the fruits of the
                                orchard and garden. Reading, singing with speech-making and mirth generally ruled the
                                dining hall of the rustic flag-draped shelter. Boat rowing and racing formed a merry
                                feature of the day. Elder Ernest Pick with his kodak took snap shots as we sailed away.
                                Sunday afternoon, the 9th inst., Eldress Anna, Sister Sarah and the writer enjoyed an
                                interesting conference with Elder Henry C. Blinn and inmates of the Office at the West
                                Pittsfield Society. We were soulfully glad to meet our dear editor and pleasingly
                                surprised to find him able to entertain us from his boundless source of useful
                                knowledge. We trust another summer will find him located among the Berkshire hills
                                enjoying frequent drives to our sunny hill-side home. By invitation of Eldress Caroline
                                we attended a musical reception given by the junior members of the family, and the sweet
                                singing by the seven happy songsters added new joy to the afternoon's pleasure. We will
                                long remember the singers. Returning to the Office we found our generous hostess, Sr.
                                Martha Johnson, and her ready helpers had prepared a sumptuous feast of the good things
                                of earth for our especial benefit, and we did it justice. Elder Ira Lawson is a splendid
                                host, possessing a host of goodness, making life sunny for all who come within the
                                radius of his liberal hospitality. The fair days find us on the mountaintop searching
                                for the blueberries. It is gay employment, for the ledges are blue with the luscious
                                fruit. Genevieve DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Alfred, Maine" TEIform="index"/>-Alfred., Me.</head><p TEIform="p">July, 1899. It has been some time since Alfred has been represented in Home Notes, but we
                                are still a little band of earnest workers in the Master's vineyard. July has brought
                                the much-needed rain, but we hope to have more before long. It is the driest season
                                known in this town by the oldest inhabitants. In consequence of the drought we shall
                                have very little fruit. The Brethren are busy haying. There will not be more than two
                                thirds as large a crop as last year. The family garden is looking well, notwithstanding
                                the lack of rain, thanks to Brother Frank Butler who has tended it faithfully. The
                                Sisters' workshop has been receiving a new coat of paint on the inside, and this
                                improves its appearance very much. <pb n="124" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 124 THE MANIFESTO. A few weeks
                                since we enjoyed a pleasant visit with Elder George Clark and the Sisters from Conn. We
                                wish these visits were of more frequent occurrence. On the 4th inst. the young people of
                                our village enjoyed a picnic in the woods, and although a heavy thunder storm in the
                                afternoon sent all within doors after a thorough drenching, yet the sun came out once
                                more and we spread tables out of doors and prepared supper which was a pleasant ending
                                of the day. We extend love and well wishes to all our Brethren and Sisters, far and
                                near. Our prayer is that peace and prosperity may bless every Zion home. Era M.
                            Ubbey.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">July, 1899. Our attention was especially attracted to the article in the July Manifesto
                                by Brother Joseph A. Wilson, and we were reminded of the saying of Emerson, "Beware,
                                when the great God lets loose a thinker." Something of importance must then take place;
                                but whether it will be for the weal or woe of the individual thinker or human society at
                                large will depend upon the source from whence is derived the thoughts that find
                                expression in words and acts. While it is true that there are some that have not the
                                mental energy to expend in extensive thought, the majority of human life in our American
                                Republic thinks enough, but the difficulty at present is to get them to train their
                                thoughts in the direction from which will emanate results beneficial to themselves in
                                the advancing of their ideal life, and as a result its outer manifestation, to a higher
                                plane consequently benefiting humanity. We are temperately optimistic and whatever
                                strengthens our hope in the ultimate destiny of human life brings a pleasure that the
                                external things of life can not take away; and to meet an individual thinker who draws
                                from that fountain of spiritual energy the thoughts that take form and expression as
                                they come from the crucible of their life is of incalculable benefit to one who is
                                reaching out with all the energies of his soul for the best that is attainable. The
                                drought that has prevailed in the eastern part of our country was felt here in
                                diminishing the hay crop and the small fruits. Strawberries especially felt it; some
                                fields in this section on the uplands were not worth picking. To read of the devastation
                                by flood in some sections of the west, we can not help questioning why are these forces
                                so unevenly distributed? We have many things to be thankful for, and out of all this
                                apparent confusion the Almighty arm will evolve harmony. In this hope we will place our
                                trust, working for a higher and more advanced life, Hamilton De.Graw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Union Village, Ohio" TEIform="index"/> Union Village, O.-</head><p TEIform="p">July, 1899. I feel a sincere sympathy for our dear Eastern friends on account of the
                                severe drought afflicting them. We suffered out west here, two consecutive years of very
                                severe drought, and doubtless it is more distressing in a mountainous and hilly region
                                than on level lands, but we hope rain will come in time to save and mature the crops.
                                Where are we to look for a living but from the earth and sky? Our year, so far, has been
                                peculiarly seasonable, and the crops have ripened up in excellent condition, of which
                                the small grain has mostly been cut and waiting the thresher, to complete the harvest.
                                Some sickness among us, but I am not disposed to dwell upon it, as I think we should
                                arise, and triumph over all physical ills as Jesus Christ did, and sooner or later we
                                shall surely reach perfection. The good Lord has it in store for us as soon as we are
                                ready for it, but a further sacrifice of our animal appetites will have to supervene
                                first, but "The glorious day is dawning, The day of full release, Even now it is the
                                morning, Of saving life and peace. <pb n="125" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 125 The train
                                is swiftly nearing, The headlights gleam afar, Of a sweet Evangel cheering, Death's
                                prisons to unbar." The revival of Christ's spiritual power in healing all known diseases
                                of body or soul is not very far distant, and the door will hardly shut between that
                                glorious time and the Millennium, so long looked and yearned for. We shall have a few
                                apples; our small fruits are remarkably plentiful this year. Corn never looked better in
                                this neighborhood and potatoes are very plentiful. Pears and plums very scarce this
                                year; the failure of the plums mostly owing to to the ravages of the Curculio. Last year
                                we had a very good crop which was all destroyed by this pest of the plum tree. We
                                sprayed the whole orchard three times over last year but it did not make the Curculio
                                one less, so we did not try it this year. Say! good eastern friends, what will destroy
                                the Curculio? If there is any such destructive agent, please let us hear of it in a Home
                                Note. O. C. Hampton.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">July, 1899. Our beloved friends who sojourned at our mountain home between the 21st and
                                27th ult. left us richer for the blessing they imparted. Eldress Ellen Green represented
                                our sister society at Harvard, Mass., while Elder George W. Clark and Sisters Angeline
                                Brown, Mariette Esty and Alice Braisted were from Enfield, Conn. Such happy seasons give
                                us a glimpse of the "hundred-fold" relation whice is destined to supplant the narrowness
                                of kinship. Will angel visits ever be other than "few and far between?" In this section,
                                at least, the drought is at an end. After two months of dry ness the tears of the skies
                                fell steadily for two days, as if touched by the parched wistfulness of the under world.
                                The repentance was eagerly accepted by the forgiving earth, and the cooling drops sank
                                gratefully to their work. Haying is in progress and an average yield reported for this
                                season. Our ancient Church, which has survived one hundred and seven summers, is now
                                receiving a much-needed coat of paint. Did it hear the Governor's call for "Old Home
                                Week," and is it preparing the gala dress for the occasion? However this may be, such
                                old settlers will not be away from home on the appointed date, and the thoughtful
                                painters will also be there in person as well as in grateful memory. The day School
                                closed for the summer holidays on the 12th inst. after a term of ten weeks. The closing
                                exercises gave proof that good effects follow good causes. Our beloved Elder Benjamin H.
                                Smith, while passing into one of the fruit gardens near home, was the subject of a
                                severe apoplectic stroke at about 11.15 a. m. on the 15th inst. He had experienced a
                                less severe attack while in the city of Concord one week previous. He was at once
                                tenderly removed to the Infirmary, where until 3 a. m. on the 20th he lay unconscious.
                                He rapidly neared the "streets of gold" and met the dear ones there. By a devoted
                                Christian life of sixty years, his passport was sure, yet the suddenness of the illness
                                gave us no time for the tender farewells which love would prefer. Jessie Evans.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Trust" TEIform="index"/>TRUST,</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Estabrook, Fidella" TEIform="persName"/>By Fidella Estabrook.</byline><p TEIform="p">Gob is with thee, why then falter, Is His arm not strong to bear, Does He not in every burden
                            Claim as His, the greater share? Can we ever doubt His promise Who has ever been our friend,
                            Who through countless ages calleth "I am with thee to the end." Every little bird that
                            twitters And each tiny fragrant flower, Proofs are giving of His goodness, Emblems of His
                            endless power, <pb n="126" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 126 THE MANIFESTO. Even sunbeams sparkling brightly
                            Messages of love now bring, Every voice of nature singeth "God is seen in everything." Then
                            we'll trust Him, trust Him ever, Through the day or darksome night Knowing that the way He
                            guideth Leadeth ever to the light. Souls who wait on Him in stillness, Simply trusting day
                            by day, Doing just the things He biddeth,- Following where He points the way, Find a rest in
                            gladly bearing Just whatever He may send, For His promise never faileth He our Comforter,
                            our Friend. When we're moulded to His likeness Then shall we be satisfied, From all
                            selfishness and sinning, By His spirit purified. We shall count the pain and struggle,
                            Blessings free, in mercy given, Stepping-stones from earth s dark shadows To the firm, blest
                            shores of heaven, And we'll thank the loving Father For each fear or heavy sorrow, Knowing
                            that its fruit is gladsome On the bright eternal morrow. Stars that twinkle in their
                            brightness In the fields of heaven, so blue. Only can be seen when darkness Yeils all other
                            lights from view. So sometimes our seeming pleasures, If removed, leave freer sight, For the
                            truths of God's great lessons In his promises so bright. Then just trust him, daily, hourly,
                            Trust him fully, never fear, List the echo sounds still nearer, "I am with thee, do not
                            fear." Greater blessing ne'er was given, Than this presence at our side, We can travel ever
                            safely, Hand in hand with Christ, our guide. Though the cross seems hard and heavy, Hear him
                            saying "Follow Me." He himself has borne the burden Up the heights of Calvary. Yea, he
                            knowsOh blessed solace, All our weakness, doubt and strife, And looks down in love and pity
                            On each sincere, humble life. Then forever praise and trust him, Leaving all things to his
                            will, He is faithful, failing never, His true promise to fulfill. Listen, he repeats it
                            sweetly, "I am thy Father, Savior, Friend, I'll not leave thee, nor forsake thee, I'll be
                            with thee to the end." West Pittsfield, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mellowing of character" TEIform="index"/>THE MELLOWING OF CHARACTER.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Buckham, James" TEIform="persName"/>By James Buckham.</byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> It takes time to ripen character. You can not force it any more than you can
                                    force the ripening of an apple. There must be a season of growth, and then a season
                                    of mellowing,first the soft spring and summer sun and dews and rain, then the dry
                                    autumn heat and the nights of frost. It is life, and life only, that ripens
                                    character; and it takes all of life to do it, too,the bitter and the sweet, the hard
                                    and the easy. Let us not be afraid, then to live, however intensely! The moral
                                    cowardthe man who is afraid of life, afraid of its depths and its heights, its
                                    valleys of humiliation and its peaks of vision, its significant experiences of
                                    whatever kindis incapable of developing character. All these are the ripening
                                    experiences of the soul. We must expect them, as the apple expects the noonday blaze
                                    and the midnight frost. It is childish to shrink from the intensities of life. Why
                                    do we live, if not to meet life's requirements and bear its fruits? It is always a
                                    sad thing to see a soul yielding and breaking under the stress of life; a soul that
                                    complains perpetually because it is afflicted; a soul that groans night and day
                                    beneath its burden; a soul that holds up despairing hands to God, and cries out that
                                    it is forspent and crusht to earth, and can strive no more. <pb n="127" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/>
                                    TJ IE MANIFES TO. 127 Souls are not made of such stuff as this. Souls are made to
                                    endure. Life's stress and strain are not to break them, but to strengthen them.
                                    There is not one of us who can not endure the discipline of life, no matter how
                                    hard, if he understands what it is for and seeks the divine aid in bearing it. It is
                                    simply because we so often misinterpret the meaning of trial that we are so weak to
                                    bear it. Looked upon as mere aimless torment, of course there is no grace in
                                    suffering. No wonder we sink beneath the burden if we fail to see the hand that
                                    placed it, and feel only, as we think, the grievous, purposeless weight crushing us
                                    to earth. Everything depends upon the why,the why of pain, the why of struggle, the
                                    why of weeping. If we could see, day by day, the mellowing process going on in our
                                    souls, how differently we should feel about these intense experiences of life! But
                                    so many of us seem to have no conception of the real meaning of life. These vital
                                    experiences that are meant to cut our souls so clear and fine, like the delicate
                                    tools of the sculptor, are to vis but sharp misfortune. We would fain escape them;
                                    they hurt us, and we hate them. Ah! what a sad misinterpretation of the will and
                                    purpose of our heavenly Father! We say he is hurting us, and that is all the meaning
                                    we get out of the marvellous process of soul refining. Bravery, moral bravery,
                                    courage under the stress of life,how sorely we all need it! Our childishness clings
                                    to us too long with its shrinking from all that is hard and unpleasant; its
                                    petulance, its shortsightedness, its complaining. When we become men and women, are
                                    we not to put away childish things? Let us try to understand, let us try to bear,
                                    let us try to co-operate! Note the sweetness and richness and beauty of those
                                    characters that have always resigned themselves cheerfully and trustingly to God's
                                    will, and have gone on mellowing and perfecting in holiness unto the end. Such souls
                                    afford some adequate explanation of what life means, or may mean to a true jhild of
                                    God. They are revelations of ourselves to ourselves: for the image inco whose
                                    likeness they have grown is a possible ideal to every one of us.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Christian Register" TEIform="index"/>From he Christian Register.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My enemy" TEIform="index"/>MY ENEMY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hall, Eliza Calvert" TEIform="persName"/>By Eliza Calvert Hall.</byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> I have an enemy. And shall he be A useless thorn to vex and worry me? A dominant
                                    discord in life's perfect strain, Marring my dreams, turning my joy to pain, Molding
                                    my life to his malicious whim? Shall he be lord of me, or I of him? A bitter stream
                                    may turn the mill wheel round A thorny tree may burn to heat and light; And out of
                                    shameful wrong may spring the flower Of perfect right. So from my enemy I may demand
                                    A priceless tribute of perpetual good; And lead him captive at my chariot wheels, In
                                    royal mood. Because my enemy hath cunning ears, That listen hourly for my idle
                                    speech, My words shall flow in wise and measured way Beyond his carping reach.
                                    Because my enemy has eyes that watch With sleepless malice while I come and go, My
                                    days shall own no act I would not wish The world to know. Because my enemy doth
                                    hourly wield Some subtle snare to trip me every day, My feet shall never for one
                                    moment leave The straight and narrow way. Because my enemy doth hate me sore, I fix
                                    my gaze beyond him and above, And lift, as shield to all his fiery darts, A heart of
                                    love. And of my enemy I thus shall make A beacon light, to light me to my goal A
                                    faithful guardian of my house of life A spur and whip to urge my laggard soul; And
                                    though our strife may never have an end I yet might call this enemy, my friend.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Independent" TEIform="index"/>The Independent.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The primal duties shine aloft like stars..." TEIform="index"/>The primal duties shine aloft like stars...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The primal duties shine aloft like stars; the charities that soothe and heal and bless are
                            scattered at the feet of man like flowers.</p></div2><pb n="128" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bible Class" TEIform="index"/>From the Bible Class.</head><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kind shepherd" TEIform="index"/> THE KIND SHEPHERD.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Crook, Hattie" TEIform="persName"/>By Hattie Crook.</byline><p TEIform="p">In the Bible we are given the story of the lost sheep, where it strayed away from the
                                fold, and when the master went out to feed his flock he found one missing. Then he left
                                the ninety and nine and searched and called, until he found it, and then he took it home
                                with him. This shows us that Jesus was kind to everybody even to dumb animals. The
                                lesson to be derived from it to me is, that the kind shepherd looking for his one lost
                                sheep amid night and storm, is a sign that God will not lose his care and tenderness for
                                us when we wander away from Him. In our thoughts and ways we often wander away from this
                                good spirit and like the sheep we stray from the fold of Christ, When the Christ spirit
                                calls us we often do not hear, and if we do it is only to wander deeper and deeper into
                                the jungles of sin and selfishness. We at last want the comfort and rest found only in
                                this heavenly fold, but where shall we find our rest and comfort? None but the good
                                Shepherd who has searched our hearts for the first repentant thought can at last lead us
                                home. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Abutilon" TEIform="index"/>THE ABUTILON.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>By Martha J. Anderson.</byline><p TEIform="p">Hail, queen of the bells, the fairy bells, Whose bloom gives such delight, Thro' the
                                summer days and wintry haze, And the close veiled hours of night. Thy chalices deep are
                                filled with gold And crown each towering stem, Where emerald leaves rich tracery weaves
                                Around thy diadem. Thy clustering buds each day increase, And blossoms fair unroll, Then
                                withering fall to earth's dark pall Robbed of the flower-soul. Oh, the blushing rose and
                                lily white May all our senses please, Their odorous breath they yield in death To the
                                passing summer breeze. Not so with the bright Abutilon, When its flowers lose their hue,
                                At their base is seen in the calyx green Clear drops of honey dew. Oh, lesson new for my
                                heart to learn, 'Tis the secret of God's grace, Some sweet surprise life underlies
                                Though we fill the humblest place. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If you want to be loved" TEIform="index"/>IP YOU WANT TO BE LOVED,</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> Don't contradict people even if you're sure you are right. Don't be
                                        inquisitive about the affairs of even your most intimate friend. Don't underrate
                                        anything because you don't possess it. Don't believe that everybody else in the
                                        world is happier than you. Don't repeat gossip, even if it does interest a
                                        crowd. Don't go untidy on the plea that everybody knows you. Don't express a
                                        positive opinion unless you perfectly understand what you are talking about.
                                        Don't get in the habit of vulgarizing life by making light of the sentiment of
                                        it. Don't scoff at anybody's religious belief. Don't try to be anything else but
                                        a gentleman or a gentlewomanand that means one who has consideration for the
                                        whole world and whose life is governed by the Golden Rule. "Do unto others as
                                        you would be done by."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Ladies' Home Journal" TEIform="index"/>Ladies'1 Home Journal.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Smith, Benjamin H." TEIform="index"/>Elder Benjamin H. Smith
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Elder Benjamin H. Smith, at East Canterbury, N. H. July 20, 1899. Age 70 years 4 mo. and
                                10 days.</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p19"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
POPULAR SCIENCE
Nature, Invention,
M CIS/PArchaeology, Electricity 11 CjM TM
IILHuChemistry, Mineralogy, ULlKL I II
Health, Hygiene, Medicine.
Formerly  Boston   Journal  of Chemistry
ENLARGEDund IMPROVED.
This popular monthly contains a large num.
ber of Short, Easy. Practical, Interesting and
Popular, Scientific articles, that can be Appreciated and Enjoyed by any intelligent reader,
even though he knew little or nothing of Science. It is intended to interest those who think
Profusely illustrated and Free
from Technicalities
Entirely Different from and much superior to
other papers with a similar name.
Monthly,   SI.60 per year.    Newsdealers,   15   cts.
Largest Circulation ofany
Scientific Paper.
LILLAED & CO.,
108 Fulton St., New York.
xJSg-Jilentton this paper for a sample copy
Eldresses
Dorothy A, Durgin,
Joanna J, Kaime,
The book contains photographs of the
Sisters, and also a short biographical
sketch.    A notice of the Memorial Service
including several pieces of music.      Manyletters of sympathy from  friends  not of
the Community.
A copy of the book may be obtained by
addressing Hart & Shepard,
East Canterbury, N. H.
Price, Cloth, 75 cts.    Boards 50 cts.
WITHOUT   DOUBT
THE BEST FAMILY PAPER PUBLISHED
IS   THE
NEW   YORE   WEEKLY   WITNESS.
16 Pages.   Only   $1 a year.
Has a very wide scope, comprising as it
does the following departments:
Editorials,
Spirit of the Press,
Scientific and Instructive,
Tli** iitid and Uncommon,
Our Country's Hope,
Foreign News,
A Talk Witli the Doctor,
Around the Hearth,
little Men and Women,
"Weekly Articles by George R. Scott
fainiiis'''s Sermon,
Money and Business,
World-Wide Field,
Our Family Story,
Farm and Garden,
Market Reports,
16 Pages.   Only 50 cents a Year.
An Inter-denominational Weekly Paper.
Sabbath Reading is solely religious.
No news; no politics. A grand paper
for the truth-seeker.    It contains:
Editorial.
Christian Endeavor Topic,
Epworth League Topic,
Sabbath-School Lesson,
Choice Poetry,
Good Sories,
Reports of Mis&ions,
Mothers' Sabbath Afternoon
With the Children,
And a mass of matter carefully selected.
Send for free sample copies of Witness
and Sabbath Reading. And send for
free sample pages of our Bagster's Bible.
Address
J0HNDOUaALL& CO., 150 Nassau Street, New York.
IN    MEMORIAM
SABBATH    READING
<pb n="" id="p20"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
Royal
BAKING
Powder
Absolutely FREE
Makes the food more delicious and wholesome
ROYAL BAKING POWDER CO., NEW YORK.
50   YEARS'
EXPERIENCE
SHAKER HAMAMELIS
(WITCHHAZEL,)
A. remedy for Cuts, Burns, Scalds,
Headache, Sore Throat and all
cases of external inflammation
Taken internally for Bowel
Complaint, Bleeding of the
Lungs or Bowels, and for
all aches and pains.
For use externally, bathe the parts and
lay on a cloth wet with the Extract.    Internally, take one half teaspoonful three
times a day.    Use hot or cold.
Ask your druggist for it or send your
order to Abthur Bruce,
East Canterbury, N. H.
Trade Marks
Designs
copyrsghts &c.
Anyone sending a sketch and description may
quickly ascertain our opinion free whether an
invention is probably patentable. Communications strictly confidential. Handbook on Patents
sent free. Oldest agency for securing patents.
Patents taken through Munn & Co. receive
special notice, without charge, in the
Scientific fltneiiQfi.
A handsomely illustrated weekly. Largest circulation of any scientific journal. Terms, $3 a
year; four months, $1. Sold by all newsdealers.
MUNN &Co.36iBroadwa"'New York
Branch Office, 625 F St., Washington, D. C.
HOW TO MAKE MONEY!
If you are out of employment and want
a position paying you from $50 to $100
monthly clear above expenses by working
regularly, or, if you want to increase your
present income from $200 to $500 yearly,
by working at odd times write the GLOBE
CO. 723 Chestnut St. Phila., Pa. stating
age, whether married or single, last or
present employment, and you can learn
how to make more money easier and
faster than you ever made before in your
life.
AUTHORISED   RULES
OF
THE   SHAKER   COMMUNITY,
The religious basis of the Order must
be a foundation resting on the principle of
righteousness, which principle is God.
This should rule the life of the individual for the protection of his own soul, for
the peace of the family and as an evidence
of his upright standing before the world.
Price, 10 cts.
HAVE YOU ''COMMON SENSE?"
If not, send at once for a free copy of this
liberal-minded  advocate of advanced
thought, which brings health and
success.    Address
"Common Sense," M. O. 55 State St.
Chicago, 111.
The exponent of West Gate Philosophy.
A. new occult system-An unlimited field of labor open to teachers, lecturers
and healers.   Address,
The ORACLE, Sta. A.    Boston, Mass.
to advanced thought peoplesample copy of the mosi original and
practical occult journal of the age.
FREE
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>