<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ss0406" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">Shaker and Shakeress</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Society</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Mount Lebanon, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">4</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">6</biblScope><date value="18740601" TEIform="date">June 1874</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">41-48</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="4" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="41" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="6" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!-- <p>Vol. IV. No. 6. PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETY. F. W. EVANS, ' ^^ ^ -,^~^ EmTOIl Mt. Lebanon, Col. Co. N. Y. June,
                        1874. Fifty Cents PER ANNUM</p>
                    --><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kingdom of Heaven" TEIform="index"/>KINGDOM OF HEAVEN</head><p TEIform="p">The Kingdom of Heaven is like a man, who, out of his treasures, bringeth forth things new and
                            old. Very good. If correct, that kingdom is a system of constantly unfolding truth. Also,
                            under the figure of a harvest of the world, we conceive the grand idea of a time when human
                            organization, in its ultimate, should conserve the truths of all previous epochs and
                            dispensations. Dividing our immediate spiritual history, according to our religious records,
                            into two parts, first, the history of the Jewish race, or people, second, that of the
                            Gentiles; we have this map before us. The spiritual seed time was in the days of Abraham,
                            Isaac, Jacob and his twelve sons. The spiritual harvest of that Jewish race, was in the days
                            of Jesus, his twelve disciples and the Pentecostal Church, with its community of goods, and
                            the resurrection of its members, up and out of the individual and family relation that
                            Abraham, Isaac and Jacob founded; as the basis of the twelve tribes of Jews, comprising the
                            House of Israel. The intervening history, between Abraham, with the twelve sons of Jacob;
                            and Jesus, with the twelve apostle3, is simply the growth of the grain, from the sowing to
                            the reaping. The progress of the Jewish Nation, was from the individual, to the husband and
                            wife —¦ with their property possessions —• gradually increasing into a private family; and
                            that family swelling into a Tribe, and the twelve Tribes uniting into a Nation. Unto that
                            Nation the Christ Spirit came, as a Savior, to bring that world to an end. Henceforth, that
                            which God Himself had planted and sowed — the generating family relation, with its selfish
                            property — its individual life—-was ruthlessly plucked up. And, that which God had builded —
                            a people, who should dwell alone, and not be numbered with the nations — was unsparingly
                            pulled down. And the whole race of Jews became as a handful of corn, in the top of the moun-
                            tains ; to be scattered, as a spiritual seed, among the gentile nations of the earth, as is
                            recorded, ; In thee, and in thy seed, shall all the nations of the earth be blessed." That
                            Order, of resurrected Jews — Jesus, the twelve disciples and Pentecostal community, which
                            the Christ Spirit had thus harvested from the world; was, itself, also translated — cut off
                            from the earth —in about three hundred years. The Holy City — Religious community—was
                            trodden under foot of the Gentiles — the Roman people. Their ensign — the dragon — devoured
                            it by persecution; and it was caught up to the spirit world, where it exists to this present
                            time, a source of prophecy, from which the Kingdom of Heaven will draw old things — Jewish
                            truths — that will revolutionize its agriculture, its physiology, its dietetics, and its
                            community business relations, until all that is worldly and Gentile, all that offends, is,
                            in all respects, abolished and purged out of the Kingdom. Happy day ! Glorious anticipation
                            !! Heavenly light, to enlighten the Gentiles!!! We have beheld the harvest of the Jewish
                            nation, Christ incarnated in a Jewish man, a representative of the Eastern, or masculine
                            part of the earth — Christ, in their first manifestation. We have seen the power of the holy
                            people scattered, the seed sown among the Gentiles, the Gospel of the Kingdom preached to
                            all nations, living in perverted generation, perverted property relations, and in perverted
                            nutrition: and then the end came, and the Christ Spirit was incarnated in a Gentile Woman,
                            as a representative of the Western, or feminine part of the earth. A second Pentecostal
                            Community has been formed ; and is now, in its several branches, nearly an hundred years
                            old. " What hath God wrought ?" The history, twelve hundred and sixty years, of Gentile
                            Christianity. Regeneration taught, and Generation practiced. Peace taught, and war
                            universal. Forsaking all, laying all at the feet of Jesus, preached; keeping all they have,
                            and getting gain without right, from all whom they can circumvent, the rule of Priest and
                            People. This is confusion, worse confounded. But the peaceful Kingdom of the Branch, that
                            has grown up out of Jesus, and out of the root of the stem of Jesse, is a refuge — a home
                            for the Gentile — and his rest is glorious.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Language" TEIform="index"/>LANGUAGE</head><p TEIform="p">We are pleasantly bearing in mind the voice of the Prophet, calling our attention to the
                            beautiful future, when God shall return, to his people, a pure language — Zeph.-III-9. With
                            what joy we anticipate that heavenly blessing — an Angel visitation of deeper spirituality —
                            " when the time of refreshing shall come from the presence of the Lord." Indeed, they who
                            have already tasted the good word of God, are even now, speaking to us in a language,
                            understood only as we enter the resurrection order, and accept the life of Christ as our
                            heavenly guide. We would ask, in prayer, its adoption, by all who turn their faces toward
                            the City of Peace. It is recorded, that illuminated minds, in the Pentecostal Church, spake
                            with tongues of fire that came down from Heaven. Should not those who have recently entered
                            the Pentecostal Church, of the present day, seek to be inspired by the same consuming
                            element, and by a baptism of speech from the same elevated sphere ? Why should we retain the
                            language of the children of this world ? Why should we accept it, knowing, as we do, that
                            its corrupting influence awakens only shame and contempt ? A reference to this subject seems
                            highly necessary at this time, when there is so much license given to gross improprieties of
                            speech, designated as " slang phrases." Added to this is the list of idle words, unkind
                            words, vain words, silly words, angry words, revengeful words, that, in the world, are used,
                            without regard to place or persons. This recklessness of language, like the plagues of
                            Egypt, threatens to deluge the land. Would writers and speakers occupy the same time in
                            speaking truthfully and affectionately, what immeasurable blessings would be the result. Our
                            home, our beautiful gospel home, consecrated to God, should never be contaminated with the
                            virus of the carnal mind, this blighting sin of the world. Were these objectionable features
                            confined to the society of the vulgar and abandoned, whom we are obliged to meet in every
                            city, town and village, it might seem to bear a cor- respondence to their lives. But we find
                            them accepted and used, by those who stand as teachers in society. Oftimes, the man, who
                            shudders to hear the voice of the blasphemer, does not hesitate to intersperse his
                            conversation with slang, or licentious phrases. He, who uses the first form of speech, if
                            heard, expects to be condemned; while one, who pours this undercurrent of filthiness into
                            the minds of hearers, looks up to be approved. Upon all deviations from strict propriety
                            —from moral rectitude — the disciples of Jesus Christ and Mother Ann should let their light
                            shine, in serious protestation. Moses — in Leviticus, chapter V — taught his brethern, that
                            if they even heard the voice of swearing, and did not report the case to the minister at the
                            altar, they should stand equally guilty with the transgressor, and should bear the iniquity.
                            Are we not equally negligent, if we fail to walk as carefully as did the children of Israel
                            ? And in any wise not reprove our neighbor, suffering sin upon him, lest unpleasant lessons
                            be impressed upon the minds of the young — lessons which may not become obliterated while in
                            the journey through life. Should one be so careless as to mutilate a sentence, by the
                            introduction of a profane, or vulgar word, it is certainly fastening a bad habit, one which
                            may ultimately lead to serious consequences. It is equally as improper to force vulgar
                            expressions upon hearers, or readers, as it is to oblige them to inhale expired breath.
                            Ironical expressions are censurable and in many cases no better than falsehoods. Speak,
                            carefully and distinctly, words worthy to be repeated, and we are safe in saying, there will
                            be but few expressions of which to repent. Be as the Lord's servants, advocates of that pure
                            language, which should have the first place among the followers of the Christ Spirit — the
                            children of the Resurrection.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>Eld. Henry C. Blinn, Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div2><pb n="42" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Theological treasury" TEIform="index"/>THEOLOGICAL TREASURY</head><p TEIform="p">Confession—Repentance. Among the instructions given to the earlyChristians, none were more
                            essential than that they should confess, and forsake their sins. This should not be
                            overlooked by honest seekers after truth. To those who feel that they are whole, this
                            medicine of the good physician is very distasteful, even to abhorrence; while such as have
                            been trained in popular sectarian channels, will pronounce the confessional a supporter of a
                            spiritual inquisition — a relic of barbarism. Be confession a Roman Sacrament, or not, is
                            quite immaterial. Confession is a Christian dispensation, nevertheless ; and is, after
                            conviction, the first step in Christian progress. We honor the Roman Church for retaining,
                            even though imperfectly, this Godly ordinance. And while Protestants sneer at such
                            humiliating procedure as the confession of sin, we would that God in his mercy, inaugurate
                            something equally effective for the condemnation of sin, in Protestant Churches, the world
                            over. True, these latter churches have protested against the wrong-doings of their Mother;
                            and so zealous have they been in their protests, that the vices and virtues of the Mother
                            have shared the common fate of denunciation by the Daughters; while the latter are wanting
                            in some of her redeeming features. The Confessional was a Jewish establishment. John Baptist
                            was a confessor. Among multitudes of Jews, who came to be baptised of John, in Jordan, was
                            one Jestjs ; and as John baptised them — they confessing their sins — Jesus passed the same
                            ordeal, with other Jews. As a good Jew, he had accustomed himself to do this, once a year.
                            If Jesus, as Christian, was tempted in all points, yet without sin ; there is wanting
                            evidence that he failed to fulfill his Jewish obligations in the confession of his
                            physiological, or Jewish sins. Jesus taught his followers to confess, and repent of their
                            sins. Did Jesus err, under either Jewish or Christian government, he confessed and repented
                            of the same. Protestant Clergymen are realizing the fact, that some of the blackest crimes,
                            commonly committed by their flocks, are almost unknown in Catholic folds. Some of them are
                            noble enough to make public this admission, and attribute the greater protection to the
                            Confessional. It is interesting, though not positively necessary, to allude to the
                            consternation in Thos. K. Beecher's Church, when he recommended the practice of confession,
                            as making a man feel nobler, by going to some confidential friend and confessing the wrongs
                            of his heart. Confession of wrong is not only a reasonable requirement, but through this
                            door of hope— the valley of Achor — individuals are enabled to pass to the higher condition
                            of life — repentance — the forsaking of sins confessed. But confession may be made a mere
                            churchal formality, which, without the necessary accompanying repentance, is like faith
                            without works — dead. To souls burdened with Pilgrim's bundle of sins — with the knowledge
                            that God requires confession to Him, witnessed by the most confidential friend, ere
                            absolution can be obtained — confession becomes a balm for all their woes; while repentance
                            reinstates them in justification. Confession was demanded in Hebrew times, but was not
                            followed by Christian mercy. In Joshua's address to Achan, we have clear defi- nition of
                            rational Jewish confession — " My son, make confession unto God, and tell me what thou hast
                            done. Hide not from me." Confession is made to God — narration to the Elder. " Whoso
                            covereth — hideth — his sins shall not prosper." He that confesseth and forsaketh shall have
                            mercy." Coming down to Apostolic times, we are counseled to confess oar faults, one to
                            another : " If we confess our sins, and forsake them, He is just to forgive our sins, and
                            cleanse us from all unrighteousness." " They that believed, came and confessed and showed
                            their deeds." Under the baptism of the Pentecostal spirit the same fruits will be manifest.
                            As a legal document, void of signature, so are the Nations and Sects who forget God by
                            denying auricular confession. Mother Ann Lee's testimony revived the form and spirit of oral
                            confession. As Jesus confessed to John, so did Ann confess to Jane Wardley. Thus Ann became
                            the Mother of a New Order— a New Creation—wherein should be confession of sin — Males to
                            Males — Females to Females — and wherein, as a consequence, should dwell exceeding
                            righteousness. Said Mother Ann — "I love the day I first received the Gospel — I call it my
                            birthday — I felt such a sense of my sins, that I was willing to confess them before the
                            whole world. I confessed my sins to my Elders, one by one, and repented of them in the same
                            manner. When my Elders reproved me, I felt determined not to be reproved twice for the same
                            thing, but to overcome the evil for myself." Many were Mother's counsels concerning the
                            definiteness of honest confession. The same testimony is maintained by her followers ; and
                            their growth and spiritual prosperity are commensurate with their punctuality to the order
                            of confession, and renunciation of their sins. Some one asked Mother — " What is repent-
                            ance ? " Mother instantly replied — " Leaving, forever, the sins we have confessed." This,
                            as an accompaniment to the definition of Truth, by Jesus, can hardly be excelled. To those
                            who would experience thorough and eternal abandonment of error—who would have their sins go
                            beforehand to judgment, and not follow after them to condemnation — we advise honest
                            confession to God, and the narration to some bosom, or confidential friend. And let him, or
                            her, understand that confession and repentance are the door to Shaker homes and heavens. To
                            the sin-sick and heavy laden, the invitation is," Seek and ye shall find — Knock and it
                            shall be opened unto you."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/>Elder G. A. Lomas, Watervliet, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Scattering chips" TEIform="index"/>SCATTERING CHIPS</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Peebles, J. M." TEIform="persName"/>J. M. Peebles</byline><p TEIform="p">It was a beautiful inspiration that led the apostle to write " Not as though I had already
                            attained, either were absolutely perfect." (Phil, iii, 12.) So long as there is a
                            consciousness of imperfection — so long as there is a willingness to confess — to forsake —
                            and try again to " overcome ;" there is hope — yea, certainty of a harvested soul. There is
                            a marked distinction between Spiritism and Spiritualism. The first is a mere science — the
                            demonstration of a future existence ! But Spiritualism in its broadest, divinest sense,
                            spans every thing that is spiritual and holy. " God is a Spirit "— and to be "
                            spiritually-minded is life." Those only are spiritualists who believe in the ministry of
                            angels and spirits, and make that belief not a philosophy only but a religion, a practical
                            power in their lives. The fruit reveals the tree. Though there are " many mansions " in our
                            Father and Mother's house — one door only leads into them — and that door is purity. The
                            pure in heart alone have the promise of seeing God. Our good Quaker poet John G. Whittier is
                            a celibate — a " virgin unto the Lord." That glorious picture-gallery of apostles, martyrs,
                            celibates, that crown with gold the pages of history, is reflected and made immortal upon
                            the jasper walls of the New Jerusalem. " Resist temptation," is a rational biblical command.
                            Though the thread of magnetic sympathy, which the enchantress winds around her victim, is
                            unseen, it often binds the individual so firmly that escape is next to impossible. Mind must
                            govern the physical — soul conquer sense. " I keep my body under," writes the apostle, " and
                            bring it into subjection, lest by any means, when I have preached to others, I myself should
                            be a castaway." It is not philosophical to say — " man has a spirit" — but rather, man is a
                            spirit; and the " death-rattle " is the angel-signal for moving out, and up into the better
                            mansion of immortality. Melchesidec, over the purple of the priesthood, was an individual
                            baptized of Christ. Abraham recognized this at once : " Wherever a real saint has lived, and
                            worshiped, wherever a great seer has appeared, walking thousands of years before his time,
                            and lifting the soul of generations into a higher civilization, there is an element of
                            historic authority for Spiritualism. Spiritual philosophy is the living science of all time.
                            Its priests are such souls as Pythagoras, Socrates and Plato ; Jesus, Swedenborg, and Ann
                            Lee; * Copernicus. Kepler, Galileo, and Newton; Leibnitz, Descartes, and Laplace. These have
                            been the ministers of an ever-advancing religion, whose ideas and discoveries have given
                            names to certain epochs of thought. Members and chiefs in God's infinite spiritual republic
                            are they, from whose souls whole civilizations have sprung. The historical authority behind
                            Spiritualism is equal to that behind all the thou- sand and one theological sects of the
                            whole world." Modern Spiritualism is having much to do in the politics of the French nation.
                            A late London Daily has this : " M. Thiers a Spiritualist.— The Paris correspondent of the
                            Echo of Aug. 28 says: —"M. de Lavedan, the Prefect of the Department of the Vienne,
                            furnishes us with the following authentic details: —A few weeks ago M. Thiers did me the
                            honor to inform me that he was occupied with a special work, independent of his other
                            labors. ' I should be glad,' he exclaimed in atone of noble indignation, 'to confound
                            materialism, which is a folly as well as a peril. There is a fine .book to be made on this
                            subject, and I have as yet only written the half of it. Certainly I devote myself with my
                            whole heart to the liberation of the territory and the reorganization of the country, but at
                            times I cannot help regretting my peaceable and cherished studies. For twelve years I have
                            been engaged in this work; during all that time I have been explor- ing botany, chemistry,
                            and natural history for arguments against the detestable doctrine which leads honest people
                            astray. I am a Spiritualist, an impassioned one; and I am anxious, I repeat, to confound
                            materialism in the name of science and good sense." As death is no savior, and as there are
                            spirits mischievous, erring and fallible, John wisely said—" Beloved believe not every
                            spirit but try the spirits." Try them how ? by our judgment and the reasoning faculties that
                            God has given us. " Men shall judge angels." * Jesus and Ann, through a Christ baptism, were
                            annointed Mediators of a New Covenant.</p></div2><pb n="43" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Answer to a letter from an outside friend..." TEIform="index"/>Answer to a letter from an
                                outside friend, who states that our best public men are dropping off tlie stage — that
                                plundering the public by corrupt officials exceeds any thing ever experienced by the
                                citizens of this Republic — that huge rascalities are coming to light every week; and
                                that dull times prevail.</head><p TEIform="p">Respected Friend: The public officials of to-day demonstrate that human nature (the lower
                                nature in man) is the same now as in the past. Office holders in this country imitate,
                                as far as they can, their cousins in England. There is Earl Derby, he is in office, and
                                paid out of the public purse to sustain an order of things which enables him and his
                                compeers to take the cream off the industries of the nation, every day. These men have
                                been so long at such kind of work, that they have organized their robberies into order
                                and respectability. In this country, stealing and lying about it, go on bravely; but are
                                not yet respectable. Tweed is in the penitentiary. Now if we could contrive to send
                                these dukes to the penitentiary too, how pleased I should be. I would not have anybody
                                be at the trouble of keeping them in doors, in a costly building, and bringing victuals
                                to them. I would leave them out doors on a ten acre farm. And seeing every- body desires
                                to be Duke or Duchess, I would send them, to a ten acre penitentiary too. All being
                                engaged to get a living, the Duke would not be able to coax anybody to work for him.
                                Hence, he would have to dig his own drains, and grub out the scrubs for himself. And the
                                Duchess might enjoy the poetic duty of milking her own cow, and stand a chance of being
                                kicked over as well as anybody else. As regards the legislative wisdom in council
                                assembled in Christian nations (so called), I am down on the whole of it. I would have
                                no such gatherings; everlastingly doing something that does not and ought not to stay
                                put. They breed corruption. Let every man stay at home, save mileage, and do the voting
                                and talking by mail. Why not ? As far as personal behavior and public honesty are
                                involved, the assembled legislative wisdom of Christendom is rather rude, windy withal,
                                and rather devilish I venture to say, that the monkeys in the woods manage their affairs
                                with more dignity than do our male Solomons. At all events, they never confound their
                                own confusion, by creating panics that last more than an hour or two, and that cannot be
                                healed over by a good night's rest in the trees. In the morning the monkey is right side
                                up ; no soup kitchen in the midst of plenty ; no sending of their food out of their
                                country (as in India) during a famine. Carlyle thinks, that a hundred years ago, matters
                                in England were in a better condition than they now are. A London editor shows up the
                                state of things about that time. Going back on the record does not improve the aspect.
                                Some think there is more good on the earth now than at any former period. The
                                indications are, that justice between nations and individuals will increase. But I have
                                not time to wait till the animal emotional man has brought forth a civilization bearing
                                only good fruit. A civilization based on divine human emotions is my choice. The result
                                is, I am where peace, and something more than justice is the rule—-where dull times
                                never come ; and where obedience to Hygienic Law will triumph over hereditary taints,
                                and induced disease ; and where the power of sinless life " will finish transgression,
                                put an end to sin, and bring in everlasting righteousness "— a new creation. In the land
                                of souls, states and conditions — the growth of our past lives— will be to us, as the
                                case may be, heaven or hell. To heighten the joys of the former, by loving the neighbor
                                at the expense of self; and to utterly extinguish the latter, by an application of the
                                same Law, will be the employ of every good spirit. To " Speak peace where discord
                                reigns, Appease the flood; And for revenge, Persist in doing good."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Frazer, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Frazer, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nature and revelation" TEIform="index"/>NATURE AND REVELATION</head><p TEIform="p">It is related that the first Ambassadors of the English Government to the king of Siam, told
                            him many strange things concerning their country, and among the rest, that the water of
                            their rivers sometimes became so congealed by cold, that his elephants could walk upon their
                            surface. To this he replied, that they had previously told him many things hard to believe,
                            but now he knew they lied and he did not believe the rest of their stories. Did disbelief
                            alter the facts, or prove any thing but the king's ignorance? Does the assertion that it is
                            impossible for all mankind, in the final event, to become Christians or Shakers, either in
                            this or the next world, have any better foundation than did the disbelief of the king ? Is
                            it not assuming to know more than God has given nature wisdom to teach ? Is not the argument
                            upon that side confined to negations, like those of the materialist, who disputes beyond the
                            test of his physical senses ? Who, without the previous knowledge of the metamorphose, would
                            prophesy a moth from a caterpillar, or even believe the change possible, without witnessing
                            the fact? Who, without any previous knowledge of eggs, could tell, the first time they saw
                            one, what it would produce under suitable conditions? Is not man frequently discovering new
                            developments of facts, for which his previous experience affords no satisfactory clue to an
                            explanation ? What does man know of the latent powers and faculties engermed in his own
                            being, awaiting proper seasons and conditions to call them into activity and growth ? What
                            can he know of what will be his state, after putting off the mortal form, except by
                            revelation of a wisdom superior to any yet found in material nature, or by the physical
                            senses ? And that Revealing Spirit which has proved itself superior to all the reasons and
                            philosophy of man, by its power to control the destinies of nations, and direct the kingdom
                            of the world, claims to emanate from the Creator, which none can dispute, while man's
                            greatest wisdom is unable to scan the mystery of his own being — or to certainly ascertain
                            whence, or why, he came, or whither he is going. Should not these plain facts teach us
                            humility and dependence upon a wisdom and love superior to our own ? " Come now, and let us
                            reason together, saith the Lord." When man approaches the subject of Deity, as a learner,
                            and investigates his religious and spiritual nature by the light of Divine revelation, with
                            the same care and diligence that he now investigates material nature and science, being
                            careful to reduce his light to practice as fast as he obtains it, he will cease to obstruct
                            the avenues of spiritual and religious knowledge by hastily deciding the truth or falsity of
                            that which he does not comprehend. When he enters the realm to interrogate, consider and
                            practice, his advance in true religious knowledge will be as rapid and marvelous, as has
                            been his advance in science and useful art since he exchanged theorizing for the inductive
                            methods. But man is born in a natural state which was designed to be a preparation for the
                            spiritual and superior ; hence " that is not first which is spiritual, but that which is
                            natural, afterward that which is spiritual." Nicodemus did not comprehend how a man could be
                            born again, and. comparatively few know any thing about it now. Still, it is a fact known to
                            have occurred with many individuals. And yet, of the many who barely suppose the thing
                            possible, how few desire to understand any thing of its nature and character. We think we
                            know, universal experience being the proof, that mortal death is sure to every living
                            creature. This is a fair type of the death in Christ, of the earthly generative nature by
                            which the sentient life principle of the soul, is liberated to mount higher, broader, into
                            purer fields of light, to expand in blissful activities, free from the blight of sin and
                            shame, wrought into the texture of its earthly covering by its own transgressions and those
                            of its natural ancestors ; amid the discords of a previous transient, shadowy, end mole-eyed
                            existence. What is possible for one in this respect will, soon or late, be possible for all.
                            As none are exempt from physical death, so none will be exempt from death to the pleasures
                            and satisfactions of the earthly, generative life. But according to the plan of human free
                            agency, which God does not arbitrarily control, it is left to man's option, after being
                            fully enlightened as to consequences, whether he will accept that life which is eternal, or
                            cleave to the earthly and shadowy unto the second death, from which as yet we have received
                            no certain knowledge of the issue. Hence the divinely inspired Teacher and Father of the New
                            Creation says, " He that loveth his (natural, generative) life shall lose it," for it shall
                            expire by natural limitation, according to the law of growth and decay, which inheres in all
                            natural things — or by the limitations of Time and season, natural and spiritual, in the
                            gradually unfolding plan of the world, of which men's earthly being forms a part; unless it
                            be previously de- stroyed by the operation of the seed of " Faith in Christ." But " He that
                            hateth his life in this world, shall keep it unto life eternal," receiving the latter in
                            exchange as he puts the former off. For, as no man can receive a reward or permanent
                            possession of happiness in himself, except by his own labor voluntarily performed,
                            therefore, this first life is the price put in his hands, wherewith to purchase the next and
                            superior one by toil and sacri- fice. Then, " diligently agonize to enter in at the strait
                            gate," all ye who desire the privileges and immunities of the New and supernal Creation,
                            which is not formed by a partial Deity for a specially favored few, irrespective of choice
                            and works, but for every soul of Adam's race who is willing to earn it by paying the full
                            price necessary to gain it. For now, the disabilities referred to by our Savior, in his
                            first appearing, are being removed from every creature that hears and obeys his voice ; and
                            are laid upon the body of sin, from which the soul is liberated by confession and repentance
                            — and the daily cross — while the call proceeds from the Spirit and the Bride saying, "
                            Come, for all things are now ready" — " Come whosoever will, and let him that heareth, say
                            Come, and partake of the water of life freely."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo" TEIform="persName"/>Alonzo Hollister, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thanksgiving" TEIform="index"/>THANKSGIVING</head><p TEIform="p">At Pleasant Hill, Kentucky, Thursday, Nov. 25, 1873, the Shakers, as is their wont on such
                            occasions, in all due respect to the powers that be, regarding them as ordained of God, for
                            the protection of both the civil and religious departments, each in its appropriate sphere,
                            assembled. Kindly invited, by the Elder of the congregation, I spoke; in substance,
                            something as follows: Much beloved Brethren and Sisters, We are met here to-day in
                            compliance with the Civil Department, through the instrumen tality of the Governor of the
                            State. I hope and believe it will result in the fact, that it is good for us to be here. If
                            ever I felt thankful for any favor, I feel thankful to-day, especially to-day, for the
                            government under which we live — believing, as I sincerely do, from overwhelming evidence,
                            that it is the way — the contemplated Highway, which the good Lord said should be cast up,
                            accompanied by the Way of Holiness. The aforesaid two Ways were, according to the true
                            letter and spirit of prophecy, introduced into the world simultaneously, at the proper time
                            and age of the world, as a special act of the Divine providence and grace of God, for the
                            true foundation of both the Civil and Sacred departments, and their eternal progress and
                            prosperity. Now, permit me to express my surprise, to find a party of Americans, either
                            native or adopted, under the auspices of this, the best government God ever gave to man, who
                            are making strenuous efforts to place their sectarian God in the National Constitution. The
                            Constitution, framed, under Divine Guidance, by our revered Revolutionary Fathers, for an 43
                                <pb n="44" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 4:4 8HAKEE ^lND everlasting Bulwark of Human Liberty, both civil
                            and sacred. Let every American, with a Soul in him, and her, unite as the heart of one man
                            and woman, and stand up in support of our Magna Charta, and not suffer a faction to plunge
                            us back to ages of oppression arid wrong, entailing abject depression upon coming
                            generations. Let this favored land of Liberty be, for ever be an asylum for liberty-loving
                            souls, for the oppressed of all nations — of all lands — until Earth shall be filled with
                            the knowledge of the Lord, as the waters cover the sea.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Runion, George B." TEIform="persName"/>Geo. B. Runion, Pleasant Hill, Ky.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Higher life" TEIform="index"/>THE HIGHER LIFE</head><p TEIform="p">Man is a duplex being, represented by two opposite conditions, the earthly or generative
                            life, and the higher, spiritual or regenerative life. These two states are often in conflict
                            with each other; the one urging him to look for enjoyment in sensual indulgences ; while the
                            other urges him to seek his enjoyment in the development and growth of his intellectual,
                            moral and spiritual nature. The internal life of man is like a flower, that gradually
                            unfolds itself from the dormant bud, swelling and bursting its covering and expanding itself
                            in its utmost beauty, — the immortal, spiritualized man or woman. In his rude and
                            undeveloped state, man seeks to supply merely the wants of his animal nature , but as his
                            mind expands, his intellectual nature must be nourished with its proper aliment. The
                            pleasures that once delighted him, now prove inadequate to supply the wants of his being.
                            Rising still higher in the scale, his moral faculties claim attention; the spiritual now
                            begins to unfold itself and demands the necessary nutriment. He is called upon to hold in
                            subjection the propensities of his animal nature, and bring them to the law of use. If he
                            allows them to control him as they formerly did, heavy penalties are sure to follow ; for
                            light has come from the higher spheres and illuminated the soul, influencing it to advance
                            beyond its former condition, and attain to that which is the ultimate of human aspirations.
                            This is not a myth, nor a dream, but a reality. The spiritual life is in harmony with all of
                            nature's laws, and hence perfectly natural. Though the higher faculties be buried in the
                            grave of sensuality, yet, some day, they will rise to life and hold complete sway over the
                            lower propensities. To a soul who is living in the indulgence of perverted passions, the
                            idea of the sexes living together in the enjoyment of the higher life, in daily association
                            with each other, appears mystical, and unreal, if not quite impossible. As James Peebles
                            says : —" You might as well talk metaphysics to mummied gorillas as to talk of a love
                            divested of passion and earthliness, to those who swelter in the lower departments of their
                            cranial organisms." The fact is, their minds are not developed enough to comprehend the
                            higher life ; there must be a gradual unfolding of the mind up to the plane of morality, and
                            then onward till the higher life is attained. If we trace the history of mankind back for
                            thousands of years, we see the higher life unfolding itself in the establishment of
                            institutions designed to aid the soul in its aspiration for something above the merely
                            sensual. The sexes secluded themselves, in such, from each other's society, for the purpose
                            of attaining to that which they thought it impossible to gain by association. History does
                            not furnish us, in all the past, the example of a reli- gious community, that has
                            practically carried the higher life to that degree of perfection, which the Shaker Church
                            has done. Here there are no bolts to prevent social and spiritual communion, sex commingling
                            with sex in accordance with the law of divine love, but every thing tends to give growth to
                            the whole man and woman, intellectual, moral and spiritual. Brethren and sisters feel the
                            band of union growing stronger as time passes, while faithful performance of the duties of
                            the present life prepares them for the enjoyment of every thing which awaits them in the
                            future.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="DeGraw, Hamilton" TEIform="persName"/>Hamilton De Graw, Groveland, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tribute of thanks and love" TEIform="index"/>TRIBUTE OF THANKS AND LOVE</head><p TEIform="p">As it is a cardinal principle, and standing order, in Shaker organizations, to pay all just
                            debts, I feel it incumbent on me to present my thanks and love to the editors, contribu-
                            tors, and all, who bless and sustain our Gospel messenger. I have been edified and
                            instructed in reading valuable articles, on various interesting subjects, all designed to
                            help the mind develop and grow into the angelic life — to form a Heaven now, on this
                            terrestrial sphere. I offer my union and blessing, as a link in the chain of universal love
                            — now being created in our Zion home — to draw the wandering and erring under the benign
                            influence of peace. In purity is peace. An eye single to the glory of God, and the testimony
                            of Christ, now in the Female Order, is good religion. It yields the peaceable fruits of
                            righteousness. I pray for a living increase of resurrection life and power, to carry us away
                            from all that is held in high esteem, in the narrow selfish, generative order. We want a
                            higher, purer and holier relation. Here are the germs of Life Divine unfolded to us, as we,
                            by virtue of the Cross of Christ, live a true, consecrated life of self denial. I love my
                            Shaker home. For the blessings found therein, I freely sacrifice all that is dear to the
                            carnal mind. In bonds of Love,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Brown, John M." TEIform="persName"/>John M. Brown, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Burning, but friendly" TEIform="index"/>BURNING, BUT FRIENDLY</head><p TEIform="p">Like an oasis to the desert traveler—like a city of refuge to the ancient criminal—Shaker
                            villages stand, with hospitable, open doors, inviting the sin-sick and needy to partake of
                            their spiritual verdance—to come and claim their spiritual birthright—and, if not accusable
                            of hypocrisy, or deceit, to be judged worthy the rights and privileges of the Sons and
                            Daughters of God. Had I a voice, loud as the Archangel's Trumpet, I would gladly proclaim to
                            that world of sin, that maelstrom of iniquity, from which I have so recently severed myself,
                            that I have found Christ—a Savior, risen anew. Come, and behold what wondrous things are
                            wrought here, by the Lord—Men and Women, who have washed and made themselves clean—living
                            lives of virgin purity, by day, and by night, doing only what is pleasing in the sight of
                            just Heaven. Formerly, differing in language, religion and blood, now agreeing in one faith,
                            living in sweet harmony, dedicated to the Lord, to do his will—at all times willing to spend
                            and be spent in the cause of their God, and for each other—void of selfishness, inviting
                            all, who will, to come and partake of their blessings and favors, and of the waters of life
                            freely.—Come, and having tasted of heavenly fruits, and breathed the air of purity, say if
                            this is not the way of God—the very Gate of Heaven. Nothing other than heaven-born love and
                            influence could make the sons and daughters of fallen, degenerate, sensual man, to be, from
                            virtuous principle, so self-denying, generous, forgiving and self-crucifying. To me, a
                            novitiate, it is most encouraging to know, that though many systems of socalled religious
                            reform, with their Vesuviuslike, fitful ebulitions,have been, and gone, the true, radical,
                            adamantine principles of Shakerism remain entire—the same living testimony to-day, as in the
                            beginning—like the thunderings of Sinai, sharp, powerful and convicting— a terror to evil
                            doers—yet a praise to those who do well. Built upon the Rock of Ages, it shall stand ! It
                            shall stand, a witness for the truth, until no one shall say to another, Knowest thou that
                            new way ? All shall know it, in spirit and in truth, rejoicing in this new Jerusalem, Jesus
                            and Mother Ann being the key and corner stones. Though threatened, at times, by foes within
                            and foes without, the sea of life, with its passions and prejudices surging around, the
                            spiritually deserving canjread on her portals, Holiness to the Lord. Thus far shalt thou
                            come, and no further. We have the assur- ance, that though angry billows assail, the
                            righteous shall surely prevail. I rejoice in that which makes me free from the power of sin
                            and death—that in the midst of so much darkness and delusion, there is so much life and
                            light. I rejoice in the testimony of Mother Ann, which, compromising nothing to truth, wages
                            eternal warfare against the growing evils—the damning sins of society, in this and other
                            lands—particularly fceticide and infanticide. What ground of hope, for radical reform, is
                            there, while Government Officials barter and betray the interests of their common country ?
                            while wealth, not principles, is the criterion by which they are measured ? while spiritual
                            guides—blind leaders of the blind—remain hushed, in the midst of such vice ?— while luxury
                            and sensual gratification are the desideratum ?— while science is prostrated to mercenary
                            purposes ? — while scholars are pensioned flatterers in Church and State? — while education
                            and talent can be bribed ?— while the medical profession, from being the handmaid of nature,
                            can, for filthy hicre, be seduced to dig elbow-deep in ways that are dark, soul-destroying
                            and damning? How long—how long, O God, shall the working of such iniquity go unpunished ? In
                            view of the plague spots, in all grades of society—thankful that I have been ealled to the
                            higher life—my constant prayer is, that in childlike obedience to my spiritual Father and
                            Mother, I be fitted and prepared, a living stone in the Temple of God—a light, to such as
                            walk in darkness, that they, too, may come forth and partake of the resurrective power of
                            life.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Moore, Robert G." TEIform="persName"/>Robert G. Moore, Enfield, Cl.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Day of judgment" TEIform="index"/>THE DAY OF JUDGMENT</head><p TEIform="p">"The Christian ¦world is looking forward to a time when all men will be judged. But they look
                            too far. They overlook the great fact that every day is a day of judgment; that the trial is
                            going on, convictions are obtained, and sentence is being pronounced upon men every day, and
                            they are taking their places at the right hand or the left, according to the verdict. "The
                            laws of the divine order extend to the minutest events of life, and to all the operations of
                            nature ; there is no escape from their jurisdiction, and no possibility of evading their
                            police. Men vainly think ?hey can do wrong and evade its consequences; but it is impossible.
                            Wicked men conspire to rob a city. They succeed. They take millions of money from the
                            people; they gain immense power; they control elections, and legislators, and courts of
                            justice. There seems to be no limit to their power, no means of bringing them to justice:
                            and they riot in their stolen wealth, and laugh at the feeble efforts to punish them. " But
                            their trial is going on while they least suspect it. The witnesses are being called, and the
                            evidence of their guilt is accumulating. They may defy the civil law for a time, but they
                            cannot escape the power of a higher law than the civil, and in the end they cannot evade
                            that. Every new act of fraud or robbery, and every word of defiance and contempt for the
                            principles and the friends of justice, is one step toward conviction and punishment. "It may
                            not always be the punishment which the civil law prescribes, but it will be quite as severe.
                            They may escape to foreign lands; but their escape is banishment and disgrace. They may
                            revel in their stolen wealth, but it will not bring them happiness. Even if they become so
                            hardened as not to feel any compunctions of conscience for their evil deeds, that hardening
                            of the heart and indifference to right is a greater punishment than the civil law can
                            inflict. It is imprisonment of the worst kind. It bars the soul from all that is good and
                            true; it renders it incapable of enjoying the greatest blessings of life; it imprisons it in
                            a dungeon to which no ray of the highest light can ever gain access. There is no condition
                            more terrible than that. " We come to wrong conclusions concerning the certainty and the
                            severity of the punishment of sin, because we judge it by too low standards, and regard the
                            civil penalty as the principal one. We forget that the divine laws operate whether human
                            laws are executed or not, and that it is impossible to escape their penalty, which in all
                            cases is exactly measured by the guilt. It is not a feather's weight more or less. The civil
                            penalty is only the shadow of the real one. So far as the criminal is concerned, it is of
                            but little consequence whether he escapes the civil penalty or not. The real one he
                            certainly will suffer." — New Jerusalem, Me.</p></div2><pb n="45" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakeress: courage, toilers" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERESS: COURAGE, TOILERS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">Life and growth, or death and decay, are stamped upon all things in a terrestrial sphere of
                            existence. Inaction precedes decay, and indolence endangers the health of both body and
                            mind. In this world of ours, where human suffering abounds, caused by either ignorance or
                            willful transgression of natural or spiritual laws, and where so much is needed to be done,
                            how can any, who are capable of feeling the convulsive throes of hearts struggling for
                            liberty, and longing to burst the chains that bind them, and to flee the prison houses whose
                            massive walls encase them, be willing to withhold their efforts from doing what is in their
                            power to bring about a better state of things ? Everyone may do something ; no one who has
                            strength should fail to give it in a good cause. Does the question arise, what can I do ? I
                            am but as a grain of sand upon the sea shore, when compared with millions of earth's in-
                            habitants, who possess talent, wealth, and power, that would far outweigh all that I
                            possess. The answer would be : Every grain placed in the scale of truth, against error, will
                            be of use ; for ten thousand such grains might turn the scale in the right direction; and it
                            is far wiser to cast our mite into the balance than to do nothing. It is better to
                            sympathize with, and to pray for, those who feel the bitter pangs of destitution, whether in
                            a physical, moral, or spiritual point of view (each condition produces misery and woe), than
                            to turn a deaf ear to the cries of the needy, and think that God is able (if willing), by
                            some miraculous power, to change conditions, without the agency of man and woman, and thus
                            shirk all responsibility, and seek the epicurean's part. The orderly arrangement of God's
                            laws through mediative agencies cannot be changed; as well might the agriculturist attempt
                            to plow, and sow, and reap, without the utensils of husbandry, as for God to accomplish* his
                            work unaided by the instruments which He has created for that purpose. Man and woman,
                            assisted by a superior intelligence, are his implements to effect his designs in relation to
                            the elevation and salvation of the human race. Those who deposit seeds in the soil, expect
                            them to germinate and return an increase to the sower. Some may bring forth " thirty, others
                            sixty or a hundred-fold," according to conditions; but all are expected to return something.
                            So should it be with created beings who are endowed with reason, whether they possess one
                            talent or five. God will call for his own with usury. There are diversified gifts and
                            talents, and there is a place for every-one; for there is a large field open, and a great
                            work to be done, to pull down the false, and build up the true ; and that work should
                            commence with every individual. The exercise of true wisdom and charity would lead to
                            self-discipline — to the correction of error in the individual life and character— before
                            attempting to destroy the wrong , that is in others. "Ah, here comes the rub! " There are
                            thousands of brilliant talents employed at the present time in advocating right principles,
                            depicting the wrong, and decrying the flagrant sins and crimes that are increas- ing with
                            fearful rapidity throughout the length and breadth of our land, who have never sub- dued the
                            producing causes of those crimes in themselves. That is the reason why so many who are
                            professedly in the work of reform accomplish so little ; they point the way, but do not
                            practically lead the van. There is power in Truth ; and, when uttered by the tongues and
                            lips of the righteous — those who do the truth —" it is like choice silver," and brings
                            health and life to the hearer. Words, thus spoken, breathe vitality to the fainting spirit,
                            and give solace to the afflicted, rest to the weary, and meat in due season to the
                            famishing. But seers may well be ashamed, and learned divines confounded and cover their
                            lips, when there is no answer from God, and no response from the hearts of the people.
                            Talent, when rightly improved, is a great blessing, not only to its possessor—'it is a gift
                            to humanity. Wealth of mind is of far greater value than gold of Ophir ; for gold cannot buy
                            wisdom. But when talent is profaned, and laid at the feet of ambition, selfseeking and
                            self-pleasing, then we feel that an enemy has usurped what should have been the inheritance
                            of the needy ; and God, the Giver, is dishonored thereby. If, on the other hand, all worldly
                            and selfish considerations are sacrificed to just principles, and, with integrity of
                            purpose, talent grasps the hand of virtue, and holds it with unflinching purpose, then we
                            feel that there is a triumph of truth, and a victory gained for humanity. Without doubt,
                            many of the ancient philosophers, knowing the frailties of the human heart, and the danger
                            of temptation to desecrate their God-given powers to false uses, were influenced to avoid
                            such temptation by seclusion ; and through prayer, ablutions, sexual purity, and extreme
                            self-denial, to do their work; and they were blest in their trusting devotion. They became
                            so far lost to worldly attractions and pleasures, derived through the medium of the external
                            senses, that they were linked to the Divine. The earth was younger then than now; and her
                            children reasoned less and believed more ; they were guided more by conscience and in-
                            tuition than by reason. Now people reason much, and believe little, for the voice of con-
                            science is but little heard or heeded. Those Ascetics were " the salt of the earth," the
                            Saviors in their day. Many of the sublime truths which they taught, have overleaped time and
                            space, and have come down to us in their soundness, freshness, and beauty; and they will
                            descend through history to future generations. Truth never grows old. Now, if we can strike
                            a middle line between Epicurism and Asceticism, and boldly engage in the Christian warfare,
                            and meet temptation and overcome it, and let both reason and conscience have a place to work
                            and perform their proper functions, then will Justice and Truth join hands, and Mercy and
                            Peace embrace each other, to the joy of mortals, and the delight of Angels. Our credentials
                            to the higher Christian life, and our claims as workers in the fields of physical and moral
                            reform, must be presented in life deeds—real tangible works. Then we can with confidence
                            declare our faith whenever and wherever there are ears to hear. Living, active faith,
                            attended with righteous deeds, will conquer death and bring new life, and will give new
                            soul-aspirations for the companionship of Angelical beings in regions supernal.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mental vision" TEIform="index"/>A MENTAL VISION</head><p TEIform="p">I retired to rest with a feeling of anxiety on my mind, as to the future growth of Zion. And
                            turning restlessly on my pillow, I exclaimed aloud, " 0 Lord, what will attract souls to
                            Zion ! What will make them willing to accept the cross, come in and fill up the ranks, and
                            build up the waste places in Zion? What will bring laborers into the Lord's vineyard?" And
                            immediately a ponderous wheel rolled up before my mind's eye, the motion of which was
                            perpetual. Each cog appeared to represent a cycle of time, within a general cycle, and
                            attached to the central part or shaft of the wheel, grouped together by fine threadlike
                            fibres, each group in its distinct place, was the advancement of art, science and re-
                            ligion. Every element and principle that bore a close relation to practical life was
                            represented, each one good and indispensable to the harmonious growth of intelligence. The
                            continual motion of the wheel brought some one of these within the sphere of mind, which
                            appeared to engross the general attention of mankind at a given time; and then came the
                            words, " It is just as easy to excite the religious element as any other element, when the
                            proper time rolls around; and souls will as surely be attracted by the magnet of truth in
                            religion, as in any other element." Art and science have engrossed the public mind for a
                            long period of time; the results of which are seen in railroads spanning the continent,
                            coursing their way through hills and over mountain tops — in the electric wires threading
                            the air and sea from shore to shore — the very elements of destruction reduced to the
                            control and use of man. As they facilitate the advancement of knowledge, may they not be the
                            very means needed to advance the Gospel, and spread it over the earth ? When the proper time
                            rolls around, the beautiful truths in religion, and a spiritual life in holiness, will
                            attract souls, and cause them, through increased light, to loathe the hollow theologies and
                            false doctrines upon which they now depend; and nothing but practical truth and goodness
                            will satisfy them. Then they will accept the cross of Christ. I am waiting and watching the
                            motion of the ponderous wheel. It is moving. Eldress E. Farr, Union Village, O.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Farr, E." TEIform="persName"/></byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The earth is thine, O Lord! and all that is contained therein..." TEIform="index"/>The earth is thine, O Lord! and all that is contained therein...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The earth is thine, O Lord! and all that is contained therein; notwithstanding
                                    thou hast given the possession thereof to the children of men. We heartily pray thee
                                    to send thy Holy Spirit into the hearts of them that possess the grounds, pastures,
                                    and dwelling-places of the earth, that they, remembering themselves to be thy
                                    tenants, may not rack and stretch out the rents of their houses and lands; nor yet
                                    take unreasonable fines and incomes, after the manner of covetous worldlings; but so
                                    let them out to others that the inhabitants thereof may be able to both pay the
                                    rents, and also honestly to live, to nourish their families, and to relieve the
                                    poor. Give them also grace to consider that they are but strangers and pilgrims in
                                    this world, having here no dwelling-place, but seeking one to come, that they,
                                    remembering the short continuance of their life, may be content with that which is
                                    sufficient, and not join house to house, nor couple land to land, to the detriment
                                    of others ; but so behave themselves in letting out their tenements, lands, and
                                    pastures, that, after this life, they may be received into everlasting
                                    dwelling-places: through Jesus Christ our Lord. Amen."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Liturgy of Edward VI" TEIform="index"/>Liturgy of Edward VI</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="46" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tribute" TEIform="index"/>TRIBUTE</head><p TEIform="p">Ever Loved Eldress A.: I have often felt that I would be pleased to sliow my appreciation of
                            our precious little paper, that I love so well, by offering a small tribute to its columns.
                            I feel my inability to contribute any thing that will be worthy to occupy a place ; but I am
                            eighty-two years of age to-day, and feel conscious that I am nearing the banks of that river
                            which divides the earthly and super-mundane spheres, and cannot reasonably expect to remain
                            on this side of the stream many years longer, and I wish to say to my friends, that I feel
                            that my prolonged life has been a blessing to me. I am thankful that in early life I was
                            brought to see and to sense, in a degree, the purity of angelic beings, and the work that
                            was necessary for me to do to prepare myself to dwell with them in their pure and happy
                            mansions. And to-day my soul is filled with thankfulness to our Father and Mother God, for
                            their loving kindness in calling me into this purifying, soul-saving work, that I might
                            become a perfected stone, squared and fitted to fill a place in that " house not made with
                            hands, eternal in the heavens." Dear friends and Zion travellers, we have much to encourage
                            us to pursue the heavenly journey, to be valiant and strong, knowing that every step we take
                            brings us nearer to him who said (speaking to his brethren), " Be of good cheer ; I have
                            overcome the world." We must all do the same work, be baptized as Jesus was baptized, bear
                            the same cross of self-denial that he bore, to become his true followers ; and we must be
                            resurrected into newness of life, if we would reign with him over the power of sin and
                            death. I rejoice in the blessed gospel of salvation, through a full consecration of body,
                            soul and mind to God. By living a pure angelic life while in time, the spirit is raised
                            above earthly things; and I feel, at times, as if I was wafted on angels' wings to the
                            abodes of the blest in the immortal land. I thank our Heavenly Father and Mother that I have
                            lived to see the commencement of a glorious era, wherein the Sun of righteousness rules the
                            day, and excludes the darkness of night, the sequence of sin. Now we hear the joyful sound "
                            Peace on earth, good will to all, who will do unto others as we would that others should do
                            unto us." Thus doing we become one with angels in heaven. Seventy-two years of my life have
                            been spent in proving the power and efficacy of this work, and I am now prepared to
                            recommend it as a sure and safe way to happiness in this life, and the best work of
                            preparation for the life beyond. With a loving and prayerful spirit, I have written this,
                            with my own hand, hoping it may encourage and comfort those who are seeking to find the path
                            that will lead them home to God.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Brewster, Cassandana" TEIform="persName"/>Cassandana Brewster, W. Pittsficld, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sun's orbit" TEIform="index"/>The Sun's Orbit.</head><p TEIform="p"> A Tennessee philosopher has made the discovery that our solar system travels about the star
                            Alcyone, in an elliptical orbit, taking twenty-two billions of years for the trip. He claims
                            that this huge cycle has its spring, summer, autumn and winter, and that in its changing
                            seasons the vegetable and animal life on the earth are liable to be ex- tinguished, to be
                            followed by a new order of things-. These are very nice contingencies to contemplate, but
                            the process is so terribly slow that we have little hope of being there to see.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Love" TEIform="index"/>LOVE</head><p TEIform="p">There is much said and written at the present time, upon the subject of love. Without
                            agitation, there would not be thought; therefore, it is well to have the subject
                            investigated and analyzed, that it may be thoroughly understood; and when it is understood,
                            we hope there may be sufficient honesty of purpose to carry the highest ideal of the law of
                            love into practice ; for knowledge, unless reduced to practice, is ineffective. Our highest
                            conception of wisdom and love takes us to Deity, the primal source of all good. In
                            scriptural language, " God is Love." We also read of a wisdom that cometh from above that is
                            pure and peaceable ; and of a wisdom that is not from above, but is earthly, sensual, and
                            demoniac. Will not the same justly apply to love? There is a Divine love, and a human love ;
                            and a love (so called) that is sensual, and is the antithesis of true love, producing
                            opposite results. Those who acknowledge two Orders, the natural and spiritual, accord to
                            each its proper sphere of action, and the love, or bond of relationship, which governs, and
                            holds them on the plane where they belong. The love that rules in the highest spiritual
                            Order is from God, and will lead to Him ; Human, natural love, is also God-given, and has
                            its uses, and is a necessity; it flows to the whole brotherhood of man. It is that which
                            obtains in the family relation on the generative plane, where the affections center to kith
                            and kin ; it is good, if unperverted,and is necessary while the temporary relationship
                            exists. We see that there are various kinds of love, but at this time we will only contrast
                            the higher, which is Divine, and leads to all that is pure and noble—to peace and happiness
                            — with the lower, which is antipodal; and should be called inordinate lustful desire, for it
                            leads to all that is low and degrading — to war and misery. The higher love makes no
                            provision for the flesh, while the lower provides for nothing else. There is great confusion
                            in society at the present time ; and many minds are bewildered by the commotion. There is a
                            disintegrating power at work; monogamy is being superseded, in a degree, by polygamy and
                            incest. Infanticide is practiced to an alarming extent, and foundling hospitals are crowded
                            with the innocent offspring of guilty parents. It has been stated that there are thirty
                            thousand female prostitutes in the city of New York at the present time. How many male
                            prostitutes must there needs be to support those vile women ? They are not supported by
                            vagrants ; for many of them dwell in splendid palaces, and live in luxury. Who, we would
                            ask, are their supporters, if not men of wealth and station, who cover them- selves with a
                            cloak of respectability, while their associates of the opposite sex, are marked and
                            consigned to infamy and disgrace? But these " respectable " hypocrites—whited sepulchres—
                            are the more dangerous to society, because their true character is unknown. It would occupy
                            too large a space in our small sheet to notice all classes, from the lowest stratum of
                            society up to the highest; who in desire and practice are one and the same, differing
                            perhaps in degree, and name, and we shall be under the necessity of following Paul's
                            example, of " including all in unbelief." We look upon all, from the perverted marriage
                            institution, as it now exists, (which is a cloak for licentiousness) to Mormon- ism,
                            Perfectionism, Free-lovism, down to the seducer and procuress with their poor captives, as
                            adulterers and adulteresses in the sight of God ; all seeking to save the carnal life. And
                            the reader will not think us too plain and severe, if we quote the words of Jesus, "Who-
                            soever looketh on a woman to lust after her, hath committed adultery with her already in his
                            heart." It is not our purpose to condemn any who are living up to their highest convictions
                            of right and duty ; but to strive to " show a more excellent way," by pointing out the
                            Christian life, as distinct from it all. We give place to the orderly seed-sewers on the
                            plane where they belong, and honor them if they do their work honestly, and replenish the
                            earth with healthy offspring. But we accord the highest place to the harvesting angels,
                            whose mission is to reap souls from the generative plane and gather them into the
                            resurrection Order, where marriage has no place, and the male and female live in virgin
                            purity, and toil together to upbuild Christ's kingdom. " All cannot receive this saying." In
                            other words, all persons are not prepared to enter into the angelic condition of life on the
                            higher plane. But they who have heard the voice of the Spirit calling them to " Come up
                            higher," are thankful to enter the school of Christ, and learn of the heavenly teachers,
                            that he has sent, how to love unselfishly, and to do unto others as they would that others
                            should do unto them ; and how to gain that perfect love which casteth out fear — that kind
                            of fear in which there is torment. The prize to be obtained is worth the conflict. If we do
                            not attain unto perfection in this life, we shall continue in the same work when we enter
                            the spirit world, and complete the heaven there, that we have commenced here. We rejoice
                            that woman is putting forth her efforts in the work of reform ; she has been the greatest
                            sufferer in the sexual relations of life, and from intemperance ; and she will be the most
                            diligent worker. Let her assert her freedom, the right to own and govern herself, and work
                            her way steadily up to her proper position ; i.e., to stand side by side with man in framing
                            and keeping the civil laws of the land, and be his true help-meet in all the duties of life
                            ; and thus move step by step in the work of progression.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webster, Ruth" TEIform="persName"/>Ruth Webster, Union Village, O.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prayer" TEIform="index"/>PRAYER</head><p TEIform="p">Prater is the breathing of the soul — its desires unfolding towards its Creator. At the
                            approach of judgment or impending danger, those who fear God, involuntarily look to Him
                            through the agency of prayer for deliverance. Why is this ? Because in the human mind is
                            sown the knowledge of a Being, Supreme, whose power pervades immensity, and whose
                            beneficence forgets not the least of creation. Thus, how instinctively the mind seeks its
                            Creator. Those who love God seek to know him better, and there is no greater medium for this
                            purpose than fervent prayer. In this state of mind the veil seems rent, and we are permitted
                            to look beyond the limits of earth, into the " holy of holies," where the soul bows in
                            penitence, seeking forgiving love, or weeps in silence its gratitude to God for his manifold
                            mercies. How many instances are recorded of our Savior, when in the depths of his
                            sufferings, he sought relief in prayer to the Father. In one of those seasons, we read, that
                            there appeared unto him an angel from heaven, strengthening him. And being in an agony, he
                            prayed more earnestly ; and his sweat was, as it were, great drops of blood. How deep and
                            earnest must have been that prayer, made doubly fervent by his approaching trial and the
                            knowledge of his dependence upon Divine power for support. He also taught his disciples, "
                            Pray that ye enter not into temptation," because, the act of prayer concentrates the powers
                            of the mind upon the subject of its desire ; thus guarding from present evils and drawing
                            strength from other sources towards its accomplishment. How necessary then, to the
                            Christian, is the spirit of prayer. As man communes with man, so may the soul commune with
                            its God ; and the more constant and fervent the desires of the mind are, the nearer will be
                            our relation to God, and the clearer our knowledge of Him. From whence come the strong
                            resolves of the devotional hour ? From whence the new life-power, the assurance of victory,
                            and the strong emotions of love and reverence for the Divine —inciting us to greater
                            self-denial and watchfulness, greater trust and more elevated feelings — if not from the
                            presence of the holy Spirit of God, more fully recognized through prayer? Let us bear in
                            mind that God is not only Wisdom, but Love ; not only SH^lKER <pb n="47" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> Father,
                            but Mother. Here then let us bring all the burdens of the soul. As a child seeks the
                            guidance of its kind parents, in whom it has perfect confidence, let us ask in faith to be
                            led according to the wisdom of God; and, though we may walk in unknown paths, let us fear no
                            evil; for God is with us, and He has promised to sustain all who obey and serve Him. Let us
                            not forget the fact, that there are many agencies between our souls and the Supreme ; spirit
                            friends, who are ministers of love, and messengers of truth, from the source of all love and
                            truth ; bearing the gifts of consolation to the soul. We have long cherished this truth,
                            because we have felt its power; and it is no less potent for passing through those agencies
                            ; for God is Infinite and Omnipresent, in all, and tlirough all.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Martin, Elizabeth" TEIform="persName"/>Elizabeth Martin, Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lafayette, Indiana, March 6, 1874" TEIform="index"/>Lafayette, Ind., March 6, 1874</head><p TEIform="p">Much Esteemed Editkess : — Your beautiful and well-laden little sheet has (for some cause
                            unknown) failed to reach me. I am truly sorry to miss a single number, as it contains so
                            much truth and spiritual food. I believe true Shakers are nearer the Kingdom of God than any
                            others. Most of their doctrines I fully indorse, and trust that their works agree therewith.
                            My firm conviction is, that God is now raising up instruments in the great " Woman's
                            Reform," or uprising of the people in the Temperance Cause. We, the Ladies of Lafayette, are
                            holding daily prayer meetings, often twice a day, which are very largely attended. This
                            great Temperance revival is spreading, not only through our State, but in Ohio, Illinois,
                            and other Western States. May the God of Heaven grant wisdom and strength to those devoted
                            workers for the elevation of man; and this accomplished, many will be prepared to join you
                            in a higher, holier cause. Now, I do not wish to dictate to you ; but I would suggest that
                            it would add a number of names to your list of subscribers would you treat more largely on
                            the evils of intoxicating drinks. I solicit the attention of many persons to subscribe for
                            your valuable paper; and the uniform response is, Does it treat on the temperance movement ?
                            any thing to encourage that warfare let us have. We are an earnest band here; and our motto
                            is, victory or death! In this noble cause we are banded together in one great Sisterhood,
                            all denominations (Catholics excepted), without distinction of sect, mingling our hearts and
                            voices together in prayer to Almighty God for the destruction of this great evil,
                            Intemperance. Please give us your sisterly aid in your next. Go on, beloved Sister and
                            friend; for a great work is before thee. May the angels of God hold up thy arms. Thine for
                            the truth's sake, P. S. Pray for our cause.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Nagle, Sarah A." TEIform="persName"/>Sarah A. Nagle</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The mild face of Henry Bergh, the apostle to the animals..." TEIform="index"/>The mild face of Henry Bergh, the apostle to the animals...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The mild face of Henry Bergh, the apostle to the animals, who sits in his ornamental office,
                            with blue and gold surroundings, looking placidly out of his window, receiving the grateful
                            nods of recognition from the quadrupeds which pass, particularly from the mild steeds of the
                            Fourth avenue cars, will be grateful for the opportunity of perusing the following extract
                            by the author of "Travels on Horseback:" "The Chinese," says this writer, " are always kind
                            to animals and never punish ; hence a mule, that in the hands of a foreigner, would not only
                            be useless, but dangerous to every one about it, becomes, in the hands of a Chinaman, as
                            quiet as a lamb and as tractable as a dog. We never beheld a runaway, a jibbing or a vicious
                            mule or pony in a Chinaman's employment, but found the same rattling, cheerful pace
                            maintained over heavy or light roads, by means of a 'tur-r or cluk'k,' the beast turning to
                            the right or left and stopping with but a hint from the reins. This treatment is extended to
                            all animals they press into their service. Often have I admired the tact exhibited in
                            getting a large drove of sheep through narrow crowded streets and alleys by merely having a
                            little boy to one of the quietest of the flock in front; the others steadily followed,
                            without aid either from yelping cur or cruel goad. Cattle, pigs and birds are equally cared
                            for." In the small state of Rhode Island there are no fewer than seven divisions of
                            Baptists.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="For the shakeress" TEIform="index"/>FOR THE SHAKERESS</head><p TEIform="p">We often meet with persons who anxiously inquire, " How we became members of the Shaker
                            fraternity, and why we continue our connection with them ? " I offer a few words of personal
                            experience through the columns of the " Shakeress," and hope they will be acceptable to
                            those inquirers who feel interested in this question. Tn early childhood, I was brought to
                            Mt. Lebanon by my parents, residents of the town of Saybrook, Conn. Both received faith in
                            the principles of Believers (or Shakers), and being obedient thereto, united with their
                            family. I was then five years of age, and was subject and obedient to them, as my proper
                            guardians. They placed me in a condition, where I was taught the principles of prudence and
                            industry, and my morals were so strictly guarded, that I grew up in innocence and virtue. As
                            I increased in years and strength, I found that I had an enemy within my own heart to
                            contend with, that was seeking to bring me into bondage to sin — to allure and draw me away
                            from the path of purity — and thus destroy my peace of mind by robbing me of innocence,
                            which I found had hitherto been negative in a degree, because it was untried, and had not
                            been subjected to stern discipline in the school of self-denial, and the cross of Christ.
                            This brought a conflict; and I was forced to decide whether I would yield to the lower part
                            of my nature, which would prompt me to seek indulgence in worldly things, or turn from the
                            wily temptations to sin, and give my heart to God, and spend my life in his service. I chose
                            the latter, and by obedience to the testimony of the Gospel of Christ, I have been protected
                            from sin, and from its direful consequences. I have now attained unto the age of three score
                            years, and fifty-five of those years have been spent with Believers at Mt. Lebanon. I look
                            back upon my life, and feel an inward peace and joy that worldly riches or carnal pleasures
                            could never give ; and I reflect with thankfulness upon the choice that I made in early
                            life, to dwell with those whose pure and innocent lives were like incense of praise to their
                            Creator. God requires purity of heart in thoughts, words and deeds, and to be privileged to
                            dwell with the pure in heart on earth, with the prospect before me of an eternal union with
                            them in the unseen world, is an unfailing source of joy to me. My heart often wells up with
                            gratitude and love to the benefactors and guardians of my early life. And I also raise my
                            voice in thanks and praise to God for the Gospel of salvation, and to his chosen witnesses
                            who kept the testimony in its purity, and through suffering of spirit paved the way for
                            others. An invitation is sounding to-day for the weary and heavy laden to " Come to the home
                            which God has prepared, through agencies of his own choosing, for those who will cast off
                            the yoke of sin, and accept Christ's yoke of purity, which gives true liberty." Then can
                            they join with the poet and sing : Now, freedom waves her golden wings, And spreads her
                            mantle round ; Can we be slaves to earthly things, Who have this treasure found ?</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Eliza R." TEIform="persName"/>Eliza R. Avery, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="Article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Change" TEIform="index"/>CHANGE</head><p TEIform="p">We live in an eventful time — a day of change. Science, Literature, Art and Theology, keep
                            the elements in commotion ; and there is a perpetual turning and overturning. Each has its
                            place, and is doing its work, with more or less interest and profit to humanity. While we
                            cannot say much in favor of the mixed theologies, which prevail at the present time, we
                            recognize a religious power and fervor which come from the hearts of the people, and which
                            rise above the false dogmas and churchcreeds of our time; and are far superior to them.
                            Religion is good, wherever it exists, and always does good. It possesses power, and its
                            influence is felt in the suppression of wrong, whenever it is allowed a place to work. But
                            where, among all the multifarious church organizations, shall we look for the embodiment of
                            those principles, which constituted the first Pentecostal Church ? We find church-goers and
                            mammon-worshipers in abundance; but practical cross-bearers and yoke-wearers—Jesus like, and
                            like his Apostles, and followers whom he baptized with the fire of truth, and unselfish love
                            — are rare examples. They were induced to lose their individuality, for the good of their
                            brethren and sisters, in a new spiritual relation, in that kingdom which he was sent to
                            inaugurate. The deep soul cry "Lord, increase our faith ! " and " What shall we do that we
                            may work the works of God and be saved from the sins of this adulterous age ? " is seldom
                            heard. Yet, we are convinced, that there are earnest struggling souls, who would willingly
                            and thankfully lay their all upon the altar of truth, and pay the price for the pearl of
                            salvation, if they knew how and where to find it. Many, at the present time, are looking for
                            the millennium ; and a cry is heard, " Watchmen, what of the night ? " A response com- eth
                            from the high watch-towers, " The morning dawns— the sun is rising in brightness I" Again it
                            is asked, " How shall we distinguish the day of the Lord ? Unto what may it be likened?" The
                            parable of the seed sower put forth by Jesus, exemplifies the true idea of the kingdom of
                            God. Like the grain of mustard seed it is small in its beginning, but great in results. Not
                            with outward observation, attended by great signs, and miracles, and pomp and show, may we
                            look for the true millennium. But for a deep heart-work, accompanied by a spiritual power
                            that will change the whole life and make new creatures of all its subjects. And, we testify,
                            to those who may be inclined to hear, that " Now has come salvation and strength, the
                            kingdom of our God, and the power of his Christ." And that a few havo found power, through
                            the cross of self-denial to " cast out the great accuser," and rise above the sensual,
                            selfish life, to a spiritual plane; where we have been enabled to form a brother and
                            sisterhood, upon the broad basis of universal love. Paul in his day, asked, " Why it should
                            be thought a thing incredible that God should raise the dead ? " And we ask, " Why should
                            our testimony be discredited? If any are doubtful, we say, let them come and practi- cally
                            live the life ; then they will know of the doctrine, if they will do the works," and be able
                            to prove for themselves, whether we testify truly, when we say that Christ's king- dom is
                            already commenced on earth.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leavenworth, Elvah" TEIform="persName"/>Elvah Leavenworth, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Waste no time" TEIform="index"/>WASTE NO TIME</head><p TEIform="p">Time lost can never be regained. After allowing yourself proper time for rest, don't live a
                            single hour of your life without doing exactly what is to be done in it, and going straight
                            through it from beginning to end. Work, play, study, whatever it is, take hold at once and
                            finish it up squarely and clearly; then to the next thing, without letting any moments drop
                            out between. It is wonderful to see how many hours these prompt people contrive to make of a
                            day; it is as if they picked up the moments that the dawdlers lost. And if ever you find
                            yourself where you have so many things pressed upon you that you hardly knew where to begin,
                            let us tell you a secret. Take hold of the very first one that comes to hand, and you will
                            find the rest all fall into file, and follow after, like a company of well-drilled soldiers;
                            and though work may be hard to meet when it charges in a squad, it is easily vanquished if
                            you can bring it into line. Dr. Cheever says : " If you imagine that you have nothing to do
                            after this prayer, you are greatly mistaken. You must have an incessant watchfulness. When
                            you make this prayer — 'Breathe in me a pure heart' — you have entered upon a lifelong
                            struggle. It is an unceasing, never-ending fight between the higher and the baser nature,
                            which are both working to obtain the mastery. Therefore your work must last with your
                        life."</p></div2><pb n="48" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our mission" TEIform="index"/>OUR MISSION</head><p TEIform="p">1. We all have a duty of life to perform, A mission of love to fulfill; A work that is worthy
                            our pow'rs to engage, With firmness of purpose and will. We all have a journey of life to
                            pursue, The highway of progress to climb; A strife to endure, and a vie t'ry to win, 'Mid
                            perils and dangers of time. And should we not linger to proffer our aid, To those who with
                            trials oppress'd, Are leaving the earthly for treasures divine, Who're seeking but finding
                            no rest? And shall we not give all our feelings in prayer, For souls who are yearning for
                            light, And place in the pathway of safety and truth The upward bound traveler aright ? O,
                            yea! we can brighten with smiles of good cheer, The way of the downcast and sad, And give to
                            the sin-sick a promise of hope, The sorrowing spirit make glad. We can comfort the mourner
                            with tidings of joy, And lighten life's burden and care; Uplifting the spirits of those who
                            are bound, The blessings of freedom to share. 4. We can hush the wild tumult of discord and
                            strife With love's gentle accents of peace, And welcome the weary worn pilgrim to rest,
                            Where storms of contention shall cease. O, this is our mission, and this is our call, To
                            resurrect souls from the earth, And aid them, through high aspiration, to rise, To joys of
                            the angelic birth.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lines written for, and read at the funeral of sister Nancy Osment" TEIform="index"/>Lines
                            written for, and read at the funeral of Sister Nancy Osment</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="W., E. H." TEIform="persName"/>E. H. W.</byline><p TEIform="p">Pearly gates, are ye unfolding To receive from earth a soul ? Angel guides, O, are ye holding
                            Her, in strong and tirm control? Bearing from our life a mother, Who did tenderly impart, To
                            each sister, and each brother, Love to soothe the weary heart. Shall we see no more her
                            presence, Beaming gladsomeness around? Shall we long for spirit-presence, When no more her
                            smile is found? Dark and lonely, if no angel Lights with joy the narrow way — If no
                            heaven-sent Evangel Cheers us with its blessed ray. Never fear! I hear her whisper ; Trust
                            in God and I'll be near; Ye are my interest — my treasure — Let your hearts be of good
                            cheer. Just the thinnest veil between us, Loving souls 'twill not divide; Mother's love
                            around — within us — O, how sweet to there abide! Mother's love! how like a glory, Pure and
                            blest encompass'd her* Made her life a record holy, Of the Christ that dwelt in her. Leave
                            thy mantle, O beloved, As the mortal drops from view I Comforter that Jesus promised. Still
                            remain to bear us through. Not one sad farewell we'll utter! No more tears bedimour eyes!
                            May thy peace be as a river; Hush'd be all our selfish sighs. Striving for a world's
                            uplifting We'll unite with saints above, Stem all careless downward drifting, Till we
                            perfect grow in love. Harvard, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My God" TEIform="index"/>MY GOD</head><p TEIform="p">And can I live one day to Thee In that perfection which I see? Not merely without sin that's
                            known, But without fault before thy throne ? How straight the path, how easy stray'd; What
                            strength by which we must be staid; What thought, what interest, all to keep Thy laws, the
                            blessing full to reap! We see amiss, we speak untaught; And folly's acts are often wrought,
                            Where principle and simple mien, Should ours possess'd be ever seen. Where is the center of
                            our ill ? Do we the laws of life fulfill? If house is kept in graceful way. Then grace may
                            there descend each day. The noblest structure that is found — Its basis rests upon the
                            ground; Though many stories nearing heav'n Strength to uphold from earth is giv'n. Then, our
                            foundations can we shun, And build our hopes the winds upon? Or, must we seek through light
                            yet dim, To build for God and live to Him?</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>Mary Whitcher, Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Subscribers may send 25 cents for the next six months..." TEIform="index"/>Subscribers may send 25 cents for the next six months...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Subscribers may send 25 cents for the next six months, but we advise that they remit 50
                            cents, and begin with January, 1874.</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The women of Iowa are rapidly preparing for the ballot by instruction in..." TEIform="index"/>The women of Iowa are rapidly preparing for the ballot by instruction in...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"The women of Iowa are rapidly preparing for the ballot by instruction in parliamentary
                            debate and general business. There are nearly 2,000 granges in the State, in which 25,000
                            women are entitled to vote. In the 7,000 granges in the whole country there are nearly
                            100,000 women."</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cheap food for the starving" TEIform="index"/>Cheap Food for the Starving</head><p TEIform="p">Here is a suggestion for the starving poor of our large cities. The Boston journals furnish
                            it gratuitously for the great number of destitute people in New York. Oat-meal is, of all
                            foods, the cheapest and most nutritious. It is stated that three cents worth of oat-meal,
                            milk costing the same sum, and sugar enough to sweeten it, will give a hearty meal to six
                            persons for twelve cents. This, it will be remembered, is the price for milk in the East.
                            Properly prepared, oat-meal possesses more bone and muscle-making material than any other
                            food that can be purchased for the same money, and, though but little appreciated in this
                            country, forms the staple food of a brawny race, remarkable for their devotion to athletic
                            amusement— the Scotch. The fact that oat-meal possesses a large amount of nutriment has long
                            been pro- claimed by scientific men, and has long been prescribed by physicians as a diet
                            for invalids. The suggestion of its use as food by the destitute people of the great cities
                            is timely, and will doubtless be heeded. </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pleasant item" TEIform="index"/>A Pleasant Item</head><p TEIform="p">Elder Harvey, Kentucky, sends us 110 names of new subscribers.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Osment, Nancy" TEIform="index"/>Nancy Osment
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Osment, Nancy" TEIform="persName">Nancy Osment</persName>, aged TO, Shirley, Mass. Born
                                August 15,1804. Died April 17, 1874.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Meechan, Sarah" TEIform="index"/>Sarah Meechan
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Meechan, Sarah" TEIform="persName">Sarah Meechan</persName>, aged 74, Shirley, Mass. Died
                                April 26,1874.</p></div3></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>