<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1108" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">11</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">8</biblScope><date value="18810801" TEIform="date">August 1881</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">169- 192</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="11" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="8" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--                 <pb id="p1"/>
                                        <p>AUGUST, 1881. MANIFESTO. G. A. LOMAS, EDITOR, SHAKERS, N. Y. Published by the United Societies. OUR HOME AT SHAKERS
                        N. Y. And they shall turn to you for a testimony: " Go preach the Kingdom of God ! " ADDRESS ALL COMMUNICATIONS TO
                        G. B. AVERY, PUBLISHER. 1881. Vol. XL No. 8. c 60 Cents Per Annum The Shaker " The Shaker Manifesto, Shakers, N.G."</p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --><pb n="169" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Only a pauper" TEIform="index"/>ONLY A PAUPER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Byrdsall, Charlotte" TEIform="persName"/>CHARLOTTE BYRDSALL</byline><p TEIform="p"> With fevered brow and hurrying feet, Eagerly on. through the crowded street, Pausing not,
                            though the many pass, Pausing not though the grand oppress, Onward ; we ask, " O ! where ?
                            Following with cautious, silent tread ; We hear the murmur," no home, no bread! " What is
                            the world or its wealth to-day — Unto a pauper turned away, With none for her sorrow to care
                            !" On with a look oft backward cast, Till reached is the wharf at the river at last; Then,
                            with a worn heart, in purpose more brave, She plunges into a watery grave, Leaving the world
                            and its gold. Gone, and the tidal waves over her close, Sealing in silence a wearied repose
                            ; Gone ! but the eye that never can sleep Knows of the many who seek the lone deep, Many
                            that grim want doth hold. In the bright wavelets borne to the shore, Singing the lone song,
                            " goue evermore," Eyes that see in the crystal and stone, That to the thousands is hidden,
                            unknown, Read of her sorrowing life. Read in the sands washed by the cold tide, How in her
                            great need friends turned aside, Left her because of society's curse. Which turns in a
                            moment the good into worse, Augmenting the hour of strife. Riches have wings that quickly
                            take flight, Leaving the once glad, sorrow and blight;. Leaving the full home empty and
                            loue, Fortune and friends all turned to stone, Just in the moment of need. Angels of
                            goodness shower on eartli, Powers to dispel all sadness and dearth ; Help to make equal the
                            lord and the serf; Equal while living, as well " neath the turf," For death locks all in one
                            creed. O ! in the distance though far it maybe, Beautiful homes for the millions I see!
                            Prison-house, slaughter-house, emblems of pain, Long since supplanted by rich waving grain,
                            Food for humanity's strength. Meadows all smiling beneath the blue dome, Murmuring the sweet
                            song plenty and home, Homes for all people where love holds the • power, Peace in the temple
                            and freedom the tower. Days are increasing in length. Churches where pride has fostered her
                            taste, And held over many the dire hand of waste, Tumble and fall ; for God who is light,
                            Leadeth to worship "neath sunshine so bright, Instead of the temples of death! Hasten, O,
                            hasten the glad time along, Angels of power who triumph o'er wrong! God is advancing ; its
                            might I can feel, Writing in truth humanity's weal. Industry leadeth to wealth. Mt. Lebanon,
                            N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is said that most any person can give a reproof, but there are only a few who can take one" TEIform="index"/>It is said that most any person can give a reproof, but there are only a few who can take one
                        </head><p TEIform="p">It is said that most any person can give a reproof, but there are only a few who can take
                            one.</p></div2><pb n="170" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Heavenly brideship" TEIform="index"/>THE HEAVENLY BRIDESHIP</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Eads, H. L." TEIform="persName"/>H. L. EADS</byline><p TEIform="p"> There are two very important things which every true follower of Christ in the Second
                            Appearing must ever appear very sacredly to conserve, among many others. 1st. The pure
                            unalloyed testimony of the Gospel of Christ's second appearing in the line of the female,
                            2d. The-pure union of the spirit of Christ among Gospel Kindred— true Brethren and Sisters
                            of the family of Christ — the writer's life interest is bound up in both. In the interest of
                            the first we would remark, that, as the writer understands the following quotation from an
                            article in the July Manifesto, it seems to us to controvert a vital principle of the Shaker
                            Religion. Thus: "The marriage of the Lamb and Bride means a union of the Law and Gospel,
                            this, and nothing more." " Certainly it was not the marriage " (spiritually of course, and
                            in no other sense), " of Jesus and Ann according to our first childish thoughts." Now, in
                            the name of our suffering, bloodsweating, tortured, crucified and God-chosen Father of the
                            New Creation, Jesus Christ, and in the name of our imprisoned, tortured, much abused,
                            suffering, and Godchosen Mother Ann Christ, and in the name of the bleeding hearts of their
                            faithful children we must protest against this denial, before the world, of the long
                            prophesied of and Heaven-born truth, that the scriptural "Lamb and Bride" are persons as
                            vicegerents of God, and not things. The Churches that embodied and still conserve their life
                            baptism may be considered, figuratively, in the same sense. It is our ineradicable faith and
                            understanding that Jesus and Ann were the chosen ones, as vicegerents of God, to inaugurate
                            the Gospel plan of Christ's First and Second Appearing to save and redeem a sin-stricken
                            world. This testimony we believe can be maintained in the face of all the prophecy of the
                            world. Let us reconsider the assertion that " the Lamb and Bride is nothing but the union of
                            the Law and Gospel." That is to say, the marriage of the Law and Gospel. Thus to speak : The
                            Law would be the Lamb, or Bridegroom, and the Gospel the Bride ! The Law masculine, the
                            Gospel feminine. Thus making the Gospel subordinate to the law ; the spirit, to the flesh.
                            "Because the law was weak, through the flesh." Exactly to this does that argument lead. To
                            our understanding it cannot be tortured to a different conclusion. Now, if that which was
                            declared to be " weak, through the flesh," is superior to the Gospel, what hope is there to
                            be redeemed from the flesh ? None whatever ! But it is not true. The cheering voice of the
                            Bridegroom rings out, and above a deathstricken world. "Little children, be of good cheer, I
                            have overcome the world." This was the voice, not of the Law, but of the Bridegroom, and the
                            voice of the? Bride was like unto it. Their united voice is, "My sheep do hear my voice, not
                            the voice of the typical law. And they follow us. To follow one is to follow the other, for
                            all their work, testimony and life are one. Come unto us, all ye ends of the earth and be
                            saved. Although they come slowly, yet will they come, for the testimony and spiritual
                            baptism of the Bridegroom and Bride is all the hope for the redemption of a lost and ruined
                            world. To quote further from the article under consideration it is stated, " Unless we do
                            right about food, generation and property, there is no use multiplying words about sal
                            vation in this world, or any other." The way to do right about food is to govern the
                            appetite, not to eat too much of any thing, this was Christ's doctrine, which can't be
                            improved; some people make themselves as sick in eating buckwheat cakes and molasses, as
                            others do in eating oysters. The way for the followers of Christ to do right about
                            generation is to let it entirely alone, not soil our bodies nor our spirits therewith, but
                            leave its whole management with the lower floor generators. We anticipate this is what the
                            writer from whose article we quote meant, but we fear it would not thus be generally
                            understood. South Union, Ky.</p></div2><pb n="171" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good time coming" TEIform="index"/>THE GOOD TIME COMING</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="White, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>ANNA WHITE</byline><p TEIform="p"> There are few in existence, comparatively speaking, who have failed to catch this sound as
                            it reverberates from the smoldering ashes of past centuries. Ancient seers with extended
                            vision caught glimpses of it. Prophets and propketeses—rife with inspiration — proclaimed
                            its near approach. Poets in rytlmiical measure wrote and sung: "Of a time and a holy way,
                            Where the unclean foot shall never tread, But from it the lowly shall not stray, To it the
                            penitent shall be led. No lion shall rouse him from his lair, No wild beast raven in foaming
                            rage ; But the redeemed of earth shall there Pursue their peaceful pilgrimage. The ransomed
                            of God shall return to him With a chorus of joy to an angel's lay ; With a tear of grief
                            shall no eye be dim, For sorrow and sighing shall flee away." All that is inherent in the
                            human heart, that tends to uplift and elevate it from inferior conditions, and points to a
                            higher and better life — something still beyond that has not yet been attained — is
                            God-given. Even though the goal of anticipation is not reached, still the effort remains for
                            succeeding generations. As the " iniquities of the fathers are visited upon the children,"
                            in the natural order, so does the baptism and inspiration of the prophets and sages of one
                            dispensation rest upon another. Each dispensation derives benefit from the preceding one.
                            One is as essential to the other as are the rudiments 01 education to the scholar. In
                            alphabetical precision knowledge is acquired, neglect the fundamental principles of it and
                            we get the result. Had the inspired prophets of past centuries lived to witness the
                            fulfillment of their predictions—even to the degree that has been already attained—they
                            would probably have felt that their hopes, desires and prayers had been met and answered in
                            a large measure ; and in joyful accents, from the fulness of their hearts would be heard to
                            say: " It is enough fur us; the good time lias come; our work is finished ; Lord let thy
                            servants rest in peace !" Angels would respond amen. True, the present generation of workers
                            in the many fields of labor opened before them can see much more to be done before the good
                            time which has been and is promised shall have been reached, and they continue to break the
                            fallow ground, and sow the seed, perhaps for other hands to reap. " One sows and another
                            reaps." We sing of our fathers and mothers who have preceded us, " We reap where they have
                            sown, and the harvest fields have grown, and the fruits of faith and righteousness appear;"
                            still the law and order that regulated them in their intercourse with each other would be
                            thraldom to the liberty-loving people of our day, who incline to rush forward with a wild
                            enthusiasm that soon comes to a terminus, and retrogression is sure to follow. In this
                            respect we must not be children, but men and women of God who work and wait patiently, with
                            that sweet confiding trust, so prominent in those of the early Christian church. To indorse
                            all of the fundamental principles of Christianity and abide by them does not infer that we
                            of the nineteenth century have not a work to do as well as our predecessors; far from it. "
                            Of the increase of his government and peace, to order and to establish it with judgment and
                            with justice, there shall be no end." As we partake of, and enjoy the fulfillment of many of
                            the prophesies — " of the lutter day of liberty and peace, of freedom of conscience and the
                            rights of man"—we too must increase and advance, as the light is revealed, and the way made
                            manifest; our righteousness should exceed their righteousness. Admitting as we do, that a
                            bright morn has dawned upon us — that the Son and Daughter of Righteousness have arisen
                            "with healing in their wings," and that to many the good time has already come — yet do we
                            look forward to the better time coming, when all the nations of the earth shall learn she
                            cause of war and bloodshed, when the land shall be free to homeless millions, and where
                            neither rich or poor, black or white, bond or free exist, and the knowledge of the 171 <pb n="172" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 172 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. Lord shall cover the earth as the waters
                            cover the sea; then shall we arrive at the acme of the highest aspirations and hopes that we
                            then possessed, but when attained, heights above will loom up to our vision, showing that
                            eternal progress must mark the course of mortals through successive generations. Mi.
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Who are true spiritualists?" TEIform="index"/>WHO ARE TRUE SPIRITUALISTS?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Byrdsall, Charlotte" TEIform="persName"/>CHARLOTTE BYRDSALL</byline><p TEIform="p"> Through faith in the immortal laws that govern our existence we are spiritualists. Salvation
                            consists, or is dependent upon, the relation that human beings bear to the spirit and matter
                            that constitute life. The most important and exalting law of our being is summed up in few
                            words, "Be true to thyself." Let nothing obstruct or hinder the powers that would unfold
                            industry, true cultivation, religion, revelation, and science, for upon the unfoldment of
                            these depend our destiny. By a willingness to accept scientific truth, the physical and
                            moral laws and principles upon which life is built, and by which it is sustained, we form
                            the basic foundation of a true understanding how to advance in wisdom until in the ever
                            unfoldment of spiritual and eternal truth we intuitively comprehend the divine, and
                            inbreathe and outbreathe the faith, the love and genuine religion, which bind humanity in
                            the golden cords of jastice, mercy and peace, and unites the lower to the higher by
                            successive degrees ; and in return, the knowledge of the goodness of God is transmitted
                            through spirit unto spirit, from spirit unto mortal, and from mortal unto mortal. Science
                            and religion are brother and sister, and point upward to infinitude, the father and the
                            mother, God. The object of science is to attain the bounds of all righteous presents, and of
                            religion not merely to symbolize but to actualize that attainment by bringing into existence
                            a true brotherhood and sisterhood. If innate faith in the Divine be stifled in the human
                            heart, then the soul is fettered ; truth is bound, and reason in a measure is dethroned;
                            happiness diminished and inspiration is checked by ignorance, and we are ruled by the senses
                            instead of being guided by the higher aspirations of the mind which reach toward the eternal
                            progress of truth. By a proper use of spiritualism we may acquire a relation to the forces
                            and changes of the universe, which afford the material that enshrouds our spirits. If we
                            avail ourselves of a knowledge of a future life, which blind creeds, bigotry, and dogmatism
                            cannot change, the balance of existence is ours. Only as'we harmonize with the elements of
                            growth can we be adapted to the modes and means which simply and truly embody spiritualism.
                            Human beings are greater than circumstances. As we love aright, we learn to live aright, and
                            to mount the ladder of truth whose every round reveals some noble thought, some high and
                            lofty aim, and we learn that spiritualism does not consist of some phenomenal wonder, but of
                            the development of the indwelling, God-implanted germ in the hearts of manhood which will be
                            a key to the chambers of human souls, and reveal true character. It will be a health
                            restorer, by imparting the knowledge how we should live to avoid disease, and the proper
                            medicine to be used, and show the real utility of life in mortal form, and its continuance
                            in a future state of existence. In seeking this valuable knowledge we must not lose sight of
                            individual responsibility, nor embrace the idea that we may be safe in remaining in a
                            mediumistic state of mere passivity to unseen forces. There is work for all to perform. We
                            cannot justly claim to be true spiritualists while subject to a halting, doubting, wavering
                            spirit in regard to the influx of spirit life and power by agencies which Divine wisdom
                            employs to minister to our needs. Spiritualists, who are worthy to bear the name, should be
                            guileless, ready to grasp the Christ-principles, irrespective of persons ; to call home the
                            erring, uplift the fallen, and unite with spirit voices that call, " Come up higher." Woman
                            must act well her part and use her God-given powers to expand, <pb n="173" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            SHAKBE MANIFESTO. 173 beautify and immortalize existence, and to blend and unite human
                            hearts and teach them to walk in the illumined pathway that leads to realms of peace. "
                            There are, who like the Seer of old, Can see the helpers God has sent; And how life's rugged
                            mountain side Is white with many an angel tent." Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Love's endurance" TEIform="index"/>LOVE'S ENDURANCE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Schultz, Maria L." TEIform="persName"/>MARIA L. SCHULTZ</byline><p TEIform="p"> Trial makes us brave and strong, Suffering makes us stronger; Faith endures the trial long,
                            Love the suffering longer. Ills which 'tis our lot to share, Faith will kindly help us bear,
                            But the ills we cannot cure, Love will help us to endure. Death hath agonies its own, Life
                            hath sorrows greater ; Miseries which sin alone Is the chief creator. We can bear them, if
                            we will Faith will kindly help us still; But the pains we cannot cure, Love will help us to
                            endure. Human hearts go down the way, Pausing, but to borrow Wisdom from their grief to-day,
                            Comfort for their sorrow. Disappointment, trouble, care, Faith hath kindly helped them bear,
                            But the griefs they could1 not cure, Love hath helped them to endure. Be for worthiness —
                            our prayer — Of such sweet assurance ; God be praised for faith to bear, Praised for love's
                            endurance. God forbid that doubt of heart Ever should bid faith depart ; Thus the ills which
                            have no cure, Love will help us to endure. Canaan, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Covenant by sacrifice" TEIform="index"/>COVENANT BY SACRIFICE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/>ANTOINETTE DOOLITTLE</byline><p TEIform="p"> What is the Christian's cross, and sacrifice, and what the reward ? Truth is a unit,
                            absolute and indivisible, and always seeks to gather into one. Error, its opposite, leads to
                            inharmony, and tends to individualize, scatter and divide. The prophets in ancient Israel,
                            when imbued with the Christ-spirit which had come down through the ages, cried, " Gather my
                            saints together, they who have made a covenant with me by sacrifice." Men and women, while
                            in a natural, unregenerate state, are selfish in their loves, divided in their interests,
                            and each, according to their capacity, seeks his or her gain from their quarter, and neglect
                            to seek their neighbor's wealth. This narrow, selfish spirit in human hearts has been the
                            great barrier in the way of spiritual progress ; and it has stifled the voice and killed the
                            prophets, and stoned the loving messengers sent of God to gather them under the wings of
                            Divine protection, even "as a hen would gather her brood under her wings ; " which could not
                            be done, except through sacrifice of individual interests and selfish loves ; else, there
                            would be no cohesion nor power of attraction to bind and hold together. Thus the good spirit
                            through the prophets grievously added, "But ye would not." Why? Because of the cross, the
                            sacrifice called for, that was, and is, a rock of offense, over which multitudes stumble !
                            God, who is long suffering and abundant in goodness and truth, waits for the ripening of the
                            golden grain, and continues to point to a harvest, a time of reaping and gathering the
                            fruits of the seeds which the martyrs, seers and sages have sown in tribulation and tears,
                            while they mourned over the degeneracy of the race in their time. Still, those faithful
                            servants of God were inspired with faith and hope, and toiled on, trusting that in His own
                            good time He would fulfill all His promises. Great principles have been at work, rolling
                            onward the car of progress, through various instrumentalities ; and as civilization goes on,
                            and light increases, those principles are more apparent, and claim the attention of deep
                            thinking men and women more and more. All must admit that within the three last decades more
                            has been accomplished in natural art and science than in the preceding half century. Great
                            moral principles come in for their full share. Those noble souls who enlisted in the cause
                            of the down-trod- <pb n="174" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 174 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. den African, who toiled
                            with little to encourage and much to oppose, and hoped as it were against hope, nerved
                            themselves for the conflict, and struggled on. God was with them, and they triumphed. Are
                            not their sufferings, their prayers and deeds recorded where they will not be effaced ? The
                            wheels are moving. The denunciators of war are becoming more numerous, and they protest
                            against it, not only as being unchristian, but as inhuman also, and are making great efforts
                            to convince the civil leaders of nations and kingdoms that it would be far better to call
                            home their war ships, destroy their navies, disband their armies, and let all the
                            blood-thirsty and blood-shedding warriors engage in some honest, honorable and peaceful
                            employment, and learn to settle all vexed and knotty questions and difficulties by the
                            reasoning powers, which is God's throne in man and woman, in lieu of carnal weapons. This
                            cannot be effected without great individual sacrifice of opinion as well as love of power
                            and authority. No true principle will ever be maintained and brought to a successful issue,
                            except by selfsacrifice and diligent exertion. Millions of people at the present time feel
                            that intemperance is a direful curse which threatens to deluge the land; that it is the
                            source, or seductive incitation, to sensuality, murder, and every crime that demoralizes and
                            sinks humanity below the brute creation. The question arises : Can the opponents of war, of
                            intemperance, and all the great evils which exist under different names, work the most
                            successfully, and conquer those wrongs in human society the most effectively, by working
                            within certain limits, each in a different field, or by concentrating their forces and
                            working in harmonious relations together ? Strong efforts have been put forth within the
                            last century to form Communistic societies upon the basis of temporal economy and social
                            advantages without the sacrifice of natural loves and selfish interests, which make especial
                            provision for me and mine. All efforts hitherto made to organize upon that basis have proved
                            abortive. When will human beings \ progress to a condition that love to God and love to man
                            shall take precedence and rise superior to all other loves, and form communities upon a
                            religious basis so deep and broad that it will embrace and enfold all that is good and true,
                            physical, moral and spiritual ? We need not question the possibility of such an attainment.
                            The pentecostal church, founded in apostolic days, is our witness. Let us examine the
                            foundation of that noble structure, which arose in such perfection of beauty that it has
                            claimed the attention and admiration of myriads of thinking people from that age to this.
                            The underlying principles were a virgin life, non-resistance, and community of interests in
                            all things pertaining to body and soul. The maintenance of those principles could not be
                            effected except by great individual sacrifice. Nor were they able to make that sacrifice
                            until, like Jesus, they were baptized with the Holy Spirit, and received spiritual power
                            from the unseen world. Virgin purity was the rock upon which that organization rested ; and
                            while they strictly maintained their testimony in regard to that principle, and kept it
                            inviolate, they prospered, but when they listened to the siren song which the deceptive
                            spirit that the gods and goddesses of carnal pleasure began to sing in their ears, little by
                            little they lost their spiritual power, and went back to their former condition of servitude
                            in the generative, order, marrying and being given in marriage, and of making provision for
                            the flesh, forming selfish relations which involved the necessity of private individual
                            property, and they were scattered and no longer recognized as a " peculiar people," worthy
                            of God's especial notice and care. Principles do not change, "like causes will produce like
                            effects." The true Christ-spirit always seeks to gather into one. False christs and prophets
                            are seductive, and seek to divide and scatter. They cry, " Lo here and lo there !" and point
                            to the deserts and to the secret chambers. They who heed and follow that voice are unwise.
                            Where the truth, the body, or " the carcase is," there will God direct His angels to gather
                            His elect. We are not able to see how one principle upon which the primitive pentecostal
                            church was <pb n="175" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 175 founded could with safety have
                            been omitted, nor even one timber from the superstructure. SAakers, or believers in Christ's
                            second coming, by a baptism of the same spirit, have been led and directed to found an
                            institution upon the same principles that the first Christian church rested upon; that is,
                            virgin life, non-resistance, community of property, with the addition of a dual government,
                            where the rights of woman are recognized, and the " counsel of peace " is between the male
                            and female ; and this institution seeks to gather all that is good and true to its embraces
                            ; but it requires a sacrifice of all. It is a priceless pearl if obtained. That is the
                            reward ! If the Shakers ever lay down their testimony in regard to the principle of a
                            celibate life, so soon will they leaven back into the spirit and element of the world, and
                            disintegration will follow as a sequence ! The system of ideas and principles that have held
                            believers together for a century, if faithfully maintained, will bear them on and prosper
                            them spiritually and temporally through the centuries yet to come. There is room within
                            Zion's boundary lines for all the progress that increasing light may call for, upon the
                            basis of more cross, and denial to the pleadings of the carnal mind; but we need to be very
                            careful not to heed every call for change, and name it progress, when in reality it is a
                            spirit of innovation seeking to weaken instead of strengthening Zion's bulwarks. It is
                            always safe to try the spirits who come to minister unto us. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beards vs. shaving" TEIform="index"/>BEARDS VS SHAVING</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Eads, H. L." TEIform="persName"/>H. L. EADS</byline><p TEIform="p"> " Colloquy between an inquirer and a Shaker :" I.— Please, sir, tell me why the Shakers take
                            off their beards ? Have they any religious scruples about wearing it ? S. — None at all -¦—
                            the subject has nothing at all to do with our religion, only so far as shaving is conducive
                            to cleanliness and uniformity. A man might wear a beard and be a better man than another who
                            did not, and " vice versa." I.— But did not God give the beard to man for a wise purpose ?
                            And, if so, how dare you mutilate what God has given? S.— If God gave the beard for a
                            purpose He also gave the hair and finger and toenails in like manner ; but this is no reason
                            why we should not trim them. And we would ask : Why should the hair on the face be more
                            sacred than the hair on the head? and, we see you hesitate not to cut that closely this hot
                            weather. I.— Well, I presume God allows us to be comfortable; but there is this difference.
                            Physiologists tell us the beard is a necessity, and is conducive to health of body, as every
                            hair is a hollow tube, and, if worn uncut, it prevents the escape of electricity, which is
                            essential to the brain and nervous system. S.— Admitting the testimony of Physiologists to
                            be true, would not the argument apply to cutting off the hair from other portions of the
                            head, as well as the hair of the face, particularly on the nape of the neck, at the head of
                            the spinal column, where the system is extremely sensitive to change of temperature ? Again
                            it is, perhaps, as possible that electricity escapes as easily if not more so, from a
                            clipped beard, than from a smoothly shaven face. Thus the health argument is, at least, much
                            frustrated. Now, permit us to ask you why you take off a part of yours, since you seem so
                            sensitive relative to the gifts of God ? I.— I take off a part for decency's sake, as one's
                            delicacy is sometimes insulted by dining with a man who wears such a mustache that it must
                            be lifted with one hand while putting food to his mouth with the other. S.— Very true the
                            habits of some beard wearers are truly disgusting, and render a good reason for shaving. Now
                            allow me to ask you a question, which please answer unequivocatingly. If, as you admit, it
                            is more decent to remove a part of the beard (all religion aside), is it not most decent to
                            remove it all ? I.— Yes, sir, it is, and, on that ground alone, it would appear to be
                            justifiable, except where diseased eyes, or throat, or sore <pb n="176" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 176 THE
                            SHAKER MANIFESTO. faces from cutaneous diseases, or scrofulous tumors would require the
                            wearing of the beard from necessity S.— In such cases it would appear most proper to wear
                            the beard, but not for mere fashion's sake. I.—¦ But, says the worldly motto, "A man may as
                            well be out of the world as out of the fashion." S3.— But who is authorized to institute
                            fashion. The only justifiable and true basi of fashion is that which is really best adapted
                            to the needs of life, the preservation of virtue, and the elevation of humanity to that
                            which is most useful, true, pure and beautiful. South Union, Ky.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Perfect whole" TEIform="index"/>A PERFECT WHOLE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="De Veyr, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/>CECELIA DE VEYR</byline><p TEIform="p"> What can we spare from the Gospel, The gift of eternal life ? Can we spare the lovely gem of
                            peace, And take the thorns of strife ? Can we spare the equal rim of gold, On which the eems
                            are set, Then seek to claim, to grasp, and hold Whatever we can get, And from the love of
                            God to all That shields us round about ? What order, either great or small. Can safely be
                            left out ? The Gospel is a perfect whole, However it may come, And blest and happy is the
                            soul That takes its teachings home. The father and the mother love, And mighty burning
                            flame, Are inspirations from above, The source and end the same ; They come to teach our
                            souls to make A sacrifice of sin ; They come our spirits to awake — The precious pearl to
                            wiu. The pearl of virgin purity, The fadeless, priceless gem, The anchor of security, The
                            star and diadem ! We cannot gain it, till we stake The life to nature clear; And hearts, the
                            sacrifice that make, How glorious they appear! The shining angels "blessings bring That fall
                            like gentle dew, For every good and holy thing Is given to the true. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y".</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Earnestness" TEIform="index"/>EARNESTNESS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>MARTHA J. ANDERSON</byline><p TEIform="p"> Life's inspiration lies in earnestness. The man or woman who would prove successful in any
                            undertaking must be thoroughly in earnest; cold indifference accomplishes nothing. The lamp
                            of genius burns only as it is supplied by the oil of enthusiasm. It is fuel that feeds the
                            unquenchable fires which set the world aglow with the light of knowledge, and scatters the
                            gifts of brain and hand in rich profusion over the earth. It is the impulse of civilization
                            that overcomes every obstacle that would hinder its triumphal march over sea and land. In
                            every department of life we see its grand results. It shines in truthful pictures on the
                            canvas: speaks in sculptured forms of grace and beauty; glows in immortal poetry and song ;
                            appeals to hearts through words of inspired wisdom and truth; and molds organizations for
                            broad philanthropic labor in all fields of reform. It is the breath of religion, the soul of
                            science, and the tireless spirit of practical skill and industry . The effective work of
                            ardent purpose ever transforms the ideal into the substan tial and real, and gives to
                            mankind increasing strength of intellect and character that progresses them above gross,
                            animal planes of existence, into spheres where mental and spiritual pleasures supersede
                            natural intinctive qualities. The herculean shoulder of earnest endeavor placed at the car
                            of human progress often lifts it from olden ruts and miry sloughs — that clog its onward
                            course — and starts it forward on the highway of truth and freedom. " All earnestness is
                            magnetic." Its plea has been heard from the pulpit, the forum and the hearth-stone, in
                            behalf of religion, ustice and social equality. The world feels its impulse and is moved to
                            loftier purposes, and higher aims in the harmonial developnent and blending of human forces,
                            in things physical, mental and spiritual. We live in a time of elemental agitation ; <pb n="177" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 177 the Divine Energy of life runs through
                            every fibre of being. Earnestness, the motive power, and ceaseless activity of mind and
                            muscle accomplishes wonders. And though we see great evils existing, which we deplore and
                            deprecate, still the triumphs and consummation of great and good plans, aided forward by the
                            indefatigable zeal of the workers for truth and right, give us hope, courage and faith, that
                            the destinies of mankind are in the hands of the Allwise Father and Mother; and with
                            confidence and trust, we offer a heartfelt prayer, that the heavenly powers may inspire us
                            with earnestness of feeling, and a spirit of consecration and devotion to the cause we have
                            espoused ; that our lives may embody the principles of the living dispensation of truth. And
                            that our light may so shine abroad, that souls, hungering and thirsting for righteousness,
                            may seek and find within our borders rthe resurrection life and power of Christ-, that shall
                            lift them into diviner spheres of angelic love, light and purity.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lines suggested from seeing three flower beds, kept by our three little girls" TEIform="index"/>LINES SUGGESTED FROM SEEING THREE FLOWER BEDS, KEPT BY OUR THREE LITTLE GIRLS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stephens, Annie" TEIform="persName"/>ANNIE STEPHENS</byline><p TEIform="p"> Three little mounds lay side by side, Kept free from weed and tare ; I'd passed them often
                            on my way, Nor gave them thought or care, But now, they seemed to speak to me, And my
                            attention drew; They spoke in silent whisperings, Of things both old and new. They told me
                            when the skies were blue, And birds began to sing, Some little hands went forth to sow
                            Flower seeds in the spring. They planted balsams, pink, and red, And violets white and blue;
                            And many sweet and lovely flowers Of every name and hue. The dews came down at eventide, And
                            nurtured them by night; And solar beams upon them shone, To give them warmth and light, Till
                            they began to peep above Their darksome prison earth; O! the wondrous latent powers That
                            give creation brith! Still on they grew — for grow they must • Till embyro buds were seen;
                            Then blossoms followed, one by one, To rival with the queen. And there they lived, to bud,
                            and bloom, And yet to fade away; Ah! are they not the emblems true Of life's fair passing
                            day ? Childhood and youth are vanity; They pass too soon we find; But plants eternal, bloom
                            within The garden of the mind. For truth can grow within the heart, And purity bloom there;
                            Sweet love, and charity and peace, Are flowers of fragrance rare. O let these plants be
                            watered well, By dew drops from on high ; That they may bloom in loveliness, And never,
                            never die. For all that's pure and beautiful, From virtue ever springs ; And linked with all
                            that's dutiful We'll think upon 'these things. Mt. Lebanon.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Inward monitor" TEIform="index"/>INWARD MONITOR</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Van Houten, Catharine" TEIform="persName"/>CATHARINE VAN HOUTEN</byline><p TEIform="p"> Is there not placed in thy heart A monitor to teach thee? Doth not God's free love impart A
                            spirit pure, to reach thee ? Beams there not from heaven, light, To guide thy footsteps ?
                            truly ! Cans't thou then not judge aright, And balance all things duly ? Judging, first,
                            thyself in wrong, Will not thy heart feel sorrow ? May there not to thee belong, Much more
                            than thou woulds't borrow? Wisdom bids thee to come down, In owning up thy error; How cans't
                            thou wear, Truth's bright crown, Whilst wrong keeps thee in terror ? Mercy to thy neighbor
                            give, Though erring still thy brother; Does he wrong; forgive, forgive, And strive to love
                            each other; Keep ye judgment, Justice do, For'time is short, and fleeting; Soon we'll bid
                            the earth adieu, Iu heaven be next our meeting. Mt. Lebanon.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What an amulet to draw down the blessings of Heaven upon a soul..." TEIform="index"/>What an amulet to draw down the blessings of Heaven upon a soul...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., G. B." TEIform="persName"/>G. B. A.</byline><p TEIform="p">What an amulet to draw down the blessings of Heaven upon a soul, who, in truth can say, 0
                            Lord, the soul thou gavest me is clean ! </p></div2><pb n="178" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bury me on my feet" TEIform="index"/>BURY ME ON MY FEET</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sproat, Granville T." TEIform="persName"/>GRANVILLE T. SPROAT</byline><p TEIform="p">The last words of Me-tah-win-a-view. Metahwinaview was a chief among the Meuomonces. He lived
                            an upright, honest life. His word could ever be relied upon. As he said, "the Great Spirit
                            gives us but one tongue, and that cannot tell the truth and lies also.'1 As the shadow of
                            death began to fall athwart his way, his heart fearlessly faced the unknown future ; and in
                            the conversation, he expressed no fear of meeting the Great Spirit, in whose existence he
                            firmly believed. He requested the Indian Agent to " bury him on his feet" (a symbol of his
                            soul's progression), andjto see that " no dirt was put upon his head" (a symbol of his
                            purity). The first request could not be granted ; but the promise was made that no dirt
                            should be put upon his coffin. The funeral of the old man was simple, but strange and weird.
                            After the tribe had assembled at his home, remarks were made, and prayer ofiered to the
                            Great Spirit by one of his old comrades, who asked that in his journey to the happy Hunting
                            Grounds, a messenger might be sent from the other land to show him the way. Then a
                            procession was formed, and with wild chants, he was carried to the brow of a hill in the
                            forest, and In a lonely place, left for his final rest. In acccordance with the promise made
                            him, a shallow grave was dug just large enough to receive the air-tight coffin, on which no
                            earth was placed. Over this was built a little house, which was inclosed in a larger one.
                            His companions placed by his side a hand mirror, a comb, and other articles, with rice and
                            pounded corn, that he might journey in comfort toward the Land of Souls ; and then a prayer
                            was offered, again entreating the Great Spirit to send a messenger to meet him on the way. A
                            brother chieftain, for whom a little shelter had been built, close by the grave, remained
                            there alone for three days and three nights, to keep him company, ere he should depart on
                            his long and perilous journey, over the spirit prairie, and river, to the Country of Souls.
                            Bury me on my feet, Beneath the linden tree ! Boldly my spirit would pass on, To the Country
                            of the Free. Boldly as when I tracked The red wolf to his den ; And chased the buffalo and
                            deer, O'er mountain, moor and glen. Heap up no mound of earth, No dust upon my head, To tell
                            the wondering passers by I slumber with the dead. Not dead! there is no death, No slumber to
                            the Brave ! The good shall triumph over death, And live beyond the grave. Bury me on my feet
                            ! Still onward would I go — Onward, still onward, as I walked While journeying here below. I
                            walked no crooked ways; I scorned Deceit and Wrong; I set a seal upon my lips, A bridle on
                            my tongue. Bury me on my feet ! Wail out no dirge for me, I go to Him from whom I came — The
                            Great, the Good, the Free ! Sing your triumphant songs, Till the forests ring afar, I go, as
                            chieftain never went, With all the spoils of war. Bury me on my feet, That all who pass may
                            say, " Straight as his arrow flew, his soul Is marching on its way. He walked the trail of
                            Truth ; His feet no fetters knew ; His soul is marching on, to join The Faithful, Just and
                            True ! " Canaan, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Copy of a letter" TEIform="index"/>COPY OF A LETTER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>GILES B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p">To the Editor of a Country Paper, bearing date January 6, 1880. Mt. Lebanon, Columbia Co., N.
                            Y. D. H. Talbot: Esteemed Friend. — In your issue of December, 1879, in your leading
                            article, dwelling on the Mormons of Utah, and thence proceeding to refer them to what you
                            term " the Example of the Shaker Community of New York State," we see you made a sorrowful
                            mistake, calculated to entirely misinform your readers relative to the true character of the
                            Shaker Community. Of <pb n="179" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 179 course we understand
                            the same to have been done ignorantly and unsuspectingly. You referred to the " Oneida
                            Community " whose basic principle was complex marriage, and called it a Shaker Community.
                            Now the Shaker Institution is the exact antipode of the Oneida Community, and has been so
                            from its inception. All Shaker Communities hold Virgin Celibacy to be a cardinal principle
                            of Christianity, and neither marry nor are given in marriage, nor do they admit of sexual
                            indulgences of the animal passions in any form, or under any circumstances in the conduct of
                            the members of the Shaker Household of Faith, whether they have joined the Shaker Commune,
                            or live in isolation from it in outside society. The Shakers do '' not forbid to marry " nor
                            " command to abstain from meats" nor do they " constrain to marry," 'Tis true they protest
                            against, and do not use pork, having abundant evidence that its use abundantly contributes
                            to the origin of inflammatory diseases and virulent sores. The Shakers understand marriage
                            to be essentially and exclusively a jvorldly institution ; and, as Jesus declared " My
                            Kingdom is not of this world (or the world), therefore marriage does not belong to the
                            kingdom of Christ. Jesus Christ did not object to marriage per se. He said, " The children
                            of this world " (the world ) " marry, and are given in marriage, but they that are counted
                            worthy to obtain that world " (the Heavenly, the habitation of the "'New Creator in Christ
                            Jesus " whether in this present time, or after they have shuffled off the mortal coil)
                            "neither marry nor are given in marriage, but are " (present tense) " as the Angels of God
                            in Heaven." In following Jesus, the Shakers do not object to marriage, as a worldly
                            institution, but think it, when used in a normal manner, the most fitting social relation
                            for a worldly kingdom, but only when freed from the abuses from the sexual relations which
                            embrute man and degrade woman, and which now extensively, if not almost universally, envelop
                            the marriage relations. We recognize that all persons are not able to become subjects of the
                            kingdom of Christ in this world, but agreeably to the words of Jesus: "Others make
                            themselves eunuchs for the kingdom of Heaven's sake" (not physically, but spiritually and
                            socially considered). Yet, as Jesus further says, ¦' All men cannot receive this saying,
                            save they to whom it is given ; he that is able to receive it, let him." The Shakers
                            understand that the only God-given use of sex is reproduction ; and, had mankind always
                            regarded and obeyed the simple laws of nature relative to sexual relations, generation, for
                            the kingdom of this world, would have been as good, as innocent, as eating or drinking; but
                            even then it would not and could not have satisfied all the longings of undemoralized normal
                            humanity ; because that would have been simply satisfying the demands of the physical body,
                            and man has a soul that as really yearns for its development, evolution and support, as doth
                            the animal body. Hence had man always regarded the laws of God in nature, in regard to the
                            sexual and social relations, when the female had fulfilled the normal age of reproduction,
                            both the man and woman should cease from sexual commerce entirely, and henceforth becoming
                            spiritually excited only, should have thenceforth " taken the kingdom of heaven normally,
                            not by violence," but, as the next step of human evolution in climbing the ladder of human
                            progress which the patriarch Jacob saw in vision, reaching from earth to Heaven* But let it
                            everlastingly be kept before the eyes of the people, and burned into their very soul's
                            escutcheon, that marriage and its legitimate fruit, generation, belongs entirely and
                            exclusively to the worldly order, and has no part nor lot in the kingdom of Christ! Mount
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Little stone" TEIform="index"/>THE LITTLE STONE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Burger, Martha Ann" TEIform="persName"/>MARTHA ANN BURGER</byline><p TEIform="p"> If we may credit sacred history, King Nebuchadnezzar's dream concerning the great image
                            formed of gold, silver, brass, iron, with a mixture of clay, was very sin- <pb n="180" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 180 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. gular in conception and expression, as was also the
                            interpretation thereof by the Hebrew Prophet, Daniel. Although somewhat metaphorical, it was
                            a substantial prophecy of something to be revealed in the then yet future time. Evidently
                            the ruling powers, whether monarchial or ecclesiastical, or both combined, were represented
                            by the head of the image made of gold. The silver, brass, iron and clay symbolized the
                            lesser powers, as we understand it, down to the laboring classes in society, which in
                            reality is the substratum upon which all rests ; the feet upon which the image stood and
                            depended for support. Perhaps there could not have been a grander or more complete
                            representation of the Gentile nations and kingdoms than then existed, than the image as seen
                            in the dream, nor a clearer prophecy of the means which God, in His own time, would use to
                            break in pieces all false systems that men had builded, or might build, that the good, the
                            just and true might be exalted. We see by that wonderful night vision that tioubled the king
                            so much, that many material substances were brought into requisition in forming the image,
                            and found a co-relation, and when fitly conjoined were indispensable parts of one great
                            whole. The Stone, cut from the mountain without the aid of human hands, was evidently a
                            divine revelation of truth emanating from the Christ sphere, with which Jesus of Nazareth
                            became deeply imbued and was divinely inspired. By obedience through suffering he became the
                            servitor of the Christ-spirit, and an especial medium to inaugurate a new Christian
                            dispensation on earth of which he became the leader. In the new dispensation, a spiritual
                            temple was to be erected, of which Christ, through the mediumship of Jesus and others as
                            coworkers, was to be the masterbuilder and head over all. But even the foundation of the
                            temple could not be laid until a place could be found for it to stand upon, by removing and
                            displacing some part of the old structure, or the image that had formerly occupied the
                            ground. The Little Stone of Truth was set in motion to grind and break in pieces the image
                            or institutions formed by the device of men, which undoubtedly contained much good in their
                            day and time, but were gradually to give place to something better. Jesus was the first
                            anointed son in the Christian era, and by self-denial and selfcrucifixion, he was eminently
                            fitted to be. come the corner stone of the Christian temple. He was the pioneer in tne great
                            work and was a " tried stone," as no other one to the same degree could be ; yet every one
                            according to their measure that finds a place in the temple must be baptized with the same
                            baptism and suffer as he suffered. Many stones have been tried, proved and fitted by the
                            masterbuilder, and securely placed in the Christian temple. Although to human observation,
                            the progress has been slow in arranging and placing each stone one by one, in its proper
                            order, it is compact and sure j for the great underlying principles are true, and cannot
                            fail nor be moved. They form a basis solid, deep and broad, and as imperishable as is all
                            truth, that flows from God the eternal Fountain. As man was not created to dwell alone, and
                            is not perfect* in his manhood without his counterpart — woman — it became a necessity that
                            in due time, a female should be found who could also be baptized with the Christ-spirit that
                            Jesus was anointed with, that constituted him the elder of many brethren, that she might
                            find a just relation to him on the plane of virgin purity, and thus manifest the dual order
                            which we think we have reason to believe exists in God, the all Father and Mother, as the
                            first great cause of all causes, and descends through the Christ spheres to intermediate
                            orders of angelic beings in spirit life, down to the earth sphere. Ann Lee, as we believe,
                            was the chosen and prepared instrument, and was not only chosen and appointed, but was found
                            faithful and worthy to form an alliance with the first baptized man Jesus ; and that they
                            now conjointly work together in harmony with the Masterbuilder in preparing and fitting
                            stones into the temple of God on earth, and are ready and willing to assist souls to find an
                            abiding place in the great spiritual tern- <pb n="181" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 181
                            pie in that Holy City, which is lighted with God's truth and is brighter and more glorious
                            than can be comprehended by mortal beings in this terrestrial sphere. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mr. Evans" TEIform="index"/>Mr. Evans</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Philips, George H." TEIform="persName"/>Geo. H. Philips</byline><p TEIform="p"> —I wish to obtain a knowledge of your hygiene and cookery. Shall I trespass too far on
                                your patience if I ask what roots and grains, and meats, if any, are used in your
                                community 1 Do you use pork, or beef, or mutton, or any fine flour, or cider, or
                                tobacco^or spices, saleratus, tea, coffee ? and do your cooks make any pastry ? I would
                                be especially pleased to know just how you prepare for food that great cereal that feeds
                                humanity — wheat. One of the Shaker women stated, from the platform at Lake Pleasant,
                                last August, that she was iinable to procure a proper ~"meal of victuals on the grounds
                                — and I am ready to believe it. Will you, or some Shaker, tell me what a wholesome meal
                                should be composed of, and how to cook it? Respectfully,</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., July 16,1881" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., July 16,1881</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prentiss, Oliver" TEIform="persName"/>Oliver Prentiss</byline><p TEIform="p"> Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., July 16,1881 Geo. H. Philips—By request of Elder Evans, who is
                                otherwise engaged, I respond to your inquiries about Shaker "hygiene and cookery."'
                                Virginity and community are the cardinal planks in the Shaker platform. Something over a
                                century ago, there began to be Shakers. On the start, they were, in meats and drinks,
                                not much unlike the material of which they were composed. Humanity, at that period, had,
                                in general, risen above the cannibal—had left bipeds and gone to devouring quadrupeds,
                                without discrimination. With increased facilities of intercommunication, we have
                                corresponding increased mental expansion. There are now Shaker Societies, one or more,
                                in seven of the States. Societies are composed of families. Each Family is a community.
                                These communities, like Sovereign States, revolve around a common center. Great changes
                                have come over Shakers during my Shaker life — something over 61 years. Sixty-one years
                                ago, we ate pork, beef and all manner of things, drank cider, beer, tea and. coffee,
                                chewed, smoked and snuffed, not much unlike folks in general. The change has been
                                gradual— not by compulsion — in accord with the increased resurrection from the earthy
                                to the heavenly. Most of my Shaker life was at Watervliet, near Albany. I now live in
                                the North Family, Mt. Lebanon, with Elder Evans and some 60 Sisters and Brothers. No
                                meat is eaten by the family, that I know of. We all eat at the same table, at the same
                                time. Graham bread, oat cake, fruits and vegetables, served up most invitingly, are
                                staple commodities. Some drink tea, some coffee, in small quantities. Most drink water
                                only. Cider, beer and tobacco, in all forms, are behind the age. Other Families, T
                                suppose, make corresponding advances. Humanity takes its initiative low down in the
                                scale of being. We are on the ascending grade, with Eternal Progress inscribed on our
                                banner. When the Sun of Righteousness can shine through us, clear as crystal, casting
                                never a shadow on the canvas, we may take rank with the Seraphim and Cherubim of the
                                more ad vanced Heavens. Respectfully,</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Adamsville, June 11, 1881" TEIform="index"/>Adamsville, June 11, 1881</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Barrington, Joseph Warren and Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>Joseph Warren Barrington and
                                F. W. Evans.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Adamsville, June 11, 1881 Respected Friend:—Your note of June 5th is at hand. Am much
                                pleased therewith. Many thanks for the kindness in answering my question. My full
                                consent to publish my letter, if it seems to you good. If published, I'd like a copy. I
                                am looking for light from any and all quarters. Your people surround yourselves with an
                                aura that is good and pure, by not associating with the outside world, which is
                                altogether too material, dealing and believing only in material things. Your humble
                                correspondent comes daily in contact with material and worldly people, and being
                                sensitive, clairvoyant and clairaudiant, senses and sees those wrong conditions that
                                many people are making for themselves. Do we not build up the physical and mental from
                                that which we take to nourish our system ? <pb n="182" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 182 THE SHAKER
                                MANIFESTO. If we use spiritual food, shall we not be spiritual ? If we use earthly food,
                                shall we not be earthly ? And if we use animal food, shall we not be beastly ? This is,
                                as it tome doth appear by coming in contact with people that surround me. The
                                theological inspiration of to-day all comes from the printing press — cast iron theology
                                — how changed from our first teachers — Moses, Confucius, Boodha, Jesus, Swedenborg, Ann
                                Lee and others — would that the time come, when the Christ-spirit shall be resurrected
                                in the churches, that they follow the teachings and example of the humble and spiritual
                                Nazarene, in diet, in dress, in temperance, in finances and in all reforms, both
                                physical and spiritual, that tend to our happiness, in this life and in the life which
                                is to come. The churches are looking for the material man, while the spiritual is in the
                                world and with us. They see not, they hear not the things of the spirit. Should they not
                                heal the sick ? cause the lame to walk ? the deaf to hear ? the blind to see ? prophesy
                                1 interpret ? and even greater things than these ? and by the signs shall they not be
                                known ? We think you hear it, see it, feel it, and live it. The church condemns me as a
                                visionary lunatic. I may be wrong in some things — do not claim infallibility, but am
                                trying to go by the truth as fast and as far as I can see it. Sometimes I have to break
                                away from all society, go to the woods and enjoy nature, yea more, receive the best of
                                visitors. You tell me Heaven is somewhere on earth. Yea, it is within, of whatsoever
                                degree we make it, by indomitable self-control, cultivating the germ of divinity, our
                                birthright inheritance — holding appetites and passions in subordination to the divine
                                overruling. By analysis we find that wheat contains some 14 chemical elements, and the
                                human physiology correspondingly the same, while fine flour contains 68.7 starch and
                                carbon — a pure heater — 3 chemical elements, minus the other 11, or the gluten which
                                corresponds to the albumen, fibrine and gelatine. Through the courtesy of Mr. Q. H.
                                Philips, I learn that your people have brought the culinary art — the selection of food
                                and preparation thereof — to a fine science. Being a sensitive and having to adopt rules
                                different from the people around me, in order to live at all (in the body) I would like
                                to get a little light on how your people prepare their food, and the kinds you use in
                                every-day life, for my own benefit and health. If not asking too much, would like to
                                have you write me whatever you feel disposed to concerning this subject. I eat no meats,
                                and find white flour injurious ; live principally on fruits and cereals ; find it hard
                                to get the whole grain and save the necessary chemical properties contained therein. If
                                you will give me a little light on the choice of food, and the preparation for use, you
                                will confer a great favor. Mr. Philips wishes me to insert a few questions on cooking ;
                                I comply ; they are inclosed; you can act your pleasure concerning them. Yours in
                            truth,</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My dear manifesto" TEIform="index"/>My Dear Manifesto</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt</byline><p TEIform="p">:—I have long contemplated writing to you from a deep sense* of gratitude, for I feel
                                that I owe you much. I have resolved to do so, as you monthly appear at my Zion-home. I
                                cannot withhold my acknowledgment longer with a peaceful conscience. How earnestly I
                                we]-. come your coming; how eagerly I peruse your columns ; how much I find in them 'hat
                                is pure and elevating. Every article contains good instruction. How beautiful you appear
                                in your dress ; the type so clear, the paper so white and firm. I am made better for
                                having communed with the minds that teach through your pages; and in this I only express
                                the sentiments of thousands of others. Accept heartfelt thanks for holding up such a,
                                pure, standard of life, and inspiring me with earnest endeavor toward the right. When
                                writing to distant friends I tell them of your merits. Let me express my appreciation of
                                your untiring efforts in spreading truth and purity; it is labor that all cross-bearers
                                delight in. Twenty years ago I began to follow Christ, and the prize I <pb n="183" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 183 am bound to win. How sweet are the hours I
                                spend in His service. Can I do too much for the cause of purity ? My spirit answers
                                firmly, nay, not half enough, though I toil incessantly. " My thanks to God cannot be
                                told, that I was called into the fold." How .comforting the thought that salvation is
                                free — to all who work for it. "Work out our own salvation." Oh ! dear Manifesto you
                                hold a place in my heart that no other periodical fills. That all who read your pages,
                                clean and pure, may be true Christians, is the prayer of one who desires to be "numbered
                                with the Lord's jewels." Wishing you all success, in gospel love, , Enfield, Ct.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wherefore?" TEIform="index"/>WHEREFORE?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">That the Shakers and their peculiar life should appear novel in a professedly Christian
                                country is entirely in favor of Shaker preeminence, and speaks badly for the simply
                                professed, when comparison and contrast are drawn between Shaker life and ordinary,
                                worldly life, and both compared with the life of the first Christian. We wonder, when
                                people, calling themselves Christian, professing so great admiration for Jesus and His
                                life, yet seeming to and really despising the thought of living like Jesus, and deeming
                                those unworthy of recognition who, at great expense to selfishness, are trying to live
                                like Jesus. We cannot account for the wherefore of so great inconsistency of professedly
                                Christian people. That which we admire, we will strive to be like. How much strife is
                                there on the part of the great body of professors, to he, to live just like the Jesus
                                whom they profess so great admiration for ? Is it unreasonable for Shakers, both to
                                attempt a practical admiration of the Christ, by as exact a following as they are able,
                                and to feel a little censorious toward those who are content with a very distant and un
                                truthful admiration ? Wherefore admiration for the Jesus of old by expression, and
                                almost detestation for any who try to be the Christs of to-day ? Wherefore should Shaker
                                life be a novelty, to those who claim such familiarity with New Testament writings,
                                descriptive of Jesus and his immediate disciples? Our platform simply introduces anew
                                the religion of Jesus, which was -CELIBACY; positive EQUALITY among Christian brethren ;
                                PEACE at expense of every thing else; and unspottedness from every thing worldly. ¦</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Can we afford to suspend?" TEIform="index"/>CAN WE AFFORD TO SUSPEND?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">It may, or it may not, be a serious subject for us to suspend the publication of The
                                Manifesto. When we personally urged its advent, we set the period of its life at ten
                                years. It has lived and flourished longer — flourished in its illustrations of the most
                                preeminent Christian testimony, but has ever been poor in purse. It may not be news to
                                any or many, when we state that there is scarcely a paying religious paper in the world
                                — one that is not sustained by means other than subscriptions! The Shaker, The S. and S.
                                and The Manifesto have been no exception to this assertion. We have not only failed to
                                make a dollar by the enterprise, but have only been able to keep afloat by diligent
                                prudence, and the practical<pb n="184" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 184 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. sympathy of
                                our friends. Our circulation amounts to thousands to be sure; but look at the
                                subscription price; look too at the thousands we gratuitously circulate! It has been
                                mentioned that the entire superintendence of The Manifesto has been only a thankful task
                                — thankful only though, because duty seemed to point that way. It has been the reverse
                                of a sinecure. A few years ago, one of our best ministers in the east was anxious to
                                know how fat the editor of our paper was after the December number was issued ! Upon the
                                rendering to him of our accounts by publisher, he was'so shockingly sympathetic that he
                                sent us ten dollars as a penance! To some, who love dollars more than they love religion
                                or its missions, The Manifesto has seemed to have fulfilled its mission. To others, its
                                suspension is looked upon with dread, for very many reasons. From the former class there
                                has been received only that which has made the labors on The Manifesto a thankless task
                                and any thing but a labor of love. From the latter we have received only that which was
                                comforting, commendable, and cheering — making the simply honorary position of editor a
                                position of love. We have for years wished to retire from its head, simply because its
                                burden, borne by us as it is, is too weighty. We are among those who would that it
                                continue for all time — who believe we cannot afford to suspend. The Manifesto occupies
                                the most unique of fields — no other periodical teaching and demanding such radical
                                Christian life-truths. It is the only missionary we have in the world, and its
                                suspension will, we fear, breed dearth at our homes and distrust among our friends
                                outside, in regard to the permanence of the cause it represents. But let none fear for
                                tb,e cause — let them rather pity those who only pretend to love it, loving themselves
                                in preference. We purpose retiring from the editorial chair. We ask for a successor,
                                unless the body whose faith it. represents determines that we can afford its suspension.
                                So far as personal benefits, ease, emoluments, honors, with much adverse criticisms,
                                none can better afford its supension than Yours truly, The Editok.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorial notes" TEIform="index"/>EDITORIAL NOTES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">A novelty, in top carriages, is the invention of E. Myrick of Harvard Shakers. An
                                ingenious device, to protect the curtains when rolled up. They are placed in a pocket,
                                made by means of the connection between the posts and top of the carriage, requiring no
                                strap nor buckle,and giving a very neat and tidy appearance. It has been shown in
                                Boston, and thought by carriage dealers and others to be a great improvement. It is now
                                at the carriage manufactory of Brigham, McEay &amp; Co., where it can be seen, and
                                by whom it was made, than which there are no better manufacturers of carriages in this
                                vicinity. We understand they are to make one to exhibit in the New England Mechanics'
                                fair. A patent has been applied for and there is a prospect of a revolution in a certain
                                class of top carriages.</p></div3></div2><pb n="185" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>DECEASED</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Parkhurst, Amos" TEIform="index"/>Amos Parkhukst</head><p TEIform="p">At Union Village, 0., June 21, a most estimable man and member; for years a godly
                                    minister, Elder , aged 80 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Witt, Jessie" TEIform="index"/>Jessie Witt</head><p TEIform="p">Also, July 16, , aged about 11 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Snedin, Jemima" TEIform="index"/>Jemima Snedin</head><p TEIform="p">At Hancock, Mass., July 18, , aged 75 years.</p></div4></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our forever memorable friend, Herman Mueller..." TEIform="index"/>Our forever memorable friend, Herman Mueller...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Our forever memorable friend, Herman Mueller, has sent us again, as annually usual, Five
                                Dollars. Still The Manifesto has friends.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>The Children's Grotto</head><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What a mother can do" TEIform="index"/>WHAT A MOTHER CAN DO</head><p TEIform="p">A mother on the green hills of Vermont was holding, by the right hand, a son, sixteen
                                years old, mad with love of the sea. And, as she stood by the garden gate one morning,
                                she said : "Edward, they tell me, for I never saw the ocean, that the great temptation
                                of a seaman's life is drink. Promise me, before you quit your mother's hand, that you
                                will never drink liquor." "And," he said, for he told the story, " I gave the promise,
                                and I went the globe over, to Calcutta and the Mediterranean, Ban Francisco and the Cape
                                of Good Hope, the North and South Poles. I saw them all in forty years, and I never saw
                                a glass filled with sparkling liquor that my mother's form at the gate did not rise up
                                before my eyes, and to-day I am innocent of the taste of liquor." Was not that sweet
                                evidence of the power of a single word ? Yet that is not half. " For," still continued
                                he, "yesterday there came into my counting-room a man forty years old." " Do you know
                                me? " "No." " Well," said he, " I was brought drunk into your presence on ship-board;
                                you were a passenger; they kicked me aside; you took me to your berth and kept me there
                                till 1 slept off my intoxication. You then asked me if I had a mother; I said I had
                                never heard a word from her lips ; you told me of yours at the garden gate; and today I
                                am master of one of the finest ships in New York harbor, and came to ask you to come and
                                see me." The mother's words on the green hills of Vermont! God be thanked for the mighty
                                power of a single word!</p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="No bad habits" TEIform="index"/>NO BAD HABITS</head><p TEIform="p">That the absence of bad habits, such as drinking, using tobacco, and playing games of
                                chance does speak volumes for the success of young men when considered merely from a
                                business standpoint, is clearly illustrated by the following anecdote from a popular
                                daily : " Horace B. Clafflin, the most prominent and wealthy dry goods merchant of New
                                York, was alone in his office one afternoon, when a young man, pale and careworn,
                                timidly knocked and entered. ' Mr. Clafflin,' said he, ' I have been unable to meet
                                certain payments because certain parlies failed to do by me as they agreed to do, and I
                                wTould like to have $10,000. I come to you because you have been a friend to my father,
                                and might be a friend to me.' "'Come in,' said Mr. Clafliin, 'come in and have a glass
                                of wine.' "'No,' said the young man, 'I don't drink.' " ' Have a cigar, then?' " ' No, I
                                never smoke.' "'Well,' said the joker, 'I would like to accommodate you, Lut I don't
                                think I can.' " 'Very well,' said the young man, as he was about to leave the room. ' I
                                thought perhaps you might. Good day, sir.' " 'Hold on,' said Mr. Clafflin, 'you don't
                                drink?' " ' No, sir.' " ' Nor smoke, nor gamble, nor any thing of the kind?' "' No, sir'
                                " ' Well,' said Mr. Clafflin with tears in his eyes, 'you shall have it, and three times
                                the amount if you wish. Your father let me have $5,000 once, and asked me the same
                                questions. No thanks — I owe it to you for your father's sake.'"</p></div3></div2><pb n="186" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True goodness" TEIform="index"/>TRUE GOODNESS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stephens, Annie" TEIform="persName"/>ANNIE STEPHENS</byline><p TEIform="p"> Where shall we find that wealth of soul, True goodness pure and deep, That worketh by the
                            golden rule Its recompense to reap? Not in the soul whose lips would speak In loud and
                            lengthy prayer, Yet feeleth not for others' needs Their sorrow and their care — It glows in
                            smiles of tenderness, In every loving deed; In thrilling tones of sympathy They prove a
                            friend in need. And in the heart, deep rooted there Is its true glory seen ; Shedding a
                            Christ-like radiance, As did the Nazarene. O ever blessed power of gooc, Within my being
                            shine ! And may thy graces lovingly Around my spirit twine. For I would crave the pearls of
                            truth, And purity of heart, To deck my spirit now in youth, And joy to me impart. That mine
                            may be a life made blest By goodness e'er untold; Thus weaving for my spirit form A robe
                            more bright than gold, That dimmeth not by length of years Nor wears by moth nor rust; But
                            brighter grows by deeds well done While in this form of dust. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Are women slaves?" TEIform="index"/>ARE WOMEN SLAVES?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Meriwether, Elizabeth Avery" TEIform="persName"/>Elizabeth Avery Meriwether</byline><p TEIform="p">[Letter to the New York Sun.] The founders of this government called themselves slaves,
                            because they were taxed without representation. Yet the slavery in which they lived under
                            George III was a large and liberal freedom compared with the condition of the women of this
                            country. Under George, the king, our forefathers were free to pursue any profession their
                            intellect or inclination desired. The women of America are debarred the lucrative and
                            honorable professions. Under George, the king, the despot, our forefathers were free to
                            aspire to any office lower than the throne. The women of America may not aspire to the
                            humblest office in the gift of the people. Under George, the king, if accused of any
                            offense, petty or penal, our forefathers were tried by juries of their peers, and sentenced
                            by judges who were only their equals before the law. If accused of any offense, petty or
                            penal, the women of this falsely-called republic are tried by juries of masters and
                            sentenced by judges who are their sovereigns by the accident of sex. When one class of men
                            hold absolute power over another class, as the white men in the South once held over the
                            black, we call the one a master class and the other a slave class. So, when one sex holds
                            absolute rule over the other, as men hold over women, the one is a master sex and the other
                            is a slave sexWe are not only taxed without representation, and governed without our own
                            consent, but from birth to death we labor under such a load of legal disabilities as only
                            abject slaves endure. Doors of learning are closed to our ambition. Offices of honor and
                            profit forbidden. Lucrative professions debarred. In addition to these wrongs, every
                            institution in the land, taking its tone from the law which holds us inferior to the males
                            of our kind, also looks upon us as inferior, thereby overwhelming us with untold and
                            uncounted humiliations and wrongs. The churches consider the best of our sex as unworthy to
                            enter their pulpits ; while the sinful they seem to look upon us as having no part in the
                            plan of salvation. Medicine deems us unfit to practice its therapeutics. Even the mechanical
                            trade of dentistry fancies it may elevate itself among the learned professions by excluding
                            women from its practice. The tribunals of so-called justice forbid women to enter their
                            courts save as criminals to be tried by juries of masters and sentenced by judges who are
                            their sovereigns by the accident of sex. If this is not slavery, what is it? Because some of
                            us have good masters, who give us long ropes, are we any ess in a slave condition? Thousands
                            and thousands of negroes in the old time had good masters, who gave them long ropes; were
                            they any less slaves? <pb n="187" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. 187 Men will not study
                            this question. Sex bias so distorts their judgment, they cannot see straight. About a month
                            ago Gov. Long of Massachusetts made a speech in Boston from a woman's suffrage platform,
                            advocating the cause on the ground of woman's abstract right to suffrage. Gov. Long stated,
                            however, that he brought no enthusiasm to the cause, because he did not see any suffering
                            that came from woman's enslavement, or any good that would come ¦ from her freedom. This was
                            precisely the position of the southern planters in the old time. Many of them admitted the
                            abstract right of all men to freedom, but saw no need in the negro's case, he was so
                            contented and well off under his master's government! Thinking women, who look from effects
                            to causes, see a million evils resultant from slavery. Every wife-beating is directly
                            chargeable to the law, which tells the man that he is the superior, the governor, she the
                            inferior, the subject. Every street walker is directly chargeable to law. Prostitution is an
                            unnatural trade — is directly opposed to the ingrained physical laws that should govern
                            woman. This horrible trade is the outgrowth of the unnatural condition of absolute
                            subjection of women to men. Firmly convinced of this, is it any wonder that women bring to
                            the advocacy of this cause all the enthusiasm of their souls?</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hope on! Hope ever!" TEIform="index"/>HOPE ON! HOPE EVER!</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Field, D. H." TEIform="persName"/>D. H. Field</byline><p TEIform="p">Should we despair e'en though the present Seems the fiercest fight of life ? The future, with
                            its fairest treasures, May crown our efforts in the strife. What if to-day be fraught with
                            sorrow ? Dark and heavier than the past, Brighter may beam the glad to-morrow, With not one
                            cloud to over-cast. Remember, 'tis night's darkest hour That welcomes in the happy morn ;
                            And where the cross seems to be heaviest, The best and richest gifts are born. Let us, then,
                            be up and doing ; Faint not in the glorious strife ; " Onward, onward still pursuing !" Be
                            the watchword of our life. Canaan, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Foolishness of preaching" TEIform="index"/>THE FOOLISHNESS OF PREACHING</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Willett, Edward" TEIform="persName"/>EDWARD WILLETT</byline><p TEIform="p"> Doctors in plenty, doctors of laws and divinity, Each with his satisfied air, in his
                            wellpadded place: Each with his time-worn notions of Godhead and Trinity, Justification by
                            faith, and salvation by grace ! What, after all, is the just and truthful amount of it, All
                            of their arguments, all of their eloquent speech ? What can they show as the issue of all
                            that they preach ? Truly the finger of each, as erect as the steeple is, Pointing to heaven,
                            conveys a continual call: Yet they are over or under the point where the people is, Mostly
                            beyond or behind the great mass of us all. Sins may be checked here and there, the vile and
                            out-breaking ones ; Good men grow better, and evil men sometimes are stirred ; Hearts may be
                            eased by the comfort held out to the aching ones; Life has been purified greatly by
                            preaching the Word. Yet are their labors too often mere weakness and vanity, Soft on the
                            ears of the cultured and satisfied few ; Yet do the hungry and thirsty great droves of
                            humanity Wander afar from the preacher, the choir, and the pew. Eminent doctors! Doctors of
                            laws and divinity ! Where is the spirit of Peter, Apollos and Paul? If, as you say, you are
                            duly ordained by Infinity, Cast in your nets, and give God a miraculous haul! If, as you
                            claim, there is truth in the Word that you preach to us, Think of the years and the days and
                            the moments you lose ! Stand not too high, but humbly come down here and preach to us —
                            Preach to the millions who never find room in your pews ?</p></div2><pb n="188" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Precept and practice" TEIform="index"/>PRECEPT AND PRACTICE</head><p TEIform="p">An ingenious writer has made a good point at the expense of those whose advice is better than
                            their practice,by comparing them to the wood-pigeon, which cries. "Do, do, do," all day, but
                            never does any thing itself. The value of good advice to the hearer does not always depend
                            upon the character or performance of the speaker, but this fact hardly excuses the volunteer
                            counselor for being stone deaf to the wisdom which he dins into the ears of others, nor does
                            it promote the speedy acceptance of his suggestions. After all, people not unreasonably
                            expect a guide to be somewhat familiar with the ground over which he professes to lead
                            others.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Negro prayer" TEIform="index"/>A NEGRO PRAYER</head><p TEIform="p">The following grotesque, yet solemn prayer is a verbatim report, taken in the winter of
                            1862-3, at a public meeting held by plantation negroes in a settlement near camp: " O Lord
                            God of dis glorious universe, wilt dou look down in the omnipresence of dy eye upon dese dy
                            collard children bowed upon de knucklebone dis night. Take a solemn peep upon us, and let a
                            beep o' light in. Dou knowest what dese, dy poor darkies, need. Dere be Sam, dere be Jerry,
                            and dere be Pompey. Dey are in dere sins, dat's what I reckon. Help d'era to git up and git
                            dem from de wilderness of sin, and come into de clearing of salvation. Take a solemn peep,
                            also, upon de darkies in de oder cabin, who fiddle and where de bombastic toe, while dy
                            servant fulminates words to dee. And, bress dy humble servant now supplicating dee in behalf
                            of dese benighted darkies. It behooves dee to dig deep and sound in de very bottom of his
                            heart. May dere be nary blimmage between myself and my Saviour. In de language of de mighty
                            Washington, dis world is a fleetin' show. To-day we are alive and hoppin' round like
                            grasshoppers, to-morrow de sickle of death cuts us down and spreads us out like grass in hay
                            time. On every side dou knowest, 0 Lord, is de evidence of de dislocation and destruction of
                            de human family. Dere be fighting among one anoder and natural disease. But we die to live
                            again, either as saints or evil spirits. Dese discussions 'bout doctrine election before
                            ordination, perfection and such like, confuse de intelligence of both black men and white.
                            Many dere will be with slick countenances, white collars and fine clothes who will find de
                            gates shut against dem, while de blind old woman, hobbling on crutches, she go straight in.
                            Amen."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Preacher's artifice" TEIform="index"/>A PREACHER'S ARTIFICE</head><p TEIform="p">.----------?---------- Frater Roces, the celebrated but eccentric preacher of Naples, once
                            scared his congregation in the most beneficial way. He preached a tremendous sermon on the
                            inevitable consequences of a sinful life. His hearers were in a convulsion of excitement,
                            with the blazing picture of a sulphurous retribution before their imaginations. All at once
                            he stopped in the very midst of an eloquent appeal and cried out: "Now, all of you who
                            sincerely repent of your sins, hold up your hands." Every hand in the assembly went up in an
                            instant. The preacher looked upon the scene for one awful moment, and then, addressing the
                            higher powers, exclaimed: "Holy Archangel Michael, thou who with thine adamantine sword
                            standest at the right of the judgment seat of God, hew me off every hand which has been
                            raised hypocritically." In an instant nearly every hand dropped to its owner's side.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thomas Clarkson says that in the first two centuries when Christianity was the purest..." TEIform="index"/>Thomas Clarkson says that in the first two centuries when Christianity was the purest...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Clarkson, Thomas" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Thomas Clarkson says that in the first two centuries when Christianity was the purest, there
                            were no Christian soldiers on record. The war degeneracy of the church began very early in
                            the third century, and went so far in the fourth, that under Constantine the Great,
                            Christians engaged in war, as they generally have ever since. We do not know how accurate
                            this statement may be ; we cannot challenge it; but we do know that if the spirit of Christ
                            controls both of two men or two nations, they will never go to war with each other.— Golden
                            Censer.</p></div2><pb n="189" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sunshine bread" TEIform="index"/>SUNSHINE BREAD</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Garfield" TEIform="persName"/>Mrs. Garfield</byline><p TEIform="p">An extract from a letter written by to her husband ten years ago is quoted by The Student of
                            Hiram College, into the hands of whose president it accidentally fell: " I am glad," Mrs.
                            Garneld wrote," to tell that, out of all the toil and disappointment of the summer just
                            ended, I have risen up to a victory ; that the silence of thought since you have been away
                            has won for my spirit a triumph. I read something like this the other day : There is no
                            healthy thought without labor, and thought makes the laborer happy. Perhaps this is the way
                            I have been able to climb up higher. It came to me one morning when I was making bread. I
                            said to myself: here I am, compelled by an inevitable necessity to make our bread this
                            summer. Why not consider it a pleasant occupation and make it so by trying to see what
                            perfect bread I can make ? It seemed like an inspiration and the whole of life grew
                            brighter. The very sunshine seemed flowing down through my spirit into the white loaves, and
                            now I believe my table is furnished with better bread than ever before." [Any woman who can
                            write such a letter, having its sentiments originate in her sincere heart is worthy of being
                            the first lady of our nation.—Ed.]</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fashion's wondrous changes" TEIform="index"/>FASHION'S WONDROUS CHANGES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="L., L." TEIform="persName"/>L. L.</byline><p TEIform="p">[From the New York Evening Post.]</p><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New York evening post" TEIform="index"/></bibl><quote TEIform="quote">One thing greatly amused me last season at Saratoga. 1 overheard a lady from New
                                    York describing the dress of a Shakeress, which she declared was too prim and
                                    ridiculous to be seen in. It is wonderful what changes a few short months will bring
                                    in one's opinions, and the style of one's dress, especially of a woman's. To-day
                                    directly in front of me in the meetiug-house sat my Saratoga critic, clad in a dress
                                    which was almost an exact copy of the Shaker garb — a short kilted skirt of just the
                                    heliotrope shade which the sisters wear, and with round waist gathered at the belt,
                                    over which were deftly laid the neat folds of an India mull handkerchief ! She was
                                    actually dressed in the " prim and ridiculous " cos tume over which she had so
                                    recently shrugged her pretty shoulders, and turned up her little aristocratic nose.
                                    But then she did not look like a Shakeress after all, for upon her graceful head was
                                    placed a flower garden and fruit stall, yclept a hat, that in turn would have been
                                    set upon and scoffed at by every right minded Shakeress in the house, and upon her
                                    dainty feet were worn a pair of French heel kid boots, that in contrast with the
                                    flat-bottomed gaiters of the sisters was a shameful frivolity not to be tolerated by
                                    a disciple of Mother Ann Lee. In response to the above, we would say, that if the
                                    present liigh heel is of French origin, it must have been introduced into this
                                    country some time during the last century, for it is the exact shape of the high
                                    heel worn by the Shakeresses from .the start of the Community until about
                                    twenty-five years, ago when it was considered by us as too " ridiculous " and
                                    unphysiological "to be tolerated," thus it has been gradually displaced by the flat
                                    heel, though in buying shoes we are obliged to take them as they are in market,
                                    regretting that we are compelled to return to a fashion long since discarded through
                                    propriety. But as we stand and walch the rotation of Fashion's wheel, observing that
                                    each spoke comes up " over and over again/' we are ready to admit that there is a
                                    little truth after all in the sigh of Solomon of old, " nothing new under the sun."
                                </quote></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to observe fast days" TEIform="index"/>HOW TO OBSERVE FAST DAYS</head><p TEIform="p"> A good old Governor of the State of Maine, when he issued a fast-day proclaination,more than
                            fifty years ago, made up his mind to forego platitudes, and to tell his people just how, in
                            his opinion, they ought to get ready to observe the day. This was his advice : " I recommend
                            to each citizen to observe the day as a Christian ; if he be under the influence of any
                            vice, to banish it; if in error, to correct it ; if under obligations to others, honestly to
                            discharge them; if suffering injuries, to forgive them; if aware of animosities, to
                            extinguish them; and if able to do any benevolent act to any being created by the Almighty
                            Power to which he owes existence and his faculties, to do it."</p></div2><pb n="190" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shout of triumph" TEIform="index"/>SHOUT OF TRIUMPH</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="White, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>Anna White</byline><p TEIform="p"> Mt- Lebanon, N. Y. The sound of distant music, It is the welcome greeting Sing glory
                            halleluia, As from the heavenly spheres, From saints who've gone before, While in this vale
                            below, Is wafted on the breezes, To those who follow after, Tho' storms may rend the
                            mountains, By angel New regions And earthquakes choristers', to explore, overthrow, And O,
                            Yet notes of joy and gladness, happy is the transit, God will hold His chosen, Ru thro' the
                            And glorious In the hollow sweet refrain, the reward, of His hand, And Of And we in feeble
                            accents faithful overcomers, guide them thro' all danger, Re peat them o'er again. The
                            servants of the Lord Un to the promised land. <pb n="191" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO.
                            191 CHORUS. Full. F Sing glory to the righteous glory! glory! And with a shout of triumph
                            Proclaim the ransomed free,</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sensible governor" TEIform="index"/>A SENSIBLE GOVERNOR</head><p TEIform="p">Governor Roberts of Texas, the last to respond to the request to have a day of thanksgiving
                            and jubilee for the recovery of the President, sends the following: "My failure to answer
                            you favorably is not on account of any want of sympathy for thu President, but because I do
                            not deem it consistent with my position as Governor to issue proclamation directing
                            religious services where the Church and State ought to bis KEPT SEPARATE IN THEIR FUNCTIONS.
                            I doubt not that the people of Texas havu as strongly wished and will as devoutly pray for
                            the recovery of the President as any people in the United States."</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is a very common thing for Christians to pray that the Lord will add His blessing to their works..." TEIform="index"/>It is a very common thing for Christians to pray that the Lord will add His blessing to their works...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">It is a very common thing for Christians to pray that the Lord will add His blessing to their
                            works, as if they were ahead and the Lord followed after. A Christian's daily prayer should
                            be, that he may know what the Lord would have him do. A Christian's daily work should be the
                            doing of what the Lord sets him at. There is never any doubt about the blessing, when that
                            order of service is observed.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ices" TEIform="index"/>ICES</head><p TEIform="p">It is a very customary thing to eat ices after dinner ; those whose digestion is not strong
                            should never touch ices, and should avoid them most determinedly. How ever hot the weather
                            may be, a too sudden cooling process injures a weak digestion, and creates a peculiar
                            feeling of weight in the region of the stomach. Ices do not encourage the flow of the
                            gastric juice, but discourage it, and where this flow is already weak it must not be
                            diminished. A great wrong is committed by the constant consumption of iced and very cold
                            beverages in hot weather; instead of really cooling, the reaction creates an irritation
                            which almost amounts to inflammation of the walls of the stomach, and does not allow the
                            natural flow of the secretion, which is necessary for perfect digestion. It is necessary to
                            warn those who suffer from a weakened digestion against very cold foods or drinks, because
                            these bring about a peculiar suffering and diminished vilality. The temperature of the
                            stomach has to be maintained, and any sudden chill is fatal to it.</p></div2><pb n="192" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Early agriculture" TEIform="index"/>EARLY AGRICULTURE</head><p TEIform="p">Hartlib, the friend of Milton, pensioned by Cromwell for his agricultural writings, says,
                            that old men in his days remembered the first gardeners that came over to Surrey, and sold
                            turnips, carrots, parsnips, early peas, and rape which were then great rarities, being
                            imported from Holland. Cherries and hops were first planted, he says, in the reign of Henry
                            VIII; artichokes and currants made their appearance in the time of Elizabeth ; but even at
                            the end of this latter period we had cherries from Flanders ; onions, saffrons, and
                            liquorice from Spain ; and hops from the Low Countries. Potatoes, which were first known in
                            these islands at about the year 1536, continued for nearly a century to be cultivated in
                            gardens as a curious exotic, and furnished a luxury only for tables of the richest persons
                            in the kingdom. It appears in the manuscript account of the household expenses of Queen
                            Anne, wife of James I, that the price of potatoes was then Is. per lb.</p></div2><div2 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Waste of manure" TEIform="index"/>WASTE OF MANURE</head><p TEIform="p">It should be a cardinal principle with every farmer to economize his manure. Upon it depends
                            his success, and without it his labors must, to a very great extent, be without profit if
                            not attended with absolute loss. If it is necessary to have the barnyard on a hillside it is
                            equally necessary to have the lower side of it protected by a wall or some other arrangement
                            by which the escape of liquid manure may be prevented. It is almost equally important to
                            have a spout to convey rain water from the roof of the barn in some other direction than
                            immediately through the barnyard. It is bad enough that the manure heap should be exposed to
                            the rains which fall directly upon it, without adding to it the droppings from the roof of
                            the barn. If such improvident farmers were to behold the actual value of the fertilizing
                            material thus lost, rolling from their purses in the shape of dollars and cents, how
                            energetically would they labor to prevent this waste. The loss of a single little gold
                            dollar would stir them up to a greater activity than the direct waste of a hundred times
                            that little gold dollar's value in the form of liquid manure. Year after year, silently the
                            golden streams are flowing from their purses. Tell them of their ; error and they
                            acknowledge it, but rarely does it happen, that being reminded of it in a friendly manner,
                            they make a single effort to correct it. How many are there who, after a life-time of steady
                            unremitting toil, find themselves no richer in lands aud money than when they began. They
                            cannot explain the reason. Other causes may have led to such discouraging results, but if
                            the drain of liquid manures from the barnyards had been checked when they began farming,
                            very many of these unsuceessf ul ones would have been as prosperous as their more provident
                            neighbors.— Western Rural.</p></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In Iceland the Bible is constantly read by all the people..." TEIform="index"/>In Iceland the Bible is constantly read by all the people...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Here are six facts : In Iceland the Bible is constantly read by all the people. There is uot
                            in that land a theatre, nor a prison, nor a sheriff, nor a cannon, nor any military drill.
                            Now look through these six facts again and tell what is the cause of all the rest. Is it not
                            the peace principle produced by a careful study of the Scriptures ?</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In a time of profound peace..." TEIform="index"/>In a time of profound peace...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">In a time of profound peace, and with an army of only 25,000 men, yet our government paid
                            last year $41,000,000 for military expenses, besides $6,500,000 for Indian expenses,
                            $15,800,000 for naval expenses and $50,200,000 for pensions. War and all its incidents are
                            very expensive. What a jubilee it will be when men learn war no more.</p></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Two hours' work about a hot stove..." TEIform="index"/>Two hours' work about a hot stove...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Two hours' work about a hot stove exhausts more than four hours' work out of doors. Americans
                            in Europe are shocked, or pretend kto be, at sight of women doing men's work in the fields.
                            They are much better off than the American women, fivesixths of whose life is spent in the
                            kitchen. The out-door woman shows some blood through the tan on her cheeks. The American
                            kitchen housewife is sallow and bleached out.</p></div2><pb id="p29" TEIform="pb"/><!--                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>