<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2905" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">20</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">East Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">29</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">5</biblScope><date value="18990501" TEIform="date">May 1899</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">65-80</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="29" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="5" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
&

THE
MANIFESTO
1899.
 strange WMM
EXPLAINING
DANIEL'S & STJOHN'S
A SUMMARY VIEW
OF  THK
 CHURCH,
OR
PROPHECIES
"United   Society   of   Believers"
It treats of the Rise and Progress of the
48 page pamphlet.     Price 10 cts.     Society,  together with  the general Prin                       ciples of the Faith and Testimony.
13 for $1.00.
Price, 50 cts.
Address,   H. B. Beak, Preston, Ohio.
Sketches of Shakers and Shakerism. A synopsis of the United Society of Believers iu Christ's Second
Appearing. Illustrated. By Giles
B. Avery.    Price 15 cts.
BRIEF EXPOSITION
or the
Principles and Regulations
of the
SOCIETY   OF   BELIEVERS.
Price, 10 cts.
THE ALTRUIST.
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is publisht by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all their
property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. It now has 5,000
acres of land in Southeast Missouri on
which it offers a home and employment
for life to all acceptable persons who may
wish to join it.            50  cents a year;
specimen copy free.    Address A. Longley, 2819  Olive St. St. Louis, Mo.
MAY,
worarui.
MILLENNIAL
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
There has been so much reference in the reoent cable news from Europe to the strong
feeling in France against England, and so
much significant allusion to the experiments
which the French are making with submarine
boats, that the question of the possibility of a
French military force ever crossing the English Channel becoming interesting, a writer
in the April Cosmopolitan, "Quatre Etoiles"
evidently a nom de plumetells an ingenious
story of the results of the consummation one
hundred years later of that plan which was
first conceived by Napoleon when he brought
his army to the plains of Boulogne in 1804.
When every detail of the plan has been successfully prepared, a great fete on the cliffs of
Boulogne brings the Channel Squadron and
the Prince of Wales to join in the ceremony.
Insult intentionally and suddenly given by
the President of the French republic, leads
to an immediate declaration of war.   The English fleet, unsuspicious of its real danger,
moves to engage the battle-ships and cruisers
of the French which merely serve as a decoy
for their more than one thousand submarine
vessels.   How these latter accomplish their
deadly work is told in a startling way.   Then
follows the invasion of England by three hundred thousand French troops, in accordance
with plans carefully arranged in advancean
invasion which takes place so quickly that
the French battle-ships and transports are
landing men at Sandgate almost before the
Foreign Office knows of the declaration of
hostilities: then follows the occupation of
London, et cetera.   This class of speculation,
while improbable, nevertheless has some interesting points in view of existing complications.   The subject is evidently handled by
some one familiar with the military details
involved.   The nom deplume would seem to
indicate a French officer.
To curtail the good work of such an excellent order would be wrong.   Moreover, to deviate from the guiding star of their rule is
certainly incompatible with-the object of
their founder, the great La Salle.   Looking to
the amelioration of the people, he conceived
the idea of forming a brotherhood of Christian scholars, under the auspices of the
Church, to elevate the standard of education
and morality.   Rallying to his cause men of
erudition and zeal for the honor and glory
of God and the salvation of souls, La Salle
established the main house of the new order
in France, about the year 1679.   The order was
sanctioned by the Sovereign Pontiff, Benedict
XIII.   The object of the Brothers of the Christian schools is not the teaching of the higher
branches of science and literaturethe classics, philosophy or theology,but the ordinary branches of education and the knowledge
of Christian doctrine, which are so necessary
for the good citizen.   The days of expansion
have been growing ever since the foundation
of our republic, and though in a geographical
point of view, we might deem our growth t-uflicient, still in regard to the education of the
masses we believe that the principles of La
Salle will best subserve the needs of the peo
pie.Donahoe's.
The illustrated articles of the April Magazine Number of The Outlook include one by
F. Marion Crawford, the famous novelist, on
Leo XIII.; a personal and anecdotal article
on M. Loubet by Mr. ElbertF. Baldwin, called
"A Peasant President;" "The Face of Christ
in Art," a collection of opinions from prominent clergymen of all denominations, with
many reproductions of the paintings referred
to; a somewhat unusual poem called "The
Violin," which has four full-page pictures;
and a curiously entertaining article by W. H.
Richardson, called "A Day with the Pennsylvania Amish."   There are also several important unillustrated articles- the chief of
which is the article by Mr. Charles B. Spahr
in his series "America's Working People"
and the usual full news, editorial and critical
departments.   The Outlook continues to be
unique in that it is tit the same time a monthly illustrated magazine and a weekly newspaper under one subscription.   ($3 a year.
The Outlook Company, New York.)
The policy of TJie Ladies' Home Journal, in its
religious department, seems to be always to
engage the pen of the man mo&t immediately
prominent in the eyes of the religious world.
Thus it has had the services of Mr. Beecher,
Doctor Talmage, Doctor Parkhurst, Ian
Maclaveri, and now it will have those of Dr.
Newell Dwight Hillis, the new pastor of Plymouth Church, in Brooklyn.   Doctor Hillis
has given the Journal a series of articles upon
which he had been working for over a year
previous to his Eastern call, and the first of
these articles will be published in the next
issue of the magazine.   The series is all connected in thought, and presents the general
subject of "The Secrets of a Happy Life."
"The Romance of Rome," by F. Marion
Crawford, will be among the prime literary
and artistic attractions of Frank Leslie's
Popular Monthly for April.   Mr. Crawford
was born in Rome, has been steeped from
childhood in the romance and legendary lore
of the Eternal City, and writes of her with
the enthusiasm of a lover as well as the erudition of a student.   His paper is illustrated
with some beautiful views of Rome, and a
fine portrait of Pope Leo XIII.
The Book of Job, by H. L. Hastings.   The
writer says,   "Since doctors disagree so
widely concerning the book of Job, we may
perhaps be permitted to investigate and
judge for ourselves."   We can not say anything better than that.   Address, H. L. Hastings, 47 Cornhill, Boston, Mass.--><pb n="65" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Strange doctrines" TEIform="index"/>STRANGE DOCTRINES.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>By Elder Henry C. Blinn.</byline><p TEIform="p"> THE doctrine that I believe, can not be strange to me, as in that case I might not accept
                            it, although all other systems may seem peculiar. The doctrine which Jesus taught need not
                            be strange to any one, and yet the Christian church presents more shades of belief than
                            there are points to the compass, and these shades are strangely opposed to each other. If we
                            believe in the testimony of Jesus, we can accept it as the only door of hope. His mission on
                            the earth was to teach men how to live soberly, honestly and righteously that they might in
                            the resurrection share with him the blessings of eternal life. His authority for teaching
                            and for pointing out to man the way in which he should go to obtain treasures in heaven, is
                            not generally questioned. As we denominate ourselves Christians, we also claim a right to
                            present those views which are published so fully in the New Testament. While we are anxious
                            that none should be led away by strange doctrines, we are equally anxious that they should
                            become steadfast in the ways of righteousness and manifest by faith and good works their
                            confidence in God. To become a Christian, one must build on the foundation which was laid by
                            Jesus the Christ. Paul has said, and truly,"Other foundation can no man lay than that is
                            laid, which is Jesus Christ." Now it becomes a matter of interest to ascertain how near we
                            come to this Christian foundation and the kind of material that we are using as we build for
                            ourselves a creed, a sect, a party, or a community. Possibly we may <pb n="66" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 66
                            THE MANIFESTO. find a near relationship to the old, caraally-minded Corinthians, who built
                            with gold or silver, and a poorer class tried to build with hay, wood and stubble. Human
                            nature is the same to-day as it was in Corinth and the churchal religion is kept just about
                            the same, with gold and silver or hay and stubble. Men will try everything except the
                            crucifixion of their own lives. Jesus says 'Whosoever he be of you that forsaketh not all
                            that he hath, he can not be my disciple." Did Jesus mean what he said? We believe he did,
                            and this becomes the first, step in our Christian work. As no man can well perform any
                            manual labor while fastened with heavy chains, so no man can well perform a Christian's duty
                            while carrying along the sins of the world. The first sermon that Jesus preached
                            was,"Repent, for the kingdom of heaven is at hand." Every man who believes he is called of
                            God to be a Christian should repent; should change his mind and make for himself strait
                            paths in which to walk. He should then take an account of the stock that he has on hand.
                            Bear in mind "All that he hath." All his gold and silver, all his houses, horses, oxen,
                            sheep and goats. "Sell all that thou hast." Then the disciple must forsake all his worldly,
                            generative relations and keep company only with those who do the will of God. Men will
                            forsake all else to consummate their own wills in the obtaining of wealth, fame or sensual
                            enjoyment, and the whole nation will shout for joy. The Christian must love his enemies, for
                            Jesus has said, "Love your enemies and pray for those that despitefully use you. If ye love
                            them chat love you, what thank have ye? Sinners also lend to sinners to receive as much
                            again." It is said that the great preacher of Brooklyn advised the pioneers of Kansas to
                            take with them the New Testarmnt, and also Colt's revolver. Both weapons have been used for
                            conversion at an earlier date, or corresponding ones and why not at the present time ? Moses
                            had taught his brethren to hate their enemies and they did it most effectually. The
                            Christian church has used the same record to mark its own antichristian course. "Love your
                            enemies," said Jesus. No man would harm that which he truly loved, and to be a Christian,
                            one must be a loving peace-maker, a child of God. The army and navy can obtain no system of
                            rules and regulations from the New Testament, and the lawful or unlawful fighters can not be
                            the disciples of the Prince of Peace. Some assume to think that God encouraged the
                            Israelites to fight against their enemies and utterly exterminate them, but as God is the
                            same yesterday, to-day and forever, the old Israelites must have accepted a very crude
                            conception of God's will. Peter said to Jesus, "Behold, we have forsaken all to follow
                            thee." There are many Peters in this day who, after forsaking a few of their selfish
                            possessions, ask "What shall we have therefor?" Then some of the much mar- <pb n="67" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 67 ried divines, keen on the use of subtleties think that
                            Peter, while a disciple, did not disturb nis family relations. That he and his wife became
                            disciples of the Teacher and still lived in the little cottage by the sea. Peter tells his
                            own story. He had forsaken all, and no man can call himself a Christian until he can
                            say,"Behold, I have forsaken all to follow thee." Peter's doubts were removed when Jesus
                            said, "Ye who have followed me in the regeneration shall receive an hundred fold and shall
                            inherit everlasting life." To believe in Christ one must believe in the resurrection of the
                            dead. Martha, the sister of Lazarus says, "I know that he shall rise again in the
                            resurrection at the last day." Many still believe with Martha, and our cemetaries fully
                            testify to our traditionary beliefs. This resurrection of the physical body, however,
                            belongs to the Pharisees, while Jesus taught a resurrection from dead works. He says, "I am
                            the resurrection," and the Christian's resurrection is to rise out of the grave or state of
                            selfishness and lust, out from the generative conditions of his own soul and live the new
                            life with Christ. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Balm in Gilead" TEIform="index"/>BALM IN GILEAD.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stewart, Ezra J." TEIform="persName"/>By Ezra J. Stewart.</byline><p TEIform="p">"Bless the Lord 0 my soul, who forgiveth all thine iniquities; who healeih all thy
                            diseases."Psalm, ciii., 2, 3. Once more the Lord reveals His grace to men. With healing in
                            His wings The Christ comes forth again, Inharmony and discord cease As to this earth-bound
                            sphere He brings Immortal life, and joy, and peace. Signs follow those whose firm belief
                            Reveals a substance, sure and safe relief. Mortality is doomed to death, The curse of God
                            rests on its brow, Dust unto dust, for lack of breath Its sinful, suffering sense must go.
                            Spirit, life and truth shall now Possess His rightful place below, And God will lead through
                            love His image and His likeness unto himself above. Shirley, Mass.</p></div2><pb n="68" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Order of mediation, no. 4" TEIform="index"/>THE ORDER OF MEDIATION. NO. 4.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lyon, John" TEIform="persName"/>By Elder John Lyon.</byline><p TEIform="p">"TT"T"HEN Moses sent for Dathan and Abiram, they said, "We will not VV come up." It is quite
                            remarkable that the same spirit of rebellion should be found in every age, considering the
                            punishment was so summarily executed. The Christian church met with the same experience,
                            Nicholas, one of the seven deacons in the church at Jerusalem, laid' a selfish foundation
                            and taught a doctrine of his own. Peter, Paul, James and Jude all tell us of the sins and
                            enormities of this class of professors. But, said the apostle, "There were false prophets
                            among the people, even as there shall be false teachers among you." It requires different
                            faiths, different doctrines and different opinions to make different sects. But it is
                            possible that each of these sects might hold to some particular point of faith with them to
                            crucify the flesh with its affections and lusts. History states that in the second century,
                            the universal church formed its creed, faith and doctrines from Pagan philosophy, Pagan
                            rites with Jewish ceremonies, and then adding some forms that had been practiced in the
                            Apostolic church, to give it the name and appearance of a Christian church. In 325 A. D.
                            they assembled a council of contending prelates and passed a decree, hy vote, that Jesus
                            should no longer be looked to as a mediator, but that he should be considered as a very God.
                            As Jesus said to his disciples, "I am the vine, and ye are the branches. He that abideth in
                            me and I in him, the same bringeth forth much fruit, for without me ye can do nothing."John,
                            xv., 5. When the fullness of time was come for the Son of man to make a second appearance on
                            earth, he came as he promised, in an hour when the}7 wTere not aware. He found that faithful
                            and wise servant who was watching for her Lord. He made her ruler over his house, to give
                            them their meat in due season, and as he was crowned with two crowns, as was typified by
                            Joshua, he gave one to his faithful servant who was a, co-partner with him in his work and
                            kingdom. To him was given the principles on which the new creation was founded; the same he
                            gave to her, with full power to dispense them to the human race in due season, when he had
                            raised the order of mediation and laid it for the foundation of his work complete. During
                            this work of preparation but little was known of submission. The people were like the
                            Corinthians, who said, "I am for Paul, and I for Apollos and I for Cephas."1 Cor. i., 12.
                            The people were in this state when Father Joseph Meacham and Mother Lucy Wright were chosen
                            as mediums to carry the work of the church. They were empowered to establish an order of
                            mediation in every place where a church was to be established. The law was a shadow of good
                            things to come <pb n="69" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 69 and though not the very things itself,
                            yet it typified the thing it represented as nearly as the type can represent the antitype.
                            Whoever tries any other way except the one appointed by the spirit of God, will find his
                            labor in vain. It seems that every one that has faith in the anointed, must see that the
                            order of mediation is the foundation of the whole work of regeneration. (The End.)</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New life" TEIform="index"/>THE NEW LIFE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Phelps, Lillian" TEIform="persName"/>By Lillian Phelps.</byline><p TEIform="p">"Verity, verily I say unto thee, Except a man be born again he can not see the kingdom of
                            God." WITH the opening of a new year, oni' thought is called to the new life, which, as
                            disciples of Christ, we are seeking to live. What is this new life, and how is it to be
                            obtained? "No man pntteth new wine into old bottles, lest the bottles break and the wine be
                            wasted ; neither do we put a piece of new cloth unto an old garment for that which is put in
                            to fill it up, taketh from the garment and the rent is mads worse." So the new life can not
                            be grafted into the old branch with its withered and gnarled conditions of worldliness and
                            selfishness. Nicodemus asked Jesus, "How can a man be born when he is old?" not realizing
                            that the body may reach maturity, while the soul may never have been awakened by the
                            spiritual forces that lead to a new life in Christ. To a soul that is born again, the old
                            heavens and earth pass away; all that once absorbed the selfish love, and gave rise to a
                            transient happiness, gives place to the new heaven and earth conditions, wherein the chief
                            source of happiness lies in doing good and fulfilling the mission of Jesus Christ. The new
                            law, which governs this new life, is the law of Loveof unselfish, sacrificing love. "Greater
                            love hath no man than this, that a man lay down his life for his friends." There is no limit
                            to this love. It embraces all who are needy and suffering, the erring or repentant, as well
                            as the good "elder sou" who hath served faithfully these many years; none are orphans in the
                            love of this heavenly Parentage, for the mission of Christ is to seek and save the lost.
                            Broader, grander and purer than that which the world calls love, and which is confined to
                            the few who form the circle of friends, is the love of Christ which is the crowning
                            principle of this new, this divine life, and claims as brother or sister all who are seeking
                            to do the will of God. To those who will leave all for Christ's sake, is promised the
                            hundred-fold in this world, and in the world to come everlasting life, which may be
                            commenced here, in this world, as we rise from the old life into the newness of Christ's
                            holy doctrine. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><pb n="70" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Self-denial" TEIform="index"/>SELF-DENIAL.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="DeGraw, Hamilton" TEIform="persName"/>By Hamilton DeGraw.</byline><p TEIform="p">THE denial of self has been the great dragon that has frightened many timid souls when urged
                            by the promptings of their higher sell' or the solicitations of friends interested in their
                            welfare to reject certain conditions of life which, judging from the results, were
                            derogatory to their best good. What is that self that must be rejected and cast out as an
                            unprofitable servant? In answering it must be understood that human life has not advanced to
                            its present condition only by first realizing the fact that there are conditions of life in
                            advance of the present, and its interests will be promoted by their attainment. As the soul
                            can not have its allegiance divided this advancement can only be made by the rejecting of
                            those which are controlling at the present time, even if by thus doing temporary
                            inconvenience and suffering is caused, for it is a law of the spiritual world that every
                            effort made by the soul for advancement, a stepping on to higher vantage ground where the
                            responsibilities and enjoyments of that state can be realized, causes pain to the lower
                            self. Here is where the denial is enjoined, for, the soul desirous of ease, would iucline to
                            that condition which produced it, but as true enjoyment can only come by progressing,
                            growing, finding a field of more expansive culture where the environments that formerly
                            controlled have ceast to exist, then so long as those conditions are present which prevent
                            the soul from making those higher attainments there will be a necessity for the practice of
                            self-denial, a rejecting of the inferior life for the superior. As life is a continous
                            movement, no stopping on the way, it must either advance or recede and the fact must be
                            recognized that there are forces existing in the soul that would strive to hold it down to
                            its present level, and even lower the plane of life on which the soul is living. Sometimes
                            it is made to realize that by a surrender to those lower promptings there will be certain
                            pleasures granted that are not recognized by the higher self ; but the soul realizing that
                            if it attain to these higher altitudes, it must be by a denial of those pleasures which
                            belong to lower levels. "Excelsior" must be the motto and watchword, and as the higher
                            conditions of life are attained the attractions of the lower will be lessened until they
                            cease to have a controlling influence upon the life, and self-denial will cease to be
                            operative, as there is no affinity in the soul that would attract it to the conditions which
                            it formerly was compelled to reject. There is a freedom of thought and action not understood
                            nor accepted while dwelling on the lower planes of life. While it is admitted in all phases
                            of life that the law of self-denial as a restrictive and directing power is a necessity, it
                            does not bear upon all alike, <pb n="71" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 71 that which in one would
                            call for an extra exertion of the will and conscience to keep the life within the limits of
                            what the higher self has shown to be right; to another whose attractions lead in a different
                            direction, the law of thus far and no farther shalt thou go, wou'd be inoperative, because
                            unnecessary. It is a true saying "we are not all tempted alike," and while dealing with our
                            own life, controlling its wayward impulses and encouraging its aspirations for an advanced
                            growth, enforcing the higher mandates with an uncompromising sternness when it comes to sit
                            in judgment upon the conditions that have made other immortal souls what they are, and who
                            many times we are. incapable of understanding, then the gift of charity is best made
                            manifest by self-denial of those inclinations that would work only harm. Many times
                            reformers in their zeal to combat the false conditions and vices that are oppressing human
                            life, condemn the individual more than the causes that have been productive of that state of
                            being, forgetting the fact that the one afflicted is the subject of environments that have
                            made his life what it is, and the first step in the reform of the individual life is to
                            stimulate an effort to practice denial to the lower self, helping, by improving the
                            conditions that surround its life, making it more in accord with the internal aspirations of
                            the toul for improvement. Removing the temptations by placing before the tempted one, a life
                            so superior to the old, so full of attractiveness and beauty that it be absorbed in
                            admiration, even to the forgetting that there was a need of denial of the old life. It is
                            possible for the soul to attain unto a condition of such supreme spiritual exaltedness that
                            the necessity exists for a rejection of the lower emotions. This does not imply that the
                            soul has arrived at the boundary line and can not progress farther; but it is evidence that,
                            in the most perfect comprehension of the word it has just begun its spiritual journey. All
                            former efforts were only preparatory, clearing the highway of the incumbrances which would
                            impede its advancement. In the efforts made to attain unto this exalted state, great
                            strength and help is given by avoiding those conditions that attract the soul to that lower
                            life for, "Vice is a monster of so frightful a mien, that to be hated needs but to be seen,
                            but seen too oft, familiar with its face, we first endure, then pity then embrace." There
                            are times when it is wisdom not to try to avoid a conflict, but let the soul unfurl its
                            banner and combat its enemy in its own stronghold. In evidence of the truth of this
                            assertion we are reminded of the inebriate who, having his conscience roused to a
                            recognition of the fact that if an effort was not made for his emancipation he soon would be
                            where help was useless, resolved to make one mighty effort to release himself from the demon
                            that had him in its grasp for so long. He seated himself before the table with a lighted
                            lamp and a bottle of liquor, bid his family retire, as "Jesus Christ and the devil were to
                            meet that night and decide which should have possession of his soul." We are told he met his
                            enemy and conquered. By <pb n="72" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 72 THE MANIFESTO. a courageous self-denial he
                            emancipated his life from the bondage to his former master. We who believe in the divine
                            ministry of angels, know that the soul is not left in its battles alone ; that the
                            inspiration of angels gives courage to work for the victory. The existence of that mighty
                            host which the Revelator saw, who had come up out of great tribulation and made their
                            'garments white, is not a myth as some materialistic writers assert, but the number is being
                            iucreast day by day, as hitman life is advancing and the soul, through self-denial, attains
                            to that condition where it can say to the discordant and destructive elements of the lower
                            life "Peace be still." Shakers, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Discovery" TEIform="index"/>A DISCOVERY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, Oliver C." TEIform="persName"/>By Oliver C. Hampton.</byline><p TEIform="p">i4 A ND thine ears shall hear a word behind Thee, saying, this is the way, -/TX. walk ye in
                            it, when ye turn to the right hand, and when ye turn to the left."Isaiah xxx., 21. When
                            sickness, pain, outward trials cr inward conflicts come upon us, what is to be done? Ah!
                            sure euough what is to be done? I think I know considerable upon this subject, b-&gt;th by
                            experience and observation. Sickness and pain can be relieved if not entirely cured in nine
                            cases out of ten, by fasting. But inward conflicts and outward trials, can be made to cease,
                            and peace can be restored, if we only know how to do it and will take the proper means
                            thereto. The Bible says we are direct emanations from the Great Father (and Mother) of the
                            Universe. Our inmost Being, then, must be exactly like His in all respects. Jesus also said
                            that the Kingdom of Heaven is within us. What is the kingdom of Heaven? Jesus said it is
                            righteousness, peace and joy in a holy Spirit. Suppose we should sit down in silence and
                            solitude, and dismissing for the time all other thoughts, should pass into and explore this
                            interesting region. As it consists of the aforesaid qualities, there can be no pain,
                            sickness, sorrow or agony there, for none but The Father is there and He never suffers in in
                            any way. So as long as we remain there we must be at rest and in perfect peace, for we are
                            in the Kingdom of Heaven. This is not speculation, it is truth,for I have proved it by
                            experience. The more this habit of inward retirement is acquired, the more is the peace and
                            felicity thereof increased. Again, when we are tried from outward bad or unkind treatment,
                            what is it that suffers in us ? It can not be the God that is in us for He is incapable of
                            suffering. Well,whatever it is, if we will take Jesus' method, and say "Get thee behind me,
                            satan, for thou savorest not the things that be of God, but those which be of men;" it will
                            surely leave us to the enjoyment of the. Inner Kingdom of Peace. Now by persistence in this
                            method for a longer or a shorter period, all inward and outward troubles will gradually <pb n="73" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 73 pass away like the clouds in the sky, and leave us
                            in a state of contentment and invulnerable peace. Once moreSuppose we are insulted as we
                            call it. What is it in us which is insulted? Is it the Father in us? Not at all. He can not
                            be insulted. Is it not exactly like that which insulted us? To be sure it is. Then if we are
                            foolish enough to receive and be affected by the insult we take into our hearts two devils
                            instead of the one which we had before, and our last estate is worse than our first. By
                            determining that we will not be insulted, nor wounded, (the decision which is always made in
                            our inmost Kingdom) we may parry all the anguish and agony which it was intended to inflict
                            upon us, and our peace will remain as a river, and our righteousness as the waves of the
                            sea. Now if we do not prefer discord and bad feelings, to peace and good feelings, we may
                            enter into the Promised Land of Eternal peace at once, and by first confessing all our sins,
                            and getting once for all rightly into gospel harness, we may soon possess a Kingdom wherein
                            dwelleth righteousness, peace and joy in a Holy Spirit. Try it and you will surely become
                            convinced that all that Jesus ever said on this important theme is trueUnion Village,
                        Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Holden, Joseph" TEIform="persName"/>[Introductory remarks of Elder Joseph Holden, Sabbath,
                            Dec. 5, 1898.']</byline><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bring the best" TEIform="index"/>''BRING THE BEST."</head><p TEIform="p">God wants the best. He in the far-off ages Once claimed the firstling of the flock, the
                            finest of the wheat; And still He asks His own with gentlest pleading To lay their brightest
                            hopes and talents at His feet, He'll not forget the feeblest service, humblest love; The
                            Best we have. God gives the Best. He takes the hearts we offer, And fills them with His
                            glorious beauty, joy and peace; And in His service, as we're growing stronger, The calls to
                            grand achievement still increase : The richest gifts for us in earth or heaven above Are hid
                            in Christ; Him serving we receive The Best God has. And is our Best too much? O friends,
                            remember! How once Our Lord poured out His soul in loss, And 'mid the prime of His majestic
                            manhood Gave up His precious life upon the Cross. The Lord of lords, by whom the wondrous
                            worlds were made, Through groaning grief and bitter tear gave us The Best He had. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><pb n="74" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. MAY, 1899. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is publisht by the "United
                            Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued regularly by
                            the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the religious
                            views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. Address all communications
                            to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N: H. One copy one year, postage paid. .50 A
                            cross in the margin will show that your subscription has closed. Remittances for
                            subscription by Money Order should be on the Post Office at Concord, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">March. Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. Thermometer. Rain. Snow. 1898. 40.5 1.375 in 2
                                in. 1899. 29.52 1.75 " 3 ft. Highest Temp, during this mo. 52 above 0. Lowest " " " " 10
                                " Number of rainy days " " 4 " " snowy " " " 12 " clear " " " 6 " " cloudy" " " 9 March,
                                1899. March has been more like a winter month than spring. It has been full of bluster,
                                snow and sleet. Less than half of the days have been warm enough to force the mercury
                                above freezing point. Tracing back several years T fail to find a March that equals the
                                present one in sterility, inclemency, and unhealthfulness; especially the last. Very few
                                if any have escaped being prostrated by sonic epidemic. The entire year of 1899 thus far
                                has been a sickly one. Sleigh-bells have played their signal music the entire length of
                                the month. Snow-banks are still spread over the landscape from 3 feet deep down to now
                                and then bare ground. By appearance it will be the middle of April before the fanners
                                begin to plough, sow and plant, if not later. We have finished sawing, splitting and
                                piling our year's stock of fire-wood. As unpropitious as the season appears we are
                                religiously and conscientiously told: "The seasons tell us that God is Love, for he gave
                                us the seasons,Spring with its fresh green leaves and buds, Summer with its flowers and
                                berries, Autumn with its grains and fruits, and Winter, with its frost and snow, that
                                cleanse the air and prepare the ground to be more fruitful." Calvin G. Heed. South
                                Family. April, 1899. Hick's weather predominates, and April with its showers of rain and
                                housecleaning has come to stay for thirty days. The summer birds are returning singing
                                songs of the resurrection of life, fore-runners of the good time coming, when snow-banks
                                and snow-shovels will be seen no more, when frost and slush will disappear, when the
                                orchards will blossom, the gardens and fields rejoice in a newness of life, and the
                                frozen streams renew their onward march oceanward. We have read with delight the
                                biographical sketch of Eldress Eliza Babbitt, published in the Phrenological Journal for
                                January, and The Manifesto for February. For ninety-two years the world has been
                                benefitted spiritually, morally, intellectually, socially and scientifically by this <pb n="75" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 75 much gifted woman. The Autobiography of Sister
                                Mary Hazard was also read with interest. She too was one of God's noble women and better
                                has grown the world for her eighty-seven years of unselfish service rendered in the
                                cause of human elevation. We are busy making and repairing garments, attending to the
                                various household duties and preparing for the annual house renovation. The chair
                                enterprise continues, and demands the beautiful "Shaker Chairs." We find plenty of work
                                for hands and mind; no time for idleness, which is a great blessing on our journey
                                heavenward. We recently received a "Souvenir of Rochester" published by James Vick's
                                Sons, of Rochester, N. Y. The fine scenery of the famous Genesee Valley was pleasingly
                                familiar. The "Flower City," as Rochester is often termed, is one of the grandest in
                                western New York. The Genesee Valley is noted for its healthful climate and fine natural
                                scenery; it represents one form of God's handiwork, and the Berkshire hills another.
                                Geueoieve DeGraiv. North Family. April, 1899. A slow March indeed! and to many a funeral
                                march. But be of good cheer. Soon the snow will be gone, for already the voice of the
                                bluebird and of the robin is heard in the land. Another sound not so cheering is also
                                heard; that of the beating of carpets and adjusting of closets prophetic of the grand
                                house-cleaning so trying to the souls of the unregenerate and unclean,the white woman's
                                burden! In the meantime the frisky calves and lambs ought to be making pastoral poems of
                                our hill-sides; but alas! who cares to write or act pastoral poems in sheets of snow?
                                Not the calves and lambs surely. It is the poetry of action that is most appreciated now
                                and the beacons are flashing their signal fires from peak to peak, calling us to the
                                battle; and of all people we should be first and foremost in this war waged against the
                                wrongs of humanity. Let us keep the cobwebs swept from our brain and our soul as well as
                                from our rooms. Less protesting against evil and more practice at putting this evil down
                                and out; fewer words, among us, and more works. G. Ada Brown.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">April, 1899. We would render thanks to Sister Jessie Evans for the excellent article from
                                her pen in the April Manifesto. While perusing it we thought what a blessing it would be
                                to those who were struggling for the light, and yearning for that food which would
                                strengthen their spiritual life, if such gifts of the spirit could he sown broadcast
                                with a liberal hand; be placed where they could reach the myriads of lives that are now
                                groping in darkness. It is a grand and inspiring thought that we have the immortal life
                                with us now. That notwithstanding all the environments of a repressive nature that
                                surround multitudes of life's pilgrims, the desire to attain unto life's higher levels
                                can not be wholly suppressed, though for a time it may slumber, the individual not being
                                conscious of its existence. We are glad to see that our Manifesto is doing far better
                                than even that, son of Erin who said he "started in life with nothing and had held his
                                own." We hope it will be sustained. It is a medium through which the testimony of the
                                everlasting gospel can be sent forth to those who are hungering and thirsting for the
                                bread and waters of life; and regardless of what external appearance may indicate the
                                conclusion that we have drawn from reading and correspondence is that the principles of
                                the higher life are being unfolded in human life as never before, its necessity is being
                                made apparent to the lives of a large body of thinkers interested in human progress. We
                                were one of a delegation who at- <pb n="76" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 76 THE MANIFESTO. tended a
                                lecture by Rev. C. IT. Mead, at Lothridge hall, Verdoy, N. Y. on March 14th. "The Mills
                                that Grind," was the subject of the speaker. It was a powerful incitement of the curse
                                entailed upon society by the liquor traffic. The literarystyle was excellent, but
                                overshadowing all else was the tremendous earnestness of the speaker, his utterances
                                fell like sledgehammer blows upon that accursed system. We give our hand of fellowship
                                to all such laborers. Hamilton DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>West Pittsfield, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">April, 1899. As to outward appearance at present, it is very muddy. Mother Nature is very
                                late with her work, and we fear will now be obliged to do double duty in consequence.
                                She slept so long and soundly during the winter night, and was so snugly covered with
                                her white mantle, that it was a difficult task to arouse her. The sun commenced gently
                                and gradually to awaken her, but failed. Then a fierce thunder storm tried its power and
                                crashed and boomed, but to no avail. Then the crows came, a congregation of them, and
                                tried coaxing and calling, and as a last resort, singinguntil they were hoarse, but
                                still no sign of life appeared from under the drifts of snow. At last King Sol came to
                                the rescue, and rising higher and higher, sent his beams down with such warmth that she
                                began to move and then to throw off her covering, although she yet clings to patches
                                here and there. She is fully awake now, and very busy, so we hope that by diligence,
                                spring will not keep summer waiting long. The early birds are with us once more. The
                                chickadees have hardly left us, and the Phebes have returned, but are still hunting for
                                that unfortunate sister, for this morning they came under my window and called for her
                                incessantly. The robins have come in a band and landed so suddenly in our midst that we
                                were surprised when they perched around the house and commenced a full chorus of their
                                merry melodies. Dear, friendly, hopeful, trusting robins ! How many lessons we may learn
                                from your lives, how by your simple trust and cheery sonps you reprove our doubts and
                                quiet our murmurings. The Father surely has revealed to you his wisdom, that from you we
                                may learn object lessons of faith. Although most of our trees and plants are tardy in
                                their growth, the wood piles have grown to their full size. The mill has been busily
                                worked converting the pine logs into material sufficient for another winter. The eighty
                                calves before mentioned, wish to submit their report occasional,y. They have flourished
                                and grown during the winter, although the hay mows have suffered. The little, wild colts
                                are fast developing into well educated horses; although they can not obtain a No. 1
                                diploma, yet can draw a carriage very nicely. The Ministry are with us once more. While
                                receiving all of the good we may, let us also extend our tenderest love, our kind
                                sympathy and loyal obedience. For he who lives only for self, finds only self at last,
                                but he who gives all shall receive all in Christ. Fidelia Estabrook.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">April, 1899. Easter day with its annual incentives to work for full resurrection from the
                                tomb of earthly entanglements and pass into the light of God and partake of soul
                                energies that embellish life with Christly attributes, was appropriately observed by our
                                Church with a morning service full of short sermons and inspiring songs, and in the
                                evening held a service of music, songs and recitations referring to the arisen Christ,
                                and the immortal work of his followers. In reviewing some of the events of the past year
                                our hearts waft notes of gratitude to the powers that have levelled the unrighteous
                                forces that enslaved the Cu- <pb n="77" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> TJ IE MANIFES TO. 11 ban and
                                Philipino people; never again, we hope, to pass into the state of barbarity. The world
                                wide resurrection movement seeks egress from the dust of material desolation into a
                                sphere of better order and life, thus enlarging the silver lining of Christian affinity
                                fringing the clouds of human grief and turmoil, and making it possible for the white
                                dove of peace to fly from heart to heart, from home to home, and nation to nation with
                                its spotless love, caroling notes of resurrection's truths, joys and works. The few days
                                that Brother A. G. Hollister sojourned with us last month, and his visit was one of
                                profit and pleasure. What tine testimonials in favor of mortal resurrection from error
                                and evil are souls like our brother, who devotes his all to resurrecting laws, that
                                raise the whole organism above earth's corruptions and pleasures. We also entertained
                                our friend Kev. T. l^osco, of Rochester, Vt., who has lately accepted a call to preside
                                over the Universalist church of Enfield. The bond of union made will be conducive to
                                reciprocal associations that work for greater righteousness. George H. Baxter.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Sabbathday Lake, Me.</head><p TEIform="p">April, 1809. The robins gave us a welcome concert on the first inst. Although they made
                                their appearance on "All Fools' Day," their notes were the welcome announcement of
                                spring to us who have been surrounded by the drifts of snow for the past months. An old
                                orchard which has stood for scores of years is now being laid low, and the gnarled trees
                                that for a century, at least, have furnished the tables with the nice, spicy apples, are
                                soon to be converted into fire-wood. We are glad to see the unsightly place cleared and
                                to feel that new fruit trees are soon to take the places of the old ones. On the 8th
                                inst. the family were surprised to find radishes on the the table, which were grown in
                                the greenhouse in 40 days. Work in that department is pressing, just now. The hum of the
                                wood saw has already commenced. Logs at the mill will soon be made into lumber. While
                                the Brethren are thus employed, the skillful fingers of the Sisters are busy fashioning
                                the pretty boxes, brushes and baskets to sell during the summer months. Housecleaning
                                and culinary work also need immediate attention and there is no place for a drone in our
                                hive of busy bees. "O friends whose hearts still keep their prime Whose bright example
                                warms and cheers, Ye teach us how to smile at Time, And set to music all his years." Ada
                                S. Cummhif/s.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">April, 1899. Our Notes were all tuned with becoming concentration last month to the happy
                                themethe visit of our beloved Central Ministry. The pleasure of anticipation was
                                exceeded only by the richness of realization. They brought us wealth from an ever full
                                treasury, and the love and blessing of a grateful people echoed every footfall as they
                                passed from our midss. Brother Alonzo Hollister paid us a visit on the 7th ult., leaving
                                for Enfield, N. H. on the 15th. The brevity of the season was its only fault. The
                                presence of a thoughtful Christian is a blessing everywhere. Truly the salt has not
                                "lost its savor.1' During March, a new boiler marched into line to share the burden of
                                Laundry and knitting factory engine. New recruits are not to be despised, but we look
                                with pride on the retiring veteran that for thirty-nine years has so nobly borne the
                                heat of faithful service. Wood-sawing, which opened on the 17th ult., is progressing
                                briskly. The spirit of thrift has flourished despite the severity of winter, and the
                                quick-witted farmer is on the watch to turn nature's first upris- <pb n="78" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/>
                                78 THE MANIFESTO. ings into a useful as well as an ornamental channel. Our society has
                                been signally blest with freedom from disease and accident during the long winter, and
                                as we render thanks for personal and society blessings, we remember in Christian
                                sympathy all who have shared in the world's serious calamities recently so numerous.
                                .les$ie Evans.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Narcoossee, Florida" TEIform="index"/> Narcoossee, Fla.</head><p TEIform="p">April, 1899. The warm, growing weather of the past ten days begins to show us the extent
                                of the injury to the fruit tiees and pine-apple plants, resulting from the freeze. All
                                our little household have been very anxious about our pine apples, as they have been and
                                still are our main dependence for an earthly subsistence. They have been carefully
                                watched every day since the freeze, and now the report comes that we are good for
                                seven-eights of a crop. So says Brother Egbert who is presiding chairman of the
                                Committee. These peculiar experiences are teaching the people of Florida the value of
                                true knowledge in horticultural as well as in agricultural cultivation. Pine-apple
                                growers are now building tight board fences around their plants, which may be used as a
                                protection, in case of cold weather. Small fires are also used for this same purpose.
                                The peach trees were frost-bitten on Feb. 13th, but now they have put out new foliage
                                and a few are in blossom. Pear trees, although young, have come through all right. The
                                sons of Florida will not be found sleeping while the enemy is near, and they are now
                                shedding whole orchards with tight board fences. With a fence and the fires they claim
                                they can govern the temperature and save their orchards from harm. So do not be
                                surprised, dear Editor, when you visit Florida should you see the state under a farmer's
                                canopy. Andrew Barrett.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Food we eat, no. 3" TEIform="index"/>THE FOOD WE EAT. NO. 3.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/>By Elder H. C. Blinn.</byline><p TEIform="p">To show that the human race do eat of every thing that moves and breathes, may be a surprise
                            to some, but when it is learned that the civilized and Christianized nations aie but a very
                            short distance in advance of the most barbarous tribes, we may well be astounded. All
                            reforms seem to move at a snail's pace. It has been more than 3000 years since Abraham
                            delivered his reformatory lecture on dietetics, or that the rulers of Israel decided by law
                            that certain articles of food were injurious. It required fully 4000 years before a
                            messenger could say to the people, '"You must love your enemies, and pray for those who hate
                            you." But the Christians have not only ignored the message that was delivered by the Christ,
                            but have equally ignored the wisdom of Abraham, and the Law of God through Moses. Many of
                            the following curious customs, in regard to the preparation of food for the human family
                            were taken from the writings of the Rev. J. G. Wood. We have made some of our first
                            references to the uncivilized races as they live now, in a wild state, and really represent
                            the omnivorous character of man better than those more advanced. Of the diet of the
                            civilized Christians we shall speak more fully, before we close. "The native Australians eat
                            almost everything. For vegetables they cultivate the yam and eat the young shoots of the
                            mango tree. They also eat the roots of the rush and fern, but the chief reliance is on
                            animal food, as the kangaroo, reptiles and dogs, with fish, moluscs, lobsters, crabs and
                            insects. Tadpoles are a favorite article of diet. The limpet is eaten as the English and
                            Americans eat clams. The fish are thrown on the fire and turned once or twice and when the
                            outside is scorched, they are eaten without farther ceremony. The Australian is fond of
                            honey, but does not extract the honey from the <pb n="79" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 79 comb.
                            He eats it just as it is taken from the hivewith the honey, bee bread and bee grubsall are
                            consumed with equal satisfaction. The larva of the caterpillar is eaten as are the beetles
                            and their grubs. They eat butterflies the same as the Egyptians eat locusts. Reptiles form a
                            part of their diet. They will eat any kind of beast, bird, reptile or fish. They gather
                            moths by bushels; these are baked, and then the legs and wings are rubbed off, when they are
                            ready to be eaten. An Australian can go on a day's journey, and by hanging a small snake and
                            a rat to his girdle, he has no fear of hunger at the hour of dinner. A snake is considered
                            one of the greatest of delicacies and he is always easy in his mind, so long as he can catch
                            one. "The Digger Indians of North America are said to eat sand, rats and bugs. Crickets are
                            pounded and made into a paste, and enjoyed as a rare feast. Worms, grubs lizards and horned
                            frogs are also eaten." This will not seem so strange when we refer to the Bible and to the
                            command that was given to Noah. "Every living thing that moveth shall be food for you," and
                            the worms and lizards and horned frogs did move. Some of the missionaries to Africa said
                            they occasionally had white ants served as a delicacy. Dr. Junker says, "After a while I
                            could eat fried ants with as much relish as any of the natives." Dr. Brazza sat down cne day
                            to eat dinner with the natives. He was very hungry and enjoyed his palatable dish which he
                            supposed to be fish, but when he told the delighted cook of this fact, he was informed that
                            it was a snake. The information ruined his appetite. "The Hottentots and Bosjesmans eat
                            strongly tainted meat as eagerly as though it were fresh. They hunt the ostrich, and if
                            lucky enough to get one bird and a nest of eggs they are made very happy. They are quite
                            indifferent as to the quality of the eggs. If they should be addled or have a chick partly
                            grown they think themselves in luck." "Blood and fat are used in medicinal preparations.
                            They also eat the eggs and larva of the white ant. Some tribes keep their milk in bags made
                            of skins and draw from them as often as it is wanted. These milk bags are never washed, but
                            a little sour milk is left in them to aid in coagulation. If pieces of butter should luckily
                            be found, they are valued, though not for eating; these are reserved for the more important
                            office of greasing the hair or the skin. These nations eat corn, melons, pumpkins and many
                            kinds of roots. They also eat dogs, cats, ants, mice, lizards, snakes, cs terpillars and
                            other creatures. Many kinds of insects and their larva are also eaten. Ingenious hooks are
                            make by which the larva are drawn from the hiding places in the ground or under the bark of
                            the trees." "The Kytch tribe will eat mice without removing the skin. If the bonus aiv, too
                            large, they are pounded and the whole mass is made into a sort of porridge. These people
                            keep herds of cattle but never kill one to eat, but if it should happen to die they will use
                            it as food. One tribe eats crocodile meat, also boiled monkej ; indeed, a well cooked monkey
                            is considered a rare dish. They make a pudding of meal mixed with blood. A palatable dish is
                            made of liver and the stomach chopped up fine and mixed with the half digested grains
                            therein and this is flavored with the contents of the gall bladder and highly seasoned with
                            pepper, salt and onions, and eaten uncooked. The dirt-eaters of South America seem to enjoy
                            the eating of a species of soft and smooth clay. It is not their only food, but is eaten
                            when other food, such as alligators and turtles begin to fail. The young turtles are eaten
                            just as they are caught, without removing the bones or any other part." (To be
                        continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A beggar raised to wealth..." TEIform="index"/>A beggar raised to wealth...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A beggae raised to wealth, is generally unmindful of any but himself.</p></div2><pb n="80" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bible Class" TEIform="index"/>From the Bible Class.</head><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New love" TEIform="index"/>THE NEW LOVE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Rothwell, Flora" TEIform="persName"/>By Flora Rothtwell.</byline><p TEIform="p">Closely allied to the "New Commandnu'nt" is the new love, which characterizes the
                                disciples of Christ, who are ever ready to bear and forbear, give and forgive, and would
                                willingly suffer pain to alleviate another's sorrow. It is written of those who love the
                                Lord, that, "their leaf shall be green and they shall not cease to bring forth fruit."
                                It is also recorded that love is as strong as death." Surely this is no vague imagery,
                                nor could it be classed with the love that "waxeth cold." Love is represented in the
                                words: "Many waters can not quench love neither can floods drown it." This love is no
                                fitful feeling which comes at extraordinary seasons, but it is a continual, abiding
                                principle in the soul. St. John writes, "This is the love of God, that we keep his
                                commandments." We often read of David's love to God in the words; "As pants the hart for
                                cooling streams, so longeth my soul for thee, O God." Genuine love to God, calls forth
                                similar desire; not as a child who loves and serves his parents, expecting the benefits
                                which they can bestow; nor as the self-deceived one who loves God on account of
                                blessings received from his hand, but who never would voluntarily make a personal
                                sacrifice from the love of a Godlike life; or would suffer the good he might do, to
                                stand unrewarded. But the true Christian loves and delights in the law of God, and his
                                chief source of grief is, that he falls short of keeping it to its fullness according to
                                his understanding. And if disappointment follows his efforts, he never wearies, for the
                                "fruits of humble trusting grace," are offered as his tribute of love to God in this
                                hour of testing. "Thou shalt love the Lord thy God with all thy heart, and with all thy
                                soul, and with all thy strength, and with all thy mind; and thy neighbor as thyself."
                                Love to the neighbor is the fruit of genuine love to God and is the fruit of
                                sellsacrifice. .Better still is that unalterable true love to God, which finds its
                                source in our heart of hearts, dependent on no time or circumstance, place or emotion,
                                to diffuse and circulate its power, but resting in our lives as an increasing substance,
                                gaining in strength and depth with passing years and growing experience. The selfish
                                love of the natural .heart is but an undesirable counterfeit of the love of God, for
                                God"s love is a creator of peace and harmony, rather than strife. The love of the old
                                dispensation taught ''Love thy neighbor and hate thine enemy," but Jesus said, "Love
                                your enemies, bless them that despitefully use you," "For if ye love them that love you
                                what thank have ye." "Be ye therefore perfect even as your Father which is in heaven is
                                perfect." For "He maketh his rain to fall on the just and on the unjust." "Love one
                                another as I have loved you." How did Jesus manifest his love? He says, "I lay down my
                                life for the sheep." This is the love of God. If we could "look into the seed-time of
                                life and say which grain would grow and which would not," how mercifully we would extend
                                the love of God, and how bountifully, according to our limited capacity, would we bestow
                                our best efforts for the increasing good of others. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Taylor, Caroline" TEIform="index"/>Caroline Taylor 
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Caroline Taylor at Pleasant Hill, Ky. Feb. 25, 1899. Age 63 years. Sister Caroline
                                entered the Society when a child, and has been a kind and worthy Sister. Peace to her
                                memory. J. W. S. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pilot, Maria" TEIform="index"/>Maria Pilot
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Maria Pilot, at Watervliet, O. April 6, 1899. Age 81 years and 24 days.
                                J. O. T.</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p19"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
POPULAR SCIENCE
NEWS.
H
Nature, Inventicm,
Archaeology, Electricityliri I Til
Chemistry, Mineralogy,IILnL I 11
lealth, Hygiene, Medicine.
Formerly  Boston  Journal  of Chemistry
ENLARGED artd IMPROVED.
This popular monthly contains a large number of Short, Easy. Practical, Interesting and
Popular, Scientific articles, that can be Appreciated and Enjoyed by any intelligent reader,
even though he knew little or nothing of Science. It is intended to interest those who think
Profusely illustrated and Free
from Technicalities
Entirely Different from and much superibr to
other papers  with a similar name.
Monthly,   $1.60 per year.    Newsdealers,   15  ots.
Largest Circulation of any
Scientific Paper.        .
LILLAED & CO.,
108 Pulton St., New York.
4S~Mention this paper for a sample copy
 to advanced thought peoplesam ple copy of the mos'   original  and
practical occult journal of the  age.
The exponent of West Gate Philosophy.
A. new occult system.An unlimited Held of labor open to teachers, lecturers
and healers.   Address,
The ORACLE, Sta. A.     Boston, Mnss.
IN   MEMORIAM
Eldresses
Dorothy A, Durgin,
Joanna J, Kaime,
The book contains photographs of the
Sisters, and also a short biographical
sketch.    A notice of the Memorial Service
including several pieces of music.      Many
letters of sympathy  from  friends  not  of
the Community.
A copy of the book may be obtained by
addressing Hart & Shepard,
East Canterbury, N. H.
Price, Cloth, 75 cts.    Boards 50 cts.
WITHOUT   DOUBT
THE BEST FAMILY PAPER  PUBLISHED
IS   THE
NEW   YORK   WEEKLY   WITNESS.
16 Pages.   Only   $1 a year.
THE
Has a very wide scope, comprising as it
does the following departments:
Editorials,
Spirit of the Press,
Scientific and Instructive,
The Odd and Uncommon,
Our Country's Hope,
Foreign News,
A Talk With the Doctor,
Around the Hearth
Little Men and Women.
Weekly Articles by George R. Scott
Titlmas'e'N Sermon,
Money and Business,
World-Wide Field,
Our Family Story.
Farm and Garden,
 Reports,
SABBATH READING.
16 Pages.   Only 50 cents a Year.
An Inter-denominational Weekly Paper.
Sabbath Reading is solely religious.
No news; no politics. A grand paper
for the truth-seeker.    It contains:
!E2 tutorial.
Christian Endeavor Topic,
Eptvorth Lvalue Xopic,
Sallath-Mchool LfNNon,
Choice Poetry,
Good Stories,
Reports o Missions,
Mothers' Saliltath At'ternoon
fTith the Children,
And a mass of matter carefully selected.
 Send for free sample copies of Witness
and Sabbath Reading. And send for
free sample pages of our Bagster's Bible.
Address
J 0 E N D 0 U a A L L100., 150 Nassau Street, New Tork.
Market
FREE
WITNESS
<pb n="" id="p20"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
ROYAL
Baking
Powder
Absolutely PURE
Makes the food more delicious and wholesome
ROYAL BAKING POWDER CO., NEW YORK.
SHAKER HAMAMELIS
(WITCHHAZEL,)
A. remedy for Cuts, Bums, Scalds,
Headache, Sore  Throat and all
cases of external inflammation
Taken internally for Bowel
Complaint, Bleeding of the
Lungs or Bowels, and for
all aches and pains.        f
For use externally, bathe the parts and
lay on a cloth wet with the Extract,    Internally, take one half teaspoonful three
times a day.    Use hot or cold.
Ask your druggist for it or send your
order to Arthur Bruce.
East Canterbury, N. H.
50   YEARS'
EXPERIENCE
Trade Marks
Designs
Copyrights &c.
Anyone sending a sketch and description may
quickly ascertain our opinion free whether an
invention is probably patentable. Communications strictly confidential. Handbook on Patents
sent free. Oldest agency for securing patents.
Patents taken through Munn & Co. receive
special notice, without charge, in the
Scientific American.
A handsomely illustrated weekly. Largest circulation of any scientific journal. Terms, $3 a
year; four months, $1.   Sold by all newsdealers.
MUNN & Co.36lBroadwa> New York
Branch Office, 625 F St., Washington, D. C.
HOW TO MAKE MONEY!
If you are out of employment and want
a position paying you from $50 to $100
monthly clear above expenses by working
regularly, or, if you want to increase your
present income from $200 to $500 yearly,
by working at odd times write the GLOBE
CO. 723 Chestnut St. Phila., Pa. stating
age, whether married or single, last or
present employment, and you can learn
how to make more money easier and
faster than you ever made before in your
life.
HAVE YOU "'COMMON SENSE?"
If not, send at once for a free copy of this
liberal-minded advocate of advanced
thought, which brings health and
success.    Address
"Common Sense," M. O. 55 State St.
Chicago, III.
AUTHORISED   EXILES
OP
THE   SHAKER   COMMUNITY.
The religious basis of the Order must
be a fdiindation resting on the principle of
righteousness, which principle is God.
This should rule the life of the individual for the protection of his own soul, for
the peace of the family and as an evidence
of his upright standing before the world,
Pric, 10 ct.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>