<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ss0403" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">Shaker and Shakeress</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Society</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Mount Lebanon, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">4</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">3</biblScope><date value="18740301" TEIform="date">March 1874</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">17-24</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="4" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="17" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="3" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!-- <p>Vol. IV. No. 3. PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETY. F. W. EVANS, Editor. Mt. Lebanon, Ool. Co. N. Y.. March, 1874r.
                        Fifty Cents per annum.</p>
                    --><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="About the mennonites" TEIform="index"/>ABOUT THE MENNONITES</head><p TEIform="p">A letter from a member of the House of Representatives, who was asked for information: "
                                I went first thing this morning to the Department. Results : Two years ago, U. S. consul
                                at Odessa, addressed Interior Department. Mennonites came from Germany to Russia, the
                                Emperor Paul promising military immunity. Present emperor threatened to withdraw this,
                                hence Mennonites question American consul about his country. Next, last spring appeared
                                Heller, attorney for Mennonites, and personally questioned Interior Department. Next, in
                                October, came Mennonites in person. Cornelius Janzen, Berlin, Ontario, Canada. That's
                                your man. He is spokesman, and will spend the winter in Ontario. Rev. John Funk,
                                Elkhart, Indiana, knows something. I assume this, simply because Janzen visited him
                                before he went to Canada. They [Mennonites] still speak German; have decided to settle
                                in the United States instead of Canada. That's all they know here. So you must write
                                Janzen, and mayhap visit him."</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, December 21, 1873" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, Columbia December 21 Co.,
                                1873.</head><p TEIform="p">To Cornelius Jansen: Esteemed Friend — I understand that you are the authorized agent of
                                the Russian Mennonites, who contemplate emigrating to America. I address you greeting,
                                on behalf of the United Society of Believers in Christ's Second Appearing (commonly
                                called Shakers, or Shaking Quakers), in these United States. There is a strong bond of
                                religious sympathy between the two Orders. In theological views we may differ somewhat,
                                until we understand each other; but we are one in spirit, and in the desire to serve God
                                without regard to self. Our Founders fled from England, as you propose to flee from
                                Russia, for conscience sake. And, having " clean escaped the corruptions that are in the
                                world through lust," by all living together as brethren and sisters, a pure holy,
                                religious, celibate life, they and their successors have established, in different
                                States, some sixty Communities having " all things in common." Many flock to these
                                households of faith, partly for the temporal advantages to be therein obtained. The late
                                general " suspension of faith," or decline in the religious elements, throughout
                                Christendom, together with the universal uprising of the war spirit, which permeates all
                                the sects and churches — Greek, Catholic and Protestant—is turning the Clmrch-and-State
                                Governments of the world into blood, as their highest source of delight, and their most
                                intoxicating drink. The " two tcitnesses" — male and female — have borne their
                                testimonies against war as being anti-Christian, throughout the reign of "the beast and
                                his image"—1,260 years — and have endured persecution and death, rather than kill their
                                fellow-beings. The Moravians, the Quakers, and the Mennonites, are links in that great
                                chain, extending from the First Christian Church (whose members would not fight in the
                                Roman armies, and who had " all things in common," in communities, for three hundred
                                years, and did neither marry nor give in marriage during that long period of time), to
                                the Second Christian Church, which is built upon the Rock of a new Divine Revelation;
                                and which, during a hundred years, has been inspired by the same Christ Spirit, and has
                                faithfully carried out the very same principles which, in the sight of even all nominal
                                Christians, formed the crown of glory, and palm of victory, of the Jewish Pentecostal
                                Church. Dear friend, our object in thus addressing you, is to ascertain whether, among
                                the great body of Mennonites, there be not a small body of deeply spiritual-minded
                                religious souls who are inwardly hungering and thirsting after more righteousness, and
                                who, in response to the voice from the kingdom of heaven upon earth (now in existence),
                                saying, " Come up hither," on to higher ground ! would " rise and stand upon their
                                feet," and ascend up, like " a cloud of witnesses," into the Shaker Communities. If
                                there be such a company (having according to the flesh, fathers and mothers, and
                                brothers and sisters, and children, and houses and land, or their equivalents), who will
                                " forsake all for Christ's sake, and his Gospel "— all the relations appropriate to the
                                generative earthly order — and will come up into the Resurrection state, wherein these
                                are all forsaken, left behind, and supplanted by their spiritual correspondencies, they
                                would be welcomed, as the children of the Spirit, to our hearts and homes, our houses
                                and lands, now, in this life, and, in the world to come, they shall have, with us, an
                                eternal relation in the heaven of heavens. From the above remarks, do not adopt the
                                popular error that the Shakers, any more than did Jesus, condemn marriage per se. The
                                earthly or Adamic order is for propagating human beings on this earth. In so doing,
                                however, Nature's laws (as kept by the lower animals, which do not copulate except for
                                offspring), should be strictly observed by men and women. Nor should they war or fight,
                                or kill their own species. Land should be accessible to all, as " Moses, the servant of
                                God," taught, when he gave to each individual an inheritance therein, and appointed a
                                Jubilee wherein to restore it when lost. And while on the one hand, if all were Shakers,
                                the world would run out; on the other, if all men and women were married, and reproduced
                                their kind, the whole earth would soon become, like China, unable to sustain its own
                                children. Hence there would be a necessity for infanticides, diseases, famines,
                                pestilences, desolating wars, etc., in order to keep population in check. And I submit
                                whether, to be consistent, the great body of the Mennonites, in fleeing from Russia
                                because they will not fight, should not separate from amongst themselves a small body of
                                Mennonites as an "offering to the Lor(i"— a Prophetical or Melchizedek people, who
                                should be as a holy priesthood : the first or larger portion being as a new earth; the
                                second or smaller portion, as a new heaven. Again, I would suggest that, as the landed
                                possessions of our Communities are large, and (owing to the aforesaid decline in the
                                religious element in Christendom), our numbers comparatively few, there may be Shaker
                                families, and perhaps Societies, who would be willing to sell out their possessions to
                                the Mennonites. They would thus have, not only large estates in land, but buildings
                                already erected, and ready for use; in which events, both classes of Mennonites would be
                                accommodated: those who choose to " do well," and marry; and those who might choose to"
                                do better," by uniting with the Shakers in a more self-denying and Christ-like life.
                                With kindest regards, and prayers that you may be providentially directed for the good
                                of your people, and the honor and glory of God, I am your friend in the truth, On behalf
                                of the Shaker Order in America. An early answer is respectfully solicited. F. W. E.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Berlin, Ontario, January 2, 1874" TEIform="index"/>Berlin, Ont., { January 2,1874.)</head><p TEIform="p">F. W. Evans, Esq., Lebanon, N. Y. Dear Sir: Your kind letter and enclosed pamphlets of
                                December 21, were received in due time, but as the subject is a very important one, and
                                my time at the present much occupied by an extended correspondence, etc., I only wish to
                                acknowledge, with these few lines, the receipt of yours, and to state, that there are
                                several families in Russia acquainted with me, who are in full sympathy with you, and I
                                will not fail to communicate to them about the matter, and to write to you again as soon
                                as possible. Believe me to be very truly, Yours,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Jansen, C" TEIform="persName"/>C. Jansen</byline></div3></div2><pb n="18" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mennonites" TEIform="index"/>MENNONITES</head><p TEIform="p">"Ward" says, "The Mennonites are descended from the tolerably pure evangelical Waldenses, who
                            were driven, by persecution, into various countries ; lived, simple, exemplary lives; in the
                            villages as farmers ; in the towns by trades, possessing the most pure Christian principles,
                            which they exemplified in a holy life and conversation. They fled to Flanders, and Zeland,
                            in the 12th Century. There were then two sects of them, the one distinguished by the
                            perfect, who held to celibacy and community of goods; the other, the imperfect. The greater
                            part of them were the most pious Christians the Church ever saw. By the labors of Menno
                            Simons, they obtained a regular state of Church order in 1536. They were formerly called
                            Anabaptists, but subsequent to this arrangement, Mennonites. They are considered In Church
                            Histories as the only Christian community which has stood on the platform of the Judean
                            Christian Church, since the days of the Apostles. They plead for universal toleration in
                            religion, debar none from their societies who live pious lives, and own the Scriptures as
                            the "Word of God. They object to the term Trinity, referring to God. They are utterly averse
                            to oaths, war, and capital punishment, as contrary to the spirit of Christianity. In their
                            private meetings every one has liberty to speak, expound the Scriptures, and pray. They
                            decline salaries from Government for their priests. Their Church worship, at present, is
                            conducted similarly to the Dutch Reformed. There are, already, in the United States, more
                            than two hundred Mennonite Churches, some containing three hundred members."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Theological treasury" TEIform="index"/>THEOLOGICAL TREASURY</head><p TEIform="p">JESUS. At the head of Christianity, stands one of " Nature's noblemen "— Jesus. In him we see
                            a man without a creed, unless a fanatical love for a pure life may be considered a creed.
                            This love made and makes all Christian disciples as one in their thoughts, and identical in
                            their lives. Love is not an indefinable, inexpressible illustration, as many would incline
                            to believe—a pretty word, but a myth! There is nothing that can exceed this love in making
                            individuals alike in their life ; and consequently, in their theology, which is of small
                            account. If any say they love Jesus, or any one else ; or any thing like the testi- mony and
                            life of Jesus, the only evidence of their sincerity is the assimilation of their character
                            with what they assert they love. We become like unto that which we love, as really as "the
                            sparks fly upward," or " water inevitably seeks its level;" and this truism remains intact,
                            regardless of what we merely express of love by words. This truth has an important bearing
                            upon the constitution of our Treasury. As an evidence : Among the millions who say they love
                            Jesus, let them become like him ; and let them commence by simply living a virgin life ; or
                            by abstaining from fleshly lusts, as did Jesus ! As a Jew, Jesus loved the Jewish Law; hence
                            he lived out its principles in his youth — kept its provisions with commendable punctuality.
                            He never condemned the Law of the Jews ; and, up to the time of his conversion to
                            Christianity, and his baptism by John, we know not that he declared his love for any thing
                            in preference to Jewish Provisions. And even then he did not condemn the Jewish Law ; nor
                            did he attempt its suppression ; but he did supplant this by superior characteristics in
                            life ! One of the noblest instances that could occur in the life of any one, was
                            demonstrated by Jesus' answer to the rich young Jew ; " Keep the Law ! " To the sectarians
                            of to-day, this would seem a lost opportunity to make a convert; but the sequel showed the
                            wisdom of the remark, in preference to immediately enjoining the newly-received principles
                            of the Gospel of Christianity. A good Jew, is very much better than a poor, hybrid
                            Christian, and Jesus appreciated this fact. So long as Jesus loved Judaism better than the
                            principles of Christianity, which he had not yet conceived, he lived like a good Jew ; but,
                            when he learned of the higher law of the Christ, which he was the first to conceive,
                            practice, and then to teach, then his love for the better, changed his thoughts and life;
                            and then, by his love for the superior law, came his conversion to Christianity ! We are
                            edified by the spiritualism of Jesus ; we love it, and purpose to keep it. We wonder at his
                            paucity of theology ; and yet we propose to have only as much, and with this, our Treasury
                            will be filled. True, he did introduce a system, which, when its principles are adopted,
                            will cause a separation from the soul, of all that constitutes the life of Adam —
                            generative, or worldly. And, as a matter of economy, expedition, and success, the
                            prosecution of a superstructure upon a model Jewish organization is more possible and easy,
                            than upon any other of which we know. Humiliating though it may be, the well-ordered life of
                            a good Jew is sooner and easier carried into a brilliant Christian, than the best Gentile
                            that has yet been presented ! And this truth will appear cogent to the philosopher who is
                            able to compare Jewish antecedents, physiology, and law generally, with the same of any
                            thing constituting a departure therefrom. From the numerous tenets put forth by professedly
                            Christian Churches, we are variously inclined to think that Jesus was an iin- tnense
                            theologian ; and as erratic in theology, as multitudinous in ideas. I would show him to be a
                            lover and a model Exemplar of a better life, rather than a multiplier of new ideas. If I
                            thought of Jesus as a theologian, I should soon forget him; but, as an ever-enduring
                            monument of living purity I have in him, a morning acquaintance, a noon-day companion, and
                            an evening guest, always happifying, and always new! With Parker, I have, in this nobleman
                            of Nature, " the possiblity of the race," and, by example, not as proxy, a hope of the
                            salvation and redemption of the race from any and every fall, to the highest and truest
                            standard.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/>G. A. Lomas</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Coming events cast their shadows before" TEIform="index"/>COMING EVENTS CAST THEIR SHADOWS
                            BEFORE</head><p TEIform="p">Something like forty years ago, when the Shaker Community at Union Village, Ohio, was full of
                            people, and, in the zenith of its prosperity, Jason and Daniel, Prophets, from Canada, made
                            a visit there. The Prophets had hospitable reception, and were in ecstacies of delight — for
                            a season. But the spirit of sadness came over Daniel. He seemed caught up, as were Prophets
                            of old. Looking thro' the Prophetic telescope, he exclaimed, " They are going ! —¦ They are
                            going!! — 'Twould seem they'd all go But they'll not. There'll be some left." For a time,
                            animation seemed suspended. A new scene burst upon his vision. He arose clapping his hands,
                            he exclaimed —" They come! — From the East, and the West, and the North, and the South !!
                            'Twould seem the whole world would come." The Prophets were in a second transport of joy,
                            largely exceeding the first.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spirit correspondence" TEIform="index"/>SPIRIT CORRESPONDENCE</head><p TEIform="p">Edwin M. Stanton, late Secretary of War, to the Father of the Nation, Ulysses S. Grast, to
                            whom I bow with respect and honor. Be not astonished at my communication ; but receive it
                            from a heart warm with brotherly affection and love. My spiritual eyes are now open, and I
                            can see the order and beauty of the new creation, and am anxious for the dawn of a new day,
                            when many shall be baptized in the river of life, from which peace and purity perennially
                            flow. After the close of the war, and a short time before my departure from earth, I was
                            invited to make a visit to the Shakers of Mt. Lebanon, which I accepted ; and, in the few
                            days I was with them, I enjoyed the most comfort, and received the greatest amount of good
                            to my soul, that I ever experienced; and I look upon it as the greenest and brightest spot
                            in the field of my memory. I humbly solicited their prayers to God for me, that I might be
                            guided by Wisdom to perform my official duties. I had often bowed myself in sincere prayer
                            to God, and I put my trust more in his power, than I did in my own abilities, or in weapons
                            of war, to put down the Rebellion. I was convinced that, as a people, the Shakers were
                            nearer the Throne of God, and more accessible to Him, than myself, becavise of the greater
                            purity of tlieir lives ; and I felt unworthy to be in their midst, yet was blest by their
                            kind reception and frequent expressions of tender sympathy, which seemed to pervade their
                            whole being with impartial love for all humanity ; and I knew that they had often offered
                            prayers to God in my behalf, as also for all the officials at the seat of Government, that
                            Wisdom would guide all our proceedings ; and that the Union of the States might be re-
                            gained, with a permanent increase. From a previous acquaintance with some of them, I had
                            gained a love to that people which carried and bore my spirits up, through all the trying
                            scenes of adversity that I was afterwards called to pass through, till my work was closed on
                            earth. I had inquired of them the origin of their Society, their first Founder, etc., and
                            received liberal information, satisfactory to my feelings. They informed me that they
                            originated through the ministrations of some of the French Prophets in England; and that the
                            immediate Founder of tlieir Society was of the Quaker Order. Her name was Ann Lee. Her
                            followers call her their Mother in the New Creation. In 1770, while in prison, on account of
                            her mode of worshiping God in the dance, she received a baptism of the Christ Spirit, and
                            saw in vision the loss and depth of the fallen nature of both man and woman. She was called
                            to go forth and proclaim to the world—especially to those of her own sex —the way of
                            redemption from sin, and from the bondage of the flesh. In 1774, she received a revelation,
                            directing her and eight of her followers to repair to America, and they arrived in New York
                            on the 6th of August of that year. I had long had a strong desire to see her spirit; and
                            often prayed that I might be gathered to the Shakers in the spirit world, when I had done
                            with time ; for I desired to dwell with the pure in heart. In my last sickness, I was
                            frequently impressed that Shaker spirits were near ; and the innocence of their <pb n="19" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKEEESS. 19 angelic countenances soothed my troubled mind, and knit me still
                            closer to them. On one occasion I saw, in a night vision, the answer of my prayers :— " A
                            woman clothed with the sun, with a crown of stars upon her head, and the moon under her
                            feet;" and a breast-plate with these words written thereon: "And she shall be called the
                            Lord our Righteousness, the Mother of the New Creation, the Redeemer of the human race." She
                            stood with Jesus, the first Saviour of men. Around her was a band of holy angels, who were
                            continually passing and repassing, and receiving from her hand, transparent seals, with
                            these words upon them : " These are the pure in heart." And they placed the seals upon the
                            foreheads of the surrounding multitude of angelic spirits, who stood at her right hand, on
                            an ascending plane, illuminated with her brightness. While those on the left who came the
                            nearest, were only in the shadow, and on a descending plane, and did not receive seals. I
                            greatly desired to possess a seal. I was a great way off', quite in the rear, and on the
                            left side; but, as my spiritual eyes were open, I beheld the glory of God, and the
                            brightness of eternal Love, upon that female. So bright was its illumination, that it put
                            the sunshine of Nature in the shade; and those living in Nature had only the light of the
                            moon. There was a gulf between me and that holy band, into which I had got to enter ; and,
                            to do this, I had to cast off my filthy garments; I had also to read, before appointed
                            witnesses of God, the record of my whole life—every deed, one by one, as they were engraven
                            on the book of my memory ; the good on the righthand page, and the evil on the left, before
                            I could ascend that plane, so beautiful, or receive the golden seal. I awoke from my vision,
                            and was satisfied that I had seen the spirit visage of Mother Ann. At my last closing
                            breath, a lovely spirit from the higher Order, asked me what class of spirits I desired to
                            be gathered to; and I said, " To the pure in heart;" and he bore me to that Order, with whom
                            I am now united in faith, and am daily striving to be clothed with the brightness of their
                            glory. And, through their agency, I have selected, from among the Shakers, a Medium. I
                            remain your friend and spirit brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stanton, Edwin M." TEIform="persName"/>Edwin M. Stanton</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My humble request is..." TEIform="index"/>My humble request is...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/>Editor</byline><p TEIform="p">My humble request is, that, if I may be accounted worthy, you would give the above
                            communication a place in the " Shaker and Shakeress." Given at Mt. Lebanon, Jan. —,
                        1874.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To the President of the United States of America—Ulysses S. Grant—from the spirit of ex-secretary                                 Edwin M. Stanton" TEIform="index"/>TO THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA- ULYSSES S. GRANT- FROM THE SPIRIT OF EX-SECRETARY EDWIN M. STANTON</head><p TEIform="p">My worthy friend and fellow-laborer: Although you are yet on the earthly plane, and I in the
                            spirit sphere, yet I am privileged to grasp the hand of one whom I esteem as a brother and
                            true friend, with a new year's greeting. It is the commencement of a new year, and I do not
                            meet you, as formerly, to feast upon luxuries and be merry; but, instead thereof, to present
                            to you my richest and best of all gifts — the greeting of the heavenly hosts. Peace and good
                            will to the earthly man and woman! The kingdom of heaven is established, and its
                            righteousness must be fulfilled upon earth. For, on every plane, those only who fear God can
                            be accepted of Him. And how can this be accomplished, while the earth is groaning under its
                            heavy weight of sin and condemnation ? Even the seat of Government is defiled; its doors are
                            daily darkened by those who are guilty of the blackest of crimes, and think they are covered
                            from the eyes of the people. But they are seen. These are hard sayings, which all men cannot
                            receive. But you, my brother, I believe, can and will treasure them up in an honest heart,
                            and let them have their perfect work, to the purifying of your own temple, and the cleansing
                            of the official departments in which you are called to toil and labor for the good of all
                            who are subject to your Administration. You are chosen to be the Father of the Country, and
                            that is why I thus address you upon these important subjects. I take the liberty to converse
                            with you freely, with all confidence, as one friend converseth with another ; believing that
                            your noble mind will be in unison with my sentiments, even as they were in days gone by,
                            when these subjects were too delicate, and too near home, for us to talk about, or inter
                            fere with, while I was with you in the body. But be assured, my friend, that, when I came to
                            enter the spirit world, and the record of my life was laid open before me, I found my
                            private and official sins of omission and commission stood against me. And, as there are
                            three years more to come before the close of your Administration, I beseech you to " work
                            while the day lasts," and put forth your best energies to search out the hidden abominations
                            that are daily in operation at the seat of Government, by those who collect there for the
                            purpose of enacting laws for the protection of the people. How can an evil tree produce good
                            fruit ? It does not, and cannot, nor can it prosper. This evil tree, whose branches spread
                            over the entire city of Washington, whose fruits are dens of debauchery and whoredom,
                            together with murders, thefts, deceit, lies, forgery and hypocrisy, must be hewn down, and
                            dug up by the roots. That city ought to be consecrated to God, and occupied by pure-minded
                            men and women, who will devote every faculty of soul and body to the honor and glory of God,
                            and to the redemption of the human race in the earthly order, inspiring and raising the
                            people up to a higher and holier life; instead of sinking themselves still lower in
                            filthiness and condemnation, until the very atmosphere is dense with its stench and
                            putrefaction. I warn you to be prepared ; for the old heavens and the old earth must pass
                            away ; and there must be a new heaven and a new earth, wherein not any thing can dwell that
                            defileth or maketh a lie. But the will of God shall be done in the earthly order, even as it
                            is done in the heavenly. The Lord is searching your camps " as with a lighted candle ;" and
                            He will yet expose to the light, and set before every soul his and her true state and
                            standing; and " every knee shall bow, and every tongue confess their abominations; and every
                            error of their life will have to be corrected, and washed away by humiliation and
                            repentance." Yea, even the mouths of infants will be opened, and they will rise up in
                            judgment against the guilt and shame of their unnatural parents, and the judgment will be
                            justly divided between the male and the female, according to their true merits ; for their
                            children will curse the day of their birth, because they were begotten in sin, and brought
                            forth in iniquity and disease. Thousands are made wretched and downcast, and are trodden
                            under foot of those " brutish " men, who have caused their ruin and distress, and whose
                            victims rend the heavens with their cries and lamentation; and their visages are engraven
                            upon ineftaceable records, there to remain, as a testimony against the transgressors, until
                            removed by confession, with tears of godly sorrow and repentance from both parties. These
                            things troubled me some while I was on earth. Now they are a distress to my spirit. I cannot
                            enjoy that true happiness for which my soul aspires, until I have fulfilled the duty in this
                            respect, which is encumbent on me in consequence of my former neglect; that is, clear my
                            soul from these causes of condemnation. My dear friend, I want that your Administration
                            should be crowned with success ; and that the brightness of the glory of God may illuminate
                            the Capital; so that " Peace and Goodwill to all nations" may be the motto engraven on its
                            portals ; and that wars and fightings may be known no more. May it become " a house of
                            prayer," where the laws of the nation shall be enacted by virtuous, pure-minded men and
                            women, raised up to stand in their proper rectitude, who shall fear neither men nor devils ;
                            but, in the fear of God, and by the help of their holy Mother, Love (the female in Deity),
                            be enabled, through your fatherly aid, to purge out these evils from the Rulers of the
                            Nation, and liberate their captive sisters, and restore them to their proper order and
                            calling in creation — help-mates together — striving for the honor and comfort of each other
                            in the earthly order. For, I say unto you, that the least among these oppressed ones will be
                            greater in the kingdom of heaven than the greatest among men who fear not God, nor keep his
                            commandments. The Ten Commandments, when kept, are all-sufficient to rule the whole world.
                            Peace and goodwill " shall cover the earth, as the waters cover the seas."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stanton, Edwin M." TEIform="persName"/>Edwin M. Stanton. Given at Mt. Lebanon, Jan.
                        14,1874</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Great intellects" TEIform="index"/>GREAT INTELLECTS</head><p TEIform="p">The abrupt discrepancy existing between the exceedingly splendid hues and colors of the
                            spread tail of a peacock, when it glistens in the morning sun, and his homely feet, has
                            often been noticed. Is there not much the same discrepancy existing between the mental
                            glories of the illustrious brain-workers of Babylon, and their immorality ? How very often
                            it has happened that in the actual every-day lives of these immortah) there was no
                            foundation of character — no pure morality — why go any further ? Is it meet for Shakers to
                            come into magnetic rapport with the incestuous Byron, the rowdy S, the drunken M, the
                            thievish Bacon, or the licentious "Bard of Avon? " Nay ! and yet we will, in due time, have
                            all of their noble, but much abused gifts, without the ugly peacock feet, to mar the
                            beautiful picture of: our spiritually-intellectual lives.</p></div2><pb n="20" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religion" TEIform="index"/>RELIGION</head><p TEIform="p">Religion is natural—innate ; and its latent powers become developed by the light of in-
                            telligence, reason and revelation. Now that " light " — a higher development of religion — "
                            is come i'nto the world, and you have no cloak for your sins." Religion is good armor but a
                            bad cloak. Man may possess a hundred theological systems of ideas, and still be destitute of
                            real religion—the right acts of life proper to each succeeding development of his religious
                            nature. Religion is obedience to God, improvement of selfhood, and love to man. It can never
                            be ingrafted on any foreign stock, and retain its original purity. It is augmented and
                            intensified in proportion to the enlightenment of the understanding. It has three phases of
                            development : The 'physical, the moral, and the spiritual. Obedience to the fundamental law
                            of animal life — Physiology — and a sacred regard for the proper introduction of life into
                            this world, and the needful training thereafter; instead of that weakness which forestalls
                            defeat — being born vanquished. The first step toward the attainment of " eternal life," is
                            to keep the commandments and observe the requirements of natural religion — physical and
                            physiological laws. The second step is to keep the Moral Law — to " do justly, love mercy,
                            and attend to the golden rule." " On earth peace, and unto men good will;" instead of the
                            religion (?) of Christendom — ill-will and war. " Sell all that thou hast, and give to the
                            poor," or Church, which has all things in common; and not generously give of your abundance
                            ; but divide all with the less fortunate, as on the day of Pentecost; and thus be equal — be
                            just — be religious. Justice is the higher moral obligation. It makes all places a temple ;
                            all seasons a summer. It is the prime virtue of those in command, and leaves no cause of
                            complaint for those who obey. It is the bread of the multitude, after which they all hunger.
                            It gives to all their " daily bread," and secures to the meek their rightful inheritance —
                            the eartk; for the Church owns the land. To go no further than bare justice, is to stop at
                            the beginning of a higher virtue. Love, the offspring of the third degree, or spiritual
                            religion, is the divine sequence of the fulfillment of the law of physical rectitude and
                            moral justice. Love sacrifices all things for its cherished object. Its roots, when in
                            virtue's soil, grow to enduring friendskip. But, when it acts independent of justice and
                            virtue, it becomes capricious and volatile, and even malevolent. Love is active in pursuit
                            of friendship, firm in possession. Can the injustice of inherited imbecility, and legalized
                            sensuality, beget love ? Nay ; there is no religion in the one, and it cannot be extracted
                            from the other. " The life is more than meat, and the body is more than raiment;" so is
                            religion more than theology. " Pure and undefiled religion," is to provide a permanent home
                            for all those wives who make themselves " widows indeed," and for all adult children who
                            make themselves " fatherless " and motherless orphans, " for the kingdom of heaven's sake,"
                            as well as for those " men " — husbands — " who will make themselves eunuchs " for the same
                            object ; and thus to " keep one's self unspotted, from " a selfish, physically and morally
                            prostituted " world," fortified behind the license of legalized but corrupt human
                            enjictments. For the Second Pentecostal (or Gentile Christian, or Shaker) Church, in which
                            "all things are common " to all, as in the First (or Jewish) Pentecostal Church, is where
                            the " widow and the fatherless " (as above) can not only be " visited," but are amply and
                            equally provided with all things necessary for life and godliness ; and where all are
                            required to " keep themselves unspotted from the world." There is no error in religion : it
                            is as true as truth. Error obtains in the systems of theology — false doctrines, the very
                            reverse of " Do the works, then shall ye know of the doctrines." Religion—the acts (not the
                            resolves), are Scripture; but Scripture record cannot make religion, although it may
                            stimulate and aid in the development of the innate and latent powers to action. Never
                            mistake the road for the city you expect to reach by it; nor a guide-board for a live man —
                            the means for the end. Water baptism was the symbol of repentance for physical and moral
                            sins; fire, for spiritual sins. Water cleanses; fire refines. Hence the grosser nature
                            perishes in the using, as the resurrection of the spirit obtains supremacy. Should the
                            classical scholar find his ubiquitous primer an impediment to indulging his matured
                            thoughts; or the mechanic find his boyhood toys constantly thrown in his way to hinder his
                            ambition to benefit the world, they would become hateful to them; not that they were hateful
                            in themselves, but because of their impertinence. And the child — the immature man — would
                            stand amazed to see the objects of absorbing interest to him thus cast aside. So with the
                            subjects of spiritual and heav- enly religion. Their resurrection life causes them to hate
                            natural relationship, and the generative life, when they obtrude out of their own order into
                            the realm of the spiritual; and also to hate the perversion of the generative life
                            everywhere. "If ye believe not his" (Moses1) " writings " — physical and moral religion — "
                            how shall ye believe my words ? "Effectual, fervent prayer"—-good deeds — will redeem the
                            world, usher in the Millennium, and " the song of Moses and the Lamb " will be fraught with
                            new harmony, which no irreligious man can ever learn.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, Elijah" TEIform="persName"/>Elijah Myrick, Shirley Village, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="About coal" TEIform="index"/>About Coal</head><p TEIform="p">Experiments have been made with a view to ascertain the amount of loss coal undergoes when
                            exposed to the weather. It will, perhaps, surprise many readers to hear that the loss is
                            considerable. Anthracite and cannel-coal, as might be anticipated from their compactness,
                            suffer least; but ordinary bituminous coal loses nearly one-third its weight and nearly
                            one-half its gas-making quality. From this it will be understood that coal should be kept
                            dry and under cover, and that to expose it to rain or damp is to lessen its quantity and
                            weaken its quality.</p></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="More than 328,000,000 persons..." TEIform="index"/>More than 328,000,000 persons...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">More than 328,000,000 persons, exclusive of season-ticket holders, traveled upon the railways
                            of England and Wales, in 1871. Out of this immense number, only six people were killed by
                            causes beyond their own control. The fatalities were in the proportion of one killed to
                            53,803,728 carried. Taking all the railways of the United Kingdom together, the deaths from
                            accident were but twelve during the year, of which two occurred in Scotland and four in
                            Ireland.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Moderation" TEIform="index"/>MODERATION</head><p TEIform="p">"Let your moderation be known to all men." —o— We live in a day of momentous events, and
                            social reforms ; and improvements move with lightning speed. Looking back, through a period
                            of fifty years, we behold springing into existence, railroads, telegraphs, ocean tele-
                            graphs, ocean steamers (or floating cities), ironclad vessels, heavy guns carrying balls of
                            600 lbs. weight several miles, tunnels piercing under and through mountains many miles,
                            costing twenty millions of dollars; Science, j in every direction, expediting the labor of
                            man by machinery applied to agriculture, as well as mechanical arts and domestic pursuits,
                            making the farm a great machine shop, and the woman's parlor or sitting room a sewing or
                            knitting factory. The effect, morally, of these things is to move human society along
                            through time on the journey of human progress with lightning speed, without even a brake to
                            steady the car of Progress around the curves of the track. The mental powers, especially of
                            juveniles, grasp faster and more than they can comprehend or digest, so as to be thereby
                            benefited. And, while scientific and religious views move so rapidly, the minds of mankind
                            are so completely swallowed up, in the rainbow hues of progress, charmed with fine
                            appearances of human gain, eagerly grasping at the variety of human benefits, huddled
                            together, in some minds, in a confused mass, that their mental and physical systems are
                            overwrought and paralyzed, rendering them measurably insane. But, while the mind is thus
                            floating in airy castles of imaginary bliss, grasping greedily the newly-revealed wonders of
                            science, art, and discovery in the universe of God, it is wise to consider that truth never
                            dies, nor grows rusty with age ; that those truths which were uttered thousands of years
                            ago, are the same unalterable truths to-day ; and that our knowledge of them is very
                            limited, and our comprehension of the dignity and expanse of Truth's realm, yet hidden from
                            our view, very small. Man is but a mite, a worm, Little heeded, little known : A germ of
                            something yet to learn: Why placed here, to weep and mourn? Eternity God's works declare,
                            He's set the bounds for mortals here ; Thus far, no farther, shalt thou share, Than earn'd
                            by diligence and prayer. Whence art thou, Mortal 1 Going where ? Why boast of knowledge
                            gained here 1 Eternity ! — bewildering thought — Will teach thee knowledge dearly bought.
                            Keep steady, ponder well; for safety choose the middle pathway in the march of progress.
                            Weigh well thy talents; be steadfast in the truth revealed to thee, and true to convictions
                            of right, both to thy God and thy fellow-man, then happiness and peace will crown thy
                            efforts. While the wheels of progress are in motion, and their rapid movements stir the
                            world from centre to the poles, keep the head and heart steady ; thus, man will better
                            comprehend and appreciate the purposes of the Divine Mind, relative to the final results of
                            progress.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Haskins, Orren N." TEIform="persName"/>Orren N. Haskins, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="From Mexico" TEIform="index"/>FROM MEXICO</head><p TEIform="p">Reforms Inaugurated — Church and State to be Separate—jESUfTS Banished—Monastic Orders Not
                            Recognized — Matrimony a Civil, Contract. Congress has decreed the following: The Church and
                            State are to be separate. Congress cannot make laws establishing or prohibiting any
                            religion. Matrimony is to be a civil contract. Religious institutions cannot possess
                            property. A simple promise to speak the truth, complying with obligations contracted, with
                            penalties in case of violation, is substituted for the religious oath. Nobody is obliged to
                            give his or her services without just compensation. No contract is to be permitted which
                            aims at the sacrifice of the liberty of man in the matter of work, education, and religious
                            vows. The laws consequently, do not recognize Monastic Orders, nor permit their
                            establishment by any denomination, or under any pretense. And no contract will be allowed to
                            be made among persons consenting to their own proscription or banishment.</p></div2><pb n="21" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakeress: education" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERESS: EDUCATION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">What is the line of demarcation between an educated and an uneducated person? If the amount
                            of letter learning, the knowledge that is obtained through the study of books, be the
                            criterion by which to determine, then it is an easy matter to define the status of individ-
                            uals in regard to education. Where it is said of anyone he has finished his education, it
                            must be relatively, and not absolutely so considered. A child may be instructed in the
                            elementary department of a common school, and receive all the knowledge that is to be gained
                            therefrom ; but it is only preliminary to something higher. When we get even a faint glimpse
                            of the construction of the human mind, so vast are its powers of receptivity and
                            elimination, we might as well think of setting bounds to Omnipotence as to mark the
                            boundaries of human progress in knowledge and understanding, through the ages of the great
                            future. In the earth-sphere of our existence, knowledge is bounded by time and
                            circumstances. If children were begotten and born by lawguided and law-abiding parents, and
                            there could be an equal distribution of the elements of subsistence among earth's
                            inhabitants, based upon a just inheritance in the soil, then the distinctive marks of caste
                            between rich and poor, educated and uneducated, would disappear to a great extent. Idiots
                            and physical deformities would pass behind the curtains of the dim past; and a new earth
                            with a new central light — civil polity and Jaws justly administered—would warm and vivify
                            the earthly Order, while the Sun of Divine revelation would give life and light to the new
                            heaven. Now, a chance fortunate few, give their whole lives to book-learning, and pleasure-
                            seeking. Such are chiefly theorists, who live by brain-work and speech-making; and they cast
                            all the muscular toils and drudgery of life upon the less favored. But all knowledge
                            relating to the external world in which we live, if justly acquired, and practically
                            applied, to aid humanity in the highway of physical, social, moral, and spiritual progress,
                            is good, and worthy of all commendation. Personal exertion, through honesty of purpose,
                            enriches whole nations. True knowledge attained, descends to succeeding generations, and is
                            a legacy of far greater worth than the miser's chest of gold, which is generally pocketed by
                            a few; while useful knowledge is given to the many; whether it relates to the stellar
                            regions — the Science of Astronomy — or to Geology, where, by the study of the different
                            strata of rocks and soils, knowledge is obtained concerning the historic periods of time,
                            and of the different races of men, and of the lower orders of animals; and also of the
                            nature of the soils, that they may better understand how to app]y fertilizers of different
                            kinds to advantage, or whether it be the study of Arboriculture, each and all is profitable
                            education. But, when we see men (who ought to have been created in the image of the
                            All-Father, through pride and ease-seeking, evade the heavy burdens of life, and willingly
                            eat the bread of idleness at the expense of others, rather than engage in tilling the soil,
                            and thus obtaining their bread by honest and honorable industry), dodge behind a counter in
                            a close room, with effeminate hands, and pale faces, measuring prints, and silks, and
                            ribbons, from early morn to dewy night, while scores of delicate females are out of
                            employment, homeless, and perhaps friendless, left to beggary and want, and who are
                            oftentimes forced to sell their virtue, or starve for the want of proper means by which to
                            earn an honest living, we are led to the conclusion, that, if " God," in the beginning, "
                            made man upright," " he has " since that time " sought out many " senseless " inventions."
                            And, when we see young women, who are endowed with intellectual and reasoning powers, and
                            are capable of becoming bright-leading stars in the world of reform, and who should be
                            counted with the true workers in helping to elevate the race from moral degradation, and in
                            raising a standard of Freedom for Woman, giving all their time and energies to the study of
                            the fine arts, to instrumental music, to speaking the French language, and to imitating
                            French manners, and in patronizing the fashions in dress, gotten up by the courtesans of
                            France, and call it " accomplished education," how can we help thinking of what the Lord
                            said by one of the olden Prophets : " I planted thee a noble vine, wholly a right seed ; how
                            then art thou turned into the degenerate plant of a strange vine unto me 1" And is this
                            happiness ? Do all those attainments satisfy the real desires, or supply the needs of the
                            human soul ? While in this life, those who possess wealth may employ others to provide food
                            and clothing for the mortal bodies ; but they cannot feed and clothe the immortal part. They
                            who neglect to do that work for themselves, will suffer hunger, spiritually ; and, when they
                            part from the tenement of clay, and become stripped of all their vain and worldly trappings,
                            and shall appear in the real character which they have formed in their earth life, will not
                            such feel shame and destitution ? While, on the other hand, those who conse- crate all the
                            powers of their being to useful ends and purposes, who seek to elevate and honor labor by
                            taking part in it, and feel that duty requires them to serve as well as to be served, and to
                            use the things of this world as God's blessings, and not abuse them ; when the death angel
                            comes, with his chariot to convey such spirits to their future home, will they not pass the
                            shadowy confines of earth, to new life and joys in the heavenly spheres, there to continue
                            the useful and the true in a world of realities; where they may learn to think, to speak,
                            and to act, as do the angels, and like them be robed in garments of spotless purity, and
                            listen to their sweet melodies ? All that is learned of the true and good while in the
                            earths sphere will be retained and be of use in the celestial spheres; and knowledge will be
                            added to knowledge while the ages roll</p></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dr. Letheby, cf London, the well-known sanitary statist..." TEIform="index"/>Dr. Letheby, cf London, the well-known sanitary statist...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Dr. Letheby, cf London, the well-known sanitary statist, has just reported as to the
                            adulteration of green tea in that city. He discovered, it appears, that some tea on sale in
                            Mincing lane required looking after, and he succeeded in getting authentic samples from the
                            bonded warehouses in which the article was stored. On examination it was found that this
                            so-called tea contained from forty to forty-three per cent of iron filings and nineteen per
                            cent of silica, in the form of fine sand, which had been cleverly mixed with and added to
                            the leaves before curling, with a view to increase their weight and bulk. After the leaves
                            were curled they had been thickly covered with green pigment. When it was infused in boiling
                            water it produced a very turbid solution, offensive to the smell and nauseous to the
                        taste.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Free indeed" TEIform="index"/>"FREE INDEED."</head><p TEIform="p">" O, Freedom, lovely in mine eyes, To thee I'm bound in duty I In thee is an eternal prize,
                            Thy ways are ways of beauty. As fawns upon the mountain's height, Or as the eagles in their
                            flight, To be in perfect liberty, My soul does long to be as free I" Eveky thing in nature,
                            from the bird on the wing to the pearl in the depth of the sea, lives a life of freedom,
                            choosing from among the surrounding elements those it needs to add to its development as
                            part of the perfect work of God ; and we see little to mar that perfection, save in those
                            whose simple habits of life have been modified by man, without attention to nature's laws of
                            periods and rests, etc. etc. And can we believe that humanity—God's highest work—should be
                            less free ? In the words of another, we believe that " There is no greater crime than to
                            stand between a man and his development; to take any law, or institution, and put it around
                            him like a collar, and fasten it there, so that as he grows and enlarges he presses against
                            it till he suffocates and dies." But we also read, that " whom the truth maketh free is free
                            indeed," and have believed that such freedom was attainable, and a duty. Consecrated to the
                            service of the eternal Good, we have sought deliverance from "the bondage of Sin" (not from
                            its condemnation, for that was mercy's work to lead us to repentance), and have felt called
                            to attain that " glorious liberty of the sons and daughters of God;" liberty to become the
                            Lord's free men and women, and arrive at the stature of manhood and womanhood, which no
                            state of subjection, or slavery, could possibly afford the conditions of attaining. For, not
                            only was the soul to be cultured and disciplined, but the body, by living in obedience to
                            God's laws was to become "every whit whole." And we see that the same work which the
                            manifestation of the Christ Spirit revealed in the life of oneness and equality of Jesus,
                            when he washed the disciples' feet, or stopped to speak comforting words to the suffering or
                            needy, was emphatically the Spirit of our Mother in the second manifestation of the Christ
                            Spirit. " Hands to work and hearts to God." No matter how high or exalted hitherto. " The
                            common people heard him gladly." They were " the vallies to be elevated." Many had already
                            formed habits of industry ; and they had the common people's contempt of monopoly and caste.
                            Then, with the steady habits which come of simple and unstimulated living,there was more
                            hope of gathering a band of self-deniers who could endure " the hardness " which would
                            follow those who could become Apostles of such disorganizing truths, as these were to be, in
                            all the elements of worldliness. That they fell peculiarly hard upon the rich and elevated,
                            we see from the callings of the twelve, from the words of Paul: "Not many great, not many
                            mighty are called • " and also from the account of '' the young man whom Jesus loved," but
                            who apparently had nothing dearer than his " great possessions " to stand between him and
                            self-denial. But even in this selected twelve, how soon the native lust for mastership
                            commenced, and broke forth, to be met with those pro- found words of the teacher: " Ye know
                            that 21 <pb n="22" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 22 SHAKER AND \ the rulers among the Gentiles exercise
                            dominion, or authority, over them. But it shall not be so among you; for whosoever would be
                            great, or chief, or ruler, let him be your minister, or servant. For, which is greater, he
                            that sitteth at (the table) meat, or he that pre- pareth it 1 but I am among you as he that
                            serveth " (a servant). " The Son of man came not to be ministered to." Therefore, the sons
                            and daughters who would follow him, are workers and toilers, ministering to their own
                            necessities, and lightening the burden of life in every available way for others. He assured
                            them, that, if they learned to rule and conquer their own lusts of dominion and possession,
                            they would eventually become " kings and priests " (in the temples of their bodies),
                            ministering to all sacred and consecrated uses, not the least of which would be the putting
                            away of sins by confession, through some appointed individuals of their number, as see John
                            20 : 23, and Mat. 16 : 18, 19. But, in this stage of the world, growing so fast republican,
                            theoretically, if not practically, " kings and priests " are not enviable characters. And
                            thus, while the illuminations from the celestial world have, ever since the opening of this
                            Dispensation, been growing brighter and clearer, that equality and brotherhood are the
                            radical truths which these messiahs came to consummate, and which can only be realized
                            through a virgin life, still we see that the struggle will be great and mighty, and that
                            none but those who love truth and justice better than their own carnal lives, can be
                            prepared to endure the trial. Power acquired and gradually increased, until it holds the
                            mastership and control of other human beings, whether male or female, reacts most painfully
                            upon the person using it; by hardening the heart, and deadening the sensibilities; so that
                            the mind that could once see the beauties and rightf ulness of freedom, and equality for all
                            the sons and daughters of God, can grasp its hold even on the conscience, and say, in
                            Spirit, Obey me, rather than thy own weak imaginings. The seeds of anguish which they thus
                            sow in sensitive and afflicted souls, must be harvested in their own spirits, ere they feel
                            the wrong they do. When the Prophet declared that " all should be taught of God," and that
                            his " law should be written on their hearts and inward parts," he saw, in vision, the day in
                            which we live, when the heavens are opening, and natural, spiritual, and celestial truths
                            are shining on the mind with a force and beauty hitherto unknown. All new truths, however
                            popular, ultimately have their periods of being heresy to those who so rigidly conserve the
                            old, that they cannot, will not, or dare not, comprehend them. And all receivers and
                            abettors of such ideas are, for the time, heretics and infidels, until the age to which such
                            unprogressive minds belong comes slowly up the hill of time. Had Jesus Christ never been
                            accused of ambitious or mean and sordid motives ; nor Ann Lee, our Mother, censured for
                            disloyalty to her country, or pure womanly instincts, not ere their mortal days had reached
                            their meridian, would they have been called to leave their sorrowing disciples. The support
                            they needed in life came but with their death and ascension. The truths which Mother saw
                            (most radical in that day), are now acknowledged by the Spiritual intuition of not a few who
                            cannot fully actualize them, as something higher and purer than earth has to offer. But what
                            depths of anguish must they have cost the pure spirit which was called to eliminate them ;
                            and, if she had not had the fortitude to strike herself free from every man-made restraint,
                            their birth-hour never would have come through her mediumship. A late writer has said: " The
                            world still awaits the great deliverance. And the needs press, always imperative, now
                            importunate, and utterly resistless. The old hastens to decay; the new is beating in throes.
                            Never was there such a day as our eyes behold. Social reorganization is the question of the
                            hour, but not superseding individual regeneration. The old order has well nigh come to the
                            unbearable state. The competitive selfishness, the low aims, and the mean idolatries, that
                            have long prevailed, have reduced us to the last stages of endurance. What throes in the
                            civil world ! and these but faintly typical of the revolutions and transformations that are
                            soon to be ; foreshadowings of which are now visiting saintly souls. Man shall know the joy
                            x&gt;f a full redemption, perfect enfranchisement, perfect doing, and perfect peace."
                            Those whom God calls, he cheers with the clarion notes of freedom, and they sing accordant
                            strains. No bands can bind them; for compulsory service is of no available use. And, after
                            the soul learns to obey the laws of God in its being, and obedience is its joy and delight,
                            it comes into freedom as spontaneously as the eagle in its aerie, or " the fawn upon the
                            mountain's top."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webster, E. H." TEIform="persName"/>E. H. Webster, Harvard, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><p TEIform="p">By the request of friends we give publicity to the following correspondence, which took place
                            between two Shaker Sisters of the North Family, Mt. Lebanon, in the early part of October
                            and November, 1873. They both left the shores of time, to seek a home in the elysian fields
                            on the other side of the stream, on the 10th and 23d of December last.</p><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="October 5, 1873" TEIform="index"/>October 5, 1873</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Companion, Friend and Sister : What have I to give thee from my storehouse, dear
                                one, that would serve to cheer thee, or add to thy comfort ? I have looked over my
                                treasures, and have found sympathy, love, and a heart to pray for you, loved one. I
                                often think of you in our seasons of solemn and sacred devotion; and I sing and march
                                for you ; and many times I visit you in spirit when you know it not. I think I hear you
                                say : '' This is all very well, but I want to join in worship and sing and march for
                                myself." Well, be patient; the good time is coming. Do you remember the time when 1 was
                                so feeble that I had to stand or sit by, and could not sing, or march, or join " in the
                                dances of them that make merry ?" Now that time is past, but I have some fears that it
                                will return to me before I am ready for it, for I often feel very sharp, darting pains
                                between my shoulders, and I have an exceedingly weak stomach. But why do I trouble you
                                with my ails ? I will away with them, and take you by the hand, and we will sit down in
                                the most comfortable seat that we can find, and call to mind the many, many soul
                                communings we have had together! O Rhoda, dear Rhoda, how much good they have done me !
                                I would that they might be repeated. The cares of this life ought not to engross the
                                mind to that degree, that such communings should occur but seldom. 0 for more of God in
                                the soul, and less of earth! My heartfelt prayer is "My Heavenly Father and Mother,
                                give, Oh give me the true riches." I do not presume to know my own heart as the good
                                angels know it; but, so far as I under' stand my desires and motives, I am willing to
                                pass through any amount of tribulation and suffering, to secure my hold upon eternal
                                life ; and yet, dear Sister, it is an every-day struggle ; is it not ? The food given
                                yesterday, does not suffice for to-day. O what a wise petition is that contained in the
                                Lord's Prayer, " Give us this day our daily bread." As I travel in the Gospel, I plainly
                                see that there is no stopping place with the least amount of safety for any individual
                                (no matter what the age or privilege may be), until full redemption from the very nature
                                of sin is obtained, and the divine life fills the soul. The following passages of
                                Scripture often occur to my mind: " Ye did run well; who did hinder you ?" and " Ye
                                wyere willing for a season to rejoice in his light;" and " Let him that thinketh he
                                standeth, take heed lest he fall." I resolve and re-resolve to live nearer to my faith;
                                and yet how feeble are my efforts, unless assisted by divine powrer. I sometimes think
                                the poor frail body has something to do with our spiritual progress. Do you think so ?
                                But I would not impute more to the body than belongs to it. Dear Rhoda, I should have
                                been pleased to have had you heard Brother Levi speak in meeting this morning ; it was
                                so good. Now, Sister, I am going to make you a promise, and I want you to make me a
                                promise ; i. e. if I go to the summer-land first, I will intercede for you; and should
                                you go with the white-robed angel before I do, you will intercede for me. Is that fair ?
                                I commenced this letter this afternoon. I have written it for a little union, and I want
                                you to have it this evening. So you will accept the first draft, and extend charity.
                                Farewell in sweetest love, my tried and faithful friend. Yours affectionately, To Rhoda
                                Offord.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pattison, Margaret" TEIform="persName"/>Margaret Pattison</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="November 2, 1873" TEIform="index"/>November 2,1873</head><p TEIform="p">Affectionate Sister Margaret : In response to your loving letter, I would say that the
                                pure, gentle and sunny influence that surrounds you comes to me like balm, which
                                soothes, cheers, and comforts my spirit, and brightens my pathway, even in the gloom
                                which physical infirmity brings in these days. Dear Margaret, I would that I had some-
                                thing to communicate to you, that would inspire and animate, and, in a measure, com-
                                pensate you for the rich treasure that I received from your benevolent heart; but this
                                is the best tribute that I am able to offer, under my present circumstances. Do accept
                                my grateful thanks for your love and sympathy, and kindly remembrance of me in your
                                prayers. I have unshaken confidence and trust that the petitions of the righteous will
                                be heard by our guardian angels, and that they will be carried by them to the throne of
                                our Heavenly Parents ; and that they will be answered, in due time, in justice and
                                wisdom. I deeply appreciate your extra exertions, from time to time, in my behalf, to
                                sing and march for me, while I realize that your feeble frame has no strength to spare
                                for me; you need all that you can gain from any quarter, to strengthen and support that
                                poor stomach, so weak and tremulous ; yet, the interest, love, and affection which you
                                manifest for me is worthy of my heart's best gift in return. My dear Sister, if you can
                                call to mind any thing that I have ever said that has comforted your spirit, I am glad.
                                The subjects we have dilated and reflected upon, often come to my mind; also those
                                earnest expressions and sentiments, concerning the future increase of the Gospel work,
                                individually and collectively, and they are a portion of my happiest reflections. I do
                                indeed recollect the time when you did not feel able to engage in active service in our
                                spiritual meetings ; that is, as far as the physical powers are concerned; but your
                                spirit was so wide awake that bodily exercises were not needed to show the activity of
                                your mind, and the sincerity of your heart in the <pb n="23" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> 8HAKEEE8S. work
                                and worship of God. Angel deeds stood as witnesses of your integrity to principle, your
                                Christian life and character. It is in the house of worship, when every heart is blended
                                in devotion, and seeking for the operation of the quickening power of truth, that we
                                gain our supplies of spiritual food to sustain our immortal souls; and, as you remarked,
                                we need each day our daily bread; the food of yesterday will not suffice for to-day ;
                                nor will the gift of the last meeting answer for the next; each and every meeting needs
                                new ministration, adapted to the present conditions. Therefore, I feel that I am losing
                                much good and strength in being absent from worship so long a time, as I always have
                                felt a living inspiration from the testimonies borne by our beloved Elders and the
                                Brethren and Sisters ; but I hope that, through consecrated and quickened exertion, I
                                may yet be able to redeem the time, and unite with you in devotional exercises to my
                                soul's satisfaction. I believe that the power of God is able to resuscitate the mortal
                                frame ; and let us seek aid through spirit agency, that health may come to our frail
                                bodies, and that we may live long on the earth, to do good in the household of faith.
                                Should we not be permitted thus to do, and either of us should pass over to our spirit
                                home, would it not be the better way to gather up the vital forces, and come back as
                                ministers of healing power to the feeble and infirm, instead of drawing from the ranks
                                of our external home such as we feel an affinity for and attraction toward ? According
                                to my understanding, that would be •practical love, corresponding with our faith and
                                principles. It is thus, my dear sister, that I promise to intercede for you. I do most
                                earnestly pray (if it is God's will), that a healing power may descend upon me, and
                                resurrect me into physical life and health, that I may renew my early vows of
                                consecration, to dedicate all the powers of my being —body,soul, and spirit — to the
                                upbuilding of the cause of truth and righteousness on the earth. One word more, and I
                                close. I want to express my gratitude for the tenderness and kindly attention of our
                                good Sisters, who watch over and provide for all my wants. You know their worth, their
                                self-sacrificing spirits, and devotion to the sick; how they toil, to comfort and
                                alleviate others. Their sympathy is real. I would remain, in a spirit of reconciliation,
                                your Gospel Sister, now and forever. To Margaret Pattispn.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Offord, Rhoda" TEIform="persName"/>Rhoda Offord</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beloved Eldress A.:" TEIform="index"/>Beloved Eldress A.:</head><p TEIform="p">I ACCEPT the invitation to the Sisterhood, given through the columns of the Shaker and
                                Shakeress, and contribute my mite freely; and would thus give expression to the feelings
                                of my heart, which often go out in profound love and respect, for the truths which the
                                little sheet contains. When I contrast my situation with that of thousands who have not
                                been blest as I was, i. e. to be called in early life, by the Spirit of Truth, to leave
                                the paths of sin and temptation to seek happiness through vanity and carnal pleasure,
                                and to devote all their powers of mind, might, and strength, to the upbuilding of a New
                                and Living Order, founded in Truth, by the revelation of God, I give thanks to Him, that
                                I have been thus favored ; and that I was not left to grope my way in darkness, without
                                the light of life to guide me: but, through the ministry of Angels, have been
                                spiritually fed, and, by consecration and honest labor, am blest with a beautiful
                                temporal home for the physical part. By obeying the injunction, " Seek first the kingdom
                                of God and his righteousness," I find that all other needful things are added. The cross
                                which Jesus taught his followers to bear is not heavy when cheerfully taken; and the
                                Christian's yoke, to those who are reconciled to wear it, is far easier, and less
                                grievous, than the yoke of sin. The reward of the Christian's cross is a " crown of life
                                ;" while the " wages of sin is death." My spirit yearns for the many of earth's in-
                                habitants, who are traveling in the broad road of sinful indulgences, that leads to
                                trouble and vexation of spirit; and who find, by sad experience, that it is all vanity,
                                and who would gladly turn their feet into the straight way 'which leadeth unto life
                                eternal," if they knew how, and where to find it; and my daily prayer to God is, that He
                                would send ministers of light and truth to show them the path of purity which leads to
                                peace and rest; and to teach them that God is Love ; and that He is ever ready to lend a
                                listening ear to those who call upon Him, and to extend a helping hand to those who seek
                                His aid. All such will find that His arm is not shortened, that it cannot save; neither
                                is His ear heavy, that it cannot hear the earnest cries of the humble and contrite in
                                spirit; and, that God is Father, Mother, and Friend,unto all who will draw nigh to Him
                                in spirit through self-denial and the cross ; and that a goodly inheritance is offered
                                in a kingdom of justice and righteousness, where there is neither high nor low ; rich
                                nor poor ; but all are one in labor, one in sacrifice, and one in rewards. The law is,
                                Give all, and receive all. There is a feast of good things prepared, and all who are
                                ready to don the garments of virgin purity, are invited to partake. " The Spirit and the
                                Bride say, Come !" and they who hear, say, " Come one, come all, who will lay down the
                                worldly life, that they may attain unto life eternal in the heavens !"</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Van Houtan, C." TEIform="persName"/>C. Van Houtan, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div3><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fragments" TEIform="index"/>FRAGMENTS</head><p TEIform="p">Prudence and economy are essential to the success of individuals, and are the main-
                                springs of true and lasting prosperity in families and institutions. All are familiar
                                with the teachings of Jesus, after he had fed the multitude that had followed him,
                                either from motives of curiosity, or for the loaves and fishes, or to be instructed by
                                him; he made no difference, but supplied them all. He then taught his disciples, through
                                whose agency the bounteous meal had been served, an important lesson of prudence, which
                                was, " Gather up the fragments that remain, that nothing be lost." That was a
                                fundamental principle with him, to which he gave practical illustration at that time. He
                                felt the responsibility of his mission, which was to put an end to the Levitical laws
                                and customs pertaining to the flesh—the generative life—in himself, and his followers,
                                and of setting up a new and spiritual kingdom that would be founded on Virgin Purity;
                                the fruits of which would be " Peace on earth, and good will to man." He felt that the
                                physical necessity of those who would gather to the New Order, which it was his work to
                                begin, must needs be supplied, which could not be done, except by strict economy ; and
                                this idea he wished to impress upon the minds of his disciples, on whom the burden must
                                rest when he should pass from their sight. The same principle, and the same language,
                                may be applied with equal force to mental, moral, and spiritual, conditions, " Gather up
                                the fragments, that nothing be lost." Intuitive knowledge gained through mental
                                perception should be carefully treasured, and not wasted; for through that medium we may
                                gather an inspiration that will enable us to " give to those who ask a reason for the
                                hope that is in us." Instructions and admonitions, and even suggestions, in a moral
                                point of view, should claim our strict attention, and be stored in our minds as too
                                precious to be wasted. Every fragment of truth, relative to the welfare of soul or body,
                                should be gathered up. " Order is Heaven's first law." Then every gift and blessing
                                should have its place in our hearts in order, according to its worth. All the essential
                                principles taught by Jesus and his Apostles, in the first appearing of Christ, have,
                                after many centuries have passed, been revived by the second advent of the Christ Spirit
                                through Ann Lee. She taught all her followers " to put their hands to work, and their
                                hearts to God," and to be prudent and saving of every blessing, both spiritual and
                                temporal; and that, as we cannot make one spear of grass, nor one kernel of grain grow,
                                it would be sin to waste them, and that it is a Christian duty to gather up every
                                fragment, that not any thing that is worth saving may be lost through carelessness or
                                neglect.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hale, Tryphena Porter" TEIform="persName"/>T. P. Hale, Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear S. &amp; S." TEIform="index"/>Dear S. &amp; S.</head><p TEIform="p">—We tender our hearty thanks, that you have decided to make your monthly visits to our
                                homes, through the coming year. You bring new hopes and aspirations to our spirits, and
                                our hearts are warmed with the love that is brought to us, through your richly laden
                                columns ; and we pray that you may be a messenger of good tidings to humanity : and we
                                also pray, that those who are chosen to bear the burden of conducting the little sheet,
                                may be strengthened and blest. While reading the January No. (more especially the
                                editorial address to the Sisterhood), my soul bowed before God in humility and
                                gratitude, that there had been so many noble, self-sacrificing workers raised up, who
                                give unmistakable evidence of their love to truth and to human souls, by actual works,
                                and thus show that they are willing to spend time and talent, to promote the righteous
                                cause, and who ceased not to implore Divine assistance and inspirational power to aid
                                them, while they seek to unfold the truths of the Gospel of Christ, and to point out the
                                way which leads to life and peace. Truly there are Saviors standing on Mount Zion to-day
                                : and the wells of revelation and salvation are full and running over; and we • join our
                                voices in harmonious accord with those who stand on the heights of Zion, and who are
                                extending a heavenly invitation to all souls who are thirsting for the living waters, to
                                come and partake^ freely ; to sell all that is vain, selfish, and unclean, and wash in
                                Jordan's flowing stream, by an honest confession of all sin; and seek that repentance
                                which can be found only by forsaking all that is wrong. Heaven's storehouse is full of
                                mercy and blessing for the contrite in spirit, and earnest seekers after truth. The
                                angels beckon such, and reach forth a helping hand to lift them up to a higher life,
                                that they may find power to live free from sin, and be like unto them. They who take
                                Christ's life for their example and guide, will be pure in heart, innocent, and just
                                before God and all men, and thus secure to themselves inestimable treasures in mansions
                                " not made with hands, eternal in the Heavens." Dear Eldress Antoinette, do receive our
                                love and thanks for your kindly greetings for the New Year; and. in response we say, May
                                heaven's blessing — peace and prosperity — ever rest upon you and yours; and may the
                                blessing of God rest upon the whole camp of Israel, and crown every effort with success,
                                is the prayer of your humble sister,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Riley, Nancy" TEIform="persName"/>Nancy Riley, Hancock, Mass.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Encompass'd here we find we are..." TEIform="index"/>Encompass'd here we find we are...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Encompass'd here we find we are, With many who will witness bear, That 'neath the cross is
                            found a prize, Concealed from the great and wise ; Then let us cast aside each weight, And
                            every sin which us beset; And, with a courage firm and strong. Toil on, till we the race
                            have run. Think not the future with success will shine, Unless the present time you will
                            improve; Neglect the moments, and the years (you'll find) Will soon elude your grasp, afar
                            to rove. Grant me, O Lord, a heart inclined to Thee ; A soul enrobed in truth and purity; A
                            mind in whose recesses Thou art found ; Yea lips which move, my Maker's praise to sound.
                            Give me a tongue which speaks what Thou canst own, And hands which work for Thee, and Thee
                            alone; O give me feet which tread thy righteous way; May my whole life be spent for Thee
                            each day.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Gainer, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. Gainer, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We hail the anniversary of our Redeemer's birth..." TEIform="index"/>We hail the anniversary of our Redeemer's birth...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">We hail the anniversary of our Redeemer's birth, And we bless the God of missions who sent
                            him to the earth; We acknowledge him our Leader, the chosen "King of kings," And join in
                            hallelujas for the peace his Gospel brings. With angel choirs above us, we'll unite in songs
                            of joy, And, with spirits who surround us, our choicest notes employ, Tor the light that
                            Star has given, thus far, to lead us on : May it still illume our pathway, till we reach the
                            shining throne.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hale, Tryphena Porter" TEIform="persName"/>Try. P. Hale, Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div2><pb n="24" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Eternity's gain" TEIform="index"/>ETERNITY'S GAIN</head><p TEIform="p">1. The 2. The 3. promise of life shall breathe o'er our souls, winter of gloom its sorrow and
                            care We'll Eternity's growth is onward to God, Where Devotion and truth without fear, And
                            the bury neath goodness and love. For hush'd is the voice of despair. And the toil shall
                            impart, purity's joy, life of each year, No Shall Will grief to the heart, be our employ,
                            bring us still near, But a Our The joy ous theme of realm of delight, A love for the right,
                            Shall desire While faith's hallow'd fire, Will the blest, The angel ic rest, The welcome
                            each change with good cheer, clothe us with grace from above. home of redemption and
                        pray'r.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Work of the century, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>THE WORK OF THE CENTURY No. 2</head><p TEIform="p">O ye that prize the Nation's life, Her honor, and her noble call, Awake, arise, and join the
                            strife, To gain equality for all. Financial systems, based on fraud, Like empires, cover all
                            the earth, Distorting sacred laws of God, And giving countless horrors birth. Look on the
                            scene that but of late Was re-enacted far and near; 'Tis but the index of the fate That
                            swept through ev'ry lowly sphere. They stood around with faces paled, And eyes aglow with
                            fires of dread ; Their heavy hearts within them quail'd, As if all hope of life had fled.
                            'Twas not the battle's sanguine heat, Nor vessels lonely wreck at sea; 'T was not the hour
                            when tempests meet, And earth convulses mightily; But there was wildness in the air ; Men
                            struggled as with forms unseen, While some, close pinion'd with despair, Gazed motionless
                            upon the scene. The tumult of that human tide, The darkness of that mental sky, All earthly
                            terrors far out-vied; For there was heartfelt agony! The crush of hopes, the loss of place,
                            The homes that in their grandeur fleet, The pain of ev'ry household face, The rugged paths
                            for tender feet, The plans that were but idly wrought, The schemes for boundless wealth and
                            pow'r, The long life efforts brought to nought, All crowded through that fearful hour ; And
                            ever and anon there came New messages that seemed like death ; The failure of each trusted
                            name Was listen'd to with bated breath. Some felt their quivering reason fall, Some wept as
                            if to b,reak the spell, Some hazarded their little all, In hope that it might yet be well;
                            But there were some, O hearts of steel! Where were your human pulses (warm), That, like the
                            wreckers, could but feel Exultant through that rending storm ; That, like the wreckers,
                            fiercely grasp The treasures of that sinking crew; That callously the hand unclasp'd, That
                            nerved itself for life anew? Yet you and they were of one kin; Had fortune but reversed her
                            wheel, Like yours, their hands would joyful win; Their hearts be dead to all appeal. Now
                            from your splendid ruins turn, To watch the waves that carry woe, To where the flickering
                            tapers burn In garrets high, and cellars low. Think of the children starved for food, The
                            strong men humbled in their pride, The women robb'd of womanhood, The crimes to wretchedness
                            allied; And pledge, against this weight of sin, The time that to you yet remains; You have
                            ability to win The country from commercial chains. Change, from the word to very deed, " The
                            Declaration " that was given; Let Christ-like action meet the need ; There is no poverty in
                            heaven. And when her crown the Century lays Upon the young Republic's brow, The jewel that
                            will brightest blaze Shall be the star * she strives for now. *Abolition of monopoly.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Devyr, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/>Cecelia Devyr, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Voice of the ages" TEIform="index"/>VOICE OF THE AGES</head><p TEIform="p">Prophetic eyes see by a lens, Which give a double view; And oft their vision so extends,
                            Beyond what men deem true, That they will turn in deep disgust, And call him " mad " or
                            fool; Or (if a woman) think it just To say, " She ne'er shall rule." Has history no lessons
                            taught To those who scoff and jeer ? Have truths divine, so dearly bought, (Which we to-day
                            revere, For which the martyrs bore the rack, The dungeon, and the flame), No pleading voice
                            to turn men back From future deeds of shame? Must those who 're called to lead the van On
                            battle fields of right, Be ever, by their fellow man, Doom'd to destruction's night ? Will
                            those who pray '' Thy kingdom come, Fight all their answer'd prayer, When it (although
                            foreseen by some), Steals on them unaware ? The ages past, in confluence met, Give answer
                            with one voice; In darkness all our suns have set; The light was not our choice. Our
                            histories are quite replete With crimes of deepest hue ; When truth would not from earth
                            retreat, (Men did as you now do) : Seized on the reins to guide the steed, And bend it to
                            their will, They hoped thereby to slacken speed, For truth they could not kill. But we would
                            say, roll up that page, All stained with sin and blight, And claim, for each succeeding age,
                            A love of truth and right. For setting suns, with light aglow, Oft paint the heaven aflame;
                            Or span it with a brilliant bow, Whose language is the same ; Foretelling that the morrow's
                            dawn Will bring a cloudless day ; The " golden age," of error shorn, Will come with men to
                            stay. But blindly yet we read the signs, Bid progress' car stand still, And trace in shining
                            letter'd lines, "God has revealed his will." We bow with reverence to the past, Do homage to
                            the old, While on the new, contempt we cast, As though all truth were told. The present age,
                            though devotee To forms by Truth once worn, Will crucify the truths to be ; Their votaries
                            treat with scorn; Unheeded, still the warning note, From age to age is heard— The truth
                            still lives, though death hath smote The form it once preferr'd. But suns will rise to set
                            no more, Their days will know no night; While creeds and dogmas melt before The glory of
                            their light ; Till abject slaves no longer cower, But stand erect like men; No kingly rule,
                            or priestly power, Shall hold dominion then. But love, within all hearts enshrined, Will for
                            the past atone ; And to oblivion consign'd Be names who prophets stone. And earth's fair
                            seil shall not be wet With martyrs' precious blood ; Nor woman strive in vain to get Her
                            rightful womanhood. But she with man, co-worker true, In government of state, Shall
                            harmonize their life anew, The race to elevate. Then earth her harvests will increase, God's
                            blessings all will share, All hail the perfect reign of Peace ! And for its life prepare. 0,
                            would that all, before the dawn, Might look beyond the screen That vails the gleamings of
                            that morn Prophetic eyes have seen! And heavenly brilliancy behold, As each triumphal car In
                            splendor rose, 'mid light of gold, And shed bright beams afar.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Persons, A. E." TEIform="persName"/>A. E. Persons, Harvard, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I want the day to come when women will vote..." TEIform="index"/>I want the day to come when women will vote...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Simpson" TEIform="persName"/>Bishop Simpson</byline><p TEIform="p"> said: " I want the day to come when women will vote. Without their vote I fear we will never
                            be able to put down the houses of infamy and liquor saloons of our country. Nothing is so
                            ruinous to the country, it is true, and it is my opinion that we can't get along without
                            women voting."</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>