<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0110" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Mount Lebanon Bishopric</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Albany, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">1</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">10</biblScope><date value="18711001" TEIform="date">October 1871</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">73-80</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="1" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="73" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="10" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p"> I WILL SHAKE ALL NATIONS, AND THE DESIRK OP ALL NATIONS SHALL COME J AND I WILL FILL THIS HOUSE
                        WITH GLOKT, SAITH THE LOKD.'' Published Monthly, by, and under the direction of the Mt. Lebanon
                        Bishopric, Vol, L SHAKERS, ALBANY CO., N. Y., OCTOBER, 1871, No. 10.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home again" TEIform="index"/>Home Again</head><p TEIform="p">When drawing nigh unto the wharf, on the steam-tug that landed us from the Atlantic, it was a
                            happy sound whea some ¦of the officers said: "Your people are waiting for you." And it was a
                            joyful meeting with a company of Elder brethren and Elder sisters from different families,
                            among whom was the ever-welcome presence of " the Managing Editor," G. A. Lomas. How good to
                            meet with ' loved ones after long and distant absence! Having sailed on the 1st of July in
                            the Atlantic, under Captain Murray, we landed from her, now under the command of Captain
                            Perry, on the 4th of September. We have received from my dear friend and fellow-traveler, J,
                            M. Peebles, the representative of the S.piritualists of America, the following communication
                            for the little Shaker, which will speak for itself.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Steamer Atlantic, White Star Line, September 3, 1871" TEIform="index"/>Steamer Atlantic,
                            White Star Line, September 3, 1871</head><p TEIform="p">Editor of The Shaker : It is Sunday at sea. The mimic bell has summoned the passengers to the
                            saloon for divine worship. Bibles, prayer-books, hymnbooks, are strewn around loosely upon
                            the table. A pulpit is improvised—all is ready. The English clergyman, richly vestured, ap-
                            pears, to read the service. The measured mechanical music now reaches our ears. Is this
                            serving God ? Does God require any such cold, formal service ? Would not feeding the hungry,
                            clothing the naked, and educating the masses in the principles of justice, equality and
                            charity, be infinitely more acceptable in the sight of God and angels ? Elder F. W. Evans,
                            ourself and a few others retired —retired as a protest against making the Eng- lish church
                            service a sort of religious steamboat "church and state " institution on board the White
                            Star line of steamers. No American, touched with the fires of freedom, or thoroughly alive
                            to the genius of this progressive age, can for a moment encourage any thing that tends to a
                            church and state estab • lishment—the entering wedge of which is the strenuous effort now
                            being made by sectarists to put " God," the trinitarian God, into the Constitution. This
                            done, and the Declaration of Independence becomes a nullity, and religion degenerates into
                            theology, bigotry and persecution unto death. 2%is done, and farewell to freedom of speech
                            and press—farewell to that freedom which now grants to all the organizations, orders and
                            denominations of the land the privilege of worshipping God after the "dictates of their own
                            conscience." The virus of churchal sectarism is as poisonous to-day as in the sixteenth
                            century. Let Americans be on their guard. English Lands. Travel in any direction from London
                            by the interlacing railway conveyances, and you involuntarily pronounce England a garden.
                            Industry has seemingly carried cultivation to perfection. There is a neatness, a thrift in
                            the agricultural districts seldom seen in America, where lands are cheap, and where wide
                            prairies are waiting to respond to plow and sower. Though meadows, hedge-rows and waving
                            harvest-fields charm the eye, the soul is burdened with the knowledge that only the few own
                            the soil. Land monopoly is the rule in the British kingdom. Few seem to ponder upon the
                            fact, that the right to life presupposes the further right of each indi- vidual to
                            sufficient soil to sustain that life. The land-holders in her "Majesty's realm" are rapidly
                            decreasing. It is said, and without contradiction, so far as we know, that a hundred and
                            fifty'' persons own to-day onehalf of the land in England; while twelve proprietors hold,
                            and professedly "own," nineteen and a-half millions of acres in Scot- land. Magnificent
                            mansions, elegant parks, and vast deer forests with odious game laws, abound for the comfort
                            and amusement of English noblemen, while the starving poor beg for bread. London journals
                            reported one hundred and fifty thousand paupers in the city alone, last March. It is also
                            estimated that there are a million more women than men in England. Poverty and
                            dissatisfaction are on the increase. Elder Frederic bore a strong testimony, in all his
                            public meetings that we attended, against the terrible condition 'of things in Britain—the
                            land of his birth. Is not America, England's younger brother, imitating her in sundry wicked
                            schemes of land monopoly? Capital is continually concentrating, and, through cunning and
                            cupidity, banking institutions, railroad corporations and land monopolies are becoming
                            fearful engines of power, making the rich richer, the poor poorer. When, oh ! when, will
                            selfish, land-grabbing Americans feel the heaven-voiced principle of equality—feel the
                            pentecostal fire—feel the descending baptismal flame—and verify the conviction by this
                            apostolic practice : "And they that believed had all things in common " ? ; The English
                            Mission. A long time ago, we read the great speech of Elder F. W. Evans, made at the Rutland
                            Convention, in. Vermont. Some six years since, I met him in New York. Handing me several
                            Shaker works to read", he utterly astounded me with his perfect familiarity with
                            spiritualists and spiritualism. He had been converted from cold materialism to a knowledge
                            of the future existence through his own personal mediumship. He further sur- prised me by
                            relating wonderful manifestations he had witnessed in their communities, and through our
                            media who had fled at different times to their societies for rest and mental recuperation.
                            This interview interested me in Shakerism, its testimonies in favor of pres- ent
                            inspirations, communications, peace principles, temperance, etc., etc. Work with all true
                            workers for reform, has been my motto for years. Denominational names are but "tinkling
                            cymbals." To this end, those joint conventions of Spiritualists and Shakers were held last
                            winter in Cleveland, and Troy, N. Y., to the satisfaction and mutual profit, we believe, of
                            both parties. Elder Frederic's first London meeting was held in Cleveland Hall. The audience
                            was composed mostly of Spiritualists and Secularists. Mrs. Emma Hardinge was present, and
                            expressed herself highly delighted with his radical, utterances against orthodox theologies
                            and monarchical governments. He also publicly testified to the facts of Spiritualism. The
                            great meeting was held in St. George's Hall, Langham place. W. Hepworth Dixon, Esq., author
                            of "New America," "Spiritual Wives," etc., occupied the chair. The large hall was densely
                            packed before the hour for service. After the lecture commenced, a continual stream reached
                            the outer door, and then left, unable to gain admission. There were pressent, members of
                            Parliament, distinguished journalists, prominent Darwinians, clergymen, Spiritualists,
                            Secularists, social reformers. The music was excellent. And never have we seen greater
                            attention paid to a speaker than to Elder Evans upon this occasion. The "Spirit of the Lord
                            was upon him." Occasionally there was a dissent; as, for instance, when he advised the
                            English to dispense with the "bishops and noblemen constituting the 1 House of Lords,' and
                            put women in their places!" He further shocked them when declaring that the repenting,
                            warring " God of Israel" was nothing but a tutelary divinity— and that the seventy
                            communities of Shakers in America were so many communities believing in present revelations
                            and spirit minis<pb n="74" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHA.KER. trations. As a whole, the audience was
                            charmed with the simplicity, sincerity and solid logic of the speaker. Mr. Dixon did himself
                            great credit as the presiding officer. To James Burns, editor of Medium and Human Nature,
                            and publisher of spiritualist literature in London, belongs the honor of getting up this and
                            a series of meetings for the Elder in the provinces. At several of these gatherings he
                            presided as chairman, making at each an appropriate opening address. Friend Burns is an
                            inspired man, with great versatility of talent, and Mrs. Burns is truly a "helpmeet." They
                            have two rosy-cheeked boys, perfect specimens of health, that never tasted of meat nor
                            medicine in their lives. A Grove Meeting. It was our privilege to be present at the first
                            large open-air demonstration of Spiritualists in England. The meeting was held at Bowling
                            Hill, near the city of Bradford. Those gifted in calculation, estimated that there were two
                            thousand present. It was a grand spectacle. Mr. Burns, elected president by acclamation,
                            made the preliminary speech, earnest, eloquent and catholic. Elder Frederic, ourself and
                            others addressed the hungering crowd. It was a grand success. At the second session, after
                            the Elder had given a detailed account of his conversion from Robert Owen Materialism to
                            Spiritualism, he elaborately elucidated the leading principles of Shakerism. The interest
                            was intense, and the questions interesting. The Elder showed great wisdom in answering them,
                            Take these as samples. " If Shakers do not marry, now do they increase their communities ?"
                            " By gathering in from the world those who have ripened up for the sickle—ours is the
                            harvest order." " But did not God in the beginning of creation command men to multiply and
                            replenish the earth ? " " I do not know, not having been there at the time; and then, other
                            than the instincts of the earthly nature, a special command from God to insects, beasts and
                            men to ' replenish the earth,' would seem quite useless. They certainly do such business now
                            without any direct command from God." "Well, if all should turn Shakers, would it not run
                            the world out ?" " I apprehend no immediate danger of all men turning Shakers -—the cross is
                            too great and the life is too self-denying. And, as for running the world out, the tendency,
                            considering fceticide, abortions and illegitimate offspring, seems to • run' in a different
                            direction at present. But, if the world should be 'runout,' the calamity would not be very
                            serious, inasmuch, as upon the Darwinian basis, there are plenty of monkeys in Asia and
                            Africa to get up a new race ; and this might be an improvement! " " But you oppose
                            marriage." " Nay, friend, not marriage per se. The marriage relation is legitimate on the
                            earthly plane, for reproduction, as Moses taught. But ours is the resurrection order—a
                            degree above—and bears the same relation to the world that the spirit bears to the body." My
                            work in England was mostly of a business character, relative to the publication of Higgins'
                            "Anacalypsis,"new edition of "Jesus myth, man or God," and the gathering of facts for the
                            European department of the Year-Book of Spiritualism for 1872, Perpetual Communism. Without
                            pronouncing judgment at this time either for or against the ascetic orders of the ages, I
                            confess myself astonished, after reading the histories of the East, at the silver threads of
                            celibacy and communism that run like crystal waters through all the nations of antiquity.
                            Jamblichus, writing of Pythagoras' visit to Italy, says : " More than two thousand, in the
                            firs-t public discourse of Pythagoras, were arrested by his doctrine, who, together with
                            their wives and children, forming an immense auditory, and having founded the community
                            called Grcecia Magna, received from him laws and ordinances, which they regarded as maxims
                            of divine authority, and whien' in no instance they transgressed, but which the whole
                            assembly with one accord obeyed; being admired and proclaimed blessed by all around. They
                            had their goods in common." (2)e Vitcb Pyth., c. 6, p. 22.) The learned Philo, writing of
                            the wise men of Egypt, observes that "The object of these philosophers is manifest from the
                            title which they assume. The men, and even the women, call themselves TherapeutvE, that is,
                            Healers, and this with propriety, as professing a medical art superior to that practised by
                            mesi of the world; The1 latter profess to heal only the bodies-,, while the former cure the
                            souls of men, when seized by disorders, when occupied by lusts or by an innumerable
                            multitude of oth«;r vices. The persons who profess this art, embraee it not from, education,
                            nor from the persuasions of others, but because they are seized by the love of Heaven.
                            Thinking themselves already dead to the world, they desire only a blessed immortal
                            existence. They fix their habitations oo the outside of cities, in gardens and villages,
                            seeking retirement, not, I conceive, from religious hatred of mankind, but to avoid a
                            pernicious intercourse with the world. This society now prevails throughout the habitable
                            globe, the members thinking it their duty to share with Greeks and barbarians the consummate
                            blessings they enjoy. They have a sacred apartment in which they perform the mysteries of a
                            holy life. Into this place they bring neither meat nor drink, nor anything but the laws and
                            divinely inspired oracles of the prophets. The idea of God is ever present to their
                            thoughts. Many of them deliver magnificent visions, suggested by their sacred philosophy in
                            the home of repose. Their clothing is plain and simple. They eat no food more costly than
                            coarse bread, regarding plenitude as prejudicial to both body and mind. They practice great
                            humility; and, holding all things equal, each seeks another's good." The Jewish historian,
                            Josephus, writes thus of the Esseneans : " They cherish mutual love beyond other men. They
                            reject pleasure as evil; and look upon temperance and a conquest over the passions as the
                            greatest virtue. There prevails among them a contempt of marriage ; but they receive the
                            children of others, and educate them as their own. * * * They despise riches, and are much
                            to be admired for their liberality; nor can any be found among them who is more wealthy than
                            the rest. It is a law with them, that those who join their order should distribute their
                            possessions among the members. They wear white apparel; and neither buy nor sell among
                            themselves. They avoid oaths—teach the immortality of the soul, and hold forth the rewards
                            of virtue to be most glorious. * # # ijhg course of life they pursue is exempt from change
                            or the caprices of fashion, and they bear some resemblance to the communities said to
                            subsist among the Dacians." The Hindoos had their Rajahs, the Egyptians their Therapeutse,
                            the Syrians their Esseneans, the Greeks their Pythagoreans, the Romans their Anchorites, and
                            the Mediaeval ages their Hermits. These often fled to deserts to escape persecutions.
                            Finding solitude sweet,they remained. Athanasius, Basil, Chrysostom, Gregory of Nazionzen,
                            Jerome, Augustine, Evagrius, Cassians, and others of the first centuries, encouraged or
                            practiced lives of retirement—lives of self-restraint, celibacy, poverty, and the exercise
                            of charity and good deeds towards all men. When the principles of self-sacrifice,
                            benevolence and mutual love abound among individuals, races and nations as reigning forces,
                            then will dawn the Republic of Plato, the Arcadia of the poets, the Eden of tbe bards, and
                            the happy-valleys of the seers seen in visions. These golden days are coming. The peace
                            echoes of the Quakers, the reform principles of these seventy Shaker communities, the
                            radical teachings of Elder Frederic, the daring enunciations of William Denton, the brave
                            utterances of Lucretia Mot't, the pathetic pleadings of Mary F. Davis, the eloquent orations
                            of Eaima HarcHnge, and the stirring appeals of other great-hearted philanthropists and
                            speakers, are harbingers ofthe millennial era^ Each religious cycle yields its harvest
                            sheaves. But before the victory, before the shouting of the "harvest -home," comes another
                            outpouring of the Revelator's "vial of wrath."" Crucifixions precede transfigurations as do
                            thunders the storms that purify the air. A religkvus-politisal war-cloud is gathering in the
                            distance. Only the ministry and mediation of spirits can arch this cloud with the rainbow of
                            peace. Let Shakers, Quakers, Secularists, Spiritualists and Liberalists all form a solid
                            phalanx to meet the emergency, using "spiritual weapons" for the pulling down of strongholds
                            and the upbuilding of the temple of truth.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Peebles, J. M." TEIform="persName"/>J. M. Peebles</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life in God" TEIform="index"/>Life in God</head><p TEIform="p">Intelligence and Love are the primary attributes in the Godhead; all others are subor-
                            dinate, and move in harmony with these. Without supreme intelligence, the universe of mind
                            and matter could not exist. No other attribute is adequate to the comprehension and
                            execution of the stupendous whole ! Remove intelligence, and what remains ? Love is the
                            feminine in God, the Mother of all their children in the universe. Wisdom is the appropriate
                            use by the Supreme, in tbe design and creation of the universe of mind and matter. Power is
                            only the inherent force of God in creation. Judgment is only the Omniscient exercise of the
                            divine mind and will. Love is the attraction of mind and matter, and binds the stupendous
                            whole—the universe of God. Remove love from the human soul, and what remains to time and the
                            children of earth ? We should immediately fall asunder and become extinct. Between supreme
                            intelligence and love there 74 <pb n="75" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> THE S H .A. K E H . 75 has been an
                            eternal union, co-existence, mutual recognition of excellence, and immutable purpose in the
                            grand, design—Perfection absolute ! Love is the magnet of creative intelligence, and dra^s
                            her children to herself, and the embraces of each other, and contiguity in the proCreative
                            union ; without love, the sexes are a nullity, and an unmeaning distinction of creation. We
                            can only reason by the powers of body and mind given us; these powers acting on the objects
                            of time, and, by analogy, necessarily rising to a higher source, give us our ideas of
                            ourselves, and of a Supreme intelligence. We find ourselves in this lower sphere, male and
                            female, a perfect adaptation of the appropriate, productive power, and thelove principle, or
                            passion in co-operation. By analogy, we ask, are (there) Father and Mother in God ? As we
                            are only recipients of their gifts, could they impart attributes not contained in themselves
                            ? The whole creation, as far as we comprehend it, is male and female, and the female as
                            Mother, and centre of influence in the family ! Come, ye savans of the earth, these are
                            facts, and logical deductions; we ~ask you to fairly examine the same, and publish to the
                            world your conclusions. On this subject we have the testimony of the holy Saviour, in these
                            words: "Have ye not read, that He who made thema£ the beginning, made them male and female,
                            and said, for this cause, shall a man leave father and mother, and shall cleave to his wife,
                            and they twain shall be one flesh: wherefore they were no more twain, but one flesh." l
                            What, therefore, God'has joined together, let no man put astmder." Mark.' In the procreative
                            union they are one; so pronounced by God, and so confirmed by the Son. The teaching of the
                            holy Saviour, not only acknowledges, but confirms the Mosaic account of creation, as male
                            and female, and also their likeness to the Godhead : " And God said, let us make man in our
                            image, after our likeness; and let them have dominion over the fish of the sea, and over the
                            fowl of the air, and over the cattle, and over all the earth, etc. So God created man -in
                            Mis own image, in the image of God created He him; male and female created He them: and God
                            blessed and said unto them, be friutful and multiply, and replenish the earth, and subdue
                            it." This is the record of the Bible, as plain as the English language can make it, as
                            expressed by God himself, that God is male and female; and that Adam and Eve are one, the
                            express image of them or him, as you please. Those w-ho believe the sacred record, are as
                            sacredly bound to receive His testimony! There can be no shadow of doubt or turning ^ it is
                            yea, amen! Three males in the Godhead are a monstrosity, and repugnant to every feeling in
                            humanity.! A barrea conglomeration of unproductive elements. The holy Saviour never told his
                            disciples that there were three male persons in His Father, and that He was one of them. But
                            this Trinity is a most mortifying and degrading image, in the Christian (?) galaxy;
                            borrowed, yea stolen from Oriental mythology. Go into the Hindoo temples, and you will there
                            find his catholic majesty, and the Hindoo worship nearly verbatim to that of the holy See.
                            The Hindoos, Tartars and others say, the west inherited or borrowed Catholicism of their
                            oriental brethren; theoatholics deny the charge, and say, the missionaries carried the
                            sacred dogma to the heathen nations; but every oriental scholar knows tshat the gods
                            belonged originally to the east, and-that the west is the dupe of paganism. The missionary
                            Hue, on his way to China, tarried over winter in the Tartar city of Lassa. Here he made the
                            acquaintance of a young Tartar prince, and spent most of his time in converting the young
                            nobleman. In the spring before his departure, Hue thus addressed his young friends " I am
                            about to depart on ray mission, and wish to have a memorial of my labors. I think ycra are
                            fully prepared to enter upon the solemn rites of our sacred religion; I propose baptism."
                            Said the prince, "Stop, my worthy friend, you are quite too fast; I have listened to you
                            attentively all winter, and perceive, to my astonishment, that our theologies are
                            identical." " 0, well, well," said Hue, " our missionaries have been here, and taught you
                            these sublime truths." " Quite too fast again," said the prince; " Whatever of religion,
                            law, physic and the sciences you have in the west, all are oriental, and the east are your
                            teachers." So Hue departed on his mission., " a wiser if not a better 'man."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Redmon, William" TEIform="persName"/>Wm. Redmon U. Village</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In character, in manners, in style..." TEIform="index"/>In character, in manners, in style...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">In character, in manners, in style, in all things the supreme exceUence is simplicity.
                            Nothing new, nothing great, nothing curious, nothing marvelous, nor even miraculous in
                            creatures, tends in the least to effect the work of regeneration. This is wrought by daily
                            self-denial, mortification and suffering ; by quietly and patiently doing and suffering the
                            will of God in preference to our own. Nothing can long delight him who dclighteth not, above
                            all things, in God. True repentance is turning from evil to good; from self to God. Tears,
                            without turning, will never be owned for repentance. Grant, O Heavenly Father, that I may
                            fear nothing but sin; hate none but self; love nothing but thee and thine. Count not that
                            time lost which is spent in meditation and prayer. Pelham.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Innocence" TEIform="index"/>Innocence</head><p TEIform="p">True innocence is like a bright, lovely jewel; this jewel is easily tarnished. How important
                            then, that we keep it bright by a life, pure and unspotted. We should shun the very appear-
                            ance of evil, even in thought and feeling. To my mind, true innocence consists in living a,
                            life so pure, that nothing will enter the mind, but what is perfectly refined from all
                            grossness and everything that would lead thereto, so that if our thoughts were written,
                            there would be no occasion for shame. The innocent mind has needs of keeping no guard, nor
                            taking thought, for fear of overstepping the bounds of modesty; for as the heart is, so will
                            be our words and acts. Innocence will join us to the angels, and fit us to dwell with them.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pierson, Julia E." TEIform="persName"/>Julia E. Pierson, Shirley</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thoughts by a shaker sister" TEIform="index"/>Thoughts by a Shaker Sister</head><p TEIform="p">David said, MI am fearfully and wonderfully made." This is true of every man and woman. Our
                            life, in all respects, is a wonder. We live and move and have an existence. We breathe— some
                            unseen power keeps the machinery in motion—the heart beats; the tongue moves to sound forth
                            the thoughts of the brain and feelings of the soul, and the ears of others catch those
                            sounds; tfhus mind meets mind and we impress our thoughts upon others. The eyes, the sole
                            medium through which light is transmitted to the body, are wonderful in their construction.
                            All the members of the human body (if healthy) move in conformity to the will-force, or in
                            nrtison with the controlling governing wheel of the machine; the intelli- gence coming
                            through the brain. We eat, we drink, we wake, we sleep. Who can tell how all the vital
                            forces operate ? and how the subtile agencies are brought to bear upon the human organism,
                            so as to retain the equilibrium, and preserve the harmonious action of all the parts ? We
                            speak of life and death. Life represents action. "Life is heat; Death is cold," means
                            decay—dissolution. Does the philosopher, the theologian, or the greatest seer of the ages,
                            understand the modus operandi by which this "harp of a thousand strings " is constructed and
                            attuned ? 1 We see an ordinary machine, produced by man's ingemaity or intelligence, and
                            perhaps comprehend how, by wind, steam, or water, as a propelling force, the wheels are set
                            in motion; but the thoughts—the reasoning powers—of human beings, the emotional feelings—
                            feelings of joy and sorrow, of love and hate — who understands their origin, so that they
                            could take us by the hand, and lead us along the path which conducts to the fountain, and
                            reveal the mystery ? "Help, Lord, for the godly man"—the preserver of the earth—" ceaseth;
                            for the faithful fail from among the children of men." Whether the above quotation is
                            applicable to our own time, keen observers of men and things, of cause and effect, must
                            decide. One thing is certain; that is, "Truth," as applied to practical life, does not, at
                            the present time, "ride (very) prosperously through the land." *' All have sinned," have
                            violated the physical and spiritual laws of their being, more or less; and few indeed do
                            good—do right— according to their highest conception of right. Is there a remedy ? If so,
                            where is it to be found? A crucified Jesus has been preached ; runners have gone up and down
                            through the land crying, "Lohere! and lo there!" Spiritual teachers and modern prophets have
                            arisen; periodicals and daily journals have become very numerous ; and others are springing
                            into life; and now, by the aid of the iron horse, which wends its way among the hills and
                            valleys with almost lightning speed, from the Atlantic to the Pacific, they are conveyed
                            from city to city, to every hamlctf and nearly every cottage throughout the civilized land
                            over which the cultivator has passed. Knowledge is thereby increased; but "the wicked
                            continue to do wickedly; " and true understanding, touching the Christian life, is, to a
                            great extent, hidden from mortal sight. <pb n="76" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 76 THE SHAKER. Christendom is
                            full of names—sects. Manychurches, with their towering spires pointing somewhere, attract
                            attention from those who are thirsting for the spiritual waters of life, " as the hart
                            panteth for the water brooks," and they ask the learned divines, "Is righteousness, which
                            makcth men and women righteous, practically righteous, found within these courts ?" Their
                            answer is, " No; we rely on the merits of a crucified Jesus I By his stripes we are healed !
                            By his righteousness we shall, in the future, be saved I " The people known as " Shakers,"
                            have not sought to be numbered with popular Christians —the sects called orthodox. They hare
                            dwelt alone, and have preferred to let works, rather than worldly profession and gorgeous
                            display of Church paraphernalia, bespeak their faith. As birds, they hare fled to the
                            mountains— the highest revealed spiritual truth — and sought cover " under the wings of the
                            anointed cherub." There they patiently wait, drinking in inspiration from the celestial
                            spheres, and watch for the bright morning star to arise, the precursor of a new day, when an
                            angel messenger to the present generation will come forth, who will speak unto the Churches
                            and breathe the breath of life into them, and cause them again to "rise and stand upon their
                            feet"—rebaptize them with the same spirit which first called them into being. They have, for
                            a long time, lain as " dead bodies in the streets spiritually called Sodom and Egypt"—
                            sensual pleasure, and the darkness arising therefrom—" where our Lord was crucified." The
                            carnal life is opposed to the spiritual, and always kills the life of God in the soul. When
                            the first angel messenger has performed a work, then another angel will follow, who will
                            testify of the dual God, and the dual Christ—a living, risen Saviour, who will walk with
                            those who are willing to enrobe themselves in linen white and clean—virgin purity. Then the
                            voice will be heard, saying: "Come up hither "—to the higher life. • Modern Spiritualism is
                            an angel of light, and has wrought a great change in society. Not a quarter of a century has
                            passed since a believer in spirit communings was called heterodox. Revelation was a thing of
                            the past, except in natural science. Not one spirit friend was welcome to bear a torch-light
                            of truth to this sin-darkened world. Spirit influences have now become so strong and
                            subtile, that they have found their way into almost every household, and pierced nearly
                            every circle. It is doing its work— shaking old-established creeds and dogmas, "confounding
                            the wisdom " of the hierarchy, and is " bringing to naught the understanding of the
                            prudent." In this way, God will pull down what man has builded that is false. Truth alone
                            will stand! All the. dashing, surging waves of error and superstition that may beat against
                            it cannot move it! Truth will live! and all who build upon it will live ! such will behold a
                            risen Saviour, and feel his power. Truth has no bounds ; as it is co-eternal with Deity, so
                            it fills immensity ! Error must fall before it. May God, through the medium of his own
                            choosing, speed the work !</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. Doolittle</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Inspiration" TEIform="index"/>Inspiration</head><p TEIform="p">A very interesting study, to the observer of Nature, is the combination of its various ele-
                            ments, whether spontaneous or artificial. The solid earth itself, with its ocean and its
                            atmosphere, is the result of this union of elements. One combination produces the delicate
                            plant with its exquisitely beautiful flowers, and another the stately tree—the glory of the
                            vegetable realms. One, the sparkling gem ; another, that which gives us the material for our
                            most durable and magnificent edifices. One furnishes that which is agreeable to the sense
                            and productive of health and vigor; another, that which is every way disagreeable and even
                            destructive of life. Separate these into their constituent parts, and the beauty, the
                            fragrance, the solidity, and even their foul and destructive characteristics disappear. The
                            grand truths to be deduced from these facts are, that the various results which are effected
                            in the material world are all owing to the different combinations of its elements; that
                            these combinations and their results are all under the control of the Divine Mind; are
                            partly within the power of created beings at the present time; and, in the future, so far as
                            they affect man's condition, will be wholly under his control. For, it is not to be supposed
                            that our chemists have arrived at all the ultimates of things in their various analyses of
                            Nature, though they have resolved substances into more than sixty of, what they call,
                            primates or elements . And even Huxley, with his newly discovered protoplasm, is likely to
                            be surpassed by future analysts. Seasoning from what has already been discovered by man in
                            the realms of Nature, it is not contrary to the deductions of sound logic to believe that
                            hereafter he will so far penetrate into what are now its secrets, as to be able to give
                            unerring rules for the maintenance of physical health, and, as a necessary consequence, such
                            as shall have an important bearing upon the moral status. Much has already been done towards
                            " a consummation so devoutly to be wished;" but the manifest uncertainties in our various
                            schools of medicine declare how very far we are yet from that most desirable state of
                            things. And the numerous schools for moral health show that there is, at least, among the
                            masses as much uncertainty respecting the true mode of the soul's salvation as of that of
                            the body. And yet, we have all learned something. We have learned that there are certain
                            influences to be shunned if we would maintain physical health, and others to be earnestly
                            sought after. There are those, also, that affect the moral well-being, equally to be
                            avoided, and others, again, to be ardently desired. "Evil communications corrupt good
                            manners," because, like the atmosphere charged with elements that enter not into its
                            constituent parts, they insinuate themselves into the moral system and deposit there what
                            does not belong to the soul. We may shun all these. We live in a physical atmosphere liable
                            to be corrupted by various influences, but we may build our residences above them, so as to
                            be beyond their reach. We are in a world, also, whose moral atmosphere is tainted by various
                            hurtful things, but we may choose that portion of it which is far away from their
                            contaminating influences. The prophetic language of past ages corroborates this. "It shall
                            come to pass in the last days that the mountain of Jehovah's house shall be established in
                            the top of the mountains," far above the moral miasmas of the marshes below, where the pure
                            breath of heaven completely fills field and forest, avenue and dwelling. The angel that
                            talked with the prophet Zeehariah made this declaration: " Jerusalem shall be inhabited as
                            towns without walls," or, literally translated, as country villages; evidently a literal and
                            truthful prophecy of the actual dwelling places of " Jerusalem which is above;" above the
                            old one with its narrow, filthy, disease-producing streets, and its lofty, war-enticing
                            walls, and above everything that is low in its moral and spiritual condition. "I," says
                            Jehovah, "will be a wall of fire round about, and will be tiie glory in the midst of her."
                            He is her protection both from external foes and internal vices, better than walls of stone
                            and gates of brass. The Divine Breath goes through her fields, her streets and her
                            dwellings. It makes music in her groves, moves in her waving grain, and manifests itself in
                            the beauty and fragrance of every flower that greets the eye. Entering into the innermost
                            spirit of every one enrolled as a citizen of fhis Jerusalem, and working outwardly, it
                            brings everything within him into the completest harmony with the whole. "Every divinely
                            inspired scripture is profitable for doctrine, for reproof, for correction, for instruction
                            in righteousness, that the man of God may be perfect." He in whom God breathes the divine
                            life, may impart that life to others, and even his writings, though subject to numerous
                            copyings and translations, will have an influence for good on all after generations, so that
                            the apostle has justly styled such, " God-breathed scripture." This inspiring influence is
                            not confined to the books of the Bible, whether Catholic or Protestant, but is discovered,
                            also, in the writings of many others, by those whom the Divine Spirit illuminates. This
                            life-giving breath was that which inspired John Wesley on that memorable occasion when,
                            listening to the reading of Luther's scripture comments, he felt a strange glow in his
                            heart. It was this which gave him " thoughts that breathed and words that burned," and made
                            him so efficient in turning others to righteousness. If, however, he had given more heed to
                            the word that spoke within him than to those written by Luther, he would have effected a
                            more thorough work than he did; though, it is true, Luther's theology could not shut the
                            divine teachings wholly from his soul. This, also, dwelt largely in George Fox, as a fire
                            within him, constraining him to cry aloud and spare not the vices of his age. This pure
                            breath of Heaven became the permanent life of Mother Ann when she had wrought out her
                            redemption from the lower life; and, in the possession of this, she could say, " If there is
                            anything within me contrary to God, I do not know it." This was recognized by many of her
                            devoted children as soon as they came into her presence; was felt in her singing, in her
                            words of encouragement, and in her reproofs of sin. This must be the life-element of the
                            Christian, <pb n="77" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. 77 which shall purge from his entire being
                            whatever does not belong to the life of Heaven; must create within him new desires and
                            dispositions that will, in the end, infinitely surpass the best which he possessed
                            previously. When this is effected within him, then is accomplished in him, in its highest
                            sense, the divine fiat, " Behold, I create all things new! "</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName"/>Wm. H. Bussell</byline></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Physical improvement" TEIform="index"/>Physical Improvement</head><p TEIform="p">It is not a question, but a settled fact, that physical culture and improvement should go
                            hand in hand with spiritual progression. It is uphill work to be good Christians, unless we
                            learn to live rightly, physically, and obey the laws of life and health. A sound mind in a
                            healthy body is the best condition in which to lire out the true principles of Christianity,
                            and enable us to do the greatest amount of good, spiritually and physicallyLet us set about
                            the work more earnestly, to correct all the wrong habits of life. Let us learn to take care
                            of our health, keep the digestive organs in good order, being careful not to overtax them.
                            Our food should be healthful, and healthfully prepared; we should eat our food slowly, with
                            thankful hearts and cheerful spirits. There is much said and done to suppress the sin of
                            intemperance in alcoholic drinks, while the great sin of gluttony is winked at; and who is
                            wise enough to tell which is the more deplorable, the more effectual in breaking down the
                            constitution, benumbing the senses, depressing the spirits, and unfitting people for active
                            duty ? The Shakers have made some efforts to reform and over- come the wrong habits of life;
                            they have gained some victories, but have more yet to gain. "Would it not be well for some
                            to speak through The Shaker in regard to these matters ? Let the testimony go forth, both to
                            Shakers, and to others who have ideas that need to be shaken. Those living in the order of
                            nature, in the marriage state, should so live as to produce healthy offspring; such as will
                            make good Shakers. The world stands in need of more Shakers, to act as a balancing power ;
                            to keep in check the increasing tide of human depravity. It is for the world's interest to
                            have more good Shakers on the earth. Then, let all be awakened to feel the need of coming up
                            higher ; of living holier and practicing more self-denial; and let all who feel that they
                            are able to bear the Shaker cross and live the life, be Shakers.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wetherbee, William H." TEIform="persName"/>Wm. H. Wetherbee, Shirley, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="End of the world" TEIform="index"/>The End of the World</head><p TEIform="p">This subject is being agitated at the present time with increased animation. "The World's
                            Crisis" is positive of this event occurring within five years.; when the earth will
                            collapse, and Jesus make an appearance to save Second Adventists from the otherwise general
                            destruc tion. We have before us a pamphlet,* written with much sincerity, and compiled with
                            much mathematical ingenuity, declarative of the destruction of the physical world in the
                            year 1873. We are believers in the ending of the * " The Midnight Cry !" by Barbour, world,
                            and of the appearance of Christ's Spirit; and make no objection to the times that have been
                            set; but of choice would name 1871. We have a hopeful faith that the world will end in 1875
                            ; also in 1873 ; and nearer still, the present year of 1871! The world to which we refer is
                            the world of sin; others allude to the physical earth. The result of our opinions, would be
                            perfected Christian characters, by being those "upon whom the ends of the world have come,"
                            as really to-day as two or four years hence. The result of Miles Grant's opinions would be
                            the resurrection of dead bodies ; weeping, wailing and gnashing of teeth on the part of the
                            multitude, while a few would rise to ineffable glory in perfected physical trim. If the
                            world is to end, we say let it end to our largest Christian profit; at the expense of our
                            pride; our lusts; to the destruction of all that makes us unlike our pattern—Jesus, who
                            became the Christ. Our earth is too pretty to be destroyed ; but our evil dispositions, made
                            up of the world, are only worthy of annihilation, and the quicker they merit their just
                            dues, the better for the individual and the race. Our beautiful earth will continue to
                            revolve, we believe, a few centuries longer; but the work of purging from our souls '' the
                            beggarly elements of the world" should commence at once; let these come to an immediate
                            ending. The elements composing the world which should end, are " the lusts of the flesh, of
                            the eyes, and the pride of life ; " and "be of good cheer," said Jesus, "for I have brought
                            these elements to an end." Putting an end to the world, after the manner of Jesus, causes
                            the dead to rise—the dead in sinful works; for they cease their sinfulness and are
                            resurrected to the life of the righteous. The Adventists are looking in the clouds of earth
                            for the coming man; while they should seek among the clouds of heavenly witnesses, the
                            truth, that the second appearance of Christ will be through the feminine order I But why
                            dwell upon the second appearance of Christ, while so few are assured that Christ has made a
                            first advent ? The first appearance of Christ to any individual will have the effect of
                            saving him from his sins; not from the penalty of past sins, but from the necessity of
                            transgression in the present and future. How many experience this salvation? to just so many
                            has Christ appeared, no more. And none can realize the second advent of this blessed Spirit,
                            until they have experienced the baptism of the first appearance, which will put an end to
                            the world of sin, ere the second advent can take place. All will yet experience the end of
                            the world. All will be visited by the Spirit of Christ. But these occurrences will not
                            happen simultaneously to all. Some have already put an end to the world in themselves, and
                            are experiencing the blessing of Christ's Second Appearance ! Others are ripening up to be
                            harvested from the world, by the harvestman —Christ; then will they willingly forsake a
                            worldly life; all that composes the practice of "the children of this world" will be brought
                            to a speedy close. Here is the hope of the people called Shakers—having ripened up to the
                            necessity of living angelic lives, they are those " upon whom the ends of the world have
                            come;" and they look for the continuance of their organization, to those whom the Spirit of
                            Christ will similarly affect. But the people generally, at present, seem too devoted to the
                            pleasures of a worldly life, and are quite unwilling that these should end. Elder Grant,
                            while looking for a general smash-up in 1875, is quite unwilling to become " a eunuch for
                            the kingdom of heaven's sake" before that time; and we will have patience with him, and all
                            other Adventists, if, upon the non-appearance of Jesus; the continuation of the earth in its
                            course; the willful adhesion of dead bodies to their graves, and the absence of a general
                            conflagration, they will come to the common-sense conclusion, that what they are earnestly
                            looking for with their natural eyes, will occur only in a spiritual manner and be
                            spiritually discerned. Many arrived at this conclusion after the failure of 1843; and are
                            among the staunchest supporters of the principles of the Shaker Church to-day. They have
                            since seen the earth, and earthly pleasures pass away with a great noise; they have heard
                            Gabriel's trumpet sounding the "come up higher" invitation; they were dead in trespasses,
                            and were raised up to the mount of salvation ; and when they realized their mistake they
                            sung, as all sincere Adventists are destined to sing: " Adieu, adieu, vain viorld, farewell
                            I I find no rest in thee ! Thy greatest pleasures form a hell Too dark and sad for me! Alas,
                            alaa! I have too long Preferred thy sinful crowd ; I've listened to thy siren song 'Till
                            mercy called aloud ! "Adieu, vain world, I say once more j I'iti bound for Canaan's land j I
                            see a happy world before, Prepared at God's right hand! On life's tempestuous sea I sail,
                            Where countless billows roll; Yet Christ, my pilot, will not fail,— With him, I trust my
                            soul. "He can command the roaring tid«, And silencie all my foes; With courage, safely I can
                            ride Through every wind that blows; And as I daily homeward steer, Toward the sweet land of
                            peace, 'this iVorid does less and less appear, And all its charms decrease t "While shining
                            millions, sailed before,— Who've gained the port above, Found nothing in old Babel's store,
                            That they could prize or love ; That everlasting glory bright, Will tarnish all below; Just
                            as the sun's meridian height Forbids the stars to glow i" *</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Be strong, be steadfast..." TEIform="index"/>Be strong, be steadfast...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Be strong, be steadfast in fair virtue's cause. Nor fear reproof, nor covet vain applause;
                            Heed not of evil tongues the envious strife, Nor the loud storms that rage in human life. On
                            truth's firm basis let your hopes remain, And seas may rage and tempests roar in vain. 'Tis
                            easiest dealing with the firmest mind; More just when it resists, and where it yields, more
                            Blest are the lips that open but to bless! [kind. That never yet the gentle heart belied!
                            Still prompt to smile, to praise, or to cares*, And ever slow to censure or to chide; Blest
                            shall they be on earth by all who hear, Nor their vocation change in heaven above; For what
                            do angel lips in that bright sphere, But sing of praise, of mercy, and of love. How terrible
                            is passion ! how our reason Falls down before it; whilst the tortured frame, Like a ship
                            dashed by fierce encounter's tide, And of her pilot spoiled, drives round and round, The
                            sport of wind and wave. Conn.</p></div2><pb n="78" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let truth roll on" TEIform="index"/>Let Truth roll on</head><p TEIform="p">Eoll on, thou mighty tide of Truth, and deluge ali the land; Sweep error from a suffering
                            World, where now it holds command. Koll on, roll on, nor cease to flow, 'till each vile weed
                            shall die,— The worthless tareg and bitte? fruit sown by the enemy* Too long already hath
                            this tide let back upon Its source| But yet 'twas gaining added strength and a resistless
                            force; And as the rains from heaven descend, this swelling; torrent deep1 Shall dash the
                            foam impetuously, and every barrier leap. Then raise the flood-gates, free its course, and
                            let it onward go j The thirsty earth will drink it in, and better fruit wiil grow. Why
                            should we waste our precious stores, in this the time of dearth, When lo ! grim want and
                            famine gaunt, are stalking o'er the earth. Why not get free this blessed stream, to irrigate
                            the land; Why not " go into all the world," obeying Christ's command? These solemn thoughts
                            and feelings deep, are surging in my soul, I can no longer silence Ikeep, Truth must and
                            will control. To wakeful watchers, it is true, the night seems very long; Some fear in
                            darkness should we work, it might be all done wrong ; But morning now is dawning bright upon
                            the traveler's way, And glorious rays of gleaming light declare the coming day. 'Tis time
                            for gospel light to spread abroad o'er land and sea; And man must learn that nothing else
                            but truth can make him free. O, let it have an outlet wide—let gospel graces shine, 'Till
                            all can see and own, that love and virtue are divine.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Persons, E. H." TEIform="persName"/>E. H. Persons, Harvard</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Retrospection" TEIform="index"/>Retrospection</head><p TEIform="p">A century has passed since Mother Ann's gospel was revealed to mortals; and, though we may
                            think the progress slow, that but little has been achieved, yet let us consider how great,
                            how laborious, was the work of the first pioneers. I have watched the rise and progress of
                            Pleasant Hill from my childhood up, for sixty-two years. I saw the brethren, with their own
                            industrious hands, fell the sturdy oaks and maples, right here, where our large and
                            commodious dwellings now stand and have stood for many long years. I saw very soon, young as
                            I was, that providing for the outer man was not their greatest aim, but they sought first
                            the kingdom of heaven, and then, by giving their hearts to God and putting their hands to
                            work, they wrought wonders in this land. How very easy now for the wayfaring man, the widow
                            and the orphans to find a home oi sweet rest, where everything is ready, provided by the
                            hands of kind and tender friends. ] verily believe, that in the course of another century,
                            the beautiful villages, that are being reared by the hands of the pure and righteous
                            servants of God, will become ''As diadems on the brow of the Universe."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hooser, Hortency G." TEIform="persName"/>Hortency G. Hooser, Pleasant Hill</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Time, its records" TEIform="index"/>Time, its Records</head><p TEIform="p">Thou precious boon to mortals given, A little space in which to learn— Probation is thy name
                            in Heaven, Thou'rt fruitful with immortal germs. Whither dost thou flee forever? Say what
                            freight thy moments bear ! From my soul What strong endeavor? What the deeds thou dost
                            declare? None can stay thy rolling ages, None recall thy moments past; Deep engraven are thy
                            pages, Fadeless are thy photographs: Life, the silent; tireless artist, On thy flying canvas
                            lays Every changing scene, regardless % That the form so soon decays. O, thou viewless
                            portrait taker; thy unerring pencil, df'atri The minutest act or feature, And records its
                            secret cause ; Slaves and nobles, fools and sages, There behold their likeness cast j Time
                            will soon unfurl its pages, Nothing perished but the mask. Spoken to the ear in closets, Or
                            in deeds revealed to sight; Even though you've only mused them, There are blazing, wrong or
                            right! Faithfully they stand recorded, Pleading at the angel court; And though never, never
                            worded, Each shall make its true report. The revelations of physiology, phrenology and
                            psychometry go to prove that every person carries his history with him, and that history is
                            manifest in his actions, and stamps his features with unerring precision. " A man is, what
                            he does." Every act of mind or body, open or secret, helps make each individual life, that
                            is displayed in character. Each act records itself with a faint or deep impression,
                            according to the nature and intensity of the impulse that prompts it. Behold the astronomer,
                            gauging spacej and resolving the intricate mazes of planets, suns and systems—those mighty
                            chroniclers of unnumbered cycles. He seems already to have entered eternity, and, in his
                            contemplation of past and future, to gaze upon the eternal. Somewhat nearer, see the
                            geologist, closely scanning the rocks, and drawing from the depths of the earth her secret
                            records, extending back through countless ages, to primeval chaos. Nearer, still, we see
                            history laid under contribution, and the exhumed monuments o1 buried races are made to
                            testify to the past transactions and acquirements of the human family. Also the Bible, that
                            venerated book and much abused record, is put upon trial, it doctrines canvassed and merits
                            discussed, in this age of ages. Even that which has so long claimed the name and station of
                            Christianity is brought to the bar and sharply interrogated; and we opine that, before the
                            trial terminates, it will be found miserably wanting in ali the essential elements of pure
                            Christianity—for, see i it does not save its votaries from sin 1 Its most sanctified
                            teachers and professors confess themselves sinners, and believe it impossible to live
                            without sin! What a sham Christianity is that which, instead of burning up iniquity, spreads
                            a veil over it! All departments of human knowledge anc research seem to be undergoing a
                            sifting or shaking process, by the power of the quickenec ntellect of the rade. If any
                            believe these are not the external manifestations of the judgment day, will they believe
                            that the spirit of jrogress is less active, less progressive in the spiritual than in the
                            natural and intellectual slements of man's creation ? If the spirit of God operates among
                            mankind ike wheels within wheels, the centre being much smaller and slower in movement than
                            he circumference, may not attract so much attention, though it be the source, both of notion
                            and power to those more external. People see a small body of Shakers, view their external
                            organization and habits, and, perhaps, think them a strange curiosity— being, however, only
                            as one tree surrounded by a forest, or as one block in a quarry, they are deemed remarkable
                            for singularity, but otherwise of little consequence. Few stop to inquire why it is so, or
                            what will come of it. Alter learning that Shakers hold a community of interests, that they
                            are very neat, very honest, and do not marry, they care not to go much further. But why is
                            it ? What induces free and intelligent people to associate together for the practice of
                            principles so repugnant to the natural feelings and desires of the earthly man as are those
                            of the Shakers' ? Wealth cannot be the motive, where all are upon a level, and distribution
                            is made to each according to needs and circumstances, without reference to individual tastes
                            and peculiarities, and where the surplus goes for the benefit of the needy, or unfortunate
                            outside of the organization. The desire for a comfortable home cannot be the bond of union
                            in so much voluntary restraint; neither can it be ignorance of themselves or of the world
                            that keeps the Shakers together. What, then, is the secret bond of their union ? Who devised
                            a plan so contrary to man's depraved nature ? Who sustains it ? And what is the purpose of
                            its Author ? These are questions well worth the consideration of the seriously inclined.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo" TEIform="persName"/>Alonzo Hollister, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Setting sun" TEIform="index"/>The Setting Sun</head><p TEIform="p">The setting sun resplendent shone, And bade the earth farewell ; Soon night's deep shades
                            will intervene, And cast upon each lovely scene Ita dark and silent spell. Yet weep not
                            thou, but humbly bow— God worketh not in vain ; Although beneath the stormy wave, The
                            brilliant orb sinks in the grave, 'Twill rise, 'twill rise again, 'Twill rise again, 'twill
                            rise again; Although beneath the stormy wave, The brilliant orb sinks in the grave, 'Twill
                            rise, 'twill rise again. What then, if here the silent tear Doth oft unbidden roll; While
                            every joy that filled the heart, In sorrow seemeth to depart, And darkness veils thy soul;
                            Yet fear not thou, but humbly bow— Thy tears aie not in vain; Although beneath the stormy
                            wave, Thy sun of gladness make its grave, 'Twill rise, 'twill rise again, 'Twill rise again,
                            'twill rise again ; Although beneath the stormy wave, Thy sun of gladness make its grave,
                            'Twill rise, 'twill rise again.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Robe, John" TEIform="persName"/>John Robe, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><pb n="79" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="American shaker in London" TEIform="index"/>The American Shaker in London</head><p TEIform="p">To the Editor of the Golden Age •¦ Your kind favor of the 27th of July is at hand. I have not
                            received (but expect to in a day or two) The Golden Age. Indeed, many " lovers of this
                            kind," have waited for that in the shadowy past, and "obtained not the sight." But thanks to
                            time and the laws of progress, which, like those of gravitation, never relax their efforts,
                            now is the desired consummation nearer than ever before. I am in London, England. I see, I
                            hear, I observe, and u I keep up a terrible thinking." Ninetysix years ago, a poor woman
                            externally, but rich in the notice of the Heavens, was driven from these shores by the "
                            Church and State" " beast " to the wilderness of America, then in the Revolutionary
                            struggle, which by the " visions of God," she declared would result in the establishment of
                            a government that would let each person frame their own theology. And thanks to the
                            yet-to-be-honored name of Thomas Paine, more than any other, that " Golden Age " idea was
                            realized. And to-day I am in London, as the representative successor of this same woman ;
                            and back of me are some seventy communities of people, who believe that she experienced the
                            return to our earth of "the Christ," which first the Heathen Roman Church and State, and
                            then the Christian Roman Church and State, crucified; and the latter a good deal more
                            effectually than the former; for the " saint " who sins, serves the devil more acceptably
                            than any "sinner" can possibly do. So far as my mission has been known, England has said "
                            Blessed is he that cometh in the name of the Lord! " I have been most hospitably received
                            and attentively listened unto. I began by announcing a meeting in Cleveland Hall, where the
                            Spiritualists had held frequent meetings. The attendance was small, but increased at each
                            succeeding call, until I decided to give all who wished to hear and see a Shaker, an
                            opportunity to do so, by engaging St. George's Hall, and inviting Hepworth Dixon to occupy
                            the chair. But I sadly miscalculated the slow, unexcitable, and unfanatical English mind, as
                            not more than a third of the people who came could get into the hall. Those who did fill it,
                            were of the " better classes," to use an Englishism. As tickets had been sent to some two
                            hundred M.Ps. and sixty editors, we had a corps of reporters. And among them all, the Times
                            did itself the honor to make the fairest report ; and much to my surprise, the Thunderer has
                            taken the lead in welcoming " the Shaker," saying that " it was an opportunity not to be
                            lost, to hear an authentic exposition of Shakerism." The result is that I am literally
                            overwhelmed with visitors, invitations to lecture, and applications to go home with me to
                            "Zion." My impressions, while in my quiet mountain home, of the state of England, is
                            realized to the letter. Politically, as well as geographically, there is only " the Channel
                            " between England and Prance. The plethora of population is felt by everybody. " There are
                            too many of us," is the common expression. Yesterday I received an invitation to deliver an
                            address before the Co-operative Emigration Society ; I have spoken before " The Temperance
                            League;" the Woman Suffrage people are especially favorable to an Order, founded by a woman,
                            claiming that God, being dual, the Government of the Universe itself is equally masculine
                            and feminine ; and that it ought to be the type and pattern of all human governments, from
                            that of the household of nature to " the household of faith," with its " father and mother
                            and brethren and sisters," having their houses and lands1 m common. The Peace advocates find
                            coadjutors in Shakers; and in proposing (as you will see by the report of my St. George's
                            Hall speech, which I send you, I have done), that the English people put their governmental
                            machinery into the hands of the Quakers, who "marry and are given in marriage" (as we have
                            turned our Indian government over to them), I have put the " dead body " of the Quakers on
                            their feet again, and would give them something to keep them alive. And inasmuch as this
                            government, in the society, is dual, and they are practically acquainted with the rights and
                            capabilities of woman, who thus, " by reason of use," have their managing abilities
                            developed, let the Quaker men take possession of the House of Commons and the Quaker women
                            have the House of Lords. This will begin the millennium. The reign of "peace on earth "
                            would commence by disbanding the army and navy, and" breaking up the whole military System.
                            The people would soon be the owners of the soil; poverty be banished; "the social evil" be
                            no more an eye-sore, and a cancer on the vitals of the nation. The national debt would be
                            paid and cancelled; and one nation would actualize the visions of the seers; and the words
                            of promise spoken by "all the prophets since the world began," would be no longer vain
                            visions, or hope deferred, which has made the heart of humanity sick; but hope would have
                            its fruition in a just, peaceful, and happy people; and the co-existence of the
                            resurrection, or Shaker Order of celibacy, would hold in check, and balance the principle of
                            population.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans London, August 11th, 1871</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Draw nigh" TEIform="index"/>Draw Nigh</head><p TEIform="p">There was a law among the ancient Persians, that whomsoever should present themselves before
                            the king, unless they were called to his presence, should be put to death, except such to
                            whom the king should extend the golden sceptre. (See Esther, iv:ll.) But in this our day we
                            have no such prohibition. The sceptre to us is always extended. And it is a sceptre of
                            mercy. The still small voice says come. It is a general and universal invitation, from our
                            glorious King, to draw nigh at all times, and in all circumstances, by prayer and devout
                            supplication, to make known our desires to Him. And we may freely address Him, not only as
                            the Eternal, the Almighty, Creator of all things, but as our heavenly Father and Mother. It
                            is not in the spirit of bondage, or of fear, that we may approach Him; but in the spirit of
                            love. We may cry to Him, not as a criminal to a judge, nor as a slave to a master, but as a
                            child to a Father, whom he tenderly loves, and who feels for him a pure and holy affec-
                            tion. The Apostle John says : " I write unto you, little children, because ye have known the
                            Father." Who is a child so likely to know as his Father ? What is the first word he utters
                            but "My Father," or "My Mother?" To whom is he so likely to flee in the hour of danger ? On
                            whom will he call so freely in distress ? He relies on him for care and protection. He
                            expects that he will defend him and provide for him. Then, will not God, who stands in this
                            endearing relation, in a much higher and holier degree, exemplify it and fulfill it more
                            perfectly aud divinely ? He certainly will. Then let this give us boldness and courage, at
                            all times, to ask, and the promise is that we shall receive. Draw nigh. Conn. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What hidden works of darkness lie shrouded..." TEIform="index"/>What hidden works of darkness lie shrouded...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">What hidden works of darkness lie shrouded beneath the mask of base deception—of speeches
                            fair, and colors false! Oh! the depth of human depravity. It is honorable to be great; it is
                            excellent to be small. " Suffer little children, and forbid them not, to come unto me; for
                            of such is the kingdom of heaven." Plough deep the fallow ground of the heart, sow and
                            cultivate the seeds of purity, love and truth, and you will reap a rich harvest of true
                            felicity. What is hell?—A condemned conscience. Where, and what is Heaven ? — Heaven is
                            within you; it is a condition or state of the mind devoid of error or remorse. Let those who
                            profess faith in Jesus Christ maintain good works. " By their fruits ye shall know them." "
                            I am a dead dog," exclaimed a poor backslider to the Christian faith! Is there not more hope
                            of him than of a professing Christian saint, who sins daily and seeks to hide his iniquity ?
                            Prayer, like a golden key, unlocks treasures of inestimable value. Be careful which way you
                            turn it.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The heart of a wicked person drinks in vanity as a dry sponge absorbs water..." TEIform="index"/>The heart of a wicked person drinks in vanity as a dry sponge absorbs water...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The heart of a wicked person drinks in vanity as a dry sponge absorbs water. When they are
                            full, a very little pressure causes an emission.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Buckingham, D. A." TEIform="persName"/>D. A. Buckingham</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Why I am a shaker" TEIform="index"/>Why I am a Shaker</head><p TEIform="p">A friend asks : " Why are you a Shaker ?" jJnswer.—Because I have resolved to be an honest
                            man — a Christian. Jesus was the first Christian. By precept and example he pointed to a
                            more excellent way than was marked out even in the Jewish economy, which was far above
                            heathen idolatry. When I was awakened to see my loss from God, through a departure from his
                            laws, I sought to become a Christian. I looked to the Churches to find the good Shepherd who
                            feeds his flock, for my soul was hungry. But I could not find him ; nor hear his voice. I
                            then looked to find his footprints, that I might know whither he leadeth his flock to rest.
                            The ministers of the popular churches told me that I <pb n="80" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 8O THE SHAKER. was
                            a Christian. But my conscience said, Nay! Jesus Christ, the great examplar, said, come out
                            from the world and be separate; be pure, be just, be holy; renounce war, and those lusts
                            which produce war. " As ye would that others should do to you, so do ye the same to them." I
                            knew that I could not be a full Christian unless I followed the example of Jesus Christ, and
                            lived, in word and deed, as he did; and my conscience reproached me, and was my accuser day
                            and night; for I was so very unlike the Pattern, who was a celibate from deep principle;
                            this I was not. He utterly condemned war; I did not. He said, " Whosoever shall do the will
                            of my Father who is in Heaven, the same is my relative — my mother, or sister, or brother."
                            The ties of consanguinity (not the principles of pure celibacy) formed the bond which held
                            me. The Spirit, through Providential agencies, led me to the Shakers. I found them to be a
                            community of people living as did the Pentecostal Church, ignoring war and private property,
                            loving their brethren and sisters as themselves, and abstaining from all sexual and sensual
                            gratifications ; indeed, living pure virgin lives. " By their fruits ye shall know them."
                            Here were the fruits. As an honest man, I cast my lot with them. They taught me to confess
                            and forsake all sin ; to right every wrong; to cleanse my heart from all impurity, and to
                            "go and sin no more." TTiis is why lam a Shaker.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Georgeson, Adam" TEIform="persName"/>Adam Georgeson", Canaan, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">We learn that black was the color, decided by the majority, for the new fence at the
                                Church Family—we yield to majorities. Apples scarce; pears abundant, but suffering from
                                blight or rust; blackberries many—'•' twenty-two individuals, including horses and
                                wagon*, visited Washington Mt. to collect them, September 2." F. W. Evans arrived home
                                on the 5th of September, in good health, though somewhat worn; he was more than
                            welcome.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watervliet" TEIform="index"/>Watervliet</head><p TEIform="p">Ministry here on the 13th of September, from Lebanon. General health. Sealing fruits in
                                full operation. </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hancock, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Hancock, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">A new woodhouse is completed here— thirty feet by seventy feet. Crops look well—corn a
                                little later than usual. </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Chiirch family have done some painting. The North have painted all their buildings within
                                the year. If any Shakers, or those who admire Shaker work, are in need of Shaker pails,
                                tubs, etc., write IT. Cumings, Enfield, N. H. We are vouchers for quality. </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shirley, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Shirley, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">says we made a mistake concerning blackberries—they Were 6he-berries; glad to correct.
                                They also want more health than wai represented in September. </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Canterbury, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">"Larger crowds at our meetings this year than for years. Wish we could better administer
                                to their necessities " Usual health. Elder Benjamin Smith is afflicted by over-exertion
                                and sunstroke, bnt improving. </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Alfred, Maine" TEIform="index"/>-Alfred., Me.</head><p TEIform="p">Ministry at Mt. L. on the 2d of September. Sale of place not mentioned. </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="South Union, Kentucky" TEIform="index"/>South. Union, Ky.</head><p TEIform="p">Religious element very scarce in these parts—about fifty attending public service from
                                without the village—more beinjj too lazy to get up, and to our meetings by 10 A.
                            it."</p></div3><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Obituaries</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Youngs, Henry" TEIform="index"/>Henry Youngs
                                </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Youngs, Henry" TEIform="persName">Henry Youngs</persName>, Mt. L., aged 83, August
                                22.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dean, Richard" TEIform="index"/>Richard Dean
                                </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Dean, Richard" TEIform="persName">Richard Dean</persName>, W. V., N. Y., aged 73, Aug.
                                    17.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rawson, Anna" TEIform="index"/>Anna Rawson
                                </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Rawson, Anna" TEIform="persName">Anna Rawson</persName>, Hancock, aged 92, August
                                17.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hastings, Eunice" TEIform="index"/>Eldress Eunice Hastings
                                </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Hastings, Eunice" TEIform="persName">Eldress Eunice Hastings</persName>, Hancock, aged
                                    80, Sept. 9.</p></div4></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">Notice.—Stereoscopic views of Shaker villages can be obtained by addressing James Irving,
                                Troy, N. Y., and H. A. Kimball, Concord, N. H. *</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gospel treasures" TEIform="index"/>Gospel Treasures</head><p TEIform="p">Should we take the bright wings of the^morn And soar over mountain and sea, From isles that
                            old ocean adorn, To lands where the bright flowers be; Should the mountains unbosom their
                            gold, And ocean her jewels restore. Should earth all her treasures unfold, Our spirits would
                            still thirst for more. There are far reaching depths in the soul, No phantoms of pleasure
                            can fill; There are wild waves of passions that roll, No power but of Heaven can still:
                            There's a heart sad and lonely within, A hunger for good from above; There's a deep seated
                            sorrow for sin, And thirst for pure Heavenly love. There's a happiness purity brings,
                            Contentment the gospel bestows; There's a hope in the trusting heart springs, Triumphant
                            o'er earth and its woes: There's a treasure of bliss far away, Reserved for the righteous in
                            store; And the bright morn is dawning to-day That never knows night any more. There are
                            pleasures that never grow old, And hopes that will never decay; There's a wealth that is
                            richer than gold, To all who the gospel obey. Rejoice, then, ye faithful and true, Your day
                            of salvation has come; The bright crown of glory in view, Invites to your Heavenly home.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leggett, E. T." TEIform="persName"/>E. T. Leggett. Union Village, Ohio, Aug. 1871</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To the juvenile class" TEIform="index"/>To the Juvenile Class</head><p TEIform="p">The different stages of human existence may be compared to the seasons of each year— Spring,
                            Summer, Autumn and Winter. The skillful agriculturist and horticulturist understand the
                            appropriate work for each of the seasons as they roll around. Spring is the proper time to
                            prepare the soil for the reception of choice seeds. The earth itself contains seed which
                            will grow without cultivation, and bring forth fruits and flowers. Some of the various kinds
                            of fruits which grow spontaneously, are good and useful for food, both for men and birds;
                            other kinds, which look very inviting, are poisonous and very hurtful. So of wild flowers
                            and plants; some contain deadly poison, although they may be beautiful in appearance, while
                            other kinds emit a sweet perfume, and the aroma is healthful. But cereals, and the choicest
                            fruits and flowers, are produced by skill and labor. After the soil is properly prepared,
                            the wise and careful husbandman deposits the good seed in the earth, where it is kindly
                            nourished, warmed and enlivened by the sun's rays, and moistened by the dew-drops and gentle
                            showers. Thus nurtured, those seeds germinate, and the little roots being weak and tender,
                            they work their way down into the soil to get a strong hold there; while the delicate
                            tendrils climb upward.into the sunlight and unfold their leaves, which are full of little
                            fibres, resembling the veins and pores of the human body, which open their mouths to inhale
                            the pure atmosphere and drink in the sweet dews of the morning. With intense interest the
                            agriculturist watches the growth of the good seed, and also watches, with a jealous eye, the
                            appearance of every wild plant, or weed, that he may without delay pluck them up so that
                            they may not choke the better seed, which should occupy the whole ground and have room to
                            expand and grow, nourished by the full strength of the soil. Even then, if the sun refuses
                            to shine, or the clouds withhold the rain, those choice plants or vines become enfeebled,
                            and wither, droop and die. But, aided by those essential elements, and the nice implements
                            which art has produced, he toils hopefully on, and by midsummer he begins to reap some of
                            the fruits of his labor. The gathering in of a bountiful harvest is a joyful task, although
                            somewhat laborious. With an eye to the future, day after day he toils on and gathers the
                            ripe fruits, each in their season, and stores them carefully away; and, by the time that
                            Spring, Summer and Autumn have passed, his garners are filled. And when the cold bleak winds
                            of winter come riding along in their chariot, and the fleecy snows cover hill and dale, and
                            ice-bound rivers and lakes are seen on the right hand and the left, this wise tiller of the
                            soil is ready to wrap himself in his mantle and gather to his warm fireside to enjoy the
                            fruits of his labor in the midst of peace and plenty. In my next I will show the analogy of
                            the seasons with the life we call human.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. Doolittle</byline></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is desired that Believers interested in the Medium and Daybreak, of London..." TEIform="index"/>It is desired that Believers interested in the Medium and Daybreak, of London...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">It is desired that Believers interested in the Medium and Daybreak, of London, should
                            subscribe for the same. F. W. Evans will act as agent. </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker, monthly journal, devoted to the exposition of religion, acording to Shaker theology" TEIform="index"/>THE SHAKER. MONTHLY JOURNAL, DEVOTED TO THE EXPOSITION OF RELIGION, ACCORDING TO SHAKER
                            THEOLOGY.</head><p TEIform="p"> Fifty Cents, Per Annum, in Advance. G. A. Lomas, Resident Editor, Shakers, Albany Co., N. Y.
                        </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Members of society" TEIform="index"/>MEMBERS OF SOCIETY</head><p TEIform="p"> Appointed to answer Correspondents, among whom are the Board of Editors. Elder F. W. Evans,
                            Mt. Lebanon, Columbia Co., N. Y. 11 Issachar Bates, Shakers, N. Y. " Calvin G. Reed, Mt.
                            Morris, Livingston Co., N. Y. " Simon Mabee, West Pittsfield, Mass. " Stoughton Kellogg,
                            Thompsonville, Conn., Shakers. " Albert Battles, Tyringham, Berkshire Co., Mass. " ffm,
                            Leonard, Aver, Mass., Shakers. " John Whiteley, Shirley Village, Middlesex Co., Mass. "
                            Nehemiah Trull, Shaker Village, Merrimack Co.,N. H. " Henry Cummings, Enfield, Grafton Co.,
                            N. H. " John B. Vance, Alfred, Shakers, York Co., Me. " Alonzo Gilman, West Gloucester,
                            Cumberland Co., Me., Shakers. " Chas. Clapp, Union Village, Warren Co., O., Shakers. " Ezra
                            Sherman, Preston, Hamilton Co., Ohio, Shakers. " Stephen Ball, Dayton, Shakers, Ohio. "
                            Jacob Snip, Pleasant Hill, Mercer Co., Ky. " J. R. Eades, South Union, Logan Co., Ky. " J.
                            S. Prescott, Cleveland, Ohio, Shakers. </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Publications" TEIform="index"/>PUBLICATIONS.</head><p TEIform="p">Christ's First and Second Appearing - Dunlavy's Manifesto .... Millennial Church .....
                            Compendium of Shakerism Three Discourses on United Interests Tracts free, where postage is
                            paid. 1 25 1 00 0 50 0 50</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>