<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2510" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">28</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">East Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">25</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">10</biblScope><date value="18951001" TEIform="date">October 1895</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">219-242</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="25" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="10" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
OCTOBER
MANIFESTO
PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES.
VOL. XXV.
" Cast thy bread upon the waters; for thou shalt find it after many days."
Eccl. XI: i.
East Canterbury, N. H.
1895.
THE
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
CONTEXTS.
The I'nfol -ing of Life
S'lcritice
Sj]f-Cult\mv
Envy,
Jealousy,       '  Kllcr .John Ljon.
Manhood.
Compensation,
Mine a'l.l Thine,
Kind   Words,
Faith,
Muni'e,True Riches,
HoiiK Notes,
Sanitary.,
K.Nc.hi.nyes,
I)  ivth~,
Books & Paper- -,
2! 
-'/1
2^1
2'2iH
22!l
   -232
'233
2:54
240
24n
WANTED
 SALESMEN
We
W il 11 t
one or
vo GOOD MEN in each County to take
orders for a Ciioice line of NURSERY
STOCK or SEED POTATOES Stoi k and
Seed guunuiteeu. We ftan give you Steady
Employment with Regular Pay. It will
eos-t you nothing to give it a trial. St.-ite when
\\ ii i fit.u which yor prefer to sell.   Undress
The Hawks Nursery Co.,
Rochester, N. Y.  .
cAVEATSJRHDEMARt
COPYRIGHTS.
.CA1V I  OT5TATN   A   PATENT?     Fora
Srompt answer and nn honest opinion, write to
IUNN &; CO., who have had nearly fifty years'
experience in the patent business. Commnnieations strictly confidential. A Handbook of Information concerning Patents and how to obtain them sent free. Also n catalogue of mechanical and scientific books sent free.
Patents taken 'through Munn & Co. receive
special^notice in the Scientific Americnii, and
thus are brought widely before the public without coat to the inventor. This splendid paper,
issued weekly, elegantly illustrated, has by far the
larpeat circu)ation of any scientific work in the
world.  $3 a year.   Sample copies sent free.
Building Edition-inonthly, $2.50 a year. Single
copies, ii;5 cents. JSvery number contains beautiful plates, in colors, and photographs of new
houses, with plans, ejinblinfr builders to show the
latest designs and secure contracts.   Address
MUNN & CO., NiiW York, 3(51 BROADWAY.
THE DIVINE AFFLATUS,
A
FORCE IX HISTORY.
Price,  10 viz.
Good r'liiU)le men, to -;<>11
our Choice ;'rH Hstrdy
Niivssery Stock ^ich hs Fruit
Trei s, Ro.se.-> Shniljsiuid i)rin. nic.ntjils. LiidU'!* uake tin- lusiae.-s a sucec.-> . F&sv work, ]J 'iisunt, lifilit mi I i>rofitiiblc. < IJT, IT FREE. ^ I'plv iitonce, witli I'cfiTenci:-'. Mid securcchoict' of t^i'ritoi-v.
ter, 3ST. Y.
 and   Seedsmen,   Roches.
Everyiu) ly knows "Piiul Revere'.' Rile'
but what else did he ever <>o? The "Dictionary of United States Historx " U'll>.
:Tliis s>ta.ncinr(l reference book is arranged
lalphitljetifiilly, and  contains  s-lioit,  erlsp,|
eoni-ise, eoinpreheiif-iive information ><bout!
ievery event in American liistory, ;im':
!aliout the man  who  made the event .   It
tells at a slanee what wouLl take hours oi
.rrfsearch in other bocks. It fills a pla-je in
ibooktloin that was -wholly vacant l.eioiH it
Icaine. It is needed in every home inn,
:libiary, by   writers,   teachers,   preachers,
and laymen. Oxw author, J. Franklin
;.lameson,   Ph. 1).,   Professor of History of
Brown -University, foiuieriy of Johns Hop
!kins Xniversil y.
 cau make more sales with less talk
U ami  less  walking  with   this book
jiliim with mi) thing else -tliey ever sold.   It
'appeals to everybody..  Jt is" htai<lsome, en
tertaining- and useful. It is good for every
;meinUer of the familyuseful alike to
^schoolboy and  gramlpu!   Write   for circu
lars and terms to
i          . Puritan Publishing Co.:       '               36 Bromfield St.,   Boston, Mass
Salary or commission to good men
Stock: failing to live replaced free.
We sell, Only High Grade
Also Pure Seed Potato Stock our Leader
"Lincoln," (480 bu, per acre-past season
Address   R. D. LUTCHFORD &   CO.,
NURSERYMEN..
( Letter*promyilii nnxwartd.)   ROCHESTER,   N. Y.
now i came
TO   15 K
 SHAKER.
Price  5 ct.
WANTED
AGENTS
WANTED
Fast selling Imported Specialties.
F. N. mAy company,
Nurserymen
A
Stock and True to Name.--><pb n="219" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Unfolding of life" TEIform="index"/>THE UNFOLDING OF LIFE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="DeGraw, Hamilton" TEIform="persName"/>By Hamilton DeGraw.</byline><p TEIform="p">" These ar they who came out of great tribulation, and hav washt their robes and made them
                            white." ALL transitions from lower to higher forms and conditions of life ar necessarily
                            preceded by pain. The seed placed in the ground and expected to produce a higher existence
                            must struggle to break the bonds that environ it before it can rise to the fulfillment of
                            its destiny. The immense periods of time that hav elapst since our globe evolvd from
                            primeval chaos, hav been periods of mighty convulsions to throw off the old conditions that
                            it had outgrown and which only hindered its progress to the higher forms of life. While a
                            gradual change and growth has been going on, geology points very plainly to the fact, that
                            to leave those old conditions there has necessarily been times of terrific convulsions when
                            all of the forms of life previously existing were seeemingiy totally destroyed; but the
                            germs of a higher existence remaind, making it impossibl for the lower types of life to
                            exist; the struggle continued and stil continues for more advanct conditions. As in the
                            natural world, so it is in the moral and spiritual universe, for the former must be evolvd
                            in its order before the latter can develop in perfection. The rise and fall of the nations
                            of antiquity, and especially their fall need not cause a feeling of alarm for fear of the
                            degeneracy of the race, for they had outgrown their usefulness and lived beyond the limits
                            of their allotted day, and must giv way to something more advanct. Many times the shel that
                            encased the national body became so hardened that it needed sumthing of a very energetic
                            nature to enabl the interior spirit to burst the fetters that bound it. The national
                            organizations of to-day, representing the highest advancement OCTOBER, <pb n="220" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/>
                            220 THE MANIFESTO. that has been attaind politically, socially or religiously, contain
                            within their organized body the germs of a higher development that wil eventually evolv
                            conditions far in advance of existing ones. While not pessimistic in our veiws, yet, looking
                            down the highway they ar treading, it is apparent that they also contain the germs of
                            dissolution. Conditions are existing in the body that wil eventually result in their death
                            as at present organized; for nothing of human creation can lay claim to the glorious
                            distinction of immortality. Like the forces that removed the dead and dying matter that
                            prevented the growth of the material world, may cum the spiritual power that wil remove the
                            incubus that is holding down the expanding forces that ar struggling to rise and lift the
                            world to a higher plane of life. As with the life history of nations, so with individuals.
                            As the career of the former merely represents the concentrated thought force of the latter,
                            they being the unit from which starts national and world progress, so conditions and
                            environments that surround the individual largely determins what his development shal be.
                            This may seem paradoxical; but when reared amid rugged surroundings that necessitate the
                            exercise of both mental and physical energy to overcum the barriers placed by nature in the
                            way, this very fact enabls us to uze these obstacls as a means for attaining a higher
                            development. A Southern gentleman, reared amid luxury and having every want and desire
                            granted, with chattels to do his bidding, was some years ago traveling in the north, in a
                            section of the country noted for its stern and rugged aspect, accosted a farmer with the
                            question, "What ar the crops they managed to raise in such a rocky cuntry?" The reply was to
                            the point, "Men, men." The nations of to-day who stand in the vanguard and represent the
                            highest development of intellectual and spiritual force ar those who hav had to fight their
                            way upward step by step against adverse influences; while as travelers tell us there ar
                            sections of the earth where nature has provided everything ready for man's material wants,
                            but climatic conditions ar such that it is next to impossibl for him to attain physical or
                            intellectual energy, much less to develop his higher spiritual powers. The law of
                            compensation is absolute, there is no deviation; we do not receive sumthing for nothing.
                            This may not seem to be founded at all times upon facts, but failure to understand this law
                            only arises from the undevelopt condition of the soul on the line of the inner sight. The
                            unfolding of life is continuous ; there is no cessation. To the materialist who considers
                            matter as he views it by the external senses as the ultimatum, the final cause ; and not
                            merely the effect temporary as that of spiritual causes; these statements may not seem to be
                            logical, but to the mind whose spiritual powers dominate, the truth of the statement is
                            apparent. The development of the new can not be accomplisht but by the death and <pb n="221" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 221 removal of the old. While looking down the dim vistas of
                            time, thru which humanity is slowly and painfully traveling to a more exalted destiny, our
                            spiiit is quickened within us and we feel the Divine inspiration of the heavens, and knowing
                            that, if "creeds, empires, systems rot with age, the great peple ar ever youthful," and tho
                            it may be thru great tribulation, yet triumphant wil be the journty and glorious the reward
                            of those who overcum. Shakers, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sacrifice" TEIform="index"/>SACRIFICE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, Oliver C." TEIform="persName"/>By Oliver C. Hampton.</byline><p TEIform="p">If others sacrifice their all, To human weal and God, How can I be excused at all, Or my own
                            course applaud? X7 a man sits down and s?riously counts the cost of salvation at V V the
                            price Jesus proposed, viz. the sacrifice of all that he hath,houses, lands, wife, children,
                            Brethren, Sisters,yea, and his own life, or selfish will and desires also, it seems at first
                            sight quite a forlorn hope, almost a matter of desperation. Yet it has been done by not only
                            Jesus the Christ, but by thousands since his day, if not before. If any should feel to go
                            cautiously about such a stripping experiment, let them try it gradually, by making some
                            little sacrifices by way of experiment. God is in no great hurry and can wait on us if we
                            will only be sincere with ourselves. There are many little ways to begin this solemn work
                            and plenty of time to prove, as we go along, whether the words of Jesus are likely to be
                            verified or not in regard to the prodigious blessing and glory promised as the result of
                            such stupendous sacrifices as he required. I was once in a state of agony in my experience
                            and travel through the valley of the shadow of (egotistic) death so intense, that I felt
                            almost, that there was no hope nor help neither in heaven or earth; neither in God nor man.
                            At this fearful crisis, there seemed to be whispered in my ear "when you climb a ladder, you
                            never try to rise with your feet, until you have made sure of a step above with your hands.
                            If you should you would surely fall, so you are not wise to take a step with your feet, till
                            you have secured one above with your hands. Can you afford to wait calmly for a time even if
                            you have to stand still, and see the salvation of God? Try it any how and it will relieve
                            you. I did so, and a serene calm settled upon me and I was brought through that scene
                            quietly to a state of perfect peace. After it was all over, I felt a sense of victory and
                            heavenly rest which I never could have experienced without that very searching scene of
                            trial and tribulation. I have heard some say they never felt any cross in doing right. I am
                            a little different from that. For instance, I never took one <pb n="222" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 222 THE
                            MANIFESTO. step yet in the upward path of progress, that was not attended with an agonizing
                            sacrifice of some selfish, darling idol. That is the kind of a canary bird I am, and yet
                            every such sacrifice has been uniformly followed by a fresh up-springing of life and peace
                            in that kingdom of heaven within me, which Jesus spoke of, as consisting of righteousness,
                            peace and joy in the Holy Spirit. Another thing I have noticed and that was, that those who
                            claim such a happy immunity from even the shadow of a cross in their travel, are such as
                            have never made any progress worth naming toward the kingdom, or scarcely any perceptible
                            change from rudimental, to higher conditions. The real secret of how to come into the
                            enjoyment of the kingdom of heaven soonest, is to try to take our crosses and
                            self-abnegations cheerfully ; this will gradually turn them into crowns of rejoicing.
                            Because though chemicalization of the elements of our common nature, can not be parried in
                            our upward progress, yet they may be very much shortened and also moderated by a cheerful
                            acquiescence in their operation, and a lively good-natured faith in their necessity and
                            efficacy. This is not to be gained at once but every effort brings us nearer to success and
                            almost before we know it, we have changed ground prodigiously for the better. We soon get
                            into the habit of occupying and enjoying our newly found kingdom, then come to pass the
                            halycon words of the rapt Prophet, "And the ransomed of the Lord shall return and come to
                            Zion, with songs of everlasting joy upon their heads: they shall obtain joy and gladness,
                            and sorrow and sighing shall flee away." Isaiah, xxxv., 10. Union Village, O.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Self culture" TEIform="index"/>SELF CULTURE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bowers, Lucy S." TEIform="persName"/>By Lucy S. Bowers.</byline><p TEIform="p">Strive well for every fair, adorning grace, For healthful growth of body, soul and mind, For
                            love, in which all beauty is combined. In true self-culture sin we may not trace, In lovely
                            lives it has no part nor place. Who is so nicely molded soon will find His heart a source of
                            good, rich and refined Revealed in brightness of his kindly face. Our heavenward walk
                            another's steps may lead, In our sweet thoughts, another's peace is found, Our purity may
                            guide another's deed, Our courtesies, in good to all abound. Self-culture is not selfish,
                            'tis sinless greed; Light in ourselves, sheds radiance around. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><pb n="223" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Envy" TEIform="index"/>ENVY. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Andrews, Watson" TEIform="persName"/>By Watson Andrews.</byline><p TEIform="p">A partial transposition of an article by Julia M. Lincoln
                            appearing in the August number of THE MANIFESTO, 1895
                            Among the voices of the human heart, There's none, perhaps that acts a baser part Yields more
                            unhappiness, regret, unrest, Than envy, tyrant of the human breast. Like rank and pois'nous
                            weeds this passion grows ; From selfishness proceeds, and only knows To crave the gifts that
                            other souls enjoy, Nor knows to gain, but only to destroy. When deeply rooted in the human
                            mind, It dwarfs the soul, its fine perceptions blind, And withers at another soul's success,
                            And hates the excellence it would possess. It still belittles what it can't deny, And greets
                            the subject with a scornful eye. O! poorest of the poor, that barren soul, That darkened
                            heart, whom envy doth control. O! pity him ye wise, and lend your light Of wisdom and of
                            love, to aid his sight To see, and know the gifts of every one As common goods, an equal
                            share his own. The proud and arrogant sees art and skill, And straightway envious fires his
                            bosom fill. The quenchless flame consumes from out his soul, That generous love, which
                            should his mind control And make him see, in human brotherhood, His best progression, and
                            his greatest good. And that the gifts of all should interblend, As woof and warp, cementing
                            friend to friend. We've but to read the history of the race To know that this most
                            loathsome, vile, and base Besetment of the darkened human mind, Has largely ruled the hearts
                            of all mankind, And caused the fierce dissensions, war, and strife, That blots the page that
                            tells of human life; That tells of envy, inbred cruel foe To human happiness, and source of
                            woe Untold, and desolation dark and dire, <pb n="224" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 224 THE MANIFESTO. By rapine
                            and by famine, sword, and fire, Condemning unto torture and to death, The generous, noble
                            souls of purer breath, Who wisely, kindly, seek the good of all Impartiallythe subjects of
                            the fall. The rich in wisdom, the unselfish heart, Perceives in every good a fitting part Of
                            that divine economy, or plan, Displayed in nature and displayed in man; Hence shares the
                            gifts that each and all possess, Seeing their virtues, but to love and bless. The state of
                            loving, being a state of bliss, In gaining love, we gain in happiness, For happiness
                            consists in love alone ; A holy love, to earthly loves unknown. 1 Earth lovers bring all the
                            passions in their train Among them, envy, pride, and love of gain. For pride and love of
                            gain there is excuse In rudimental life, they have their use As stimulants to effort,
                            needful thrift; And hence may be considered nature's gift. But "envy, spitting cat, dread
                            foe to peace, For thee there's no excuse, and no release From utter condemnation by a world.
                            Thou art to hades with indignation hurled If any folly is more foolish seen Or any vice more
                            vicious, low, and mean Than any other vice or folly known Envy, 'tis plain must claim them
                            as its own." Union Village, O.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Jealousy" TEIform="index"/>JEALOUSY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Rullhausen, Belle" TEIform="persName"/>By Belle Rullhausen.</byline><p TEIform="p">alHERE ar many vices that hav their deepest root in selfishness; but one _ of the most
                            poisonous and destructive is jealousy. It is closely allied to envy, and like envy,
                            constantly feeds upon suspicion. The Bible says, "wrath is cruel and anger outrageous, but
                            who is able to stand before jealousy?" Ah, that is the one important question of our
                            subject. Who is able to stand before jealousy, that terribl element that is like a fierce
                            demon, when it is allowd to go unchaind in the human heart ? The Kabbins hav a curious story
                            which has cum to us in the form of a <pb n="225" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. . 225 fable and it
                            wil afford a vivid illustration of the bold wickedness by which a jealous person is governd.
                            There were two individuals, one covetous and the other jealous, to both of whom were promist
                            whatever they should ask ; the one who solicited the least was to receive a double portion;
                            the covetous one would not ask first, because he desired the most, and the envious one did
                            not wish to, lest he should benefit his neighbor; but, prompted by the spirit of jealousy,
                            the latter requested to hav one of his eyes taken out in order that his companion mighj be
                            deprived of both. If this little incident has been handed down to us correctly does it not
                            clearly demonstrate the truth of the old adage that jealousy is as cruel as the grave.
                            Surely it does,it wil not live in peace, nor wil it permit others to do so. History reveals
                            many of the most vile acts, committed thru jealousy, that the mortal mind is capable of
                            conceiving. What has proud Rome to record of some of her rulers, but deeds of infamy that
                            hav left a dark stain upon the world's memory. When we look back upon the successiv reigns
                            of Tiberius, Caligula and Claudius the first, and remember the lives that jealousy caused
                            them to sacrifice, we shudder with horror and exclaim, how daring is that evil spirit, how
                            fiendishly has it ever defied G-od and ignored his justice. Well may we shudder, for the
                            same viciousness has dwelt in the hearts of the peple of every nation, and it stil lives and
                            unless conquerd by higher impulses would gain control of our being and destroy the better
                            qualities of the mind and soul. When the divinity of Christ permeates our lives the
                            malicious, detestabl spirit of jealousy wil not find place in us, for then the angels of
                            Justice, Mercy and Love wil reign supreme in our hearts, and enable us to rise abuv all that
                            is baae in our natures. Christ-love, which is universal love, wil cause us to render unto
                            every one that which is his just due, and gladly acknowledge the excellencies in others
                            which we ourselves do not possess. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Elder John Lyon, second paper" TEIform="index"/>ELDER, JOHN LYON. Second Paper.</head><p TEIform="p">I WAS at work in the field, while my mind was absorbed in the beauties of the world; in the
                            temptations presented to such as leave the Believers. It was the temptation of old: "the
                            lust of the flesh, the lust of the eyes, and the pride of life." While listening to these
                            temptations I heard in an audible voice, the following words : "What will you do with your
                            conscience?" This disturbed me, as I thought I had been talking to myself, but I now feared
                            that I had been heard by some one concealed in an old hedge fence that was near the place of
                            my work. I then searched the old fence thoroughly, and could find no <pb n="226" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/>
                            226 THE MANIFESTO. trace of any person. I then returned to my work and to my meditations as
                            before. In a short time I was saluted oy the same voice and in nearly the same words. "Will
                            you carry your conscience with you?" This time I made a search among a clump of bushes and
                            in every hiding place in the vicinity, but found no one from whom this voice could proceed.
                            Again I went to my work, but it was not long before T heard the same voice with redoubled
                            energy, proclaim these words. "You must carry your conscience with you; you may depend upon
                            that fact." I now concluded that the voice was from a spirit agency and thru my subsequent
                            life, if any thoughts or temptations arose, this voice and the impression it made upon me
                            never faded away. I hav never hesitated five minutes at a time since that date in regard to
                            my duty as a Believer. This to me was a very profitabl scene in all times of temptations.
                            During a term of about three years, there was nothing of a supernatural form that took
                            place. I was very happy in my order of life among Believers and rendered a willing obedience
                            to my Elders. I made a careful confession of my life, but in this had no real sense of
                            coming before God in judgment. In August 1798, as I was in the field at work, with four or
                            five others, suddenly I heard a sound as of rolling thunder which seemed to fill immensity ;
                            I then heard a voice which proclaimed; "Now is the time of the judgment; the time for every
                            motive, word or intention, as wel as every evil work to be brought to judgment." Immediately
                            it seemed as tho thousands of motives and words were attached to actions of which I had
                            formerly made confession now came before me, and demanded of me a new work. I found that I
                            must attach all my motives and intentions to their respectiv actions, thus bring them to the
                            judgment. I was now furnished with work for some months. Doing this work faithfully brought
                            me in sight of my earthly nature, thru which I was tempted. It seemed that the spirit of
                            evil had incorporated itself so fully with my nature, that I was at once placed in a
                            situation to be tempted. For a number of years, I sufferd from the power of temptation and
                            made my confessions to the appointed order, whether it was anything sinful, or a harbored
                            temptation to sin, fully believing that I went into the presence of God. Little did I
                            realize that when I received counsel or instruction, that I was being taught of God, but
                            often treated it as from the mind of man, according to their best judgment, and decided
                            whether they instructed me correctly or not. In this way I continued for some years, during
                            which I found that the Elders generally counseled and directed as I thought about right, tho
                            once in a while, I wished for them to understand as I did, and thought they would not do as
                            they did in such cases. From this it will be seen that I had Elders and good Elders too, and
                            such as I could respect; yet my teacher was in myself as long as I judged the work of my
                            Elders. I moved along very well unless the Elders taught me <pb n="227" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. 2&amp;7 something that was not exactly what I thought it ought to be. This
                            would at times, bring me into trouble, but I dispensed with it as well as I could and went
                            on with a determination not to quarrel with the cross of Christ. At length 1 was aroused in
                            my mind by having a further view of my life. I saw very plainly that my nature was unsubdued
                            and in truth appeared more potent than ever which almost threw me into a state of
                            discouragement, though I knew of no actual transgression against light. As often as the
                            Elders would counsel me what to do, (and no doubt it was the best thing for my good,) and
                            while they were instructing me, it felt like consolation to my soul, but as soon as I left
                            their room, I began to think they were mistaken, especially in my case. In this way, I cast
                            aside their instruction by substituting my own ideas in its place. T went on in this way,
                            til I brought myself into a sad condition. All this time I was ignorant and did not realize
                            the use I was making of the witnesses of God. One morning in the month of June, 1804, I made
                            one more effort to get help by opening my case as well as I could and getting what advice I
                            could. I told them my situation, and they gave me the following advice. "Young man, turn
                            your sense from the sins of the world and attend to your duty as a Believe]'. Labor for the
                            gifts of God and they will help you to overcome all wrong." This gave me some comfort while
                            they were speaking to me, for I thought I received it; but the truth is, I only heard it. As
                            soon as I was beyond their room I began to be quite apprehensiv that they had misunderstood
                            my case, or they would net set me to labor for the gifts of God. In this manner I disposed
                            of the counsel of my Elders, because I chose to lead myself. I now returned to my work. At
                            ten o'clock the same morning, I was at work alone in the grist mill. Suddenly I was taken
                            from the things of time and I heard a sound which it may be hard to describe, as it seemed
                            to be a heavy rolling, like the echo of distant thunder. This sound continued for some
                            length of time until the whole heavens were filled, and then it rolled in every direction.
                            {To be continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Manhood, second paper" TEIform="index"/>MANHOOD. Second Paper.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sevester, Edwin P." TEIform="persName"/>By Edwin P. Sevester.</byline><p TEIform="p">AN, endowed with so many noble faculties, is so grand, so far supe.rior to the brute
                            creation, that his higher spiritual nature allows him to commune with angels, drawing
                            heavenly influences around him, receiving divine inspirations which cause him to aspire
                            after those durable riches which never pass away. M <pb n="228" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 228 THE
                            MANIFESTO. Our manhood is progressive. Those animals that have the fewest faculties to
                            develop are the first to arrive at maturity. Man, the lord of all created beings, has the
                            longest and most helpless infancy, and it takes him the longest to grow to mature age. The
                            same is true with our faculties. The noblest are the longest in developing. In childhood we
                            manifest sensation, in the youthful period our intellect is developed, in mature age the
                            moral feelings, farther on in manhood the reasoning powers, judgment, religious aspirations,
                            love for the beauty of the soul, dignity of character, nobleness of mind, and the spiritual
                            part of our being is developed. After we have undergone the great change and left this body
                            as a worn out garment, our minds will be still more expanded. There are abstract truths,
                            principles and motives, invisible things, although not seen by the external eye, neither
                            heard by the corporeal ear, nor felt by the material hand, that are yet really true and
                            substantial as the material things around us. To beautify our characters, form good habits,
                            live by just principles, and grow in righteousness and holiness, this is a real and true
                            life, which will prove an everlasting source of enjoyment, Shakers, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Compensation" TEIform="index"/>COMPENSATION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bodine, Sarah F." TEIform="persName"/>By Sarah F. Bodine.</byline><p TEIform="p">The seed implanted in the earth Unfolds and reaches toward the light, Soon stem and leaves of
                            emerald green Reveal their beauty to our sight; Then blossoms of the richest hue Exhale
                            sweet perfume day and night. But ah, too soon the fair sweet life Yields to the chilling
                            touch of death, And petals that were fresh and bright Lie scattered by each passing breath.
                            The loss of fragrant living bloom Portrays a law all grand and true, 'Tis from the ashes of
                            the old Another life is brought to view ; And thus our hearts are always cheered With
                            blossoms ever fresh and new. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="He who shall introduce..." TEIform="index"/>He who shall introduce...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">He who shall introduce into public affairs, the principles of primitive Christianity will
                            revolutionize the whole world.</p></div2><pb n="229" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mine and thine" TEIform="index"/>MINE AND THINE.</head><p TEIform="p">WHOEVER reads the Bible and believes it. would not turn carelessly from the word of God to
                            the children of Israel whom God was pleased to designate as his doves. While sum of us may
                            take exceptions to certain passages of that ancient work, we stil find in it much that is
                            well worthy of our perusal and even to the close application of our lives. It is not
                            creditable to the Bible believers, the class who accept its plenary inspiration, to cast
                            aside a large portion of the work and assume to follow in their lives a few of the teachings
                            of some special prophet or apostle. The old Testament is as well worthy of our perusal as is
                            the new. In it we find the operation of God's work upon the mind of man. Speaking of this
                            part of the Bible and of the administration of the Lawgiver, Moses, one writer says,"Such a
                            code of laws as is embodied in this portion of sacred writ is nowhere to be found in the
                            jurisprudence of any other nation under heaven. Never had laws their basis in such profound
                            wisdom, never were they so benevolent in their character and never so salutary in their
                            influence." AH men may not harmonize exactly, in thought with this writer, but perhaps they
                            might by a careful perusal of the Mosaic Law, approximate to a corresponding appreciation of
                            the work. It does no good for a man whether he officiates as a clergyman or walks in the
                            humbler paths of life, to tell us that the old Testament is out of date and that the Jews
                            were a race of ignorant, half-civilized beings, more like our wild Indians than like
                            Christian men, like ourselves. It is well understood that Moses did not teach the Christian
                            doctrine. It was the moral Law, the Law of generation, the Law which to-day should rule
                            every man and woman that enters the marriage relation. He advocated the principl that this
                            is mine, and that is thine, while all that we possess belongs to God. Moses did not say as
                            do some of the Christian brethren,Keep what you have and get all you can. Now, if the Mosaic
                            dispensation was of God, and we believe it was, we should necessarily suppose that the next
                            degree of God's grace to man would be an increasing work, demanding more self-denial, more
                            cross, and making the separation from the world more and more apparent in its every form.
                            Does the Christian church proclaim that testimony as effectually as did the Jews ? The word
                            of the angel wil ever be,"Come out of Babylon, my peple that ye be not partakers of her sins
                            and that ye receive not of <pb n="230" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 230 THE MANIFESTO. her plagues." See how
                            carefully they were held to the order of the Law, which has been termed a schoolmaster to
                            lead us to Christ, and these ar some of the first lessons of Communism. Here is God's
                            word,"Behold I wil rain bread from heaven and you shal gather a certain rate every day." It
                            was to be gathered every day, and only sufficient for the present demand. This cut off all
                            selfishness, all monopoly. There could be no rich, no po3i\ With this bread they were
                            allowed to hav water and only water, and with this restricted diet it was the work of forty
                            years before they were considered suitable to pass into the promised land. If it cost so
                            much in that first dispensation to prepare men to be able to enter an earthly "Land of
                            Promise," can it be possibl that any in this day, professor or profane wil reach the
                            heavenly "Land of Promise" with less discipline, less self-denial? Six days shalt thou labor
                            and do all thy work. This was a testimony against idleness,another step in community life.
                            It obliged every man to be industrious during the six days and then came equally for all a
                            day of rest for man and beast. In the seventh month of the year was kept a week of Sabbaths,
                            and probably the time was spent as it is by the brethren at Alton Bay, near the close of
                            each year. They were to sow the fields and prune the vineyards for six years, but the
                            seventh year was to be a Sabbath of rest to the land. Again they might go on buying and
                            selling for seven times seven years, but the fiftieth year was to be universal liberty, when
                            every man should becum free and return to his former possession. The selfish, grasping
                            spirit of "Mine and Thine" which had been developing for forty-nine years was during one
                            whole year, to cum to an end. For three hundred and sixty-five days they could take no
                            advantage, or rather could not oppress each other. God says, the land is mine and ye ar
                            strangers. When wil the Christians hav a year of jubilee? and for three hundred and
                            sixty-five days take no advantage over each other? Here is another among many Mosaic rules
                            which is quite worthy of our attention. "Seven days there shal be no leaven found in your
                            houses." A trespass on this would be sufficient reason for expelling a member from the
                            community. History tells us that during this period of the year the houses were thoroughly
                            swept, day after day, from attic to cellar lest a morsel of leaven might be left unnoticed.
                            A Christian church would not necessarily suffer with this salutary pro- <pb n="231" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 231 vision aded to its rules. Neatness if not next in point of value to
                            godliness, is certainly an indispensabl acquisition to a Christian. Was Jesus thru his
                            ministration an end of the law ? An end of the discipline of God's work? Wil the Bible
                            warrant the interpretation of the church? Jesus says, "Xot one jot or tittle of the Law shal
                            fail til all be fulfilled," and if it was of no consequence, as many would hav us believe,
                            why did Jesus instruct his discipls to observe the Laws of Moses as taught by the Scribes
                            and Pharisees ? Is the Christian church of to-day any less a church of "Mine and Thine" than
                            was the Mosaic order ? And is it not more selfishly and oppressively "Mine and Thine" than
                            any church of the past ? Like the world at large the church buys and sells and accumulates
                            wealth with which to oppress others. Like the world the members of the Christian church
                            marry and ar given in marriage without the least form of discipline in regard to the
                            maintenance of the first great command. "Verily they hav their reward," corresponding so
                            fully to their works. We believe that the mission of Jesus the Christ was to call his peple
                            out from the world and to save them from their sins, from the selfishness and from the lusts
                            whi :h so thuroly rule the world. In his life the "Mine and Thine" came to an end. Among the
                            poor he was the poorest and he illustrated this by saying,"the foxes hav holes, and the
                            birds hav nests, but the son of man hath not where to lay his head." He had no selfish
                            property, no place that he could call his own. After Jesus had closed his conversation with
                            the young man concerning; his wealth, he found that it had astonished the discipls. They
                            were not, as yet, so far Christianized as to see the reason for this great sacrifice. In the
                            primitiv Christian church there was no private property for they had all things common. They
                            sold their houses and lands and brought the prices of the things that were sold and gave
                            them in charge of the apostls. Where is the corresponding Christian church which
                            says,"Behold, we hav left all to follow thee." If the Pentecostal church gave us this
                            example of consecration, how ar the Protestant brethren justified in giving so little to the
                            Lord and holding so much for their own selfishness ? Can it be possibl that this class of
                            peple read their Bible, and understand what they read? If they ar called Christians, the day
                            has gone by when they wil be honored for their religious profession. Whether belonging to
                            the church or not, it makes but slight difference ; and <pb n="232" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 232 THE
                            MANIFESTO. yet all difference whether a man is honest and a peacemaker, and a man of the
                            world, or a disagreeabl, dishonest man and a reader of the Bible. By their fruits ye shal
                            know them." How very much we need the religion of Jesus the Christ, the best gift of God to
                            man. Not creeds, not f rms nor ceremonies, not the theology of any sectarian body, but the
                            spirit which inspires men to walk with God and to be peacemakers among their brethren.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/>H. C. Blinn.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Publication" TEIform="index"/> KIND WORDS.</head><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">All who are interested in the prosperity of The Manifesto will be pleased to read what
                                the Editor of "The World's Advance Thought," of September has so kindly said of it. "The
                                Manifesto" the organ of those truly spiritual peple, familiarly known as the Shakers, is
                                always filled with matter for the benefit of humanity. It could not be otherwise, coming
                                as it does from those who manifest only the good every day of their lives." note goes
                                out with kind thanks to Br. Henry Greene, from whom we have just received a thought of
                                remembrance and a beautifully illustrated book of the Maplewood Hotel, at the White
                                Mountains.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Faith" TEIform="index"/>FAITH.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Burger, Sarah J." TEIform="persName"/>By Sarah J. Burger.</byline><p TEIform="p">Bright star that lights the firmament of thought, Sending a genial warmth through the deep
                            blue, The golden arch-way where each pilgrim true Must pause to know the wonders God hath
                            wrought, Must learn the glad refrain by angels taught, The song so sweet which as the
                            morning dew Ascends through all our life with rapture new; The culmination which all souls
                            have sought, Oh, light divine that gleams through sun and shade May thy bright beams pierce
                            through the veil of care, And bring a hope for sacrifices made For those who trust and
                            suffer, do and dare, When death shall close the evening of life's day Be thou the guide to
                            light their upward way. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. dThis</p></div2><pb n="233" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True riches" TEIform="index"/>TRUE RICHES.</head><p TEIform="p">" What shall it profit a man if he gain the whole world and lose his own soul." Mark, viii.,
                            36. Canterbury, N. H. 1. Be fixed my heart on higher aims Than seeking 2. Enlist ray thought
                            on nobler themes Than fame or 3. Let purer motives guide my feet In Wisdom's 4. What profit
                            e'en to gain a world Of Eden worldly pleasure; Thy longing spirit hath its claims wealth
                            inspires; For these shall pass like idle dreams ways so pleasant; Since future bliss is made
                            complete, joys or glory, If by our gain we lose the soul, On an eternal treasure. Before
                            truth's altar fires. By guarding well the piesent. In depths of sin and folly? Chorus. Ah,
                            "What shall it profit a man, If he gain the whole world and lose his own soul ?"</p></div2><pb n="234" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">OCTOBER, 1895. _a,- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -
                            - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is published by the
                            "United Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued
                            regularly by the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the
                            religious views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. All
                            communications should be addressed to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H.
                            TEE.MS. One copy per year, postage paid .75 " " six months, " " .40</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. August. Thermometer. Bain. 1894. 66.50 1 in. 1895.
                                68.36 2.875 in. Highest Temp, during this mo. 88 above 0 Lowest " " ' " " 40 " Number of
                                rainy days " " 8 " " clear " " " 12 " " cloudy " " " 11 C. G. Reed. North Family. Sept.
                                1895. Seed-time and harvest bring their respective work each in their season, one
                                equally as important as the other. Abundance of early apples give ample employment for
                                young bauds in picking and sorting for market. Sisters are preparing and canning fruits
                                and vegetables for winter use, beside working on shirts. The higl: tasseled corn, much
                                better than that of last year, is being harvested for ensilage; it requires a steady,
                                watchful eye to feed the machine that no accidents occur. For the present we are blessed
                                with plenty to do, but as a writer remarked, "Work is the birthright of the human race.
                                It is not a curse but a benediction. It is not a mark of degradation, or of servitude,
                                but an insignia oi royalty. To work is godlike. 'My Father worketh hitherto, and I work'
                                said Jesus, and the universe bears witness to the fact. Ceaseless activity is the law of
                                life. He who would live must work. There can be no growth or development of body or mind
                                without it." On August (3th we commemorated the one hundred and twentieth anniversary of
                                the arrival of Mother Ann Lee and co-laborers to America. Shakerism, past, present and
                                future was ably treated by Elder Daniel Offord. Commemorative articles, addresses and
                                singing made a long but very interesting and "instructive meeting. Early in the month
                                our beloved Sister Ann Offord returned to her home improved in health. August 23rd
                                Brother Daniel Orcutt, Sisters Caroline Tait, Mabel Tompson and Robena Page of Enfield
                                brought blessing and love from the dear friends of Connecticut. They made their home
                                with us, remained a weeka season of mutual pleasure and profit. September 2nd. Our dear
                                sister Mabel M. Franklin is again with us. Through receiving a shock by reading a
                                telegram of the death of her friend and attending nurse the Abbess, she was restored to
                                her former consciousness. The perfection of the modern surgery is indeed wonderful, but
                                had not an attending spiritual power overshadowed her, the silver thread of life would
                                probably have snapped even under the most careful operator. We live to learn. To grow
                                wiser and better every day should be the aim of all. Sarah J. Burger.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Sept. 1895. Beloved Eldek Henry;Yours of the 26th ultimo at hand. I am alive, but some
                                234 <pb n="235" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 235 like the Son of Man, between home, Florida
                                and Kentucky, I hardly at times know where I am to lay my head or rather settle my mind.
                                I have had rather too many irons in the fire for some not to burn a little. Benjamin
                                tells me that the people do not want to come back, although they have to rough it a
                                little. It will take time and a good deal of patience to turn a wilderness into a
                                fruitful garden. What the result will be time alone can tell. When we get settled in
                                Florida I will call for you to come and help. The weather at this place is very warm and
                                dry and we are suffering for rain. We have lost a pillar of our Church, Sr. Nancy Wicks;
                                her loss is deeply regretted. Isaac Anstatt. North. Family. Sept. 1895. Beloved Elder
                                Henry: -When we read the poem in the Sept. number of The Manifesto entitled "He was an
                                Editor," our sympathies went out strongly toward the one who should undertake such a
                                task as that poor editor assumed for himself. For finite beings there are some things
                                impossible and the one he undertook could be classed in that category. We trust that
                                experience taught him to take a more optimistic view of the situation. We are moving
                                along the even course of our way busy with the ordinary duties of life, striving to look
                                on the bright side and to extract some poetry and music from conditions that to the
                                superficial observer appear only as clouds. Personally we feel that we have a great many
                                things for which to be thankful. Firstly for those who are able to minister the
                                spiritual gift of the resurrection life and if obedient can give that power which will
                                enable the soul to say to all discordant elements, peace be still. Also for the temporal
                                blessings of home and plenty for the sustenance of the physical being, and when we think
                                of our dear gospel parenta who in their day suffered for the necessaries of life, we
                                feel that our duty is to put on the whole armor and be ready to champion the cause of
                                truth in its conflict with the powers of darkness and error; and when called to walk in
                                tribulation feel that it is only a means needed to evolute the soul out of the elements
                                of the lower life and to bring it in more perfect concord with the Divine Spirit. The
                                past month we were favored with a flying visit from our brother, George Clark of Canaan,
                                N. Y.. It was short but sweet, and hope some time in the future it may be lengthened.
                                It is getting very dry in this section. We have had occasional showers to keep the
                                growing crops from seriously suffering; and it is very fortunate that the drouth did not
                                come in the early part of the season. Many of the creeks and ponds have ceased to exist,
                                but we trust that in due time the refreshing showers will come. Hamilton DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station, Ct.</head><p TEIform="p">Sept. 1895. "If we take care of the minutes the hours wil take care of themselvs." Each
                                moment of time is valuabl and each moment lost can not be regaind. XotLing can
                                compensate for mis-spent time. Today can never return, and to-morrow can not hold the
                                opportunities gone forever. Time present, is the only time for us We should so liv that
                                we can look upon a record in the use of time that wil be pleasing and consoling. Moments
                                wisely improvd wil bring durable riches. The past is gone and the present is here; its
                                duties and opportunities ar ours now: by fulfilling the duties of this moment while we
                                hav it, we shal be ready for the duty of the next moment when it comes. Our time is
                                flying; let each hour and moment be employed in virtuous work. "The great secret of
                                success in life is for a person to know when his opportunity comes." "One pound of gold
                                may be drawn into <pb n="236" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 236 THE MA XIFES TO. a wire that would extend
                                round the globe. So one good deed may extend its intiucnce thru eternity; one kind word
                                may extend its echoes down the avenues of time thru myriads of hearts." "The giant water
                                plant of the world is the lily calld the Victoria Kegia, and its leaves often grow to be
                                twelve feet in diameter, when in its nativ South American home, but seldom attain a
                                greater width than seven feet when under cultivation. Each leaf is surrounded with a rim
                                five or six inches in height, and two men hav floated on it in perfect safety." Daniel
                                Orcutt. South Family. Sept. 1895. The first of autumn has arrivedrich, golden, fruitful,
                                autumn. We are in the midst of smiling plenty, with bountiful harvest fields around us.
                                I hear the song of the reaper pouring forth his joy amid fields where his daily toil
                                brings unfailing harvest in its season according to promise. Gracious Father we would
                                return our heart-felt thanks for thy bountiful goodness and care. The summer though
                                short has granted us many privileges and means of spiritual growth. Some very precious
                                seasons of communion with our gospel kindred from other Societies which afforded
                                strength, and inspiring all with greater zeal to sustain our most holy faith. We are
                                blest with a happy home, where we are taught how earth may yield pure enjoyment, if the
                                Spirit of God dwells within us. This is the season when nature begins her decline, the
                                yellow leaf appears, and the song of birds is dying away. The weather is delightful, not
                                much rain, causing a shortness of water. Corn cutting has commenced for the silo. Fruit
                                canning has received much attention with us, and shall do more still later on. We have
                                had the largest and best tomato crop this season ever grown here, all the vegetables
                                have yielded well. Apples quite good and our pears excellent, peaches and plums of good
                                quality. Potatoes are large and good are not yet dug, judge that it will be a fair
                                yield. Health usually good. Maria Witham.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harvard, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Harvard, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">Sept. 1895. With the many duties pertaining to this mundaneship and to loving friends,
                                one is neglected if we fail to remember The Manifesto, whose many readers hail it with
                                pleasure at the close of every month. Through its columns we have tidings from sister
                                Societies and can rejoice in their prosperity and sympathize with them in adversity. We
                                have been blest with the presence of five respected and worthy Sisters from Enfield, N.
                                H., who were the bearers of love and blessing from their Society. Such visits tend to
                                harmonize and draw us into closer union of spirit. Our school is now in session; few
                                pupils enrolled yet, but expect more soon. The farmers report an abundant supply of farm
                                products although the potato harvest was injured by the prevalent potato disease; yet we
                                have a good supply. Our herbs are not as fine as we anticipated on account of the
                                drought of the early part of the season. With grateful hearts we sing. We are blest in
                                many ways, We are blest in many things, We enjoy the happy days That true contentment
                                brings. Marcia M. liullard.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Sept. 1895. How rapidly whirls time's dial plate! Only a few days since and we were
                                heralding the approach of balmy spring, and as I write, the artistic fingers of Autumn
                                are busily tinting the foliage with varied hues, forming one of nature's most brilliant
                                pictures. Among our present blessings, we count the visit we are enjoying with Sisters
                                Marion Johnson and Jennie White, of the North family of East Canterbury. We trust the
                                interchange of thought may result in mutual benefit. Sisters Isabella Russell and
                                Henrietta Spooner report a large sale of home made <pb n="237" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE MA NIFES
                                TO. :37 articles at the Interstate Fair, held at White River Junction, Vt. We have
                                recently erected a cider mill to replace the one lost by fire in April last, and our
                                Brother Frank Theobald, with an eye to multiplying our home comforts, is building a cold
                                storage of chestnut wood, 7x11 ft. We have gathered between four and five bu. of
                                blackberries. Apple crop is small, but the yield of potatoes is par-excellent. As I note
                                the seed-time and harvest of the vegetable kingdom there arises the thought, that by the
                                crucifixion of the lower qualities of the mind, we give place for the blossoming of
                                Christian virtues, and surely humanity, like nature, should bring a constant renewal of
                                heart goodness into life, that a harvest of the fruits of love and justice may be
                                realized. George H. Baxter.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Alfred, Maine" TEIform="index"/>-Alfred., Me.</head><p TEIform="p">Sept. 1895. July, August, and September, and no Home Notes from Alfred. Have they gone to
                                Florida or the North Pole? Neither. We are still in Alfred, but the many duties incident
                                to the season have kept us so busy that we have failed to appear in Home Notes. We have
                                beloved Elder John Whiteley to thank for our being remembered in the last Manifesto. We
                                enjoyed a very pleasant though short visit from him. Like the rich man in the parable,
                                our Brethren have their barns full, and fifteen tons of second crop with no room in
                                barns to store it. The potato crop is large but unfortunately they have commenced to
                                decay. Br. Franklin Butler's garden has supplied us with a good quantity of vegetables,
                                so we have been for a time almost if not altogether vegetarians. I know Elder Henry
                                would be pleased to see our nine acres of improved learning corn, with its tops reaching
                                well up into the heavens. He would feel sure of our silos being as well filled as the
                                barns. The Brethren have nearly completed the work commenced a year ar.ro, of clearing
                                an adjacent field of its many boulders and so much of the earth is the better. Br. Henry
                                Green is now on his third trip to the White Mountains, with t! e dainty work baskets the
                                Sisters' busy hands have made. They give much pleasure to the guests and no doubt call
                                forth a few "smiles." On the morning of August 28th, twentyeight members of our Society,
                                by the kindness of the President of the Portland J and Rochester R. R. had a free ride
                                to ! Portland and the New England Fair grounds. Space will not permit of a description
                                of that day's occurrences. Aug. 31st, a company of five Sisters, Julia Russell, Emma
                                Spooner, Almira Elkins, Katie West, and Eva Mellen of Enfield, N. H., came to our quiet
                                little home and spent four days with us. One day was the Sabbath and we enjoyed a most
                                heavenly meeting, not alone with angels in the form but with angels out of the iorm.
                                Such seasons encourage us to bide well our time for soon there will be a grand meeting
                                where parting wiil not be known. Sept. 2nd, our worthy Elder Wm. Anderson of Mt.
                                Lebanon, N. Y., called to see us. His tarry was short, but we enjoyed it very much. His
                                descriptions of England, London, and Paris were very graphic. To say we enjoyed our
                                privilege with gospel friends does not half express our feelings. The interchange of
                                gospel love and friendship unites us more closely to such worthy souls, and we feel that
                                we, the little company in Alfred, are not alone on the battle field, but there are
                                innumerable companies of volunteers marching on to victory, following Jesus Christ and
                                Ann Lee, our chosen Leaders. Fannie Casey.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Sabbathday Lake, Me.</head><p TEIform="p">Sept. 1895. We have recently enjoyed a very pleasant visit with Elder William Anderson of
                                Mt. Lebanon who called on business, thus <pb n="238" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 238 THE MANIFESTO.
                                blessing us with his presence for several days; during which time he was kindly
                                imparting interesting reminiscences of his life and gospel experience which afforded us
                                all much pleasure. At this time we have with us live lovely Sisters from Enfield N.
                                H. ia., Sr. Julia Russell, a precious and well loved friend whom we met to love long
                                ago, also Srs. Emma Spooner, Almira Elkins, Katie West and Eva Mellen, all souls of
                                sterling worth to the Society unto which they belong and we are made happier by their
                                t;irry among us. We have felt the need of rain in our vicinity and many things have
                                grown brown and seal before their time. At this writing we are having a large well dug
                                on top of the hill west of the buildings which we are in hopes will supply our Village
                                with a good means of irrigation by another summer. Fruit is very scarce. Apples are the
                                fewest that have been known for years. Vegetables of all kinds are extra in quality and
                                quantity. Corn very fine. During the busy summer we have striven to maintain the Cause
                                of Truth and now as it is already waning we wish to keep our spirits alive and not let
                                the testimony of God wane within our own souls. Ada S. Cummings.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes from Florida" TEIform="index"/>Notes from Florida.</head><p TEIform="p">Live Oak Lake, Aug. 1895. Am I to be the first to send some Home Xotes from our new home,
                                if so I hope I shall do justice to the occasion. Our little company are trying to build
                                up a home spiritual as well as temporal, and how we shall succeed the future only can
                                tell. We are building on the principle of love and kindness which is the fundamental
                                work of the gospel of Christ. This includes a love for every Brother and Sister as we
                                shall manifest it to them through acts of kindness. We need not fear to show our colors,
                                especially to our friends upon whom we so much depend. Of course we must exercise our
                                best judgment in all that may be presented to us. Out of the good treasures of the heart
                                let the mouth speak to those who form the home, as often as opportunity may offer.
                                Kindness begets kindness and an interest in the prosperity of others becomes reciprocal.
                                There are many homes that hold a vacant chair, where it would have been otherwise if an
                                affectionate regard had been expressed, and a little encouragement extended to them in
                                the hour of need. Andrew Barrett.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Sept. 1895. Now we are quite ready for the Harvest song, Summer has given place to autumn
                                and the singing birds have taken their flight to more southern climes. If for the
                                bounteous blessings daily received from the hand of our Heavenly Father, we break forth
                                into songs of joy and gladness, we shall only do what may be expected of those who share
                                so freely those multiplied gifts that are always to be found in "God's holy mountain."
                                Two silos of an hundred tons each have been built for the benefit of the Milch cows, and
                                these are now being filled with the best quality of ensilage. A steam engine of eight
                                horse power, a machine for cutting the corn stalks, and a company of active workers to
                                haul the corn from the field makes active work for several days, for a large company.
                                The fall term of school for girls has just commenced. The school Commissioners are
                                becoming more exacting in their examination of the teachers, and in this way anticipate
                                better results in the schools. We must state that one little humming bird visited the
                                flower beds on the 19th inst. The reason for this extended visit after the migration of
                                the other birds is a matter of special interest. H. C. Blinn.</p></div3></div2><pb n="239" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Inquisition of 1895" TEIform="index"/>THE INQUISITION OF 1895.</head><p TEIform="p">"The American Sentinel" for August comes out fully illustrating the horrors of religious
                            intolerance and utters its protest with no uncertain sound. A great deal has been said and
                            written about the cruel persecutions of the Catholic church, and all kinds of bad names have
                            been thrown upon that church for holding the Protestants in check in matters of conscience
                            in religion. Now and at this late day the Protestants of Tennessee are setting up the
                            inquisi tion and seeing what may be done to afflict those of another order of faith. It
                            seems that some of the Advent brethren reside in the state of Tenn. and being consistent
                            Bible readers and Bible believers, they keep the seventh day of the week holy and agreeably
                            to the commandment. The Bible demands that the seventh day or Saturday shall be kept holy
                            and no work shall be performed on that day. The Adventists keep the seventh day
                            conscientiously and spend the time in saying their prayers and in sinking their psalms. They
                            could not keep another day even to please the Protestants for the Bible says,"Six days shalt
                            thou labor and do all thy work." They must work six days if they believe the Bible. But
                            these persecuting Protestants demand the acceptance of their views or they "will hale their
                            brethren to the judge and the judge will cast them into prison." Paul was more liberal than
                            are these dominating religionists. He says,"One man esteemeth one day above another; another
                            esteemeth every day alike. Let every man be fully persuaded in his own mind. He that
                            regardeth the day, regardeth it unto the Lord, and he that regardeth not the day to the
                            Lord, he doth not regard it." Every day in the week is kept as a Sabbath day, and the
                            Sabbath of the Jew is, no doubt, as acceptable before God, as is the day that is kept by the
                            Protestants and probably one day is quite as good as another day, either for religious or
                            for secular purposes. It is a pity that any form of religious persecution should be
                            tolerated in this free country by a liberty loving people; but the church that carries the
                            sword and believes in war and its horrible carnage, will be free to use that sword when it
                            advances its interest and permits it to be the dominant party.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/>H. C. Minn</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary.</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Salt is a mineral poison..." TEIform="index"/>Salt is a mineral poison...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Salt is a mineral poison which dries up the fluids of the body, and is not found in
                                nature's bill of fare. Much of the depraved condition of society is brought about by an
                                irritated nervous system which is poisoned by unwholesome substances called food.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pratt, B. F." TEIform="persName"/>Pro/. B. F. Pratt, M. J). in Human Nature.</byline></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Medicine is not a science..." TEIform="index"/>Medicine is not a science...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Medicine is not a science. The best that can be said of medicine is that it is a system
                                of experimentsno doctor of any standing will s ly it is a science. The best brains of
                                tie allopathic school declare that medicine is only an experiment. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Flower, R. C." TEIform="persName"/>Dr. R. C. Flower, Boston, Mass., in Human
                            Nature.</byline></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Meat, tea, and coffee are not suitable..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Meat, tea, and coffee are not suitable...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Meat, tea, and coffee are not suitable food for young children, neither are cake and
                                candy, except in small quantities.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Capen, John L." TEIform="persName"/> John L. Capen, M. D.</byline></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Children who are called 'stubborn'..." TEIform="index"/>Children who are called 'stubborn'...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Children who are called "stubborn" usually lack self-government and are weak in will
                                power. Directing such children in the right, will do infinitely more for their gcod than
                                blaming them continually for the wrongs they commit.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Capen, John L." TEIform="persName"/> John L. Capen, M. D.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A note from 'The Gospel of Good News'..." TEIform="index"/>
                            A note from 'The Gospel of Good News'...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A note from "The Gospel of Good News." "Employees of the Boston and Maine K. R. have received
                            the following circular," "Your attention is called to the fact 239 <pb n="240" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/>
                            240 TJ IE MA NIFES TO. that you are not allowed to use tobacco in any form whatever, while
                            on duty, nor on trains, nor in stations when off duty with uniform or badge on. This rule is
                            imperative, and must be regarded at all times." Scientific American. REMARKS. The managers
                            of the B &amp; M. R. R. are certainly worthy of many tlianks for this advance movement
                            in moral reform, and we hope they may be able to carry it to a successful issue. Neatness
                            comes quite near to godliness, even in and around the railroad cars, and if as it is said
                            that great corporations have no soul, and as a consequence can not become godly, they
                            certainly have a quality the next best which allows them to preach the gospel of neatness.
                            We wonder what the tobacco chewing and tobacco smoking ministers will do now?</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>EXCHANGES.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian register" TEIform="index"/>The Christian Register
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Christian Register is publisht by the "Christian Register Association" of Bos. ton,
                                Mass., in the interest of Liberty, Holiness and Love. Office 141 Franklin St. Boston.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Western insurance review" TEIform="index"/>Western Insurance Review
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Western Insurance Review, is published in St. Louis, Mo. by Mrs. H. L. Aldrich,
                                Proprietor. "It is in the interest of Life, Fire and Marine Insurance, embracing all
                                topics relevant to the system." Office 810 Olive St. St. Louis. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True protestant" TEIform="index"/>The True Protestant
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The True Protestant is
                                publisht by P. A. Seguin, an ex-Romish Priest. This paper is certainly a pro-test-ant
                                against Catholicism. It is in favor of free thought, free speech, free press, free
                                worship, free schools, free shops, and a free ballot. It is publisht in Chicago, 111.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dr. Foote's health monthly" TEIform="index"/>Dr. Foote's Health Monthly
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Dr. Foote's Health Monthly, is an outspoken exponent of medical knowledge. Its sword
                                cuts right and left thru the multiplied facia that are springing up on every side. The
                                Journal is publisht by the Murray Hill Pub. Co. of New York. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Altruist interchange" TEIform="index"/>The Altruist Interchange
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Altruist Interchange is
                                devoted to the exchange of news between wide-spread Philanthropic Societies, and to the
                                diffusion of information concerning various forms of progressiv organized work for the
                                genuine good. Publisht by the Altruist Interchange Co., New York City. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian register" TEIform="index"/>The Christian
                                Register
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Christian
                                Register is publisht weekly, in the interests of the Unitarian church by George H.
                                Ellis, Boston, Mass. "As a matter of fact, there are few Protestant churches today broad
                                enough to admit to membership the mixture of saints and sinners which made up the
                                primitive church."</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes and queries" TEIform="index"/>Notes and Queries
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Notes and Queries is a magazine of History, Folk Lore, Mathematics,
                                Mysticism, Art, Science, etc. Publisht by S. C. &amp; L. M. Gould, Manchester, N.
                            H.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How a woman paid her debts" TEIform="index"/>HOW A WOMAN PAID HER DEBTS.</head><p TEIform="p">I am out of debt, and thanks to the Dish Washer business for it. In the past five weeks I
                            have made over 500, and I am so thankful that I feel like telling everybody, so that they
                            can be benefited by my experience. Anybody can sell Dish Washers, because everybody wants
                            one, especially when it can be got so cheap. You can wash and dry the dishes in two minutes.
                            I believe that in two years from now every family will have one. You can get full
                            particulars and hundreds of testimonials by addressing the Iron City Dish Washer Co., 145 S
                            Highland Ave., Station A, Pittsburg, Pa., and you can't help but make money in this
                            business. I believe I can clear over $3,000 the coming year, and I am not going to let such
                            an opportunity pass without improvement. We can't expect to succeed without trying.
                            Mackintoshes and Rubber Clothing large commissions can be earned by retailing to users.
                            Samples free. Manufacturer, P. O. 1371 New York.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B." TEIform="persName"/>Mrs. B.</byline></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A minister startled his audience..." TEIform="index"/>
                            A minister startled his audience...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A minister startled his audience by saying, "I have forgotten my notes, and shall have to
                            trust to Providence, but this evening I will come better prepared." At a revival in a small
                            town the invitation was given for any one who wished to live a better life and desired the
                            prayers of the congregation to rise. A man arose. The congregation was jubilant and noisy
                            with "amens." Looking about him he said: "There is no need of making such a fuss and noise.
                            I ain't the worst man that ever lived."</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The best reformer..." TEIform="index"/>The best reformer...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The best reformer is the man quick to see all beauty and all worth.</p></div2><pb n="241" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Children:--'Out of the abundance of the heart..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Dear Children:--'Out of the abundance of the heart...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Connecticut, Shaker Station" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station, Conn.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Children:"Out of the abundance of the heart the mouth speaketh," and, "As a man thinketh
                            in his heart so is he." To be able to speak true and noble words, you must think the
                            thoughts and live the life of which virtue and truth form the basis. To make your words pure
                            and true your heart must be pure and true. If you think good thoughts words expressive of
                            those thoughts naturally flow from your lips. If you sow impure thoughts you will reap
                            sorrow and grief. Thoughts produce actions. The more you strive for virtue the better.
                            Purity of thought is the best safeguard against impurity of action. Guard your soul from
                            every snare, that leads to ruin. Sinful pleasure brings no rest. Be true, beautiful in
                            character, faithful in duty, careful not to deviate from the path of virtue. Watch in little
                            things. Often it is the little faults, little carelessness in conduct, little blemishes in
                            character, the "no harms" that bring trouble and woe. The little things tell on the endless
                            life beyond. Think of that. It is the attention to details that insures success in the
                            self-denying work. What an infinitude of details there are, and how much depends on these
                            little things. It is the little moments well improved, the little deeds well done, the
                            little crosses faithfully borne, that make up the sum of a holy life.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Humility, self-abnegation" TEIform="index"/>Humility, self-abnegation
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Humility, self-abnegation Is Christ's most precious gem, He gives it foremost exaltation In
                            his own diadem. Who would not wrestle with affliction, And conquer every sin, To gain the
                            crown of benediction The poor in spirit win.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Witham, M." TEIform="persName"/>M. Witham.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A cheerful spirit..." TEIform="index"/>A cheerful spirit...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A cheerful spirit is like the wind harp, that every gentle zephyr awakens into the sweetest
                            music</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="R., B." TEIform="persName"/>B. R.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wicks, Nancy" TEIform="index"/>Nancy Wicks
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Nancy Wicks, at Shakers, N. Y. Aug. 29, 1895. Age 88 years. A life of faithful devotion
                                was hers and she will hear the welcome, "Well done good and faithful servant." I. A.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Streeter, Bertha" TEIform="index"/>Bertha Streeter
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Bertha Streeter, at Enfield, N. H. Sept. 10, 1895. Age 10 years and 2 mo. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shannon, T. J." TEIform="index"/>T. J. Shannon
                            </head><p TEIform="p">T. J. Shannon,
                                at South Union, Ky. Aug. 21, 1895. Age 94 years. He lived to an extreme old age. and
                                went out calmly. For years he was very successful in doing business for the Shakers, and
                                in his intercourse with the world he was famous for his affable manners and polite
                                address. An old pioneer has gone out from among us. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="White, Denolius" TEIform="index"/> Denolius White
                            </head><p TEIform="p"/><p TEIform="p">
                                Denolius White, at South Union, Ky.
                                Aug. 26, 1895. Age 20 years. This young Sister was much beloved. J. H. II.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cosmopolitan" TEIform="index"/>Cosmopolitan
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Late Literary News. Fiction and travel sire the strong points of the September
                                Cosmopolitan, which, by the way, illustrates better than any previous number the
                                perfection of its plant for printing a magazine of the highest class. Conan Doyle, H. H.
                                Boyesen, and Clark Russell are among the story-tellers. A well known New York lawyer
                                relates the story of "A Famous Crime"the murder of Doctor Parkman by Professor Webster.
                                A delightful sketch of "An English Country Hou &gt;e-Party" is from the pen of Nina Larre
                                Smiththe house at which she visited being no less than the historic Abbotsford, still
                                occupied by the direct descendants of Sir Walter Scott. "The Realm of the Wonderful" is
                                descriptive of the strange forms of life discovered by science in the ocean's depths,
                                and is superbly illustrated in a surprising and marvelous way by the author, who is a
                                member of the Smithsonian staff. An article on Cuba is timely. Without bothering the
                                reader with unnecessary description of the famous yachts now so much talked of, The
                                Cosmopolitan presents four full-page illustrations showing these noted boats. Thomas
                                Moran again contributes a <pb n="242" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/> 242 THE MANIFESTO. series of the most
                                exquisite landscapes of western scenery, twelve in number, illustrating an article by
                                Col. John A. Cockerill, on "Modem Utah." And it may be said that no more beautifully
                                illustrated number of The Ccosmopolitan has ever been given to the public.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological Journal and Science of Health" TEIform="index"/>
                                The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">In The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health for September a phrenograph of
                                Elizabeth Cady Stanton, from a personal examination by the editor, occupies the first
                                place, and explains the elements of character which have made her an eminent reformer.
                                Several fine portraits accompany the description. "How Three People Did Europe Afoot,"
                                by George C. Bartlett, is the first of a series of letters from Europe which illustrate
                                the possibilities of cheap living abroad, and promise to be exceptionally entertaining.
                                "The Scientific Relation, Past and Present," by Dr. H. S. Drayton, will be especially
                                acceptable to scholars. The Rev. Stanley Mercer Hunter argues eloquently and logically
                                for phrenology as a definite science of character. Mrs. Charlotte Fowler Wells concludes
                                her interesting sketch of the Rev. Joseph A. Warne. "Proportional Brain Development," by
                                Albert Zimmerman, contains ideas of practical value to phrenologists. In the department
                                of Child Culture Prof. Nelson Sizer gives bright descriptions and excellent advice
                                concerning "Pets of Several Homes." "Modern Education and Morality," by Dr. Drayton, is
                                timely and will appeal strongly to teachers. Under Science of Health several hygienic
                                problems are discussed. In the editorial pages Doctor Beall introduces the subject of
                                "Fellowship Among Women" and quotes certain views likely to arouse controversy among the
                                fair sex. "Phrenology and Penology" are also considered, and a physiognomical study is
                                given, with illustrations, of the mouths of Edwin Booth and Adelaide Neilson. $ 1.50 per
                                year. Sew York: Fowler &amp; Wells Co., 27 East Twenty-first street. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Journal of Hygeio-Therapy" TEIform="index"/>The Journal of
                                Hygeio-Therapy
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Journal of
                                Hygeio-Therapy for August has a beautiful article on Religion. The spiritual or
                                religious life stands in advance of the intellectual or moral life, and is indeed the
                                embodiment of all that is good or can be known as God. That such an article should be
                                found in a medical journal, that has to interest itself in all manner of diseases, is
                                evidence that the author's mind rises above the many ills that flesh is heir to and
                                finds time to explore a region where religion and the spirit of God is better known.
                                This subject can not but have a health giving influence and the reader is made better
                                through this manifestation of life to the body and no less to the soul. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Guiding hand" TEIform="index"/>The Guiding Hand
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Guiding Hand
                                is a volume of nearly four hundred pages. It is a wonderful collection of Providential
                                Interpositions that hav been brought out under sum special Deliverance, under Dreams and
                                Impressions and under Conversions. The many incidents ar written in a brief and very
                                instructiv manner so that this varied collection of spiritual manifestations wil be red
                                with an increasing interest. The volume is nicely printed on a good quality of paper and
                                a clear faced type, and this goes far in the comfort of the reader. Pub lisht by H. L.
                                Hastings, No. 47 Cornhill, Boston, Mass. Bible study at its best includes the star1- of
                                Bible lands. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sunday school times" TEIform="index"/>The Sunday School Times
                            </head><p TEIform="p">In The Sunday School Iiaies of August 17 the Rev. William Ewin; for many
                                years a missionary in the Holy A id, gives a description of the Dead Sea P" ns, and
                                tells of an exciting journey through that region. This territory is of rare interest to
                                students of the Old Testament, and Mr. Ewing's description of it is vivid and
                                picturesque. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ladies' home journal" TEIform="index"/>The Ladies' Home Journal
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Mrs. Burton Harrison has written a new novelette, dealing in the main with
                                the "fashionables" of New York at the Horse Show, which The Ladies' Home Journal is
                                about to begin. Mr. W. T. Smedley has illustrated the story. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Every where" TEIform="index"/>Every Where
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Have Flowers Any Rights?
                                This question is discussed, both in prose and poetry, in Will Carleton's Newspaper
                                Magazine, Every. Where, for August. The great roadway of the lakes to the ocean, the
                                lordly St. Lawrence River, is treated, both by poet and artist. Dozens of other features
                                peculiar to this most original of papers, are at their best in the current number. Fifty
                                cents a year; ten cents for sample copies and agents' outfit. Address, Every Where Pub.
                                Co., Brooklyn, N. Y. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Popular monthly" TEIform="index"/>Popular Monthly
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Frank Leslie's Popular Monthly for Oct. is an exceptionally
                                beautiful number pictorially, without any sacrifice of that quality of timeliness which
                                makes it unique amongst illustrated magazines. The opening article is an idyllic
                                description, by Mrs. Leicester-Addis, of a summer holiday visit to old England's
                                loveliest county, Surrey, with a description of the stately manor of Deepdene, upon
                                which the present American Duchess of Marlborough has spent large sums of money to a
                                good purpose. Apropos of this year's tercentennial Tasso celebration, there is a
                                sympathetic and elaborately illustrated paper on "The Last Days of Torquato Tasso," by
                                Marie Walsh. Another Italian contribution of rare artistic interest is Miss. E. C.
                                Vansittart's description of Monte Oliveto Maggiore, to which are appended some
                                "Souvenirs of Siena," by the late John Addington Symonds. Other picturesque features
                                are; "Women as Athletes,'' byW.de Wagstafle; "Burmese Women," by H. Fielding;
                                "Light-Givers," by Mary Titcomb; "Town and Cloth Halls of Flanders," by Alexander
                                Ansted: "Widowed Sovereigns," by A Oakey Hall; and "Alpine Soldiers," by Henry Tyrrell.
                                This number also contains some unusually interesting short stories and poems.</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p27"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
Books and PapersContinued.
A FREE TRIP lO ATLANTA EXPOSITION,
And TGturn(from the home of the sender) i->
offered by tlie publishers of the Lftdie.x' Every
Saturday of 3G South Seventh Street, Philadelphia, to the first person able to make seventy
small English word." by using the letters con
tinned in EVERY S-A -T-U-K-D-A-Y. and no
letter to occur more times in any one word
tan it is contained in "Every Saturday."
/ First-Class Pneumatic Tire Bicycle (for
<-it. t'r boy or girl) is offered to the first person
.se    j.ng list of sixty wotdn as above,
. ^ady's Elegant Gold Watch to first person
se- Hnglist of fifty words as above, and one
Inn, rtd other article* ot rahie for first li.-t.s in
on.    v of merit as received.
Twelve two-cent stamps must be sent for
trial subscription (four -numbers of that beautiful thirty-two page illustrated Newspaper
for Women) containing full particulars and
rules of the. Leisure Hour Circle Word Building Exercises for bright people; also names
and address of, the 103 successful persons in
test Educational Contest, given by that publication. If interested, answer promptly, and
address- Ladie.s' Ernry Saft/rd'it/, Department
"B," 37 South Seventh Street, Philadelphia, Pa.
POUR
By Pressing the Lid.
Tea and ( o'Vo P< is that pour h\ lh< lid \utl 
out hltn * ct tiDTni-r      l-imj>k lnnnd 1 Jiu.
Pr    tu il and nr*i^tn     b i  Hot prnmhlct
THE ASBURY=PAINE MFG. CO., Phila., PTftib u * jv dtli ij -LI
SHAKE R 'S   ANSWER
To the oft repeated question.
"What will become of the
World, if all become Shakers?"
Price 10 cts.
This   is  an American   St jm-wirsd'JP-,   up. to dntip.    It represents  t' o   ir.u::t  i:r-portant step taken in watch evolution in niiny  yeirs.    It  descrilw s   aline HUeyond
which nothing radical will pass for yoirs, not only in the matter <>i'pi ice,  but qua.!:'-'
Twostyles.   Oilt siiicl niclcol,   Snap  back, Bevel crystal,
8teni Set.   F'ully timed and resii'iilalecl.
Fov $2.00 we  will   send   the Watch   and also a copy of Tjie Manifesto tor oiu
yeir, to any address in the TL S.           Address
The   Manifesto.
East     CANTERBURY,    X,    II,
THE CLIMAX
<pb n="" id="p28"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
AT" '
VI B  E
POWDER
Absolutely Pure.
A erciim of tartar  baking   powder.
Highest of all in leavening strength.
 l.fifaxt   Utiltit!   Stntek   Gorcnmu'ti
!"<><id i'<'pn'i'\.
Eoyal Baking Powder Go.
106 Wall St.,'N. Y.
THE   ALTRUIST.
Is a moiitlily paper, partly in Phonetic
.spelling, and devoted to coiunion property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is published by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work -together, and hold all
their property in common, all the men and
women having-.equal" rights in electing
officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. 50 cents a year;
specimen copy free. Address A. Longlicy
Higbee.   Mo.
Should have the beautiful 36-page Monthly
 IX*UBTBATED HOME JOUBJTAIi =
 Sample free-   Agents wanted.
SHAKERS*
:?2T0TJ^  CONCENTRATED
^SYRUP of SARSAPARILLA, |
        With 1 02. HVCKIODATK OF POTASS* to 12 BotleSk
ft
ft                                         PREPARED AT
ft
ft  Sbaher Tlillage, Mcrrtmach go., H. #
 This medicine has proved to be most
 valuable in the following diseases :
 Chronic Inflammation of the Digestive
 Organs; Dyspepsia, or Indigestion ; Weak ness and Sourness of the Stomach; Iiheu matism ; Salt Rheum; Secondary Syphilis;
 Functional Disorders of the Liver; Chronic
 Eruptions of the Skin> and all Scrofulous
 diseases and disorders arising from im [rarities of the blood. It is also an excel- 
 Z-;;*i remedy for the Erysipelas, Asthma,
Dropsy, Dysentery, and Diarrhoea, and
for the complicated diseases of females,
 so ff^t to end i>t consumption.
THOMAS a. NSWMAXT ft BOB,
CHICAGO, ILL.
Dose:For an adult, a teaspoonful I
four or live times a day, with or without i
a, little waiur, which li^iy be increased to j
a tablespoonful, -via best suits the patient. \
To guard against counterfeits, observe ]
the signature of the inventor on each ]
label and on each wrapper.                     ;
HUMAN NATURE
is an illustrated Monthly, now only 50cts.
per    year,    devoted   to   PHRENOLOGY,
PHYSIOGNOMY,  HEALTH, ^ MEDICAL
& SOCIAL REFOEM.
Would you like a copy?
Send 5 cts. for Sample to Prof. Haddock,
Phrenologist, 1016 Market St.,
San Francisco, Cal.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>