<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1101" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">11</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">1</biblScope><date value="18810101" TEIform="date">January 1881</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">1-24</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="11" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="1" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                    <pb id="p1"/>
                    <p>JANUARY, 1881. The Shaker MANIFESTO. G. A. LQMAS, EDITOR, SHAKERS, N. Y. Published by the United Societies. OUR HOME
                        AT CANTERBURY, N. H. "And they shall turn to you for a testimony:*' ''Go preach the Kingdom of God! " ADDRESS ALL
                        COMMUNICATIONS TO " The Shaker Manifesto, Shakers, N.D.." G. B. AVERY, PUBLISHER. 1881. Vol. XI No. 1. 60 Cents Per
                        Annum.</p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --><pb n="1" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p"> THE Shaker Manifesto. Where is the Christ? Life, not an Echo, but a Jewel, Religion, The
                            Temple of Solomon, The ^Increase, ... Humility —Dignity, Earnestness, ... Aspiration, The
                            Feet of Chinese Women, The Hindoo's Request, Interesting Correspondence, Elder Eads' Shaker
                            Theology, PAGE. 16 16 17 18 19 19 20 22 23 23 24 Vol. XL JANUARY, 1881. No. 1. CONTENTS.
                            PAGE. 1 " Know Thyself," 2 The Shoe that Fitted, 4 Editorial: 6 The Church of Christ, 9
                            Editorial Notes, 9 Some of the Kindly Words, 10 Society Record, 11 The Children's Grotto, 11
                            Music: — 12 Home Topics, 13 Winter Rules, 15 Agricultural,</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Where is the Christ?" TEIform="index"/>WHERE IS THE CHRIST?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Byrdsall, Charlotte" TEIform="persName"/>CHARLOTTE BYRDSALL</byline><p TEIform="p">The bells in the steeple rang out on the air, T'was the hour for Christians to mingle in
                            prayer, And listlessly, eagerly, onward they pressed, With a form in the mind and a creed in
                            the breast. Some were richly attired within without, but Were the gnawings of envy, of
                            passion and sin. O, what was the motive that led them along, These gaudy attendants of
                            Trinity's throng ? Were the precepts the Savior gave out on the mount, The cleansing he
                            shadowed in life's crystal fount, The good they were seeking and striving to find, A
                            substance to give to the struggling in mind ? Was the cry of the pauper for raiment and
                            bread The Christian thus led ? incentive, that thousands But now they have reached the fair
                            temple of praise, And enter with faces that sinners can raise ; Now softer, then louder, the
                            organ notes ring, And concert of voices in melody sing. The vestry door opens, the
                            clergyman's form Comes forth robed in vestments the soul cannot warm. The hymn faintly
                            ceases, he rises to show How the life-blood of Jesus will cleanse from all woe. 0, Father of
                            freedom ! why should it thus be, So many withheld from a knowledge of Thee— Bound down by
                            the dogmas that darken the soul, Vain priestly illusions, that minds would control ? But
                            listen ! he tells how the Savior of man Was slain on the cross and then rose up again ; He
                            tries to impress them with mysteries cold, That never the truths of religion unfold. We turn
                            for a while, that our spirit may glance Outside the delusion of bigotry's trance ; For we
                            hear the soul-cry of a seeker for life, 'Mid the narrows of error, and highways of strife.
                            She heard in the distance the chimes of the bell, Which caused in her heart deep emotions to
                            swell ; The sound I will follow, she inwardly said, Perhaps 'tis the signal that others hath
                            led, To find him who suffered to show us the way That leads to the mansions of eternal day.
                            So onward she journeyed, with joy in her heart, Like Mary to seek for the far better part.
                            The temple is reached, and with wearisome feet She enters, to share of the life-bread so
                            sweet ; <pb n="2" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. Some beads are averted, while lips
                            wreathed in scorn, Forbade one a welcome, of grandeur so shorn. No place in the pews,
                            through the carpeted aisle So meekly she paces, while hope sinks the while ; But why came
                            she here, she gave not the That rich over poor in their tyranny hold. At length by the door,
                            on the sexton's lone seat She drops, while she asks, is it here I shall meet The Savior I'm
                            seeking, who ne'er cast The true trusting spirit which wealth cannot hide ? Then like a
                            response to her inward appeal, Came down from the pulpit the words like a seal, Not here, 0
                            not here ! then a deep lengthened breath, As he held them to think of his rising from death
                            ; It, thrilled her whole being, again and again, Like the pealing of thunder from mount
                            Sinai's plain, And she fled from that tomb to the free open air, Like Mary to find the true
                            Savior elsewhere . * * * * * * * Away, far away, from the din and the strife— Where priestly
                            contention forever is rife— Is a home on the hill-side of Lebanon blest, Where the way-worn
                            and weary may find a soul rest. No pulpit is reared, and no organ tones raise The hearts of
                            its dwellers in service of praise ; But labor, and worship so nobly combined, Yield incense
                            to God, through the motives refined. Here lowly and gently the pure Nazarene Wears honesty's
                            clothing without lordly mien ; Here the rule that is golden triumphantly reigns, And none
                            know the curse of Monopoly's chains. And when we look over the dismal broad way, Whose sins
                            of oppression still darken our day We pray that the angel of fire may go, With brands from
                            the altar of truth all aglow ; To sweep away systems of error and wrong ; To burn up the
                            false and illumine the strong ; 'Till in every nation an altar shall stand, A symbol of
                            justice protecting the land. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life, not an echo, but a jewel" TEIform="index"/>LIFE, NOT AN ECHO, BUT A JEWEL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, G. B." TEIform="persName"/>G. B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p">This subject is of incomparable importance, and in dealing with it, we have to consider the
                            different notions of life involved, and the stuff each is made of. All individuals, classes
                            and characters in society are filling up their measured cup of life, the contents of which
                            are either embittered by the mixture of principles, qualities and characters not compatible
                            with the unchangeable laws of God, or sweetened by a line of conduct conformable to the
                            same, An old time writer asks: " Dost thou love life ? Then do not squander time, for that
                            is the stuff life is made of." This phase of life has reference to the period during which
                            the soul and body are united — between birth and death. The ambitious politician fancies he
                            is liv ing when canvassing for the votes, and feel ing the social pulse of his countrymen,
                            by firing their blood and sympathy through stump speeches, and dinner toasts. The speculator
                            supposes himself living when buying the trophies of his pursuit for thousands, and selling
                            the same for hundreds of thousands. The miser anticipates his living in getting and hoarding
                            his silver, gold and jewels, while he roves in rags for clothing, and starvingly fasts to
                            save his farthings. The lawyer blindly supposes himself living while disguising or
                            discoloring the truth, or squarely lying to please his client, and by misrepresentations,
                            gain his cause. The doctor stubbornly violates reason by courting life in dealing deathly
                            potions to his patients, to prolong disease for the purpose of extorting more money. The
                            courtezan presumes to be living while selling the value of her soul for the pleasure of her
                            body and that of her paramour. The idler would woo life by squandering time in quest of ease
                            and pleasure, theatre going, gambling, to tickle the senses, or purloin nnjust gains. The
                            pseudo religionist would seek to win life eternal by proxy — the merits of Christ. The
                            hypocritical religionist would propose to win the gift of life by merely professing a
                            virtuous Christian name, without practicing 2 <pb n="3" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. the
                            principles of self-denial, virtue, and truth, or by merely conforming to a few of the
                            prominent ceremonies of religious life, while neglecting to discipline himself by the spirit
                            of religious culture and devotion and in spirit, really omitting both the praise, worship
                            and service of God, or the duties of love, mercy and justice to his brother, sister parents
                            and neighbors. The materialistic professor of religion would seek life's goal by simply
                            aiming at physical righteousness, while entirely ignoring and neglecting all labor of the
                            spirit, the fountain of all life. But these pursuits for life are a covenant with
                            discomfort, ruin and death. Our arrow now aims at a higher phrase of life. 1. So spend time
                            as to enjoy the favor of God, as the reward of the right use of all our powers and
                            faculties, adapted to the sphere in which God has placed us. 2. To keep constantly in view
                            the rank in society our hourly conduct is fitting us for, whether high life — one of honor,
                            virtue, usefulness; or low life — a character of dis- honor, shame and degradation. 3. To
                            act with spirit, vivacity, vigor, energy in all we do. As the mechanic, who makes a
                            successfully operating machine, before proceeding with his labors, has first to consider the
                            kind and character of the work to be performed by it, whether very heavy, rough and
                            straining, whether requiring the use of substances of greatest strength, the firmest
                            solidity and most massive proportions, as, for instance, the engines of 10,000 horse power
                            to move a steamship 500 feet ]ong, 50 feet wide, and 40 feet deep, carrying seven thousand
                            tons burden; or a machine for drilling the countersinks in jewels less than the size of a
                            pin's head, for the boxing of the fine cambric needle like arbors of the delicate wheels of
                            a lady's gold watch, so the successful winner of life's happy golden crown must determine,
                            before proceeding far on life's journey through time, during early youth, to what end and
                            purpose, life shall be devoted; and although all individuals are not adapted to the same
                            pursuits and conditions, yet all, who rigidly and resolutely so will it, and steadfastly
                            pursue the principles of truth, honesty, purity and love, can lead a noble, honorable,
                            useful life, in harmony with God's laws. The great crying need of the present age is: 1.
                            Honesty of purpose. 2. Sacred regard for truth. 3. Stability of resolution, or continuity of
                            intention and pursuit. 4. Energy, vigor, spirit to go forward in duty with hope, confidence
                            and determination to win. Life, in the present age, presents in an immense degree,
                            instability, love of ease, pleasure, creature comforts, desire for frequent changes; and
                            these characteristics apply both to secular and temporal pursuits, and to religious duties
                            and spiritual devotions. More dignity, real manhood, and philanthropy are needed,
                            willingness to live for the benefit of the race of mankind, and less bondage to the narrow
                            bounds of self ease and pleasure. The life character, model, largely manifested in the
                            present age of human society, spoken of in a soldierly sense, as warring against the errors
                            and evils of life, is not chivalric enough; that is, the heroic defense of virtue and honor.
                            There is a supple bending to discouragements under disappointments and difficulties,
                            disregarding the truth of the motto, " Where there's a will, there's a way." There is a more
                            eager and erroneous grasp for a fictitious reputation, than solid toil for earning real
                            character, of which the poet, Sewell's panegyric on " Reputation," is more deserving. Thus;
                            "' Reputation'" {character) dearer far than life, Thou precious balsam, lovely, sweet of
                            smell, Whose cordial drops, once spilt by some rash hand, Not all the owner's care, nor the
                            repenting toil, Of the rude spiller, ever can collect To its first purity and native
                            sweetness." Discontent with present errors in life ought never to relapse into despondency,
                            discouragement and indifference relative to a straggle for reform. Multitudes, who as they
                            suppose, have espoused principles and systems of virtue, err most sorrowfully by attributing
                            all their personal lack of success in life's enterprises and pursuits, to an error in the
                            principles, or system espoused, when in fact, their disappointments principally 3 <pb n="4" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. originate in their personal nonconformity to those
                            principles and institutes. Thus, Christianity is vilified because so many professed
                            Christians do not live the Christ life. But those who live it succeed. There's now so much
                            knowledge of truth, and light of reason among mankind, that society is heart sick of shams,
                            either in religious professions, the manufacturer's wares, or merchants' stores. But
                            innumerable hypocrisies do not disprove the merits of the honest Christian, nor do limitless
                            numbers of failures declare the impracticability or error of living the virgin, Christian
                            life. He is but the counterfeit of a Christian who hath not the life of a Christian. " He is
                            but the counterfeit of a man, who has not the life (resolution and endurance) " of a man."
                            Q,professed Christian! Be not thou a pendulum "twixt life and death, vice and virtue, now
                            swinging to the right when favor invites, but to the wrong, when pleasures woo thee. A true
                            life manifests, in all its deeds, the love of man to fellow man, and of man to God ;
                            contending for truth in meekness, undaunted, though all the powers of earth and hell oppose;
                            not veered for pleasure, nor turned aside for sin. Thus marshalled with the heavenly
                            worshipers at wisdom's shrine, and basking in the sunshine of God's love.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religion" TEIform="index"/>RELIGION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/>ANTOINETTE DOOLTTTLE</byline><p TEIform="p">Natural religion, pertaining to the earthly and physical part of man's existence, and
                            spiritual religion, relating to immortality and the soul's growth into the divine life, the
                            duties and responsibilities of each, and the relation they bear one to the other, is
                            undergoing a rigid investigation and passing an ordeal hitherto unknown. The civil code of
                            laws, and the highest functionaries of the American government are called to an account,
                            their acts scrutinized, adjudged, justified or condemned, according to merit or demerit,
                            without regard to personality. The people who compose a nation^are the sovereign power of
                            that nation ; they make and unmake presidents and rulers. They frame laws—through official
                            agents whom they elect — and annul those laws when needful. But many times prudence directs
                            that wrongs, not sanctioned by the majority of the people, should be endured for a time, to
                            avoid still greater evils. Experience is an educator. If moral sentiment has room for
                            expansion and growth, it will mould the public mind and discipline individuals to right
                            modes of thought and action, until nations will combine their efforts to raise =the standard
                            of civil polity and religious freedom higher and higher. There are two contending forces in
                            every human heart; the one contending for the right, the other battling against it. As with
                            individuals, so with collective bodies. Slowly but surely the car of human pro- gress moves
                            on and on, regardless of opposing forces. They may impede for a time, but as truth is
                            stronger than error, right will finally triumph. At one time chattel slavery was the crying
                            sin of America. Many grievous wrongs existed, but slavery was the deepest dyed of them all.
                            Churches and legislative halls were stained with the blood of the crushed and enslaved
                            African. Priests and people were imbued with the same spirit, to uphold and encourage the
                            vile traffic, regardless of the injuuction " As ye would that others should do unto you, do
                            ye the same unto them." Then they had the effrontery to stand up in their velvet-cushioned
                            pulpits and with unclean lips and in sanctimonious tones ask high heaven for a special
                            blessing. But Ethopia, bowed in the very dust, stretched forth her hands and in anguish of
                            spirit lifted her voice and cried to Grod for help. Those simple prayers from hearts filled
                            with sorrow, ascended above the petitions of those who were clad in priestly robes and "
                            fared sumptuously every day," and ministers were sent to work for their emancipation. A few
                            men and women were raised up who took their lives in their hands and went forth to do battle
                            against the giant sin and the host of blood-stained sinners — for the majority were on the
                            side of wrong — but God was with the few, and right prevailed. 4 <pb n="5" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            SHAKER MANIFESTO. The then acting president of the United States was in principle and policy
                            with the oppressor, and against the oppressed. But the ultimate was reached. In the
                            providence of God a man was raised up as chief ruler of the nation " who feared God, loved
                            righteousness, and hated iniquity." He felt in his heart of hearts that slavery was wrong in
                            the sight of God ; a foul blot upon the symbol of American liberty, and a curse to the
                            enslaver as well as the enslaved. He felt that there could be no permanent peace to the
                            nation until the ax should be applied to the roots of the tree of slavery and the source of
                            its life destroyed. Although troubled in spirit through weary days, and in night dreams, he
                            had to wait for the masses to be educated up to the point where they would sustain him in
                            dipping his pen into his'' Ink-horn " and signing the "Eman- cipation Proclamation," which
                            in the sequel cost him his physical life, and for which his name will be remembered and
                            honored throughout many generations. Thus has it ever been as far as our knowledge extends.
                            Through the influence of both good and bad rulers, individuals and nations have been
                            educated, refined and improved from age to age, " debtors to the wise and unwise." And only
                            as civil governments have progressed in justice and moral equity, in natural religion
                            pertaining to the physical, has the religion of the soul pertaining to the immortal part
                            been tolerated. If we go back over the highway of life to the primordial state of our race —
                            according to Bible history — we find two parallel lines running through the ages,
                            distinctive, and yet more or less interblended ; a mixture of heathenism and Judaism. The
                            general rule has been " Like priests and rulers, like people," adaptation to times and
                            conditions. And yet we note development and growth in the right direction from one
                            dispensation to another. As we trace the superintending forces, or Gods who ruled and guided
                            the people in the " thus saith the Lord " epochs (and whenever and wherever civil government
                            has been under clerical rule, it has been and will be more or less " thus saith the Lord,"
                            as really so in the present as in the days when Judaism and heathenism walked side by side,
                            if not hand in hand together); we see that the wisest and best Gods did not attempt to go
                            beyond what the people were able to bear. In the Adamic age only obedience to physical laws
                            was required. If obedient thus and so,they would be blest in basket and store. The
                            immortality of the soul was not mentioned. At that time it would have been as difficult to
                            have reached the soul senses, and taught them spiritual things, as it would now be to teach
                            an infant astronomy or geology. Gradual growth made way for a small measure of the
                            spiritual, and a higher form of intelligence began to manifest itself to certain
                            individuals, in dreams, and semi-pellucid visions. Angels appeared to Abraham and Lot; but
                            so nearly resembled earthly beings that it was difficult to decide whether they were men or
                            spirits. However, that much indicated progress. The Israelites were a little farther removed
                            from barbarism than were the Egyptians, and were called the chosen people of God in that age
                            ; but the Israelites were not all right, neither the Egyptians all wrong ; both possessed
                            some elements of good, and both were enveloped in ignorance and darkness, which would
                            require the work of centuries to remove. After passing through a disciplinary school, the
                            Israelites were prepared for the code of laws, given through Moses, which was designed to
                            restrain the lower passions by divers sacrifices and atonements, more than as a soul
                            purifier. It was a canon of moral ethics, of sacrifices, retributions and awards. Although
                            it was a severe ordeal for them to pass, yet it was a necessity at that time, and all that
                            the people, even the most progressed, were prepared to receive. The Apostle Paul, speaking
                            of that dispensation, said : " It consisted of carnal ordinances, and could not perfect
                            those who observe them — touching the spiritual part — the conscience — and were only
                            imposed until something better should be revealed." It is a long journey from Moses and his
                            people, by way of the numerous kings who ruled the people from age to age, under the
                            guidance and direction of the one God of many names, or of different Gods. We read 5 <pb n="6" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. that God talked familiarly with Adam ; that he
                            walked with Enoch. He appeared to Moses in the burning bush, and told him not to fear; for
                            He was Ids father's God, and the God of Abraham, Isaac and Jacob. It appears that one called
                            the Lord dealt chiefly with Pharaoh and his hosts, and accompanied the Israelites through
                            the Red sea, and overthrew the horse and his rider, and achieved a glorious conquest. Moses
                            said emphatically : " The Lord is a man of war ! " One thing is evident, i. e., that the God
                            or Gods of that dispensation, by whatever name they were called, whether Lord, God, the most
                            High God, Almiglity God, Lord of Hosts, Jehovah, or I Am that I Am, not only tolerated but
                            instigated War, and upheld slavery in different forms, and sanctioned polygamy and
                            intemperance. We now discern a gradual but steady growth preparatory to the development of
                            higher spiritual 1that would touch and awaken the vital soul energies, the religion relating
                            to immortality — the life to come. The order of Prophets that arose in Israel, a class of
                            spiritual media, were at times inspired to speak beautiful words concerning Christ's
                            Kingdom. But of all the people we judge that Ezekiel was the greatest visionist. I love to
                            go with him to the river Chebar and enter into rapport with the spirit that communed with
                            him there, and to try to catch a glimpse of the enfolding cloud and of the brightness that
                            surrounded it, and of the likeness of the four living creatures — their faces, wings and
                            feet; and to mark their onward course, how the rolling wheels move steadily onward, turning
                            not to the right nor left, and to search out the meaning of such an extraordinary vision. To
                            our mind it beautifully illustrates the four great cycles or periods of time in the world's
                            history, and the spirit of progress represented, by the wheels and the living creatures that
                            moved them. The vision, by the same prophet, concerning the waters that flowed from the door
                            of the temple at four different issues, clearly exemplified the same thing. We cannot longer
                            tarry with the prophets, for our story is already too wordy for the ideas contained or
                            expressed. We pass on to Jesus, and go with Him to the mount, and listen to His teachings. "
                            In olden time ye were taught thus and so. I have not come to destroy the law, nor the
                            prophets. My mission is to teach the law of Love." The law was imperfect, it tolerated
                            errors, was vindictive and unchristian ; but the best that the appointed agents of those
                            times could give, or that the people were prepared to receive. The time had come for a new
                            epoch, and a change of administration. And Jesus affirmed that God was love ; and he
                            annulled the law of retaliation " an eye for an eye " precept, and said : Love your ene-
                            mies ; bless and curse not. Be pure, peaceable and just; sheathe your swords ; render good
                            for evil.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Temple of Solomon: emblematic of man, and prophetic of his destiny" TEIform="index"/>THE
                            TEMPLE OF SOLOMON. Emblematic of man, and prophetic of his destiny</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL FRASER</byline><p TEIform="p">To get an understanding of the significance of the porch of the temple and its contents, is
                            to get the key of the temple. All things are the subjects of law; the atom and orb alike
                            yield sweet obedience. Man is required to do no more. The temple and its ordinances were for
                            the maintenance of laws involving the physical and moral welfare of all; and emphati- cally
                            pointed to a higher law and life, than was embraced in the Mosaic dispensation. To open some
                            of these pointings is the object of this paper. The temple was emblematic of man not as he
                            is, but what he can attain to. The Jews were called but to an observance of hygienic and
                            moral law; and of these, but to a limited extent. Thence, the Law made not the comers
                            thereinto perfect. The fulfillment of divine law does, and gives a wider scope to the action
                            of said laws. The temple had a porch, a holy place, and a holy of holies. Man has a body, a
                            soul, and a spirit; his body is the porch; his soul the holy place. Within these is a spirit
                            — a holy of holies. When the " veil of the flesh, which is cast over the face of all na6 <pb n="7" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. tions" is removed, these matters will be better
                            understood. The temple stood lengthwise, east and west; in the porch there were two pillars
                            of brass, about three feet in diameter; and with their chapiters, upwards of forty feet
                            high. That on the right hand was called Jackin — to establish; that on the left, Boaz — to
                            strengthen. They did not support any part of the porch, they stood each on its own
                            foundation. Without doubt, they had an impressive appearance, and could easily be accepted
                            as emphatic emblems of the two principles or pillars — Hygiene and morals, on which Jewish
                            life individually and socially rested. These pillars are also emblematic and prophetic of
                            the two anointed ones, whose function it was to introduce, to strengthen, establish, and be
                            the pillars of the New Creation. They also stood as did the pillars. Wherever there is a
                            lack of hygienic and moral righteousness, in that degree, there will be bodily weakness, and
                            social disunion. Feeling the importance of these laws, Jesus uttered these remarkable words:
                            " It is easier for heaven and earth to pass away, than for any part of the Law to fail."
                            Again, " not a jot shall pass from it, till all shall be fulfilled." Six hundred years
                            before these words were spoken, the prophet saw the glories of the latter day; and the word
                            to him was " I will put my law in their inward parts, and write it on their hearts ; they
                            will be my people and I will be their God." (But), " if these ordinances pass from before
                            me, saith the Lord, then Israel shall cease being a nation before me forever." Does not the
                            increasing light on the principles alluded to indicate that the glories of the latter day
                            cannot be far off ? Are not the hill tops already illuminated? The temple and its courts was
                            the place of prayer for all nations, emblematic of the human sentiment, " all men are
                            equal." It was approached through three separately inclosed courts. The court of Israel, the
                            court of the Gentiles, and the court of the Priests. These courts were open above, but the
                            galleries ^supported by two or three row; of pillars, afforded shelter, and apartment for
                            the necessary uses of the temple and the people. Within the court of the priests, and over
                            against the eastern gate, was the altar of sacrifice; to the west of the altar was the
                            porch. The altar, its distance from the porch, its fires, and the sacrifices thereon, are
                            replete with significance. They represent conscience, conviction, repentance and atonement;
                            that nothing impure should go beyond the altar, is the emblematic intent, that every animal
                            emotion should be consumed by fire preparatory to the worship of God. To worship God, is to
                            irritate him, to be like him. Even the priests were not acceptable unless they were
                            sanctified ; and even then, before they entered the holy place, they had to wash their hands
                            and feet. Emblematically expressive, that in all our goings forth, in all that our hands
                            find to do, that purity of life is an imperative requirement of all who would approach the
                            Eternal Parentage. "Be ye clean who bear the vessels of Jehovah." " The law of the house of
                            holiness unto the Lord " ; the prophet saw that in the future common things would be
                            sanctified, that even cooking utensils would be set apart to the fulfillment of hygienic
                            law. When Moses saw the bush burning and not consumed, "he turned aside to seethe great
                            sight." The voice from the midst of the bush was, " put off thy shoes from thy feet, for the
                            place on which thou standest is holy ground." Jacob on a certain occasion exclaimed: " How
                            dreadful is this place, this is none other but the house of God, and the gate to heaven!" We
                            live in times when sacred things are often treated in a spirit of lightness; this mainly
                            arises from a lack of growth into the law of the higher life, and from a want of a knowledge
                            of its bearings, hence, irreverence is ignorance, and a lack of culture. In approaching the
                            holy place, let us put off our shoes, and wash and be clean in spirit. With proper feelings
                            let us enter the courts of the temple; pause, and kneel at the altar, enter the porch, pass
                            between the pillars, look within the holy place, but enter not. There are the holy lights;
                            in man's consciousness there are also lights; there is the bread; a symbol of the 7 <pb n="8" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. bread of life, and of its renewal from time to
                            time. The golden altar of incense from which ascend the aspirations of honest hearts, as
                            pure as is the altar's gold, is there. Beyond, we see the veil of separation; it is lifted
                            but for a moment; there are the cherubim ; their wings spread from wall to wall; the Ark of
                            the testimonies,and the mercy seat are also there. The veil is dropped, and we retire to
                            seek a knowledge of these sacred symbols. The Cherubims with extended wings, their faces
                            towards the Holy of Holies, show, that there is a line of separation between even the
                            justified natural man, and the angelic life. The sins of the natural man may be atoned for
                            by repentance, and the sacrifice of the lives of sheep and goats; but access to the holy of
                            holies can only be reached by the sacrifice (spiritually) of his own animal emotional life,
                            and by the unfoldment of the germ of angelic life within him. This agrees with the testimony
                            of Jesus: " Except a man be born again, he cannot enter the kingdom of heaven," the holy of
                            holies. Again, except a man forsakes Ms relationships of father and mother, etc., and his
                            own lower life also, he cannot enter that kingdom. This agrees also with prophetic
                            declarations — " Behold, I create a new heaven and earth, and the old shall not be
                            remembered, nor come into mind." Again, '' with thee, the angelic man or divine principles,
                            1 will break in pieces kingdoms and nations. With thee, I will break in pieces the horse and
                            its rider, and the chariot and its rider, the elements of human pride and display. With
                            thee, I will break in pieces captains and rulers, the elements of war. With thee, I will
                            break in pieces the shepherd and his sheep, the husbandman and his yoke of oxen, individual
                            and selfish interests. With thee, also, will I break in pieces man and woman, the old
                            relationships, all the Adamicties and loves. With thee, I will break in pieces the young man
                            and the maid, the organizing affinities, and created forces of the old creation. And they,
                            the Angelic Order, will not take of these a stone for a corner, nor a stone for a
                            foundation, but they shall be desolate forever, saith the Lord." The ark contained the
                            testimonies ; they were judgment to the line against all unrighteousness—all violations of
                            hygienic and moral law. Repentance, confession and sacrifice were the conditions of access
                            to the mercy seat. The presence of the cherubim on that seat declares mercy to be an angelic
                            attribute. Most people find in themselves a judgment seat, sit thereon, and judge others
                            freely, to find the mercy seat in our own spirits, and extend the wings of the cherub in
                            piece and goodness to all, is the work we are called to do. A singular feature of this
                            wonderful temple was the many little chambers which hung on the external walls, about large
                            enough to accommodate one person. They were in three rows. " In my Father's House, there are
                            many mansions." These chambers may represent the states of individuals, and the rows,
                            general conditions. The central person in the temple was the High Priest; he was clothed
                            with divine authority, and bore the conditions of all the tribes; the name of each tribe
                            rested on his shoulders and on his breast. Every Jew had a claim on his love and blessing.
                            Love is the credential of God-given authority ; he was anointed with its emblem—oil, till it
                            flowed to the skirts of his garments— to all the people. Love makes all the machinery of
                            life go smoothly. The father and mother of the new creation were anointed with love above
                            all their fellows, all their children are known by it ; " and this is love, that ye keep
                            their commandments ;" and love all who do. Thus you will fulfill the new requirement. The
                            holy of holies was opened once a year, showing that there is such a place in every human
                            spirit yet to be opened, and the conditions thereof attained to; also, showing that a divine
                            order of human life and procedure will be instituted upon earth. Its manifestations will be
                            virgin purity, goods in common, a government of love, and angelic obedience; and that all
                            accumulations of consecrated property shall be applied beneficially, not to speculate with,
                            nor to usurious ends. The Holy of Holies is the home and destiny of all angelic men and
                            women. The necessity and value of a heaven ap8 <pb n="9" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKES MANIFESTO.
                            pointed and a love anointed priesthood to humanity are unspeakably great. Without such,
                            angelic obedience cannot be attained, there being no altar on which self can be laid. Seeing
                            and feeling the lost condition of men in this respect, I am led to bend my spirit low in
                            prayer. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Increase" TEIform="index"/>THE INCREASE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Devyr, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/>CECELIA DEVYR</byline><p TEIform="p">If but the Polar regions we had known, How could we paint the tropics rich and rare ? Or of a
                            strange seed sparsely round us thrown, E'en guess the harvest that it yet might bear? The
                            lightning, drawn upon a single string. Seemed but like child's play in the years gone by ;
                            And now it forms for earth a magic ring, On which her thoughts and interests safely fly. We
                            know fair Spring and sunny Summer hours, We know rich Autumn and old Winter cold ; But there
                            are round us and within us powers We cannot know, 'till they their life unfold. We may not
                            tamper with the lightning's flame ; Nor gather fruit in misty blossom time ; Nor from green
                            summer autumn's treasures claim ; But we must wait the viewless laws sublime. The earth
                            revolving on her aerial course, Or turning to the star-space, or the sun, Receives impetus
                            from a hidden force, And thus secure, her dangerous path can run. But out amongst the
                            midnights of our life, We grope in darkness, or we stand in tears; Contend with shadows,
                            wage an aimless strife, Or cowering, shrink before our gathered fears ! And what we lack is
                            Faith that can confide, And never count the measure of its trust; A deep reliance spreading
                            far and wide, 'Till doubt and disobedience are as dust. And then the heavenly, hidden law
                            can take Our willing souls to govern and recast ; No lingering weakness, and no gloom, can
                            break Our growing prospects in the Future vast. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Humility—dignity" TEIform="index"/>HUMILITY—DIGNITY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName"/>WM. H. BUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p">The life of a Christian is a life of contrasts. Lowliness in him is set against pride, a
                            marked trait in the character of human beings. There is no necessary condition of life, it
                            matters not how others regard it, but the disciple of Christ assumes that, cheerfully, even
                            gladly. Is the man who does the world's work, without which neither physical, mental nor
                            moral life can be sustained, deemed and held as a chattel, a thing, a slave ? The Christian
                            is kin to such, in condition at least; for he " labors, working with his own hands." It is
                            worthy of note that the apostle Paul, in some of his epistles, applies to himself and his
                            fellow laborers the term doulos — slave: "Paul and Timothy, the douloi — the slaves of Jesus
                            Christ;" "Paul, the doulos — the slave of God." In his epistle to the Philippians he applies
                            the same term to Jesus Christ himself. " Let this mind be in you which was also in Christ
                            Jesus ; who, being in the form of a God, did not think the being equal to a God something to
                            be sought for, but made himself a nobody, taking the form of a slave — therefore the very
                            God has highly exalted him." The term was adopted, doubtless, from sympathy with the lowest
                            condition which human pride has imposed upon man. Had Jesus thought the dignity and grandeur
                            of a Jupiter or a Mars worth aiming at, he evidently possessed the natural endowments equal
                            to the task ; but far higher, in reality, were his aims — to be one inspirit with Divine
                            Love; to put himself on an equality with the lowliest, and thus ultimately to raise himself
                            and them to a seat on the very throne of Universal Beneficence. The world's work is
                            performed by its workers. They are, under God, the creators of its wealth, whether that
                            consist of material or mental wealth ; and they, of all persons, should enjoy its
                            advantages. Hitherto they have labored, but others, for the most part, have appropriated the
                            fruits of their labors. This has been done not by the secular aristocracy alone, but by the
                            9 <pb n="10" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 10 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. priestly as well. These classes have not
                            only taken what has belonged of right to others; they have assumed numerous titles — sham
                            dignities— and called upon others to do them reverence because of these shams. The real
                            reverence that belongs to meekness, kindness, gentleness and love has often been displayed
                            towards arrogance, haughtiness and vanity. These are among the lessons that mankind have had
                            to learn, but, thank God, they are beginning, little by little, to unlearn them. The
                            passions and fashions of the world pass away, though slowly. Better things must come and
                            they do come. It is worth one's while to acquaint himself with the history of the past to be
                            assured of the victories which the advancing ages are surely gaining over the ignorance and
                            consequent brutality of the remote as well as the nearer past. Oppression gradually relaxes
                            its chains ; pride carries a neck less stiff; love is regarded as less a passion and more a
                            principle that has in view the supreme wel- fare of man; faith lays hold of the Infinite
                            Patience that is never discouraged at what seems to short-sighted man perpetual
                        disaster.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Earnestness" TEIform="index"/>EARNESTNESS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bostock, Charles Baxter" TEIform="persName"/>CHARLES BAXTER BOSTOCK</byline><p TEIform="p">Not • being gifted with fluent speech as some are, yet having thoughts that may do others
                            good if known to them, causes me to note the following, in the hope that they may,
                            perchance, lead others to do the same, and thereby be the cause of preserving gome valuable
                            thoughts of other and abler minds. The most striking idea brought to my mind in reading the
                            life of Jesus Christ is, the intense energy or earnestness of His character, for, from the
                            time we find Him saying to His mother, " Wist ye not that I must be about my Father's
                            business ? " up to the hour of His death, we can see the quiet, resistless earnestness of
                            His character showing itself in every word and deed of His recorded life. Earnestness is the
                            foundation of true character ; without earnestness we are, nay, must perforce be, of those
                            lukewarm ones whom we are warned against in the Bible ; in the outside world, in business,
                            in fact wherever we look we find the successful ones to be those who have devoted every
                            energy of mind and body to their work, in other words, have been in earnest ; they are
                            conscious of having a mission to fulfill, and are self-consecrated to their work and its
                            fulfillment. This subject grows on us the more we view it, and I hope some, who are better
                            qualified than I am, will take it up and clothe it with justice. I feel that I can only be a
                            finger-post, and a poor one at that, but still useful in its place. What would have been the
                            present condition of our society if we were not now enjoying the fruits of that band of
                            earnest workers, Mother Ann, James Whittaker, Joseph Meacham, Lucy Wright and others whose
                            names are too numerous to repeat. They went through trials and struggles that I am afraid
                            would daunt some of us ; and what carried them through all ? A consciousness of a divine
                            mission and a resistless earnestness of purpose that inspired them to go through
                            and'conquer. Demosthenes, when asked what was the secret of successful oratory, is said to
                            have replied : " There are three things needful ; the first is Practice ; the second is
                            Practice ; and the third is Practice. I would add Earnestness, Earnestness, Earnestness, are
                            the three things we want to enable us to succeed in our holy calling. The words, "seek and
                            ye shall find, ask and it shall be given unto you," inculcate a lesson of earnestness we
                            would do well to lay up in our minds and act on in our lives. " By their fruitsshall ye know
                            them ! " If we apply this test to the author of the saying, what do we find ? An example we
                            can follow but hardly expect to realize. One, who from the moment His recorded public life
                            begins, we find engaged in the constant prosecution of His work. When He left the place of
                            His baptism, full of the Holy Ghost, it was to enter on His mighty task ; and from that time
                            to the hour when He said '"It is finished," He was incessantly about His Father's business,
                            doing a work in the short time of His public life (about three years and six months), that
                            could only be done by Earnestness. Mount Lebanon, J¥. T.</p></div2><pb n="11" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Aspiration" TEIform="index"/>ASPIRATION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, Catherine" TEIform="persName"/>CATHERINE ALLEN</byline><p TEIform="p">With the grass that struggles upward to the light; with buds that break their dark sepulchre
                            in the rugged bark and with precious cereals that burst the lone kernels which enfolded the
                            life germs and haste to feel the sunny beams and genial showers that will crown with golden
                            harvests, so our spirits feel the quickening influences of new life, and would struggle from
                            the bondage of earthly conditions to light and freedom in truth,would
                            _._____________________ have our souls like living plants, yield the fragrant bloom of good
                            desires, springing forth from silent places there, and like the inverted grain that first
                            must die within the ground, before its vital force can rise and draw from surro unding
                            elements, the bounteous gifts of harvest, so we would lose our life of selfhood. Let earth
                            return to earth, that the immortal germ, no longer wrapped therein, may rise and bear a
                            harvest unto God. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="figure" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Feet of Chinese women" TEIform="index"/>Feet of Chinese women
                        </head><p TEIform="p">[Figure]</p></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Feet of Chinese women" TEIform="index"/>[From the London Times.] </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">THE FEET OF CHINESE WOMEN. An American missionary, Miss Norwood, of Swatow,has
                                    lately described how the size of the foot is reduced in Chinese women. The binding
                                    of the feet is not begun till the child has learned to walk and do various things.
                                    The bandages are specially manufactured, and are about two inches wide and two yards
                                    long for the first year, five yards long for subsequent years. The end of the strip
                                    is laid on the inside of the foot at the instep, then carried over the toes, under
                                    the foot and round the heel, the toes being thus drawn toward and over the sole,
                                    while a bulge is produced on the instep and a deep indentation in the sole. The
                                    indentation, it is considered, should measure about an inch and a half from the part
                                    of the foot that rests on the ground up to the instep. Successive layers of bandages
                                    are used till the strip is all used, and the end is then sewn
                                    ---------------------------------tightly down. The foot is so sqe'ezed upward that,
                                    in walking, only the ball of the great toe touches the ground. Large quantities of
                                    powered alum are used to prevent ulceration and lessen the offensive odor. After a
                                    month the foot is put in hot water to soak some time ; then the bandage is carefully
                                    unwound, much dead cuticle coming off with it. Ulcers and other sores are often
                                    found on the foot, frequently, too, a large piece of flesh sloughs off the sole,.and
                                    one or two toes may even drop off, in which case the woman feels afterward repaid by
                                    having smaller and more delicate feet. Each time the bandage is taken off the foot
                                    is kneaded, to make the joints more flexible, and is then bound up again as quickly
                                    as possible with a fresh bandage, whicli is drawn up more tightly. During the first
                                    year the pain is so intense that the sufferer can do nothing, and for about two
                                    years the foot aches con- tinually, and is the seat of a pain which is <pb n="12" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 12 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. like the pricking of sharp needles. With
                                    continued rigorous binding, the foot in two years becomes dead, and ceases to ache,
                                    and the whole leg, from the knee downward, becomes shrunk, so as to be little more
                                    than skin and bone. When once formed, the " golden lily," as the Chinese lady calls
                                    her delicate little foot, can never recover its original shape. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="London times" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let us come down to the rock of utility..." TEIform="index"/>Let us come down to the rock of utility...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline><p TEIform="p">Let us come down to the rock of utility, Standing most firm on the basis of truth, Manhood,
                            henceforth, retain its virility, Woman enjoying perpetual youth. Shaving the face to
                            disfigure the mien, Banding the feet to cripple the body, To fashion or habit, tho' right it
                            may seem, Will bear not the test of wisdom or study. If four hundred millions, for ages and
                            ages, Have failed to destroy the least vestige of truth, When left to herself, if nature
                            produces Right beautiful feet at the moment of birth. Why is it that mortals continue to
                            marry, Well knowing that nature they cannot deceive; The shape and the size are not "golden
                            lily," But perfected pedals, like Adam and Eve. Tho' fig leaves may alter, or fashion may
                            vary, From crinoline skirts to this or to that, Yet change not the model, if white, black or
                            hairy, Of child, man or woman, to suit a fiat.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fashion" TEIform="index"/>FASHION</head><p TEIform="p">That fashion, whatever that may be, has no sense of utility is demonstrated amongst all
                            people. But that fashion prides herself upon receiving sacrifices of utility has not been so
                            fully demonstrated. Substitute the word devil for fashion, and remember that health is ever
                            the thing called for, and we have a key to the follies and foibles of mankind. They are
                            sacrifices unto devils; as were all the lives lost in the Salem persecution of witches and
                            witchcraft. Let us make that which is good and true, fashionable. By accepting Divine
                            Revelation in our own time, we shall sweep away the evils that have come thro' the
                            instigation of wicked sensual spirits.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hindoo's request" TEIform="index"/>THE HINDOO'S REQUEST</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>MARTHA J. ANDERSON</byline><p TEIform="p">Friends and kindred, I am dying, Death's cold hand is on my brow, And alone, my heart is
                            sighing, That the change is coming now. But I ask you, yet to bear me To the Ganges — sacred
                            stream — Where my fathers have before me, Dreamed earth's last and sweetest dream. I would
                            gaze upon the bosom Of those waters clear and bright; Cast upon the tide some blossom,
                            Emblem of immortal light. While I view the sky above me, And the palms outspreading wide, I
                            will think of those who love me, And my time in patience bide. Take me at the day's first
                            dawning, Place me on the verdant sod, And without a thought of mourning, Leave me to commune
                            with God. Where the winds and waves—low moaning— Death's soft requiem shall sing, And the
                            angel harps intoning, Heavenly harmonies shall bring." Soon beside the flowing river, On his
                            humble mat he lay, Where his soul went out forever In the golden light of day. And the last
                            faint words were spoken In a spirit true and calm. " Hope and trust are still unbroken, 1
                            shall yet be one with Brahm." For the ancient faith had taught him Reabsorption of the soul;
                            And a holy life had brought him Perfect power of self-control. Thus at rest, unto the mortal
                            Friendly offerings were brought, As they bore him through the portal Of the high-walled
                            burial Ghaut. Kindly hands, in preparation Reared the teen ted funeral pyre, And the process
                            of cremation, Soon was wrought by ruthless fire. <pb n="13" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO.
                            13 Priests with solemn rites attending. Slowly paced around the pile, • Incense sweet from
                            censers sending, Chanting dirges all the while. And the white-robed mourners tarried 'Till
                            the last gleam died away ; Then in earth were ashes buried, Dust to dust, without decay. In
                            India it has been a custom, from time immemorial, to burn the dead. The Ganges, the largest
                            river in Hindostan, is the Hindoo's sacred stream, in which they freely bathe, and before
                            which they pay their religious devotions. To die with one's face toward its waters is deemed
                            by the trusting and reverential Hindoo a great blessing conferred on the soul. Their burial
                            Ghauts are walled inclosures, along1 the banks of the river, within which they rear their
                            funeral piles; for the wealthy, sandal and spice wood are used. Friends bring rice and
                            fruit, which are placed in the coffin. Priests perform the last duties with a solemnity
                            becoming the scene ; first anointing the head and sprinkling the body; then, during the
                            process of burning, they walk slowly around the pyre, "chanting prayers of consolation" and
                            peace. Quite in contrast to western custom, the mourners dress in pure white.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>INTERESTING CORRESPONDENCE</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sheffield, England, November 24,1880" TEIform="index"/>Sheffield, England, Nov. 24,1880</head><p TEIform="p">F:~,W. Evans: Dear Sir: I have long contemplated writing you upon a subjectnear to our
                                hearts. Knowing that you are a leader in one of the most Angelic Communities of Brethren
                                and Sisters existing upon earth, I feel sure that a mighty power rests with you; but
                                whether this power is used in the wisest manner for those outside of yourselves, I very
                                much doubt. Yet to discuss this question with you would do little good, as I doubt not,
                                you and your celibate friends are fully convinced of the wisdom and necessity of the
                                self-denying practice of celibacy. You may also be convinced that this self-denying
                                practice is a great obstruction to the spread of your institution. I have several
                                friends who require but an assurance from the head of some Community that they would be
                                welcome and made equals in a social sense, to induce them to come at once, but who would
                                object to being separated from the dearest objects in life, to wit: husband and wife. I
                                have wondered much why some of the Communities in America do not grow more rapidly. The
                                reason was clear in your case, but not with Oneida and others. I have read that they
                                have many applicants. A friend of mine wrote J. H. Noyes, at the same time he wrote to
                                yourself. He neglected to answer; you sent a full reply. In a life hereafter I never
                                could believe; my concern is with this present earth life ; but to the main purposefof
                                this letter. Pardon me for suggesting that a goodly portion of your estate should be set
                                apart for the use of people desiring to practice Communism, and still live with their
                                dear life partners, husband and wife. What higher ambition could the leaders of an
                                association have than to see such people gathered by thousands, a process that I think
                                would be easy and rapid. The fact of so many seeking entrance into the Oneida Community
                                corroborates this statement. Now, I understand that Oneida Community is changed into a
                                joint stock association. What can be the reason of this wicked change? Is it an evil
                                covetousness of the leaders ? It is deplorable to think of ! Near half a century since
                                it was founded, and so few members, and these few go back to the old order of things!! I
                                have long desired to live in a Community ; I made a great effort to establish one in
                                Sheffield, received much pecuniary assistance from Prof. Ruskin, of Sheffield. It
                                failed, and I have lost all hope of a rational Communism being practiced in England. I
                                am personally doing well in business, but I want to get out of this wicked, miserable,
                                wretched pandemonium. I have just received a letter from Shirley, a Shaker village in
                                Massachusetts, U. S. He is a very dear friend, Harrison Riley; he speaks very highly of
                                your people; I am so glad he is amongst you; I know you will like him. I have a copy of
                                the letter you wrote my friend, and shall be pleased to receive one from you.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Shaw, George" TEIform="persName"/>Geo. Shaw</byline></div3><pb n="14" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, December 11,1880" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, Dec. 11,1880</head><p TEIform="p">George Shaw: Respected Friend : Your interesting letter, showing that its writer has
                                arrived at the end of the world, is at hand. Your friend, Harrison Riley, wrote me from
                                Boston, Nov. 5. I answered him Nov. 7. I received a letter advising me that he was at
                                Shirley, Shaker Village, Mass. He is still there. Having come to the end of the world,
                                you are looking for another world to live in. If you would please to die, and be buried,
                                and allow yourself to be resurrected from the dead, then to be born again; and thus
                                being an infant, receive the new world spiritually* as you received the old world
                                physically, the hundred fold of fathers, mothers, brethren and sisters would be as real
                                to you as the community houses they live in, or the lands from which they derive their
                                daily bread. You would learn to walk straight in a narrow road. Being simple and
                                obedient as a child should be, your burdens would be light, and the yoke of community
                                fellowship would be easy to bear, in connection with associates, who " bear each other's
                                burdens " and are seeking each other's wealth, rather than their own. This is becoming a
                                new creature, and living in a new creation. It is thus that old things are done away and
                                all becomes new. Is all of this, to you, as idle tales, or unmeaning hackneyed phrases
                                for which I should ask pardon ? Robert Owen was a Materialist, a Communist. Twice he
                                visited the Shakers at New Lebanon. His conclusion was, that celibacy was necessaryin
                                the founding of a community. Our conclusion is that it is a necessity to the perpetuity
                                of a community. Robert Owen and Robert Dale Owen, with the galaxy of brilliant names,
                                who gathered at New Harmony, Ind., made a most notable, world-wide, failure of
                                intellectual, philosophic humanitarian, transcendental materialism, and social
                                communism. I will show you my auto, from which you will perceive that I speak of that
                                which I do know, as I came out of that same company of earnest, sincere souls, who
                                worked for the good of mankind. They builded a tower, but it did not quite reach heaven.
                                Do you realize that Quakers are a company, who, if they did not marry, would be Shakers?
                                And that should we marry, it would enroll us with the Quakers ? Your suggestion to set
                                apart two-thirds of our estate, for a company to form a community upon, is kindly
                                received and entertained, as would be the proposition, to its parents, of an unborn
                                infant. Quakerism is preliminary to Shakerism. We are " Shaking Quakers." Quakers marry,
                                using marriage, as the unperverted animals use it, simply for propagation. With private
                                property, they have no poor amongst them. They dress plain, speak plain, eat plain food,
                                drink no intoxicating liquors — are temperate in all things — will not fight, swear, nor
                                use tobacco. They hold no slaves. They eat with their servants. What more, or less do
                                the Sheffield communities want ? Go preach to Bright and his people. Say to
                                them,''whatsoever ye command and teach, we will do — we will be as ye are — good Quakers
                                — only that ye consent to become Pentecostal Christians, selling all your vast
                                possessions to found hundreds of happy communities, in England, wherein all is common,
                                where none shall say this, or that is mine." So, you see, if all Communists and Liberals
                                join the friends, how influential they would be, in causing the Friends to unite with
                                them in creating communities. For the Quakers the change would be from good to better,
                                whereas should the Shakers join you, introducing marriages, the change would be from
                                better to bad. The trouble with the flesh would cause wars and fightings, destroying our
                                community as it destroys all communities, sooner or later. Therefore, by all means,
                                friend Sbaw, join the Shakers. Shakers hold the fort of abstract Christianity. In
                                England, there are thousands of noble men and women who will come and help us, when they
                                come to know the whole council of God. When all England becomes Quakers, as they should
                                do at once, the theories of Malthus and Ricordo will be quickly verified, the checks of
                                war, famine, pestilence, would <pb n="15" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 15 not exist,
                                and population would not only lack food, but standing room. In the London Economist, W.
                                W. Hunter, government director of statistics for India, shows that while France has 150
                                people to the square mile, India has 243. That in a region as large as Ireland, there
                                are 680 to the square mile. In some districts in Bengal, the population is as high as
                                1280 to the square mile. Thus, in regions with 80,000,000, the permanent danger is as
                                great as in Ireland, before the famine exodus. The pressure for food is so great that
                                land has no rest. The forests are destroyed and the manure is used for fuel. In spite of
                                their poverty, the people increase with marvelous rapidity. This frightful condition
                                comes of the virtue and excellence of the British government. Foreign and domestic wars
                                have been stopped, marshes drained. Epidemics suppressed. Infanticide abolished and
                                prop- erty and life made secure. If this come of halfway measures, what would be the
                                result of genuine Quakerism in England ? Let the wise and beneficent rules of England
                                reastablish, in her vast Indian Empire, the thousands of celibate institutions which
                                Maria Child affirms did formerly exist under the superintendence of the celibate
                                Buddhist Priesthood. From the tenor of your letter it is evident that you regard
                                celibacy as an end. We regard it as an effect. It is said : "Seek first the kingdom of
                                Heaven and its righteousness and all these things"—eating, drinking, wearing, lodging —
                                community — " shall be added," as an effect. To the Saducees — Materialists— he said:
                                "Ye know not the scriptures, neither the power of God." I may add, ye know not human
                                nature Community, of itself, would satisfy no body, long at a time. We could show you
                                gov- ernmental establishments, in America, where hundreds live, whose every real want is
                                sup- plied as long as they live. Do you think them happy? They prefer to tramp, beg and
                                suffer. But, my friend, you are in connection with people high and low, who would, with
                                us, simply be in Heaven. Send us some of them. We know the God of the world is
                                generation. But all do not worship that God. A million of women and as many men, in
                                England, do not marry. Many have progressed beyond it, spiritually, and they are nigh
                                unto the kingdom of Heaven. There are good practical laboring men, shoemakers,
                                carpenters, teamsters, shepherds, herdsmen, etc., whom we could put into good places in
                                our com" munity, at once. Your friend, William Hunter, had every thing to learn, and his
                                wife, who was the better man of the two, came here only to please him. He was not what
                                we call a practical man, he was a physical victim of your vicious one idea system of
                                things. Have you killed in your wars all the manly Englishmen ? I will send you some
                                reading matter, but I wish there were some way to sift out the precious souls — the
                                wheat — that is amongst you. I hope spiritualism will yet be a means to help some. I
                                long and pray for the gathering together of the saints— "Corneoutof her, my people, that
                                ye be not partakers of her sins, and receive not of her plagues." Your friend,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Elder Eads' shaker theology" TEIform="index"/>ELDER EADS' SHAKER THEOLOGY</head><p TEIform="p">Bowling Green, Ky., Dec. 4, 1880. JRev. H. L. Bads, South Union, Ky. Dear Sir : You have
                                my sincere thanks for your book of theology. For some of its thoughts you ought to. have
                                the thanks of the whole Christian world; but as an old, tough Calvanist, I think we
                                ought to congratulate ourselves that there are so few to present your peculiar theology
                                as you do, for I am sure some of the elect would be drawn too far from the catechism. I
                                shall take the book down to Elkton, as I go there to open court Monday, and I know that
                                Rev. Gill of the Calvinistic church and Petree, will be glad to see it. As ever your
                                friend,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dulaney, William L." TEIform="persName"/>William L. Dulaney</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="When pained by an unkind word or act..." TEIform="index"/>When pained by an unkind word or act...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">When pained by an unkind word or act, ask ourselves, " Have I not done as badly and desired
                            forgiveness ? "</p></div2><pb n="16" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Know thyself" TEIform="index"/>"KNOW THYSELF."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName"/>ABRAHAM PERKINS</byline><p TEIform="p">The difficulty of obtaining this knowledge next approaches that of searching out the
                            Infinite; of fathoming the powers and comprehending the origin of the eternal God. And yet
                            it is a lesson in life of the greatest impertance, and most necessary to learn. To search
                            our own hearts; to learn our individual proclivities; the weaknesses of our nature ; our
                            most conspicuous traits of character; especially those qualities of the mind most hidden,
                            which lie buried 'mid self-love and ignorance, is a duty we owe to ourselves. What is the
                            process best calculated and the means most efficient for acquiring knowledge so fundamental
                            to human progress? Success depends, largely, upon the knowledge of the organization of
                            souls, whose properties can only be fully understood ; but by turning our eyes within, there
                            to watch the operations of the mind ; there to learn where failures are most likely to come,
                            and there to mark such features in our constitution as are most strongly attracted and drawn
                            to the elements and spirit of a selfish, worldly, animal life. The tendencies of the human
                            heart are to ease and indulgence. We naturally incline to adopt the forms, manners and
                            customs of the worldly man and woman ; shunning that which would bring sacrifice and
                            self-denial; that which results in restrictions upon a selfish life. He who knows the most
                            of himself finds the most in his own heart to condemn ; where corrections should first
                            begin, rather than make attempts at amendments in the lives of others, he begins with
                            himself. Interwoven in almost every part of human character, objectionable colors,
                            knotty.coarse threads are to be found, which injure the texture of the web of life, mar its
                            beauty and make manhood any thing but lovely and agreeable. Hence, our manners, our habits,
                            our lives in every sense, should be governed by principle; not only should we take
                            cognizance of our acts for emendation, but our language, our thoughts and imaginations
                            should be watched over and controlled. As the tree is known by its fruits, so is the
                            condition of mind understood by the acts which crop out into life; — "our bodily habits
                            reflect those of the spiritual." Therefore, he who respects himself is interested in the
                            preservation of an unstained character ; and will not only study the theory of life governed
                            by true principles, but will publicly and privately, in the blaze of day and in the
                            blackness of night, whether seen and known or unseen and unknown, make the principles of
                            truth practical, "whose issues," as remarked by beloved Elder Giles B. Avery, in the
                            December number of The Manifesto, "eventuate in the evolution, development and perfection of
                            humanity, and which consummate in the glory of God." Enfield, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shoe that fitted" TEIform="index"/>THE SHOE THAT FITTED</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The minister hit 'em every time, And when he spoke of fashion, And riggin' out in
                                    bows and things, As woman's rulin' passion, And comin' to church to see the styles,
                                    I couldn't help a winkin' And nudgin' my wife, and says I, " That's you," And I
                                    guess it sot her to thinkin'. Just then, the minister says, says he, " And now I've
                                    come to the fellers Who've lost this shower by using their friends As a sort o'
                                    moral umbrellas. Go home," said he, " and find your faults Instead of huntin' your
                                    brother's ; Go home," says he, " and wear the coats You tried to fit for others." My
                                    wife she nudged, and Brown he winked, And there was lots o' smilin', And lots o'
                                    lookin' at our pew, It sot my blood a bilin.' Says I to myself, our minister Is
                                    gettin' a little bitter; I'll tell him, when meetin's out, that I Ain't at all that
                                    kind of a critter.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Swinburne's Church canticles" TEIform="index"/>Swinburne's Church Canticles.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ecclesiastics do an injustice to their calling..." TEIform="index"/>Ecclesiastics do an injustice to their calling...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Ecclesiastics do an injustice to their calling, when they fail to recognize that
                                    the legislature is superior to the church in all worldly matters.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><persName reg="New York mercury" TEIform="persName"/></bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="17" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Church of Christ: today and in the future" TEIform="index"/>THE CHURCH OF CHRIST. TO-DAY
                                AND IN THE FUTURE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We have strongly advocated an Ecclesiastical Council, .to determine what really is the
                                Church of Christ; not as aagured by the various theological academies, but one fashioned
                                after the primitive arrangement of affairs, that tended to make brethren in deed and in
                                truth of "all who believed." Certainly this would be a Paradise — a heaven on earth —if
                                all would live as Jesus lived, seeking to make others happy, regardless of the cost to
                                his or her selfish comfort. If none could feel happy until all the surroundings were so,
                                what an effort would be made to create a heaven on earth ! And this effort would create
                                a new individual of any who would engage in the enterprise; and while the world would
                                call such an individual " an eccentric," none the less would the world roll on towards a
                                heavenly perfection. " Oh, that Christ would come!" has been the throbbings of many
                                sincere hearts ; but these same hearts would be numbered among those who are unready for
                                the establishment of things on earth as they have them in heaven. The founder of the
                                Oneida Community resisted the Shaker idea of Celibacy, upon the ground that heaven would
                                be incomplete with it — and the world at large agree with him. Yet there stands the
                                grand examplai* Christ — a Celibate. The Community spirit is acknowledged as right by
                                the various churches, but the practice is limited to accommodate individual selfishness
                                to an extent that leaves the churches with their rich and pooi----very unequally sharing
                                the blessings of this life, and fully representing the parable of Dives and Lazarus for
                                the future. If the parable was a truthful picture, then the churches of to-day are
                                preparing startling comparisons, to be evidenced in more truthful reality in " the world
                                to come." If heaven to come — if it comes upon earth — means peace, what shall the
                                churches do with the elements of war, strife, contentions Y "Whence come all these ?"
                                said the grandest Apostle James. And if they come from the lusts of the people now, as
                                they did from the people then, have not the churches of to-day a duty to do which they
                                are not performing ? So flagrant were the wrongs of the olden Church of Rome — so given
                                to contentions and strife, so wanton in lusts and worse, that every feature of these
                                lusts were evidenced in its ranks — that the champion of the Reform Church, Luther,
                                while finding but little of the real Christ in Rome, did himself only subside from
                                Christian testimony, while contending for un- christian indulgences, and call the
                                epistle of James " an epistle of straw !" Are the churches of to-day ready for the
                                advent of the Christ ? Are they ready to welcome the Jesus of old, renewed in all the
                                glory and power of the heavens, to introduce anew his humble testimony, of Celibacy for
                                the kingdom's sake on earth ? Are they ready to equalize all their members, after the
                                pattern, when "all who believe are together, and none possess aught he or she calls<pb n="18" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 18 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. her or his own ?" When none are married?
                                When no one says this or that is mine ? When peace and quietness reign ? Such is the
                                Church of Christ, and such is to be the grand church of the future, in vaster numbers
                                than ever were counted! And what will bring about all this grand evolution ? Simply, the
                                overwhelming conviction that in the absence of the Christ, the self-denials of the same
                                Christ have been wanting. Simply, that until those same denials are inaugurated, the
                                Church of Christ cannot be again established. Is the selfishness of man and of the world
                                forever to predominate? Every church in Christendom to-day prays, "Heaven forbid! " Yet
                                nearly every church fosters, directly or indirectly, the elements which make the coming
                                of Christ, evidenced among the people, an impossibility. "When Jesus comes," we will see
                                a church, like the one of olden time, patterned after the heavens, where people will
                                live as they believe the angels live in heaven — Virgins, because why ? Brethren and
                                sisters in Christ, not husbands and wives, and why? "None possessing aught he calls his
                                own," and why? The Church of God, of Christ, in the future, and in the present, will
                                present some of these noble, unselfish, primitive Christian Church features. Are the
                                churches ready for the change ?</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="'Tis not that the hypocrite despises a good character..." TEIform="index"/>Tis not that the hypocrite despises a good character...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">'Tis not that the hypocrite despises a good character; that he has not one himself ; but
                                because he thinks he can purchase it at a cheaper rate than the practice of it, and thus
                                obtain all the applause of good men merely by pretending to be so.</p></div3><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>EDITORIAL NOTES</head><div4 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Happy year" TEIform="index"/>HAPPY YEAR</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Once more we come, wishing all a Happy New Year ! Happiness consists in doing good at
                                    the expense of self and selfishness, and this self-denial will ever make heaven on
                                    earth. We come to the people anew, teaching unpopular, unpalatable truths — but
                                    truths none the less. If Shaker teaching represents the Christ of olden time and
                                    now, how far off from Christ are the popular churches, and their numerous following?
                                    We wish a Happy Year in the reintroduction into the churches of the ancient
                                    sacraments. We wish a Happy New Year of Jesus' life; of Paul's life; of each and
                                    every Apostle's life of the Christ of old." Not only in the form of Monks and Nuns;
                                    not only in the name of Celibates; not only as apostles of Peace, of Brotherhoods
                                    and unworldly named institutions; but let us have a Happy New Year in the
                                    resurrection of Christ in Spirit, wherein " the old" selfish world and ourselves
                                    will have departed, and we shall be " new creatures " indeed, and new in Christ's
                                    life, and after his pattern!</p></div4><div4 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><p TEIform="p">All who read this number of The Manifesto will concede that we present an unusually
                                    brilliant number. The extensive array of prominent contributors augurs well for the
                                    coming year. The sweet singers, in charming poetical lines, tell us much of wisdom
                                    and grace. The similar, yet solid prose articles will be found very read<pb n="19" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 19 able and interestingly profitable. We hope
                                    for a continuance of such company through the year. We would credit the kindness of
                                    Mttnn &amp; Co., of The Scientific American, New York, for the cut illustrating
                                    the deformities of Chinese feet.</p></div4><div4 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Some of the kindly words" TEIform="index"/>SOME OF THE KINDLY WORDS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><div5 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div5"><p TEIform="p">But the Chair editorial cannot be better filled than it is at present, look where
                                        you will. Put some of those physical burdens upon other shoulders — if not of
                                        those within the Family, then of those without. You cannot dispense with the S.
                                        M. Just such a messenger is needed to proclaim the essential gospel of Infinite
                                        Love and of the essential Power of Christ.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName"/>Wm. H. Bussell</byline></div5><div5 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div5"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Office of the Free Press, Mt. Pleasant, Iowa, December 10, 1880" TEIform="index"/>Office of the Free Press, Mt. Pleasant, Iowa, Dec. 10, 1880</head><p TEIform="p">Publisher Shaker Manifesto, Shakers, N. Y. : By whose favor am I the recipient of
                                        The Shaker Manifesto, which comes to me regularly, and which I have enjoyed
                                        reading very much? I feel that it has made me a better man ; that since reading
                                        it I have taken a step forward in the onward march toward the goal which I am
                                        striving to reach. I want it to continue right along, and when the time expires
                                        for which it is paid, please send bill, and I will at once remit for another
                                        year. Yours very truly,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Throop, James A." TEIform="persName"/>James A. Throop, Editor</byline></div5><div5 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div5"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Friends: The enclosed $l.00 is for the Manifesto..." TEIform="index"/>Friends: The enclosed $l.00 is for the Manifesto...
                                    </head><p TEIform="p">Friends: The enclosed $l.00 is for The Manifesto, and with the remainder could
                                        you send me the " Divine Afflatus" or any reading matter you like? And I must
                                        tell you, Friends, about the first of each month The Manifesto is looked for —
                                        in fact anxiously. It has been tardy of late — the December number was received
                                        on the 7th. Now I like The Manifesto above all other journals it has been our
                                        fortune to read, so if you will send it to me for another year I will be able'to
                                        thank you very kindly.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Arnot, Hamilton" TEIform="persName"/>Hamilton Arnot</byline></div5></div4></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>[Obituary]</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rankin, George" TEIform="index"/>George Rankin
                                </head><p TEIform="p">South Union, Ky. , Nov. 27, 1880. Dear Editor — A veteran soldier has left us for the
                                    " evergreen shore." Our good and estimable and valued brother <persName reg="Rankin, George" TEIform="persName">George Rankin</persName>, passed off last eve., the 26th
                                    inst. With uplifted hands his dying worda were: " I'm going ! Truth ! truth !
                                    beautiful truth is what is wanted." He was 92 years old on the 7th day of January
                                    last. He was the oldest son of John Rankin, who was instrumental in bringing about
                                    the great Kentucky Revival about the beginning of this century. Lovingly and
                                    hopefully thine,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Eads, H. L." TEIform="persName"/>H. L. Eads</byline></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Price, William" TEIform="index"/>William Price
                                </head><p TEIform="p">Union Village, 0., Nov. 27,1880. To the Manifesto :<persName reg="Price, Wm." TEIform="persName">Wm.
                                        Price</persName> died this day at North Family of the society, in the eightieth
                                    year of his age.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Reynolds, William" TEIform="persName"/>William Reynolds</byline>William Reynolds
                            </div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Knight, Jane D." TEIform="index"/>Jane D. Knight
                                </head><p TEIform="p">Departed from her home at Mt. Lebanon, to heavenly spheres, Dec. 16,1880, <persName reg="Knight, Jane D." TEIform="persName">Jane D. Knight</persName>, aged 75 years. This good sister
                                    was the daughter of one who was prominent in many of the leading reforms of the
                                    world. At the time of her decease there was issued by Weed, Parsons &amp; Co.,
                                    of Albany, N. Y., a little book written by her, entitled, "Events Touching Various
                                    Reforms," and which, for its size, is a spirited and interesting treatise — espe-
                                    cially to the Quaker fraternity and our own.</p></div4></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Received" TEIform="index"/>Received</head><p TEIform="p">From Elder H. L. Eads, Dec. 10, one hundred dollars ! For this first subscription to The
                                Manifesto for 1881, we almost caught a republican politician's spirit, and cried "hurrah
                                ! " Thankful, to say the least, we ask oar friends due us, aiul^ to be due, to be
                                prompt, and help us through the trials of one more year, if no more. From John Norton,
                                North Union, O., $30.00. Also, from E. Stickney, $5.00. Canterbury, N. H., Society sends
                                us towards one hundred new subscribers. Blessed be Canterbury !!</p></div3></div2><pb n="20" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>The Children's Grotto</head><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To-day and to-morrow" TEIform="index"/>TO-DAY AND TO-MORROW</head><p TEIform="p">Don't tell me of to-morrow ; Give me the boy who'll say That when a good deed's to be
                                done, " Let's do the deed to-day." We may all command the present If we act and never
                                wait; But repentance is the phantom Of a past that comes too late. Don't tell me of
                                to-morrow; There is much to do to-day That can never be accomplished If we throw the
                                hour away. Every moment has its duty; Who the future can foretell? Then why put off till
                                to-morrow What to-day can do as well. Don't tell me of to-morrow ; If we look upon the
                                past, How much we have left to do We cannot do at last. To-day ! — it is the only time
                                .For all on this frail earth; It takes an age to form a life — A moment gives it
                            birth.</p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Noble boy" TEIform="index"/>A NOBLE BOY</head><p TEIform="p">As I was walking along a street of a large city, I saw an old man, who seemed to be
                                blind, walking along without any one to lead him. He went very slow, feeling with his
                                cane. " He's walking straight to the highest part of the curbstone," said I to myself. "
                                And it's very high, too. I wonder if some one won't tell him, and start him in the right
                                direction!" Just then a boy about fourteen years old, who was playing near the corner,
                                left his playmates, ran up to the old man, put his hand through the man's arm, and said,
                                " Let me lead you across the street." By this time there .were three or four others
                                watching the boy. He not only helped him over one crossing, but led him over another, to
                                the lower side of the street. Then he ran back to his play. Now, this boy thought he had
                                only done the man a kindness, while I knew that he had made three other persons feel
                                happy and better and more careful to do little kindnesses to thosp about them. The three
                                or four persons who had stopped to watch the boy turned away with a tender smile on
                                their faces, ready to follow the noble example he had set them. I know that I felt more
                                gentle and forgiving toward every one for many days afterward.</p><byline TEIform="byline">— <persName reg="Hudson, Ruth" TEIform="persName"/>Ruth Hudson</byline></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Speak kindly always" TEIform="index"/>SPEAK KINDLY ALWAYS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="McCarthy, Justin F." TEIform="persName"/>Justin F. McCarthy</byline><p TEIform="p">By the banks of the river I wandered alone, And into the pure depths I dropped a small
                                stone; It sank from my sight ere I went on my way, As the eddying circles were fading
                                away. I passed by that spot in a day or two more, And the waters flowed on as I saw them
                                before ; But no ripple came over the surface so clear, To tell that the pebble was still
                                lying there. So the harsh word from lips, p'rhaps unheeding, will fall And sink to some
                                gay heart, tho' tender withal, And the pain of that heart seems to pass in a sigh — Yet
                                the pang will remain, tho' unseen it may lie. Oh! pluck not one petal from out a gay
                                flower, To leave it to wither and die in an hour ; Destroy not the bloom you ne'er can
                                restore, But cherish it fondly, by day more and more. Rather speak the kind word to the
                                nigh broken hearted. Shed light on the soul from which joy has departed ; Let the balm
                                of sweet speech on the stricken heart fall, Speak kindly to each one, or speak not at
                                hll.</p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Boy was honest" TEIform="index"/>THE BOY WAS HONEST</head><p TEIform="p">One day the Duke of Buccleuch, a Scotch nobleman, bought a cow in the neighborhood of
                                Dalkeith, where he lived. The cow was to be sent home next morning. Early in the morning
                                the Duke was taking a walk in a very common dress. As he went along he saw a boy trying
                                in vain to drive the ©w to his residence. The cow was very<pb n="21" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                                SHAKER MANIFESTO. 21 unruly, and the boy could not get on with her at all. The boy, not
                                knowing the Duke, bawled out to him in broad Scotch accent: " Hie man, come hear, an
                                pie's a han' wi' this beast." The Duke walked slowly on, not seeming to notice the boy,
                                who still kept calling for his help. At last, finding he could not get on with the cow,
                                he cried out in distress: "Come here, mun, and as sure as anything I'se gie ye half I
                                get." The Duke went and lent a helping hand. " And now," said the Duke, as they trudged
                                along after the cow, " how much do you think you will get for the job?" "I dinna ken,"
                                said the boy, "but I'm sure o'something, for the folks at the big house are guid to a
                                bodies." As they came to a lane near the house the duke slipped away from the boy, and
                                entered by a different way. Calling his butler, he put a sovereign in his hand saying,
                                "Give that to the boy who has brought the cow." He then returned to the end of the lane
                                where he had parted with the boy, so as to meet him on his way back. " Well, how much
                                did you get?" asked the Duke. " A shilling," said the boy, " and there's half o' it to
                                ye." '' But surely you had more than a shilling," said the Duke. " No," said the boy, "
                                sure that's a' I got, and d'ye no think it's plenty?" " I do not," said the Duke, "
                                there must be some mistake ; and as I am acquainted with the Duke, if you return I think
                                I'll get you more." They went back. The Duke rang the bell and ordered all the servants
                                to be assembled. "Now," said the Duke to the boy, " point me out the person who gave you
                                shilling." '¦ It was the chap there with the apron," said he, pointing to the butler.
                                The butler fell on his knees, confessed his fault, and begged to be forgiven; but the
                                Duke indignantly ordered him to give the boy the sovereign, and quit his service
                                immediately. " You have lost," said the Duke, " your money, your situation and your
                                character, by your deceitfuluess; learn for the future that honesty is the best policy."
                                The boy now found out who it was that helped him to drive the cow, and the Duke was so
                                pleased with the manliness and honesty of the boy, that he sent him to school and
                                provided for him at his own expense. — The Children's Friend.</p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nothing to do" TEIform="index"/>NOTHING TO DO</head><p TEIform="p">" Nothing to do! " in this world of ours, Where weeds grow up with the fairest flowers.
                                Where smiles have only a fitful play, Where hearts are breaking every day. " Nothing to
                                do ! " thou Christian soul, Wrapping thee round in thy selfish stole, Off with the
                                garments of sloth and sin, Christ, thy Lord, hath a kingdom to win. " Nothing to do ! "
                                There are prayers to lay On the altar of incense, day by day ; There are foes to meet
                                within and without, There is error to conquer, strong and stout. '' Nothing to do ! *'
                                There are minds to teach The simplest form of Christian speech ; There are hearts to
                                lure with loving wile, From the grimmest haunts of sin's defile. " Nothing to do !"
                                There are lambs to feed, The precious hopes of the church's need ; Strength to be borne
                                to the weak and faint, Vigils to keep with the doubting saint. " Nothing to do ! " and
                                thy Saviour said, "Follow thou me in the path I tread." Lord lend thy help the journey
                                through, Lest, faint, we cry, " So much to do ! "</p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hard Customer" TEIform="index"/>A Hard Customer</head><p TEIform="p">Elder Daniel Boler once had a case which quite nonplussed him. Rebuking an indolent boy,
                                one very indifferent to business or religion, he endeavored to awaken some enterprise,
                                temporarily and f uturitively, by pressing the axiom : "William, remember you will be
                                rewarded according to your works — you will have just what you earn, no more ; and if
                                you want a good and great reward you must labor for it." " Well, Elder Daniel," said
                                William, " I'll tell you how it is with me : I'd rather do less and have less ! " </p></div3></div2><pb n="22" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Crown eternal" TEIform="index"/>CROWN ETERNAL</head><byline TEIform="byline">Words Selected.<persName reg="Pillsbury, O. W." TEIform="persName"/>O. W. Pillsbury</byline><p TEIform="p">1. On the brow of mighty monarchs May sparkle many a gem, 2. Proud were the mighty
                            conquerers Crowned in Olympic games; 3. With a harp of angel melody And a palm branch in his
                            hand, And gold and pearls and jewels May deck the diadem. They deemed that deathless
                            honors Were entwined around their names, The saint 'mid circling spirits Round the golden
                            throne shall stand. But it shines with earthly lustre, It will tarnish and decay, But sere
                            was soon the parsley wreath; The olive, and the bay, And his song shall be enduring As
                            heaven's eternal day; But the Christian's crown of amaranth But the Christian's crown of
                            amaranth While his victor crown of amaranth Will never fade a way. Will never fade a way.
                            Shall never fade a way.</p></div2><pb n="23" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>Home Topics</head><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Keep tea in a close chest..." TEIform="index"/>Keep tea in a close chest...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Keep tea in a close chest or canister. Keep coffee by itself, as its odor affects other
                                articles. Bread or cake should be kept in a tin box or stone jar. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Oil cloth is ruined..." TEIform="index"/>Oil cloth is ruined...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Oil cloth is ruined by the application of lye soap, as the lye eats the cloth. </p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To select nutmegs..." TEIform="index"/>To select nutmegs...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">To select nutmegs, prick them with a pin. If they are good the oil will instantly spread
                                around the puncture. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="When you drive a nail into a wall..." TEIform="index"/>When you drive a nail into a wall...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">When you drive a nail into a wall, clothes-press or closet, to hang things on, drive it
                                through a spool up to the head. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To clean brass kettles..." TEIform="index"/>To clean brass kettles...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">To clean brass kettles, after washing clean, take a teacup of vinegar and a table-
                                spoonful of fine salt; wash every spot on the inside of the kettle with it; then rinse
                                off in pure water. </p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A remedy for corns is as follows..." TEIform="index"/>A remedy for corns is as follows...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A Remedy for corns is as follows: Bathe the feet in tepid water, 1o soften the corns ;
                                pare these off very closely with a sharp knife; then rub on well green peach tree
                                leaves; after continuing the rubbing once or twice a day, the corns will disappear. </p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Diseased teeth" TEIform="index"/>Diseased teeth
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Diseased Teeth.—A distinguished anatomist made the assertion that a particle of matter
                                taken from a decayed tooth, if inoculated into a person's veins, would produce almost
                                instant death. Dr. Ewer tried the experiment on a dog, and it died in twenty minutes.
                                The amount of disease produced by retaining decayed teeth in the mouth is immense. The
                                dentist is one of our best friends.—Dr. Dio Lewis. </p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Neuralgia" TEIform="index"/>Neuralgia
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Neuralgia.— For neuralgia in the face or other acute suffering elsewhere, the following
                                remedy has been tried with good effect: Cut a thick slice of bread all across the loaf —
                                fresh bread is best; soak one side for a minute in boiling water, and rapidly sprinkle
                                cayenne pepper over the hot side; apply while still smoking hot to the painful surface.
                                The bread retains the heat long enough for the cayenne pepper to begin to act, and
                                cayenne does not affect the delicate skin as mustard does. It acts as a rubefacient, but
                                not as a blister. </p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beets" TEIform="index"/>Beets
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Beets. — One of the most satisfactory ways to cook beets is to bake them. When boiled,
                                even if their jackets are left on, a great deal of the best part of the beet is
                                dissolved, and so lost. It will, of course, take a little longer to bake than to boil
                                them; but this is no objection. Allow from fifteen to twenty minutes more for baking;
                                slice them, and heat as you would if they were boiled. After they are cooked, season
                                with pepper, salt and butter, and a squeeze of lemon</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Winter rules" TEIform="index"/>WINTER RULES</head><p TEIform="p">Never begin a journey until the breakfast has been eaten. Never take warm drinks and then
                                immediately go out in the cold air. Keep the back — especially between the
                                shoulder-blades — well covered; also the chest well protected. In sleeping in a cold
                                room, establish the habit of breathing through the nose, and never with the mouth open.
                                Never go to bed with cold or damp feet; always toast them by a fire ten or fifteen
                                minutes before going to bed. Never omit regular bathing, for unless the skin is in an
                                active condition, the cold will close the pores and favor congestion or other diseases.
                                After exercise of any kind, never ride in an open carriage nor near the window of a car,
                                for a moment. It is dangerous to health, and even to life. When hoarse, speak as little
                                as possible until it is recovered from, else the voice may be permanently lost, or
                                difficulties of the throat be produced. Merely warm the back by a fire, and never
                                continue keeping the baok exposed to heat after it has become comfortably warm. To do
                                otherwise is debilitating. When going from a warm atmosphere into a colder one, keep the
                                mouth closed, so that the air may be warmed by its passage through the nose, ere it
                                reaches the lungs. Never stand still in cold weather, especially after having taken a
                                slight degree of exercise; and always avoid standing upon ice or snow, or where the
                                person is exposed to a cold wind.— Albany (W. Y.) Argus.</p></div3></div2><pb n="24" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>Agricultural</head><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nots of the horse" TEIform="index"/>NOTS OF THE HORSE:.</head><p TEIform="p">Going up hill, whip me not; Going down hill, hurry me not; On level road, spare me not;
                                Loose in stable, forget me not; Of hay and corn rob me not; Of clean water stint me not;
                                Of soft, dry bed deprive me not; Tired and hot, wash me not; If sick or cold, chill me
                                not; With sponge and brush neglect me not; With bits and reins, oh, jerk me not; And
                                when you are angry, strike me not.</p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Measuring corn" TEIform="index"/>Measuring corn.</head><p TEIform="p">A number of rules for measuring corn have been published. As a multiplicity of rules
                                tends to confuse, the question arises, why can we not have one good rule. The reason is
                                obvious. New corn will not measure as many bushels to the foot or inches as old corn, on
                                account of shrinkage. A crib of corn measured in the fall will not yield as many bushels
                                to the cubic foot as when measured in the spring or summer. Corn in wagon, when first
                                put in, will not measure as much to the foot as when hauled several miles. Hence the
                                necessity of working by different rules under different circumstances. All rules are
                                based upon the number of cubic inches in a bushel of shelled corn, which is 2150.4. If
                                all corn shelled out the same, under all circumstances it would be very easy to have one
                                rule As near right as any rule I have tried is twelve cubic feet to the barrel for corn
                                in crib in the fall of the year, eleven and a half feet in spring time and about eleven
                                feet in summer; twelve feet as thrown in wagon in the field and eleven and a quarter
                                hauled four or five miles.</p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Patent flour" TEIform="index"/>Patent flour.</head><p TEIform="p">Almost everybody knows of patent flour, but not everybody understands what it is.
                                Stripped of technicalities, this is about the story of its manufacture. The best flour
                                used to be made of winter wheat. Spring wheat yielded either much less in quantity, or
                                else so much of the. bran got into the flour in its manufacture that its color was
                                intolerably dark. The wheat would be ground and then bolted. In the refuse — the bran
                                and middlings — would be included a large proportion of the spring wheat, and this would
                                sell more particularly for feed for horses. Now, the best of flour, and the most
                                expensive, is made of this very refuse of the old-fashioned process. It all came out of
                                the discovery of a way to draw out the bran. Under the new process the wheat is ground
                                about as before. The first result is an ordinary flour sold for exportation. Then the
                                remainder is taken and put upon great horizontal sieves, and while agitation is going on
                                there, an ingenious system of draft is rushing up through and carries off the bran. What
                                is left is the glutinous portion of the wheat, the most nutritious and most productive,
                                and out of this purified now by the drawing off of the bran, we get our new process
                                flour. The result of the discovery of the process has been to make the poor spring wheat
                                of Minnesota and upper Wisconsin the most valu able of grain. </p></div3><div3 type="equipment" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Farm Tools" TEIform="index"/>Farm Tools.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Farm tools will rust out sooner than they will wear out. Many farmers injure
                                        their farm implements more by exposure to the weather than by the use on the
                                        farm. An implement which witli good care would last twenty years, will, when
                                        exposed to the weather, become use less in five years, or even less. A farm-cart
                                        which, with good usage, would last almost a lifetime, will last only a few years
                                        when exposed to the weather. The reason why farming does not pay with many is
                                        found in this neglect to take care of the farm tools. All farm implements are
                                        costly, and the farmer who has to buy three or four times as many as his
                                        neighbor, because he does not, take care of them, of course will not find much
                                        profit in farming. The same carelessness in any other kind of business would
                                        ensure equally as disastrous results.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Lewiston journal" TEIform="index"/>Lewiston Journal.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If a man have love in his heart..." TEIform="index"/>If a man have love in his heart...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">If a man have love in his heart, he may talk in broken language, but it will be eloquence
                                to those who listen.</p></div3></div2><!--
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>