<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0705" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shakers, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">7</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">5</biblScope><date value="18770501" TEIform="date">May 1877</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">33-40</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="7" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="33" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="5" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">OFFICIAL MONTHLY.—PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES. " t§a $rexch the Jungdotn of %oAl *' ^J\e
                        tentimonv of eternal tptth. Yol YII. i G. A. LOMAS, Bditok, ' Shakers, N. Y. MAY, 1877. i N. A.
                        BRIGGS, Publisher, 1 Shaker Village, K. H. No. 5.</p><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker on Moody and Sankey" TEIform="index"/>A Shaker on Moody and Sankey</head><p TEIform="p">Beloved Elder Daniel Boler : You say, " Write me, atter your return from Boston." In that
                            city I met Brother Elijah Myrick, and we attended one of the meetings in the Tabernacle. It
                            was on Friday evening. The hall was filled with some six thousand men, women and children.
                            There was a measure of satisfaction in finding so many assembled for religious teaching. It
                            was not necessary that I should find fault with the manner in which the doctrine of
                            salvation was presented. The world is filled with more or less of this light, and those who
                            have it should let it shine. I was there to witness the light, and not to teach. On the
                            platform were ministers, musicians, singers, and a liberal sprinkling of those who evidently
                            came to see and be seen. Many, no doubt, were made better by the musical, as well as vocal
                            prayers. On Saturday noon, we attended prayermeeting at the " Meonian." Several hundred
                            people were in the hall. Our good minister, who directed the services, very kindly informed
                            us that it was ordained from the foundation of the world that we should have just such a
                            meeting as we were having that day. His inspiration, or intuition, whichever it may have
                            been, pleabed me, as it warranted the establishing of the order to which we belong. There
                            was not much that savored of prayer in this information ; neither did it do any harm. On
                            Saturday afternoon, there was a meeting expressly for women, and no less than seven thousand
                            tarried there for an hour of prayer and praise ; while hundreds, if not thousands, were
                            obliged to enter the churches in the vicinity. The evening meeting was said to be expressly
                            for men—and it was masculine in its every feature. They formed a crowd—an awful crowd—before
                            the church door ; and I stood in that crowd full three fourths of an hour before the house
                            was opened. There was laughing, loud talking, singing and swearing. The moment the doors
                            were ajar, it was, in every sense, a jam. The passage-way was quite narrow, and those who
                            were so unfortunate as to get against a post or door, were crying for relief, as the
                            unreasonable thousands left them to their fate. There was no mercy before the church for
                            either saint or sinner. No man walked into that tabernacle is ever and only shunned dv
                            ignorance, superstition, and bigotry. An exchange of ideas is an improvement, intellectually
                            and spiritually, to readers and writers, especially when the vindication of truth and
                            refutation of error are aimed at. Let us see to it that The .Shaker lives well, grows, and
                            preaches peace and goodwill to all men. We cannot afford to let it dwindle—the very stones
                            should cry out! Its decadence would cast a cloud upon minds now illumed in our own circle,
                            and deprive sincere inquirers of the best means of information in regard to our
                            principles—which is now being so generously dispensed through its columns. Let us, gospel
                            and liberal friends, contribute to the maintenance of The Shaker in every way open toour
                            influence—financially,intellectuallyf God? All at peace, at rest. " I tell you," said James,
                            "that if those should hold their peace, the stones would immediately cry out." But I will
                            not enlarge. I spent one day in Newburyport. The revival meetings in that place still
                            continue. The interest is largely theological, rather than practical. They are for the
                            promulgation of the atonement, the blood of Jesus, and endless punishment. How sad to know
                            that so many are becoming freshly inoculated with doctrines so objectionable—untrue — while
                            a better, far better, lies hid in a napkin. Several of the New England cities and villages
                            are much interested in the present revival. A great deal of work is being done—work which
                            requires self-abnegation, as well as religious zeal. While we may not be able to commend the
                            course which is adopted, nor to endorse the dogmas which are promulgated, we should be the
                            last of all religious bodies to cast an influence over the work which might prove
                            detrimental to the cause, so long as our position is certainly one of "respectable
                            indifference." The position may seem very singular, when we bear in mind that all our
                            accessions are from the order of the world. But our gospel testimony teaches us that the
                            Word of God opens to us an everlasting new day—a revival in spiritual life which knows no
                            end. Yours,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>Henry C. Blinn</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In this life of show, puffing advertisement and manufacture of public opinion..." TEIform="index"/>In this life of show, puffing advertisement and manufacture of public opinion...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">In this life of show, puffing advertisement and manufacture of public opinion, all excellence
                            is lost sight of in the hunger for sudden performance and unearned praise.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Emerson" TEIform="persName"/>Emerson</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker" TEIform="index"/>The Shaker</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dibble, Chauncy" TEIform="persName"/>CHAUNCY DIBBLE</byline><p TEIform="p">It is generally known that The Shaker was first issued at Shakers, ST. Y., by the direction
                            of the leaders of 3ur institution, and under the supervision of its present editor. It is
                            not commonly known that its introduction was attended by very many disadvantages, which
                            required energetic efforts to surmount. To some of us, the undertaking appeared like running
                            off the track—opening a door to controversy, heretical views, proselyting, etc.
                            Notwithstanding these objections, and the censorious criticisms of those who predicted its
                            failure, the little sheethasfound worthy, interested, qualified friends and supporters, who
                            look hopefully, bej'ond the sordid policies of temporalities, to see the advancement of
                            truth, peace, love, purity, and universal brotherhood. With these living gems, the pages of
                            The Shaker are decked. Its every appearance is comely, cheerful, unassuming; yet. its simple
                            truths of Christianity cannot be gainsaid. As a searcher after truth, it dares to grapple
                            with a bigotry and superstition of almost infallible respectability. And if- it has dealt
                            too freely and unfeelingly with some of our pet theories, may we not be enlightened,
                            emancipated from the shackles of tradition, and have our faith more firmly grounded upon
                            eternal truth, by its freedom of thought and expression ? If some errors have crept into its
                            columns, it remains that these shall bear the crucible of increasing light, which The
                            Universalists and Unitarians,who seem to be begging a privilege of felowship, are left out
                            in the cold ; these, with the Catholics, the Quakers, the Shakers, and some others, are
                            maintainng a " respectable indifference." The Jniversalists, especially, feel chafed. They
                            were not invited to take part. 3oth Universalists and Unitarians think hey have a higher
                            light, a more reasonable system of theology, but admit they aave allowed themselves to rest
                            passivey in their higher knowledge, and that this indifference on their part may have caused
                            the present upheaval. What position do believers hold before the world? Heirs of God and
                            oint heirs with Christ? Fellow-citizens with the saints, and of the household of hey were
                            forced along by the pressure of the thousands—every one determined o secure a seat. The
                            writer reached the interior without injury, and gladly stepped aside to take breath. The
                            mul:itudes were pouring into the building, hrough four entrances, more like wild leasts than
                            human beings. Officers were at every corner, screaming their orders: " Don't crowd ;" "Go
                            slow;" 'Pass along;" "Keep to the right;" etc., etc., and, at the same time, brandishing
                            their batons, which the crowd •egarded about as much as they would the buzz of a fly or the
                            club of a pigmy. '. never experienced the like before, and would not care to again. It was a
                            thundering of boot-heels, as they rushed into the church, walking, running, and even jumping
                            over the chairs, each eager for the best place. Well, the wrriter obtained a seat, and heard
                            all that was said and sung. As the papers publish so fully the words of the evangelist, I
                            need not enlarge. But it is one thing to read the sermon in the paper, alone in the
                            chimney-corner, anJ quite another to hear it spoken with the life and intense earnestness
                            which a congregation of seven thousand must inspire in the soul of a determined man. Brother
                            Moody did not impress me as a very spiritual man ; not as one chastened by the
                            cross—crucified to the world—but rather the reverse. That he is earnest, and in sympathy
                            with his work, no one can doubt; and he is evidently as much a servant of God in that
                            revival as a Shaker may be in his quiet home. He writes, in one of his sermons, that " the
                            only way that death can be met is by death ;" and, perhaps, the only way for the world to be
                            met is by one fully imbedded in the world ; hence, the fitness. Attila considered himself
                            the "scourge of God," and was indeed terrible in his conquests. It required an Attila to do
                            the work ; and when Brother Mood} denounces those who differ from him in theology, and says
                            : "A man who preaches a bloodless religion is doing the devil's work, and I don't care who
                            he is!" This sounds very much like Satan quarreling with Satan. Everybody wants to hear
                            Sankey sing, and his soul in singing, as well as Moody's soul in much plain-speaking
                            attracts the crowd. If Sankey shoulc die to-day, I believe much less people would attend the
                            meetings. <pb n="34" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. prayerfullyus credit. -and the heavens will give
                            " Oh ! Zion, in thy fearful struggles With Error's galling chain, Can I behold thy strength
                            go down, Or see thy beauty wane ? "</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian culture, no. 3" TEIform="index"/>Christian Culture, No. 3</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, W. H." TEIform="persName"/>W. H. BUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p">COMPLETENESS. All persons who view themselves in the light of the divine truth are
                            constrained to acknowledge various deficiencies in their moral, and social. character —
                            mental, Admiring friends, in writing the biography of the great man—hero, statesman, or
                            philosopher —would fain gloss over defects in their idol, or shut them out entirely from the
                            public gaze. But there they are, nevertheless ; and there is no one, whatever his merits may
                            be, but is subject to the keen-eyed scrutiny of some critic, who may be actuated by the
                            desire to bring out the whole truth, or, possibly, by envy alone, " To draw his frailties
                            from their drear abode." The inference from the above paragraph is the old-time truth, that
                            all are " miserable offenders," and need, alike, to enter upon the work of self-purification
                            and perfection. The perfecting of the human character is not a sudden nor brief pi'ocess,
                            but the work of long years of steady effort; and that, for the sufficient reason that this
                            character is to endure forever. Hence, nothing is more essential, in the very commencement
                            of the work of Christian culture, than the spirit that looks with calm eye beyond every
                            intervening obstacle to the glorious consummation. One imbued with this never hears " The
                            lingering knell that tells his hopes are dead," but is ever cheered by the all-animating
                            voice, " Come up hither, and I will show thee the beauty and 'Splendor of the heavenly
                            city." Faith and hope in an individual may be more or less strong in proportion to original,
                            natural development, but their strength does not depend entirely on this. The constant
                            inflow of the divine inspiration into the spirit, will animate one with greater courage and
                            far stronger hopes, than the most powerful arguments presented to the reason can do without
                            this. In fact, these inspirations are themselves the most convincing arguments that can be
                            presented to the human mind, so far as a knowledge of God and man's future destiny are
                            concerned. As the inspirations of the common air and light, impress upon the soul a
                            consciousness of physical life that requires no other persuasive force, so will those deeper
                            inspirations that are intended to renew the powers of the moral and spiritual being impart a
                            consciousness of their own eternal nature. Too great stress cannot be laid upon these in
                            moulding and completing the Christian character. " Ye must be born rom above." The grace of
                            humility, which forbids one to exalt himself above another, is cherished, strengthened, and
                            confirmed by the constant inlow of the Christ-life into the soul. Where would be the
                            dignitaries of the world, both political and ecclesiastical, f this universally pervaded the
                            hearts of men? Oh, from what heights would many fall, were this the case ! Not nine days
                            only, the time which Milton's Sa:an occupied in making his descent from the battlements of
                            heaven, but years might be needed for some to gain their proper level! Gentleness can attain
                            its true sweetness of character only by makng its abode where the mild beams of he heavenly
                            light continually shine. r*atience, that turns all the trials of life nto the greatest
                            blessings, receives its sparkling crown only after it has finished its course of discipline,
                            which its Danoply, drawn from the celestial ai'mory, has enabled it to accomplish. Charity,
                            the lovely attendant of Faith and Hope, shows her divine origin whenever and wherever she
                            makes her appeai'ance. When one admits her as lis permanent guest, she readily makes lis
                            dwelling her abode. She diffuses throughout, the joyous radiance of her own countenance ;
                            introduces the order, Deace, and quiet that reign supremely in the blest regions whence she
                            descended ; makes her presence felt by all who approach her; and sends abroad the inluences
                            which it is her delight to make others feel. In a word, health, which imparts soundness to
                            the limbs, fullness to the muscles, an agreeable tone to the nerves, and vigor to the brain,
                            is known in its completest power, only when the forces that are imparted by spiritual
                            inspirations are conjoined with those influences which come from earthly life-sources. This
                            union of forces was recognized by the Apostle John, in the words, "Beloved, I wish above all
                            things that thou mayst prosper and be in health even as thy soul prospers." Bodily health
                            and vigor cannot properly be dissociated from the intellectual and moral forces. In fact,
                            body and spirit are one, anc ever must be connected in the most intimate union, whether that
                            be the result of the combination of the grosser elements during the earthly life, or of the
                            more refined elements in the celestial spheres when the earthly union shall cease.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Commune life" TEIform="index"/>Commune Life</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="George, Henry" TEIform="persName"/>HENRY GEORGE</byline><p TEIform="p">How little is communism understood ! and how few of us are fitted to live the life of
                            communists ! We are here enjoying the necessaries of life, not because we are more worthy
                            than others of the human family, but rather as creatures of circumstances. When we see our
                            brothers and sisters of the out side world suffering for want of fooc and clothing, our
                            sympathies ought to go out to them abundantly, and no grudgingly. How many of us, to-day
                            thrown on our own resources, and lef bility to our own appetites, would be much better than
                            those with whom we occasionally come in contact? I think, surrounded as we are with all
                            physical comforts, we are very apt to forget our former conditions, and the circumstances
                            which brought us here. We should try and use our privilege so that when we are called to
                            account for our stewardship we may hear the saying of " Well done, good and faithful
                            servant," for we are only holding treasures in trust for those that come after us, and have
                            no right to use them to exalt ourselves. If we would live a commune ife, we must curb our
                            selfishness ; live to make others happy ; and by doing so, we are indeed made happy
                            ourselves. "It is more blessed to give than to receive." This truth is realized by every one
                            that tries the experiment. Take, for example, two school-boys ; one has an apple.
                            Selfishness says, keep it, and eat it when alone. Generosity says, share it with your
                            playfellow. Then follows the conflict. If Generosity triumphs, then he is made happy ; if
                            not, mean, sordid Selfishness brings discontent. When I reflect upon the uncertainty of
                            riches—in affluence to-day and penury to-morrow—it makes me thankful for the heaven-born
                            principle of commune life. As our song says, " the strong shall help the weak along ; "
                            which may be taken literally. I believe we may enjoy, in this world, a heaven, inasmuch as
                            we are willing to give up self and work for the benefit of the whole human family. May we
                            not weary in well-doing. May we show a light that is steady, not flickering; living a fully
                            consecrated life, that will fit us for the much larger commune we are on our way to join.
                            Shakers^ N. 7".</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Words fitly spoken" TEIform="index"/>Words Fitly Spoken</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Neal, Sarah A." TEIform="persName"/>SARAH A. NEAL</byline><p TEIform="p">When we reflect that the power oi speech was given to humanity as a means of communication,
                            and intended only for a blessing, and know that it frequently proves the contrary, we heave
                            a sigh of regret that greater wisdom is not manifested in the use of language. But we yearn
                            more for those words fitly spoken, behind which only truthful motives are concealed, and
                            which would be more than "golden fruit" set in " silver pictures," to those tender natures
                            born to thrive only in the sunshine of kind words. Humanity is largely diversified ; al are
                            not sufficiently strong to bear the trials of life alone ; neither have they intuitive
                            judgment to always direct their own course wisely. And how many of the weaker class glide
                            unconsciously into the road to desperation and sin— left finally with only a "forlorn hope'
                            of ever finding salvation ; and all for the want of those kindly words "fitly spoken " in
                            season, to aid the soul up ward. And where will the responsiultimately rest? On the poor
                            un-l fortunate sinner's soul ? Heaven spare t. But words are but the mediums of our thoughts
                            ; and how important it is hen that we always think so kindly and correctly that our thoughts
                            can be fitly illustrated in words, without inury to even the most tender. Were ;his always
                            the case, then indeed would our language become like a garden of blossoms, ever looking
                            upward to meet ;he smiles of approving Providence. The erring would no longer remain the
                            estranged exile, roaming amid the shadows of sorrow and despair; for gentle words and
                            pleading tones would savor of reclamation, while the grieved and despondent would be taught
                            to look ip and behold the "silver light" belind the darkest cloud. Oh, we say, 'it would be
                            joy to be there!" But, shall we anticipate this descending of leaven to earth? Hardly, while
                            we remember that even in this, our christian land, we sometimes forget our alegiance to
                            Christianity, and wander away into harsh tones, unpleasant words, and the rendering of a
                            language ;hat would sound unbecoming even in leathen territory, much more so in a
                            proressedly Christian neighborhood, leaving those who most need, to mourn the oss of those
                            words which, "fitly spoken," would be the bearers of blessings like those only that are
                            spoiled by the trammels of description, Dut are better known through the symoathy of hearts.
                            Scripture teaches us that from the abundance of the heart the mouth speaketh ; and while
                            this may be true at times it is an indisputable fact that the mouth often utters what the
                            heart recognizes as not its own ; for were it otherwise, the drama of life would be relieved
                            of very many heartbreaking scenes which now appear as prominent features, the legitimate
                            results of shallow words, broken vows, and false friendships. But we plead : Gentle angel,
                            help us keep All our vows intact and true; Teach us how to think, and speak, To live, and
                            love, as angels do. Then will "fitly spoken" words always grace our society, and true
                            friendship will be an eternal outgrowth.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sound" TEIform="index"/>Sound
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Sound.—Awell-knowrn Shaker minister, in present service, thus successfully hits the mark:
                            "When I say or do that which I should not, it is not the minister's saying nor doing,—it is
                            me, N. Y. Z. When I so arrange my words and deeds that they accord with Christ's spirit and
                            our gospel instruction, then the minister is paramount, and should be respected! " How very
                            careful elders and ministers should be !</p></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Particular notice" TEIform="index"/>PARTICULAR NOTICE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The American Agriculturist is a very worthy monthly. Its subscription price is$i.6o. We will
                            send The Shaker and // together during 1877 for #1.50!! Now take advantage of our offer, and
                            get both for less than quarter cost. Address the Publisher of The Shaker.</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">To our surprise, two editions of "Shaker Child's Prayer" are exhausted !</p></div2><pb n="35" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What shall I do to be a shaker? no. 4" TEIform="index"/>What shall I do to be a Shaker? No. 4</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fletcher, Richard" TEIform="persName"/>RICHARD FLETCHER</byline><p TEIform="p">Or, what shall I do to be d Christian ? is not a common question around here. "What shall I
                            do to be saved?" is a favorite text with " revivalists," who stir up many people to echo the
                            question, without knowing exactly what they wish to be saved from. Can God save them from
                            the danger signaled from so many pulpits, in language almost red with hell-fire and
                            damnation? Can He save them while they carry around enough secret, unconfessed sin to burn
                            in their memory for years, adding a little fuel every day by fresh sinning? "O, weak human
                            nature cannot help it. Miserable sinners that we are, thank God that we are not in danger of
                            losing our souls by growing vain-glorious and self-righteous." A certain amount of
                            sinning—enough to keep fashionable robes of righteousness comfortably filthy—acts like a
                            safety-valve with them to keep Christian virtues from pressing them too near the kingdom of
                            heaven before they have got enough of earthly pleasure. Let no one think—not even Mr Moody,
                            nor other zealous laborers foi good — that genuine Christianity wil ever have a majority
                            here below. I never was popular; never will be Enthusiastic dreamers might as wel content
                            themselves for the failure o: plans for wholesale reform, by reading Matt. 7:14: " Narrow is
                            the way tha leads to life, and few are they who fine it." Reader, do you smile at the
                            question before you ? Do you passing shrug of pity, ' think, with a What are those simple
                            people preaching virtue of celibacy, in these days, for ? If there is any virtue in it, the
                            very ones who need it most are least willing to practice it. Why do they dream of bringing
                            peace on earth, of making nation forgive nation, as Sunday-school children are taught, in
                            these days when man's God given ingenuity develops, faster thai ever, into terrible forms of
                            weapons anc agents for bloody war?—when youths papers advertise seven-shooters for chi]
                            dren's toys, forsooth? As for commu nity form of living—never ! Why, w can't share church
                            privileges togethei a few hours in the week, without envy ings, quarrels, and breaking up ;
                            muc less could we live under the sam roof with dear gospel friends." To the few who care to
                            think a mo ment on these things, we say : By dail life, as well as printed word, we d urge
                            celibacy in its strictest sense, be cause there never was greater need fo spreading its
                            healing virtue over degen erating humanity than to-day, and you know it. We urge all
                            mankind, who are able, to live as brothers and sisters, because Christ revealed the grand
                            nobility of loving God and man with a height, depth, and breadth of feeling that dwarfs
                            natural affection into comparative selfishness. We urge peace between neighbors, owns,
                            states, and nations, because war s simply devilish. During the heat of a revival, you can
                            asily take an " anxious seat," ask for Drayers, join a church. You cannot be a Christian
                            next week without checking many hasty, unkind words, curbing a quick temper, driving off
                            unworthy thoughts; in short, without denying your self in many ways your conscience will
                            suggest. Begin with lowest appetites, that link us to the animal creation. Do desires for
                            pleasing sense of taste, never carry you to excess ? Do we eat that which is not nourishing,
                            but stimulating, or merely cloying to the palate ? Do we drink that which does not satisfy
                            thirst? Some say, "Your ideal of religion is too high—beyond the power of mortals to attain
                            on earth." So was Christ's revelation too heavenly for earth. Jesus of Nazareth lived and
                            preached a life of virginity, non-resisting peace, universal love, and fraternity of goods.
                            It would be very difficult for a merchant to do business on a ready-cashdown system Most
                            merchants laugh at the idea of up-and-down-cash dealings right along. They call sixty days'
                            credit the same as cash ! Sad abuse of honest language it is. Yet all acknowl edge a cash
                            system, without trusting, etc., a noble ideal. So igion, a high ideal is needed. Sonyea, N.
                            Y.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="South Union, Kentucky, March 1877" TEIform="index"/>South Union, Ky., March, 1877</head><p TEIform="p">Editor of Shaker: The February number of The Shaker came duly, and was, as usual, fraught
                                with words of precious truth. It is, indeed, a feast to me, and I never stop until its
                                contents article especially are well attracted learned. One my attention : What shall I
                                do to be a Shaker? We are frequently in receipt of letters of inquiry, from individuals
                                desirous of information in regard to our faith and practices, and we often feel at a
                                loss how to reply, in consequence of our ignorance of the motive that prompts the
                                desire. Hence, my approbation of the article referred to, which I think is sufficient to
                                enable every one who reads it, to get a correct knowledge of the essential requisites to
                                be a Shaker. Then each one can answer for themselves, " Am I willing and prepared to
                                make the necessary sacrifices ?" We are often called upon to meet applicants for
                                admission into our society, who are totally ignorant in regard to our faith, and often
                                without any religious feeling whatever, but come exclusively from worldly considerations
                                ; and to all such I would respectfully say, our institu my personal efforts; merits of a
                                mythological atonement will not do me nor any one else any good. That is the rock upon
                                which thousands are stranded. To the extent we live the Christ-life, does Jesus become
                                our savior. Whatsoever we sow, that will we reap; then will it not be wisdom in us all
                                to sow love, mercy, and charity? I shall labor to do so. Nothing is so conducive to
                                happiness as a good conscience, and to acquire and keep one, we must live up to the
                                highest light we have in the faithful discharge of every known duty; doing so will bring
                                a peace of mind which all the wealth and fame of this world can never give. Holiness is
                                " the pearl of great price," more to be valued than all the gems of Golconda's mines ;
                                and yet, how few attain it! Why? Simply because we are not willing to pay the price.
                                Shakerism demands the renunciation of everything pertaining to the natural order, and
                                the adoption of the spiritual, the heavenly. The carnal life must die; and, in
                                proportion as we crucify it, will we rise into newness of life. My faith is that souls
                                have to be quickened ere they are prepared to receive the truth. It is as useless to
                                present truths, however beautiful or sublime, to the spiritually blind, as to " cast
                                pearls before swine." I do not mean that we are not free agents, for that would do away
                                with individual responsibility and lead into extremes from which the soul recoils in
                                horror. Every soul possesses within itself the germ of a divine life, which, if
                                cultivated and allowed to expand, will develop and unfold our spiritual natures, until
                                we will be prepared to walk, as Jesus did, in obedience to our father's commands. So,
                                brethren and sisters, the matter rests with ourselves. Will you be saved, or will you
                                not? Will you choose the narrow way which leads to a world fairer than finite mind can
                                conceive of, or do you prefer to enjoy the pleasures of sin, which are only for a
                                season, and receive the condemnation that is sure to follow? Will it not be wisdom in us
                                to choose the better part, which cannot be taken from us, and thereby secure an
                                inheritance with the saints? Let us who profess to be Shakers live according to our
                                profession. Let the spirit of Christ rule our hearts and govern our every action. Let us
                                prove the sincerity of our faith, by our daily life and conversation. I feel it a
                                sacrilege for persons to remain on consecrated ground whose every breath is a violation
                                of zion's laws. The inmates of our father's house should keep clean hands and pure
                                hearts,—avoid even the appearance of evil. Let us be an honor to our calling, an example
                                to the world. O that every one could feel as I do about this matter. As a good brother
                                expressed in out meeting last Sabbath : " O that a spirit of conviction might fall upon
                                our people, to awaken them to an interest the cause demands!" My heart echoed a response
                                to that prayer. A thorough understanding of our principles will convince any candid,
                                unbiased person of their merit; and, if lived, will produce a purity of life that can
                                never be excelled. I feel an especial interest in the young. I have been young
                                myself,—am not old yet. Words cannot express the intensity of my solicitude for finds an
                                habitation and dearest objects on which to rest, where everything is a gem, everything
                                wears beauty of the brightest colors, richest shades, and most inviting charms! Where
                                can thought alight more satisfactorily than upon home ? and upon what objects more
                                endearing than those of sympathizing, affectionate friends? There is nothing of the
                                ideal higher; the image of God is there,— yea, more: there God manifests himself the
                                most perfectly to our senses. There is a sacredness, there is something enchanting in
                                home that is real, genuine; and in the dear ones there, are our loftiest ideals of
                                angels. tion was not designed for a home for the outcast and bankrupt, but for sin-sick
                                souls, who desire salvation from the evils of a corrupt nature. " Without faith it is
                                impossible to please God," consequently faith should be our starting-point,-—the
                                foundation upon which we build. ¦ Faith in God's order, in the confession and
                                forgiveness of sin in that order. I have this faith, and deep is the thankfulness of my
                                heart that I have been led into it; that I have the inestimable privilege of being
                                numbered with God's people. I desire a fire that will purge me of dross until nothing
                                remains but pure gold. Yea, I will endure the furnace-heat, anything that will enable me
                                to eradicate evil, and obtain a pure heart, without which, no one can see God. I am
                                aware my success depends upon the young of my own sex,—those who dwell with" believers.
                                Let me impress upon your minds the great importance of cultivating, in early youth,
                                those pure principles of mental and moral excellence which are so necessary to elevate
                                and adorn the female character. Be emulous to excel in every good thought and deed;
                                imitate the virgin purity of our great exemplars, Jesus and Ann, father and mother of
                                the new creation. Be obedient to those who teach you to be useful, and you will never
                                regret, in the future, the folly of a misspent life. This counsel is given in much love,
                                with the prayer that it may fall upon some heart prepared for the seed. In conclusion,
                                my prayer is, " Let me be a true, genuine Shaker," which embodies every Christian
                                virtue.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="McLaughlin, Josephine" TEIform="persName"/>Josephine McLaughlin</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Letters from a gospel father to his gospel daughters" TEIform="index"/>Letters from a
                                Gospel Father to His Gospel Daughters</head><p TEIform="p">Enfield, N. H., March, 1877. Beloved Sister B. : Your kind favor of the 14th, containing
                                a graphic report of your journey and mission to W., is received, for which receive my
                                thanks. Such tokens of sisterly remembrance are always appreciated; they bear to me more
                                than a narrative of events or the common parlance of a letter; a spirit, an influence
                                accompanies them, which speaks to the soul and tells of home and home relations, than
                                which no intelligence so affects the mind nor operate; so deeply. It penetrates the
                                soul. No Subject gives ideas more inspirational--sensations more pathetic and emotional.
                                - .Home and home friends, the pure, Christian bro~th"fc¥hood and sisterhood, where
                                confidence reposes, ,where our great interests center, where love We there find a power
                                stronger than all other powers combined ; an affection unfathomable, knowing no limits.
                                Here are the ministrations of the highest, here is heaven, here are our saviors. Hence,
                                how great our obligations to beautify, to strengthen, and make everything about us
                                peaceful, glorious, and perfect! How necessary to bring all things into harmony, ever to
                                maintain order, heaven's first gift; never trespass upon the law of love ! Under no
                                circumstances should we depart from principle; always true, always kind and obliging,
                                ever ready to alleviate distress, comfort the afflicted, strengthen the weak, and
                                forgive the erring and penitent; always open to conviction, and equally free to impart
                                knowledge to the ignorant, and aid those who are in need of assistance. Thus, beloved
                                sister, our path becomes that of wisdom, always pleasant, and the duties of life never
                                unendurable tasks; thus, the yoke of Christ is easy, and his burden light. Accept my
                                sincere love and that of my companions. Please bear this to all our dear friends in
                                Shaker Village. Your brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName"/>Abraham Perkins</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire, March, 1877" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H., March, 1877</head><p TEIform="p">My gospel daughter, Alice : I assure you your kind, neatly-written letter was not only
                                acceptable, but fondly appreciated. It seems you have been reading the good book; many
                                excellent and saving truths are hidden there. It pleases me that j'ou search for them.
                                If you persistently and confidently seek truth, you will find it to your salvation. It
                                is a resurrecting, saving power; it contributes both peace and love, and ministers to
                                our wants of every gospel grace. Dear child, in your character make this principle
                                conspicuous. Be open to conviction, and truth will abundantly flow in, and the treasures
                                of heaven will be your inheritance. You mention regrets that you had not been earlier
                                called and gathered into the Shaker church. When the door was opened for your admission,
                                you stepped in; that was your time,—the right time; it could never have been better. It
                                was so in my case. It is equally true with all who hearken and obey when the call of God
                                reaches them. Your ears are blest; do not close them; continue to hear, and be as
                                faithful to obey; and your cup of blessing will be full. No advantage will ever avail
                                any soul who is found in opposition to the laws of God, or to the plan of salvation as
                                revealed to the lost family of Adam. When we mur <pb n="36" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 36 THE SHAKER.
                                mur, or complain of the cross, we act as the adversaries of heaven. We should realize
                                that the order of heaven is divine. It is too often the case that those who feel the
                                testimony of the cross bearing against their carnal lives are found speaking ill of
                                divine order and throwing obstacles in the way, thus preventing the beaming of light,
                                obedience to faith, and submission to the dictates of. conscience. Every soul should
                                make this a point,—never stifle emotion, never allow an .influence whose tendency would
                                cause another to act contrary to religious convictions. These are basic principles of
                                success in life. By the'k"ts of another, no one can be justified nor condemned.
                                Remember, the voice of God has reached your soul; you have heard it. It now remains with
                                you to make your election sure. And now, dear child, accept my thanks for your
                                interesting report to me of meetings, companions, etc.; remembering me in kindest love
                                to them, to vour elders, and to all my friends; and accept for yourself my love and
                                prayers forever. Yours truly,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName"/>Abraham Perkins</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York, March 20, 1877" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., March 20,
                                1877</head><p TEIform="p">Bro. Geo. Albert: I was much surprised while reading The Shaker this forenoon to learn
                                how unexpectedly rich I had suddenly become by your little article in The Shaker for
                                March! Only a few days since, and we heard the Covenant read, by which we were informed
                                that we were not the owners, individually, of a single dollar! Now, dear editor, what
                                reply can we make to a revenue or other government officer should he come to collect
                                income tax, where, by an article of agreement, signed and sealed, we represent we are
                                not worth one cent? [Send him to Harvard, Alfred, Canterbury; or let him read our
                                apology ! Ed.] And then, by our paper, we proclaim to the world we are worth millions of
                                money! Is there not a probability of a misunderstanding between officers and ourselves?
                                If not, please inform us bow we can get a few thousands to help us out of our present
                                difficulty. To some, both statements may appear correct; but how can we harmonize them?
                                To some outside of our societies, we appear very rich; but, to me, this is not the case.
                                When one devotes all he has and is to the "cause,"—consecrates himself to a Shaker's
                                life,—instead of being a millionaire, he finds himself without one cent he can call his
                                own ! Yours truly, [Our " Notice to assessors" will partly explain how we blundered,
                                what we did it for, and how generously we are paid for so doing. Ed.]</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wickersham, George M." TEIform="persName"/>Geo. M. Wickersham</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My dear editor:" TEIform="index"/>My dear Editor:</head><p TEIform="p">Had a soldier returned from an engagement in the late war as badly crippled as my
                                manuscript from its engagement with the compositors of your February number, he would
                                have been entitled to universal sympathy. Their first shot put a. period to the
                                existence of a poor, little, innocent comma, at the end of the twelfth line; their
                                second transformed lore into love, in the fourteenth line ; and their third gave the
                                coup de grace, by distorting¦ haste into hosts, in the eighteenth line. How would it do
                                for you to employ a professor of Chinese literature as proof-reader? Or better still,
                                perhaps, engage the grand high commission at Washington, who have solved the
                                presidential conundrum, to sit permanently a«^a board for determining the true intent
                                and meaning of manuscript contributions to The Shaker [bv E. T. L. Ed.], with full power
                                to go behinc the retuVns ? Most truly, as ever, yours,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leggett, E. T." TEIform="persName"/>E. T. Leggett</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Gloucester, Maine, March 20, 1877" TEIform="index"/>West Gloucester, Me. , \ March
                                20, 1877</head><p TEIform="p">[This is from one of the "goodest" chil dren. Ed.] Dear Bro. Albert: I saw a notice in
                                The Shaker for Maixh that, on receipt of nam and stamp, you would send "The Shake hild's
                                prayer." I thought that I would avail myself of the opportunity of procuring one while
                                you had a supply. I like what you mve written to the children, and I hope that ou will
                                write some more. I am also very bnd of the music. I am your affectionate hild,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Brackett, Joseph" TEIform="persName"/>Joseph Brackett, 79 years of age</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Social life topics" TEIform="index"/>SOCIAL, LIFE TOPICS</head><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Speak kindly" TEIform="index"/>Speak Kindly</head><p TEIform="p">From the Cook's Manual. t pays to speak kindly, in every case, Jse words that are
                                truthful, yet seasoned with grace. Vith the spirit of malice no good can be done, Tis
                                only by love that the erring are won. -•ray, what do we gain when we try to pay back, Or
                                the christian-like spirit of patience we lack? n the first case our measure is folly, we
                                know, ?or the soil of impatience, no good thing can grow. t pays to speak kindly, if no
                                other gain, Ahe spirit of love and good-will we maintain ; And are sowing the seed of a
                                harvest to come, Whether evil or good, we must gather it home. </p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Washing-day among the shakers" TEIform="index"/>Washing-day among the Shakers</head><p TEIform="p">My dear Sister C: Permit me to ask, if you ever read the lines of an old ballad reerring
                                to washing-day? They begin as folows : " The sky with clouds was overcast, The rain
                                began to fall; There is no luck about the house— There is no luck at all." And then the
                                rhymer goes on to say: " For 'tis thump, thump, thump, And scold, scold, scold," etc. I
                                should have been pleased, had you been present with us on our last " positive Monday,"
                                our washing-day, and for two reasons : First, to act as an artist in sketching the
                                several scenes as they occurred. Secondly, to note the spirit of kindness which
                                prevailed during the performance of this duty. The big bell on the house-top began to
                                call us to duty at five o'clock a. m., and I imagined that there was a sort of sympathy
                                in its first tones; for the weather was intensely cold; but as it swung to and fro in
                                the air, its massive ding-dong seemed to appeal to our honor; (for no one feels as well
                                to enter the laundry out of season, or after her companions have been at work for half
                                an hour.) All were in season, however, except one, this morning, and she canceled
                                tardiness by industry the remainder of the day. One, two three, four—eight—ten—twenty
                                baskets o: goods stood waiting the cleansing operation of a Shaker Washing Machine;
                                while as many as twelve sisters were employed foi seven hours, at least, as assistants.
                                Butwha is the matter? The engineer is running to and fro, anon to the loft above, with a
                                pail o hot water, where are two tanks, each capable of holding twelve barrels of water,
                                usuall&gt; heated by steam and conducted through pipe to the laundry below; but King
                                Frost ha breathed his icy breath into the main pipe and congealed just enough of the
                                crysta fluid to obstruct the passage of steam. All business is suspended for an hour, a
                                least; yet, believe me, we did not scold no fret; on the contrary, we planned how to fil
                                the time more profitably, and each siste went to perform some little household duty
                                which was necessary to complete before night Thus no time was unimproved and no cheer
                                fulness lost. After our prudent engineer had adminis tered hot applications sufficient
                                to start the circulation so that hot steam pressed into the water-tanks above, and
                                boiling-tubs below, a dense fog arose, another petty annoyance, caused by the mingling
                                of the cold air from without with a warm, artificial atmosphere within. Now, were it not
                                that we adhered uite faithfully to our favorite maxim—"A )lace for everything, and
                                everything in its :&gt;lace "—and you know the place for many flings on washing-day
                                is in the center of the floor; without care we should have seriously jostled against a
                                variety of baskets and bunles; but on this eventful day every bundle eemed to have a
                                positive friend, and every casket an owner. We had learned by previus experience, that a
                                current of air from two pposite points would speedily remove the greater part of such a
                                vapor, so we searched or the doors, intending to open one on the ast and the other on
                                the west side of the oom; but every aperture was as hermetially sealed with ice as a can
                                of fruit ought to be from air, and it was quite impossible to open either door. After
                                several fruitless attempts, and a hearty laugh at our defeat by fog, we tried the effect
                                of a good fire. All this occurred before breakfast; a pleny of " thumps " were present,
                                but not a single scold could be heard; and I think it safe o say that there was not even
                                an impatient pirit among us, for, holding in memory the nfluence of our Sabbath
                                devotions, and the &gt;ractical Christian vows we had made together, we were able to
                                reconcile all the tem)oral difficulties. But the end is not yet; our washing machine
                                next appeared to be frost-bound and out of joint, merely because we had made everything
                                else right, and there was room for another trouble ! A few drops of oil and a little
                                hammering soon coaxed this nto good-humor. The " Shaker Washing Machine" has rendered us
                                too much valuable service in the last ten years to permit us to underestimate its many
                                excellences. We have learned of only one article which will in any way take its place in
                                our appreciation, and that is the " Shaker Laundry Soap." With this soap, we are able to
                                cleanse goods with far less hand-rubbing; linens, cottons, woolens, and the finer
                                fabrics, silks, laces, muslins, etc., are cleansed thereby without injury. We have
                                ourselves proved that paint, printer's ink, writing ink, and many stains of long
                                standing are removed by a proper use of this soap. Perhaps you have heard of the
                                article, and so I will return to my story of washing-day. When our washing machine was
                                all right, and in motion, we anticipated success. For an hour every pulley and shaft
                                seemed to operate like magic; but suddenly the wringer in the north-west corner (a very
                                cold place) was seized with the epidemic and refused to move ; the application of oil,
                                even, nor of much kind treatment would effect a cure. The main-belt had beer newly but
                                improperly laced: the same was relaced, and we succeeded in starting the wringer ! But
                                there is only one right way to do everything, and we were obliged to pause many times,
                                for nothing would succeed, ex cept a thorough repairing of the belt in ques tion.
                                Finally, good luck attended us, and bj one o'clock p. m., our washing was complet ed.
                                The garments had been mill-washed boiled, rinsed, wrung and hung to dry, no by one poor
                                Bridget, however, but by a doz en pairs of willing hands dictated by cheer ful hearts. I
                                have somewhere read that cole and badly-cooked dinners are another annoy ance on this
                                ill-fated day ; we, on the contrary found a warm dinner awaiting us, and kinr sisters
                                who prepared the same, manifestly pleased to enhance our comfort in some way By the way,
                                I have taken the liberty t write a Shaker parody on the washing-da lines. There is no
                                place for fret nor scold— There is no place at all; If we the Christian motto hold, We
                                love and Avork for all. So thump, thump, thump is labor sweet Whatever be the day;—
                                Wherever virgin sisters meet, All scold is swept away. Kindly yours</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="H., E. M." TEIform="persName"/>E. M. H.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reply" TEIform="index"/>REPLY</head><p TEIform="p">E. M. H.—Valued Sister: Please acept many thanks for the kind report of our laundry
                                experiences. As I read it, I eem to be brought into closer sympathy with ou and the
                                scenes you present. One word bout the fossil rhymes you instance; for I m happv to
                                believe that the leading fact oticed in the ballad does not very forcibly pply to your
                                companions of the laundry, nd that on that day of unusual perplexity, le utmost
                                good-humor prevailed ! At least, iis is what I infer from the tenor of your tatement,
                                which, I opine, is one of the hap&gt;y results of practical religion—a religion
                                which should be as apparent in the lanudry n Monday, as in church on Sunday. Ah! vhen
                                its presence blesses every enterprise, verywhere, then the word s-c-o-l-d will beome
                                obsolete, or die for want of breath. And you all heard the bell that morning,, id you?
                                Oh ! that big bell! How often has t seemingly repeated one significant couplet vith a
                                prolonged echo to its reluctant hearrs, thus : "If one would thrive," clang! clang! " He
                                must rise at five," ding, dong, bell! We can easily imagine with what clear, harp tones
                                this injunction rang out upon he frosty atmosphere of the morning in uestion. All honor
                                to those who discipline hemselves to retire, as well as rise early, for ' early to bed
                                and early to rise, makes one lealthy, wealthy and wise," said Poor Richrd, who was quite
                                right, for this habit reners persons heroic as well as healthy and able to obey the
                                summons, to shake off dull loth, and thus early emulate one of the first principles of
                                self-denial which Shakerism embraces. But I am thinking, my dear E., ;hat the mental
                                picture which you have given me, does not wear a wintry aspect at all. It is so gilded
                                with sunlight, or good cheer, that I can hardly perceive a cloud in your domestic sky,
                                and am persuaded to believe that your companions were unusually good on that uncommon
                                day! Now, as no picture is complete without a little shade, so I wonder, ah ! I wonder
                                what those amiable sisters would have done, had they been forced by circumstances to
                                perform the same amount of washing with mercury as many degrees, below comfortable, and
                                all without a " Shaker Washing Machine," which you so heartily recommend, a convenient
                                wringer, " Shaker Laundry Soap," beside other facilities which would take space to name!
                                Think you that they would have borne the invasion of the frost-king without a murmur?
                                Further, it seems that no member of your party was blamed for the series of mishaps
                                realized, consequently no one was censured; hence, there was no temptation to even hum
                                the ancient tune to which you refer, and much less to scold. Is it the absence of
                                temptation which develops the Christian, or makes a genuine Shaker? Methinks, I hear
                                your ready reply : " Nay, emphatically nay." Are you not yet aware that all good Shakers
                                are bound by their consciences, by their honor as professed followers of the doctrines
                                of the New Testament, wherein the right use of the tongue is so ably treated by the
                                sainted apostle James, to heed these instructions, and strive always to govern the
                                unruly member, which the apostle declares, " is a world of iniquity?" I am aware that
                                this is our profession, and also, that in our imperfect, undisciplined state, we often
                                fail of living fully up to the scriptural truths quoted; and, though I am confident that
                                you each did your best, under the circumstances, I still claim that with all of your
                                perplexities you were most felicitously situated, compared with the conditions of many
                                of our sister - companions who toil abroad; and the question which I urge is, <pb n="37" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. 37 •would you be able to exchange localities and surroundings
                                and be as kind, as peaceable? Ah! I recall now that vou stated as fact, that you each
                                had spent the previous Sabbath in a worshipful spirit, that you renewed your covenants
                                with God, and made your pledges to do right in his presence together, which gave you
                                power over the tongue in emergencies; thus, you can rightfully say with the apostle,
                                "The fruit of righteousness is sown in peace of them that make peace." In this spirit I
                                easily perceive how possible is success; for they who have God in all their thoughts,
                                obey the sacred injunction ol " Hands to work and hearts to God," and are thereby able
                                to govern not only the tongue, but every other faculty, in any locality where duty
                                calls. Sincerely thine,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="C." TEIform="persName"/>C.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Epitomic history of the Watervliet shakers" TEIform="index"/>Epitomic History of the
                            Watervliet Shakers</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Buckingham, D. A." TEIform="persName"/>D. A. BUCKINGHAM</byline><p TEIform="p">No, 1.—Of the destitute condition of the believers soon after settling at Watervliet, as
                            found on record. During the year 177^' *ne believers at Watervliet suffered exceedingly for
                            food, and in temporal matters generally. It was a time when money was scarce ; and, being
                            poor, they had no means to buy. It being a fixed principle with them never to run in debt,
                            even for the necessaries of life, their existence became somewhat precarious. Their food
                            consisted principally of rice and milk. A little fish, mostly sturgeon, was everything of
                            the meat kind they enjoyed for several months. Had little or no butter nor cheese. This
                            simple fare was their main support during the spring and summer of said year. Their chief
                            employment was planting, sowing, and harvesting. They toiled hard for their scanty pittance,
                            and became so reduced in flesh that the}' looked more like walking skeletons than laboring
                            men. Oft-times, they were so weak and faint, they could not work. Hard labor and want of
                            nourishing food were telling mightily upon them. At one season, their breakfast consisted
                            only of a small bowl of milk-porridge for each, and their suppers were made up of the same
                            material. For dinner in addition to the bowl of porridge, the} enjoyed a little cake—a piece
                            two and a half inches square for each person One day a couple of the brethren wen to the
                            river to catch herring, and one o them was so pressed with hunger tha he ate, while yet raw,
                            the first two fis he caught! Their house-room was al so limited. Had but little convenienc
                            for lodging, and were obliged to slee upon the floor of their apartment Some few had a
                            blanket to cover them others had none. As the crops begai to mature, and potatoes were in
                            eata ble condition, their fare was better, anc life became more endurable. During the same
                            year, a famine pre vailed at Lake George. The citizen of Albany made quite a donation o:
                            provisions to the sufferers there ; anc the brethren of our little social bane were employed
                            to carry the said dona tion to Crown Point. On their way lither, they stopped at a small hut
                            in he woods, by the roadside, to obtain a ittle refreshment. They found there n old woman,
                            with three small chil[ren. On making their business known, he woman replied, " I have not
                            had a "nouthful of meat, bread, nor potatoes n my house for the past three months." When
                            asked what she subsisted upon, she replied, " When the brier-leaves Degan to mature in the
                            spring, I gathered, boiled, and ate them with my nilk, for I have one cow, and that supports
                            us. This is the way we have lived for three months past?" With the money the brethren
                            received "or carrying said donation, they purchased bread and flour, and our people were
                            soon comfortable. Their crops came in more bountifully than was expected, and by the smiles
                            of providence upon them, they soon began to improve n health, strength, and in many earthly
                            comforts. They were often exhorted ry Joseph Meacham,—a very influential and leading member
                            among them, who was afterwards styled Father Joseph,— to bear their sufferings with patience
                            and fortitude, for the time would come when they and their children would have plenty and to
                            spare. Shakers, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cloud of witnesses" TEIform="index"/>The Cloud of Witnesses</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Tilton, Theodore" TEIform="persName"/>THEODORE TILTON</byline><p TEIform="p">"Are they not all ministering spirits ?" I leaned upon a burial urn, And thought how life is
                            but a day; And how the nations, each in turn, Have lived and passed away. The earth is
                            peopled with the dead, Who live again in deathless hosts; Who come and go with noiseless
                            tread, A universe of ghosts. They follow after flying ships, They flicker through the city's
                            marts, They hear the cry of human lips, The beat of human hearts. They linger not around
                            their tombs, But far from churchyards keep aloof; To dwell in old familiar rooms, Beneath
                            the household roof. They waken men at morning light, They cheer them in their daily care;
                            They bring a weary world at night To bend the knee in prayer. Their errand is of God
                            assigned, To comfort sorrow till it cease; And in the dark and troubled mind To light the
                            lamp of peace. There is a language whispered low, Whereby to mortal ears they speak; To
                            which we answer by a glow That kindles in the cheek. Dear shadows, fairer than the day; With
                            heavenly lights they wrap us round Wherein we walk a gilded way, And over holy ground. Oh,
                            what a wondrous life is theirs, To fling away the mortal frame; Yet keep the human loves and
                            cares And yearnings still the same. Oh, what a wondrous life is ours, To dwell within this
                            earthly range; Yet parley with the heavenly powers,—Two worlds in interchange! Oh, balm of
                            grief, to understand That whom our eyes behold no more till clasps us with as true a hand As
                            in the flesh before. ^o longer in a gloom profound Let memory, like a mourner craped, Sit
                            weeping by an empty mound, Whose captive hath escaped. So, turning from the burial urn, I
                            thought how life has double worth, f men be only wise to learn That heaven is on the
                        earth.</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">HE SHAKER Monthly—60 cents per annum. A DUAL ADVOCATE OF CHRIST PRINCIPLES.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lift up the standard" TEIform="index"/>Lift up the Standard</head><p TEIform="p">The world complains mostly of Shaker celibacy, because it is not of the world. Even from our
                            bitterest enemies, however, we find vice paying tribute to virtue, by the remark: "Their
                            virgin celibacy is a very high order of life !" This is a verbatim sentence from the expose
                            of a rabid secessionist. But why ind so much fault, when forced finallv to so much
                            admiration? Why is Jesus, the Christ, so much admired? Was it not, and is it not for the
                            same reasons ;hat the Shakers are persecuted in pubic, and admired i i the closet of prayer?
                            Should not like causes be honored similarly ! Jesus, his disciples, and the Shakers are not
                            such antipodes that they should be used so differently. Jesus offered salvation on the same
                            terms which the Shakers now do—" Stop your sinning!" "Live unto God, die unto sin ! " But
                            our celibacy runs crosswise unresurrected human nature. Die the same of Jesus agree with
                            this nature any better? And yet, for the same specialty, the world adores Jesus—01 pretends
                            to—and dreads the Shakers O, consistency ! The gospel of Jesu relieved the poor of their
                            poverty, anc demanded that the rich should reverse the rule of robbery, and take from then
                            only that which made them uncomfort able, by adding of their stores ! Jus so with the
                            Shakers, where none are rich, and certainly none are poor. Bu while the world pretends an
                            admira tion of this leveling work of Jesus a/ic Pentecost, they do not want to admir these
                            features in the Shakers. The Prince of Peace is worshiped mentally; and the Shakers
                            condemned practically, because they do just that which made Jesus the Prince of Peace !
                            Hence, the world honors General----as a Christian gentleman ; and the Shakers, who would not
                            help him slay ten thousands, are by it unhonored, unworthy to be called Christian ; and yet,
                            wherein does Gen.------resemble Jesus, the Christ! O, consistency, fie! Is there not good
                            reason in our being more radical than all other so-called Christians ; and to raise up the
                            standard of Christianity in its true colors. Therefore, say we : Live as you please ; but do
                            not confound marriage, nor sexual lusts with the celibacy of Jesus, nor of those who live
                            like him. Selfishly leap up the good things of this world ; but do not think yourselves
                            worthy to be fellowshipped with those of old, nor to-day, who truly say and practice: "Lo !
                            we have left all to follow thee !" Have your wars,—of household, state, and nation ; but do
                            not, for Christianity's sake, think for a moment there is any Christ about them, nor that
                            any Christian ever did or will engage in them. These are some of the radicals of Shakerism.
                            They are arrived at by simple acts of self-denial toward the lusts of the flesh, the lusts
                            for money, pride of life, and lusts for power ! " Can these Shakers be Christians?"</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker, to whom it may concern" TEIform="index"/>The Shaker, TO WHOM IT MAY CONCERN</head><p TEIform="p">Be Lawful.—If leaders do not regard this, who can they expect will do so ? A Shaker eldership
                            is a place of care, example, practical wisdom, and deep, parental solicitude; not one of
                            nere authority, right or wrong ; but of neekness, charity, long forbeai'ance. True, wise
                            elders drown differences of brethren, with their sunshine, wisdom and love. Be Prudent.—If
                            those who are first in care of temporal things are not the greatest servants unto prudence,
                            who can they expect will be? The doctrine of "Don't do as I do, but as I say or wish," never
                            worked any better among the Shakers than elsewhere. An honest trustee will be first in
                            prudence, first in the comforts, and first in the burdens of the heart, of his brethren. A
                            real honest Shaker trustee truly feels and acts like the poorest man or woman in the
                            commune. How is this? Be Pure.—If, by our words or deeds, we are not so, do we not belie our
                            profession ? and do we not testify against mere profession, without practice? Be
                            Peaceable.—This follows as a matter of course ; and means a peace wrought by righteous
                            elders, trustees, and golden-rule-loving brethren and sisters. It does not mean the
                            consequences of inequality, insult, tyranny, and subjugation—where these are, he who
                            preaches peace, preaches in vain. Be Brethren.—All the trouble that can arise, after fully
                            consecrating one's self to the fundamental principles of Shakerism, comes from the neglect
                            of compliance with the "golden rule." Would it not be a healthy question for us all to ask
                            ourselves: " How would we bear our conduct, if practiced on us by others, as we exercise it
                            on others ourselves?"</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers" TEIform="index"/>The Shakers</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The friends have often asked us to give our ideas about universal celibacy as
                                    promulgated and practiced by the Shakers. Without touching upon any other portions
                                    of the creed of this honest, industrious class of thinkers, our answer js that if
                                    what they promulgate is really the truest and best to live by, as they claim, then
                                    every human being in Christendom should adopt it; which, if they did, as a sequence,
                                    in about thirty-five years, the average of human life, there would not exist a human
                                    being on the face of the broad earth, with the exception of a few oldish^ <pb n="28" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 38 THE SHAKER. looking stragglers, who may have outlived the general
                                    average. Complete and total annihilation would be the inevitable result.— L. Judd
                                    Pardee, a spirit, in Voice of Angels.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Voice of angels" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">There is no doubt that Shakerism answers a wise purpose. There are features
                                    connected with the same that excite our admiration, and they surely have a
                                    beneficial effect on the outside world. Of course, no one supposes that the whole
                                    world will become converted to that faith.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="R. P. journal" TEIform="index"/>R. P. Journal.</bibl></cit> Thus again, we are called to add "line upon line " in regard to our testimony of
                            celibacy. And this is not the only instance in which " spirits in prison" have needed light
                            on gospel economy. We believe the first of the above articles to be a genuine communication
                            from the spirit-world, and it proves that spirits are only transferred mortals, and do not
                            know very much more for the transfer. L. Judd Pardee is a spirit-editor. In this life, he
                            knew fully as much of Shaker testimony as he appears now to know. Only a short time since, a
                            life-long student of communism, a master-mind in logical deductions, wrote of the Shakers: "
                            Your reproductive organs are the offending members," etc. This is wrong. We never have
                            promulgated universal celibacy; and confine our preaching to those only "who are able" so to
                            live. This is reasonable. While we testify that the reproductive functions have been worst
                            abused of any, it is not on this account that we abstain from their lower, primitive uses.
                            If every engagement of them would produce a perfectly " sound mind in a healthy body," and
                            these every child has a right to demand, and none other should be conceived nor born,—even
                            then the practice is "of the earth, earthy," and has no part with " the Lord from heaven,"
                            is unworthy of Christ; and those who practice sexual indulgences and engage in reproductions
                            are not Christians ! We have no controversy with worldly reproductions, per se. If they were
                            better than they are, the gradation to a Shaker life therefrom would be easier and more
                            plentiful. We practice celibacy, well-knowing that the vast majority of the world cannot be,
                            is not fit to be candidatures of Shakerism ! We do not preach celibacy as right for all,
                            very few of the all being worthy or capable of it. But we stand with outstretched hands to
                            welcome all who "are able, for the kingdom of heaven's sake," to live like him who was the
                            pattern of Christians,—a specimen of the heavens on earth. Who will accept our invitation ?
                            And who will do us the justice, the right, to present us correctly before the world of
                            readers? R. P. y., we thank you. L. Judd Pardee, spirits disembodied, and yet embodied, take
                            notice, that we not only do not preach universal celibacy, but consider the number able and
                            worthy to be candidates therefor, to be so few as scarcely to keep our organizations in
                            healthy conditions ! And who is to blame? See "Particular Notice" on page 34, this No. of
                            The Shaker.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Are the shakers spiritualists?" TEIform="index"/>Are the Shakers Spiritualists?</head><p TEIform="p">[From "Plain Talks."] We are the most radical spiritualists of our day. We are thoroughly
                            convinced of spirit communication and interpositions, spirit guidance, and obsession. Our
                            spiritualism has permitted us to converse, face to face, with individuals once mortals, some
                            of whom we well knew, and with others born Defore the flood. All spiritual phenomena
                            commonly occurring in the world had an inauguration among us, ong before the " Rochester
                            Rappings." 3y our spiritualism we are become :onfirmed infidels to the foolish bodily
                            'esurrection theory; to the untrue and disappointing atonement doctrine ; to the monstrous
                            trinity scheme ; to the cruel predestination belief, and all the man-made creeds of the
                            popular churches professing Christianity. We are sure these things are untrue, and we have
                            had hundreds of testimonies Tom those who, when in the body, were as firm in the belief of
                            their verity as any can be now, but who were bitterly disappointed on arrival in the spirit
                            world. We have progressed beyond mere physical phenomena to learn that these are very
                            insignificant, cornDared with the truths leading to the ligher life of the spirit. " Walk in
                            the spirit, and not fulfill the lusts of the 3esh." We ai-e preparing to enter the ranks of
                            spirits who, before their departure from earth, or since, learned to practice the
                            injunctions of Christianity, thorough self-denial to all sensual pleasures. Thousands there
                            really need their bodies to be as happy as before death ; while tens of thousands obsess
                            mortals here, that through the indulgence of their bodies in intemperance, tobacco, theft,
                            trade, lusts of the eye, and the lascivious indulgence of the flesh, and the elements of
                            anger, etc., they may and do obtain pleasures, which death has placed beyond their natural
                            reach. Spiritualism is a light; let no one use it so that their light will become darkness.
                            And let spiritualists not prostitute the name by living in the fruitful nor unfruitful works
                            oi darkness, since they are called to be the children of light, and to be lifted up for a
                            guide to their, as yet, not so favored brethren.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>EDITORIAL NOTES</head><p TEIform="p">We begin in this number the publication of a series of papers by D. A. Buckingham, the
                            venerable presiding elder of the society at Watervliet. Beginning almost at the earliest
                            date of the Watervliet settlement, these papers will bring us down to the present time ; and
                            will give, in epitome, the history of what is now Shakers, N. Y. We have long desired such
                            an undertaking by some competent hand, and we shall be greatly surprised if our readers are
                            not greatly interested. We ask particular attention to the grand differences! what we have
                            long waited for—written articles for The Shaker ! In fact, it Many are very anxious to place
                            children under the protecting wings of Shakerism. Orphans, made so by death, or worse, have
                            for many years 3een accepted by us, and we have had large hopes that our gospel would
                            recreate them before original nature took command. In more than ninety-nine of one hundred
                            cases we have been mistaken ! Confidence in the power of our system has made us very
                            careless of the pedigree and antenatal conditions of children. Our carelessness has wrought
                            us an incomputable ruin. Those who have confidence, that by putting the children of gross
                            parentage among the Shakers, they will grow up to be angels, may be assured, that our
                            sorrowful experience is, that they are wrong. Often before school-days are over, exhibitions
                            of devils as big as woodchucks, at least, are illustrated. We must have the best manufacture
                            of humanity, or we cannot long exist as a flourishing institution. The very best of us had
                            an origin sufficiently poor to magnify Shakerism to any considerable degree, and to keep us
                            continually fighting outspurts of unheavenly dispositions. Under the head of "
                            Correspondence" will be found some of the early fruit of answers to the question : "What
                            shall I do to be a Shaker?" We commend the whole letter, zeal, and consecrated ability of
                            Sister McLaughlin ; which, so long as it is continued, wrill be worthy of intense emulation.
                            The honor of suggesting answers to the above question, belongs to Eldress Johanna Kaime ;
                            and the wonder is, it was not prosecuted before. We hope it is not as difficult for sincere
                            inquirers to get verbal answers from novitiate elders, as for us to get written ones ! We
                            hope, ere long, that we shall all become properly educated spiritually, in regard to our
                            duty to our fellows. We hope to realize, that whatsoever i, done for the furtherance of The
                            Shaker's spread, maintenance, and improvement, by those of its faith, will not be done
                            grudgingly, nor as an especiaj favor. If The Shaker is an organ for the promulgation of
                            truth, it is duty that we yield all selfish interests for the accomplishment of that end.
                            Some may be bold enough to say sometimes: " Oh, Lord, don't you remember, when we helped
                            your cause ?" It is our cause ; let us sustain it. Notice to Assessors.—Friends: We entirely
                            lost sight of your unwelcome presence, when, in the March number of The Shaker, we
                            enthusiastically told to the world, how very rich every Shaker was, and how very unselfish
                            with it all. We here enter an apology and explanation to you, and to those beloved deacons
                            of the Shaker church who have, by our blunder, done of conditions under which the gospel,
                            according to Ann Lee, has been kept and now is kept. greatly relieves the pangs we feel for
                            the mistake, to receive so many goocChristian threshings from so many excellent Christian
                            deacons. We amend the objectionable paragraph by saying ' millions of dollars' worth of more
                            than money "—gospel riches ! upon which, friendly or unfriendly assessors, you cannot affix
                            your tax, amen ! You lave ever rated Shaker property highst compared with their neighbors',
                            ind to this extent have persecuted us "or our faith's sake. Accept our apology and
                            explanation, and, gospel friends all, please forgive us.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>THE CHILDREN'S GROTTO</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My dear boys and girls:" TEIform="index"/>My dear boys and girls :</head><p TEIform="p">Among the best hings to be made into thoughts by you, is :arefulness. Have a care for all
                                things A'ith which you meet. With your friends and companions, be full of care to use
                                them as you like to be used. With the lower aninals have a care of kindness as I have
                                heretofore written you. Remember to be careful of your books; they cost money, and
                                some)ody, or many, have to be careful to get the money. Be careful of your clothes: how
                                wrong to be careless of what costs so much time to earn money to buy, and labor to make
                                ! A rent in a garment, carelessly made, not only makes work you might have saved for
                                those who love you, but disfigures the garment before it should be so, and inspires you
                                to care less for it than before! Is this not so ? I love to see a boy or girl, who is
                                not ashamed to wear well-mended clothes, particularly when they have been careful of
                                them before they came to mending. I know [ cannot expect you to be like older folk, but
                                you may be even more careful than some older ones, who were careless when they were
                                children ! Do not go in the water with your boots nor shoes when you can avoid it; water
                                destroys leather. Be careful of your food, do not waste it. There is enough food wasted
                                every day, by those who were careless when children, to feed all the hungry in the
                                world! God has been, and now is good to all. There is enough for all to eat, drink and
                                wear, and to spare. If all would be careful,—full of care for those who have not been so
                                fortunate, then all would be cared for, and this would be a happier world. Be careful
                                not to be selfish! Whoever is very selfish, is a robber of that which belongs to another
                                or others; and is wasteful and careless of God-given blessings. Be careful of your
                                health, of your voices; and shun evil companions; thus have a care for your hearts. Do
                                not let angry nor cruel thoughts stay one moment in your minds. How shall you get rid of
                                them? Why, sing a song, talk to a flower; think of some sweet, pretty circumstance that
                                happened yesterday; run, jump at the sun, or try to catch a star; do either, and your
                                angry thoughts are gone by this exercise of care. Be very careful to be good as you know
                                how, and be assured God will care for you.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="L., G. A." TEIform="persName"/>G. A. L.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>EVERGREEN SHORES</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kaime, John" TEIform="index"/>John Kaime
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Kaime, John" TEIform="persName">John Kaime</persName>, aged 85, at Canterbury, N. H., Feb.
                                26, 1877.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Walker, Jacob" TEIform="index"/>Jacob Walker
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Walker, Jacob" TEIform="persName">Jacob Walker</persName>, aged 72, at North Union, O., Feb.
                                19, 1877.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Osment, John" TEIform="index"/>John Osment
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Harvard, March —, <persName reg="Osment, John" TEIform="persName">John Osment</persName>, 75.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Swazey, Joseph" TEIform="index"/>Joseph Swazey
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Harvard, March 28, <persName reg="Swazey, Joseph" TEIform="persName">Joseph Swazey'</persName>, 59. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>BOOK TABLE</head><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker doctrine" TEIform="index"/>Shaker doctrine
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Shaker Doctrine. Any one who desires to know precisely what the Shaker
                                        doctrine is, should procure and read a copy of a neat little pamphlet written by
                                        Elder George Albert Lomas, and printed at the office of The Shaker, Shakers, N.
                                        Y. The title of this pamphlet is, " What Shall I do to be a Shaker? or Plain
                                        Talks upon, Practical Religion, being Answers to Earnest Inquirers." It is <pb n="39" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/>a curious production, and gives a better idea of the
                                        teachings of those peculiar people, than can be elsewhere obtained in the same
                                        compass.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Albany evening times" TEIform="index"/>Albany Evening Times.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Practical treatise on vocal on physiology" TEIform="index"/></head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Guilmette, Charles A" TEIform="persName"/>Dr. Charles Alex. Guilmette</byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">We have received from the publisher, C. C. Pearson, Concord, N. H., a noble volume,
                                entitled, ilA Practical Treatise on Vocal Physiology." It is the result of years of
                                study, by that musical adept and scholar, Dr. Chas. Alex. Guilmette. It is recommended
                                to universal study by the first musicians of our country, and will soon bear fruit of as
                                just a criticism over the waters in other lands. That it has long been needed, every one
                                who reads it, will be at once convinced. We have given it a casual reading; but will
                                only be satisfied by a thorough acquaintance. We recommend this work to every Shaker in
                                our land, and to all the Shakers of the future. That it will be extensively appreciated,
                                there can be no doubt. Shaker societies may address N. A. Briggs, our publisher, with
                                advantage, in ordering it. Its price is $1.50, only.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Items</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="South Union, Kentucky" TEIform="index"/>South. Union, Ky.</head><p TEIform="p">A fire at South Union, Ky., Junior Order, destroyed the cow-barn with all its contents.
                                Loss some thousands. The work of careless, smoking tramps. Cattle saved.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="North Union, Ohio" TEIform="index"/>North Union, O. </head><p TEIform="p">is contemplating the sale of some lands contiguous to the city of Cleveland, for some
                                public benefit. If we correctly situate it, their price, $300 per acre, is very cheap.
                                Scarcely any but municipal authorities appear to have money nowadays. We are glad to
                                learn of the convalescence of Bros. Steadman and Allard of Enfield, N. H., and sorry to
                                hear that Elder H. S. Kellogg of Enfield, Conn., lies dangerously near the confines of
                                our world at present. And yet, why do we say dangerously? From all accounts, "The
                                Ministry's Home" at Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., resembles one of those many mansions of the
                                upper regions. Be it so. Don't let any society neglect the perusal and study of Dr. C.
                                A. Guilmette's Vocal Physiology.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Useful glen" TEIform="index"/>THE USEFUL GLEN</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">An Invaluable Hint. Soon the farmers generally will be engaged in plowing. We
                                    wish, now, to inform farmers of a fact so simple that they will wonder why they had
                                    not thought of it before. A fact so useful to know, that it will, on trial, be
                                    considered invaluable. Believing that it belongs to farmers without the restriction
                                    of a patent, we first make it known. It is the discovery of R. M. Wagan, of Mt.
                                    Lebanon Shakers, N. Y. It wholly concerns the coulter. Invariably this has been
                                    applied obliquely, pointing away from the plow. Reverse this position of the
                                    coulter, give it a drawing instead of a pushing cut, and strange as will appear on
                                    trial, you save at least one horsepower ! We never use a knife in cutting as we
                                    apply and use the coulter. Run your knife through a bar of soap as the coulter is
                                    commonly used in the sod; then draw your knife through the soap, and some idea of
                                    this invaluable hint will be apparent. By making this public, we preclude the
                                    possibility of its being patented. Now, farmers, send our publisher a club of
                                    subscribers for The Shaker ; for, on trial of the above hint, you can well afford to
                                    do so. Stable Floors. The Scientific Farmer says of stable floors that it is common
                                    to pitch them back from one to four inches for purposes of drainage. This is all
                                    wrong. Any inclination to the rear is injurious, for the reason that the oes of the
                                    animals are thereby turned up, and the back sinews, especially of the foreegs, kept
                                    in a sort of unnatural tension. If here is any pitch at all in the floor, it should
                                    be to the front instead of the back. Weights and Measures. Number of founds to the
                                    bushel recognized by the United States. Wheat..... 60 Shelled corn .... 56 Ear corn
                                    ..... 70 Rye . . . . . . 56 Oats...... 32 Barley ..... 47 Irish potatoes . . . . 60
                                    Sweet potatoes ... 56 White beans .... 60 Castor beans .... 46 Clover-seed .... 60
                                    Timothy-seed .... 45 Flax-seed .... 56 Hemp-seed .... 44 Millet-seed .... 50 Peas
                                    ..... 60 Bran ..... 20 Coke ..... 22 Blue-grass .... 44 Buckwheat .... 50 Dried
                                    peaches .... 38 Dried apples .... 24 Onions ..... 55 Salt ...... 70 Stone coal ....
                                    80 Malt..... 38 Plastering hair ... 8 Turnips..... 55 Unslacked lime ... 30 Corn
                                    meal .... 48 Fine salt ..... 55 Hungarian grass-seed . . 50 Ground peas .... 24
                                    Charcoal ..... 30 Hominy ..... 60 A box 24x16 in. 22 in. deep, holds 1 barrel 16x16
                                    1-2 8 1 bush. 8x11 1-2 8 1-2 1 peck. 4X 4 1-2 4 1-4 1-2 peck Tea and Coffee.— Shaker
                                    sisters not )Tet having been entirely eliminated from the former; nor Shaker
                                    brethren thoroughly disgusted, as yet, with the latter, we charitably offer the
                                    following for their benefit; making no objection to the extension of.the prudence :
                                    "A method has been discovered for making more than the usual quantity of tea from
                                    any given quantity of the leaf. The whole secret consists in steaming the leaf
                                    before steeping. By this process, it is said, fourteen pints of good quality may be
                                    brewed from one ounce of tea." "Delmonico uses one and a hali pounds of coffee to a
                                    gallon of water pouring the hot water upon the coffee which is placed in a strainer.
                                    The 1 coffee is never boiled."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New York herald" TEIform="index"/>N. Y. Herald.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>LIFE THOUGHTS</head><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Equalization of emotion" TEIform="index"/>Equalizaton of emotion</head><p TEIform="p">There 3 is no worldly gain without some' loss I so there is no worldly loss without some
                                s gain. If thou hast lost thy wealth, thoi r hast lost some trouble with it; if thou art
                                degraded from honor, thou art like wise freed from the stroke of envy; i sickness has
                                blurred thy beauty, it hath delivered thee from pride. Set the al lowance against the
                                loss, and thou shal find no loss great. He loses little or 3 nothing that reserves
                                himself. Com s passion is an emotion of which we ought never to be ashamed.—Graceful,
                                particularly in youth, is the tear of sympathy, and the heart that melts at the ale of
                                woe. We should not permit ease and indulgence to contract our affections, and wrap us up
                                in selfish enoyment; but we should accustom ourselves to think of the distress of human
                                life, of the solitary cottage, the dying parent, and the weeping orphan. Nor ought we
                                ever to sport with pain and distress in any of our amusements, nor treat even the
                                meanest insect with wanton cruelty.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Blair" TEIform="persName"/>Blair</byline></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mere physical good-looks fade..." TEIform="index"/>Mere physical good-looks fade...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Mere physical good-looks fade with the years, bleach out with sickness, and yield to the
                                slow decay of mortality. But the beauty that has its origin in kind dispositions, noble
                                purposes and great thoughts, outlasts youth and maturity, increases with years, and like
                                the luscious peach which comes to us in autumn ripeness, covered with the delicate flush
                                of purple and crimson, is never so beautiful as when waiting to be plucked by the
                                gatherer's hand, silently witnessing to the full, the rich perfections time works out.—
                                Tales Co. Chronicle. Spiritualism teaches the golden rule of righteousness, and its
                                certain reward in eternal happiness; it tells us that evil deeds are sure of their
                                punishment; and it at the same time brings the great revelation to man that all will be
                                ultimately saved to enduring happiness, through expiation, suffering, and purification
                                of the spirit.</p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="More offend from want of thought than from any want of feeling..." TEIform="index"/>More offend from want of thought than from any want of feeling...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Time to me this truth hath taught— 'T is a truth that's worth revealing— More offend from
                                want of thought Than from any want of feeling. If advice we would convey, There's a time
                                we should convey it; If we 've but a word to say, There's a time in which to say it.</p><byline TEIform="byline">— <persName reg="Swan, Charles" TEIform="persName"/>Charles Swan</byline></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let us be assured that the noblest life makes the happiest death..." TEIform="index"/>Let us be assured that the noblest life makes the happiest death...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Let us be assured that the noblest life makes the happiest death ; and that he lives the
                                noblest who sacrifices most for his fellow-men, whose life is most devoted to what he
                                conceives to be the truth.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Clark, David H." TEIform="persName"/>Rev. David H. Clark</byline></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enemies" TEIform="index"/>Enemies</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Have you enemies? Go straight on, and mind them not. If they block up your
                                        path, walk arounc them, and do your duty regardless o: their spite. A man who
                                        has no enemies is seldom good for anything; h is made of that kind of material
                                        whici is so easily worked that everyone has a hand in it. A sterling
                                        character—on who thinks for himself, and speak what he thinks—is always sure to
                                        hav enemies. They are as necessary to him as fresh air; they keep him alive anc
                                        active. A celebrated character, who was surrounded with enemies, used to remark:
                                        "They are sparks which, i: you do not blow, will go out of them selves." Let
                                        this be your feeling whil endeavoring to live down the scanda of those who are
                                        bitter against you. I: you stop to dispute, you do but as they desire, and open
                                        the way for more abuse. Let the poor fellows talk ; there will be a reaction if
                                        you perform but your duty, and hundreds who were once alienated from you will
                                        flock to you and acknowledge their error.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Alexander's messenger" TEIform="index"/>Alexander's Messenger.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to treat insect stings" TEIform="index"/>HOW TO TREAT INSECT STINGS</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The pain caused by the sting of a plant or insect is the result of a certain
                                        amount of acid poison injected into the blood. The first thing to be done is to
                                        press the tube of a small key firmly on ths wound, moving the key from side to
                                        side to facilitate the expulsion of the sting and its accompanying poison. The
                                        sting, if left in the wound, should be carefully extracted, otherwise it will
                                        greatly increase the local irritation. The poison of stings being acid, common
                                        sense points to the alkalies as the proper means of cure. Among the most easily
                                        procured remedies may be mentioned, soft soap, liquor of ammonia, (spirits of
                                        hartshorn,) smelling salts, washing soda, quicklime made into paste with water,
                                        lime water, the juice of an onion, tobacco juice, chewed tobacco, bruised dock
                                        leaves, tomato juice, wood ashes, tobacco ash, and carbonate of soda. If the
                                        sting be severe, rest and coolness should be added to the other remedies, more
                                        especially in the case of nervous subjects. Nothing is so apt to make the poison
                                        active as heat, and nothing favors its activity less than cold. Let the body be
                                        kept cool and at rest, and the activity of the poison will be reduced to a
                                        minimum. Any active exertion whereby the circulation is quickened will increase
                                        both pain and swelling. If the swelling be severe, the part may be rubbed with
                                        sweet oil, or a drop or two of laudanum. Stings in the eye, ear, mouth, or
                                        throat, sometimes lead to serious consequences ; in such cases, medical advice
                                        should always be sought as soon as possible.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="London garden." TEIform="index"/> London Garden.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Darwinism [part 1 of 2]" TEIform="index"/>Darwinism</head><p TEIform="p">Carlyle is now very feeble through age, but his memory is still marvelous, and the flow
                                of his talk—doubtless the most eloquent of the age—is unabated. Take this as a sample :
                                " I have known three generations of the Darwins: grandfather, father and son. Atheists
                                all. The brother of the present famous naturalist, a quiet man, who lives not far from
                                here, told me that among his grandfather's effects he found a seal engraven with this
                                legend : 'O-rnnia ex conchis;' everything from a clam-shell! I saw the naturalist not
                                many months ago ; told him that I had read his ' Origin of the Species,' and other books
                                ; that he had by no means satisfied me that men were descendants from monkeys, but had
                                gone far toward persuading me that he and his so-called scientific brethren had brought
                                the present generation of Englishmen very near to monkeys. "A good sort of a man is this
                                Darwin, and well-meaning, but with very little intellect. Ah, it is a sad and ter</p></div3><pb n="40" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God's blessing" TEIform="index"/>GOD'S BLESSING</head><p TEIform="p">Canterbury, N. H. 1. As the dew of the morning, Or as bright rivers roll; So so does
                                God's 2. As the dawn of the morning, Or a heavenly ray; His glorious blessing Flow into
                                my soul. I'll walk ia his presence A3 brightness IIlumines my way. I'll sing of his
                                favor, I'll one greatly blessed; On whose soul the love of His work is impressed. merit
                                his love; By honest endeavor My loyalty prove.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Darwinism [part 2 of 2]" TEIform="index"/>Darwinism</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">rible thing to see nigh a whole generation of men and women professing to be
                                        cultivated, looking around in a purblind fashion, and finding no God in this
                                        universe. I suppose it is a reaction from the reign of cant and hollow pretence,
                                        professing to believe what in fact they do not believe. And this is what we have
                                        got to. All things from frog spawn ; the gospel of dirt the order of the day.
                                        The older I grow—and I now stand upon the brink of eternity—the more comes back
                                        to me the sentence of the catechism, which I learned when a child, and the
                                        fuller and the deeper its meaning becomes: 'What is the chief end cf man?' 'To
                                        glorify God and to enjoy Him forever.' No gospel of dirt, teachitig that men
                                        have descended from frogs through monkeys, can - ever set that aside."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Hartford courant" TEIform="index"/>Hartford Courant</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Shaker, G. A. Lomas, Editor, Shakers, N. Y...." TEIform="index"/>The Shaker, G. A. Lomas, Editor, Shakers, N. Y....
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The Shaker, G. A. Lomas, Editor, Shakers, N. Y., is the official monthly
                                        organ of the united societies of that faith, and a very good-looking and
                                        intelligent exponent of its material and spiritual interests. Founded by that
                                        Christly woman, Ann Lee, originally a Manchester (Eng.) factory-girl, whom they
                                        regard as the spiritual peer of Jesus, this wide-spread order of modern
                                        socialism presents many features of absorbing interest to students of love and
                                        labor reform. The Shaker is sent, post-paid, to any address, for 6o cents per
                                        annum.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Word " TEIform="index"/>The Word, Princeton, Mass. </bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sound criticism" TEIform="index"/>Sound Criticism</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">In his sermon at the Tabernacle, Rev. Phillips Brooks said, as reported,
                                        that, "the great part of life, after becoming a Christian, will be spent as
                                        before; we shall buy and sell and get gain ; but the purposes are all changed."
                                        How the life remains the same, when the purposes are changed, we do not see. If
                                        religion does not change the life, what good does it do to change the purposes?
                                        We of course would not judge of a preacher's whole doctrine by a single sentence
                                        ; but this statement is a good picture of the practical effects of the popular
                                        religion. With all its professions, rites, and observances, it makes no special
                                        or permanent improvement in a person's character and conduct. A man is persuaded
                                        that he has had his heart or life " sanctified," when there has been no change
                                        in the impulses or aims of either ; and the result is, that though there are
                                        very good people in the church, the main difference between the "ins" and "outs"
                                        is a certain flavor or conceit of piety. That religion makes no change in the
                                        life, and we can buy and sell and get gain—and a good deal of it—as well after
                                        as before becoming Christians, may be popular and pleasing gospel; but to our
                                        view religion must go deeper than that.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New age" TEIform="index"/>New Age</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The story of Lot's wife, whether we accept it literally or allegorically..." TEIform="index"/>The story of Lot's wife, whether we accept it literally or allegorically...
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., A. A." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> The story of Lot's wife, whether we accept it literally or allegorically,
                                        suggests a wholesome truth. We might as well be pillars of salt, or something
                                        far less valuable, as to be forever looking backward with regrets. Continual
                                        right-doing in the present is the best reparation for an unsatisfactory past.
                                        The angular duties of to-day may be ripened and rounded into pleasures if we put
                                        the wine of loving hearts and the strength of willing hands into them. And the
                                        wayside pleasures, so insignificant of themselves, sometimes, that we fail to
                                        notice them, often assume the dignity of duties when relatively considered. And
                                        when the busy day has given place to the leisure of twilight, instead of groping
                                        among the yesterdays for the wan face of a dead or dying sorrow, or gazing with
                                        horror upon the hateful features of some sin committed in the fever of passion
                                        or the blindness of ignorance, were it not better to take kindly thought for the
                                        morrows? Whose sorrows shall we soothe ? Whose heavy weight uplift ? Whose
                                        bitter cup sweeten? Ah! time has healing and wondrous compensations for the
                                        brave and faithful who journey on unmindful of their own heart-aches and wounds
                                        without cause.—A. A. W. in New Age. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New age" TEIform="index"/>New Age</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Germination from old seed" TEIform="index"/>Germination from old seed</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">In the silver mines of Laurium, only the slags left by the ancient Greeks are
                                        at present worked off", in order to gain, after an improved modern method,
                                        silver still left in that dross. This refuse ore is probably about two thousand
                                        years old. Among it, the seed of a species of glaucium, or poppy, was found,
                                        which had slept in the darkness of the earth during all that time. After a
                                        little while, when the slags were brought up and worked off at the melting
                                        ovens, there suddenly arose a crop of glaucium plants, with a beautiful yellow
                                        flower, of a kind unknown to modern botany, but which is described by Pliny and
                                        others as a frequent flower in ancient Greece.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="London examiner" TEIform="index"/>London Examiner</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mystery" TEIform="index"/>A Mystery</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Whittier, John G." TEIform="persName"/>JOHN G. WHITTIER</byline><p TEIform="p">The river hemmed with leaning trees Wound through its meadows green; A low, blue line of
                            mountains Showed the open pines between. One sharp, tall peak above them all Clear into
                            sunlight sprang; I saw the river of my dreams, The mountains that I sang! No clew of memory
                            led me on, But well the ways I knew; A feeling of familiar things With every footstep grew.
                            Not otherwise above irs crag Could lean the blasted pine; Not otherwise the maple hold Aloft
                            its red ensign. So up the long and shorn foothills The mountain road should creep; So green
                            and low, the meadow fold Its red-haired kine asleep. The river wound as it should wind;
                            Their place the mountains took. The white, torn fringes of their clouds Wore no unwonted
                            look. Yet ne'er before that river's rim Was pressed by feet of mine; Never before mine eyes
                            had crossed That broken mountain line. A presence, strange at once and known, Walked with me
                            as my guide ; The skirts of some forgotten life Trailed noiseless at my side. Was it a
                            dim-remembered dream? Or glimpse through aeons old? The secret which the mountains kept, The
                            river never told. But from the vision ere it passed A tender hope I drew, And, pleasant as a
                            dawn of spring, The thought within me grew, That love would temper every change, And soften
                            all surprise, And, misty with the dreams of earth, The hills of Heaven arise.</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>