<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm0911" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title><editor role="editor" TEIform="editor"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/></editor></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">9</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">11</biblScope><date value="18791101" TEIform="date">November 1879</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">241-264</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="9" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="11" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                    <pb id="p1"/>
                    <p>MANIFESTO. (OFFICIAL MONTHLY.) Q. A. LOMAS, Editoe. Published by the United Societies. OUK HOME AT HARVARD, MASS.
                        "And they shall turn to you for a testimony: " ''Go preach the Kingdom of God/" 4 ADDRESS ALL COMMUNICATIONS TO "The
                        Shaker Manifesto, Shakers, N.D." G. B. AVERY, PUBLISHER. 1879. Vol. IX. No. 11. MEMBER, 1879, 60 Cents Per Annum.
                        The Shaker</p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
--><pb n="241" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Intolerance" TEIform="index"/>INTOLERANCE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/>ANTOINETTE DOOLITTLE</byline><p TEIform="p">It is very interesting as well as painful, to trace the historic events of the past, and note
                            the action of the human mind in its growth and development from age to age, and mark the
                            changes that have been wrought. But we perceive through all, while Science and Reason have
                            forced their way and established a throne among men, higher and stronger than ignorance and
                            prejudice, still, human passion is the same to-day as in the ages long ago; and unrestrained
                            by law, and the progressive spirit which holds in check the tyrant's sceptre, whether
                            professedly swayed by politicians or theologians, would rekindle the fires of persecution,
                            and cause the strong to oppress the weak, the same now as in the days of the apostacy from
                            the first Christian Church. Then, great diversity of opinions arose, and confused ideas
                            concerning Deity; whether there was one God, two Gods, or a trinity of Gods; while Church
                            and State combined their powerful influence to repress thought, and bind the tongues and con
                            sciences of the people, and force them to bow to the decisions of the ecclesiastic synods.
                            And for trifling differences of opinions entertained, or expressed, such as whether Christ
                            was of two natures, or from two natures, which no one could intelligently define, and
                            entirely non-essentially, would serve to arouse prejudice, and cause a tempest of passion to
                            sweep as a wild wind through a dark forest. Again, when one claimed that Mary was mother of
                            one of the Gods, and another dissented therefrom, as did one Nestorius, who thought the idea
                            inconsistent and irreverent toward Deity ; for the candid expression of that thought,
                            although just in his dealings and upright in life, a council of ecclesiastics condemned and
                            banished him, and heaped anathemas upon him; and hoped that "his tongue might be gnawed away
                            with worms, and his soul gnawed eternally ;" and he died in exile on some lone island, or in
                            a barren desert. Agitators and heretics were numerous in those days, and it was said " that
                            every new heresy gave birth to some other new heresy ; " and thus the fires of persecution
                            were never suffered to die down. Thousands and tens of thousands of the pious clergy, draped
                            in the livery of the hierarchy of their time, and who Paul-like, verily thought they were
                            doing God service, were constantly on the alert to search out and punish heretics in the
                            most direful manner that human imagination, fired by brutal passion, could invent. In God's
                            name, and professedly for His honor and glory it was done ! Now, we shudder.at the thought
                            of such crimes as are recorded. Is not human nature the same in all ages ? Who can say that
                            the spirit of persecution is dead or " sleeps the sleep that knows no waking ? " Religious
                            intolerance has ever been most ruthless, and is far more to be dreaded than civil rule,
                            however rigid, when left independent to act in its own sphere, and move in its own orbit.
                            But when ecclesiastic leaders reach out their gloved hands to grasp the civil powers, and
                            seek to form an alliance, to wed and bind the two in one, then may the lovers of true
                            liberty tremble ! Under Church and State denomination, prison doors stand ajar ready to
                            receive heretics and infidels. That point gained, and every ism in the present, as in the
                            past, <pb n="242" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 242 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. would be tried and adjudged by the
                            most popular creed-bound standard of the time while the high priests would sit as judges and
                            the younger Christian (?) Associations just ripening into clerical manhood, would act as
                            jurors. If we would preserve religious liberty in its fullest, broadest sense, and give to
                            all races a home on American soil with freedom to think, and act, irrespective of the
                            opinions of others, subject to civil law only, we need to watch the juntos, the subtle,
                            secret, so-called religious conclaves, at the present time. And those who are clear-sighted
                            and able to see how cause and effect are related, should lift up their voices in defense of
                            true freedom. Let every man and woman be guided by their own reason, and be amenable to
                            their own consciences, and while they are law-abiding, and strictly regard the rights of
                            others, be free from persecution and oppression. May the testimony, like unto a " sharp
                            sword proceed out of the mouths " of God's witnesses, and ply between Church and State
                            governments. And while conceding the right of all religious denominations to combine their
                            efforts to evangelize the whole world, if they can, we urge the necessity of keeping the
                            civil and religious separate and distinct, as far as enacting and executing the civil law of
                            our common country is concerned. If the constitution of the United States government, was
                            framed by infidels (so-called) so let it remain. Let the clergy keep so far distant that
                            their flocks may not partake of the spirit of infidelity through our civil code and let the
                            law-makers, whatever their own religious views may be, know neither Greek, Jew, Gentile nor
                            Christian, as such to approve or condemn. Let each and all stand upon the basic foundation
                            of universal liberty, whether Infidel or Christian, within the pale of constitutional law.
                            Virtue and moral integrity are a staff upon which we may lean with safety, while wending our
                            way to the broad fields of endless progression, which are continually opening to view, as we
                            journey up the towering hills that rise above the plains where the sun of God's truth shines
                            brighter and clearer, and where myriads of purified spirits drink freely of those living
                            waters that flow from the eternal Fountain. Unselfishly do they give to others who follow
                            them, and extend a helping hand to aid their pilgrim brother and sister on their homeward
                            journey, in those spheres where human passions cease their ragings, and love refined from
                            dross bears rule. Truth alone will enable us to see eye to eye, and bring into harmonious
                            relation and action whatever is useful, good and true. The more we conserve Truth, the more
                            liberal we shall be, and the less disposed to oppose and persecute others for opinion's
                            sake. But let us beware of the hydraheaded monster, Religious Intolerance I</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Road to ruin" TEIform="index"/>THE ROAD TO RUIN</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL ORCUTT</byline><p TEIform="p">The history of many a wreck of body and soul, if written, would read something like this: " I
                            was my father's son, tender and only beloved in the sight of my mother. They indulged my
                            appetite and pampered my whims, instead of teaching me to control them. My career of
                            indulgence began with sweetmeats and confections. At the age of ten or twelve, I put away
                            these dainties for the more manly indulgencies of the cigar, the social glass. From these,
                            the way was short to the theater, the billiard room and the card table. My conduct separated
                            me from the society of the pure in heart; my vices made me the companion of the fallen and
                            depraved; my licentiousness ruined my health; my necessities forced me into falsehood,
                            dishonesty and robbery. And now I am without character, without friends without hope for
                            this world, or for that which is to come. Henceforth I have nothing to expect but a fearful
                            doom from the justice of God ! There is no hope. I will cast my lot with those who wait for
                            blood, and lurk privily for the innocent that they may fill their houses with spoil! " This
                            is the sad history of many a young man, who began "the downward way," with the seemingly
                            innocent mistake of making the aleasure of his appetite his guiding star, and with a
                            deviation from the straight path <pb n="243" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 243 so slight,
                            that even parental fondness unconsciously leads him into sin. He goes on, from one wrong
                            step to another, till " the beacon lights of virtue" fade from view, and at last, he finds
                            himself among the workers of every abomination ! Thousands of beings go down to destruction
                            and death, by vicious habits, who began with no idea of reaching such an end, and realize,
                            when too late, " that the way of the transgressor is hard " as well as foolish. Would you
                            escape dangers that beset you ? then heed the warning, take the alarm before you fatally
                            strike those " hidden rocks " upon which thousands have been dashed to pieces. Beware of the
                            wiles of the " adversary 1" Close your mind against his first suggestions to evil, as you
                            would bolt and lock your doors against robbers ! You cannot be overcome without your
                            consent. The key of your citadel is in your hands, and the enemy cannot enter but by the
                            gate, and that opened from within. " Who cares for consequences ? not I," has been the
                            destruction of thousands ! Ah ! those consequences are fearful reckoners ! If you do not
                            think of them they will draw you to ruin 1 " What I say unto you, I say unto all, Watch." "
                            If sinners entice thee, consent thou not; walk not thou in the way with them, refrain thy
                            feet from their path." Enfield, Conn.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prentissiana: Uniformity" TEIform="index"/>PRENTISSIANA. UNIFORMITY</head><p TEIform="p">Uniformity is the legitimate outgrowth of union. The day of compelled uniformity has passed.
                            Shakers are entering the Second Heaven of the Swedish Seer, where each individual's interior
                            becomes his or her exterior—they appear without as they are within, giving practical
                            demonstration of their center of attraction. In the Heavens before us—the Heavens of the
                            Good, the True, the Beautiful—there is uniformity—not by compulsion—for the love of
                            uniformity—all wishing to render themselves most acceptable, most agreeable to their dear
                            Gospel Kelations. hamlet's ghost. And what of Hamlet's Ghost ? It won't down —
                            Ecclesiasticism is the Power behind the Throne, greater than the Throne, of one of the
                            nearly balanced Politi. cal Parties. We, as a nation, are nearinga crisis. The
                            Ecclesiastical and Civil Hosts are about to meet in mortal combat—no quarters given. The
                            better class of minds, able to discern the signs of the times, have an important part to
                            act—Let them turn the battle to the gate—tip the scale on the side of Civil Liberty—the
                            Rights of Man—hinging, to large extents, upon the Elections of 1879 and 1880. • " THE
                            STARS." Dear Editor—In the above-named article printed in October Manifesto, the mental
                            expansion, the mechanism of thought of a child yet in her teens, reared in the seclusion of
                            Shakerdom, will compare favorably with the best efforts of maturer minds with the facilities
                            of a classic education. Such a prodnction is decidedly creditable to the Divine Order—to the
                            Purity of the Angels of God.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Stop croaking; let down the buckets" TEIform="index"/>STOP CROAKING; LET DOWN THE BUCKETS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p">A ship was sailing in the southern waters on the Atlantic, and those on board saw another
                            vessel making signals of distress. They bore down toward the distressed ship and hailed it:
                            "What is the matter? " "We are dying for water," was the response. "Dip it up, then!" was
                            answered, "you are in the month bi the Amazon river." There those sailors were thirsting and
                            suffering, and fearing, and longing for water and supposed there was nothing but the ocean's
                            brine around them, when in fact they had sailed unconsciously into the broad mouth of the
                            mightiest river on the globe and did not know it. So the people even now, as they have been
                            for years, are cry. ing "hard times," and are ready to despair <pb n="244" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 244 THE
                            SHAKES MANIFESTO. when they have fortunately reached where the sources of wealth are opening
                            all around them, and all that is necessary is to go to work and stop croaking. Is it not
                            even so with Zion ? Have we not come to the good time coming, come to the "fullness of
                            times?" Is not the spirit world big with the treasured human hopes of the past centuries ?
                            Are we not waiting, watching, thirsting, praying, putting out signals of distress to attract
                            the notice of those not half so favored as ourselves ? Let down the buckets into the
                            broadest 'ocean of good into which mortals ever sailed, and draw therefrom the waters of
                            immortal life. Friends on the other shore are literally weighted down with the precious
                            treasures of long, fruitful soul travail, that they desire to communicate to the dwellers on
                            earth. Let down the buckets into the spirit world. Spiritualism has done its work with the
                            first class of advanced minds. Now let it return home, whence it proceeded years ago to
                            water the then thirsty earth; and as water or oil follows the withdrawal of the successful
                            drill, so will souls follow the return to Zion of the angel of spiritualism. Spiritualism
                            has been leavening the first class of its recipients. It has been disintegrating. It has
                            proceeded far enough with them. Let them be put into the hot oven of Shakerism, to arrest
                            the further process of decomposition.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My ships" TEIform="index"/>MY SHIPS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Smith, Thomas" TEIform="persName"/>THOMAS SMITH</byline><p TEIform="p">When my ships come in from the foreign shores, From across the sea, . The precious wealth of
                            the sunny lands They will bring to me. You laugh and you say they are fairy ships, But how
                            should you know ? For I sent them out with their sails afloat, Long—long ago. One ship is
                            Love, and she courses on Under Faith's command ; And the shining cloud of Hope leads on Like
                            a guiding hand. And Charity, with her colors out, And her white sails spread, Steers on
                            through the winds and waves of life, To the port ahead. I've watched and waited their coming
                            in, Though, as yet, in vain, Still I know they're breaking the swelling waves Of the rocky
                            main. Sometimes I see the black clouds rise In the northern sky, And I know by the breath of
                            the old storm king, That he's thundering nigh. And think of my ships, far out at sea, On the
                            heaving blue, And then I think of the trusty hearts Of my trusty crew. And I laugh at my
                            weak and foolish fears, For at once I see, That the Father holds in his mighty hand, Both
                            the land and sea. But when the fav'ring winds blow calm, And the summer sun Go^th down in a
                            haze of blue and gold, When the day is done, Ah ! then I think of my ships afar On the
                            billows blue ; And again I think of the happy hearts Of my happy crew. And my heart grows
                            light, for I see and know, That through day and night, Through calm and storm, will the
                            beacon glow, With the promise bright. My ships ! my ships ! ah, yea, they'll come, From
                            across the seas. They'll come with their snowy sails afloat In their native breeze. My happy
                            hopes are not in vain, Nor my trustings o'er, For I know they'll come across the main— From
                            the foreign shore. Canaan, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="There is no warrant in the Bible for a faith that..." TEIform="index"/>There is no warrant in the Bible for a faith that...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">There is no warrant in the Bible for a faith that asks and expects to receive
                                    without toil, that prays, and trusts to prayer to serve in lieu of labor. The
                                    Christian's faith is a soldier's faith, who does not make belief in his commander
                                    serve in lieu of fighting, but who fights vigorously and hopefully because he
                                    believes in his commander.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New Jersey messenger" TEIform="index"/>N. J. Messenger</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="245" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker law" TEIform="index"/>SHAKER LAW</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, G. B." TEIform="persName"/>G. B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p">To all whom it may concern : Running in debt is contraband by Shaker Organic Law; and the
                            adoption of any form of contract by a Shaker, which recognizes an obligation to make a
                            payment or payments posterior to the date specified in the contract of purchase, is
                            violation of Shaker Covenant law. No Shaker Society is constitutionally responsible for the
                            payment of debt contracted by any member of a Shaker community ; and, wherever it has been
                            done, or may be done on account of past transgressions of Shaker laws, it is under protest.
                            " To hear good teaching and not obey it Is to run in debt and never pay it."</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker sermons" TEIform="index"/>SHAKER SERMONS</head><p TEIform="p">An open letter. Book and Portrait. Dear Editor Manifesto.—I am well aware that we have given
                            cause of trial to some by the publication of a book containing the portrait of the author,
                            especially when it was known to be a departure from the common usage and sense of society,
                            therefore, as the book goes out, some apology or explanation is now in order. It would be
                            but natural to suppose that the author was moved by a spirit of vanity for suggesting such
                            procedure. The desire of notoriety or fame, if any, had but little force in producing it.
                            The book was written at short intervals in the midst of other heavy burdens and labors, and
                            was thought to be of some importance, and it was suggested that double the number of copies
                            could be got into circulation by introducing the portrait of the author, than could be
                            without it. The desire for this greater circulation was the lever that moved this little
                            world. The motive was therefore good, if the deed was wrong, which should give some action
                            to the attribute of charity in those who may have felt aggrieved on the occasion. The union
                            of good souls, or those who are laboring to be good, is worth more than any book. And as "
                            charity covereth a multitude of sins," we can but hope this will not be found too large for
                            her mantle. It was thought by some in the western part of Zion, that I had borrowed from or
                            copied from Br. Jno. Dunlavy, which it would have been no dishonor to have done, for, as a
                            logical reasoner, he had no superior. If I have given reason for this belief, I must say it
                            is entirely accidental. I cannot now remember of referring to Dunlavy in any case, but I did
                            consult the Millennial Church on one occasion. Eld. B. S. Youngs was the Gamaliel at whose
                            feet I sat, and not Dunlavy ; but I claim a more strict adherence to the canons of logic
                            than Benjamin could, because this formed no part of his education. I claim for the sermons
                            logical accuracy. Still they may not be entirely flawless—none can call them sophistical or
                            illogical without proving them to be so. I am very sure I will thank any person of any cloth
                            or color who will be kind enough to point out any clause violative of any canon under the
                            "law of parsimony" as set forth by Hamilton and concurred in by Mill. Of course none but
                            those who have made logic a part of their education can be able to do me this kindness. It
                            cannot be expected that all of any profession will be able to see eye to eye in speculative
                            theology, and it should be our labor (as a sainted sister of Mt. Lebanon has lately written
                            me) " To bless all in their calling and gift, and to me it is an easy matter so long as
                            sincerity marks the course of each with good common sense actuating." The writer and author
                            of the " sermons " being one whose first word was uttered in Shakertown, and has grown up in
                            it and taken lessons from the most learned and knowing of the order, has some cause to
                            suppose himself to be in possession of the faith by and upon which the institution was
                            founded, and upon which it is built up, and on which it must stand. This he has
                            conscientiously endeavored to set forth in the book now launched upon the world ; and to
                            show that the leaven has already began to work, from what has already gone forth, I will
                            make a short quotation from one of the letters lately received from one not of our fold as
                                <pb n="246" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 246 THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. yet, residing more than three hundred
                            miles distant, as follows: "Dear Elder Bads, I re ceived the Manifesto for which I thank you
                            kindly . I was so much pleased with the discourse on the "Judgment of Sin," '. read it over
                            and over again. I like its sen . timents, on the confession of sin. * * I; ever it may be my
                            good fortune to see you I will make a clean breast of it, God being my helper, as I am now
                            fully convinced it is the only way in which sin can be forgiven, etc." The writer of the
                            quotation is a man of wealth and respectability, but bo and by a family in his present
                            position. This perhaps is enough, as I wish not to claim too much of your valuable space. In
                            purest love to all,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Eads, H. L." TEIform="persName"/>H. L. Eads</byline><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Kentucky, South Union" TEIform="index"/>South Union, Ky.</dateline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rascally gods" TEIform="index"/>"THE RASCALLY GODS."</head><p TEIform="p">PRENTISSIANA. — What a text for a Sermon ! All nations have their Gods—some, pretty
                            fair—some, no better than they should be. The Gods are, generally, not much unlike their
                            people—or the people are not much unlike their Gods. Which is the Creator, we will, if you
                            please, leave an open question ? Some years ago, the Persians had a lot of Gods that lost
                            caste with the people. The people got an idea into their heads that the jealousy and
                            perpetual bickerings among the Gods had an effect upon the weather. When the weather didn't
                            suit, they'd say : " The rascally Gods are giving us a bad day." We are not disposed to
                            resolve our self into a high court of jurisdiction for the trial of the Persians, nor their
                            Gods, nor any other people whose Gods are "jealous"— " angry with the wicked every day," "
                            laugh at their calamity"—" mock when their fear cometh." If any people can derive any
                            benefit from such Gods, they have our full consent to do so. For the Holy Eternal
                            Parentage—wisdom and love—we have high respect, bordering on adoration—too high respect to
                            bore them with toadyism—idol worship. In their paternal wisdom and maternal sympathy, we
                            find panacea for all the wouldbe ills that beset our path. We turn the little rascals to
                            good account. We don't let would-be-grievances tip us off our balance, to say naughty things
                            of evil doers. "Speak kindly to the erring," is not a bad motto, for men, nor for Gods. To
                            cultivate, to unfold, the germ of divinity—our birth-right inheritance—to come forth, in
                            likeness of our Holy Eternal Parents—to deal kindly with all, is the legitimate purpose of
                            our incarnation.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Extracts from the report of the committee of friends on Indian affairs, 1878" TEIform="index"/>EXTRACTS FROM THE REPORT OF THE COMMITTEE OF FRIENDS ON INDIAN AFFAIRS, 1878</head><p TEIform="p">Ten days were spent in the Great Narnaha (Nebraska) agency. The Indians were peaceable, white
                            men (called Christians) had stolen some of their horses and cattle, and trespassed on their
                            reservation. Schools on the reservation had been well attended. Of the [owa Children, only
                            one had not attended school. Of the Sac and Fox, but three had failed to attend school. A
                            home Juvenile Lyceum was conducted by the older children during winter months with interest
                            and profit. Three Iowa Indian families have carpeted floors in their dwellings. Five Iowa
                            Indian families own and use sewing machines. Every family able to do so, has fenced farms
                            and fields. Five Iowa Indiana have farms containing from fifty to one hundred and sixty
                            acres each ; Iowa Indians have fenced in 200 acres of land during the year; planted eleven
                            mndred and sixty fruit trees, two hundred and sixty grape vines, during the year previous
                            they had planted four hundred and 'orty trees and forty grape vines. * * * (phe jowaS;
                            although self supporting in favorable years for agriculture, are not yet advanced to such a
                            status of inancial ability to be capable, as citizens, to afely take upon themselves the
                            control of heir reservation and trust funds. Some in lividuals, in both tribes, are idle,
                            and no madic, in their habits and character. * * * <pb n="247" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. 247 IOWA INDUSTRIAL HOUSE. Eighty acres of cultivated land are attached to this,
                            producing, principally by home labor, all the wheat, corn, vegetables, pork, and much of the
                            quantity of other meats required for the subsistence of the Iowa Indian scholars, who board
                            there. The boys assist in farming, gardening, cutting and carrying wood, sweeping their
                            rooms and feeding the domestic animals. The girls daily assist in cooking and household
                            duties ; have completed, with assistance, many of the washings, bakings, brewings necessary
                            for the family ; they knit stockings, cut and make wearing apparel, and mend the clothes of
                            the boys and girls, * * . Number of full blood Indians who wear citizens dress, male and
                            female : Io was............................ 138 Sac and Fox...................... 69
                            Total......................... 207 Mixed bloods (Iowas)............. 73 Mixed bloods (Sac
                            and Pox)........ 1 Total.......................... 74 No Indians killed during the year, nor
                            were any white persons killed by the Indians, neither were there any Indians needing
                            punishment during the year. During the year Iowa Indians cultivated 750 acres, and the Sac
                            and Fox 453 acres. As a rule, there has been success in the farming operations, the crops,
                            with few exceptions, having been well cultivated, and harvested in good condition. Corn
                            raised, 30,000 bushels ; wheat, 880 bushels ; barley, 338 bushels ; potatoes, 500 bushels ;
                            besides large quantities of other vegetables. Eight hundred tons of hay were grown. The
                            Iowas have 1,600 acres fenced; Sac and Fox, 500. The former made, during the year, 1,005
                            rods of fence, and the latter, 2,000. Seventy-five acres of prairie have also been broken.
                            -------¦ In the ninth month last, a fair was held for, and by the Iowas which, though not
                            very pretentious, was sufficient to show an interest would be taken in such matters if
                            properly managed. * * * Only six Sac and Fox Indian familes live ill frame or long Indian
                            houses ;—the balance of the tribe are satisfied to dwell in tents, tepees, or wick-i-ups.
                            Two thousand lbs. of barbed fence will have been used during the year by the Sac and Fox
                            Indians. After repeated efforts an Indian apprentice has been secured to the blacksmith and
                            wheelwright, who makes good promise. OTOE AGENCY. The reservation now remaining to this
                            tribe contains 44,093 acres. Agency buildings centrally located. Of the costume of this
                            tribe the agent does not speak favorably. There are divisions and contentions in the tribe.
                            It numbers 474; of these 100 are in the Cheyenne village, two miles from the agency office ;
                            these have declined to receive rations from their agent. The Otoes are now more interested
                            in agricultural pursuits than ever before. The chiefs and head men have generally left their
                            villages of mud lodges, have selected farms and are breaking prairie. Fifteen families had
                            fields of wheat aggregating 70 acres; the yield was good. They had corn fields covering 150
                            acres ; potatoes, 25 acres ; beans, melons, etc., 25 acres. The owners are proud of the
                            results of their labors ; it must incite others to follow their example. The Agency crops
                            were 100 acres of corn ; 180 acres of wheat; 20 acres of oats ; 6 acres of potatoes, and 7
                            acres of vegetables. The school building is ample to accommodate the tribe ; but quite a
                            number of the children did not attend any session during the fiscal year. The school
                            buildings are connected with a farm capable of furnishing all the supplies needed. During
                            the spring and summer of 1877, 119,849 acres of the Otoe and Missouri lands, the western
                            portion of their reserve, were, under the provisions of an act of Congress, appraised by
                            Commissioners, at a valuation of $427,091 32-100, and soon after offered for sale, since
                            which time nearly all the allotments have been taken possession of by white persons,
                            claiming to be actual settlers. The Chiefs and the Interpreter have voluntarily taken steps
                            to form themselves into a temperance society in the tribe. The policy previously pursued, of
                            conducting a tribal farm for the benefit of the tribe, and paying Indians for their labor
                                <pb n="248" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 248 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. thereon, lias been continued. By the
                            purchase of ten additional pairs of oxen, the Indians were furnished with means for breaking
                            new ground. Twenty different parties availed themselves of the opportunity, and an aggregate
                            of 150 acres are broken. This is sown with wheat and looks well. The interest taken in
                            farming is more encouraging. About one-third of the tribe continue in opposition to all
                            improvements in civilized pursuits. The industrial school has continued in operation through
                            the year. After leaving school the children incline more to citizens dress, are able to
                            understand and speak English, acting as interpreters for their parents, keep their accounts
                            and manage their transactions at the store. The scholars are fully up to the average of
                            white children. The government has released the Quakers from the burden of the " Pawnees."
                            The Winnebago and Omaha agencies are consolidated ; the Flandreau tribe added to the Santee
                            Sioux agency. Philadelphia continues the care and oversight of the Great Nemaha and Otoe
                            Agencies, and their tribes; New York of the Winnebago Indians ; Indiana of the Omaha Indians
                            ; Baltimore, Genesee, Ohio and Illinois, joint action and care of the Santee, Sioux and
                            Flandreau Indians aud their agencies. The cost to the Friends Yearly Meeting of the labors
                            of its Committee during the past year has been $894.51. During the same period contributions
                            have been made by individual members to the amount of $767.80, for fruit trees and seed
                            grain for the benefit of Indian Agriculturists, and the construction of wells at Indian
                            homes.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ellis, Jacob M." TEIform="persName"/>Jacob M. Ellis, Clerk</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lessons from the clouds" TEIform="index"/>LESSONS FROM THE CLOUDS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fletcher, Richard" TEIform="persName"/>RICHARD FLETCHER</byline><p TEIform="p">Consider the clouds ; they toil not, nor do they worry. They move steadily and quietly,
                            forming pictures to please, and shade to comfort, carrying gentle rain and cleans. ing
                            lightning. What beautiful panoramic scenes they make for very few persons who trouble to
                            look at them. While crowds will sit entranced for hours in unhealthy theaters, gazing with
                            dazed, aching eyes upon tinseled daubs called " transformation scenes," but very few care to
                            look above the plodding of daily routine to the ever changing scenes of beauty amid the
                            healthy surroundings of nature. Little does it worry the clouds, as across the fields of
                            blue, dark and warm or light and cool, they chase one another, breaking the sameness of
                            sun-light into many shades and colors, not only useful but lovely ; little do they fret that
                            mortals do not notice them more. So should we quietly do our duties. What though the
                            hurrying masses do not stop and applaud ? Their breath, called " fame," popularity, worldly
                            honor, etc., are wasted on very different lives from those of the meek and lowly followers
                            of Jesus. Some persons can look on the bright side of common troubles, saying: ''All dark
                            clouds have a silver lining "—a good lesson to draw from the fleeting messengers. Can we not
                            go further ? Suppose, when life's firmament, from horizon to horizon, clear overhead, seems
                            like a leaden sky, with not a break in it for a cheerful ray to come (and all persons may
                            have that feeling at times), oh, then to be able to say: " A leaden sky has a sunny side."
                            This will be progress Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Minister" TEIform="index"/>THE MINISTER</head><p TEIform="p">I like a preacher to strike hard and straight With fiery scorn, at wrong, deceit, and hate !
                            Nor compromise a thought of his true feeling. Or of the Holy Gospel's just revealing. The
                            human heart his occult study make, His strife—the finer sentiments to wake ; To rouse the
                            slumbering manhood of humanity, And rescue hearts from worldly pride and vanity. Turn the
                            fierce rush of thought to noble action, Fill selfish streams with tides of benefaction ;
                            Teach scorn of policy and compromising, From mammon's bondage aid the spirit's rising.
                            Beiore each soul to place a motive glorious, Till high ambition upward turns victorious
                        !</p></div2><pb n="249" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Herald of celestial light" TEIform="index"/>HERALD OF CELESTIAL LIGHT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Andrews, Watson" TEIform="persName"/>WATSON ANDREWS</byline><p TEIform="p">Teeeming with celestial light Heaven's Herald, haste ye onward. Ever toward the highest hight
                            Soaring, call the nations homeward. Hail the day and hail the hour— Angel tongues proclaimed
                            thy calling— Kingdoms totter, lose their power, Error—Babylon is falling. Rise then, Herald,
                            in thy might, Millions wait thy saving power ; And to shed thy blessed light, ~Now's the
                            day, and now's the hour." Inspiration—gift Divine— Fans the flame upon thy altar ; Every
                            precious gift is thine ; Speed thee, Herald, do not falter— Teeming with celestial light,
                            Onward upward in the right. N. Union, O. North Union, O., Sept. 28, '79. Dear Editor
                            Brother.—The above acrostic was written some time ago, but having seen no precedent for its
                            admission into your columns until your last issue, I hesitated about forwarding it. Hope it
                            will be satisfactory. One merit it certainly has, to wit, truthfulness. All well, yours in
                            love, Watson .</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Me vs. us" TEIform="index"/>ME vs. US</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prentiss, Oliver" TEIform="persName"/>OLIVER PRENTISS</byline><p TEIform="p">Long time ago, I had an Aunt 'Rusha— Jerusha, some called her. She was my sainted father's
                            only sister, born in Shrewsbury, Mass., in the early part of the last century. At a certain
                            or uncertain age, she married Luke Hitchcock. Luke was one of the Massachusetters that went
                            to Lexington to pitch into the naughty Britishers who went there to raise hob with a few old
                            muskets, called military stores. They pursued the Britishers to Cambridge where they formed
                            a camp and commenced organizing in military style. When the war was ended, Luke went home
                            penniless. For his family of small children he wanted bread. The King's liberal offer of 100
                            acres of land, farming utensils, a cow and one year's provisions, to men with families who
                            would settle in his Canada domain, was accepted by Luke. His lot was in Sanbridge, east of
                            Missisco Bay, second town north of Canada line. Luke built a house, log-house of course, one
                            room with a ladder for the boys to go up stairs to sleep. Here, for a long time, Uncle Luke,
                            Aunt Rusha, three sons and tbree daughters were a cozy community. The children increasing in
                            bulk, another room was added to the end of the house— and still they were a cozy community.
                            But when one of the children perpetrated matrimony, the meum sprouted out—" Father's end "
                            as it is now called, must be given up to the married couple, till some other home could be
                            found—matrimony spoiled them for community. Is that the way it works generally ? will it
                            always be so ? Will matrimony and meum forever be indissoluble? Is co-operation the nearest
                            approach matrimony can ever make to community ? If so, we must have new earth, as well as
                            new heavens. The old earth—the prostitution of the reproductive powers, to purposes not
                            nominated in the bond, begins to have an offensive odor, repulsive to refined sensibility of
                            the better class of minds. Who will break up the fallow ground and plant the new earth ?
                            He—she—They, who has, or*have the moral stamina so to achieve, will leave the heroes of the
                            past back in the shade. Their names shall be PMlagathus and Philanthropos—lovers of goodness
                            and of mankind.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is a pity that a good share of the indignation visited upon wrong thinking..." TEIform="index"/>It is a pity that a good share of the indignation visited upon wrong thinking...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"It is a pity that a good share of the indignation visited upon wrong thinking might not be
                            bestowed upon wrong living. A little more emphasis in the life is what we Want. Orthodox
                            doctrine without orthodox living is the shell of the cocoanut with the meat gone — the frame
                            of a house having neither clapboard nor shingle ; and yet just this some people make their
                            refuge, and then wonder when the storms do come that theyare not sheltered.—Christian at
                            Work.</p></div2><pb n="250" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let us be honest with ourselves" TEIform="index"/>LET US BE HOiNEST WITH OURSELVES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">It behooves us, in giving the key-note to Shaker theology, that we give no uncertain
                                sound ; but surely to indicate to those who read that they may run in channels of
                                Christian life, unmistakable evidences that our theology and Christianity are so nearly
                                one, and that this latter so entirely absorbs our theology, that radical Christianity is
                                all that is left us to practice, teach, or to boast of. While very unwilling to demand
                                acquiescence with our views by those who would think otherwise; and while mindful that
                                compulsion is no part of our gospel polity, we would not permit the lowering of our
                                gospel standard through any worldly sympathy nor inimical controversy. We believe, and
                                we know that there are honest seekers after the truth of Christ in all professedly
                                Christian denominations ; and as Christian professors we should accord to every other
                                honest seeker the sympathy we ourselves would like. It only remains for us all — all
                                who, leaving self and selfishness out of consideration—will accept Christ as the
                                standard life, and as fast as our religious convictions will permit us, and teach us,
                                and urge us, pattern our lives after that beautiful standard; and being honest with
                                our-, selves, acknowledge ourselves just so far from the perfect and desirable
                                Christianity as there exists a disparity between our motives, lives and professions, and
                                these same features in the life of Jesus, our Lord. The days of theological wranglings
                                and moonshine* professions should now be considered antique, useless and dead; while the
                                living elements which made Jesus Christ so lovely and adorable may be ours to love and
                                to live by, to the same loveliness'and adoration ultimately. By such parity of
                                reasoning, we have a living faith, with ivories like unto Christ's life, as our
                                credentials of genuine discipleship. We will not quarrel with our sincere Methodist,
                                Baptist, Presbyterian, Episcopalian nor Roman Catholic brethren. So long as they
                                honestly see genuine Christianity therein, it would be wrong to disturb or offend them.
                                Indeed we know of much good in all religious persuasions; but we cannot help bringing to
                                bear upon all of these the radical, fundamental principles of Christ's life, and wherein
                                there appears a contrast, we ask each and everyone, why this is so? With Beecher, we
                                asseverate: " The servant has no right to follow, and cannot follow, where the Master
                                did not go !" Realizing, as we all may, what were the ruling characteristics of Jesus,
                                the pattern of our Christianity; and realizing, as we cannot help doing, that the lives
                                of the great majority of those who profess a following after Christ, bear little or no
                                resemblance to his; we would sound the clarion of alarm to arrest further progress from
                                Christ, and blow the horn of Gabriel to waken the thoughtless and the sleeping to a just
                                realization of the situation, and raise the dead in sins to view and copy the
                                resurrected life of the Christ. This is duty on our part; and however unpleasant to
                                distrust the imaginary prepossessions wrought out by earlier, but erroneous educations,
                                "yet being placed in charge of the gospel, must we speak, not as pleasing men, but<pb n="251" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 251 God." Let us all be honest with
                                ourselves, and demand for ourselves an honest religion, a genuine Christianity. Let us
                                again lift up to our views the beautiful Christ anew. Bring the square and the plummet
                                to bear upon him. Catechise him. Ask for ourselves " what shall we do to inherit eternal
                                life ?" And after viewing the beauty of his character; after testing the quality of his
                                purity of life ; after the rendition of our questions to our fullest satisfaction, hear
                                him: I" If thou wouldst be perfect, forsake all worldly ambitions, affections,loves and
                                lusts, and come and follow me !" Then are we truly led to remember that his life on
                                earth was one of that virgin purity stamp, which so beautifies the heavens; that his
                                life was so unselfish, that with kingdoms at the command of his ambitions, he yet fared
                                and shared with the humblest of his disciples, possessing naught that he called his own
                                ! So peaceable was he that he blessed those who cursed him, and prayed blessings for
                                those who despitefully used him and crucified him; and so unspotted from the good and
                                bad of the world, as to make us to feel at this late day that he was almost an angel of
                                God from heaven, clothed with flesh! Let us be honest with ourselves, and demand for
                                ourselves an honest, Christian theology. Let us, sincere Baptists, Methodists,
                                Episcopalians, Romans, Presbyterians and all other denominations bearing the affix or
                                suffix of Christian, compare our Christianity and our lives with these in Christ; and
                                wherein there are differences, let us be honest, and acknowledge ourselves so far from
                                being true Christians. Then let us be determined to be Christians, at any and every
                                cost, wherein these discrepancies have proved us not. It will pay to be honest with
                                ourselves. Let our theologies be secondary to the life of Christ, patterned by our
                                lives. Let our theologies go into oblivion wherein these differ from the radical
                                features of Christ's life; for this is better than all other theologies; and being thus
                                honest in our endeavors to know and to live the truth, we will only be satisfied in
                                living as Jesus lived, and thus living, will simply be followers of Christ, radical but
                                genuine Christians.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Must we forsake the good?" TEIform="index"/>MUST WE FORSAKE THE GOOD?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">In the initiative, let us particularly make declaration: We love Jesus, the Christ, so
                                well, that we think no life better than his, and as his love of life was and is, so
                                would our love be expressed in imitating his excellent example. It is commonly admitted
                                that the testimony of Jesus was denunciatory of evil, and that this testimony was
                                peculiarly sustained by his unsinful life. We do not, on this account, render to Jesus
                                any especial credit beyond what we gladly bestow upon many companions of to-day.
                                Ninetynine one-hundredths of the people condemn deeds that bear on their faces the marks
                                and intents of actual sin. Jesus was no exception in this. The world at large are ready
                                to accept and to unite with us in condemnation of the sinful; and we must very
                                occasionally give large and an increase of credit to some who are severer in their terms
                                upon sin itself than we the Shakers are. While we have so much sympathy or testimony
                                against evil, we find the largest, strongest op- <pb n="252" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 252 THE SHAKEE
                                MANIFESTO. position toward taking one step farther —the relinquishment, the entire
                                renunciation as a duty, of any good thing or practice. The great majority are against us
                                in this ; will not hear us, nor harbor the thought for a moment. And yet here is where
                                Jesus became and remains pre-eminent—by the denial unto himself, and unto his followers,
                                of every feature of worldly good, upon which we all so naturally incline to place our
                                affections ! Do not the Shakers admit the good of marriage and reproduction by the
                                children of the world ? And did Jesus ever condemn it there ? And yet, Jesus being "the
                                Resurrection"—the life raised up above even the good of marriage and reproductions—did
                                he not forsake these worldly-good things for the attainment of the very much better
                                things of the spirit ? Why did Jesus deny himself of being a good husband and father ?
                                deny himself of wife, children, houses, land, and did crucify his very worldly-good
                                life, with all its affections, loves and lusts ? And why did he imperatively enjoin upon
                                his disciples, these same renunciations of worldly-good things—the nearest, dearest and
                                most intensely satisfactory possessions to a worldly mind? Were his instructions of
                                denial to these based upon their wickedness ? Not so, emphatically, Nay ! The gospel of
                                Jesus meant progress; up from, out of and away from even the good and best of worldly
                                relations and practices, to the formation of unworldly, regenerative, angelic followers
                                called Christians. In his day his immediate disciples were implicitly obedient to his
                                instructions ; and they left off the practices of husbands, wives, fathers, mothers,
                                holders of personal possessions, children, houses, lands, etc., and forsaking the good
                                and bad of the carnal, worldly life, accepted the life of Jesus as a most glorious
                                substitute—a tetter and the test life. Among the myriads professing Christianity since
                                the days of Jesus, there have been extensive, retrograde movements. Those very features
                                which Jesus and his little company actually forsook, regardless of their most endearing
                                fascinations to their worldly inclinations, are too commonly made sacraments of by the
                                churches and people professing his name! Belief is now extensively taught that Jesus did
                                not mean "forsake " when he said so, when he lived so, and which others who followed
                                him, forsook to live like him ! The profession of Christianity remains abundantly to-day
                                ; but ask a man to hate the wife, yet love the woman as his sister in Christ; ask the
                                woman to hate the husband life of the man and yet love him as her brother in Christ;
                                only ask men and women to forsake the good and bad which Jesus forsook, and which they
                                must forsake to be genuine disciples, and there rises an opposition which vents itself
                                in derision, contempt or in open, violent persecution! Yet here stands the testimony,
                                unmoved as the heavens; here will stand through all eternity the radical truths of
                                Christianity, which to learn, demand the actual relinquishment of worldly good, and the
                                acceptance of new relations by humanity, better and best, and all in the progress of
                                godliness. Let those deride who please; but for us, Jesus the Christ, has lived as a
                                heavenly example. Our following, even imperfect- <pb n="253" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                                MANIFESTO. 253 ly, gives us by the world-loving the opprobrious epithet "fanatical
                                Shakers;" while we, in " despising such shame " as coming only from those more unlike
                                Christ than we are, will be happily content to continue in the life of Jesus, in Virgin"
                                Purity, in a United Brotherhood, as Peacemakers, and as nearly Unworldly as was Jesus,
                                as we can. Must we forsake any good thing ? To be like Jesus Christ, to be his
                                followers, we must forsake many good things, as well as all bad ones; and we shall be
                                enabled to count all such forsakings, as decided gains unto a Christian heaven.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Speculative theologies" TEIform="index"/>SPECULATIVE THEOLOGIES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">THE ESSENTIAL FEATURE. It is with some alarm that some of our good people sorrow because
                                several of the good and prominent brethren differ materially in their speculative
                                theories ; thinking that it savors of and advertises differences among us as brethren.
                                We have long made public declaration, that we had gathered into the fold of Shakerism
                                many of various inclinations as to the colors of their theologies. Among the Shakers
                                to-day, there are many whose previous educations, theologically, were from nearly every
                                one of the prominent churches; and from these earlier teachings they have, as yet,
                                neither seen nor felt any good reason to wholly depart. Among us there are some with the
                                "Atonement" theory still active in them ; others with Baptist and Presbyterian
                                proclivities; some who frequently quote the Trinity favorably, and others who believe
                                Jesus was very God, and Mary the mother of God! Thus are we comprised. And where is the
                                harm ? If one brother really believes there is an identity in the Mosaic and the
                                Christian Gods, and still other brothers and sisters who are confident there were and
                                are Tutelary Deities, who needs to object ? Count us among the last. Amid merely
                                speculative theologies, we know of but few who can see " eye to eye;" and we opine that
                                the less agreements upon such speculations, the better. Even we have some theological
                                speculations — such as perhaps we could rarely make a convert with, and never save a
                                soul—but we have endeavored to keep these outside of the office of The Shaker Manifesto,
                                and even out of our lowly pulpit, before our large audiences. Just how successful we
                                have been in these omissions we leave our readers and brethren to judge. As we state
                                elsewhere, the days of theological wrangling should be numbered among the things of the
                                past; they should, if counted at all, be recorded among the very non-essentials of our
                                religious lives. We, with others, have an idea of God. Our imagination—which means the
                                act of making an image—pictures to our mind the best God of which we can possibly
                                conceive; just so with others; and if we differ, who is to blame, and where is the
                                mischief ? Brethren, Sisters,Friends: The essential features of our theologies do not
                                exist in, nor with, these speculative imaginings and differences. Once and for all time,
                                let the life of the individual resemble Christ's life, and what can it matter about
                                mooted points of scripture, Gods many or one God ? God's mother or a motherless <pb n="254" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 254 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. God ? Christ man, Christ woman or
                                Christ child ? Away with all alarms about any mischief being done, so long as brethren
                                advocate and live the purity, peacedbleness, philanthropy and unworldly life of Jesus,
                                the Christ. This is the essential theology ; and just as welcome as we make all of our
                                brethren and friends to dwell upon speculations in theology, we would just as kindly ask
                                for their absence in their contributions to the Manifesto, and make them just as earnest
                                a welcome to the elucidation and practical illustration of the grand, eternal, Christian
                                essentials, depicted so clearly in the life of Christ. And" brethren, are we not correct
                                ?</p></div3><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>NOTES AND CRITICISMS</head><div4 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Stealing our thunder" TEIform="index"/>"stealing our thunder."</head><p TEIform="p">The beautiful Golden Rule opened one of its late numbers with the following complete
                                    truism : " To be a follower of christ is to live as Christ lived ; and to be a
                                    Christian IS TO BE LIKE CHRIST ! " If the Golden Rule does not cease issuing such
                                    resplendent theology, The Shaker Manifesto might as well hang up its pen. With only
                                    such material in the make-up of a periodical, there is only room or need of but one
                                    religious paper, and we can well afford to retire.</p></div4><div4 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life argument" TEIform="index"/>LIFE ARGUMENT</head><p TEIform="p">One of the strongest arguments favoring Christianity has been that no one has
                                    regretted its practice on the death-bed. We present a stronger and strongest: No one
                                    having lived it, and enjoyed the purity and excellence of its radical features, ever
                                    wished to live or die by any other life doctrine. The half-way, hybrid, hypocritical
                                    and Pharisaical profession of Christianity which bears the name but evades the
                                    requirements, is sufficiently odious to make a respectable lower animal sick of it,
                                    and to long for a creed that teaches annihilation as a substitute. The death-bed is
                                    no place to create a criterion, but the active, healthy, good-sensed man or woman
                                    can tell the truth more effectually.</p></div4><div4 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cetywayo and English conversions" TEIform="index"/>CETYWAYO AND ENGLISH CONVERSIONS</head><p TEIform="p">" The English shot us to make us Christians, and I ash pardon for shooting bach at
                                    them! ' We ask any of the professionally Christian world, who in the least fa^or
                                    war, or a resort to physical, violent resistance, to be ashamed of their
                                    Christianity in this conversion of the Zulu King.</p></div4><div4 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Representative standards" TEIform="index"/>REPRESENTATIVE STANDARDS</head><p TEIform="p">We have many among our numbers who pretty nearly represent the true Christian
                                    example. If there remain any of the dregs of self, or bigotry, or uncbarity, these
                                    grow more and more of an affliction to such who are sensible of the defects. It is a
                                    truth, not to be spoken lightly of, that the grandest of liberality has taken effect
                                    in the bosoms of many staunch Shakers, and they will depart this world deprived of
                                    much ill-gotten bigotry and uncharity. Many only needed these losses to be emblems
                                    of what gospel work and crosses will do for a man or woman. It is one of the
                                    brilliant signs of the times among us, that indicates the more perfect Shaker, when
                                        <pb n="255" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKES MANIFESTO. 255 each and all can admit that
                                    when a man and woman come within sixteen and one-half feet of being a Christian,
                                    they are within a rod of being a Shaker!</p></div4><div4 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How much Christian are you?" TEIform="index"/>HOW MUCH CHRISTIAN ARE YOU ?</head><p TEIform="p">In our public service, recently, Eldress Polly Eeed delivered, among many good
                                    expressions to us all, the following advice and Christian Charity : " Some may think
                                    they cannot live the true, Christian life, and perhaps this may be so ; it only
                                    remains for such to come as near to it as they can, and let their lives resemble
                                    Christ's as completely as they are able, etc." This brings up plainly and pointedly
                                    to view, and to the test, both the duty and ability of those who have made and do
                                    make the Christian profession. " Let him or her who is able to receive it do
                                so."</p></div4><div4 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Many thanks" TEIform="index"/>MANY THANKS</head><p TEIform="p">We truly feel grateful for the tangible remembrances from the friends of the
                                    Manifesto, in response to the call " To the Generous." We would still kindly
                                    petition for action on the part of those whose bills are due, and would plead with
                                    the generous who feel able to help us to do the honorable in our duty to our
                                    publishers. There can be no doubt that money so deposited will produce a harvest
                                    very pleasant to think of when time with the loaners will be no more.</p></div4></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spurgeon says he has often thought..." TEIform="index"/>Spurgeon says he has often thought...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Spurgeon" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Spurgeon says lie lias often thought, when hearing certain preachers of a high order speaking
                            to the young, that they must have understood the Lord to say, " Feed my camelopards,"
                            instead of " feed my lambs/ for nothing but giraffes could reach any spiritual food from the
                            lofty rack on which they place it.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My Dear Albert: May heaven bless your unselfish labors..." TEIform="index"/>My Dear Albert: May heaven bless your unselfish labors...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Massachusetts, Ayer, October 3, 1879" TEIform="index"/>Ayer, Mass., October 3, 1879</dateline><p TEIform="p">My Dear Albert: May heaven bless your unselfish labors, and may the love of the good
                                angels be most divinely yours, for the interest you have in keeping up to the true
                                standard of our little organ. Who will now reaffirm that we " cannot run a paper six
                                months," when the verdict is that "it has steadily improved from the first." Its ever
                                white sail is being recognized by the great crafts that sail the great ocean of
                                humanity, freighted with politics, science, physiology, morals and religion. The Shaker
                                Manifesto, Long may it live, To the new earth and heaven A pure impulse give. So hopes
                                and prays your constant friend and brother, Elijah. Since penning the above I have
                                re-read " The Grand Evolution," in August number, and place it at the head of your very
                                best productions ; and I may say the same of other contributions. " There's a kingdom
                                forever increasing." </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, Elijah" TEIform="persName"/>E. Myrick</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ed. Manifesto :—In response to your appeal to the generous..." TEIform="index"/>Ed. Manifesto :—In response to your appeal to the generous...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon, October 6, 1879" TEIform="index"/>Mount Lebanon, Oct. 6, 1879</dateline><p TEIform="p">Ed. Manifesto :—In response to your appeal to the generous, inclosed please find Five
                                Dollars as a mite toward helping " bear the burdens of the weak." I feel a deep interest
                                in the prosperity and continuation of The Shaker Manifesto, I believe it ia doing a
                                great deal of good, preparing the way for the coming of Christ to many, honest,
                                truth-seeking souls. After reading the notice in the September Number of The Shaker
                                Manifesto of the Shaker Sermons, I sat down and wrote for one of the books, and I am
                                very desirous of its early issue. Yours truly,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, Avery" TEIform="persName"/>Avery Allen</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My Dear Brother—It is not in our hearts to flatter you nor The Shaker Manifesto, but..." TEIform="index"/>My Dear Brother—It is not in our hearts to flatter you nor The Shaker Manifesto, but...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon, October 11, 1879" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.,
                                Oct. 11, 1879</dateline><p TEIform="p">My Dear Brother—It is not in our hearts to flatter you nor The Shaker Manifesto, but we
                                think it steadily grows better, and must increase its sphere of usefulness, and <pb n="256" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 256 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. be accepted as an encouragement by all
                                seekers after the truth. Believe me, Yours,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Brainard, D. C." TEIform="persName"/>D. C. Brainard</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="G. A. Lomas: Find inclosed five dollars, which..." TEIform="index"/>G. A. Lomas: Find inclosed five dollars, which...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Shakers, October 17, 1879" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y., Oct. 17, 1879</dateline><p TEIform="p">G. A. Lomas: Find inclosed five dollars, which accept as my humble contribution to the
                                valuable Manifesto. [Our noble Bro. Dye would not give consent to the use of his name,
                                and the mention of his deed ; but we insisted upon " letting his light shine " for
                                benefit of others.—Ed.]</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dye, John W." TEIform="persName"/>Jno. W. Dye</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beloved Editor. — The following caution appears so very timely..." TEIform="index"/>Beloved Editor. — The following caution appears so very timely...
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="The ministry" TEIform="persName"/>The Ministry</byline><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Shakers, October 17, 1879" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y., Oct. 17, 1879</dateline><p TEIform="p">Beloved Editor. — The following caution appears so very timely and important that we
                                desire its reproduction in our " Manifesto: " The Ministry</p><div4 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Poisons in farmers' hands" TEIform="index"/>Poisons in farmers' hands
                                </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Poisons in Farmers' Hands. The great increase during the past thirty
                                            years in the variety and number of insects which destroy the farmers' crops
                                            has made it necessary, for purposes of defense, to purchase and have upon
                                            the premises some very active poisonous agents, mineral and vegetable. Among
                                            these may be named Paris green, for destroying the potato beetle; hellebore
                                            powder, for the currant worms, rose bugs, etc.; and strychnine, for crows,
                                            blackbirds, etc., in corn-fields. These comprise some of the most potent and
                                            deadly poisons known to science. By far the most dangerous is Paris green,
                                            because it has come into such general use it is found in almost every farm
                                            house in the country. Now, it is a well-known principle in human conduct
                                            that familiarity with danger engenders indifference, carelessness and
                                            negligence, and consequently, however timid and cautious one may be in the
                                            first handling of dangerous implements or agents, in the course of time
                                            extraordinary safeguards are not thought of, and great recklessness succeeds
                                            to extreme caution. We were impressed with this fact by fortunately
                                            happening to observe a farmer, in the hurry of hay time in J uly, seize a
                                            wooden stirrer which had been used to mix Paris green with flour, and thrust
                                            it into a stone pitcher containing oat meal and water designed for the men
                                            in the field. Of course the peril was instantly pointed out, the beverage
                                            was thrown away, and perhaps life was saved. It was an incident well
                                            calculated to create a feeling of apprehension in regard to the employment
                                            of this poison by farmers. It was kept in a tool house, where also was the
                                            package of oat rneal, and here the mixing of the poison and the beverage
                                            took place. The stirrer, covered with the green powder, was the implement
                                            nearest at hand, and it was thoughtlessly seized in the hurry of the moment.
                                            All these conditions and circumstances show great carelessness, but is it
                                            greater than that shown by others in different ways ? We fear not! In the
                                            first place, no poisonous substances should be stored on farm premises,
                                            unless it be in an unused cellar or outbuilding. It is better to make a
                                            tight box, large enough to hold all the poisons needed to be kept on hand,
                                            together with dredging boxes, stirrers, etc., and place this in a secure
                                            place, away from tools, foods, etc., also from animals. Again, in using
                                            Paris green in gardens, care must be observed that no peas, beans nor other
                                            vegetables are in close proximity to the potatoes, as the powder might fall
                                            or be blown upon them, and thus reach the dining table and cause mischief.
                                            These poisons are of immense benefit to farmers, but, like gunpowder and
                                            other useful but dangerous agents, they should be used with intelligent and
                                            constant care.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Boston journal of chemistry" TEIform="index"/>Boston Journal of
                                        Chemistry</bibl></cit></p></div4></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Punished" TEIform="index"/>Punished
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wheeler, Ella" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">THE PUNISHED. ELLA WHEELER. Not they who know the awful gibbet's anguish, Not
                                    they who while sad years go by them, in The sunless cells of lonely prisons
                                    languish, Do suffer fullest penalty for sin. 'Tis they who walk the highways
                                    unsuspec. ted, Yet with grim fear forever at their side, Who clasp the corpse of
                                    some sin undetected, A corpse no grave or coffin lid can hide. 'Tis they who are in
                                    their own chambers haunted By thoughts that like unwelcome guests intrude, And sit
                                    down uninvited and unwanted, And make a nightmare of the solitude.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Cape times (Africa)" TEIform="index"/>The Cape Times, Africa.</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="257" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>LATE SOCIETY LOSSES</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pool, Sarah" TEIform="index"/>Sarah Pool
                                </head><p TEIform="p">At Pleasant Hill, aged 81 years, <persName reg="Pool, Sarah" TEIform="persName">Sarah
                                Pool</persName>.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Burnett, Zachariah" TEIform="index"/>Zachariah Burnett
                                </head><p TEIform="p">Also, <persName reg="Burnett, Zachariah" TEIform="persName">Zachariah Burnett</persName>, aged 77
                                years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Runyon, Charlotte" TEIform="index"/>Charlotte Runyon
                                </head><p TEIform="p">Also, <persName reg="Runyon, Charlotte" TEIform="persName">Charlotte Runyon</persName>, aged 93
                                years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bryant, Edmond" TEIform="index"/>Edmond Bryant
                                </head><p TEIform="p">Also, <persName reg="Bryant, Edmond" TEIform="persName">Edmond Bryant</persName>, aged 90 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Montague, Marian E." TEIform="index"/>Marian E. Montague
                                </head><p TEIform="p">At Canterbury, W. H., Sept. 23, <persName reg="Montague, Marian E." TEIform="persName">Marian E.
                                        Montague</persName>, aged 19 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fair, Emily" TEIform="index"/>Emily Fair
                                </head><p TEIform="p">At Enfield, Conn., Sept. 24, <persName reg="Fair, Emily" TEIform="persName">Emily Fair</persName>, aged
                                    39 years.</p></div4></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>Home Topics</head><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Eggs, eggs" TEIform="index"/>EGGS, EGGS</head><div4 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Boiled eggs" TEIform="index"/>Boiled eggs
                                </head><p TEIform="p">Boiled Eggs.—The best way to boil eggs is not to boil them at all. Put them in a tin
                                    dish and pour on boiling water ; cover the dish tight and set back where the water
                                    will merely keep hot; let it stand there from ten to fifteen minutes, according to
                                    the size of the eggs or the preference of the eaters of " hard " or " softs." </p></div4><div4 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Scrambled eggs" TEIform="index"/>Scrambled eggs
                                </head><p TEIform="p">Scrambled Eggs.— Beat well ten eggs, have your spider quite hot; put in a piece of
                                    butter the size of an egg, and when melted turn the eggs in and stir every minute
                                    until all are cooked ; be careful not to cook too much. </p></div4><div4 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Devilled eggs" TEIform="index"/>Devilled eggs
                                </head><p TEIform="p"> Devilled Eggs.—Boil six eggs ten minutes, then lay in cold water till cold ; then
                                    cut in halves, slicing a little off the bottom of each, so they will stand upright.
                                    Remove the yolks, and rub a smooth paste with a little melted butter, a bit each of
                                    cayenne and mustard, and a teaspoonful of vinegar. Fill the hollow whites with this,
                                    and send to the table upon a bed of chopped white cabbage. Lettuce may be used
                                    instead of cabbage, if in season, and a spoonful should be used with half an egg.
                                </p></div4><div4 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dropped eggs" TEIform="index"/>Dropped eggs
                                </head><p TEIform="p">Dropped Eggs.—Have ready the skillet half-filled with salted water scalding hot,
                                    break each egg into a cup, and slip it carefully into the hot water, so as not to
                                    break the yolk. While the eggs are boiling, throw the water over the yolk with a
                                    spoon. When the white looks firm, take them out with a perforated skimmer. Trim them
                                    neatly, place each on a piece of buttered toast, and send them to the table hot.
                                    About onethird of the egg is solid nutriment. </p></div4><div4 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="'Boss' way to cook eggs" TEIform="index"/>Boss' way to cook eggs
                                </head><p TEIform="p">"Boss"way to cook Eggs.— Butter a tin plate and break in four eggs, set in a steamer;
                                    place over a kettle of boiling water and steam until the whites are thoroughly
                                    cooked. They are very ornamental broken into patty tins, as they keep their form
                                    better. The whites when cooked in this manner are tender and light.</p></div4><div4 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Have a saucepan of boiling water..." TEIform="index"/>Have a saucepan of boiling water...
                                </head><p TEIform="p"> Have a saucepan of boiling water, and drop fresh eggs carefully into it; let them
                                    stand where they will be hot, but not boil until the whites set. Toast some thin
                                    slices of bread nicely, lay them in a dish, and pour over a gill of rich hot cream
                                    salted to taste ; take up the eggs with a skimmer and put an egg on each slice of
                                    toast; sprinkle a little salt and pepper over, and garnish with parsely if you
                                    please. </p></div4><div4 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Omelette" TEIform="index"/>Omelette
                                </head><p TEIform="p"> Omelette.—One cup of sweet milk, in which strain two teaspoonfuls of cornstarch,
                                    salt to taste. Four eggs, whites and yolks beaten separately ; butter half size of
                                    an egg. Put it in a frying pan, make hot but not scorched. Stir quickly together,
                                    milk and yolks, and lastly whites, stir lightly and pour all into the hot butter.
                                    When browned lightly at bottom, turn one-half over the other and serve.</p></div4></div3><div3 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Readers of newspapers often meet with the term 'car load'..." TEIform="index"/>Readers of newspapers often meet with the term 'car load'...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Readers of newspapers often meet with the term " car load," but few of them know just
                                what or how much it is. The Saint I Louis Times has taken the trouble to learn and says,
                                as a general rule, 20,000 pounds, or 70 barrels of salt, 70 of lime, 90 of flour, 60 of
                                whisky, 200 sacks of flour, 6 cords of soft wood, 18 to 20 head of cattle, 50 to 60 head
                                of hogs, 80 to a hundred head of sheep, 9,000 feet of soUd boards, 17,000 feet of
                                siding, 13,000 feet of flooring, 40,000 shingles, one-half less of hard lumber, one
                                fourth less of green lumber, one-tenth of joists, scantling and all other large timber,
                                340 bushels of wheat, 300 of corn, 680 of oats, 400 of barley, 360 of flax seed, 350 of
                                ap. pies, 430 of Irish potatoes, 360 of sweet potatoes, 1,000 bushels of bran.</p></div3><pb n="258" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Corn cakes, for breakfast" TEIform="index"/>Corn Cakes, for Breakfast</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Beat together one egg, two tablespoons of sugar, two of melted butter,
                                        one-half teaspoon salt, two teacups cornmeal, one tablespoon flour, one teaspoon
                                        of cream tartar, mixed with the dry meal and flour, half a teaspoon soda, and
                                        two teacups of sweet milk. Dissolve the soda in the milk, and add last. Bake in
                                        a shallow tin pan, about fifteen minutes, in a well heated oven.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="People" TEIform="index"/>The People</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rice waffles for tea" TEIform="index"/>Rice Waffles for Tea</head><p TEIform="p">One quart of thin sour milk, poured over one teacupf ul of cold boiled rice. Do this two
                                or three hours before the waffles are wanted. When ready to bake add a pint and a half
                                of flour, two or three beaten eggs and soda. Oil the waffleirons each time they are
                                used, with lard that is perfectly sweet. The rice used for rice griddle cakes and
                                waffles should be salted when boiling. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A grain of blue vitriol, or carmine, will tinge a gallon of water, so that... " TEIform="index"/>A grain of blue vitriol, or carmine, will tinge a gallon of water, so that...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A grain of blue vitriol, or carmine, will tinge a gallon of water, so that in every drop
                                the color can be perceived ; and a grain of musk will scent a room for twenty years.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="White pine shingles on the Shaker Meeting-house in Canterbury..." TEIform="index"/>White pine shingles on the Shaker Meeting-house in Canterbury...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">White pine shingles on the Shaker Meeting-house in Canterbury, put on with wooden pins
                                eighty-six years ago, are still in a good state of preservation, and if left alone, will
                                last a half century longer. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Liquid shoe polish" TEIform="index"/>Liquid Shoe Polish</head><p TEIform="p">The following is a german recipe : Dissolve 3| ozs. of shellac in half a pint of alcohol.
                                Rub smooth 25 grains of lampblack with 6 drachms of cod liver oil, and mix. A few drops
                                are to be applied to the leather with a sponge. </p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to make good apple damplings" TEIform="index"/>HOW TO MAKE GOOD APPLE DUMPLINGS</head><p TEIform="p">First procure good, sour, juicy apples, pare and core, leaving them in halves. Get all
                                your ingredients ready before beginning to mix your dough, sugar, soda, milk, lard, salt
                                flour and apples. Now make a dough as for soda biscuits, only adding a little more lard
                                to make it shorter. Take a bit of dough out on the kneading board, and after kneading,
                                roll this as for pie crust. Then cut in pieces long enough to cover an apple, allowing
                                for lapping the edges. Put in two of your apple halves, sweeten according to taste, and
                                cover apple and sugar with dough. Lay your dumplings in your bread-pan, the smooth side
                                up, first having your pan well buttered. Proceed in this manner until you get your pan
                                well filled (be sure it is a large-sized pan, for they will go off like hot cakes) then
                                place a small bit of butter on the top of each dumpling, sprinkle a handful of sugar
                                over all ; then place in a moderate oven and allow them to bake one hour. Serve (not^too
                                hot) with pudding sauce or with cream and sugar. Dumplings made in this way are really
                                delicious.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Remedy for warts" TEIform="index"/>Remedy for Warts</head><p TEIform="p">Warts are very troublesome and disfiguring. The following is a perfect cure, even of the
                                largest, without leaving any scar. It is a Frenchman's prescription, and has been tested
                                by the writer: Take a small piece of raw beef, steep it all night in vinegar, cut as
                                much from it as will cover the wart, and tie on it, if the excrescence is on the
                                forehead, fasten it on with strips of sticking plaster. It may be removed in the day and
                                put on every night in one fortnight the wart will die and peel off. The same
                                prescription will cure corn.</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Turnipetts" TEIform="index"/>Turnipetts</head><p TEIform="p">The true way to cook a beet is to bake, not boil it. Thus treated and sliced either in
                                vinegar or in butter, it is much sweeter than when boiled, and said to be more
                                nutritious. I saved the vinegar in which my beets were pickled for dinner, and the next
                                day boiled a few small, young turnips, and sliced them up in the same vinegar. I added a
                                little fresh vinegar, pepper and salt, and no one at the table knew that they were not
                                eating white beets, until I called their attention to the fact.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Story of the old minister in Kentucky" TEIform="index"/>Story of the old minister in Kentucky
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Plummer" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">"I like," says Dr. Plummer, " the story of the old minister in Kentucky. Some one said rudely
                            to him, 'you have been preaching hereabouts for twenty years, and I never heard of your
                            converting but one man.' 'And who was that ?' inquired the humble preacher. A man of fine
                            Christian character was named to him. He modestly replied, ' I had not heard of that fact
                            before. Blessed, be the Lord for so great a mercy ! And now, by His divine help, here is at
                            it again for twenty years more, and if God shall save another soul, that will be two, and
                            either one of them will be worth more than all this world.' "</p></div2><pb n="259" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lest ye cut the angels' feet" TEIform="index"/>LEST YE CUT THE ANGELS' FEET</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">"Because of the angels."— 1st Corinthians xi, 10. I. " Take heed," say the Danish
                                    peasant-folks, As they gather around to eat, '¦ That ye lay not your knives with the
                                    edge upturn ed, Lest ye cut the angels'1 feet." II. See how the Father showeth
                                    these, His " babes," whom we despise, The things that hide in our mists of pride
                                    From us the " prudent " " wise." When shall we, in our common life, Have such sweet
                                    tender care For the angel band of friends who stand About us everywhere ? III. Nay,
                                    even at our higher boards, When we gather round to eat, How often still with "
                                    upturned " " knives " We " cut the angels' feet!"</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Queen" TEIform="index"/>The Queen.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="story" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Poor little Danny" TEIform="index"/>POOR LITTLE DANNY</head><p TEIform="p">There is a touch of Dickens in Little Danny's soliloquy over the death of his mother. We find
                            it in the New Orleans Picayune : I've just been down in the parlor to see mamma. She's in a
                            long box with flowera on her. I wish she'd come back and bathe my head—it aches so. Nobody
                            ever makes it feel good but mamma. She knew how it hurt me, and she used to read to me out
                            of a little book how my head would get well and not ache any more some day . I wish it was "
                            some day " now. Nobody likes me but mamma. That's cause I've got a sick head. Mamma used to
                            take me in her arms and cry. When I asked her what's the matter she would say, "I'm only
                            tired, darling. Aunt Anges made her tired, for when she came and stayed all day, mamma would
                            take me up in the evening on her lap and cry awful hard. I ain't had any dinner to day.
                            Mamma always gave me my dinner and a little trenty pudding with " D " for " Danny," on the
                            top. 1 like little puddings with D's on the top. I like to sit in my little chair by the
                            fire and eat 'em. I wish mamma wouldn't stay in the long box. I guess Aunt Agnes put her
                            there, cause she put all the flower trimmings on and shows her to everybody. There ain't any
                            fire in the grate, but I guess I'll sit by it and make believe there is. I'll get my little
                            dish and spoon and play I've got a pudding with D for Danny on it. But any way I want mamma
                            so bad.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ill temper" TEIform="index"/>ILL TEMPER</head><p TEIform="p">A single person of sour, sullen temper — what a dreadful thing it is to have such a one in a
                            house ! There is not myrrh and aloes and chloride of lime enough in the world to disinfect a
                            single home of such a nuisance as that; no riches, no elegance of mien, no beauty of face
                            can ever screen such persons from utter vulgarity. Ill temper is the most vulgar thing that
                            the lowest born and illest bred can ever bring to his home. It is one of the worst forms of
                            impiety. Peevishness in a home is not only a sin against the Holy Ghost, but sin against the
                            Holy Ghost in the very temple of love.</p><byline TEIform="byline">— <persName reg="Parker, Theodore" TEIform="persName"/>Theodore Parker</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Heathen missionary" TEIform="index"/>A HEATHEN MISSIONARY</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">It is some years since the Chinese philosopher, through Mr. Oliver Goldsmith,
                                    expressed his opinion that, considering the superior morality of the people of China
                                    over those of England, it was little else than impudence to send missionaries there
                                    to teach a religion that had so little influence in a country where it had been
                                    taught for centuries. The disciple of Confucius also suggested that it would be much
                                    more to the purpose if China should send her missionaries to the benighted western
                                    world. What Goldsmith's Celestial friend imagined has well come to pass in these
                                    latter days ; the religions of the East are pushing their pickets into the West, and
                                    there are Buddhists and Confucians in London and New York, who are not Asiatics. And
                                    now comes the Chinese itinerant, Wong Chin Foo, to reveal to the American people the
                                    fact,—which only Parson Murray, Index Abbot, Col. Olcott and a few other
                                    theosophists have heretofore suspected—that there are other religions than the
                                    Christian, good enough to live by. Wong Chin Foo begins his mission in rather
                                    unpropitious associations with a <pb n="260" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 260 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO.
                                    number of queer people who train in the theosophist set, but it is unfortunately
                                    true that only very queer people are willing, in this country or any other, to give
                                    fair play and opportunity to a downright heathen. He is something of a character,
                                    and has quite a history for one so young. Though only 26, he has visited this
                                    country twice, has been an officer of the imperial government at Shanghai, and a
                                    rebel against the present Tartar emperor. For this last a price was set on his head,
                                    and he was hunted for months, never getting into such serious danger as when he put
                                    himself into the hands of English missionaries, who, finding out who he was, decided
                                    to give him up to the emperor. He remonstrated against their betrayal of him to
                                    torture and final execution by cutting into 18 pieces ; but they promised to obtain
                                    him the favor of simply having his head cut off, and thereupon locked him in a room,
                                    and told him to put his trust in Jesus. Disregarding this very practical advice, he
                                    broke out and got to the coast, where an irreligious seaman gave him passage to
                                    Japan. Thence he came to San Francisco on a steamer which carried in the steerage
                                    200 Chinese young women of the lower class, imported for infamous purposes ; and on
                                    arriving he went into the courts and secured their freedom and return to their
                                    country. He has spent a year or two in study, and during the past winter has
                                    lectured in several western cities. The addresses of Wong Chin Foo are not, so far
                                    as we find them reported, nearly so remarkable as the fact of his giving them. He
                                    does not make so strong a case for the Buddhist and Confucian faiths as W. H. H.
                                    Murray did in his lecture on the heathenism of modern Christianity, which made such
                                    a stir some years ago. Yet he puts sharply enough several contrasts not to our
                                    credit. He challenges any man in America, any missionary in Asia, to say that he
                                    ever heard one of the 450,000,000 of Chinese take the name of God in vain. How would
                                    we face such a challenge ? The Chinese put millions of money in wooden boxes less
                                    than an inch thick, though, says Wong Chin Foo, if the missionaries should ever
                                    thoroughly convert China, iron safes would have to be introduced to keep out
                                    burglars. The Christians have a commandment to honor parents, but a Chinaman would
                                    think the average Christian's love for his father and mother horrible neglect. After
                                    various such contrasts as these, the " Heathen " naturally objects to the arrogant
                                    conceit that all adult heathens are destined to hell-fire,—which it is true,
                                    scarcely any Christian believes, but which a.certain body of clergy in New York city
                                    recently declared in a formal resolution. Wong Chin Foo's self-imposed mission may
                                    be too heavy for him, but it cannot be called wholly gratuitous. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New York times" TEIform="index"/>N. Y. Times.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Crosses" TEIform="index"/>CROSSES</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A story is told of an old man who lived long ago. Forcible was the way in which
                                    he spoke of the struggle he had to carry on, A friend asked him the cause of his
                                    complaints, since in the evening he so often complained of great weariness and pain.
                                    " Alas, I have every day so much to do. I have two falcons to tame, two hares to
                                    keep from running away, two hawks to manage, a serpent to confine, a lion to chain,
                                    and a sick man to tend and wait upon." " Why, this is only folly," said the friend;
                                    " no man has all these things to do at once." "Yes, indeed," he answered, "it is
                                    with me as I have said. The two falcons are my two eyes, which I must diligently
                                    guard, lest something should please them which may be hurtful to my salvation; the
                                    two hares are my feet, which I must hold back, lest they should run after evil
                                    objects and walk in the ways of sin ; the two hawks are my two hands which I must
                                    train and keep to work, in order that I may be able to provide for my brethren who
                                    are in need ; the serpent is my tongue, which I must always keep in with a bridle,
                                    lest it should speak any thing unseemly ; the lion is my heart, with which I have to
                                    maintain a continual fight, in order that vanity and pride may not fill it, but that
                                    the grace of God may dwell and work there ; the sick man is my own body, which is
                                    ever needing my watchfulness and care. All this daily wears out my strength." The
                                    friend listened in wonder, and then said : " Dear brother, if all men labored and
                                    struggled after this manner, the times would be better, and more according to the
                                    will of God."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="261" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Trust" TEIform="index"/>TRUST</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName"/>Abraham Perkins</byline><p TEIform="p">Enfield, N. H. 1. Bless us through all cares and burdens, O'er the stormy sea of life; 2.
                            Weak and frail when strength is greatest, Then but little we impart; 3. Precious, faith
                            which hath preserved us, By the mercy of our God; Stay us Lord in our affliction, Help us in
                            the glorious strife. When our off'rings are most perfect, Feeble is the human heart. Never
                            can our souls reject it, Never slight the living word. Though the way be rough and thorny,
                            Flowers often hidden be, Still we ask thy kind forbearance, Till we are made strong and
                            free, Unto Thee, O Heavenly Father, Life and strength we will renew, Perilous the road we
                            travel, We will ever trust in Thee. Lord, Thou art our sure defender, Center all our hopes
                            in Thee. What the trial, what the conflict, We'll be loyal firm and true.</p></div2><pb n="262" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="world news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Food question" TEIform="index"/>THE FOOD QUESTION</head><p TEIform="p">The question of food presents itself in such a manner in England that statesmen and every-day
                            people recognize the necessity of meeting it fairly. In the severe competition upon which
                            manufacturing nations have entered, the land system of England becomes a heavy weight upon
                            the industry of that country. Parks and flower-gardens and lawns and spacious grounds around
                            aristocratic mansions are pleasant things to look upon; but they produce no food. Large
                            estates, yielding princely incomes from the rents paid by those who work the land, may suit
                            wealthy land-owners, but they augment the cost of agricultural products and cause much
                            embarrassment to the people who must work for small wages or abandon the hope of retaining
                            foreign markets for their manufactures. In former years England received a very large part
                            of the American cotton crop, and, with the superior machinery in use there, the spinners
                            converted much of it into thread, which was sold on the Continent. The nations now most
                            largely engaged in producing cotton fabrics will spin most of their own yarn. England
                            manufactures large quantities of cotton goods which are sold in the West Indies, Mexico,
                            Central and South America, and to a great extent are paid for with coffee, sugar and
                            tropical fruits, which she sells to the United States. But efforts are now being made by
                            American manufacturers to secure a part of this lucrative trade. In some other articles of
                            manufacture this country is likely to become a successful competitor with England, and the
                            statesmen of the latter country do not clearly see in what articles their manufacturers and
                            producers can pay, directly and indirectly, for the vast amount of food and materials which
                            they must get from this country. The manufacturing nations of the Continent, under ordinary
                            circumstances, do not have to buy so much of the food of the people, and the latter are
                            accustomed to the most economical manner of living. Capitalists and employers are satisfied
                            with small interest and earnings, and consequently they become formidable competitors with
                            those of England. It becomes evident* therefore, that England must reduce the cost of food,
                            or suffer in the great contest for trade with her energetic and persevering rivals. How can
                            she do this? Very rarely are suggestions which are designed to reduce the cost of living
                            received with favor. In a time of business stringency the late Horace Greeley undertook to
                            show that more wholesome, nutritious and palatable food could be procured by families at
                            much less cost than the articles to which they were accustomed ; but most persons resented
                            the well-intentioned advice, regarding it as an attempt to degrade them in their social
                            condition. If an English philanthropist at this time would demonstrate that the proper
                            selection and preparation of articles of less cost than the roast beef, plum pudding and
                            wheaten bread of the English people would improve their health and increase their comfort,
                            he would receive more rebukes than thanks for his pains. In this country one of the most
                            popular articles of food in its season is green corn, and the variety of delicacies which
                            are made from corn starch is such as to place it among our chief luxuries. In the Southern
                            States the wealthier people prefer some of the simple forms of corn bread to that made from
                            the finest wheat flour. But if Indian corn were suggested to an Englishman as a superior
                            article of food, he would most probably reply, with an expression of disgust, that it is
                            "horse food." Powerful prejudices have to be encountered in any effort to introduce
                            innovations. It is possible that England's prosperity may yet be influenced by the judicious
                            use of American corn.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Five minutes" TEIform="index"/>FIVE MINUTES</head><p TEIform="p">At the commencement at Charlier Institute, Dr. S. Irenaeus Prime spoke to the young men as
                            follows : I am invited to speak to you five minutes — and only five. Little may be said, and
                            much may be done, in five minutes. In five minutes you may fire a city, scuttle a ship, or
                            ruin a soul. The error of a moment makes the sorrow of a life. Get that <pb n="263" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. 263 thought well into your hearts, and my work is done in a minute,
                            instead of five. Tempted to sin, remember that in five minutes you may destroy 'your good
                            name, fill your soul with undying remorse, and bring, with sorrow, your father's gray hair
                            to the grave. But if you can do so much evil, so you may do a mighty sum of good in five
                            minutes. You may decide to live for usefulness and honor. Every thing hangs on that choice,
                            and it may be made in five minutes. Take care of the pence and the pounds will take care of
                            themselves ; take care of the minutes and the hours are safe. I made a little book in this
                            way ; in the breakfastroom were pen and ink and paper ; and if, when the hour for breakfast
                            came, all was not ready, I wrote a few words or lines, as time allowed. The book was
                            finished, and it had been published scarcely a week before I heard it had saved a soul ; it
                            has saved many since. It did not cost me one minute that would have been used for any thing
                            else. Five minutes in the morning, and as many in the evening, will make you 'the master of
                            a new language in two or three years. Before you are of middle age you may speak all the
                            modern tongues, if you will but improve the spare minutes of the years now flying by.
                            Minutes are more than jewels; they are " the stuff that life is made of ; " they are diamond
                            stepping-stones to wisdom, usefulness and wealth ; the ladder to Heaven. It will not take
                            five minutes to do a good deed, and one a day will make a life of honor and usefulness, with
                            glory beyond.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Please stop my—what?" TEIform="index"/>"PLEASE STOP MY-" WHAT?</head><p TEIform="p">" Times are hard, money is scarce, business is dull, retrenchment is a duty. Please stop my—"
                            Whisky 1 " Oh no ! times are not hard enough for that yet. But there is something else that
                            costs me a large amount of money every year, which I wish to save. Please stop my—" Tobacco,
                            cigars and snuff? "No, no! not these. But I must retrench somewhere. Please stop my—"
                            Ribbons, jewels, ornaments and trinkets ? " Not at all—not at all! pride must be fostered,
                            if times are ever so hard. But I believe I can see a way to effect quite a saving in another
                            direction; please stop my—" Tea, coffee, and needless and unhealthy luxuries ? " No, no, no
                            ! not these. I cannot think of a sacrifice ; I must think of something else. Ah ! I have it
                            now. My paper costs eight cents a month—one dollar a year ; I must save that. Please stop my
                            paper ; that will carry me through the panic easily. I believe in retrenchment and economy,
                            especially in brains."—[Household.</p></div2><div2 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Disinfectants" TEIform="index"/>DISINFECTANTS</head><p TEIform="p">The Commission of Experts appointed by the National Board of Health to prepare a circular
                            embodying familiar instructions for disinfectants, have made a report to the board. The
                            disinfectants to be used are : First, roll sulphur for fumigation; second, sulphate of iron
                            and copperas dissolved in water in the [proportion of If pounds to a gallon for soil,
                            sewers, etc. ; third, sulphate of zinc and common salt dissolved together in water in the
                            proportion of four ounces of sulphate of zinc and two ounces of salt to a gallon of water
                            for clothing, bed linen, etc. The commission excludes carbolic acid for the reason that it
                            is difficult to secure the proper quality, and that it must be used in large quantities to
                            be of service.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hearts of the lowly" TEIform="index"/>THE HEARTS OF THE LOWLY</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> One day three or four weeks ago a gamin, who seemed to have no friends in the
                                    world, was run over by a vehicle on Gratiot avenue, and fatally injured. After he
                                    had been in the hospital for a week, a boy about his own age and size, and looking
                                    as friendless and forlorn, called to ask about him and to leave an orange. He seemed
                                    much embarrassed, and would answer no questions. After that he came daily, always
                                    bringing something, if no more than an apple. Last week, when the nurse told him
                                    that Billy had no chance to get well, the strange boy waited around longer than
                                    usual, and finally asked if he could go in. He had been invited to many times
                                    before, but had always <pb n="264" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/> 264 THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. refused.
                                    Billy, pale and weak and emaci ated, opened his eyes in wonder at sight o: the boy,
                                    and before he realized who it wa the stranger bent close to his face and sob bed: "
                                    Billy, can you forgive a feller ? We was allus fighting and I was allus too mud for
                                    ye, but I'm sorry ! 'Pore ye die won' ye tell me ye haven't any grudge agin me ?'
                                    The young lad, then almost in the shadow of death, reached up his thin, white arms
                                    clasped them around the other's neck, anc replied: " Don't cry, Bob — don't feel bad
                                    ! I was ugly and mean, and I was heaving a stone at ye when the wagon hit me. If
                                    ye'll for give me I'll forgive you, and I'll pray for both o' us 1 " Bob was half an
                                    hour late the morning Billy died. When the nurse took him to the shrouded corpse he
                                    kissed the pale face tenderly and gasped: " D-did he say anything about — about me?"
                                    " He spoke of you just before he died — asked if you were here," replied the nurse.
                                    " And may I go—go to the funeral ? " " You may." And he did. He was the only
                                    mourner. His heart was the only one that ached. No tears were shed by others, and
                                    they left him sitting by the new-made grave with heart so big that he could not
                                    speak. If, under the crust of vice and ignorance, there are such springs of pure
                                    feeling and true nobility, who shall grow weary of doing good!</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Detroit free press" TEIform="index"/>Detroit Free Press.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vast waste of life and money" TEIform="index"/>THE VAST WASTE OF LIFE AND MONEY</head><p TEIform="p">The St. Petersburg Gazette publishes a summary of the cost in lives and money of the great
                            wars of the last twenty-five years. The Crimean war cost the lives of 750,000 men ; the
                            Italian war (1859), 45,000; Schleswig-Holstein war, 3,000 ; the PrussoAustrian war (1866),
                            45,000 ; the Mexican Expedition, 65,000; the Franco-Prussian war, 215,000 ; the
                            Russo-Turkish war, 600,000 ; a total of 1,748,000, or with the 800,000 killed in the
                            American Rebellion, 2,548,000. This number does not include deaths from the various diseases
                            incident to war. The cost in money is estimated as follows, viz.: The Crimean war cost the
                            countries engaged $1,700,000,000; the Italian, $300,000,000; the American, $7,400,000,000;
                            the Schleswig-Holstein, $35,000,000; the PrussoAustrian, $330,000,000; the Mexican
                            Expedition, $200,000,000; the Franco-Prussian, $2,500,000,000 ; the Russo-Turkish,
                            $1,250,000,000; a total of $13,715,000,000.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Business morality" TEIform="index"/>BUSINESS MORALITY</head><p TEIform="p">Religion bids men be honest, not because honesty is the best policy merely ; be truthful, not
                            because lying is unmanly only ; be temperate, not because intemperate habits weaken the
                            intellect and impair the vital energy, and, in short, put you outside the pale of society;
                            but be all these from one supreme, absorbing motive, the fear you have of offending a loving
                            God. It will be the thought of God and of Christ which will alone make us true to man. Our
                            religion will not be of that kind which displays deep emotion in the words of our lips, and
                            then goes out to drive very hard bargains, if not to steal. And what do some men mean by
                            this business morality ? Surely not that God allows and winks at some recognized code of
                            signals by which, if one man can overreach another, it is all fair play. Are the strict
                            commandments of God to be admitted in the church, and an expurgated and revised edition hung
                            up in the counting louse ? Of many business transactions it may be said, " Everybody does
                            it;" but ,he Christian man will say, " So do not I, because of the fear of God."</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pray, sisters, pray" TEIform="index"/>PRAY, SISTERS, PRAY</head><p TEIform="p">When women pray, The dear Lord listens well. He only knows How many piercing thorns fall in
                            their way For every rose. He sees alone, Of countless heavenly seeds their weak hands sow,
                            And tend with hope, how many fall for one That cares to grow. He, only He, Can gauge the
                            love that, faithful waited on Beside the Martyr's cross at Calvary When all were gone.</p></div2><!--
    				<pb n="p29"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>