<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ss0410" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">Shaker and Shakeress</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Society</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Mount Lebanon, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">4</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">10</biblScope><date value="18741001" TEIform="date">October 1874</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">73-80</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="4" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="73" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="10" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!-- 
                        <p>Vol. IV. No. 10. F. W. EVANS EUTTOK. PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETY. Mt. Lebanon, Col. Co. N. Y. October, 1874,
                        Fifty Cents per. annum.</p>
                    --><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Social gathering" TEIform="index"/>SOCIAL GATHERING</head><p TEIform="p">On the 19th August, we, the Gathering Order of Mt. Lebanon Shakers, held, for the seventeenth
                            time, our annual social union meeting — never once having failed for want of weather. Not
                            only have we had weather enough, but it has been, as on this occasion, simply perfect.
                            Whether this has happened to be so by chance, or has occurred under Law, and by design of
                            interested parties in the two worlds, is an open question. One hundred and fourteen were on
                            the ground. All enjoyed the occasion, without a drawback. Dialogues, in which from four to
                            seven took part, were enacted. Short speeches were delivered by many. Over fifty original
                            articles and treatises were read, mostly by the writers. It was a foretaste of Heaven. The
                            general feeling was, by a young sister, thus expressed: "I do not believe there ever was,
                            since the world was made, any thing quite so good as our Annual Social Gathering." Meetings
                            should be times of religious confidence among those who assemble — the interior soul
                            feelings coming from the heavens, grounded in the conscience, can then find confession and
                            expression. If the meetings of natural men and women are free, in the mutual confidence of a
                            common sensuality, to those therein immersed, how much more free should be the meeting of
                            souls, in the God element, for spiritual iudgment and mutual elevation. How sacred should
                            such occasions be held, and all things therewith connected. The proper use of secretiveness
                            is to conceal those things that are too good to be communicated — not common. A true,
                            religious meeting is a prophesy of union, in a permanent, spiritually religious life — a
                            meeting that will never break up. When that high order is attained, the past will become the
                            present, and the present will be eternity. The loves and affections will have become
                            spiritualized. We shall have found real fathers and mothers, brothers and sisters — Gospel
                            relations, who will be as unchangeable as truth, as kind and loving as their Father and
                            Mother — God.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Old world dies" TEIform="index"/>THE OLD WORLD DIES</head><p TEIform="p">And what have we to do about it ? Why, to join with angel hands who are demolishing its
                            corrupt but lingering institutions, political social and religious, for " passing away " is
                            written on all effete institutions of the age. " The yesterdays are gone. Let them go." As
                            the new born sun of righteousness peers in upon the pathway of the pure in heart, enabling
                            them to " see God " and walk " in the light of life," the crude crutches of a limping faith
                            in God, fall from their grasp. And as we see the erect living human temple — a soul arrayed
                            in truth — walking in the garden of the Lord, and beckoning us on to Elysium, a healing
                            inspiration thrills our being and makes us whole in faith that a power is about to be shed
                            upon humanity, causing it to seek after God and Heaven ; a power that makes " all tilings
                            new and all things of God" in the new Earth and new Heavens. In inimitable music a new song
                            bursts upon our souls, with our spirit eye we look down the aisles of time, of man-made
                            churches and human creeds, and see the platforms of theological error being removed plank by
                            plank. Delusions, as strongly set as the pyramids of the ages — delusions — which have been
                            the arbiters of faith, the fruitful source of division in the churches called Christian, and
                            the dominating rule in secular policies, severing the fraternal bonds of nations, and
                            bathing them in blood — are being destroyed by angel hands. Shells of truth are being
                            cracked, the kernel tasted; invigorated by its nourishment, God's agents are turning the old
                            world of error and sin, upside down. The soul of institutions, political, social, moral and
                            religious is being disrobed of garments that have deceived their votaries and the new born
                            mind, and resurrected spirit, is discovering the motors that are moving humanity to day. The
                            fulsome, hypocritical, selfish policies, that have organized and directed human governments,
                            both mundane and religious, will be exhumed and exposed, their base purposes comprehended by
                            the common mind, and truth, simple as the driving wheel of a velocipede, will be harnessed
                            to the car of human progress, propelling it onward to the goal of God. Rays of light — the
                            life examples of those who follow Christ are beaming upon the theological cloud —" mystery
                            of Godliness " — and it is found to be as simple as the two halves of an orange. The
                            Christian's God is not a triple headed male monster, not the theologically created, baleful,
                            vengeful tyrant who destroys human beings at his pleasure ; blesses and saves whom he will,
                            and damns whom he pleases, without regard to good or evil deeds. God is, in esse, a bisexual
                            being— the Heavenly Parentage of man. The Father revealed by Jesus, first born Heavenly Son.
                            The mother, by Ann, first born Heavenly Daughter. Ann Lee, imitating Jesus, in practical
                            life of Godliness, aided by the life of her children, establishes the fact of the Motherhood
                            of God, even as did the life of Jesus, the Fatherhood. They twain reveal the " new man" in
                            Christ. Mediatorially the Divine will and purpose both for the " new Earth and new Heaven"
                            are vouchsafed to man. The first by the light of a burning bush, through the thundering
                            Sinai, by commandments, etched on tables of stone, by a voice, through the ministration of
                            angels. The latter, by a succession of ministering spirits, and by souls, redeemed from sin
                            and wrong — the harvest of honest confession and repentance. Commencing with Jesus, then
                            extending down, through male and female witnesses, who, by obedience, keep heavenly relation
                            to the Divine Mind, until the testimony reaches the most debased human soul who may be
                            resurrected and elevated to the Divine Life. Christianity, instead of being a mummy saint,
                            eighteen hundred years old, dead in formulas, and smothered in ceremonies, without the life
                            of God, wrapt about with a winding sheet of human creeds; embalmed by imputed righteousness
                            ; encased in a petrified sarcophagus of the blood of Jesus, and healed of the wounds of sin
                            by the stripes of a Judean thong, in its reappearing is discovered to be a character, new
                            born, living, consisting of righteousness. Its vital currents pulsated in the veins of the
                            baptized Jesus as by humiliation he learned obedience by the things he suffered, and became
                            a " son of God," the same vitalizing spirit flows in the life currents of every true
                            follower of Christ. By the light of this new born gospel day, Christian atonement, for
                            humanity's ransom, is manifested by each individual on the altar of self denial, as did
                            Jesus, Peter, Paul, Ann, and others. In fine, the mysterious cloudy creed of theological
                            Christianity, called Catholic, with its posthumous salvation in sin, by death bed
                            declaration of faith in Jesus' death; ita water baptisms for soul purifications ; its
                            elections to salvation and damnation by Divine arbitration, without regard to works; its
                            free grace redemptions without repentance of sin; its glorifications without righteousness ;
                            its withering damnation by eternal punishment— without eternal sin ; its mysterious
                            eucharist; its triune male God; aye, its whole mystic churchal cloud, is swept away like the
                            dew, by the rays of the sun of this new born day of God. The old world dies! Christian
                            discipleship instead of being faith alone, is discovered to consist of confession and
                            repentance of sin; and redemption from its nature by crosses, thus becoming sons and
                            daughters of God — our Heavenly Father and Mother. The Christian's God is just and
                            righteous, yet merciful and forgiving. No human being is so cruel and unjust as to punish
                            the most perfectly good man for the sins of all the rest of humanity; much less will the
                            Christian's God punish man on that principle, and still less punish a fellow God. <pb n="74" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 74= SHAKEE Truth is come, the soul that sins, dies, the soul who works
                            righteousness lives. The confessing, repenting sinner is resurrected to spiritual life in
                            God and peace with man. Good works are sermons, more potent than the orations of
                            Demosthenes, the folio opinions of Calvin, Luther, or the Romish Pope. Ceasing to do evil
                            will more effectually cast out the devil than hurling a Lutheran inkstand at his head. A
                            righteous life weds its possessor to God, and thus mated—Jesus like—the human soul hath
                            boldness without egotism ; power without usurpation; authority without priestly laying on of
                            hands; pathos without human affectation ; mercy without partiality; justice without revenge;
                            love without lust; peace without sacrifice of principle, and honor with- out throne of regal
                            state. This was the amulet of Jesus! The germinal principles of human law for the protection
                            and guidance of society, needs to be purgated of the hypocrisy and deceit that now hide the
                            motive of self interest of rulers. And the greatest good of the greatest number must become
                            the laws. The old world dies, let it die. For the day is dawning when both political and
                            theological potentates shall know that there is a power above the thrones of church or
                            state, to which all knees shall bow , a simple creed, which all tongues shall confess as
                            authority, and that creed is given in two words — Godly life.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>Elder Giles B. Avery, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Situation" TEIform="index"/>THE SITUATION</head><p TEIform="p">Never did the theological world, present the appearance of " choose ye this day whom ye will
                            serve," more than the present time. At no period, since the Reformation, have there been as
                            many departures from the so-called orthodoxies as now ; nor so few successes for the
                            churches, that arraign their heretics, as since the beginning of the last half of the
                            nineteenth century. That there is a leaven hidden in the earth, that is working mischief
                            with man-made creeds and unsavory dogmas, is apparent to the dullest comprehension ; and
                            that this leaven is making Babylon, worse confounded, in the social and religious circles of
                            the earthly order, is cogent, even to the minds of those, not given to reflection.
                            Infidelity in the efficacy of infant baptism: incredulity to infallibility ; tendency to the
                            confessional, and the preference of good works before good faith, are but drops before the
                            shower, that will lead to many followers of the recent apostates, of these, and many similar
                            pre-supposed, infallible theological enactments. The expulsion of one Hyacinthe, is only the
                            rearing of the standard of a new departure, that has more followers than tongue can tell.
                            The " Swing " recently enacted at Chicago, with procedures there, of the same character, not
                            long ago, will be followed by hundreds of cases more defiant than these; should the Churches
                            accept the challenge, which the gospel of common sense seems daily multiplying, as with
                            arithmetical progression. The arraignment of a Cuyler, for recognizing that woman is equally
                            a saviour with man; and that it is only heathenish, and worse, to fail of acknowledging that
                            God is as much female as male; and the employment of Smiley and her Sisters, are making this
                            proclamation a home-thrust, in thousands of hearts, where, by no other agency, could it
                            possibly enter. This arraignment is one of the largest blessings in disguise — the sprouting
                            of a truth, in a new field, that " will not down " at the bidding of all the Churches
                            combined. God be praised, and blessed be Cuyler ! The scare of the Elmira
                            Congregationalists, as given by their noble pastor, in the advocacy of oral confession,
                            comes in for a share of our admiration, and is a notable " straw" that indicates the
                            inclination of the " situation," as being more towards Christianity, than towards Romanism.
                            And to this Beecher, of Elmira, is credited the advice to his Brooklyn Brother, of "
                            preaching less philosophy, and practicing more Christianity." No " sorrow " would follow
                            such action. The union, of the " old and new " schools, has its significance, that points to
                            less hair-splitting theology, and more real philanthropy. The universal admission that
                            Presbyterians and Universalists are nearer, and more loving neighbors, bears evidence of the
                            fact that predestination, foreordination, and total depravity, will eventually lie in one
                            common grave. What means the departure from entire reliance on the vicarious atonement
                            theory ? a declension in Methodistic mummery of leaving the whole debt for Jesus to pay ;
                            and the more prevalent demand for good works, than for good faith ? Not one Wesleyan in ten,
                            now clings to the atonement, with the confidence and tenacity of thirty years ago! Can we
                            pass by the revolt against the mili- tary drill in the Colleges, as having no significance
                            upon the religious situation ? And the general desire of the nation, as expressed through
                            its representatives, to reduce its army and navy ; does this arise from its financial
                            situation, or from the advanced ground of moral necessity ? What means the iconoclasm of
                            English, German and Italian States, with others, against their union with the Church ? What
                            happiness may we feel, that God, through the people, refuses the admission of his or her
                            name, or that of Jesus Christ, Ann Lee, Virgin Mary, the Methodist, or any other Church
                            within the constitution of these United States ! And following the progress of truth, when
                            should we stop ? The Second Adventists and thousands of others, have thankfully lost hope in
                            a physical resurrection, after death. Spiritualists are learning that spiritualism is no
                            more of a salvation to them, than is the cast-off faith of the blood of Jesus. Men and women
                            of all denominations are learning that they are sinners ; and that there is no way out of
                            sin, except by a self-denying repentance, that stops their sinning ; and good works are at a
                            higher premium, even outside of religious denominations, than is the most popular
                            persuasion, without good works. The primitive Christian Church, is brought into better
                            repute, in these days, than for hundreds of years in the past; and a demand for its
                            repetition, as a Christian necessity, is now more easily evoked than for ages. Churches are
                            admitting the great disparity of brotherhood, between the first Christian Church, and the
                            popular so-called Churches of to-day ; and reforms are already numerous. The multitudes
                            recognize great departure in their lives — however good members of popular Churches they may
                            be — from the life Jesus lived ; the life his disciples lived in that day, after their
                            conversion ; and the life which his followers — Christians — are only justified in living
                            to-day. Upon reviewing the situation, I am more than satisfied that the progress is in the
                            right direction; and that in the life and works of humble, but unpopular Christianity, the
                            Shaker saints, in their heavens upon earth, are still the Vanguard.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/>Elder G. A. Lomas, Watervliet, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pleasant Hill, Kentucky, July 28, 1874" TEIform="index"/>Pleasant Hill, Ky., July 28,1874</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Christian Brother — For the letter you wrote me two weeks ago, I am thankful: and as
                                I am in doubt as to duty on one, if not two points, please advise me. First — Can I
                                consistently unite without fully believing in the dual and sexual nature of God; or the
                                inspiration, or Motherhood of Ann Lee ? Her practical good, in the line of progress, I
                                gratefully accept, as I do yours and other Reformers.' The celibacy, communism in
                                property, anti-war, fashion, style and cast of your societies — including equality of
                                the sexes — have been my principles for years, excepting the first, which I now accept.
                                But to the " sacred roll and book " I demur. It may be even so, but as I am careful, and
                                possibly slow to prove all things, it is not yet so proven to my mind as to command
                                belief. Second — If I ought to unite, should I stay here or go to you ? As a visitor I
                                came hither one week ago. As you know, the location is favorable, the more aged members
                                industrious, frugal, and in all substantial s worthy ; and yet Conservative. Whereto
                                they have attained, they literally walk by the same rule : not forgetting things behind,
                                nor reaching forth to any new things before. I must reform and progress. They,
                                especially Paulina Bryant, Chief Eldress, and all sisters including the children, are
                                urging me to abide, and influence my wife and two daughters to come. With your people I
                                know there is more congeniality and enjoyment. Here, more need of my work. Can it be
                                done ? Will they hear, or even forbear? May they—the Elders — not go so far as to forbid
                                my efforts to reform ? For their work hands and visitors they cook poTk, lard, tea and
                                coffee and other unclean things — using, themselves, these bad drinks — and raising
                                swine on one part of their grounds — the mill. I fear they are sliding back to the
                                world, in eating, drinking and drugging. Progress, in science — practical facts in God's
                                works—they ignore, save four or five members. Can I be blessed with the wisdom of the
                                serpent and harmlessness of the dove, sufficient to persuade them onwards and upwards ?
                                The few minds, here, in sympathy with progress, discourage the hope yet wish me to stay.
                                Their property, worth near half a million, united with their great cause of human
                                purity, is too much to be lost. But their agriculture, horticulture, house-keeping,
                                hygiene, and in a word, all, needs improvement. Ought I, the least of all saints, to try
                                in my humble way? I enclose a testimonial as to a little of what I have done, and send
                                you a copy of my treatise, years ago on suffrage. In the confidence of a Christian
                                Brother, I hope to receive your advice. They have extended, to me, the utmost kindness,
                                and heard me, for twenty minutes, last Sabbath; but seem to fear widening from the old
                                paths, not to say ruts. By no means would I change a jot of the first genuine faith; but
                                desire to learn all the useful our Father has for us, in A.3STD <pb n="75" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/>
                                these latter days. As I expect to remain a week, or ten days longer, please write me
                                here. With due esteem and Christian regard, I am your unworthy Brother, Have Dr. Trail's
                                diploma, have treated sick for fifteen or twenty years, and lost but one patient, and he
                                because he left my prescription. ----W. P.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, W." TEIform="persName"/>W. Perkins</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, July 31, 1874" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, July 31, 1874</head><p TEIform="p">W. Perkins, Dear Friend—Your letter of 28th inst. is at hand. You ask if you can, "
                                consistently, unite, without fully believing in the duality and sexuality of God, and in
                                the inspiration and motherhood of Ann Lee." Jesus asked the questioners, in his day —
                                "How can ye believe, who seek honor, one of another ? " If any man will do the works, he
                                shall know and understand the doctrine. The physical, moral and spiritual state, of a
                                person, determines his or her power or capacity of belief. We have, in our family, a
                                person, who was obedient to and observant of the rules of the family, for about a year,
                                before he traveled to deep, spiritual, religious conviction of sin; and believed, with
                                all his heart, the doctrines of our system. I have been under the influence of the
                                system, some forty-four years, and its principles and beautiful doctrines were never so
                                brightly expanding, enlarging and absorbingly interesting, as at this present time. I
                                would believe, because I could not help it; practice, because I could not,
                                conscientiously, do otherwise — would preach it for the love of humanity, if left, like
                                Elijah, all alone. / have life in myself. The fruit of the Gospel tree attracts you to
                                it. If you come as a little child — a learner — you will gather to and respect those who
                                have done the works; but who do not yet fully know of the increase of the Gospel doc-
                                trines. If, in them, there be any love of self, any lack of self denial, that the
                                increasing testimony— the second thunder — would take cognizance of, new comers have
                                need of patience, until such as have been, for so many years, doing the will of God, in
                                obeying the testimony of the first Gospel degree — the first thunder — shall receive
                                their reward, which will be power to "increase with the increase of God." " To as many
                                as received him, to them gave he power to become the Sons of God and Daughters of God."
                                That was the pay they received. It will be so with the old Believers —genuine Shakers.
                                You need the Gospel that they have lived. They need the increase that you see, but have
                                not yet lived. You can well afford to bear with them, if they can bear with you. You
                                should not rebel against them because of the truths they do not yet practice. And they,
                                in the Christ spirit, can do nothing against the truths, you see, but cannot reduce to
                                practice until you do the first works which they have done — confess and forsake all the
                                sins you see in yourself, and hate the flesh. Hate your own generative life, with all
                                the relations growing out of it, without hating your own person or hating any other
                                persons. Fulfill all contracts, or legally dissolve them. Perform all duties that that
                                order has created. I do not see how you can help believing in the duality of God —
                                except from bad diet — for all things are dual. If you believe in God as the fountain
                                from whence so many dual streams flow, "believe also in me," and with me, that God is
                                and is dual. And so with the motherhood of Ann Lee. Why. she had four natural children,
                                and she has thousands of spiritual children, yourself included. Will you deny her
                                motherhood ? If you did not believe her inspiration, verbally, believe for her works'
                                sake. But you do believe. Lord help your unbelief. As to the " Sacred Roll" and "
                                Wisdom's Book," some believers had as good a right to make fools of themselves, about
                                two books, as the whole of Christendom had, to do so, for centuries, about one book
                                which they had made. When the Israelites had made a calf of choice things, they
                                worshiped it for a little while, until they became ashamed of themselves. After
                                worshiping Jesus so long, what if we did worship Ann Lee for a season ? And after bowing
                                down, for ages, to the idol King James set up — the Bible—what if we did bow down, for a
                                few years, to two books, that ourselves had made? They contain almost as much good as
                                the Protestant male book, and a great deal less evil. At least, they did represent
                                duality. Under our anti-Christian education, when Spiritualism broke out among us, we
                                mistook it for Keligion. In the beginning, what was supernatural was Divine and Holy.
                                The In- struments were Angels, and the Spirits were the Lord God, Amen. Now we know the
                                Spirits were no better than they should be, and that the Instruments were men and women,
                                of like passions, subject to the same infirmities as our poor selves. That is all. A
                                word to the wise, who discern the principle, is sufficient. As to your remaining there,
                                or coming here, it is only a question whether you will be an affliction and an
                                infliction to Pleasant Hill, or to Mt. Lebanon. Some body will have to suffer many
                                things on your account before you become identified with the institution — flesh of its
                                flesh and bone of its bone — for, until you "eat my flesh and drink my blood," said
                                Jesus, you will have no part with me. That means suffering. It means a baptism of the
                                Christ Spirit, and all the gifts and graces flowing from obedience — spiritual
                                obedience. You ask my advice, as a Christian Brother, and in a rough, off hand way, I
                                give it. But I love you, have been pleased with the feeling and sphere of your letters.
                                As you have found a certain relation to Pleasant Hill and its ruling Elders, I prefer to
                                let them " advise " as to your location of settlement. Wherever you can receive, from
                                the Institution, the most good and be the most benefited, personally, you will do the
                                most good. Fraternally,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="There never  was a great man unless through divine inspiration" TEIform="index"/>There never  was a great man unless through divine inspiration
                            </head><p TEIform="p">There never was a great man unless through divine inspiration.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cicero" TEIform="persName"/>Cicero</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker centennial" TEIform="index"/>SHAKER CENTENNIAL</head><p TEIform="p">Mt . Lebanon, August 6, 1874. Beloved J. M. Peebles : Your last, from New York, is under
                                my eye. If any thing I write comforts or strengthens you in your life work as a Christ
                                Prophet — a diffuser of light and purity — life from the inner Heavens — I am ''glad,
                                and rejoice," I live to be and do good. One hundred years ago, to-day, Mother Ann Lee
                                and her little band landed in New York, on Sabbath eve. They were in a new world, having
                                fled from the face of the monster, blasphemously calling itself the Church of Christ —
                                the Episcopalian Church of Old England — a powerful Hierarchy which was forever pointing
                                the poor of the earth to the heavens, there to behold a crucified Jesus, standing, with
                                pierced hands and feet and bleeding side, pleading for those whom they, the priests, had
                                robbed of their inheritance in the land; and then employed press-gangs to force them
                                into the English armies and navies to fight for their God and King, whom, in their
                                hearts, they cursed, and looked upwards to see if there were not better Gods and beings,
                                than their God and King. In the " Beecher-Tilton scandal," there is more than the public
                                or even your own dear self may imagine. It is not persons, but principles and systems.
                                It means Babylon. Generation and Chris- tianity mixed, God, not man, is in it. It is the
                                judgment of Protestanism in America, even as Catholicism is being judged in Europe. Does
                                not Europe possess her infallible Pope ? And does not America possess an image of that
                                infallible Pope, in every one of her great, popular preachers and leaders? War "the
                                Bible and Sharp's Rifles," are component parts of Protestantism as of Catholicism. How
                                long since Church and State Clergy were slave holders ? Some being slaves and Christian
                                ministers too. It is judgment day. The revelation of the Christ Spirits is,
                                increasingly, brighter and brighter. The Christ Angels do often obsess the public men,
                                like T. K. Beecher, Chapin, Chever, Tyng and H. W. Beecher, and corresponding leading
                                women. And in the " fervent heat" of their inspiration, cause them to forget themselves,
                                and to utter sentiments and advance ideas, consistent only with Shaker theology. This
                                creates confusion in their own minds, and great incongruity between their life conduct
                                and their preaching is the result. Not that they, as men and women, are "sinners above
                                all others." But being quickened by Christ Angels, and their spiritual powers developed,
                                they are capable of sinning beyond the power of the unbaptised. If their light be turned
                                to darkness — to do evil — how great the darkness ! And how transcendant the evil!! When
                                the seven plagues are fulfilled in Babylon, and the seven devils — of which the
                                prostitution of the reproductive powers is chief— are cast out, war and poverty will not
                                be. The noble, cultivated powers and faculties of our intellectual giants and
                                giantSHAKEEESS. 75 <pb n="76" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 76 8HAKEK esses, will be left free for the
                                service of Heavenly Ministering Angels, who are hovering — brooding — over the whole of
                                Babylon — Catholic, Greek and Protestant. And their rest from self serving, will be
                                glorious. Eepentant Peter— the symbol of Rome, which has denied and crucified the true
                                Christ for 1,260 years — "will become their Father. And Mary Magdalen—the symbol of
                                Protestantism—-will be their Mother. Babylon — Flesh and Spirit Order — is fallen — is
                                fallen — before the Angel of Spiritualism, and Harvesting Angels follow on to attend
                                unto, and cut down the wheat and tares, which are so inextricably mixed and
                                interblended, that none other than Christ Spirits could or would do any thing with them.
                                Such as call upon the name — character— of true Shakers, will be saved. For in Christ's
                                second appearing, there is salvation from the " sins of the world," that are, even now,
                                " accusing the Saints of G-od day and night continually." And swamping the
                                fieshmongering amphibious Christians — Priests and People — in Pilgrim's Slough of
                                Despond. Write and tell me you will be, in spirit, if not in body, at our social
                                gathering. Fraternally,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="As you sow, so will you reap" TEIform="index"/>AS YOU SOW, SO WILL YOU REAP</head><p TEIform="p">The man who undertakes to live two lives will find that he is living but one, and that
                                one is a life of deception. Causes will be true to their effects. That which you sow
                                &gt;ou will reap. If you live to the flesh, to the passions, to the corrupt
                                inclinations, you may depend upon it that the fruit which is in store for you will be
                                that which belongs to these things. There can be no doubt as to what your harvest will
                                be. If you think that after your day's business is done you can shut the blinds and
                                carry on your orgies in secret with your evil companions; if you think that you can
                                serve the devil by night, and then go forth and look like a sweet and virtuous young
                                man, that goes in the best society, and does not drink nor gamble, nor commit any vice,
                                then the devil has his halter about your neck, and he leads you, the stupidest fool in
                                all the crowd. You deceive nobody but yourself. There is an expression in your eyes that
                                tells stories. Passions stain clear through. A man might as well expect to take nitrate
                                of silver — whose nature is to turn him to a lead color—and not have the doctor know it,
                                as to expect that he can form evil habits and pursue mischievous courses and not have it
                                known It does not need a sheriff to search out and reveal the kind of life that you are
                                living. Every law of God in nature is an officer after you. It does not require a court
                                judge and jury to try and condemn you. All nature is a court room, and every principle
                                thereof is a part of that court which tries and condemns you. Do not think that there
                                can be such a monstrous misadjustment of affairs as that you can do this work of the
                                devil and have the remuneration of an angel.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Beecher, H. W." TEIform="persName"/> H. W. Beecher</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Canaan, Vermont, August 12, 1874" TEIform="index"/>Canaan, Vt., August 12,1874</head><p TEIform="p">Elder F. W. Evans — My dear friend — Your kind favor of August 10, inviting me to be
                                among you upon the occasion of your social gathering, was duly received. And, though
                                against my heart's wishes, must say it will be impossible for me to be present, in body,
                                owing to previous lecture engagements. But I promise to be with you in spirit and the
                                fellowship of heart, which seeks the good of common humanity. Created social beings, it
                                is eminently proper to occasionally meet and mingle upon the intellectual and spiritual
                                planes of life for mutual benefit. Such seasons, comparable to oases, are highly
                                enjoyable. Often do I mourn, because deprived (traveler and pilgrim as I am) of the
                                privilege of oftener meeting congenial souls — those whose sympathies are aflame with
                                reform; whose aspirations reach up to the heavens; whose natures have been quickened by
                                baptismal fires, and who, standing upon the mount of vision, walk even now with the
                                angels of the resurrection. The date of this assures you I am in Canaan, where lecturing
                                upon spiritualism, and reflecting upon the signs of the times, there comes to me this
                                old hymn: " On Jordan's stormy banks I stand, and cast a wishful eye. To Canaan's fair
                                and happy land, where my possessions lie." The banks of mortal life are truly " stormy "
                                and almost fainting by the way, we often cast " wishful eyes " toward spiritual Canaan
                                the Zion of eternal peace and rest. Do we see alike the signs of the times ? The old
                                theological heavens and the political earths are being rolled up like a scroll. The
                                social world is in a terrible ferment. The devil seems let loose for a little season.
                                Surely " the judgment is set." And yet, beyond present storms are lightning skies. God
                                has not forsaken the world ; Christ angels are inviting ; the reapers have come and are
                                thrusting in their sickles ; the chaff and stubble of fashions, forms and creeds, and
                                man-made institutions, are being burned up by the unquenchable fires of eternal truth.
                                The granite rock of righteousness is laid bare — and upon "this rock," with its seven
                                thunders and seven steps of holiness, an order of society is being built, against which
                                the gates of hell cannot prevail. Weary not, O brothers and sisters, ye are the first
                                fruits, prophesies of the coming harvests. Upon your forehead the angels have written
                                the word Faithful. The teachings of purity, peace, and " all things in common," are
                                based upon the foundation of eternal truth and justice. They lead to heaven, to
                                salvation, to-day; to the Zion of our God. I must come up to Mt. Lebanon — the New
                                Jerusalem of the country and century — this fall. I recently had an excellent letter
                                from Elder Eades, of South Union. He is rich in faith, and full of hope for the future.
                                Remember me most kindly to all present — " One family, we dwell in him — one church
                                above, beneath." My sincere prayer is, that God and good angels may bless you, one and
                                all. Most cordially thine,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Peebles, J. M." TEIform="persName"/>J. M. Peebles</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, August 16, 1874" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, August 16,1874</head><p TEIform="p">G. F. Tbain — My Dear Friend, I want to hear from you — and to see you. Next Wednesday,
                                if you will be here, you shall have the rare privilege of attending our Social
                                Gathering. You would be the first outsider who has ever attended. I have invited
                                Peebles, but do not much expect him. This invitation is to you, on the ground of
                                friendship, and the self-denial you practice, in abstaining from fleshly lusts and
                                fleshly food. Come by G. F. Train, on Harlem Express, to New Lebanon Depot, then to
                                North Family.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New York, August 19, 1874" TEIform="index"/>Turkish Bath Hotel, 41 W. 26th St., ) New
                                York, August 19,1874</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Elder Evans : Head and shoulders over Sects, Dogmas, Creeds, Lawyers, Doctors,
                                Priests, Politicians and Beechers, the Disciples of Ann Lee have jumped the fence of
                                bigotry, fanaticism and superstition — holding Church and State, consuming wars,
                                Inundations, Famine and Panics, at arm's length. They are victorious, over the Appetites
                                and the Passions. Startling changes are so near at hand, I seem chained here, as by
                                fate. It may be Revolution. What binds us, in affinity, is Truth. I want to meet you and
                                yours, but destiny keeps me still, a Hermit. Some time I will come, but not now. The
                                Fruit is not yet ripe. The Harvest is not ready for the Reapers. The Dead Carts will
                                soon come round, and Property will have no value. That thins out the diseased, in body
                                and pocket. Beecher's fall leads the way. All your Ideas will prevail. Nobody will eat
                                flesh, use Tobacco, drink Alcohol, chew Opium, nor destroy manhood — by and by. The
                                Nation is Psychologizing, fast. The Electric Current is being magnetized into man, and I
                                cannot move yet. So, say all manner of kind things to your people, and take much good
                                will for yourself.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Train, George Francis" TEIform="persName"/>Geo. Francis Train</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon shakers" TEIform="index"/>MT. LEBANON SHAKERS</head><p TEIform="p">[From the Albany Evening Times.] <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Mt. Lebanon Shakers, the largest and richest community of that peculiar class of
                                    people in the United States, with possibly one exception in the west. On my return I
                                    took the road which leads through the settlement, and stopped for a few moments chat
                                    with Elder Evans, the leading apostle of Shakerism of the present day. The neatness,
                                    plainness and regularity for which this people are proverbial were apparent in every
                                    detail. Even the ox carts lying idle under the sheds were arranged at exactly equal
                                    distances from one another, and their neaps were not allowed to point one hair's
                                    breadth to the right or the left. Elder Evans welcomed me with quiet hospitality,
                                    and invited me to dinner, which was prepared by one of the sisters, and was of
                                    plain, but wholesome abundance. I had but a few minutes to spare, and could not go
                                    over the place as I very much wished to. The number now in the community is about
                                    four hundred. Elder Evans said that the story, that the society was decreasing in
                                    numbers and would soon die out, was as old as the society itself. Shakerism, he
                                    said, was the ripened fruit of humanity, and if its believers dwindled in numbers,
                                    it was the fault of humanity and not of the system. Shakerism was as dependent upon
                                    the outside world as the apples upon the tree. If there was any falling off, it was
                                    on account of the low state of the religious sentiment in the world. He believed
                                    that a grand revival would take place ere long; the religious feeling would be
                                    quickened, and then Shakerism would be benefited thereby. The principles of
                                    communism and celibacy, he said, were adhered to by those who attained to the
                                    highest religious life among all people. They were found even among the Brahmins of
                                    India. He had recently been in communication with the leaders of the Mennonites, who
                                    are soon expected in this country. Among them was a class who believed as the
                                    Shakers did, and it had been suggested that on arriving here, they should unite with
                                    them, and such an arrangement seemed altogether probable. "We are living," said he,
                                    "in the highest form of religious life yet attained to by mankind. Others have lived
                                    lives of chastity, but in monastic cells, or in the cloister. Here the sexes live
                                    together, yet apart. The result is that the passions are finally subdued, or the
                                    unsuccessful ones go out from among us and marry." Regretting that I had no more
                                    time to spend with this remarkable philosopher, fanatic, saint, or what you will,
                                    and regretting still more that Shakers did not take summer boarders, I bid the Elder
                                    adieu and departed out of their coasts.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Albany evening times" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit></p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pitt" TEIform="persName"/>Pitt</byline></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="George Francis Train writes to his favorite paper..." TEIform="index"/>George Francis Train writes to his favorite paper...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">George Francis Train writes to his favorite paper: "Having eaten no meat, eggs, fish, oysters
                            poultry, or animal food of any kind for many months, all the ancient argument, antagonism,
                            ferocity of my nature has died out, and yet I am in savage health and terrible mental vigor.
                            I never imagined a Bengal tiger could be transformed into a Mongolian sheep by Turkish baths
                            and a vegetable diet. I suppose the new religion of evolution has helped to make the change.
                            I am either incubating some gigantic power to develop love and truth in mankind, or I have
                            culminated in the most magnificent fizzle produced for centuries."</p></div2><pb n="77" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakeress: indiscriminate reading" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERESS: INDISCRIMINATE READING</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">King Solomon, the Temple builder, who lived in what ia termed the fifth age of the world, is
                            said to have been a very wise man. He admonished the people in his time, that " Of making
                            many books, there was no end" — that happiness did not consist in much study — but in
                            fearing God and keeping the injunctions given through the Law and the Prophets. What would
                            that preacher of olden time, say, if he lived in the present book-inaking, news-
                            paper-reading age ? We have no account that Jesus wrote any books. It is said, that upon a
                            certain occasion, " he stooped and wrote with his finger on the ground;" but much has been
                            written by others concerning his marvelous doings and sayings; and one of his disciples
                            supposed, " that if all he said, and did, should be chronicled, the world could not contain
                            the books." We will suppose that he referred to the world of mind then in existence — not to
                            the earth: for books have rapidly increased from that time unto the present, and thousands
                            of volumes are published from year to year, and yet there is room. Jesus, the Anointed, came
                            seeking fruit. He said, " Herein is my Father glorified, that ye bear much fruit." His
                            sayings were fraught with wisdom, but he exemplified his mission by his life deeds, as fully
                            as by his words. He sought to embody all true principles in his own life and character — to
                            be a living open volume — an epistle that could be read of all (spiritually minded) men and
                            women. Would it not be wise for the present generation of people, to copy the example of
                            Jesus, to some extent, — write less, and practice more — read less, and work more 1 i. e.
                            Write what is true and useful, and read to gain knowledge that is worthy to be reduced to
                            practice ; not to kill time, nor for the lust of reading, which is done to a great extent by
                            the present and rising generations, to their injury. If we judge of the moral status of man
                            and women, by the company they keep, with the same propriety we may judge of private
                            individual character, by the books which they surround themselves with. Light or obscene
                            reading creates morbid mental appetites, and is a sure indication that those who indulge in
                            it, are prostituting the noble faculties of the human mind to base uses. In a recent number
                            of the R. P. Journal, we notice the following: " Let a man capable of judging, travel
                            through ten, or twelve States, visit three hundred families in the cities and country, and
                            make special enquiry in each what the general reading of the family consists of; then if he
                            should be asked what the American people read, I think he would say — The upper classes read
                            fiction, fashion, fable and allegories; the lower classes, fiction, fashion, love and
                            ghost-stories. Our fathers and grandfathers had no such reading. It was not in existence
                            then. But the present generation has been reared in it. And by it, the whole country is
                            filled with folly, fashion and wine." Novel reading is bewitching ; it is designed to act
                            upon and stimulate the animal uassions, and corrupt the minds of those who give their time
                            and attention to it. They taste, and thirst for more ; and the youth of our land are eagerly
                            drinking of those poisonous waters ; and they inhale the foul atmosphere, which surrounds
                            those impure fountains, which is as deadly miasm to the moral and spiritual part of their
                            being. As truly, as all food taken into the stomach goes to form bone and muscle, and the
                            blood which courses through the veins,and to make up the physical frame of a man or woman,
                            so the mental food — what the mind receives — thinks upon, and communes with, whether in
                            reading or otherwise, forms and animates the soul which dwells in the material body — the
                            tenement which is given for use while in the earth life, and not for abuse. How great the
                            necessity, that we carefully select good and pure food for the body and the mind ; for we
                            cannot escape the results. As we value health and happiness, let us strive to avoid all
                            disease-producing causes. Light, trashy literature, will never be sought for, nor indulged
                            in by true Reformers, and Saviors of our race. Those who desire to save others from
                            intemperance, and to uplift those who have prostituted their God-given powers to sensuality,
                            and thus become the victims of crime, must themselves be temperate and prove their integrity
                            by being virtuous and honest. And to accomplish this, the avenues of the heart must be
                            guarded, that no influence in the guise of friend, or foe, that would throw one poisonous
                            dart to corrupt the thoughts, — dim the vision — or pervert the understanding, be suffered
                            to approach. We shall, if consistent, select the best company that we can find — neither
                            giving nor accepting evil communications — but be ready at all times to turn from every
                            influence that would allure to false and carnal pleasure. We shall remember that every book,
                            and paper that we read, bears the impress of the author's mind; and as we come into rapport
                            with them, we receive either life, or death to our spirits. We have many times sorrowed in
                            spirit, to see talent which should have been dedicated to high and noble purposes, employed
                            in writing romance and novels to stimulate unhallowed desires, and to make money. Let all
                            lovers of virtue spurn such literature, and cultivate a taste for the good and useful; and
                            form a character which they can themselves respect. Then, they will never fail of having the
                            confidence and respect of others. When such shall have finished their course in this life,
                            they will " lift up their eyes to the everlasting hills," as did Jesus their prototype, and
                            say " The hour is come," Father, Mother, glorify us as we have glorified God on earth. Give
                            us to drink of the cup of joy with purified saints in mansions of peace and rest. As Jesus
                            and Ann, through the Christ baptisms, became one with the Father, Mother, God, so make us
                            one with them! And the response will be given, " Amen, even so shall it be."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our centennial" TEIform="index"/>OUR CENTENNIAL</head><p TEIform="p">About a hundred years ago a little company of nine embarked from the shores of England to
                            find a spot where they could carry out the principles they had received from the Spirit of
                            good, which were leading them to seek for purity of heart and life, as the means of
                            attaining the holiness required of God as the first condition of millennial dawning.
                            Instructed from the Spirit world that this work was to have its growth and fulfilment in
                            this country, struggling at that time for freedom, they forsook the land which had so
                            bitterly persecuted them for their strange and unwelcome testimony of truth, and, for nearly
                            three months, were confined to the narrow limits of a small sailing vessel, the bark Maria.
                            Feeling called upon to go forth in their simple worship, they did so, which aroused the
                            enmity of the Captain to that degree that he threatened to throw them overboard. But a
                            violent storm succeeding, the ship sprang a leak, and the captain, in terror, said " they
                            must all perish before morning." But Mother Ann told him to be of "good cheer." She had seen
                            two shining angels standing by the mast who assured her that not a hair of their heads
                            should be harmed but they should arrive safely in America. She then went to work with them
                            in bailing the water, and so inspired the men, that they were kept afloat until a wave
                            striking the vessel, restored the plank to its place. In like manner she inspired the little
                            handful of followers while suffering hardships after their arrival, in the wilderness of
                            Niskayuna, with the same precious faith in the power of God, which called them to forsake
                            all for the Christ principle. Although she did not, like her Lord and Master, receive her
                            inspiration soon enough to save her in virgin purity, still, she, through suffering and
                            struggle, obtained redemption from a sinful nature, and was made meet to be a co-worker,
                            with him, for the redemption of a lost world. There seems such a depth of wisdom, such a
                            fullness of love and such a martyr-like heroism, in her character and mission, such an
                            entire obedience to the spirit of truth revealed to her; and that truth so difficult for
                            woman's lips to utter— so shocking to the sensitive ear of man-made modesty— that I can
                            revere, and scarcely refrain from worshiping that devoted one. The good, the true and the
                            Christ-like in her I do worship. I regard it as an emanation from the All-Good, and as a
                            blessed pattern for my imitation. The world has its war and blood heroes, and who shall say
                            there is no need of Spiritual and ce- lestial heroes 1 —whole souled devotees to the
                            elevation of the race through an entire abrogation of self, save in the perfecting of their
                            own spirits by the practice of the Christian oneness: squaring their lives by the precepts
                            of Christ that they may become fit temples for the spirit of God, and to perform the
                            master's use ? In times of danger or persecution it seemed as though her own safety, or
                            comfort, were but minor considerations; and while she would shed tears at the sufferings of
                            others, her own spirit became so free from the operations of a selfish nature that she could
                            trust in the almighty arm to shield and protect her while uttering her most unwelcome
                            truths. The weak and craven fear of harm, or defeat, seemed to find no room in her soul; but
                            " per- fect love cast out all tormenting fear," and fulfilled the scripture saying " The
                            righteous are bold as a lion," yet " harmless as doves." Indeed, the dove-like Spirit of the
                            Christ, seems to awaken so much that is most lovely and commendable in its receiver, that it
                            wins a sort of homage and respect, from even those whose lives are rebuked by its spirit,
                            testimony and life ; and they behold the Christ in his works ; when a Pharasaic,
                            self-asserting spirit, would only awaken the corresponding element in them, by arousing
                            their combativeness. Oh ! for the lion and the lamb to fraternize so completely, that the
                            product will be a noble, genial, unselfish individuality, inspiring peace and happiness,
                            instead of distrust and envyings, and eliminating the pure joy and simplicity, of which even
                            the child can partake! The goodness of Mother's heart, is manifested in her enduring such
                            powerful and continued mental and spiritual conflicts, for the releasement of her own soul,
                            into the freedom of perfect purity, in the shortest possible time ; for she was a faithful
                            warrior, and ceased not, until Satan, coming, could find nothing in her to respond. But its
                            greatness is none the less manifest, which enabled her to meet physical hardships and perils
                            — self-denials and sufferings— and indeed, to shrink at nothing which came in the way, as a
                            result of her spirit's obedience to truth. <pb n="78" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 78 Noble, heroic mother! may
                            thy daughters share largely in thy courage and love, and a host of brave and self-denying
                            sons rise up to call thee Blessed. Surely in the contemplation of such a whole souled
                            pattern and leader and of such a cloud of witnesses as have been harvested during these
                            passing years, we may keep a joyful centennial in our hearts, though it find no outward
                            demonstration. And while we contemplate the past growth and increase, must we not still pray
                            that the sickle-bearing angel of truth, may reap many souls from the rapidly whitening
                            fields of nature, which we know must have become arid and barren to them spiritually, that
                            in the garners of life they may become " bread for hungry souls." " Hail, thou victorious
                            gospel! And that auspicious day When Mother safely landed In Hudson's lovely bay ! "</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webster, E. H." TEIform="persName"/>E. H. Webster, Harvard, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><p TEIform="p">The following letter may be interesting to some of the readers of our paper, when they learn
                            that the writer, who was then in good health, died suddenly in about a month's time after
                            she wrote it. It was not designed to be made public, and we withhold the name.</p><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear sister Antoinette:" TEIform="index"/>Dear Sister Antoinette :</head><p TEIform="p">Friend F. W. Evans recommended me to write to you, dear sister, and gladly I avail myself
                                of the opportunity. "Write just as you feel," he said ; but my heart is so full I hardly
                                know where to begin. That good man (F. W. E.) wrote such a beautiful reply to my first
                                letter of inquiry — and sent me papers — then, when lie came to the city, he called to
                                see me ; and I feel very grateful for such kindness. I believe he represents numbers who
                                are like himself. Well, I feel, dear sister, that my greatest need at present, is to be
                                a silent listener to your teaching. Friend Evans has done me more good than all the
                                teachers, doctors and nurses, I ever had in my life. He swept through the old and new
                                testament, from the beginning of Genesis, to the end of Revelation— and set it before me
                                in a bran new dress — common sense. After he left, I fished up my poor little bible,
                                that was banished several years ago to the bottom of a " Saratoga " trunk ; and with
                                unfeigned humility asked its pardon. Now, I will read — think and think : — by and by I
                                will come to some thing, that will neither clear away, nor let me pass. Then, may I come
                                to you for instruction dear sister ? I shall soon have to enter my profession again, and
                                shall feel so much stronger under the influence of your love. I will hurry, and finish
                                my work here — and then — if you all think best — "come home." 0 how those words
                                inspired me! I hope my brain is safely through — done forever with the molting condition
                                — and that this new crop of feathering ideas, under sound Shaker nourishment, may grow
                                up into strong, useful quills. I believe there are many right here in this very city,
                                who are starving for just such food as Elder Evans gave me yesterday ! how much I
                                wished, when he was talking, that the room could have been filled with appreciative
                                listeners ! How are they to be reached ? for that class seldom speak their minds — they
                                see nothing to satisfy their souls — and they sink in despair! A young, and beautiful
                                girl, started with me in the career of life, whose brilliant future was prophesied by
                                all who knew her; and whose untimely death was caused, without a doubt, by her utter
                                abhorrence of the poisonous materialism with which she was surrounded. Her last words to
                                me were " I am going where I shall have less trouble in making myself understood; and if
                                you love me, bid me Godspeed." It is easy to understand what a " Pearl of great price "
                                Shakerism would have been to her, and it is sad to reflect, how many are lost for the
                                want of true knowledge. But I have encroached too much upon your time, and must bring my
                                letter to a close. Please remember me kindly — and in Celtic phrase, I will say to all
                                those under the immediate sunshine of your blessed faith—"May your shadows never grow
                                less." Affectionately yours,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="S., K." TEIform="persName"/>K. S.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Answer" TEIform="index"/>ANSWER</head><p TEIform="p">My Dear Friend : Yours of the 13th inst., came to me by last evening's mail. I was
                                pleased with its con- tents from beginning to end. I love the breathings of your spirit
                                — your frankness — sincerity and child-like dependence. That " old book " that has so
                                quietly rested in the " trunk," contains some beautiful instructions, " profitable," to
                                those of enlightened understanding," for doctrine, reproof and cor- rection, that the
                                man, or woman of God, may be thoroughly furnished unto all good works." If we give heed
                                to the instructions of that book, we cannot give to the children a stone, when they ask
                                for bread ; neither say to them, when cold and naked, " be ye warmed and fed," without
                                imparting to them of our treasures. Our heavenly Father and Mother — God — give freely
                                to those who ask, if they ask in faith and sincerity. If we freely receive, it is our
                                duty to freely give. This is the reason, dear child, that I take the earliest
                                opportunity to reply to yours, that you may feel, we have ears to hear and hearts to
                                sympathize with you, in your aspirations for a higher life. Verily, my friend, God hath
                                dealt kindly and generously with us ; and after many years' experience, we are enabled
                                to say, that the eyes, ears and hearts, of those who seek pleasure in worldly things —
                                in unrighteousness — can neither see, hear, nor understand the things that God hath
                                prepared for those who love him so truly, that they consecrate all to his service ; and,
                                who not merely say, " Lord — Lord," and retain all that is self-pleasing, and think to
                                pay their way to heaven and happiness, by giving a large salary to a hireling
                                priest-hood — as they would pay their fare from New York to Cincinnati, in a railroad
                                car ; but through self-sacrifice, and toil, they gain the treasures of eternal life.
                                Such find the highway that is cast up for the ransomed of the Lord to walk in. The
                                waters of the great deep (sea of worldly, carnal pleasure,) are dried up, and truth
                                lovers will pass over and come unto Zion, joyfully. They will gladly leave the house of
                                bondage in the dark and shadowy land and seek to find the place, where broad streams and
                                rivers flow; where are green and living pastures, warmed and vivified by the sunlight of
                                truth and Divine revelation. I wish you were free from all claims that the world has
                                upon you, that you might " Come home now" and take with us the Christian's cross, and
                                with us wear the victor's crown! While duty calls you to remain where you are, you may
                                come in spirit, or by letter, to me — to us — and freely make known your feelings and
                                desires ; and while you are thus separated from us, attending to present duties, if you
                                feel at times that you are surrounded by temptation, and dangers attend you, remember
                                your Shaker friends. Come to us, and we will give you love that is not of the world, to
                                strengthen, shield and protect you. Ask any question freely, and we will be honest and
                                deal frankly with you. If we possess knowledge of the true Christian life and character
                                which you are not in possession of, we have received that knowledge through practical
                                obedience to truth, and from spiritual guides and teachers, who are progressed beyond
                                us,and we have no cause for boasting; but freely impart to others, of the treasures that
                                have been so mercifully bestowed upon us. We are thankful to know, there are many, at
                                this time like yourself, who are ready to burst their swaddling clothes — open their
                                eyes to simple truth — and leave the dark shadows of mysticism which have gathered
                                around the bible by false teachers and worldly interpreters, until all has become a
                                myth. With you, I sorrow in spirit that those who would thankfully receive food for
                                their famishing souls, do not know where to seek it. We must pray to God to send
                                Agencies to them, as he has done to you, to show them the way, the truth, and the life.
                                That good Being, who endowed us with reason and intelligence, will never ask us to
                                surrender those God-given powers, in regard to religion. Reason, Science and Religion
                                are in perfect accord. So hope on — hope ever — Write whenever you feel like it. Thine
                                in Christian friendship.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/>Antoinette Doolittle</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Morning light" TEIform="index"/>MORNING LIGHT</head><p TEIform="p">Let not thy sight be dim, nor thine ear heavy. For the daughter of Zion calleth to the
                            multitude of "erring sisters" whose mental and physical doings cast a dark shadow over the
                            future destiny of the race. She would' fain speak into their hearts words that burn, and
                            breath into their souls inspirations that would effect a radical change in their lives.
                            Creative agency is placed within the province of human responsibility, being wholly
                            committed to the power of man, and woman. And I am moved by deep sympathy, to make a
                            friendly effort to aid those suffering females, who have been drawn into the vortex of
                            "social evil" by ignorance, or poverty. The native innocence and original purity of
                            thousands of the young and inexperienced are destroyed by their imbibing false principles. O
                            that the warning instructive voice of reason might be heard like a faithful friend,
                            forewarning children and youth with knowledge to protect them from impending danger. A voice
                            from the higher spheres has long been calling to the inhabitants of earth to come out, and
                            away from the haunts of infamy, and to engage in some useful manual occupation. It will be
                            admitted that the formation of habits, either indulgence, or self-restraint, is the
                            foundation of that character which is noble, pure and good, or dark, infamous and degraded.
                            The strongest love, is often tributary to an evil influence — lust. The children of this
                            world, who marry and give in marriage, are not yet subjects of the new, spiritual birth.
                            Come forth ye heroic daughters of the nineteenth century, and protest against the " social
                            evil," which ruins so many thousands. You have been nobly engaged in overthrowing
                            intemperance, which goes hand in hand with other sensual passions of mankind. By a mighty
                            struggle, the slave was liberated from bondage ! Woman has grappled with the monster
                            intemperance; now let her, with the besom of power in her hand, sweep the social evil out of
                            existence, and restore to herself the order of times and seasons, and teach it her children,
                            and her children's children. O ye heroines, turn from the temptations of vice, — assert the
                            dignity of womanhood! Sever the bands of death—sensual sexuality— then will the spiritual
                            powers of the soul, which should pervade the whole being, limit the tide of excess. Come
                            unto Wisdom, with the whole heart, and the royal scepter of power will be placed in your
                            hands, that will insure victory, and give joy and rest.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blake, Rhoda" TEIform="persName"/>Rhoda Blake, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Boys and girls" TEIform="index"/>BOYS AND GIRLS</head><p TEIform="p">The daily habits of every boy and girl are materials with which they are building up their
                            characters, and every repetition has the effect of strengthening them for good or evil.
                            Justice, benevolence, honor, integrity and self-control are no ephemeral blossoms that a
                            day's sunshine can call into being and a night's frost can wither and kill. They grow slowly
                            and develop gradually, but once rooted firmly in the heart and trained by con- stant
                            exercise, they will prove sturdy, healthful, long-lived plants that will bear rich and
                            abundant fruit. It is not enough to teach; we must also train. It is not enough to tell the
                            child what is right; we must accustom him to love its atmosphere. So with self-culture. If
                            we would become nobler and more virtuous, we must habituate ourselves to the constant
                            exercise of pure thoughts, generous affections, noble and disinterested deeds.</p></div2><pb n="79" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hallowed mountain" TEIform="index"/>HALLOWED MOUNTAIN</head><p TEIform="p">Blest mountain, I view thee with deep admiration! Thy lands are enchanting and lovely to me ;
                            I've drank at thy fountains, and pass'd through thy burnings, I've wash'd in thy Jordan my
                            soul to set free. Thou art the sweet home of my youthful enjoyments; Fond hopes and bright
                            futures then center'd in thee; I bow'd at thy altars, the shrines of the living, And gain'd
                            the protection that hath shielded me. Again I've ascended thy summit of beauty; I've sat at
                            thy base in humility bow'd ; There pray'd to my heavenly father and mother, Lest I should be
                            haughty, exalted or proud. How kindly they listen'd to humble entreaties— Those low earnest
                            breathings that rise from the soul— They sent to me bread, by the hands of the angels And
                            life giving water, which maketh all whole. When thy skies were darken'd with clouds of
                            affliction, The flash of the lightning played fearfully'round; 0 then have I trembled, and
                            sought for repentance — I've shudder'd and shrunk at the thunders deep sound! And when they
                            were brighten'd with smiles more propitious — The bright-golden sunshine illumin'd the day —
                            1 drank the sweet dews that were falling from heaven, And gather'd rich flowers that grew on
                            the way. How can I but love thee, fair mountain of glory I My heart has one aim, and my
                            spirit one care; 'Tis ever to serve the Eternal who formed me And built on thy heights the
                            great Temple of Pray'r! So glorious and holy are all thy surroundings, Here Seraphs of mercy
                            and Cherubim rest, The Lord's house of honor and praise they are guarding, By myriads of
                            shining immortals, 'tis blest. Here reigneth the King of the first resurrection, Revealing
                            the means of salvation from sin; The Queen in her loveliness stands in the kingdom— They
                            call to the sin-sick, O come, enter in ! And now, as I'm viewing thy vast elevation —
                            Repeating the eulogies — sacred to thee, I think when a lone little wauderer in nature, How
                            I was call'd hither thy glory to see.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Smith, Jane Emily" TEIform="persName"/>Jane Emily Smith, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dress" TEIform="index"/>DRESS</head><p TEIform="p">As our little Bark arrives in port every month, laden with rich stores of good things from
                            the " Delectable Land," there is one important subject that has been treated rather
                            sparingly, the subject of Dress—the love of which, fills the human mind, and engrosses much
                            of the time and attention of the present age. Some kind of dress is a necessity. But
                            dressing for show, is woman's folly, her proclivities are to overdress, without reference to
                            use or modesty. And her vanity is apparent in this respect, both within and. outside of the
                            socalled Christian Churches of the day. Human nature is the same in all ages, differing in
                            degree. In Apostolic times, the same spirit sought entrance, and Timothy and Peter gave some
                            strong admonitions concerning it. They taught, that instead of adorning the outward person
                            with gold — plaiting the hair — and putting on costly and useless apparel — they should
                            clothe the inner man and woman with the incorruptible — " a meek and quiet spirit — chaste
                            conversation," which in the sight of God is of great price. We do not need to go back to
                            Paul, the minister of the Corinthian Church, centuries ago, to learn that " the fashions of
                            the world pass away " — not the marriage institution only, of which he was then speaking—
                            but its fashions in dress also. The marriage vows, at the present time, do not even retain
                            much of their former sanctity ; however high the priest may stand, who sanctions the
                            contract, it gives way, before the latitudinarian, as a rope of sand. Gaudy attire is the
                            concomitant of sensuality — the handmaid that seeks to cover up the diseases of the body and
                            soul — by garments of purple and scarlet — gold and costly pearls. Was Paul severe, when he
                            pointed out heady, highminded, incontinent men, as finding their way into houses to lead
                            captive silly women — those who dress gaily with the intention of enticing and drawing such
                            men to them ? And is it strange that such persons should be the servants of low sensual
                            desires and passions? They who give their minds wholly to pleasure-seeking— and to
                            fashionable dress, which is ever changing, so that they have no time to devote to the good,
                            the useful, and the true, are in a pitiable condition of servitude, whether they profess to
                            be sinning Christians, or sinning Infidels. When the Methodist denomination were a living
                            people, and possessed the vitalizing power of God, their faith led them to dress so plainly
                            that they were easily known. Where are they now ? Verily their glory, which consisted in
                            Christian plainness and simplicity, has departed. Among the many Reforms and Reformers,
                            which are now agitating the public mind, and shaking society to its very center, few,
                            comparatively, have given their attention to the subject of Dress Reform. If strong minded
                            women could possess the moral courage to stem the tide of popular opinion, and adopt some
                            mode of dress — plain — comfortable and modest; and not swerve from their purpose, until
                            they had accomplished a radical reformation in the dress of women, thousands would
                            eventually rise up and call them blessed for the good done to humanity. When the time
                            arrives that woman is accorded her legitimate right to sit in the Legislative halls — not as
                            spectator — but as Arbiter, co-operating with men, in framing and sustaining the laws of the
                            land, then may we not hope that she will rise to the dignity of true womanhood, and nobly
                            vindicate the justice of her position, by showing that she has a mind that can grasp
                            substantial things — a mind that cannot be veered by the capricious winds of fashion, which,
                            their origin considered, every noble minded woman would have cause to despise. I must
                            confess, that when I see the ludicrous style, and the extravagance of fashionable dress at
                            the present time, I turn away in disgust, I feel like prostrating my body and bowing my
                            spirit in gratitude to God, for the union and communion of those whose hearts are withdrawn
                            from the world, and lifted above its vanities — and are seeking treasures that will not
                            perish. And with my dear Gospel Sisters, I would be more fervently engaged in the work of
                            subduing those elements within, whence spring " the lust of the flesh, the lust of the eye
                            and the pride of life,—" the foundation principles of the world. Only in thus doing can we
                            fill the Christian character, and perform our mission to God's acceptance. If we guard the
                            avenues of the heart, and reject every temptation that would lead away from the simplicity
                            of the truth, and induce to worldliness, in manners and dress, and in all things conform our
                            lives to true Christian principles, then we shall become active workers in the temple of
                            God, set upon the hill of truth, that will give light to the nations of the earth.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bullard, Marcia M." TEIform="persName"/>Marcia M. Bullard, Canaan, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Queries and answers" TEIform="index"/>QUERIES AND ANSWERS</head><p TEIform="p">Are you happy and contented in your Shaker home ? Do you never feel a desire to mix and
                            mingle with the world, in its fashions, pleasures and life, in the generative order ? Are
                            you not so bound that you cannot withdraw from this people if you wish so to do ? Is not
                            life dull and monotonous, with you, — devoid of the social intercourse and entertainment
                            which add cheer and pleasure in all its phases ? These and many other similar questions are
                            often put to us by strangers. It is not strange that such thoughts and queries should arise
                            in the minds of those who have never engaged in the cause, and have not been spiritually
                            exercised to comprehend the work — its vital power of action — its inner attractions,— the
                            centripetal force which holds us together, in a body, under " one Faith, one Lord, and one
                            Baptism." To answer, lucidly and concisely, is a somewhat difficult task ; especially to
                            those who have been reared under the old theologies, which have been handed down from
                            generation, to generation, through many centuries, and exist at the present time, as
                            blinding dogmas, giving license to sinful indulgences, mixing flesh and spirit together.
                            Though we have valid reasons for the hope and faith that are within us, which lift us above
                            the world, and guide us to the higher life ; yet, we find as a general rule, people need a
                            practical illustration presented to their outward vision. Hence, to such enquirers (if they
                            are sincere),we say, Come and see what living faith, and works, combined, have produced. The
                            Shakers, to thousands of people, are a problem. That Shakers are celibates, are neat, clean
                            and industrious, is understood by many. The Principles, producing such results, are
                            understood by few. Knowing the innate love of pleasures in young minds of the present age —
                            seeking the gratification of the senses, to the greatest extent attainable — self will, and
                            independence predominating, it is natural to wonder, how the young, especially, can find
                            contentment and happiness within these supposed cloistered walls. To the truly rational
                            mind, happiness is but the result of virtue. This is the first idea to be gathered, by those
                            who would dwell in the Shaker Order. True happiness can only be found in well doing; but so
                            long has passion ruled the individual, instead of the individual ruling and governing the
                            low propensities of their natures, that the power to control the lower, and develop the
                            higher, is weakened, and seemingly lost in a chaos of worldly elements. To effect a change
                            in things both natural and spiritual, is the design now carried into action by the Shaker
                            Order. To the first question, Are you happy and contented? we make this reply. Children,
                            when first brought amongst us, seldom know why they come, further than to accord with the
                            desire of their parents, who seek to protect them from the evils of the world without. They
                            enter a school, in which the disposition and germs of future growth and character are sought
                            for. Growth from childhood years, is a continual developing, or unfolding of the prin-
                            ciples which go to make the man and woman. The faith and testimony of Christ's Second
                            Appearing, will either gather, or scatter. Those, who from a lower organization develop the
                            animal and sensual, are as a consequence, drawn back to the great magnet evil of the world;
                            such cannot find happiness and comfort among this people, because they are out of their
                            element. While, on the other hand, those who from a higher organism, develop the moral and
                            spiritual; who love good, and desire purity, are strengthened and encouraged by those of
                            riper age, who from a long experience of sacrifice and devotion to right principles, testify
                            of the glorious reward. Such, find contentment and happiness, which no other religious Order
                            or Sect, or Infidelism could in anywise afford. And while the whole being is devoted,
                            through the reason and thought of maturer years, to eradicate every form and degree of evil
                            from body and soul, and to establish the truth, with all its ennobling effects, in the heart
                            and character, there is no desire whatever to mingle with the world in its ridiculous
                            fashions, pleasures or pains. The generative life, in its highest forms, only tends to
                            darken the understanding and breathe the blight of death to the angel-part in man and woman.
                            We are under no bonds save our own faith and conscience. That we are debarred from acting
                            our free choice, is an erroneous idea — a dying echo of past fabled stories — created
                            through enmity or by those who were ignorant of the principle of the institution. Those who
                            choose a worldly life, are at liberty to have it, and are welcome to its enjoyments, if they
                            find any therein, and also to the pains and vexations arising therefrom, which are manifold.
                            Jesus likened the kingdom of heaven to a net cast into the sea; bringing forth good and bad
                            fishes — the good were preserved — the bad, cast into the sea again. Though we renounce the
                            vain amusements of the world, and ever strive to hold the spiritual of greatest importance,
                            in all the duties of life, that does not hinder a free and social enjoyment and intercourse
                            one with another — exchange of good thoughts — ideas and feelings, and the development and
                            promotion of every gift and talent. Thus united as the heart of one, we are unitedly working
                            together, striving to cement those links in the chain of life which will not be dissolved
                            either on this or the other side of the river that flows, dividing time from eternity.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Collins, Elvah F." TEIform="persName"/>Elvah F. Collins, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><pb n="80" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Journeying on" TEIform="index"/>JOURNEYING ON</head><p TEIform="p">1. Our faith is unclouded and bright as the day, Uplifting our spirits from darkness away; 2.
                            The high way of holiness we will pursue, While pleasures terrestrial recede from our view;
                            3. Brave pilgrims who traversed this way in the past, With pure hallow'd blessings our
                            spirits o'ercast; 4. Though thorny the pathway awaiting our feet, And many the dangers and
                            trials we meet, No shadow of turning our progress shall stay, We're bound for the regions of
                            bliss. We'll sip from the fountain of life that is new, And feast on the fruits of pure
                            love. They scatter'd the seedgerms of truth that will last, In beauty forever to bloom. With
                            courage undaunted no power can defeat, We'll press for the heavenly goal. We are journeying
                            on, we are :;-' journeying on, To the love land of light, our beautiful homel Where sin
                            cannot blight nor 'sorrow e'er come, O, beautiful, blest and eternal home.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Contentment" TEIform="index"/>CONTENTMENT</head><p TEIform="p">It is an old maxim, that " A contented mind is a continual feast." Tliere is, perhaps,
                            nothing more certain to insure happiness, than an even temperament— a cheerful, contented
                            disposition that can look at the bright side of things, even under adverse circumstances.
                            Nor is there any thing that will more effectually prevent usefulness, and mar the happiness
                            of individuals, or produce more unpleasant conditions in society, than the reverse of this.
                            The former looks for good, and finds it ; and is quick to discern virtue in others, and to
                            cover their defects with charity. While the latter, sees every fault, and magnifies it, and
                            finds it much easier to see deformity, than beauty ; and always inclines to put bitter for
                            sweet. If we would make life bright and happy, and have friends to love and care for us, we
                            must, while young, cultivate such dispositions and habits as will make us agreeable and
                            useful members of society. We cannot be too earnest in this ; for upon it depends, in a
                            large measure, our present and future happiness. We shape our course, the joy or fear Of
                            which, our coming life is made ; And fill our future atmosphere, With pleasant sunshine, or
                            with shade.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Martin, Florence" TEIform="persName"/>Florence Martin, Union Village, O.</byline></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Revision of the Bible" TEIform="index"/>Revision of the Bible</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">It appears, from recent developments, that another revision of this book is now
                                    going on by a body of English scholars and theologians, and so thorough is the work
                                    to be done that it is expected to occupy altogether some eight or ten years. There
                                    is little doubt the bible needs an extensive revision, and there is much in it that,
                                    if left out altogether, would greatly improve it. But if it be truly the Word of
                                    God, how about these changes?</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Cape Ann advertiser" TEIform="index"/>Cape Ann Advertiser</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Great heresy" TEIform="index"/>The Great Heresy</head><p TEIform="p">There is one form of error so fatal, so persistent, so wide-spread, that it fairly may be
                            called the great heresy. Its essence is this: Men regard religion, in some way, a substitute
                            for right living, instead of the highest form of right living.</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Candy manufacturers and consumers" TEIform="index"/>CANDY MANUFACTURERS AND CONSUMERS</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Com. Jourdan offered the following resolution, which was unanimously adopted :
                                    Whereas, Frequent complaints have been made by the press and people that terra alba
                                    (which is nothing but plaster of Paris or gypsum), glocure, lamp black, sulphuric
                                    acid, aniline, verdigris, Brunswick green, gamboge, smalts, ultramarine, oil of
                                    turpentine, prussic acid, rotten cheese, fusil oil, chrome yellow, and other drugs
                                    and compounds are largely used in the manufacture of cheap candies; and, Whereas,
                                    The indiscriminate use of such poisonous drugs and compounds is considered
                                    deleterious to health. Resolved, That the sanitary committee, or such officers of
                                    this board as they may direct, do thoroughly investigate and report to this board as
                                    soon as possible the mode and material used in the manufacture of all descriptions
                                    of wares and merchandise made or sold by confectioners, in order that children at
                                    least may be protected from the evil effects of the dangerous compounds which are
                                    sold under the description of candy. In this connection Commissioner Jourdan stated
                                    that he had heard on good authority that terra alba is used in place of white sugar;
                                    glocure in place of gum arabic consists of mucilage of starch ; lampblack, glue in
                                    place of gum arabic and liquorice ; tonquin bean in place of vanilla; tartaric and
                                    sulphuric acids in place of lemon; analine, a poisonous product of coal tar, in
                                    place of cochineal to color red candies; gamboge and chrome yellow in place of
                                    saffron to color yellow candies ; smalt, verdigris, and Brunswick green to color
                                    blue and green candies; oil of turpentine for flavoring; rotten cheese and sulphuric
                                    acid to flavor pineapple drops. Com. Palmer offered the following resolution, which
                                    was adopted : Resolved, That the sanitary inspectors be directed to inspect all the
                                    markets, vegetable and fruit stands, and report the number of street stands where
                                    fruits are sold, and the quality and condition of the fruits on said stands in their
                                    respective districts, at the meeting of the Board, August 4.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Brooklyn union" TEIform="index"/>Brooklyn Union.</bibl></cit> Cannot Believers substitute something for the children, in place of poisoned candies
                            ? Or, some family manufacture candies, and sell to outsiders and to our own people? </p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fossil oyster beds have been discovered above the snow line on the Rocky Mountains." TEIform="index"/>Fossil oyster beds have been discovered above the snow line on the Rocky Mountains.
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Fossil oyster beds have been discovered above the snow line on the Rocky Mountains.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Visiting" TEIform="index"/>VISITING</head><p TEIform="p">On the 5th instant, a company, of eight young Sisters, from the North, spent the day, at the
                            Second Family. With faces beaming with satisfaction, they report a good time. And that their
                            dinner was so rational, and simple its digestion did not, in the least, interfere with their
                            social and spiritual love feast — their soul enjoyment. They feel honored by the confidence
                            reposed — their bodily wants being considered subordinate to sweet Gospel Union and
                            Communion.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The closer together the parts of mechanism are brought..." TEIform="index"/>The closer together the parts of mechanism are brought...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The closer together the parts of mechanism are brought the more noise and friction there will
                            be. Just so with mind — or imperfected, undeveloped mind — that is not polished by the emery
                            wheel of divine truth and order.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="One ugly nature is enough to distemper an entire family..." TEIform="index"/>One ugly nature is enough to distemper an entire family...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">One ugly nature is enough to distemper an entire family; and, on the other hand, one
                            light-shedding, joy-bearing nature is enough to restore the equilibrium of a disturbed
                            family. Great is the power of a human soul.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bedell, Mary" TEIform="index"/>Mary Bedell
                            </head><p TEIform="p">South Union, Ky.—1872.<persName reg="Bedell, Mary" TEIform="persName">Mary Bedell</persName>, aged 77.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miles, Theresa" TEIform="index"/>Theresa Miles
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Miles, Theresa" TEIform="persName">Theresa Miles</persName>, aged 58.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Houston, Nancy T." TEIform="index"/>Nancy T. Houston
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Houston, Nancy T." TEIform="persName">Nancy T. Houston</persName>, aged 70.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dillon, Jency" TEIform="index"/>Jency Dillon
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Dillon, Jency" TEIform="persName">Jency Dillon</persName>, aged 75.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Smithson, Cynthia" TEIform="index"/>Cynthia Smithson
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Smithson, Cynthia" TEIform="persName">Cynthia Smithson</persName>, aged 21.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Berry Hill, Betty" TEIform="index"/>Betty Berry Hill
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Berry Hill, Betty" TEIform="persName">Betty Berry Hill</persName>, aged 83.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Martin, Margery" TEIform="index"/>Margery Martin
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Martin, Margery" TEIform="persName">Margery Martin</persName>, aged 70.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bagwell, Sally Ann" TEIform="index"/>Sally Ann Bagwell
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Bagwell, Sally Ann" TEIform="persName">Sally Ann Bagwell</persName>, aged 36. 1873.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Houston, Prudence F." TEIform="index"/>Prudence F. Houston
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Houston, Prudence F." TEIform="persName">Prudence F. Houston</persName>, aged 69.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Roberts, Martha" TEIform="index"/>Martha Roberts
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Roberts, Martha" TEIform="persName">Martha Roberts</persName>, aged 86; June 23,1874.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Barber, Eliza" TEIform="index"/>Eliza Barber
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Barber, Eliza" TEIform="persName">Eliza Barber</persName>, deceased, at Mt. Lebanon, N. Y..
                                August 6, 1874, aged 75 years. We've parted with a long loved friend, From this
                                terrestrial sphere, Whose lowly soul was well refined, Through discipline and prayer.
                                And on her banner is inscribed " Meekness and patient toil; " Peace was her motto, Truth
                                her guide; Her life was free from guile. P. A. Jones, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div3></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>