<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2208" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">27</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">22</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">08</biblScope><date value="18920801" TEIform="date">August 1892</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">169-192</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="22" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="08" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
AUGUST.
MANIFESTO,
Published by the United Societies,
VOL. XXII.
"For what is a man profited, if he shall gain the whole world, and
lose his own soul ? or what shall a man give in exchange for
his soul."Matt. XVI., 26.
Canterbury, N. H.
1892.
the
<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
CONTENTS.
The Secret of Rest,
Spiritual Parentage,
LetterN. A. Briggs,
"      F. W. Evans,     G. H. Hollister,
Retrospection,
Our SisterE. C. S.,
To be a Shaker,
In memory of S. Bowie
LetterD. Orcutt,
Eclitoral,
Notes about Home,
Kind Words,
Inquiry, No. 6,
Scripture Text,
The Hill of Life,
Peace and War,
Psyche,
Deaths,
MusicMinistration,
Books & Papers,
Page.
169
170
172
-  173
174
-  177
179
180
182
188
189
190
191
192
SCUFFLING FOB DOLLARS.
To get the dollars we have to scuffle for
themon mistake about that; but there
are different ways of going about it, and if
you are not satisfied with your progress
at present, then write to B. F. Johnson &
Co., Richmond, Va., who can give you a
good pointer or two. Eead carefully their
advertisement in another column- and
write them at once. "The early bird,"
etc.
Hall's Journal of Health. July. Contents.
Talks with Dr. Mandeville; Approved Criminality; Longevity of the Sexes; Spiritualism
pure and simple; Death by Fright; Milk as a
Diet; Bee Keeping; Care of the Ears; Beer
Drinking; Pure Air and Life, etc., etc. Office
340 West 59th. St., N. Y.
THE FLAMING SWORD
A Radical, Rational  and Racy
Reform Paper.
The bitter foe of every form of social abuse
in church and state, the expositor of Koreshanity, which is primitive Christianity revived, and the promulgator .of an equitable
system of exchange which is destined to revolutionize commercial methods and
Orush  the Iniquitous  Money Power
SAMPLE   COPY "FREE.
Tie Gniiinj Star Pi, House.
3619 Cottage drove Avenue.
CHICAGO, ILL.
The Celebrated
Strattoa
BAND   INSTRUMENTS,
8naru and Basa Oruma, Fifes.   Piccoioe, Clarionets, Cynv
balsand on other instruments pertaining toBrass Bands and Drum Corps.
JOHIV F\ STHATTON &. SOX,
43   &   45  Walker   Street    NEW   YORK.
IF  TOD   CAHHOT  GET  THKM  OT   TOOT
THE GEHVHTB        UXM.   PEALEBS,    WE   VE1   FINP  BOMB
WA!  OF SUPPLYIKO  TOO WITH T5E
STRATTON
RUSSIAN GUT
VIOLIN STRINGS.
Denim Mud for Catalogue utf Pried Li
john f stratton & son.
Musical Merchandise.
4S4 4ft Walker Su.        NEW YOIti
SPECIAL
FROM
West Pittsfield. EVfass.
F. A. Owen;
Pres. Am. Correspondence
College:Dear Sik:Some of your
students at this place having called my
attention to the course of instruction
provided by the AMERICAN CORRESPONDENCE COLLEGE, I
can say, from a personal examination
of the same, that I consider the information and benefit it imparts to be of
very great educational vnlue to teachers and students as well as to any <>ne
who wishes to increase or revive his
fund of practical knowledge.
Yours truly,
Louis Basting,   Pastor of Church at W.  Pittsfield, Mass.
r our" REVIEW
& METHOD COURSE" given by
mail. A course of 10 weeks costs but
$2.50. (40 per cent discount to teachers.) A 32 page catalogue of all our
courses on receipt of stamp. Our mail
course in SHORT HAND is the best
and cheapest. Send stamps for full
particulars.
AMEKI0AN COREESPONDEtfCE
COLLEGE.
SOUTH DANSVILLE, N..Y.
Vol. XXII.
AUGUST, 1892.
No. 8.--><pb n="169" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Secret of rest" TEIform="index"/> THE SECRET OF REST.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, Oliver C." TEIform="persName"/> Oliver C. Hampton.</byline><p TEIform="p"> A blazing torch is capable of imparting its heat and light to other bodies contiguous to it.
                            This may also be said of the heat and light of spiritual inspiration. A person possessing
                            these in a high degree may impart the same to others so as often to make them feel highly
                            charged with good feelings and heavenly ministrations. This is excellent for those of short
                            travel and small experience. It helps them along and comforts them in hours of sorrow and
                            darkness. Too high an estimate of this extraneous blessing and boon cannot be made,
                            especially in regard to the weak" and inexperienced. But there cometh a time when these
                            ministrations seem to be withdrawn and the spirit is left alone to the task of its own
                            emancipation from its negative state ; from its inward thralldom and its adverse outward
                            environments. Jesus referred to this time in our spiritual experience as an unavoidable and
                            indispensable necessity. It seemed at times in fact that the Savior became anxious for fear
                            his followers would become too much attached to his person. He knew that this would be not
                            only a mild form of idolatry, but would prevent the final permanent evolution of the Holy
                            Spirit in them. So long as he was present with them personally, and was ready to make such
                            remarkable demonstrations of his divine power in favor and for their comfort and safety,
                            they could see no necessity for anything more. Under his anxiety about this matter, he said,
                            "It is expedient for you that I go away, for if I go not away the Comforter will not come
                            unto you, but if I depart I will send him unto you." Another proof and illustration that
                            invisible energies are always behind visible entities and results. Jesus' disciples and
                            followers must sooner or later, through self-discipline and self-abnegation, come to develop
                            that kingdom of heaven in themselves which would constitute the Comforter, or permanently
                            abiding condition of peace, salvation, and complete ascendency over all negative states of
                            disease of both body and soul. Notice this remarkable expression : "Even the spirit of Truth
                            whom the world cannot receive, because it seeth him not, but ye know him for he dwelleth
                            with you and shall be in <pb n="170" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> you;" where the word "with" alludes to the
                            present tense while "in" alludes to the future tense. So when he should become invisible he
                            could impart the energy necessary to wake up and bring to life that latent "kingdom of
                            heaven" which he declared was in them and which when vitalized would urge upon them the
                            abandonment and crucifixion of all lusts of inferior things, and substitute pure, holy and
                            progressive conditions. If the kingdom of heaven is within you the King of course must also
                            be there; and who better able to lead us into all truth than the Father of all truth? Will
                            this furnish any excuse for ignoring fidelity and sacred allegiance to the visible Order of
                            the church? By no means. Did Ananias and Diotrephes ignore that sacred Order with impunity?
                            Not at all. One was engulfed in the maelstrom of pride and haughtiness "in wanting to have
                            the pre-eminence," and the other in that of blasphemously ''keepingback part of the price"
                            when he was under no obligations to surrender any of it unless he chose to. Organization and
                            systematic arrangement are necessary to the very existence of a church, and an organiization
                            which secures the greatest amount of good to the greatest number, and wherein "without all
                            contradiction the less is blest of the better," is the only one which will make a church a
                            permanent success and at the same time secure to every sincere and faithful member thereof,
                            a complete at-one-ment with God, when persevered in a sufficient length of time to wear out,
                            and do away with, by self-discipline, all old negations of sin, sorrow and sickness. But
                            such organization cannot proceed without compliance on the part of its in embers, with the
                            direction and instruction of its Leaders every time. This was the Pentecostal philosophy of
                            Jesus and Mother Ann, and so far, this philosophy has never failed of happy, sure, and
                            permanent results, so long as conscientiously adhered to by the church, collectively and
                            individually. I speak from long experience and observation, having thoroughly and
                            practically traveled over every inch of the ground herein described, and therefore do know
                            of the doctrine from being a doer of the work; also having noted the experience of others,
                            both those who have been able "to make their calling and election sure" by faithfulness, and
                            those who have failed through unfaithfulness. It is folly to deny that there are some
                            painful sacrifices in this Christ life, but when these are over and "the wicked one cometh
                            and findeth nothing in us," then do we begin to "turn and come to Zion with songs and
                            everlasting joy upon our headsthen we have obtained joy and gladness, and sorrow and sighing
                            have fled away forever." Union Village, Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spiritual parentage" TEIform="index"/> SPIRITUAL PARENTAGE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Vinneo, Cora C." TEIform="persName"/> Cora C. Vinneo.</byline><p TEIform="p"> We prefer not to wait until the form is removed from sight, and the spirit retires within
                            the veil, to publicly express our praise and appreciation, our <pb n="171" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> love
                            and affection for a spiritual parentage. The following lines speak for themselves.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beloved mother in Israel" TEIform="index"/> Beloved Mother in Israel</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Taylor, Eliza Ann" TEIform="persName"/> ELIZA ANN TAYLOR.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Adown the vista of thy fourscore years, Thy children look and lovingly behold Thy Godlike
                            life, which, free from sin appears [gold, Blight as the diamond, pure as well tried A soul
                            well moulded to the Master's will, A voice which bids all baser thoughts be still. The true
                            nobility, the constant zeal, The patient fortitude which firmly stood, And bore and suffered
                            for a people's weal, Preserved the covenant which brought us good; [shine, These are the
                            virtues which will live and And mark thee as a hero-soul divine. Behold the woman on whose
                            brow is sealed The impress of the living Christ on earth; The Motherhood in God, to those
                            revealed Whose souls have found the new and second birth, Transfigured on the mount of truth
                            they stand, [land. And catch far glimpses of the heavenly We see thee as a lily snowy white,
                            [soul, Sweet emblem of a pure and chastened Whose pearly chalice holds the sunbeams bright,
                            Waving in all their zephyrs as they roll. And deeply planted in the parent sod It grows, and
                            blooms, and breathes its soul to God. We see thee as a palm-tree tall and fair, Whose
                            spreading branches make a sheltering shade [there Where weary ones may come, and resting
                            Find comfort, yea with none to make afraid. No harmful influence finds a place in thee, Thy
                            healing leaves are love and charity. We see thee as a rock 'mid oceans' waves, Unmoved when
                            storm and tempests surge around, Firm as the rcckbed of that faith which saves All those who
                            build on its foundation sound. So true art thou to God, so true to souls, True as the magnet
                            to the electric poles. We see thee as a Shepherdess, so calm and strong, Gathering thy
                            little lambs within the fold Safe from the outer world, where they so long [and cold. Had
                            wandered, shivering in the storm O tender Shepherdess! thrice blest the name, [fame. Dearer
                            to us than queens with all their We see thee as a Priestess of the Lord, Standing within the
                            Temple's Holy Place. From whose pure lips oft came the living word, [grace. Clothed with the
                            mantle of thy truth and In knowledge wise, in innocence complete. Thy heart a shrine where
                            angels love to meet. From out that inner sanctuary pure, We' ve often felt thy testimony
                            swift As lightning's flash, then answering thunder sure Bespoke the power abiding in the
                            gift The gift that comes to us in God's good way, A guiding star by night, a sun by day. And
                            we have felt thy tender mother-love, That broadened in our souls as they grew more, [above,
                            Just as when pebbles strike the waves The widening circles kiss the outer shore; Embracing
                            all within thy watchful care, The least one in the fold thy love might share. And now at
                            last life's race is nobly run, Life's jeweled crown is resting on thy brow, Toward the west
                            thy golden setting sun Appears but brighter as we see it now; Life's beating waves have
                            anchored into calm, Life's undertones have blended in a psalm. Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Charity bears a humble mind" TEIform="index"/>Charity bears a humble mind
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Charity bears a humble mind.</p><pb n="172" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My Dear Sisters, M. E. and J.--A trinity..." TEIform="index"/>My Dear Sisters, M. E. and J.--A trinity...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Massachusetts, Boston, 1891" TEIform="index"/> Boston, Mass., 1891.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> My Dear Sisters, M. E. &amp; J.A trinity, and let us hope, three Sisters eternally
                                connected by one holy principle, a unit in faith, courage, and noble resolution, never
                                doubting, never halting by the way. You have chosen the better part; have entered the
                                path to Life Eternal, which leads straight to the Kingdom. Howbeit tempters may stand at
                                many points of your journey, endeavoring to draw you aside. They may appear as
                                relatives, urging, "Duty to natural kindred," and thus arousing your sympathies for '
                                'poor father, dear mother, or needy brother and feeble sister." They may come as
                                fanciful pictures of a beautiful world, full of enjoyment, which you have but to reach
                                forth your hand to possess, and it is yours. Tempters may appear in uncurbed desires, in
                                powerful inclinations to be more independent; to come and go as you please, without
                                questioning and without restraint. Scholarship, literature and art may offer peculiar
                                inducements. The natural desire of woman to please, and to please selfishly some one
                                man, and to be pleased selfishly by some one man : to gratify pride, vanity and
                                attendant evils. All these tempters will try to seduce you and test you as strongly as
                                they have tested other souls, some of whom have stood in honor and nobly triumphed. For
                                those who have fallen by the way we will leave our prayers and our word of pity as we
                                pass on, trying to keep step, if possible, with the volunteers who are pressing
                                earnestly forward to join the ransomed. Does a doubt as to which way your feet shall
                                walk ever confront you? Does a perverse way seem very plausible? Ask; Is it right? Does
                                my faith, my conscience lead me, or is it rather my animal affection; a judgment warped
                                by selfish and personal inclinations? Is it this which exerts such a powerful spell upon
                                me? Sisters, in your humble trust and dutiful obedience to your faith, you are
                                beautiful, more so than you now think, and yet, how easily you may fall; more easily
                                than you can realize. Those robes of lovely innocence and purity, which you love to
                                wear, will, if draggled in muddy pools of self-love, seem more odious by contrast, than
                                the already soiled garments of the habitually unclean. Are you firm in your
                                determination to abide every trial "of your faith? Can you withstand the pleadings of
                                your own hearts, or should the tempter appear in the guise of one whom you may have and
                                still do dearly love? Can you forsake father, mother, brother, sister, husband, lands
                                and your own lives also to enjoy a fullness of gospel liberty, and an assurance of Life
                                Eternal ? It is the motto of nations, "In time of peace, prepare for war," again, "In
                                eternal vigilance is the price of safety," as well as liberty, and is quite as
                                applicable to individuals as to nations. We must walk carefully, prayerfully and
                                fearfully, closely inspecting every step of ground, lest suddenly we encounter a bog,
                                and find ourselves mired: yet there is no danger of sur- <pb n="173" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> prise to
                                the watchful, but the unwary are easily ambushed by the enemy. How is it Mare you booked
                                for the Kingdom ? Eare you sure of your allegiance to your faith? Jare you fortified
                                against every possible contingency ? Is your danger signal out? Is your sheet-anchor
                                cast and helm lashed? ]f so you can laugh at breakers and sing in spite of the tempest,
                                for if every sail is trimmed and your chart is clear you are safe. The rock bound coast
                                has no terrors for the home pilot. Now shall I tell you the source of this peculiar
                                effusion? Well, these thoughts with many more passed swiftly through my mind, as I rode
                                into the City with Br. J. this evening and saw so many of our fashionable sisters
                                wandering aimlessly up and down the streets, with no purpose, seemingly, but to exhibit
                                their finery or to attract attention to their persons. There ace some noble women in
                                Boston; many who attend prayer meetings, and charitable associations, instead of
                                patronizing theaters, and parading themselves in public, as if in the market; but too
                                many will act foolishly, and in my opinion the best of these will not compare with
                                pure-minded, cross-bearing Shaker Sisters. I love our home, peopled with beautiful
                                consecrated souls, dear Fathers, Mothers, Brothers and Sisters. God preserve our lovely
                                Zion home. Guard it well, dear Sisters. To all rny youngfriends I make a strong appeal,
                                for I love your souls' interest as a gospel Brother. In kindest love,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Briggs, N. A." TEIform="persName"/> N. A. Briggs.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="William Wilson, Beloved Brother:--I hear of you a good report..." TEIform="index"/>
                                William Wilson, Beloved Brother:--I hear of you a good report...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon, June 1892" TEIform="index"/>Mount Lebanon, N. Y., June,
                                1892.</dateline><p TEIform="p">William Wilson, Beloved Brother : I hear of you a good report from various quarters. It
                                is said, that you have discontinued eating the corpses of your fellow creatures, whether
                                they have four legs ol- only two, and that you have entered into a covenant of peace
                                with all herbivorous animals. And that if the Egyptian craving for flesh meat should,
                                for a short season, again assert itself, you will restrict the desire for "evil things"
                                to the carnivorawhich are evil. The lions, leopards, catamounts, hyenas, dogs, cats,
                                bears, wolves, foxes with skunks and hogs. These animals being carnivorous, cannot
                                justly complain if carnivorous men and women eat them. But when human beings, the heads
                                and lords of creation imbue their hands in the blood of lambs who "lick the hands just
                                raised to shed their blood," unsophisticated nature protests, revolts against it. The
                                herbivorous cattle on a thousand hills look to man for protection against the ferocious
                                cruelty of carnivorous animals. Many instances are on record of wild birds and helpless
                                herbivorous anhiials fleeing to human beings when pursued by their natural enemiesthe
                                carnivora. On one occasion, Mother Ann was brought into deep tribulation and realized
                                her mission as being to all God's creation and said: "O that the fishes of the sea and
                                the fowls of the air and all things that have life and breath, yea, all the trees of the
                                forest and the grass of the fields would pray to God for me! " In that spirit would she
                                rise from her knees and kill to <pb n="174" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> eat? I trow not. She was
                                beingtaught of God, and was baptized as a Mother indeed to all the creation of God. As
                                such, she would not "hurt nor harm" any thing that she called upon to pray for her.
                                Whence come wars and fightings, persecutions and inquisitions, come they not of lust the
                                lust of eating and drinking and the sexual lusts ? War will not cease to the end of the
                                earth until, "Thou shalt not kill," is recognized as the first and great command in
                                place of "multiply and replenish." Non-resistant religious sects, as Mennonites,
                                Moravians, Essenes and many other names, of. which Babylon is full, have always been a
                                prey because they departed from fashionable iniquity. Would vegetarian celibates,
                                communistic non-resistants, ever have had a "Salem witchcraft," or "St. Bartholomew
                                massacre" and have exhausted the national resources of all Christendom in raising armies
                                and navies and building forts and barracks on land, and immense monitors and war ships
                                on the ocean ? As a man eateth and drinketh so is he. The Jews, coming out of flesh
                                eating Egypt, fasted forty years from flesh eating. They did this as a nation. Their
                                food was purely vegetable. It changed the character of the people, and separated them
                                from all the peoples on the face of the earth. They are like the Gulf stream, that runs
                                through the ocean, warming and fructifying, but not mingling with its waters, Israel
                                dwells alone and is persecuted by all nations and people. John, the forerunner of Jesus,
                                ate the honey-locusts and wild honey; "he came neither eating nor drinking" like other
                                people. Jesus fasted forty days to cast out of himself the carnivorous appetites latent
                                in him as a human being. He was an "overcomer." He ruled over all the elements of which
                                he was constituted. Dear Brother, peace, the peace of God be with you and abide. Know
                                that the power of changing old and perhaps inherited habits is of God. It should be
                                highly prized by those who have it. How else can we become new creatures ? Conscientious
                                consecration of doing right and "swearing' to our own heart and changing not," is an
                                inestimable blessing. It brings the kingdom of heaven within our own souls. What is the
                                increasing with the increase of God, but perpetual daily change from bad to good; from
                                good to better? We have the whole human race to redeem and have eternity to do it in.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/> F. W. Evans.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Brother Hamilton:--I received the Mt. Morris paper in which was..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Brother Hamilton:--I received the Mt. Morris paper in which was...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Fredonia, January 9, 1892" TEIform="index"/>Fredonia, N. Y. Jan. 9, 1892.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Brother Hamilton :I received the Mt. Morris paper in which was a marked thought from your
                                mint. I also received a postal from my brother asking me to send for the "World's
                                Advance Thought" of December because of a piece of thought from his mint upon the
                                subject Armageddon. This subject, by the way, I. am but remotely interested in, am much
                                more interested in my brother and yourself than I am in the instability of human
                                institutions, which God is so evidently shaking down to a common level even to the
                                bottom of the seas of unbelief. That part or parcel of Armageddon <pb n="175" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/>
                                pertaining to my individuality does trouble me, and how to come to life out of its
                                valley is a matter of the first importance to me. This hoio to do, has been told me
                                plainly by a woman, Ann Lee; Mother, Bride of Christ, the Truth, the Light, the Way. She
                                confessed her sins one by one, just as she committed them and had faith that she could
                                take up her cross against all that she knew or thought to be sin, and told me to do the
                                same. Having been a faithful student of the Bible, Ann's teaching is to my apprehension
                                confirmed by the teaching of the Bible from the first chapter to the last. First, obey.
                                Next, having disobej^ed, confess and obey. This sums up the whole matter in a nutshell.
                                Nowhere in the lids of the Bible do I read that man is commanded to think, but
                                frequently man is commanded to do and to seek. I do read that "your thoughts are not as
                                my thoughts, nor your ways as my ways, saith the Lord." I see this world run
                                thought-mad, every one in haste to get his thought before his brother either as to
                                investing or making of pelf, home or happiness, the founding of states, honoring of men
                                and women, fighting a branch of the great tree of evil as prohibition. Associations
                                without end, investigations of the past and pryings into the future. Close and familiar
                                acquaintance with every spirit in heaven and earth but one's own spirit. Always before
                                our spiritual eyes are our own perverted selves; we turn away from that view and are
                                confronted alway and everywhere by the final judgment of that self. One more spiritual
                                sight is permitted us and that is the righteousness that is to be obtained by faith that
                                is in Christ. No act of faith was ever enacted that did not take the actors out and
                                above themselves for the time being. Hence all progress whatsoever is due to acts of
                                faith^ and not oi; speculation, ratiocination, contemplation or observation. I do read
                                that "as a man thinketh, so is he." But I also read that "the thoughts of man's heart
                                are evil continually before God," and his heart "is deceitful and desperately wicked
                                above all things." I am sick of the whole world of thought, a vast amount of chaff and
                                some precious wheat. If a man must sift his mental pabulum from men's rehash of God's
                                thoughts so simply put forth in his commandments, he will full soon have arrived at that
                                outer darkness where there is weeping, wailing and gnashing of teethor insanity. What is
                                it that troubles the mental and spiritual world most if it is not insanity? Every soul
                                that is not marching with fearless tread to victory over their own spirit, soul and
                                body, by the faith that is in Christ, is insane. And such approach death's door with
                                anxiety and fear, because they have not chosen in this life to believe wholly in the
                                power of Christ over all flesh. "Life is not what they planned it to be." This is the
                                oft-repeated story; I have but just heard it from a hearty, wholesome man and professed
                                believer in Christ, who is now facing the uncertainty of earthly relationships by death,
                                which his profession called him to make certainly uncertain in this life. This busily
                                thinking world has made the way of truth (?) exceeding broad <pb n="176" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> and
                                easy to the extent of giving all and keeping all: to the adaptation of truth (?) to
                                circumstances of pleasurable environment, rather than binding pleasure with cords to the
                                horns of the altar, which is death. This is only berating the evil I see, perhaps with a
                                beam in my eye. It is coining thoughts from my mint, when all thoughts should bear the
                                impress of God's mind without human perversion. I might run through my camera the whole
                                of human motive, aspiration, and result, and not add tone enough to inspire one soul
                                unto salvation, nor be able to furnish a dress modest enough for the public eye. And if
                                the dress should please, I should be glorified and exalted, whereas all glory is due
                                unto God. Nay, I will prefer the 119th Psalm. That prayer which only our Redeemer could
                                pray, and try to reach the keeping of the precepts, commandments, judgments, testimonies
                                and laws of my God, for it would be impossible for this imperfect creature to be glo
                                rifled. Truly I am deeply indebted to the thoughts of others for much inspiration and
                                companionship. Great aspirations after godliness and all true and undisguised truth is
                                the bread of life to every soul at some period. But they are only temporarily mine
                                unless by suffering I have evolved them out of, or through my suffering to bring them to
                                the birth in my heart. Let one have brushed aside all sophistries that would prevent his
                                generosity in a worthy cause, and how easily he inspires his audience to give. William
                                Booth has but just launched a mighty force spreading in all directions and for good ;
                                because first he was willing to suffer many things to gain faith himself. Christ was our
                                mighty exemplar, and Christ in Ann Lee is our mightiest example of what personal
                                suffering can do in one individual to bring to birth a faith almighty and sufficient to
                                compass that strongest passion of the human heart, the power of a life to create a life
                                for the selfish pleasure of the act. That a woman should be able to inspire thousands to
                                forsake the cherished perquisite of animal life by the faith that was in her revealed
                                through suffering". And who will renew for the world again this suffering for a great
                                faith? Must not each generation suffer for itself ? Supposing we were all compelled for
                                a little to part company with shelter, lands and companionship, without fire, to sit
                                upon a stone with a crust and a cruse of vinegar, to test whether we would yet hold our
                                faith. Again, the long life of increasing self-denial step by step of the honest Shaker
                                is more than the short, sharp test by fire and the sword ; and the poor and despised
                                Shakers are the salt of the earth, the hope of mankind, the glory of God on the earth,
                                but not of it. What a wide gulf as to the sympathies which are fast binding all
                                religious denominations in a compact, as it were, to go up and war against the only
                                visible Jerusalem, and none to spare for those who "make no provision for the flesh to
                                fulfill the lusts thereof." There is a severe trial coming upon all flesh and a great
                                reward coming also. "The word of God is <pb n="177" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> nigh us even m our
                                hearts, and in our mouths that we can do it." Away with the bother of worldly gossip
                                commonly called thought and give me the power to see myself as God sees me. It will
                                bring that best of all gifts, tribulation. Amen. From your Brother in the faith once
                                committed to the saints.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, G. H." TEIform="persName"/>G. H. Hollister.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Retrospection" TEIform="index"/> RETROSPECTION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Newton, Agnes E." TEIform="persName"/> Agnes E. Newton.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Another week its record leaves Upon the page of life; Its golden moments all are flown With
                            joy or sorrow rife. Ah! what the import of the hours Passing so swiftly on? [seek, Whence,
                            what and where the goal Ave What fields are lost or won? Our human hearts indeed are weak
                            Life's mysteries to grasp; Blind guides are theories and creeds, Traditions of the past. Our
                            present need, the claim we urge Before our Father's throne; "E'en as thy day thy strength
                            shall he" The promise we have known. Increase our faith, make strong and Our spirit's sight,
                            that we [fine May see aright, where duty points The way, to follow Thee. "Thy will be done"
                            will give the peace That earth can ne'er afford; The scholar's lore, the sceptic's pride
                            Availeth naught with God. ISTo cup passed by, hut in his name Who all of earth resigned; To
                            know and do his Father's will Acceptance we will find. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The wise keep memory of themselves and are never elated..." TEIform="index"/>
                            The wise keep memory of themselves and are never elated...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> The wise keep memory of themselves and are never elated by the applause of others.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our sister. Written in remembrance of Evelyn C. Strowbridge" TEIform="index"/> OUR SISTER.
                            Written in remembrance of EVELYN C. STROWBRIDGE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Morgan, Henrietta" TEIform="persName"/> By Henrietta Morgan.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Our loved ones are taken from us one by one to dwell in that "house not made with hands,
                            eternal in the heavens," where they will receive their reward, and become arrayed in the
                            garments of purity and bask in the sunlight of God's pure love. Although it is sad to part
                            with our loving Sister, we would not call her back to a life of suffering and pain, for we
                            know that her freed spirit rejoices in its happy transition. We shall miss her in the home
                            circle, where she has so long and faithfully labored. To me she has been a true friend and
                            Sister, many times administering loving counsel, which will, I trust, be of lasting benefit.
                            Her work here is done, and I think she was prepared to meet the change. May I so live that
                            when called to leave the shores of time, I may not have to regret a misspent life. Shaker
                            Station, Ct.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What is it to be a Shaker?" TEIform="index"/> What is it to be a SHAKER?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Mason, Moore" TEIform="persName"/> Moore Mason.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Are we to infer that the question is so complicated as not to admit of a simple answer? By
                            no means. It is the old experience of every question as well as everything else, that it can
                            be approached from many different points, and consequently will be seen differently. To get
                            at this question from a certain point of view, suppose each indi- <pb n="178" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/>
                            viclual were asked the question,Why are you a Shaker? Probably some would offer the not
                            quite satisfactory answer by saying it was a matter of accident. That to me sounds like
                            degrading our religion, yet why should mortals as we are be ashamed of that? Eeligion is not
                            a mere matter of intellectual process, but history and tradition, which must be accepted of
                            those who handed it down to us. After we arrive at the estate of manhood or womanhood, or
                            more properly after we've set out as Shakers and honestly confessed our sins, and determined
                            to walk in the straight and narrow path of self-denial, then we can be no longer satisfied
                            to be Shakers by accident, because spiritual evolution is already at work within us, which
                            is so applicably described as "First the blade, then the ear,, then the full corn in the
                            ear." We ought not to be so supercilious as to think the question,"Why am I a Christian,"
                            has not the same sublime meaning to those thoughtful men and women, who try to solve that
                            problem, as the question "What is it to be a Shaker?" has to us. But we ought to be thankful
                            that we can present a life that is the highest ideal, the noblest, best and divinest, that
                            the weary, sinsick, man or woman can find. But to confine ourselves to the question, What is
                            it to be a Shaker? Now simply living with, or calling ourselves by the name Shaker is not
                            sufficient, but we must know what it is to live and act as a Shaker, so that our lives will
                            show we are the Lord's people, his children, and realize it is our duty and privilege to
                            make ourselves worthy of him and then our whole endeavor will be to lead such a life as will
                            never deviate from the golden rule, "Love thy neighbor as thyself," and then we can always
                            be ready, as the apostle Peter says, to ' 'give an answer to every one that asketh a reason
                            of the hope that is in you." Must not the first converts to Shakerism have had strong
                            evidence of its divine origin (hounded as they were day and night by the so-called
                            Christians of that day and time) that caused them to embrace a faith which called for a
                            complete renouncing of their prejudices, habits, friends, country, and even safety in this
                            world? Well may we glory in our past, the nobility of our ancestors, who were always willing
                            to become witnesses of the truth; and our great religious structure has been well cemented
                            by the tyranny, prejudice and hatred, which was then so deeply rooted, and which, with
                            sadness, we still see cropping out where we least expect it. Then to answer the question,
                            "What is it to be a Shaker?" means that as Christians, "we must live unto God," and in so
                            doing, we must "die unto sin," for he who does not kill sin, sin will inevitably kill him.
                            Also at all times be ready martyrs for a cause that is destined to bring salvation to
                            mankind where they hunger and thirst no more and the days of their mourning is ended, for
                            having buffetted with a sea of sin as strong swimmers we at length have reached the peaceful
                            shore where already the victor's song is heard "Come unto me, and I will give you rest."
                            Watervliet, Ohio.</p><pb n="179" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bowie, Samantha" TEIform="index"/> In Memory of Sister SAMANTHA BOWIE.</head><p TEIform="p"> It was with feelings of deepest sorrow that we received the message of the decease of our
                            dearly beloved Sister Sainantha; and with a profound sense of the loss to her friends, and
                            to the Society of which she was such a devoted, efficient and useful member, that we extend
                            our heartfelt sympathy, and offer this simple tribute of love to her memory. Sister Samantha
                            was bound to us by the tenderest ties. We had known her from infancy. She was a dear
                            companion of our childhood and youth, and the affection which grew with our growth, and
                            strengthened with our strength, never lessened because we chose a different road to the one
                            our dear sister pursued to the end of her journey. We recall with affection our early
                            associations with the dear little girl, who, at the age of two years was brought by her
                            father, a motherless orphan, to the Believers at Watervliet. Mary was her name, afterward
                            changed to Samantha. Born in Scotland, of Scotch parents, she inherited many sterling traits
                            of character; honesty, sincerity and faithfulness to duty, being conspicuous features. She
                            was generous-hearted, and full of noble impulses. Kind to the aged, valiant for the weak,
                            and "always, always the children's friend." Indeed, she was a friend to be trusted "through
                            thick and thin." Sister Samantha gave her life to the cause in which she early enlisted, and
                            leaves a treasure of love to all those with whom she was associated. Her loss is great, but
                            her influence will live to bless, and strengthen those yet left to bear the burden. While
                            our hearts are still sad we have this assurance to comfort usIt is well with our dear
                            Sister. After much suffering she has peace, after weariness, rest, after weakness, strength.
                            Realizing the happy change, truly may her freed spirit sing, " There is no death. What seems
                            so is transition. The life of mortal breath, Is but a suburb to the life elysian, AVhose
                            portal, we call death."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[last name not given], Lucretia; [last name not given], Annie" TEIform="persName"/> Lucretia
                            &amp; Annie.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Children;--''I pray God your whole spirit and soul...''" TEIform="index"/>
                            Dear Children;--''I pray God your whole spirit and soul...''
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Connecticut, Enfield, June 1892" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, Conn. June, 1892.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Children;"I pray God your whole spirit and soul be preserved blameless." Your lives will
                            be blameless if you "bring your thoughts in subjection to the obedience of Christ." Good
                            thoughts are lovely guests. "Your thoughts and actions will bless or blight your spirits."
                            Make the habit of choosing" in every act and thought the habit of choosing right, and it
                            will soon become so much the habit that the opposite course will be impossible. Be firm in
                            your endeavor to shun all wrong forever. Never stray, "from the high path of duty," and you
                            will never regret it. To discard evil and cultivate goodness is to beautify your lives.
                            Purity is a heavenly ornament. Strive for it with soul earnestness. Purity is
                            soul-elevating, vice is soul-darkening. The earlier you are saved from sin the better. Be
                            pure in the present, or you will have grief in the future. It hardens the heart to live in
                            sin. Sinful pleasure is short, but the woe is long. Lose none of your soul wealth. It
                            requires self-denying struggles to form true Christian characters. Do your best work in
                            character-building. Think less of self and more of others. Give kindness and strength to
                            each other, to grow better means often to suffer. Store your minds with spiritual things.
                            Grow in grace. Make rectitude your aim. Wrestle for the heavenly prize, you can win it if
                            you are wise. Shun the society of the vicious. The influence of pure associates is refining.
                            "Pure company will make tlie heart To virtue more inclined, But bad will misery impart, And
                            vitiate the mind." Your Brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/> Daniel Orcutt.</byline><pb n="180" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p"> THE MANIFESTO. .A.TJG-TJST, 1892. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is published by the
                            "United Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued
                            regularly by the Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the
                            religious views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. All
                            communications should be addressed to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H.
                            TERMS. One copy per year, postage paid, " " six months, " " Send for sample copy, free. .75
                            .40 Entered at the Post Office at East Canterbury, N. H., as second-class matter.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial.</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The renewing of the mind seems to be one of..." TEIform="index"/>
                                The renewing of the mind seems to be one of...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> The renewing of the mind seems to be one of the essential features in the life of the
                                Christian. Whatever else he may do, either for the kingdom of this world, in making it
                                honorable or exalted before men, or in the establishing of Churches and securing a
                                company who may sing psalms and read holy books, the great secret of success will be,
                                after all, in that simple and effective lesson which was first heard in the streets of
                                Galilee so many, many years ago. "Repent," said Jesus, "for the kingdom of God is at
                                hand." He could not have said much less to his anxious hearers, and he did not need to
                                say any more to make it an effective and an impressive sermon. We eat and drink to renew
                                the life of the body. We make great demonstrations of care in our arrangements, and
                                search over the whole wrorld for what may please or satisfy the cravings of the external
                                man, and at the end of all that arduous labor we may not have succeeded in securing any
                                advantages that would carry us beyond those that are forced, through nature, to eat the
                                grass of the field. With so much special care for the perishable things of this life,
                                how much more careful we should be in securing for ourselves those treasures that are
                                worthy of a place in the kingdom of God, and which can not, under any circumstances be
                                destroyed. The mission of Jesus was to preach the blessing of the kingdom, which must
                                include the brotherhood of man. He, no doubt, found even among those money-grasping
                                Jews, men who were upright, God-fearing and zealous to do the works of the law. He found
                                those who affectionately shared in the burdens of each other, and who assisted,
                                liberally, in providing for the poor. Such men in this day would be called the
                                benefactors of the race. Their names would be heralded throughout the nation, while the
                                doors of the church- <pb n="181" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> es, as well as those of the public halls
                                would be thrown open for their entrance, to receive the benedictions of the one and the
                                plaudits of the other. "Purple and fine linen" would be brought forward for decoration,
                                as indicative of the exalted position that was occupied by those who claimed a right to
                                the whole earth, and unhesitatingly denominated themselves the Sons of God. It was to
                                just such a class as this that Jesus said, "Repent, for the kingdom of God is at hand."
                                With all their boasted privileges as sons of God, for whom God had fought their many
                                battles and destroyed without mercy their thousands of enemies,for whom he had wrought
                                some of the most wonderful miracles, to save them from the Egyptians ;had divided the
                                Red Sea, and allowed the Jews to pass over on dry land ;had rained manna upon them
                                during a journey of forty years, so that they were never hungry for want of bread. These
                                men were now asked to "Repent" of their crooked lives, to change their minds, to think
                                differently about God and his work among men,and to pray for his kingdom to come upon
                                the earth, that it might be among men. It was a revolution in the mind. Before, this
                                date, God had said, Kill your enemies, but now God says, Love your enemies. All is to be
                                changed. A Jew and his treasure was closely fastened to the earth, but now he is told to
                                lay up his treasure in heaven, Avhere thieves can not steal it. If this changing of the
                                mind was necessary at that early day, it is no less so now.. There is a strong tendency,
                                in the mind of man, toward the elements of the earth. His thoughts, his language, his
                                deep interest are all thoroughly baptized into that element. Coming out from an
                                undisciplined body as do the members of our Community, the great necessity of a change
                                of mind, at once, becomes apparent. It is the beginning of the resurrection into a new
                                life,a life in and for God. Not only a new and pure language must be learned for
                                Christ's kingdom, but a new tongue must be obtained with which to speak it. A new
                                interest must be grown in the heart that shall actually desire the increase and
                                prosperity of God's work among men, or we fail to repent, agreeably to the voice of the
                                Christ, and fail even to do as much as did the voice in the wilderness.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p"> Please write the articles that are intended for publication on sheets of NOTE SIZE, 5x8
                            inches ; write with ink on one side of the paper, only, and much oblige the printers of the
                            Manifesto.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We see misery entailed on the souls and bodies of millions..." TEIform="index"/>
                            We see misery entailed on the souls and bodies of millions...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> We see misery entailed on the souls and bodies of millions by these twin vices,liquor and
                            tobacco.</p><pb n="182" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/> NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mount Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/> Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> Average of Weather at Mount Lebanon. June. Thermometer. Barn. 1891. 65.32 3*.88 in.
                                1892. 69.53 3.19 in. Highest Temp, during this mo. 92. Lowest " " " " 52. Total Rainfall
                                " " " 3% in. Number of rainy days " " 12 C. G. E. July, 1892. Working, growing,
                                developing, progressing spiritually was the earnest tone of our Society meeting this
                                morning; and "en, rapport" with this comes the pleading inquiry, how best can we
                                accomplish it? The growth and perfection of the arts and sciences are attained by adding
                                knowledge to knowledge, experience to experience by conferences, associations, debates,
                                criticisms, etc; each scientific illumination seeking to dispel the mists of former
                                ignorance, until the best light of the present is attained. Ought not spirit growth to
                                take example by the scientific? Blest as we are with a threefold life, physical, mental
                                and spiritual, who is able to solve the intricate problem of its equal growth? Who with
                                a knowledge of political economy would consider it wise to expend more labor on
                                production, than its possible remuneration? Yet is not this the constant mistake of
                                household economy? Do we not use so much time and strength on the maintenance of the
                                body, that the mind is crippled, and the soul undeveloped? Still we are obliged to
                                confess that circumstances often bind us to these conditions. Ought it to be thus? Can a
                                spiritual, intelligent people afford to lose their rightful inheritance, when the
                                conserved wisdom of many in our own Societies could come to the rescue? Gail Hamilton
                                says, "Utter no complaint whatever betide, for complaining is the sign of weakness; if
                                your trouble can be helped, help it; if not, bear it." Thus our desire to be strong and
                                brave mid the trials which everywhere creep into life, causes us to take for granted
                                that "whatever is, is right," when if we had the will and power to climb out of the
                                ruts, we should see that many things are possible with the energetic and persevering.
                                Our household economy should be constantly growing to perfection. Communal life,
                                division of labor, united interests, ought certainly to solve the problem of how the
                                body, mind and spirit can and shall be properly developed, without either of the three
                                infringing on the other. Who among the noble, brave-hearted Sisterhood will give us the
                                benefit of their experience, that our Zion home may be rich in members having sound
                                minds in sound bodies, pure and refined spirits, able to be the counterpart of angels.
                                But my space is filled ere I have time to say, that of all beautiful scenery, we think
                                nothing can surpass our home and its environments at this season of the year. The neatly
                                cultivated gardens and fields in close proximity with the leafy fulness of the wooded
                                hills beyond, make a natural picture such as many spend time and money in traveling to
                                see. A. J. C. Center Family. July 10, 1892. We again find ourselves in the month of the
                                merry hay-makers, when the harvesting really commences. Brethren have been busily
                                engaged the past week, haying, and much interest was manifested, as we find them working
                                after supper getting it under shelter, lest the rain come, and spoil their labor. Corn,
                                beans and potatoes are doing nicely. We had our first meal of peas June 26th; rather
                                early, was it not? Cherries are not as plentiful as some years, nevertheless they are
                                fine. Sisters are putting up some of the small fruit for winter use already. Our Sunday
                                Service has been held at the meeting house this season but no <pb n="183" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/>
                                public meeting and the rain lias not kept us at home thus far. Last Sunday two Sisters
                                representing the Koreshan Community attended and the general impression made was that
                                they are sincerely living out tljeir principles of right. They have the heart-felt
                                wishes of the people here for their success. The weather has been quite an improvement
                                this month on last, and July if it continues, may redeem June's rainy character. General
                                good health prevails in the family. Early potatoes this morning. I. L. P. HNTortlx
                                Family. July, 1892. We are now in the haying season with harvest of grain close at hand.
                                The hay crop with us is very light, except where the land has been highly fertilized.
                                Rye generally very good; oats medium. Fruit very much less than was anticipated.
                                Eecently we have enjoyed a very pleasant and profitable visit with the two leading
                                sisters of the Koreshan Unity: Annie G. Ordway and Virginia Andrews. Very interesting,
                                inasmuch as all doubt as to the virgin celibate character of the members of the Unity is
                                removed, and a Christian communistic relation maintained: they living the same lives as
                                do all true members of our Shaker Communities. Profitable, because we felt a renewed
                                baptism of courage, hope and life; an inspiration that prompted to more zeal in the
                                spiritual work of God. Their theology being based upon an entirely new system of
                                astronomy, overthrowing all our preconceived ideas, was well nigh enough to turn the
                                balance against them. But coming to a knowledge of their lives by personal contact, (Br.
                                Benjamin Gates having visited them in their own home at Chicago and now their leading
                                sisters visiting our home,) the prejudice has been removed, and we feel free to look
                                into and examine their theology and cosmogony; knowing that the truth will in the end
                                prevail. It is a matter for heart-felt gratitude that we have no cast-iron creed to keep
                                the soul from growing into a more perfect knowledge of the truth continually. Above all
                                peoples should 'we be the most free, and the most willing to acknowledge truth wherever
                                it is manifested. Is there any other way we can come in unity of faith unto perfect men
                                and women, to the measure of the stature of the fulness of Christ? We are now on the
                                declining side of the year 1892, which is our centennial of the gathering of our church
                                into gospel order. Believers have had much experience and learned many things in their
                                hundred years of travel that would be very interesting and profitable for the rising
                                generation to know, and might save a good deal of blundering repetition in the future.
                                "A bird in the hand is worth two in the bush." While we have living witnesses to speak,
                                could we not learn more and better from them, than from future history made up of
                                inferences gathered from circumstances? A series of meetings composed of representatives
                                from every Society to exchange experience, thought, and suggestions on the living, vital
                                issues pertaining to the increase of Christ's kingdom in the earth, would be very
                                inspiring and soul awakening. Shall the spiritual work of God be left, for the most part
                                to invisible agency, and we poor mortals just drift Avith the current? The times are
                                propitious, the fire is aglow, and the iron heating; who will tell when to strike? In
                                kindest love, D. O.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watervliet, New York" TEIform="index"/> Watervliet, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> Second Family. The weather has been wet and cold for this season of the year. We are in
                                the midst of haying, that is, when the sun shines. The crop in this section will only be
                                medium. Eye is about ready for the reapers. Corn is very backward, oats are heading out.
                                Our beloved Ministry arrived at the Valley July 5th., in good health. They brought us
                                much love from eastern kindred, also from the Mount. We are glad <pb n="184" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/>
                                to say Br. Chauncy Miller keeps improving in health and strength. May he recover and be
                                with us many years, as he has talents that are much coveted in "Zion's great need."
                                While we are busy laying in temporal stores, let us not forget the spiritual harvest.
                                Human nature is just as full of excuses to-day as it was in the days of Jesus, if not
                                more so. We need to keep our calling ever before us, it is dangerous to parley or look
                                back, for Satan is ever ready to take us on that high pinnacle and offer us the kingdoms
                                of this world if we will only bow down and worship him. Let us bear in mind there is no
                                standstill, it is either forward or backward. Let us therefore be numbered with those
                                who have put their hands to the gospel plow never to look back. *</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/> Shaker Station, Conn.</head><p TEIform="p"> "Paul may plant and Apollos may water, but God giveth the increase"giveth it not in our
                                own time it may be, but in his own best time, in his own wise way, and no repining on
                                our part, no impatience at the delay can hasten its growth. "As the heaven is high above
                                the earth, so is his thought above our thought, and his way above our way." We see how
                                nature works and waits from spring to fall and from fall to spring again, and watch how
                                slowly the seed sown in the spring-time makes progress toward the ripened fruit. Knowing
                                this to be God's own way of working, we should apply the same rule to spiritual life.
                                Let us be sure we are sowing pure seed in the heart, sure we ought to do just what we
                                are doing, and all will be well. We have but to do our part and wait in faith for God to
                                do his. He will surely do it, and as surely will He see to it that no effort of ours
                                toward the right fails of its reward. "Having done all to stand." The Manifesto is a
                                visitor at our home every month. It is like the face of a dear friend. How quickly we
                                scan the pages to see if our friends have sent us their words of soul cheer and
                                good-will. It is just what we need, we get so many instructive lessons from it we should
                                be sorry to miss its visits. Our ever bearing strawberry plants are a success. The crop
                                was abundant. It may prove to be the ideal berry. The poultry business is a study. It
                                means something more than throwing down corn to chickens. Just which breed to keep is
                                what might be discussed every month. It is a matter of experience. Every thing can not
                                be put plainly on paper, but we can talk about it and get ideas from each other. 5193
                                spaces of cream were sold in June. D. Obcutt. Sontli ITartLily. Again we are reminded
                                that "Home Notes" are due for the Manifesto, and with those who so freely give for the
                                benefit of others I would unite and speak of the many blessings whick are ours to enjoy.
                                Health, the best of all earthly blessings, has be'en conferred upon us, and contributes
                                much to the demands upon our time at this season of interest and occupation within and
                                without, when every thing is teeming with life and joy. The New England climate we
                                protest is very anti-christian weather. If there is any normal condition for the
                                weather, it appears of late to be one of rain, hot sun and disagreeable winds. We have
                                heard it hinted that certain spots on the sun are the cause of the trouble. If so, soon
                                may they leave us in peace. Our farmers look and feel disconsolate because harvest is
                                here and no good weather to secure it. Hoed crops are behindhand for the same cause,
                                every thing is growing, weeds and all. We would mention the value of Breed's Weeder in
                                keeping weeds down. But we believe that God's blessing will eventually rest on faithful
                                labors done in his service; in doing our part and leaving results with a higher power. A
                                severe thunder shwer passed over our valley on the 3rd. inst., doing some damage; the
                                wind was also terrific. It <pb n="185" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> continued for some time, blowing down
                                trees and leveling the corn and other things. It was much cooler and frost-like the next
                                morning but has again become warm, and hopes areihitertained of a few days of fair
                                weather. M. W. </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ayer, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/> Ayer, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p"> July, 1892. As one individual after another is led to apply for membership in our
                                Society, we have a line chance to see to what extent they have been baptized into a
                                refining and moralizing element necessary for a further work into that which is more
                                spiritual. And where should this refining work commence if not in the minds of the
                                children and youth, who should be pliable an d easily led toward the spirit of good and
                                thus become a blessing to themselves and to their friends. Fathers and mothers, there is
                                nothing of greater importance to you, than to make the welfare of your children the
                                first object of your life;the preserving of the purity and innocence of their young
                                lives. Is the raising of large crops to be compared to it, or is the unceasing scrub
                                scrubscrub! which makes the home a marvel of neatness, to be of parallel importance to
                                the giving of attention to the influences that are moulding the characters of our
                                children, the effects of which will live long after our hard labor has turned to dust?
                                We may not know the effect of a kind word, although it may not be held in remembrance of
                                the speaker, while in the mind of the child, who may have needed just that touch of
                                inspiration, it may awake to new life after a journey of many years. The young mind is
                                always open to surrounding influences, and the brighter those influences are made, the
                                more pleasant becomes life's pathway. Where'er you go, yea, sow a seed, If cloudy be
                                your sky or fair; God's grain shall fruitful be, indeed,. And we to heaven the sheaves
                                may bear. Haying has commenced and we are gathering in crops from some of the seed !
                                sown in early spring. May the harvest be bountiful. Apples are about a medium crop.
                                Pears and plums are about the same. Were blest with a plentiful supply of strawberries.
                                A. D. B.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/> East Canterbury, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p"> Weather Kecord, for April 189-. Highest Temp, during the mo. 90. Lowest " " " " 00. Mean
                                " ' " " " 68.7 Total rainfall " " " 3.5Gin. Number of days in 'which .01 of an inch
                                fell, 41. N. A. Biugg-s. July 13, 1892. After many days of anxious thought, if not of
                                tears, and after a fearful foreboding of continuous rain, which the heavens seemed to be
                                pouring out from their windows, through which the farmers could see the destruction of
                                their crops, and the ruinous time to make their hay, there has come a change in the
                                programme. The first few days in July were unpropitious and the mowing machines were
                                carefully kept under cover, but on the opening of the second week the sun began again to
                                smile on the earth and the hay makers were made glad. Day after day the heat comes
                                pouring down and there is a pleasing relief when the sun hides himself behind the
                                western hills. Now it is about time to begin to grow anxious lest the sunshine may be
                                too protracted, and the grass may ripen faster than it can be prepared for the barns.
                                The cold, early rains blighted the strawberries, and the still earlier cold days killed
                                most of the raspberry bushes, while the worms and cold weather have injured the uurants.
                                In a few months more we may be able to determine our loss or gain on all the fruits and
                                vegetables that have claimed our attention. New potatoes, that appetizing dish, were
                                raised in exaltation to the surface of the table on the 11th. inst. History informs vis
                                that Father James en! joyed a meal of new potatoes and in this ' respect we are his
                                worthy children. <pb n="186" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> This month we have a beautiful flower garden
                                which brings no burden and demands no care. Hundreds and hundreds of white water-lilies
                                are spread on the surface of the water garden every morning. Xo guardian watches with
                                jealous eye over this beautiful place and the small boy and big boy are wading into the
                                water or contriving many other ways to desecrate a spot which for beauty in itself and
                                surroundings would be hard to find. This month we have cut a wood's road for several
                                rods leading to a place of interest for the antiquarian. In the indefinite past;it may
                                have been 10,000 years or more, three large granite boulders were deposited on the
                                highest elevation in that vicinity and have no doubt held possession of the spot since
                                the above date. I had almost said that they had held peaceable possession, but the hand
                                of the vandal has left his mark. From one boulder large pieces have been split by hammer
                                and chisel, and now lay in their loneliness half buried in the earth. Visitors to the
                                spot, wonder. All is sphinx silence. Our Sisters at the Trustees' Office have toiled
                                early and late and at great expense to remodel a sales room, where they can present,
                                more satisfactorily, to the hundreds of visitors to the village, the variety of fancy
                                articles that have been made by the Sisters or purchased in other places. We shall wish
                                them the best of success and a fair return for all the cents and dimes and dollars that
                                they have expended.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/> Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p"> Since our last writing, we have been visited by a small sized cyclone, and yet its
                                proportions satisfied us, as we do not crave more in bulk, that we may be able to give
                                marvelous reports: we who have not as yet lived quite half a century, never saw any
                                thing like it; the heavens were suddenly darkened, and the rain came in more than
                                torrents, with a furious wind, obscuring the vision from one building to its neighbor,
                                although near by. The large vegetable garden for a time was one big mud puddle, but it
                                soon went down to slake the thirst of the angle worms, and was as firm as ever. We are
                                thrice glsil to say that the laundry is receiving a new coat of paint with very
                                appropriate trimmings; whoever has visited us recently, will of course recollect how
                                wretchedly it looked, and be glad with us; if the Brethren "continue on" and paint other
                                buildings we will tell you that also; the paint was purchased with money coming from
                                Sisters' sale work, so considering both paint and painters, it may truthfully be called
                                Home Industry, which is the better part of the story. The summer term of school closed
                                July 8th. One speaker told the scholars they had the cosiest, nicest school in town,
                                they all looked bright as dollars and to the teacher aside he said, "I've had an awful
                                good time," whether that phraseology be a good omen for the school, or a bad one for the
                                Board, we leave our readers to determine. We know that both teacher and pupils have
                                aimed to do thorough work, but we venture to assert that an interested woman would both
                                criticise and give helpful suggestions, which teachers always appreciate. Our sister
                                Society has been more fortunate in securing this element on Examination Day. The outing
                                season is upon us, so we are encamped about, if not by the armies of Israel, by a small
                                army, seeking change, and the delights of rural living; no doubt it has its bitter with
                                the sweet, as do all conditions in this world, yet when we see pale faces go away with
                                the color of health, we conclude they have been successful in acquiring a part of the
                                gift of health, which is closer allied than we all realize to the gospel of salvation.
                                E. B.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine" TEIform="index"/> Sabbathday Lake, Me.</head><p TEIform="p"> July, 1892. "He shall have pity on the poor and needy and the souls of the needy He
                                shall save." It is a comforting promise that God will have pity on the poor and needy
                                and work in them for their salvation. By <pb n="187" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> feeling the need we put
                                forth an effort and therefore are saved. Thus, in "seeking first the kingdom of heaven
                                and its righteousness" all our temporal blessings are added. While hundreds of people
                                are seeking rest in the public resorts we are busy like the bee laying up a winter
                                store. We have lately enjoyed a visit with Elder Josiah Barker and Sisters Anna Case and
                                Isabella Graves of Watervliet, N. Y. They are like polished diamonds adorning the temple
                                of God and we know there are many more like them from the same mine. Not long since Gen.
                                Butler was at the Springs and came to see us. It was interesting to hear him tell of his
                                adventures in the war and especially of his cleansing the streets of New Orleans and
                                other reminiscences. Home duties are progressing as usual at this season. The Brethren
                                are just commencing the haying with the anticipation of an abundant harvest. A. S.
                            C.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sonyea, New York" TEIform="index"/> Sonyea, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> July, 1892. "How strikingly the signs appear That the harvest time is near. Now the
                                reapers have gone forth To gather fruits from off the earth." The early rising farmers
                                are hurrying early and late to secure a noble harvest by making hay while the sun
                                shines. The sunny days furnish broad fields and lots of hard work for all who possess
                                the valuable gift of push and pull, life and stir, the four essential qualities that
                                assist in forming the perfect man and woman. The living well know that "it is not all of
                                life to live, nor all of death to die." June celebrated its twenty-seventh day by
                                visiting the land with one of the most severe rain and hail storms ever known in this
                                remote section of the great big world, the storm was accompanied with sharp shafts of
                                lightning, forming a magnificent display of electric brightness. Our currant garden is
                                the finest of any seen on this or the other side of the big waters. G. D. G.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Union Village, Ohio" TEIform="index"/> Union Village, Ohio.</head><p TEIform="p"> July, 1892. The 4th. of July is passed and the ordinary amount of powder burning,
                                firecrackers, broken limbs and loss of eyes has transpired, and this morning all who
                                have not been killed or wounded can reassume their wonted avocations. The Believers at
                                Union Tillage do not meddle with such things, so we were quietly engaged hoeing and
                                replanting our beet field, cleaning the yard, cutting our wheat, mowing weeds in the
                                street, each side of which was plowed during the winter for our ten miles of hedge which
                                was set out this spring by the Dayton Hedge Co. Among those who visit us there seems to
                                be more inquirers among men and even more who enter the Society than are to be found
                                among the women visitors. This scarcity makes it very hard on the Sisters, who
                                nevertheless are all the time doing their level best to keep up their side of the cause,
                                and their zeal and faithfulness are absolutely above all praise. We have now about two
                                thousand seven hundred young fruit trees, but this season there is scarcely any fruit of
                                any kind in our Society and in fact in southwestern Ohio. Crops likely to be good,
                                except wheat, which is badly rusted in some fields. Health and peace prevail at Union
                                Village. Elder Joseph came West because he could not stand the severe Xew England
                                winter, but if he does not take care of himself better than he has so far, he will not
                                stand this nor any other climate long, unless it is the one beyond the silent river. Our
                                office is gradually nearing completion of repairs and we hope to be able to occupy it
                                before many weeks. There seems to be but little inspiration or conviction among mankind,
                                but we keep sending out tracts, leaflets and pamphlets, to direct their attention toward
                                our gospel home. This is our instruction, and the Bible says; "Be thou instructed O
                                Jerusalem, lest my spirit depart from thee and thou become desolate, a City not
                                inhabited." Jer. vi., 8. O. C. H.</p><pb n="188" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Canaan, New York" TEIform="index"/> Canaan, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> The crops are promising even if rather late. Peas are doing quite well, while our
                                cherries are a failure. And then our strawberries, well, I must say, we do not know how
                                to raise them. Nature is attending to those that grow in the field, and the Sisters have
                                gathered a good suppiyWe have commenced haying by cutting ' a field that has been
                                fruitful in daisies. Probably we shall need an extra favoring this season, as we have
                                fifty acres of grass to cut. Two and one half acres of buckwheat, seven acres of rye,
                                six acres of wheat, fourteen acres of oats, seven acres of corn, three and one half
                                acres of potatoes and two and one half acres in the garden, making in all ninety-two
                                acres, and but a small company for such a large field of labor. The Sisters have had a
                                busy time during the spring, and are now engaged in the painting of windows. They may
                                get through bright and early about next ISTew Tear's day. June 30th. and we are having
                                rain, rain, rain. I do not know but that we shall be swamped. We have put explicit
                                confidence in Hicks, in "Word and Works," where he said that after June 25th., we should
                                have a dry warm spell; so on to the 28th. we cut some grass and daisies, and sure enough
                                before it was finished, it began to rain and we have not been able to do anything with
                                it since, and have concluded to let it rain, so long as it will. July 2nd. was a
                                pleasant day and we secured the hay that was in the field. We shall try to coax in a
                                binder to help us through the rye and wheat harvesting, if we may be blest with some
                                fair weather. G. W. C.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>KIND WORDS.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I receive the Manifesto with pleasure, and I think..." TEIform="index"/>
                                I receive the Manifesto with pleasure, and I think...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury, N. H.</dateline><p TEIform="p">I receive the Manifesto with pleasure, and I think it gives comfort and cheer to many who
                                are seeking to know the true way of life. I bless every effort to spread the truth.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Tait, Amelia" TEIform="persName"/>Amelia Tait.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Inquiry. no. 6" TEIform="index"/> INQUIRY. No. 6.</head><p TEIform="p"> If parents with children join a Shak-er Society, how long can the parents retain the care of
                            their children? This will depend wholly upon the condition of the parents and children, as
                            an agreement would be entered into with the officers of the Society, for the benefit of both
                            parties. No children are ever taken under the immediate charge of the Society, except by the
                            request or free consent of those who have the lawful right and control of them, together
                            with the child's own consent. No parents are required to give up their children. Indeed we
                            think it more proper for parents to take care of their own children and bring them up in the
                            admonition of the Lord.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Scripture text" TEIform="index"/> SCRIPTURE TEXT.</head><p TEIform="p"> Was the spirit of Jesus preaching to the spirits in prison while his body was in the grave?
                            1 Peter iii., 19. By which also he went and preached unto the spirits in prison. The
                            prison-house of these spirits was a state of disobedience to known light. In an earlier
                            dispensation they refused Grod's call, and as Noah wTas a preacher of righteousness they
                            could not progress nor enter another dispensation until they had been faithful to that light
                            already received. The object of the preaching was to urge the hearers to repent and do their
                            first work, and then they would be <pb n="189" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> prepared to accept the testimony
                            of the Christian dispensation. The apostle evidently wanted to show his brethren the
                            universal mission of Jesus. He preached not only to men in the body, but also to those out
                            of the body, in the world of spirits. After the death of Jesus, some think that he was
                            preaching to the souls or to the spirits in prison as is said by Peter, "that they might be
                            judged according to men in the flesh, but live according to God in the spirit."</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hill of life" TEIform="index"/> THE HILL OF LIFE.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> (Contributed by M. Keniston.) I had climbed a part of the hill of life, And
                                    weary paused to rest, My soul was sick with sin and strife; I had failed in doing my
                                    best. I looked around with a restless eye Far up to the hill-tops crest; The human
                                    tide'both far and nigh Surged on with ceaseless jests. And some were poor and some
                                    were old, And some were young and gay; But rich and poor, and meek and cold, Were
                                    traveling the self-same way. And many looked on with an eager eye, To the future so
                                    glad and gay, And they trampled oft with a restless sigh The beautiful flowers of
                                    to-day. And some wTere lending a helping hand To a friend in need of aid, And
                                    leading him from the burning sand To the cool and grateful shade. And some were
                                    laughing with careless air As they trod their path in life; And some were solemn and
                                    full of care, From contest with sin and strife. A few paths looked so pleasant and
                                    clear, That I said in a mournful tone, "The hardest one that I see here Is given to
                                    me alone." Then came a whisper, "closer draw," And I strained my eyes to see, More
                                    thorns by far in them I saw Than in that which was given to me. Then slow and with a
                                    thoughtful glance I looked back at the path I trod, And thought how 'twas set, not
                                    by luck or chance But my heavenly Father and God. The thorns I had found so sharp
                                    and cruel Were but lessons I must learn, Ere I can pass from this earthly school,
                                    And await at the gate my turn. Then a prayer went up from my inmost heart "O Father!
                                    forgive thy child, Help me, O God, to do my part, To be humble, meek and mild." Then
                                    came hope like a gleam of light, I was strengthened to start anew, Resolved to do
                                    with my utmost might What was given me to do.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/> Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Peace and war" TEIform="index"/> PEACE AND WAR.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> Peace is greatly the beauty of the world. War is greatly the horror of the
                                    world. Peace ne\rer grows less beautiful by consideration. Warn.ver grows less
                                    horrible by consideration. Peace is g.-ntle, patient, benevolent. War is boisterous,
                                    impatient, malevolent. Every good flourishes in time of Peace. Every evil increases
                                    in time of war. Peace is meek and modest. War is haughty and proud. Peace does good
                                    and never trumpets with loud voice its loving deeds. "War is boastful of what it
                                    claims to have done for mank'nd and erects, with unblushing face monuments to its
                                    own remembrance and glory. Peacecontinual, universal Peacewould make the world a pai
                                    adise of beauty. Warcontinual, universal warwould make, the world a hell indeed. Let
                                    every man, woman, and child do all they can for Peace <pb n="190" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> the
                                    world cannot have too much Peace. Let every man, woman, and child do all they can
                                    against warthe world cannot have too little war. Let us all read very often and
                                    carefully Christ's Sermon on the Mountit is full of peace and no war. J. II. in</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Messenger of peace" TEIform="index"/> Messenger of Peace.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Psyche" TEIform="index"/> PSYCHE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fitzpatrick, Stanley" TEIform="persName"/> Stanley Fitzpatrick.</byline><p TEIform="p"> I saw a soula human soul Crowned with a royal diadem From which the rays of lambent light
                            Fell to her shining garment's hem. In her right hand a scepter proud Seemed meet for one who
                            wore a crown; Yet while her eyes were raised on high Her scepter pointed earthward, down. In
                            her left hand a prophet's harp A harp of gold with many strings A curious, carven thing it
                            seemed, Like that to which a seraph sings. She smote the harp and words of flame Like
                            lightning leaped athwart the sky, In music rareimmortal strains Deep, swelling anthems grand
                            and high. She raised the scepter of command And then I knew her inward might I knew the
                            power was hers alone To lead man upward to the light. I knew the clustered, starry rays
                            Which formed the circlet round her head Were gathered from immortal suns Which from the
                            Infinite were fed. And so I bowed as to a god, And in the dust my forehead laid; Her
                            splendor dimmed my mortal eyes And made the trembling flesh afraid. And then a voice from
                            silence boon Arose, sense-stilling, low and deep. Like rustle of the new-born leaves When
                            wings of night above them sweep. It said: "Look up, and claim thine own! LTplift thine
                            inward eyes and see! Behold! thy soul before thee stands And yet not thinefor it is
                        Thee."</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="No one can feel the guilt incurred by another..." TEIform="index"/>
                            No one can feel the guilt incurred by another...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> No one can feel the guilt incurred by another, nor wilt thou be arraigned at the bar of
                            justice to answer for another's crimes; therefore leave off meddling with other men's
                            conduct and diligently attend to thy own ways.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The mists may hide the stars, yet still they shine..." TEIform="index"/>
                            The mists may hide the stars, yet still they shine...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The mists may hide the stars, yet still they shine; thus sin may dim our inner vision, and
                            shut out the glory of God's eternal presence, and we grope about in darkness when light is
                            above and around us.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. A.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is easier to give good counsel than to observe it" TEIform="index"/>
                            It is easier to give good counsel than to observe it
                        </head><p TEIform="p">It is easier to give good counsel than to observe it.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.
                        </head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bowie, Samantha" TEIform="index"/>Samantha Bowie
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Samantha Bowie, at Watervliet, N. Y., May 30, 1892. Age 53 yrs. 1 mo. and 23 days. J.
                                B. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Page, Mary" TEIform="index"/>Mary Page
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Mary Page, at Shaker Station, Conn. June 16, 1892. Age 21 yrs. 8 mo. and 14 days. Our
                                kind little Sister passed from our sight Just when the life-bud promised to be A blossom
                                of worth and beauty entwined With the graces of love and humility. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Strowbridge, Evelyn" TEIform="index"/>Evelyn C.
                                Strowbridge
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Evelyn C.
                                Strowbridge, at Shaker Station, Conn. June 26, 1892. Age 42 yrs. 2 mo. and 9 days. One
                                by one they drift away Across the crystal sea. Done with the toiling day by day From
                                suffering set free. Our Sister's gone, we feel her loss, All earthly sorrow's past. Is
                                not our lose her eternal gain! Her toils are o'er, she rests at last, Rest, sweet rest,
                                from care and pain. I hear her sweet voice say: "Call me not back, the sea I've crossed,
                                Beyond earth's shadowy way. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sauerborn, John" TEIform="index"/>John Sauerborn
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> John Sauerborn, at Watervliet, Ohio. July 6, 1892. Age 68
                                yrs. 7 mo. and 12 days. Br. John was a faithful man and had been with the Believers some
                                thirty years. He has lived in the order of Elders, and also in the order of Trustees and
                                has always been an honest and upright brother. He has, no doubt, found peace and
                                happiness in his spiritual home. H. W. F.</p></div3></div2><pb n="191" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ministration" TEIform="index"/>MINISTRATION.</head><p TEIform="p">"The ministration of the spirit is glorious." --2 Cor., iii., 8. Canterbury, N. H. Blow,
                            Heavenly breezes, blow, Waft, waft us inspiration; Grant us thro' this vale below, Sacred
                            ministration. Bound by all that's good and true, To perfect our journey, Thou wilt daily
                            strenght renew,-- We shall triumph fully.</p></div2><pb n="192" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers
                        </head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ladies' home journal" TEIform="index"/>The Ladies' Home Journal
                            </head><p TEIform="p">In order to stimulate American composition, The Ladies' Home Journal has just, made
                                publican attractive series of liberal prizes for the best original musical composition
                                by composers resident in the United States ami Canada. The prizes call for a "waltz, a
                                piano composition, a pleasing bailed and a popular song, an anthem and the four best
                                hynm tunes. The competition is open until November 1st, next. The opportunity has an
                                additional attractiveness since the prize compositions will form part of a series for
                                which Strauss inventing an original waltz, and Charles Gounod and Sir Arthur Sullivan
                                each an original song. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>
                                The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health for July is a
                                live number, if it is summer time. "Try Your Weight," comes from a well-known writer
                                across the sea and is pat enough. Mrs. Florence Hull spe;iks of the ''Transition Period"
                                in child life, "with her customary intelligent understanding of the subject. "Olive
                                Thorne" Miller receives marked attention, and has a halftone portrait that looks
                                "natural." The article, Original Problems, i.s commended to all teachers. A teacher
                                wrote it and from a correct point of view. Thoughts on Education, Drugs and Health,
                                Systematic Moral Education, the Editor's Xinth Paper, the Notes in Anthropology and
                                other departments deserve more than passing notice, and should be read by all students
                                of human nature. The Journal is now ., office, 25 East 21st street, New York, by Fowler
                                &amp; Wells Co., at 15 c. a No., or $1.50 a year. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New England magazine" TEIform="index"/>New England Magazine
                            </head><p TEIform="p">"On trial" to new subscriber-six
                                months 50c. An article that will attract and interest all members of evangelistic
                                organizations, is "The Christian Endeavor Movement" in the June New England Magazine, of
                                Boston, Mass. It is written by three hands, and deals with the beginnings and methods
                                and aims of the organization in a thoroughly comprehensive fashion. The President of the
                                United Society of Christian Endeavor, Rev. Francis E. Clark, whose name is inseparably
                                linked with the movement as the originator of it, opens with an account of "The Early
                                Days of the Society." Amos R. Wells, the editor of the Golden Rule, the organ of the
                                society, deals with it as "A New Religious .Force," and touches upon its relation and
                                helpfulness to the churches; and John "Willis Baer, the Secretary of the Society, in
                                "The Outlook and the Opportunity," describes the possible growth and future of the
                                movement. The article is very fully illustrated with portraits of many of the trustees
                                and with most of the presidents of the different state organizations. In fact, every
                                Christian Endeavorer will find the familiar faces of old friends there, no matter which
                                part of this great country he or she may hold friends in. This great movement from New
                                England is fittingly present in this great Magazine. " </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="World's Columbian exposition illustrated" TEIform="index"/>World's Columbian Exposition
                                Illustrated
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> World's Columbian Exposition
                                Illustrated for July."To say this number is the most interesting, beautiful and valuable
                                of all the numbers so far issued is putting the fact very mildly. Indeed it is the crown
                                jewel of the seventeen artistic gemsthe seventeen numbers so far published. This month
                                the frontispiece is a full page, half-tone, copper plate engraving of the Hon. M. H. De
                                Young of San Francisco, third Vice-President of the World's Columbian Commission. it
                                contains many reading articlesof paramount importance to all those intersted in the
                                growth and development of the Exposition. We notice especially "The Nation Wishes It,"
                                setting forth very strongly that the Exposition is not only a national enterprise, but
                                should be dignified by substantial National support. It leaves no ground for any belief
                                other than that the American people so view this great enterprise. There are two very
                                valuable and timely articles entitled, "Sunday Opening vs. Closing," and "Sunday Opening
                                at the World's Fair." The latter is by Mrs. Frances E. Bagley of Michigan, Lady
                                Manager-at-large and widow of the late Gov. Bagley. She has arrayed her arguments in an
                                interesting and convincing manner, and her article sheds considerable light on the
                                satisfactory solution of this much mooted question. There is a schedule of the "Official
                                Traffic Arrangements for the Exposition," including the railroads and the trans-oceanic
                                steamship lines. This article is of great importance to intending exhibitors and
                                visitors. Very conspicuous among the artistic features are engravings, nearly all full
                                page, of statuary for the adornment of the principal buildings. There are two excellent
                                full page engravings of the Washington State building and of the Maine State building,
                                with many photographs of the State board managers of these two States. There is also a
                                double page engraving of the Mines and Mining Building, the first of the great
                                department buildings to be completed. Altogether, too much cannot be said in praise of
                                this admirable number. In a more pleasing and definite manner, by means of it, than ever
                                before can we appreciate the great importance and the educational influence of the
                                World's Columbian Exposition. From first to last there will be sixty numbers of this
                                journal. Price of the entire issues, postpaid to any address in the United States,
                                Canada or Mexico, 12. Early in the fall it will be published semi-monthly; during the
                                Exposition, weekly. Annual subscription price (24 copies) $5. 50. The publishers
                                announce their "Special Great Offer," which includes all the copies from July to
                                January, this year, ten in number, to one address for only $1.50; or about half price.
                                Single copies 25 cts. Address, J. B. CAMPBELL, President, 159 and 161 Adams St. Chicago,
                                ILL., U. S. A. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Journal of hygeio-therapy" TEIform="index"/>The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy. June. Contents. Treatment of the Sick;
                                Mental Science; Anti-Vaccination; Hygeio Therapeutic System: Whole Wheat vs. Fine Flour;
                                Dietary Department; Vegetable Recipes, etc., etc. Dr. T. V. Gifford &amp; Co.
                                Kokomo, Ind. England</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
JACK FROST FREEZER.
A Scientific Machine made on a Scientific Principle. Save
their cost a dozen times a year. It is not mussy or sloppy.
A child can operate it. Sells at sight. Send for prices and
discounts.
29   Murray St.,   NEW   YORK.
Makes    Ice   Cream    in   3O   Seconds.
E. C. Morris 4 Co.
64 Sudbury St.,  Boston, Mass.
FIRE AND BURGLAR-PROOF SAFES.
Bank Safes, Bank Vaults, Bank Vault
Doors, and Deposit Work of all kinds.
The Best Safe in the World.   150,000 in use.
Always preserve their contents
150 sold in Lynn, Mass., since that great fire
where 50 of our safes were subject to intense
heat, preserving their contents.
Champion Record also in the Great Chicago Fire in 1871, in the Great Boston Fir* in
1872, and in all the great fires since. Send
for circulars.         Agents Wanted.
WRO Ia WRfl A MONTH can be
l/9i W livvi made working for us.
Persons preferred who can furnish a horse
and give their whole time to the business.
Spare moments may be profitably employed
also. A few vacancies in towns and cities.
B. F. JOHNSON & CO., 26th. and Main St.,
Richmond, Va.
Scientific American
Agency for
CAVEATS,
TRADE  MARKS,
DESIGN PATENTS
COPYRIGHTS, etc.
For information and free Handbook write to
MUM & CO., 361 Broadway, New York.
Oldest bureau for securing patents in America.
Every patent taken out by us is brought before
the public by a notice given free of charge in tho
mnumx
Largest circulation of any scientific paper in the
world. Splendidly illustrated. No intelligent
man should be without it. Weekly, S3.00 a
year; $1.50 six months. Address MUNN & CO.,
Publishers, 361 Broadway, New York.
THE  ALTRUIST.
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is published by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all
their property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing
officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. 50 cents a year;
specimen copy free. Address A. Longley.
901 Olive St.,  St. Louis, Mo
 QU
 N EaAGENTS WANTED <T C f\ To (
MAKE FROM            vDOU LU <P 1
Aliirri/ working for WOsLIrS COLUMBI
IILLIv POSITION"ILLUSTRATED; authentic
gan of the World's Fair. Most beautiful, interesting and popular publication issued. Sells
at sight. Send 15 c. in stamps for full particulars and sample copy containing COLOEED LITH
OaSAPHIC VIEWS of EXPOSITION BUILDUPS. J. B
Campbell, Pres., 218 LaSalle St., Chicago, 111.
DEALERS
AGENTS
We want one in every town
to handle the
<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
WANTED, a bright boy or girl in every town  to  send
us a pOstal card  asking  for particulars of how,
by a little pleasant work, they can  earn   a bicycle, a
witch   or  choice   library, without  its  costing them another cent.
Bos 46, Boston, Mass.
JOHN F. STRATTON & SOx\,
43 & 45 Walker St.              fi EW YORK.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure.
A cream of tartar baking Powder. Highest of all in leavt-ning strength..Latest
United States Government Food Sieport. ,*:',:
Roval Baking Powder Co., 106 Wall St., N. Y.
DO YOU KEEP BEES~
[f so, send your name mil address for a
Five Sample of the AMERICAN BEE
JOURNAL Weekly32 pa^esOne
Dollar a year.
Thomas G. Newman & Son,
PUBLISHERS
CHICAGO, ILL.
JOHN   F.   STRATTON   &.   SON'S
CELEBRATED
BANJOS,
Importersofand Wholemle Dealers in nil kinds of
MUSICAL     MERCHANDISE,
violins, Guitars. Banjos. Mandolines, Accordeons,
Harmonicas. 4c. all kinds of Strings, etc.,etc.
43 & 45 Walker St.,                     NEW YOKK.
LIBERAL and MUSICAL.
"Shaker Music" is the title of a book
of 250 pages, beautifully printed and neatly bound. It was published by the Believers of Mount Lebanon, N. Y.
We will send the Manifesto during the
year 1892 and a copy of the Music Book,
to any address for $1.25 postage paid. If
desirable the Book and paper may be sent
to different persons.
Address,
The Manifesto,
East Canterbury, N. H.
MUSICALPOrtMER(5HANDISE,
Violins,  Guitars,   Banjos,
Accordeons, Harmonicas, &c.
All kinds of STRINGS, etc., etc.
THE
TESTIMONY
OF
OHfilST'S   SECOND  APPEAEING.
Exemplified by the Principles and Practices of the true CHURCH of CHRIST
A History of the progressive 'work of God,
extending from the Creation of man to
the ' JFAR VEST," comprising the Four
Dispensations noiv consummating in the
MILLENNIAL CHURCH.
Price, $1.50
PLAIH TALKS
ON
PRACTICAL RELIGION,
Being    Candid   Answers   for   Earnest
Inquirers.
By  Geo. A. Lomas.
Price,  10 cts.
BRIEF EXPOSITION
or the
Principles   and   Regulations
of the
SOCIETY   OF   BELIEVERS.
Price, 10 cts.
Address, H. C. Blinn, East Canterbury,   N. H.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>