<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0702" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shakers, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">7</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">2</biblScope><date value="18770201" TEIform="date">February 1877</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">9-16</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="7" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="2" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><pb n="9" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/>
                    <!-- <p TEIform="p">OFFICIAL MONTHLY.—PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES. " 0° preach the ftingdom of God! ff\e
                        testimony of eternul tmth. Yol. YIL G. A. LOMAS, Editoe, Shakers, ST. Y. FEBRUARY, 1877. i N. A.
                        BRIGGS, Publisher, \ Shaker Village, N. H. J No. 2.</p>
--><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Moral law" TEIform="index"/>Moral Law</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescott, James S." TEIform="persName"/>JAMES S. PRESCOTT</byline><p TEIform="p">When the Centennial Exhibition closed, a clerical appeal was made to all men to keep the
                            Sabbath. " To fathers, mothers, pastors, PATRIOTS, MEN OF ALL CLASSES, KEEP the sabbath,"
                            simply because it was the fourth commandment in the moral law. We do not object to all men
                            keeping the Sabbath, the moral law, or any part of it; but why, we would ask, urge the
                            keeping of the fourth commandment and not the second? Did not both proceed from the same God
                            ? And are not all the commandments in the moral law equally binding? " Thou shalt not make
                            thee any graven image or likeness of any thing," etc. This was considered a divine
                            injunction ; but where is the precept kept? Are not graven images found in almost every,
                            so-called, Christian household in our land? What shall we call those larger images,
                            curiously cut and carved out of marble, stone and bronze, found in public squares, parks and
                            museums in all our large cities ? Would not the learned orientals be justified in calling
                            them idols, heathen idoh of America? Christian idols, kept in violation of the second
                            commandment in the Jewish Decalogue? And now, issuing a circular, the " Centennial Voice,"
                            calling upon all men, of all nations, to keep the fourth com mandment. Will not our heathen
                            neighbor: carry home a bad report,especially if they have our Bible circulating read and
                            interpret there no sectarian is the Constitution ? among them, and can its true meaning? I:
                            jod about this ? Where He Avho claimed to be Lord of the Sabbath, and recognized as such,
                            did not lay so much stress on the fourth commandment as some of his modern disciples. He
                            said that " the Sabbath was made for man, and not man foi the Sabbath," that it was made to
                            serve man's interest, and not for man to become a slave to some religious dogma, or creed.
                            He also said, " it was lawful to do good on the Sab bath." If there was any good in the
                            "Centennial exhibition," the Commissioners ough to have opened it every day in the week, and
                            let the world had the benefit of it; and to have left the Sabbath an open question, and
                            optional, with all nations; and not require them to keep a day they had no faith in for "
                            whatsoever is not of faith is sin." The good Lord of the Sabbath seemed to prefer the
                            heretical, but good Samaritan, to the orthodox priest and Levite; because h did the -works,
                            and did not omit the weight ier matters of the law. He who in a cold winter day, goes and
                            carries a load of wood, a basket of potatoes, or a loaf of bread, to a poor suffering widow,
                            to keep herself and little ones from starving and freezing to death, and says nothing about
                            it, does more towards keeping the moral law and the Sabbath in its true spirit, than all
                            burnt offerings and ancient sacrifices. Yea, more than all long prayers, sermonizing, and
                            useless ceremony now so prevalent; although he may never have heard the name of Christ, nor
                            have seen the inside of any church. We believe in keeping sacred one day in even, as a day
                            of rest. It is good for soul ind body, nature's law requires it, while every lay ought to be
                            kept too sacred to commit any sin thereon. North Union, O.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian Culture, no. 1" TEIform="index"/>Christian Culture. Eo. 1</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName"/>WM. H. BUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p">"A Christian is the highest style of man." — Young. If this is so, the evident inference is,
                            that ilone is Christian culture which elevates man :o the highest state of his being; as a
                            necessary consequence, that which falls short of :his in any degree just so far lacks the
                            true used with all indistruth more felt and requisites of Christian culture. The question is
                            not, what sort of training will make the aest statesman, such as the present conditions of
                            society demand, or the best scientist, artist, artisan, or specialist of whatever kind, but
                            what will so develop, enlarge, and refine all the native powers of the human being, as to
                            make him capable not only of comprehending what constitutes the best statesman, scientist,
                            and the like, but also of accomplishing whatever can be effected by either in his best
                            estates, whether that be of a physical, mental or moral character. It requires no great
                            power of insight nor farsight to perceive that this subject has to do not only with the
                            present but much more with the far-extending future. In fact, the very commencement of
                            Christian culture must and does start with the glorious truth of man's immortality. It is
                            conceivable thai human beings could be influenced by motives drawn only from transient
                            considerations to enter upon many courses of conduct that engage their attention; but, in
                            the language of the apostle, " to aspire after glory, honor and immortality," eternal life
                            must be helc out as a motive. It matters not that there are myriads who have development
                            sufficient only to comprehend the simplest truths. They have enough to take in this
                            elementary truth, and hence enough to start upon that course that shal ultimate in the
                            greatest conceivable blessedness. All were but children in understanding at first, and, by
                            the necessities of then condition, accepted as true the seeming instead of the real, not
                            only in external nature but also in the mental and moral states. Yet notwithstanding this
                            apparent obstacle to progress, multitudes have advanced, very slowly, it is true, until the
                            dawn of day has enabled them to see and define with sufficien exactness, the objects
                            presented to their view. Before them they behold a landscape of ineffable beauty and
                            splendor, as well as of infinite variety, and it needs only a patient endurance until the
                            sun shall diffuse its rays over the entire scene, to be completely entranced with the vision
                            of the divine glory. In considering what sort of culture is adapted to any one at the
                            various periods of life, regard must be paid to natural development. That there is a vast
                            difference in this respect in different persons all perceive. mman beings, but particular
                            methods cannot advantageously be criminately. This is a appreciated in the present than in
                            any past ige. Had it been fully appreciated in the &gt;ast, mankind would have been
                            spared many of the physical tortures and mental agonies hat have been endured from ignorance
                            and Digotry, and exalted to places of power and luthority. An essential prerequisite to the
                            highest culture of which man is capable, is freedom of thought and of action. But freedom in
                            a society where all are alike ignorant, is of little value. Hence, in the earliest stages of
                            society, the idea of continuous mental and moral progress did not exist. This is the 3roduct
                            of later ages. No mental and moral ideas were developed, teachers arose, claiming authority
                            as such. These, as a consequence of their partial developments, became arbitrary toward
                            others, mation, they were the In their own estidepositaries of all truths revealed by the
                            gods. But, all along the ages, new ideas were started, not originating in the priestly
                            brain, and not manipulated by priestly hands. Hence arose the conflicts of parties, and
                            these have continued to the present age. This is pre-eminently the age of ideas, but of
                            conflicting ideas. He who teaches from authority alone, whether that of the book or the
                            bishop, has his adherents still, but much diminished in numbers from those of other ages.
                            The greater number require proof of what they are to accept as truth, whether it be called
                            religious or scientific. This is far better, if only the truth is obeyed when known. Freedom
                            implies liberty to reject error, but is valuable only as it is accompanied with the
                            obligation to accept truth whenever and wherever proved to be such. For genuine Christian
                            culture, then, the power of discrimination is required, and the obligation to exercise it is
                            imperative. When this is in free and full exercise, there will be progress, slow, no doubt,
                            but real; and there will be the satisfaction which can be felt onlj by the one whom the
                            truth has made free, at tended by the consciousness that this freedom with all its glorious
                            results is to be perpetual</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Science and superstition" TEIform="index"/>Science and Superstition</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leggett, Ezra T." TEIform="persName"/>EZRA T. LEGGETT</byline><p TEIform="p">What a storm through earth is brewing! Temples totter, churches fall; Faith upbuilding, faith
                            undoing,— Science writing on the wall. Law demands full recognition, Truth is arming on her
                            side; Facts are ranging in position,-Nature 's summoned to decide. Rock-ribbed mountains,
                            storm-tossed oceans Lonely valley, mine and cave; Planet orbits, comet motions, Darkling
                            secrets of the grave. Seers who 've crossed the mighty river, With the love beyond the sky;
                            Sons of God, who 've lived forever,— There are general principles applicable to all' All are
                            called to testify. Startled ghosts of midnight pinion, Hosts from dreamless realms below,
                            Croaking for long-lost dominion, When 'twas death for man to know, dols from their thrones
                            are jumping, Devotees are in dismay; Buddha is with Brahma bumping, While Mahomet stands at
                            bay. ?ogies stare with big-eyed wonder, Orthodoxy quakes in fear; Progress thunders, " Stand
                            from under! " Bigots shriek, " The devil 's here ! " Creeds as old as Time, or older, Tumble
                            now before the storm ; Durgatory 's growing colder, While its friends are growing warm.
                            Darthly saints who, by election, Claim first-class, front seats in Heaven, ^ow would sell
                            that cboice selection Less than cost,—good titles given. Vlan and monkey making faces O'er
                            the Darwin pedigree; Monkey scorning all that traces Man from monkey ancestry'. Woman, too,
                            the storm is riding, Not as witches rode of yore, But with visor up, and guiding Where she
                            followed just before. Woman, stern as thunders rolling, Lightnings flashing from her eye;
                            Man, forlorn as church-bell tolling, Sadly waits the by-and-by. Woman, freed from fear and
                            fetters, Onward, upward, how she flies ! War's domain, and law and letters, Pills and
                            potions, now her prize : Tyrant man, by fear o'ertaken, Seeks for some lone island, where,
                            By all womankind forsaken, He may soothe his sorrw there.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes by the way, no. 6" TEIform="index"/>Notes by the Way. No. 6</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>HENRY C. BLINN</byline><p TEIform="p">Nothing doubting, we see still. On for the kingdom ! Not through the labyrinth which has been
                            so mystically laid out by the so-called spiritual engineers ; not through the fierce
                            tempests, nor even through the flood ; for these forms whereby to obtain Christian grace are
                            far more poetical than practical ; conditions which we are led to believe but a small
                            percentage of those who enter the strait and narrow way are ever likely to experience. There
                            are pilgrims, no doubt, who evidently enjoy all the excitement and perils and narrow escapes
                            which these multiplied states may suggest, and perhaps would not be satisfied to reach the
                            kingdom of God in any other way. They love the idea of being termed martyrs of the cross,
                            and would rather walk in thorns, even if it did no especial good, than to bear the
                            discipline of <pb n="10" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 10 THE SHAKER. the yoke, which is easy, and the burden,
                            which is light. Sloughs of despond and giants of despair may possibly awaken an inspiration
                            in some minds, and prove congenial, even, to their spiritual states. By such they may be
                            considered preferable to the more methodical and unostentatious way to which Jesus made
                            reference, "If any man will come after me, let him deny himself and take up his cross and
                            follow me." It can, by no means, be thought strange at the present day for one to ask, "What
                            shall I do to be saved?" for the lo here, and lo there, are heard on every hand. The
                            would-be infallible guides are ever ready to direct the pilgrim through this fine-spun
                            dogma, or through that traditional creed, with God, which are with us to-day, they may carry
                            us beautifully through the divine influence of faith, without which we may fail to please
                            God. Under this ministration of the spirit, the yoke becomes easy and the burden light.
                            Those formidable barriers, which arose as giants or as lions, have, as phantoms, all passed
                            away. The City of our God, the anticipated home of the pure in heart, is still before us,
                            and there yet remains the necessity for a direct and close examination into the discipline
                            that first turns our steps toward the ways of pleasantness and the paths of peace. No amount
                            of faith, nor studied form of prayer, can ever take the place of clean hands and a pure
                            heart, or even the manifestations of the common acts of civility. It would be as futile to
                            attempt to establish a good moral character, the stepping-stone to a spiritual life, upon a
                            basis of u cleanness, as it would for the foolish man to build his house upon the sand.
                            There can be no law of association by which we can harmonize neatness with slatternly
                            habits. They are the very antipodes of each other, and an unwashed Christian would be a
                            reproach to the profession. Our pathway is now by the way of the cross, and in the spirit
                            which this teaches we are bound for the kingdom. He that enters this heavenly highway, and
                            seeks to save his (worldly) life, will as certainly lose his (heavenly or spiritual) life.
                            In it the fashion of this world passes away, and a swift testimony against the lusts of the
                            flesh and of the mind becomes the baptism of the holy spirit. No mystery obscures this
                            pathway. The wayfaring man, of high or low degree, needs not err therein, but all may come
                            to a knowledge of the truth, and be saved.</p></div2><div2 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A Christian pound weight is sixteen ounces..." TEIform="index"/>A Christian pound weight is sixteen ounces...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A Christian pound weight is sixteen ounces, down weight. A Christian yard is thirty-six
                            inches, cloth not stretched. A Christian ton is two thousand pounds, not "estimated," but
                            weighed.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Elder Evans before a peace society" TEIform="index"/>Elder Evans before a Peace Society</head><p TEIform="p">[We clip the following good morsel from the local columns of a cotemporary. We are sorry we
                            could not obtain the whole address. Elder F. W. E. is constantly doing such things as
                            this.—Ed.] The elder wrent on to show the utility and great necessity of such organizations,
                            to preserve the republican institutions of our land, as these were not founded by any sect.
                            The government, he wished it to be understood, is not a Christian government, and can never
                            be. The framers of our constitution and their ancestors had been so perse:uted by the
                            so-called followers of Christ, that they refused to allow the name of God in the
                            constitution ; and :ven Washington, in forming his treaty of Tripoli, distinctly stated that
                            this is no more a Christian government than it is a Mohammedan. To the liberals of that day
                            we owe more of our present civilization, to such men as Franklin, [while a lawless style of
                            action makes ours simply a chance life. The need He then drew a complete history of the
                            early church. The primitive followers of Christ were peace men, and refused to fight under
                            any conditions up to the time of Constantine the Great, who became converted to
                            Christianity, and at once established a new order. Then was formed under him a unity ot
                            Christianity and Paganism ; wrar being introduced as one of the elements of the system of
                            church and state Christianity. Out of war grows the monopoly of all the elements of human
                            existence, beginning with the land. Under primitive Christianity the land and the products
                            were common to all people ; no man saying of aught he had that it was his own. Under church
                            and state Christianity, the monopoly of the land has been the stimulus to all wars. The
                            first form of slavery is the prisoners of war. Poverty is one of the forms of human slavery.
                            The American government was founded by rationalists, sceptics, infidels to the Constantine
                            system of church and state theology. All those sects of religionists, whether protestants,
                            catholics or Greeks, who hold to war as a means of monopolizing the elements of human
                            existence, should worship Constantine, the head of their system, and not Jesus, the founder
                            of present Christianity. Let us have peace by maintaining the American constitution, which
                            makes a union of church and state an impossibility. Ours is a rights. The atheist, the
                            deist, the pagan Chinee, Hindoo or Mohammedan have all equal rights with Christians— falsely
                            so-called—under our grand republic. Closing the Centennial on the Sabbath day of these
                            fighting Christians, which was first established by Constantine, not Jesus, was a war
                            measure, and a first step toward the subversion of our constitution, aud a union of church
                            and state.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our petition" TEIform="index"/>Our Petition</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>MARY WHITCHER</byline><p TEIform="p">Give us the ballast of a humble mind, That we may not so easily forget The many frailties of
                            the human kind, With which our barque is tossed, like barques beset. And as we stand below
                            our destined place, Let humble thought of what we ought to be Inspire our hearts to reach
                            for perfect grace; But, until there, our weakness may we see. How well it hath been said of
                            Charity, (Though all the other graces are our own,) If wanting this, we lack the purity Of
                            Christian life and love, in this, our home. Then let us strive to gain "the golden mean," "
                            To be to others ever kind and true; " Again, " to see ourselves as we are seen," Would
                            doubtless give us charity anew. Shaker Village, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Domestic economy" TEIform="index"/>Domestic Economy</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Neal, Sarah A." TEIform="persName"/>SARAH A. NEAL</byline><p TEIform="p">Nothing is more essential to the general prosperity and thrifty growth of a family or society
                            of families than economy in all things. And it is quite astonishing sometimes to see how
                            much do towards making life home convenient andeconomy will comfortable,happy, where the
                            hand of plenty has not furnished an abundance. But to be economical is to be systematical.
                            It is quite impossible to practice economy, Paine, Jefferson, and others. ul requisites to
                            promote economy are order and good calculation ; but where order is the rule, it becomes an
                            easy natter to arrange labor so as to save not only material, but time and strength also.
                            Many labor-saying inventions lave been put into operation, but few •naterial-saving
                            inventions have as yet greeted us; this still remains the labor of the economical
                            calculator, and certain it is, the individual whose motto is "keep order," whose duties are
                            governed by a system, yet unaided by any mechanical invention, will save more material,
                            'have equally as much time and strength, keep better health, and express a better
                            disposition, than one who has many mechanical inventions, but no order nor system ; who
                            meets all labor as it may chance to come, and disposes of the same as quickly and carelessly
                            as possible. Such disarrangement causes the conflicting elements between time and labor,
                            that so seriously annoy people. Our sympathies are really agitated sometimes when we hear
                            complainings of the much there is to do, and the little time there is to do it in, when a
                            proper arrangement of duties, writh a little economy of time, would do away with much
                            complaining, and give us ample time in which to perform our necessary labors, and allow us a
                            surplus for rest or recuperative exercise. Some people think by crowding two days' work into
                            one, that they save time ; but this cannot be done without sustaining a loss of something
                            equally as valuable ; for the physiological system must necessarily be overtaxed to
                            accomplish this purpose, and loss oi strength and vitality perhaps, the day following, with
                            much of the cheerfulness that surrounds living economically, are the consequences. So,
                            little, if anything, is saved other than a fretful disposition ; and right here the old
                            adage comes in to declare the truth, that " haste makes waste." Not so in creation. No
                            conflicting elements are seen to be the outgrowth of divine calculations. All nature
                            vibrates to one harmonious strain of preserving economy. So should our live; be governed by
                            order, and disciplinec in economy, as to become attuned to the melodious chord that
                            permeates the divine kingdom. Let us ever remember that economy in all things, at all times,
                            in all ways and in all places, is the sure index that will direct us in the road to
                            prosperity and plenty. Shakers, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Father Job Bishop's opinions of shaker elders" TEIform="index"/>Father Job Bishop's Opinions
                            of Shaker Elders</head><p TEIform="p">It has been asserted by our enemies, and maintained with great confidence, that the Elders
                            are very tyrannical in their government; that the members are held in bondage, and live in a
                            state of abject slavery, both of body and of mind. These charges, it would seem, might be
                            known to be false at first view, as such conduct would inevitably subvert and destroy those
                            principles of peace and harmony which are among the fundamental doctrines of the society. It
                            is certain the society could not possibly maintain its existence if any such conduct should
                            be allowed in it. If any elder or leader should usurp any authority over his brethren or
                            sisters, beyond what the spirit of Christ permits, and the testimony of the gospel teaches,
                            he would thereby dishonor his calling and forfeit his place. And if the conduct of an elder
                            or leader of any family or order, should be found subversive of peace and harmony in any
                            manner whatever, he would inevitably be removed and his place supplied by another. Because
                            no one is considered as fit to teach or lead in a society or institution, where the spirit
                            of peace and harmony is a most essential requirement, unless his principles and practice are
                            strictly conformable thereto. Not even a single family in the society could be kept together
                            without a spirit of mutual union and harmony. How then, could a whole society, constituted
                            as ours is, and built up with the united talents and interests of the whole, be supported
                            and maintained without union and harmony ? It is a truth, that if an individual member
                            should renounce the principles of peace and harmony, or any other known and established
                            principles of this society, he must of course renounce the society which is founded on these
                            principles. Strife and contention, tyranny and oppressive bondage and slavery, lewdness and
                            intemperance, dishonesty and fraud, hypocrisy and deceit, are all in direct opposition to
                            the fundamental principles of the society. And no person, let his lot or calling in the
                            society be what it may, can long continue his union and con nection therewith, while he
                            continues in the practice of any of these things. It must readily be acknowledged that no
                            institution to prevent any of the above mentioned crimes could be successfully established,
                            and prosper under the protection of persons who were themselves guilty of those very crimes.
                            Much less could an institution or society to prevent such crimes, prosper for this bland
                            assurance, the reward of eternal life. If we study the scriptures, or the revelations of <pb n="11" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. 11 many years under the care and government of leaders, who
                            are themselves guilty of living in the abominations which it was the object of the
                            institution to prevent. It would be impossible for them either to conceal their own, or to
                            preserve the morals of the society for any length of time. We are told that there have been
                            instances in which some who have been elders or leaders have deserted, and therefore there
                            can be no certainty that all will not finally do so, and the whole society fail, and come to
                            an end. But it ought to be remembered, that the fall of Judas did not overthrow the
                            foundation of the Church, which Jesus planted in that day. Judas was one of the twelve
                            apostles, chosen by Jesus himself, and it is well known, what was the cause of his fall, and
                            that similar causes will produce similar effects in this day. Those who reject the spirit of
                            righteousness, which is the support and protection of the soul, and the foundation of the
                            Church, are exposed to the temptations of the spirit of wickedness, and are liable to fall
                            under the power of evil. But the fall of any one or more, from any lot or station is no
                            discouragement to a faithful soul, because it is well known that those who fall do so
                            through unfaithfulness. And the same may possess the faith of the gospel without possessing
                            its real substance and may hang on for a long time, like dry branches on a green tree, yet
                            none but the truly faithful will endure to the end. Those who are entrusted with the
                            greatest care, whether in things spiritual or temporal, are under the greatest
                            responsibility to be faithful in the discharge of their duty. And the elders and leaders of
                            whatever order, are required to be examples of faithfulness in all things, to all who are
                            under their care. And no one is considered as capable of standing in the place of an elder
                            or leader, unless he is able to teach and lead by example, as well as by precept. Hence
                            uprightness of conduct in all things, is essentially necessary in a leader. The virtues of
                            honesty and sincerity, patience and humiliation, meekness and charity, are essential
                            qualifications in an elder or leader of this society. And those who do not ¦possess these
                            virtues themselves, are not considered as qualified to teach them to othets. Hence true
                            godliness is invariably preferred before great talents ; for the most effectual teacher, is
                            he who teaches by example as realty as by precept. A faithful elder is a faithful servant to
                            those over whom he is placed ; and such a one will not fail to gain the love and respect of
                            every faithful soul under his care. The greatest elders are not only the greatest servants,
                            but are the most highly esteemed by the faithful, '•'•for their work's sake."" I have had a
                            fair opportunity to observe the pi'ogress of the society from its first establishment; and I
                            have seen with great satisfaction, that the principles which were first taught by Mother Ann
                            Lee, have been faithfully maintained from the beginning. And though 1 have seen many fall,
                            and turn again to the beggarly elements, and pursue those very practices which the tongue of
                            slander has charged against these people, yet the society has never been robbed of a single
                            virtue thereby. Those who have kept their rectitude, and improved their talents have stood
                            'aithful, and found an increase in every virtue. But the slothful and unfaithful, lave
                            buried their talents in the earth, and gained nothing. They have lost their day, by turning
                            to pursue the vain pleasures of this world. But the truth prevails, and the foundation of
                            the Jhurch remains unshaken—the revelation of God on which it is built is sure and
                            steadfast, and never can fail. [We find in The Millennial Church, some beautiful allusions
                            to the above Job Bishop ; of his affectionate interviews and affecting farewells with Mother
                            Ann Lee. He wiis, soon after her decease, appointed to the care of the eastern Shaker
                            churches ; was esteemed almost akin to worship by their memDers, as the best of Fathers, and
                            is now referred to by the hundreds there who never saw him, with a reverence which, to our
                            mind, has been bestowed by them on only one man besides.—Ed.]</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bishop, Job" TEIform="persName"/>Job Bishop</byline></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Darwinism" TEIform="index"/>Darwinism</head><p TEIform="p">As to the gradual changes which man is undergoing, they are quite obvious to courageous and
                            clear-sighted philosophers, and plainly indicate what is to be the next stage in his
                            development. It has lately been remai'ked that the superiority of American dentists to all
                            other members of the profession is shown by the extraordinary display of dental instruments
                            at the Philadelphia Exhibition. If we ask what is the cause of this superiority—which, by
                            the way, is generally conceded to be beyond cavil—the obvious answer is that the American
                            dentist fills more cubic feet of cavities and draws more tons of teeth in the course of a
                            month than the English or Continental dentist fills and draws in a year. This fact, in turn,
                            implies that American teeth are exceptionally prone to decay ; and there is a wealth of
                            direct evidence of a conclusive character in support of this assertion. At this point the
                            superficial thinker pauses, and imagines that he has exhausted the subject of dentistry in
                            America. It is just here, however, that the profound Darwinian philosopher finds the clue to
                            the next great physical change which is to distinguish the man of the future from the man oi
                            the present. He sees that in America we are rapidly developing a race o\ men without teeth
                            and that precisely as men have laid aside their useless primeval tails, so they are about to
                            drop their nearly useless teeth. The man of the future is, then, to be a toothless animal.
                            This much can science deduce from the apparently irrelevant fact tha the American display of
                            dental instruments at Philadelphia is wonderfully and exceptionably fine.—Exchange.
                            ~—.-----------*---------------O, for the plain, unsized, unvarnished, unpatented,
                            uncertified, uncopyrighted truth.—Exchange.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Village, New Hampshire, December 12, 1876" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Village, Merr.
                                Co., \ N. H., December 12, 1876</head><p TEIform="p">Our Brother Geo. A. Lomas : Having just received a copy of the Decemoer number of The
                                Shaker, I propose to tell you my thoughts, with pen in hand, concerning the articles
                                inserted, and hope you will not object. * First: "Self Rule," which occupies a prominent
                                place on the first page, seems very necessary to be observed. On reading it carefully, I
                                am almost persuaded that I can improve thereby. ' Would You t " is another which I have
                                read, and think it a good commencement of an "unvarnished tale." Should recommend it in
                                an especial manner to novel readers, as an antidote for all active mental poisons;
                                trusting that it might prove highly alterative in its effects on that class, if no
                                other. Or, it may be considered as a sort of friction match, which, if but lightly drawn
                                across tlie hard-pan of selfishness, may casually illuminate the dark abyss, and do much
                                good eventually. I now turn to the " Flying Visit," and disover there that the writer
                                strove hard to imitate the bee, and "gather honey all the day, from every opening
                                flower; " although I perceive that when reporting Canterbury, he shows a little
                                aberration of mind in his remarks upon that locality, and its belongings. And, besides,
                                (to our astonishment!) he picked up a big rat, (that we thought was buried,) carried it
                                away in his memory, and put it into The Shaker ! O, Albert, this was too bad I So all of
                                the sisterhood say; and how you obtained even a side-glance at our infant Manual, is
                                still a mystery to us. The poor little waif had not been in existence long enough to
                                face the sunlight of publicity, nor the scrutiny of an editor. When we read it to the
                                sisters, they exclaimed, almost in a breath, "Where did he come across those penciled
                                manuscripts? They were never intended for the public eye." When my eye lighted upon it,
                                and I realized how suddenly the Manual was unearthed, I thought of a little boy whom I
                                once knew. who would plant a bean one day and dig it up the next to see if it had
                                sprouted. Now, our Manual had hardly sprouted before it was transplanted—or the weakest
                                portion of it— into the broad field of the world ! But as you overlooked a
                                correspondence written for its columns, I propose to forward the same, asking you to
                                insert it early enough to redeem the honor of the sisterhood, and cancel the rat.* But
                                did you know that your rat made a big blot on the last page of The Shaker, and that you
                                have given the whole world, as it were, a key to the moral and mental calibre of your
                                Canterbury sisters? that is, if they are to judge the Manual by the items noticed, the
                                most prominent of which is the obituary— which fact can never help to redeem a sinning
                                world. We all say that you must repent before Christmas, if you ever hope to be
                                forgiven; and "Would You" be taken into our confidence again, you must promise, and keep
                                all good promises intact. Accept, with this, a renewal of the gospel testimony, which
                                you may publish, in our names, from Niskayuna to Japan. [We sincerely promise.—Ed.} *
                                This correspondence was published in January number, as this letter was intended to be,
                                bvit space did not permit. " Do you suppose there is a man in Brooklyn who would have a
                                photograph of his heart taken ? "—Moody. Love from the sisterhood. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="S., A. C." TEIform="persName"/>A. C. S.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ayer, Massachusetts, November 22, 1876" TEIform="index"/>Ayer, Mass., Nov. 22, 1876</head><p TEIform="p">Beloved sisters A. and E. : I have concluded to write a few lines to you collectively.
                                The kind communication to me of the 12th inst. is received. As ii may be doubtful about
                                my ever attempting to write to you again, I shall try to cancel the obligations on my
                                part as well as I can. ?rom both of you I have received bjAvriting, many kind
                                communications, also one from J. For all words of remembrance to me, or in nehalf of the
                                gospel cause from those who are older than you I tender my thanks, as I do in an
                                especial manner to my three correspondents. Of the future we can know but very little in
                                regard to ourselves and still less can we know of the order in which believers are
                                engaged. Whatever that may be :hose now on the stage of action will evidently find their
                                hands and hearts rilled with labor, and this accompanied with sufferings and
                                tribulation. We hope that all they may have to pass through will serve to prepare them
                                for the jfinal enjoyment of their long and better home. I like very much the spirit of
                                love and blessing which is breathed through our little paper, The Shaker. It is what all
                                believers should labor to possess and be able to administer as a true test of their
                                goodness. Those engaged in this work find much to do to conquer that spirit Avhich is
                                opposed to their best good. Plow beautiful, and how noble and honorable it is in any
                                one, who will take an elevated stand above the influences of a depraved nature, and
                                there steadfastly remain. How much a person is to be respected and admired, who through
                                the hurry and bustle of the affairs of this life, possesses a calm, :oving and quiet
                                spirit, and strives to make all happy and joyful. In this progressive work we must keep
                                in possession the best of all gifts, which is charity for each other. This is the fruit
                                of the spiritual element, which we should seek first, and the temporal will naturally
                                bear us company. Hold, my young friends, to that which is innocent and useful. It may
                                serve to keep your minds from that which would lead you into the broad way. Please
                                remember me according to promise, as far as is consistent. May much blessing and
                                strength be yours through the journey of life. Accept love from all the Elders, brethren
                                and sisters. Your brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hammond, Thomas" TEIform="persName"/>Thomas Hammond</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watervliet, New York, January 11, 1876" TEIform="index"/>Watervliet, N. Y., Jan. 11, 1876</head><p TEIform="p">Beloved Editor Albert : In perusing the December number of your val uable missionary
                                paper, The Shaker, I found a beautiful description of your " Flying Visit" through some
                                of the eastern Shaker churches; it afforded me great joy and comfort. I was so delighted
                                with the encouraging account of the prosperity and flourishing condition of the eastern
                                branches of our Zion, that it did my soul great and lasting good; and I mean to read and
                                re-read it every opportunity for the same pleasure and profit. In relation to The
                                Shaker, I think it is the greatest "Missionary" that erer has been sent out from our
                                Zion ; also, I think it has been very ably conducted thus far since its commencement,
                                and with a blessed increase. I for one most heartily wish and desire its prosperity and
                                success in future. It deserves our best wishes.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Buckingham, J. C." TEIform="persName"/>J. C. Buckingham</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Brave words from a state official" TEIform="index"/>Brave Words from a State Official</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Editor: It was with extreme pleasure that I read in a late number of The Shaker, an
                                article from the pen of Elizabeth H. Webster, setting forth the true elements of
                                Christianity in "The Fruitfulness of the Divine Life." I testify her words to be
                                correct; it is fruits of Christianity that we want—a love that worketh no evil to a
                                neighbor. However many graces Ave may have, without the possession of Christian love all
                                will be of no avail. But how little do we find of it among even the representatives of
                                religion in our city—ministers, who preach and pray eloquently, but of whose effects I
                                am led to exclaim, "Who will show us any good? " My soul is starving for something pure
                                and good, that is not tinctured with egotism, or with a <pb n="12" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 12 THE
                                SHAKER,. love of popularity. The churches in this city are, as a general thing, places
                                of fashionable resort; from which every lover of truth and of sound theology turns away.
                                * * * I have lived to see three-score years, and I can of a truth say, I never have
                                found true peace and joy in any nor all sensual practices. * * * I wish I could set
                                forth to you the beauty I found in that article of Sister Elizabeth's. It is full of
                                truth and encouragement to those who are seeking for a higher life and a happiness above
                                this world's possessions. * * I have been acquainted with the Shakers for many years,
                                and have spent the happiest hours of my life in their company. I was very much blest in
                                your article on " Would you be a Shaker?" It was so much to the point, explaining in a
                                plain and logical manner the true merits of Shaker life, and the good reasons for
                                embracing the same. * * I have been for thirty years a State officer in Massachusetts,
                                and am happy to subscribe myself as a reader of your invaluable paper—The Shaker. Go on,
                                dear brother.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="S., D." TEIform="persName"/>D. S. Boston, Jan. 12, 1877</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kind words" TEIform="index"/>Kind Words</head><p TEIform="p">Lebanon, O., Jan. 2, 1887. My dear Bro. Geo. Albert: * * The high appreciation you have
                                won from the readers of The Shaker in the West should afford you every encouragenaent to
                                continue your onward and upward course rejoicingly. * *</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="L., E. T." TEIform="persName"/>E. T. L.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Resignation" TEIform="index"/>Resignation</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Patrick, Marian" TEIform="persName"/>MARIAN PATRICK</byline><p TEIform="p">I would be meek of heart, of humble mind, Not anxious, but to all things here resigned; Seek
                            the straight path, and follow heaven's Lord, Measure my motives by his sacred word. Be pure
                            in spirit, and of low estate, Those truly serve who only stand and wait. With charity, I'll
                            spy my neighbor's sin, And when I judge, I'll turn an eye within. Indwelling pride shall not
                            God's temple taint, Inspired with strength, not in the right to faint, Nor murmur at my lot,
                            whate'er befall, I'll summon patience, and so bear it all. I would not be discouraged when
                            sorely tried, By tribulations here I must be purified. Only a little season can they last,—
                            I'll think of glory when these scenes are past.</p></div2><div2 type="history" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Punctuation points" TEIform="index"/>Punctuation Points</head><p TEIform="p">Do you know the origin of the various punctuation points used by printers and writers? Greek
                            literature was not punctuated until B. C. 365, and there was no space between the words. The
                            Romans at a later day put a kind of division between their words, thus— Publius. Scipio.
                            Africanus. For some time after the invention of the art of printing, arbitrary marks were
                            used to divide sentences. Up to the end of the fifteenth century, only the period, colon,
                            and comma had been introduced. The latter came into use latest, and was only a perpendicular
                            line, proportionate to the length of the preceding letter. The colon is first found in the
                            "Acts of English Worthies," published in 1550, and ^the semi-colon in " Hackluyt's Voyages,"
                            which appeared in 1599. The parenthesis was introduced during the sixteenth century. The
                            marks of interrogation and exclamation were introduced many years after. To Aldus Manvitus,
                            an eminent printer of the seventeenth century, we are indebted for the present form of the
                            comma. He also laid down rules for its use. Inverted commas (") were first used by Mons.
                            Allemont, a French printer, and were intended by him to supersede he use of italic letters,
                            and it is said he French printers now call them by hat name. It is not known by whom he dash
                            and apostrophe were invented. — Gospel Banner.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="P., A. A." TEIform="persName"/>A. A. p.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>BOOK TABLE</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Book of worship" TEIform="index"/></head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Swinney, E. H." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Annual register of rural affairs" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Plain talks upon practical religion" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">The Book of Worship : E. H. S-aintey, 20 Cooper Union, New York. Is a Inelv printed book
                                of hymns and anthems ised by The New Church (Swedenborgian) n their worship. It is very
                                worshipful in sentiment, and wonderfully free from idola:rous sentiments relating to
                                Jesus or any other human being. We observe that many popular hymns have been ingeniously
                                invaded and improved theologically. The impress of music is scarcely anywhere equaled.
                                It is certainly a good, great work. The Annual Register of Rural Affairs : Luther II.
                                Tucker &amp; Son, Albany, N. Y., publishers of The Country Gentleman. This little
                                work is a multutn in fiarvo upon nearly everything connected with the farm and garden.
                                Its most prominent and valuajle feature for 1877 is an elaborate article upon
                                "Ventilation." This article is alone worth many times the price of the book, which is
                                only thirty cents. Plain Talks upon Practical Religion : This little work is intended to
                                answer the lundreds of questions naturally arising about The Shakers ; and thereby not
                                only give n epitome their general theology, but details of Shaker life. Modesty forbids
                                that we praise it. We refer readers to Elder H.'L. lades' opinion of it in January
                                number of The Shaker. To be issued in February; :&gt;rice by mail, six cents.
                                Address this office, or N. A. Briggs, Shaker Village, N. H.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>SOCIETY RECORD</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. Church Family celebrated New Year's day by eating dinner in the new
                                Mansion. Scarcity of water in this village. Prudence has been proclaimed. The North
                                Family recently brought their new water-works into action, to smother a fire, which, had
                                it reached the exterior of the building, there is no accounting the damage that would
                                have ensued. The Colosseum singing-schools in this village continue with unabated
                                success. Ministry approaching xcellent health.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Chapin, Eliza" TEIform="index"/>Eliza Chapin
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Hancock, Mass. Reports death of <persName reg="Chapin, Eliza" TEIform="persName">Eliza Chapin</persName>, on
                                Dec. 16, aged 54. Shaker Village, N. H., has been considerably "under the weather;" but
                                report says, " thorough nursing and thoroughwori have brought all round again
                            nicely."</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="McBride, William" TEIform="index"/>Wm. McBride
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Whitewater, O., reports two deaths Dec. 12, <persName reg="McBride, Wm." TEIform="persName">Wm.
                                McBride</persName>, aged 43,</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Burnham, Polly" TEIform="index"/>Polly Burnham
                            </head><p TEIform="p">and, Dec 20, <persName reg="Burnham, Polly" TEIform="persName">Polly Burnham</persName>, aged 82 years.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="shaker-press" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We are under especial obligations..." TEIform="index"/>We are under especial obligations...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">We are under especial obligations for brilliant personal allusions to The Shaker by the
                            Banner of Light, Hull's Crucible, Boston, Mass. ; Religio-Phil. Journal, which comes to us
                            newly and beautifully clad from Chicago, 111.; and to the Albany Express Evening Times,
                            Post, and Sunday Press, al of Albany, N. Y. ; to The People, a grand enterprising sheet,
                            published at Concord, N H., and to the Journal of Progress, of Mo bile, Ala. From our
                            position in life, we know of no better advice to give those wha are sixty years of age, and
                            younger than to spend the remainder of their days in doing all the good to others they are
                            able, and through these means since the Shaker Church was estab get an assurance that
                            selfishness has b dwindled to the shortest span." g.a.l.</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE SHAKER. BSontkly—60 cents per aiiaum. \ DUAL ADVOCATE OF CHRIST PRINCIPLES.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Communist failures and their cause" TEIform="index"/>Communistic Failures and their Cause</head><p TEIform="p">We are numbered among those who sorrow that so many attempts at successful communism have
                            failed. It ruly is a sad commentary upon the conditions of human nature, to observe iow many
                            efforts to found communiies, phalanxes, families, homes, etc., lave been made, the majority
                            of which lave come to a sorrowful, untimely end; and the facts of failure are the nore
                            painful when we think how no}le, unselfish, truly philanthropic have :&gt;een the
                            motives of their various founders ; how bright their mornings ; how effulgent with success
                            their meridians ; tow beautiful many of their locations and surroundings ; how bountiful
                            their physical means; how brilliant their financial prospects—nothing, apparenty, wanting to
                            make an earthly paradise—and yet, how many have failed, and why? We answer, for the want of
                            more, very much more, practical self-denial, to passional human selfishness. What an array
                            of talent have many of these ventures embraced ! what a galaxy of influential minds has been
                            prominent in their inaugurations! what a generous public in their rear, ready, through its
                            hope for humanity, to loan or give its thousands, aye, millions if need required, to aid the
                            approach of a millennium. Such thoughts urge us to speak out plainly, why the failures, why
                            the squandering of immense appropriations, under banners which pi-omised such brilliant,
                            unending successes. It is a fact that communism, or any successful attempt thereat, demands
                            the predominance of the religious element —the "one mind" of all its constituents. Where
                            this has been ignored, speedy failure has inevitably followed, or plain evidences have been
                            presented of that which must be short-lived ; and that which has often gone forth as " an
                            irresistible force," has, ere long, met with " an immovable object." The captivating,
                            scholarly writer of '¦'•American Socialisms" has chosen to speak of the Shaker Church thus :
                            " It is no more than bare justice to say that we are indebted to the Shakers, more than to
                            any or all other social architects of modern times. Their success has been the 'specie
                            basis' that has upheld all the paper theories, and counteracted the failures of the French
                            and English schools. * * * But to do complete justice we must go a step further. While we
                            say that the Rappites, Zoarites, Ebenezers, Owenites, and even the Fourierists, are all
                            echoes of the Shakers, we must also say that the Shakers are but the Jar-ojf echoes of The
                            Primitive Christian Church." Admitting these premises to be cor rect, there can be no doubt
                            that each attempt at any new, social, religious communistic organizations, attemptec since
                            the Shaker Church was estab lished, have had in mind an improve ment, or a desired
                            improvement, of it 3asic principles; retaining and mainlining all of its good, while
                            relieving; he members of the new order of selflenials, hoped and considered to be
                            non-essentials for the security of complete success. And the fact remains patent that mere
                            communities do and may exist without the exercise of so* nuch cross—so great a degree of
                            selfdenial as practiced by the ShakerChurch—it having more than mere community principles at
                            stake. But if he perfection of religious life is aimed at, leaving the principles of the
                            five oaves and two fishes out of the quesion, in no case can individuals be so protected,
                            satisfied and justified before God—come so near the model of all Christian churches, the
                            Primitive Chvisian Church, with any less self-denial han is required of Shaker commuaicants.
                            If we scan, closely, existing coranunes, which have withstood the lapse and trials of a
                            quarter century, we will igree that, excepting none, there has :&gt;een more self-denial
                            in practice theren, than the general world has given credit for; and we vouch for the
                            statenent that the more abnegations to selfsh desires practiced, the dearer, more spiritual
                            their religious lives, and more certain their endurance as a community or Christ family. It
                            is a well-known act that the Primitive Christian Church 'fell away"—failed—and why? We will
                            see. But its character and principles still loom up to guide the thorough Christian in all
                            future attempts. If we Merely are seeking the millennial attriDUtes of a bread-and-butter
                            commune, we are striking too deeply in aiming to&gt; oe the reflex of that
                            ever-brilliant house: of Pentecost. It aimed its blows more directly at human selfishness,
                            than all the Mosaic statutes combined ; acknowledging, however, that a thoroughly good Jew
                            was the best candidate for Christianity—was " not far from the kingdom of heaven !" In the
                            glory of the day when Pentecost ruled, " they were together, and had all things in common ;
                            no man had aught he called his own, but gave to every one as he had need." They left the
                            earthly, selfish conditions of fathers, mothers, husbands, wives, children, houses and
                            lands; and giving their own lives to an accordance of Jesus* life, where did self-denials
                            act most prominently ? They operated most keenly where all the communities, or attempts
                            thereat, which have failed, have been unwilling to have them affect them personally ; and as
                            the same causes produce the same effects alway, only as fully as we practice the
                            self-denials of that church in its glory can we live in that glory. We refrain here from
                            giving the details of that very self-denying organization, as it would sound very much like
                            the principles of the Shaker Church ; but we state with a confidence which can brook no
                            denial, that nothing but the want of a continued, progressive self-denial ever caused the "
                            falling away" of that early, model church ! <pb n="13" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. 13 Look, now,
                            at the multitudinous churches, each claiming the Pentecostal Church as its model, when not
                            one in one thousand but has reversed its provisions, and are encouraging a selfishness
                            to-day which that early church was organized to abolish ! Model, indeed ! Instead of
                            presenting its superior relations of spiritual brotherhood to those of husband and wives ;
                            instead of its exchanges for private, personal houses and lands ; instead of its fathers,
                            mothers and children ; the vast majority of these churches are manufacturers of the grosser
                            elements and institutions, which Christ came to resurrect men and women from ! And now,
                            another attempt at commune organization is to be made in Virginia, upon a religious basis,
                            having at its head experienced communists,— those who have known the results of success and
                            failure, and the causes of each. Hear them, now, after nearly forty years' trial: " Some of
                            our correspondents are very much afraid that their liberties will be curtailed in the
                            colony, and that somebody will want to dominate or criticise them too much. We think that
                            the kind of people most likely to succeed in association will be those who are eager to show
                            their humility— anxious to show their readiness to submit to lawful authority—i?tdeed, those
                            who zvill say, ' Search me and, try my heart', and see if there be any any evil in we.' " "A
                            large number of people seem possessed of an intense desire at present to enjoy the
                            privileges of the unitary home. There is no royal road into this paradise. The entrance is
                            through the straight and narrow wax called 'self-denial.' " Here we have the truth ; and "
                            but few will find" this paradise, because o their unwillingness to practice the nee essary
                            self-denials. Anon we look into the place of heaven in the future ; anc "but few have found
                            it," from the same cause. The multitudes roam about in spirit-land, as the multitudes do
                            here wishing, hoping, and determined to ge into heaven, without so much cross— so many
                            self-denials! As ever the failure has been, so, in time and in the eternal world, will the
                            failure proceec from the same cause—the refusal to practice genuine, Christian self-denials.
                            We have loved to linger, not only with hope, but with positive, irrefutable evidences and
                            knowledge, that the Shaker Church shall never know decay. Wre are confident of the same,
                            with all confidence still. Yet it may be swept from the earth, "and numbered among the
                            things that were ; " but this can on ly be when its constituents relinquish and abandon its
                            self-denying injunc tions.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker covenant" TEIform="index"/>The Shaker Covenant</head><p TEIform="p">sickness, and as good to its spirit, as careful nursing in care in health, as any other
                            individual in society. To these ends the Covenant binds itself to its subscribers. It
                            accepts the physical care of all who are permitted to bring themselves under obligation to
                            it, so long as they keep such obligation intact—accepting them physically, 'for better or
                            for worse." It is a spiritual Protection. It contains the constituents of the Comforter. It
                            is the Conservatory of the most sacred vows ever consecrated unto God or a godly life. It is
                            an unequaled, disciplinary Monitor—the ne plus ultra for selfish, sinful humanity, who,
                            desirous of "that better way," are struggling for that realm, where divine humanity is alone
                            active. True, we yield our private, personal rights to it; and it, in return, gives us the
                            hundred-fold of privileges, superior to any personal claims we can make. It provides us with
                            Ministers or Bishops : As premiers in government, their decisions are final, and we yield
                            thereto; realizing, at the same time, that these same decisions, as wel as their counsels
                            and instructions, are guided by the same Covenant. None are permitted to rule " as with a
                            rod o iron ;" nor by it required to act the servile or debased slave, wherever pow er is
                            acknowledged. No distinctions from obligations to the Coveiiaiit are in any case considered
                            ; most thoroughly are and firmest and the Bishops reTo the question, frequently asked " What
                            holds your people together?' we answer, " Our Covenant." Then arises a curiosity to know the
                            principles of this compact. Its record is a written Instrument, drawn with exceeding care,
                            in behalf of sin-sick souls quired to stand upon and to be guidec by it. It ordains Elders :
                            These, as nex to the Ministries, are governors, or executive officers, of the sub-divisions
                            o Societies called Families. Not less than the Ministries are the Elders re quired to be
                            governed by the Covenant The Elders deal directly with subordi nate officers and members,
                            and are ad mitted to be superiors while fulfilling and executing their official duties. To
                            them the members look for an example of close adherence to the covenanta —the weary and
                            heavily laden of the!principles ot Shakerism. If Minister "rom it, are, or should be, so
                            fully unierstood and so earnestly studied by all of its subscribers, that whatever may be
                            mplied by "a screw loose," or incomDatible relationships, may seek and find an unfailing
                            remedy by a return to the Covenant, while complete adherence hereto will be provocative of a
                            love and good-will, which will need no remedy, and which will ever cause the exclamation, "
                            See how the Christians ove one another ! " and Elders are privileged classes, the privileges
                            signify duties of service exceeding those of their subordinates,— in entrance, by sympathy,
                            into the piritual afflictions of the members, cnown by their confessions, and by vhose
                            forbearance, charity and parenal love members rise superior to spiritlal losses, to "go and
                            sin no more." Wherever there is seen a successful, lourishing family of Shakers, it may
                            :&gt;e known that at its head stand, and work and pray, in all the relinquish merit of
                            selfish emoluments of honor or posiion, Elders, true to their calling, to the
                            Covenant—''servants of all." We are provided with Trustees : To these are committed the
                            temporal trusts of the societies. The labors, and their results, of all the members pass
                            into their lands, and these are dispensed in accordance with provisions of the Covenant, for
                            ind in behalf of the members, or " for charitable and religious purposes" outside of the
                            societies, the dispensing of which is carefully provided for by the Covenant. Trustees are
                            expected to be models of prudence and industry in all temporal things, while holden to as
                            strict an accountability of their spiritual conditions as their superiors—the Elders. The
                            trusts committed to theii care are too sacred to permit scarcely Suspension of judgment is
                            asked of any, who may have been led to supDose that Elder F. W. Evans has not sufficient
                            deference for Sunday as a Sabbath. The article in Feb. No. by ' One of the Brethren," might
                            mislead some to animadvert erroneously. \Ve have on hand, an article from the elder—" The
                            Lord's Sabbath "—which we are sorry arrived too late for this lumber's insertion. It will
                            fully explain his position. Our knowledge of the elder, causes us to observe, that he is the
                            equal of Miles Standish in the observance of Sabbaths, and a great deal more
                            consistent.—Editor. a thought of their betrayal or prostitution. To their keeping are
                            committed, in confidence, the unreserved consecration of this life's labors of many, in
                            behalf of the upbuilding, upholding of a temporal Zion. Not one dollar of such trusts is
                            theirs, only as faring and sharing with their subordinate producers — the Brethren and
                            Sisters of society. The conditions upon which they receive and accept their trusts could be
                            made no safer nor more sacred by their bonds nor oaths. To those who look upon the position
                            of Trustees as desirable—to those who aspire to or envy the same—such may with certainty be
                            classed as either ignorant of what the faithful discharge of such duties are, or
                            self-seekers and servers, untrustworthy and dishonest. Trustees are strictly accountable to
                            the Elders, according to the Covenant; the Elders with the same to the Ministers ; and
                            Ministers, Elders and Trustees to the entire body of Society. It is a solemn act to join the
                            Shakers, by assigning all there is of one's self to labor for the good of others, even to
                            the forgetting of selfish considerations. Yet this is just what the spirit of The Shaker
                            Covenant expects and requires, and the results of such requisitions are invariably
                            beautiful, peaceable, peaceful Brethren and Sisters in Christ. We, ourselves, are bztt
                            learners of the full import of this sacred instrument. Standing upon this Covenant together,
                            " all is concert, all summer ; " while departures from such obligations, even to a limited
                            extent, breed unpleasant and trying relations, which are onlyamended and cured byconfession,
                            and a repentance that means will ace, who have cast off their burdens of in ; and it is
                            strongly guarded from the aggressions of envious, jealous and vituperative backsliders.
                            Since its creation, it has ever stood as a monumental invitation to the former class ; and t
                            has so invariably resisted with success the latter parties, as ever to insure their certain,
                            ignominious defeat. It is a Platform upon which we all may and must stand, or we must step
                            down and out from its sure and elevatng privileges, secular and sacred. It s a solemn
                            Obligation, accepted by each person composing Shaker societies, to maintain that peculiar
                            government, discipline and behavior which promises to transform, by such maintenance, people
                            of any kindred, tongue or nation into the "peculiar people" called Shakers. It is a sure,
                            temporal Privilege : So long as any acceptable member keeps this league inviolate, that
                            individual is worthy of, and must receive according</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What shall I do to be a shaker? no. 2" TEIform="index"/>What Shall I Do to be a Shaker? No. 2.
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Albatross" TEIform="persName"/> "ALBATROSS.'</byline><p TEIform="p">Before this question can be candidly answered, the individual asking it should answer Why do
                            you wish to become a Shaker? Shakerism, pleading for itself, is the harvest of souls— from
                            the earthly, on the earth, to the life lived in the heavens—thus forming as far as possible
                            a heaven in advance, " heaven on earth." Arriving at a conscientious conclusion, very many
                            will answer, "Hard Times ;" " 111 success in life ;" " Social troubles;" "111 health;" "Want
                            of work, victuals and clothes." Summing up, all of these mean, " unable to earn a temporal
                            livelihood!" And such answers are noble when given honestly, than to have such the facts,
                            while giving answers that mean: '•'¦We are soul-sick of the world, evejt in its best
                            prospects." Those who are not truly, so sick of sin, and a worldly life, that they would as
                            soon turn to Shakerism from the palace, as from the poor-house, are not the proper
                            candidates for this gospel work. And however many gain admittance, either through childhood
                            or through chicanery, and do not gain that loathing for a sinful, fleshly life, and
                            aspirations from the corroding, corrupting practices of selfishness through wealth or power,
                            are ever poor tools or building materials for the household of our faith ! Therefore, we say
                            to those who axe. not thoroughly sin-sick, do not apply for admittance. Many of the above
                            think they could benefit the institution by their talents and their labors, some saying they
                            will be able to pay their way, etc. If people cannot earn a livelihood outside of Shaker
                            communism, they do so no more. This construction of the cannot inside ; and if they should "
                            pay character of the Covenanting, departures their way," it must be seen, that more <pb n="14" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 14: THE SHAKER. than this is necessary, else how could our institutions
                            be sustained and improved? Do not do it—only sorrows of soul will be the consequences. But
                            to those who are sick unto death, of a sordid, sensual, selfish society; who would turn in
                            all humility to the a b c of a new life; who would become " new creatures ;" who have so
                            risen in the love of Jesus' life, that they turn from their own old life, as from vomit,
                            never to return, like dogs, thereunto ; those who would wash in the life blood of Jesus
                            Christ, from all their former sins and sorrows; those unto whom sensual pleasures, worldly
                            vanities, honors of men, earthly power and applause, are as disgusting as once they were
                            courted and agreeable—these are the candidates for genuine Shakerhood. To every such soul,
                            we open arms of greetings and hearts of welcome ; we acknowledge that we love you dearly,
                            want your company, need your assistance in sustaining the glorious cause on earth. " Is
                            there joy in heaven over one such soul ?" and well there may be ! Is it strange to any one,
                            upon reading the above requisitions, that Shakerism is unpopular, or that " only a few find
                            it" to be sufficiently agreeable to endure its " threshing and winnowing?" Truly it is a
                            harvest of souls, from sinful words and ways. It admits, invites the poor penitent to share
                            with its fellows the separation of their worldly tares from their spiritual wheat. This is
                            done by an honest confession, and forsaking of .sins—to the servants who should " first
                            gather the tares and burn them ;" then should gather the wheat into a Shaker institution, to
                            be used as food, light, warmth, and sustenance thereof. And in asking this much of those
                            desirous of being Shakers, please observe, it is requiring no more than what Jesus asked of
                            his disciples—demanded of them if such they would be —and the continued purity of life lived
                            by all good Shakers, had, and still has its eternal pattern in Jesus, the Christ. It is
                            easier to be a Roman, a Methodist, Presbyterian, Baptist, Spiritualist, etc., etc., than to
                            be a Shaker; each costs less—more of the earth is conserved therein, and less of the
                            heavenly life is demanded. It costs all that a man hath to be a Shaker ; but it returns to
                            him more than he will ever gain without it. Inasmuch as any denominational persuasion leads
                            from the world and its constituents, just so far is it Shakerism. Now, dear friends, what do
                            you wish? A mere anodyne to quiet your guilty consciences? or do you sincerely desire a
                            fire, that will try you as gold is tried until so pure that your Master's countenance may be
                            seen in your face ; and your life reflect his daily walk and conversation ? If the first,
                            join some of the respectable churches we have named, for they will do you much good. But, if
                            the latter, make yourself familiar with some of the corresponding agents of the Shakers, and
                            may the Lord and his angels help you alway.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Social life topics" TEIform="index"/>SOCIAL LIFE TOPICS</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York, January 20, 1877" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, Albany Co., N. Y., Jan.
                                20, 1877</head><p TEIform="p">My very dear H. C. B. : I am urged to write you a " Social Life " letter ; and as the
                                editor wishes it for publication in The Shaker, it undoubtedly should contain some, even
                                many of the characteristics of our social life. I will try and embrace the " some"
                                leaving to your reply the " many." My themes lead me to dwell upon those practices in
                                our life, that strongly remind one of the Quakers—prayer times, retiring times—and I
                                almost hear the readers say, there can nothing be said of them that is new, salacious,
                                or soul-stirring. Please wait a minute. You know, my dear H., that our rules cause us to
                                kneel in prayer, eight times in a day—before and after each meal, and upon rising from
                                and retiring to bed. Again, before we meet for special worship, we assemble in our
                                individual departments, and retire from external thoughts and movements, seated for deep
                                reflection from fifteen to thirty minutes. What is this retirement, but for prayer?
                                Again, we enter our sanctuaries, and there we often unite in prayer upon our bended
                                knees ; and there we sing in prayer, and there petition by vocal address, prayers in
                                abundance. Again, there are those I know of, who pray "between times;" who have sanctum
                                sanctorums beneath some beauteous tree, or on some spot, secluded by myrtles and
                                evergreens; and further, one of our early fathers was led to remark, in consideration of
                                the requisite chastity of our lives : "A good believer's every breath is prayer to God
                                !" Who will then say we are not a praying people ? And when I remind you, in
                                illustration of our lives to others, that scarcely an evening passes, that we as
                                brethren and sisters, do not meet for some united purposes of soul-improvement, we will
                                earn the sobriquet of a " meeting people." We pray before we eat, and before we meet in
                                worshipful labors ; we meet for reflection, for singing, for reading, for lectures of
                                various hues, some of them agreeable, all of them, it is hoped, profitable ; and now,
                                with all of our seasons of prayer, retirement, physical exercises, etc., are we as much
                                better therefor, as we should be ? I had a conversation with one of our most exact
                                brethren: I said, " B., do you always pray when you kneel down?" B. "What a question
                                that is to ask a man!" A. " Strange, I admit; but what do you say, or think of when on
                                your knees? Is not this a simple question?" B. "Yea, simple and impertinent too ! I
                                never had any one ask me such a question before !" A. " Well, you will excuse my seeming
                                impertinence, when I tell you, that I ask to find if you are not something like me about
                                praying. I kneel eight, and more times daily with you, and I sometimes forget where I
                                am, and what I should be doing, don't you ?" B. " Well, you are so frank about yourself,
                                I must admit that the form too frequently is all there is of it. My aim at such times,
                                is to think grateful thoughts, and I chasten myself whenever I fail of doing so." A. "
                                And don't you have to chasten yourself very frequently? I do." B. " Perhaps, I ought to
                                admit, that I should chasten myself more than I do." A. " Now my dear B., I heard L. and
                                D. talking on the same subject:" D. "Luke, when you ought to be praying, are you not
                                frequently studying up some new invention, or other project? Are you not planning some
                                new house or barn ?" L. "I'll answer you by asking: David, when you are on your knees,
                                are you not frequently going to see some man, to drive a bargain with him? Counting over
                                what others owe you, you owe others, or the dreadful time when the taxes are due?" D. "
                                Luke, if you will stop asking questions, I will! " Perhaps, my dear H., I have told
                                enough of colloquy ; but they will answer my purpose. Unless we are careful, as a
                                people, we shall permit spiritual activity to become swamped with mere formality. Of a
                                truth, these seasons of prayer, and especially our "retiring times," may be made the
                                most profitable for spiritual progress of any of our devotions. One of the most
                                celebrated of our modern sages has recently written: "One hour of silent conflict with a
                                personal fault is worth years of churchal theologies ! " He undoubtedly meant our
                                retiring times. It is not a question, but a decision with me, that when wre shall have
                                faithfully improved thirty minutes of i-etirement, wre might often be excused further
                                congregation, and the time be next best improved by retiring to rest, to awaken at five
                                or half-past five next morning. I have thought, too, whether the omission of table
                                prayers once in a while, and the substitution of remarks by some one, as a reminder of
                                gratefulness due, would not interrupt the form not only, but give us a new start and
                                better gift in saying our grace. There are other topics that I want to write you upon,
                                but hoping you will anticipate me in your reply, I leave you, to answer a letter of
                                Williams'. I am yours, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Albatross" TEIform="persName"/> "ALBATROSS.'</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York, 1877" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y., 1877</head><p TEIform="p">Friend Williams : I find, upon count ¦ ing your questions, there are twelve of them ; and
                                while I am amused at some of them, I can but admit, too many really believe, as you
                                observe, that the Shaker sexes never speak to one another, sleep in different houses,
                                eat in different apartments, and incline to coolness and unkindness. In regard to such
                                opinions, I have only to repeat once more, that the reverse of each is true ; and I will
                                add, the contrary is exceedingly true, so far as " coolness and unkindness" is
                                expressed—-none could manifest warmer, genuine kindness than is exhibited by genuine
                                brethren and sisters among the Shakers. That we enjoy separate sleeping apartments is
                                true, and that we do not converse at our meals is also true ; and, for aught we know,
                                Queen Victoria has patterned this wisdom of ours, commonly practiced at the royal table
                                ! Concerning our number of meetings, etc., see letter above. All pairing or mating is
                                not only discarded, but severely condemned and ever has been. Each brother, however, has
                                appointed for his convenience some sister to look after his individual necessities, as
                                knitting, mending, general supervision of his clothing; and this appointment demands of
                                the brother any individual, gospel kindness she may at any time need at his hands. But
                                the attempt is ever made, with considerable success, to urge into practice " the love
                                universal" from each to all. To your question, "Are you all of one mind theologically?"
                                we answer positively in the affirmative, as far as our fundamental principles are
                                theological ; but further than these, we answer in the negative. There are those among
                                us who have not progressed beyond the triune-God theory, and yet are living clean,
                                self-denying Shaker lives ; others believe in fore-ordination, predestination; and a few
                                who are not yet certain that Jesus was a Tew, conceived and born as other children ;
                                that he was not a God-man, and did not considerably wipe out human sins by atonement!
                                And minor opinions are legion among us ; and yet, on the points of virgin celibacy,
                                common property, non-resistance, peace, and a Christ-government, with which there shall
                                be no mingling of the state, we are, or must be, a unit. Concerning the accounts of
                                spiritual manifestations among us, we have to say that, though largely withdrawn at
                                present, we are not entirely without them. Considerable prominence has been given to
                                spiritualism among the Shakers ; but so far as this has been used publicly by
                                historians, and those unfit to be called such, those portions that could be presented in
                                the most ridiculous manner, have been used in preference to those which more
                                particularly represented our principles. Some have deemed our princi-. pies " so well
                                understood," as to leave little else than a garbled mass of unspiritual spiritualism to
                                be presented. The truth is, spiritualism has done greater works among the Shakers, given
                                better evidences of its reality, illustrated in superior degree its most excellent
                                features, than any account of it, given anywhere else, since its debut to the world at
                                Rochester, N. Y., of which appearance we had definite information years before it
                                occurred. The introduction of spiritualism, its more modern phases—"last
                                manifestations," as we term them—found us napping," or quite unprepared for them ; in
                                fact, we did not know what to do with them ; and, for a time, they governed us and our
                                wisdom, and we <pb n="15" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. 15 frankly admit all of this ; but we
                                have to grind " old nature " considerably to " love those who have so despitefully used
                                us" as to present to the world these unwise features of spiritual phenomena as specimens
                                of Shaker religion ! To your ninth will say that Shakerism inculcates industry,
                                believing with Bunyan that " an idle man's head is the devil's workshop," and with
                                Watts, " Satan finds some mischief still;" and from our Bishops, Elders, Trustees, down
                                to the least, some kind of industry is engaged in by each. Regarding the perpetuity of
                                our institutions, this is a matter of small importance compared with the maintenance of
                                our principles to, and before the world. Institutions are man-made; our principles are
                                heaven-born ; and if we but maintain them intact while life is ours, our mission will be
                                well-fulfilled, and we can trust their continuance in others to the Omniscient. To do
                                our full duty, we have not forgotten the need of a missionary ; and we send out at our
                                own expense thousands of copies of The Shaker, to the end that " the gospel may be
                                spread to the ends of the earth ;" and to properly quiet our consciences, that we are
                                not " hiding our lights under a bushel," but are as that city set upon a hill,—for these
                                The Shaker means to live. I have answered nearly all ot your questions. I would refer
                                you to a little work nearly in press,—"Plain Talks,"—for further, fuller information. I
                                am yours,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Albatross" TEIform="persName"/> "ALBATROSS.'</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>THE CHILDREN'S GROTTO</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Talks with the children" TEIform="index"/>Talks with the Children</head><p TEIform="p">My dear Children : I call you all mine because, all men and women being mj brothers and
                                sisters, you are mine to love and to do all the good to that I can. You are so young
                                that, like wax, you form ideas anc habits as wax receives the figures of what is pressed
                                upon it. Your language, habits, ges tures and general conduct are forming now to bless
                                you, or to blight your happy days not very far oft" in future years. I want to save you
                                much pain and trouble, and perhaps dishonor, by a word in season. Let your language be
                                clean, kind and loving to one another, and respectful to father, mother and older
                                friends. Every effort you wil make to these ends will pay you an early anc profitable
                                interest, and you will never have to unlearn them. If you know of a boy o girl so bold
                                or bad as to glory in nasty o unkind words and behavior, shun such a chile and glory,
                                and resolve to be better than that The resolve alone will be worth more than many times
                                the glory of the bad child. I you would be saved much trouble in your schooldays, learn
                                to speak and write correct \y—according to grammar—of those whom you know speak most
                                properly. Otherwise much of your schooltime will be spent in unlearning that which you
                                never shoulc have learned. A child that never hears any conversation excepting that
                                which is prop erly spoken, never needs to study grammar unless to become a teacher. It
                                is a beautifu ornament, my dear children, to be prettilj and purely spoken ; and do you
                                think of thi after reading it, and begin now to be so, i you have not been so before.
                                Shun evil hab its : ail those homely, nasty, wicked ways which you would hide from your
                                fathers o mothers because of shame. Just think that God sees you every time, and you
                                cannot lelp it; and should you not be more ashamed ;o do wrong in secret, what God and
                                good pirits always see you do, than if only your parents should see you? You have many
                                sx&gt;od thoughts—try and have these all the ime; for if you are good you will be
                                worth more than gold in this world, and what an lonor to your parents and friends you
                                will :&gt;e ! Dear children, my pen could write you ome of the glories of the clean,
                                godly child; &gt;ut if it should write for years it would then only have written a
                                part of what might be said, of you even, if you are free from sinful, unclean habits!
                                Make your parents, friends and yourselves happier, never doing ivhat you -would be
                                ashamed to do before your nother or friends. Learn to be genteel: By his I mean, use
                                good manners—those that are agreeable to good, respectable people everywhere: at church,
                                school, at the table. T.ake off your hat when you enter company, :&gt;eing sure to
                                open and close the doors softly. Speak mildly: ask your friends " to be kind enough " to
                                give you this or that, or to do vhat you wish of them; and then recall your Jncle
                                Henry's counsel in December number, o return a " kindly thank you!" You are young, as I
                                was once; noisy, full of life, plenty to spare of both noise and life, just ike me of
                                old. I am so glad I have not forgotten that I was once young, just like you. And I feel
                                sorry for your older friends who lave forgotten that they were once young. There is that
                                noise in all young people which really seems must come out, and the ony fault about it
                                is, the noise comes out too often in the wrong place. I would often take you where you
                                could let all the noise out which you had in you, and where no one would be disturbed
                                therebj'; then I think you would be quiet in proper places. Love to hear good words ;
                                love to leai n and sing good songs; love to go to Sunday-school, and to day-school, too.
                                Who ever knew a good Sunday-school child to become a bad man or woman? I do not know of
                                any one. I do know that of a hundred wicked men and women who were sent thousands of
                                miles away from their native land — away from home and friends—to work for years in
                                prison, not more than twenty could read or write, and these not well; and only five had
                                ever been to Sabbath-school! and if you will look this paper over you will see that in
                                France all of its murderers were very bad schoo children, who loved mischief rather than
                                good books. And now, dear children, I have much to say to you; but must leave it foi
                                other letters, as this is getting long. Bu before I close, I want you should try and fee
                                how well I love you, that I am living for you and working for your good only. It is be
                                cause you are loved by so many—loved by Goc and good spirits, and by so many friends on
                                earth- -'/** because of this love that you should try very hard to be very good. In
                                heaven, in the new Jerusalam, I expect to romp in happy glee with you all; for does not
                                the prophet Zechariah give us one of the most joyful prospects of heaven when he tells
                                us about the boys and girls who will be there, and what they will be doing? Ask your
                                friends to read it to you in Zech. 8 : 5 Be good, and remember.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Albert, George" TEIform="persName"/>Geo. Albert </byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>STOCK AND FARM</head><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Drying-off cows" TEIform="index"/>Drying-off Cows</head><p TEIform="p">Cows cannot be dried of their milk at once, and some cows continue to secrete milk in
                                small quantities for a long time. But in all cases where the animal has ceased to give
                                milk, or is what is termed " dry," she should have her udder examined from time to time,
                                and the teats tried, to see if any milk can be drawn. At first the trial should be made
                                at intervals of two or three days, and if there is a particle of milk in the bag it
                                should be all thoroughly drawn. Then the trial may be made at longer intervals. When
                                cows are supposed to be completely dry, the rule should be to go through lie herd every
                                week, making trial of the teats to see if any milk can be drawn. And this work cannot
                                safely be intrusted to "hired help," but must be performed under the " eye of the
                                master." Many persons are not aware of the importance of drying cows, and hired help
                                often think it a piece of folly to try to draw milk from a dry cow. Many have lost the
                                use of valuable cows by intrusting this to persons in their employ, and there is
                                scarcely a dairyman in New York who cannot trace trouble in his herd to either his own
                                neglect or that of others. Indeed, so large is the loss every year from improperly
                                drying cows, that there is scarcely a subject connected with dairy management of more
                                vital importance than this. We urge it, therefore, upon the attention of dairymen, and
                                we say to them : Be sure that the work is done properly—trust no eye but your own, and
                                when your herd comes in milk next spring you will realize the value of this advice.</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sex of eggs" TEIform="index"/>Sex of Eggs</head><p TEIform="p">A correspondent of The Sotithcrn Farmer tells how an old poultryraiser distinguishes sex
                                in eggs. It is related as follows : " ' Eggs with the air bladder on he sides will
                                produce pullets.' The old man was so certain of the truth of his dogma, and he
                                poultry-yard so far confirmed it, that I determined to make experiments upon it this
                                year. I have done so, carefully registering every 'bladder verticle' or bladder on one
                                side, rejecting every one in which it was not decidedly one way or the other, as in some
                                it was only slightly out of the center. The following is the result: 58 chickens hatched
                                ; 3 are dead ; 11 too young yet to decide upon their sex; of the remaining 44 every one
                                has turned out true to the old man's theory. I tried it myself and found it to be
                                correct, and I think it to be of great practical advantage. I am pleased to give it my
                                full indorsement, though I would remark that other writers make the statement that they
                                tried it and found no such results. I am breeding white leghorns, which seem naturally
                                to give more cockerels than pullets ; at least such has been the case until last year,
                                when I set only such eggs as had the air bladder on one side, anc in nearly every case
                                they were pullets. Late in the season I set a lot of hens with the eggs just as they
                                were laid, and more than half the chicks turned out cockerels." </p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kind Treatment Pays" TEIform="index"/>Kind Treatment Pays</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Willard, X. A." TEIform="persName"/>X. A. Willard</byline><p TEIform="p"> in his new "Butter Book,'" says: "It is really astonishing what a large difference in
                                the yield of milk it makes by attending properly to a number of small things in the man
                                agement of stock—and things which to many would seem quite too insignificant to be worth
                                observing. The dairyman should have a genuine, a hearty love for the animals un der his
                                control, providing wholesome, nutri tious food, pure water and pure air—every thing of
                                this kind in abundance; keeping the animals properly sheltered from storms feeding
                                always with great regularity; paying the most marked attention to the manner anc time of
                                milking, withal, preserving uniform kindness and gentleness of treatment throughout
                                every operation—a gentleness extendec even to the tones of the voice. Generally
                                speaking, the cow will do her best that is loved the best and petted the most in hei
                                charge. If you wish a cow to do her best, you must cultivate her acquaintance
                                intimately, and be unsparing in little acts of kindness."</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to manage and feed working oxen" TEIform="index"/>How to Manage and Feed Working
                                Oxen</head><p TEIform="p">In managing working oxen let the law of kindness be strictly obeyed. Never use the whip
                                except from necessity. When I about to strike the awkward young steer or full-grown ox,
                                ask yourself, " Will he know what I am striking him for? " Let each ox have a name, and
                                be sure he knows it. Never speak a word to an ox without meaning; lave a particular word
                                to start the team with, hat all may pull together. Never hurry the :eam while riding
                                behind them, lest they earn to pull apart. Oxen should be shod with a broad shoe to
                                travel on hard roads; :he shoe on the fore foot should be set back at the heel nearly
                                half an inch further than ;he hoof bears upon it. Oxen are frequently amed by short
                                shoes. The best feed for oxen at hard work is to give to each two quarts of meal, wet,
                                mixed with good chopped hay, three times a day, and as much hay as he will eat.</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wood ashes for fowls injurious" TEIform="index"/>Wood Ashes for Fowls Injurious</head><p TEIform="p">A correspondent of The Massachusetts Ploughman says : " It is often specified in this
                                recommendation that coal ashes should be applied, but I have lately seen in some of the
                                papers the advice given to supply wood ashes for the poultry to shuffle in. I would
                                caution all against following this advice. Wood ashes are so rich in potash that their
                                effect on fowls' feet is exceedingly injurious. I have seen poultry with bad sores and
                                blisters on their feet from this cause, and in one or two cases have seen birds badly
                                lamed. Coal ashes are excellent, but wood ashes should never be furnished for the
                                purpose above named." </p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to feed poultry" TEIform="index"/>How to Feed Poultry</head><p TEIform="p">The Massachusetts Ploughman says : " Don't feed poultry corn; for laying hns it is worse
                                than valueless ; there is so much fattening material in its composition and so little of
                                the albuminous, that eggs cannot be manufactured from it. For their breakfast a dry
                                dough of shorts is sufficient; if you have some skim-milk to mix with it, all the
                                better. A good supply of oats and barley should be kept in the feeding-box through the
                                day, and at night a feed of whole wheat should be given them. Corn should be fed only in
                                the cold weather, and then sparingly and for the last meal of the day." </p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The main purpose of keeping cows is to procure their milk..." TEIform="index"/>The main purpose of keeping cows is to procure their milk...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The main purpose of keeping cows is to procure their milk. Everything we do for them
                                should point to this purpose, and we should fail to do nothing for their comfort and
                                flow of milk, unless more expensive than the milk is profitable or convenient. Slop them
                                well, keep them warm day and night; too often that which we give them to produce milk is
                                consumed to keep them from freezing. A little care and labor can be turned into a great
                                quantity of milk.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="L., G. A." TEIform="persName"/>G. A. L.</byline></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Curing of pop-corn" TEIform="index"/>Curing of Pop-Corn</head><p TEIform="p">Pop-corn is often spoiled in curing by being put in rooms where the temperature runs too
                                high. Some people are of the opinion that the drier the corn the better it will pop, but
                                such opinions are erroneous. Pop-corn is best cured in a dry, cool room—not in a hot,
                                dry room, as can soon be proven by test. </p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gapes in chickens" TEIform="index"/>Gapes in Chickens</head><p TEIform="p">Reputable stock journals are circulating the experience of a correspondent, that half a
                                teaspoonful of petroleum given occasionally to chickens liable to, or that are afflicted
                                with, the distressing gapes, will prevent or cure the same.</p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The London Journal of Horticulture considers the peachblow potato..." TEIform="index"/>The London Journal of Horticulture considers the peachblow potato...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The London Journal of Horticulture considers the peachblow potato " not only the best of
                                all American sorts, but as good and in some respects better than many of outstandard
                                varieties." </p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If poultry are made to roost on sassafras poles..." TEIform="index"/>If poultry are made to roost on sassafras poles...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">If poultry are made to roost on sassafras poles they will never freeze their feet; and if
                                the hen-house is covered with shingles of the same timber, the frost will not affect
                                their combs.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Why the teeth decay " TEIform="index"/>Why the Teeth Decay</head><p TEIform="p">Recent investigations show that the fruitful causes of the decay of teeth are acids, and
                                a certain fungus found abundantly in the mouth. This fungus, whose scientific name</p></div3><pb n="16" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New church" TEIform="index"/>THE NEW CHURCH</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, James G." TEIform="persName"/>James G. Russell</byline><p TEIform="p">Enfield, N. H. The glory of the heavenly spheres, In visioned splendor now appears, As on
                                Mount Zion's summit stand The followers of the Bride and Lamb. They sing before the
                                Throne of God, Their harps attuned to praise and love; Emblazoned on their banners
                                bright. The ensign Victory—• glorious sight. Their gallant Leader, at the head, Before
                                them moved with fearless tread ; Opposing forces could not stand Before this valiant,
                                marshalled band. Through fields of conflict they have moved, And loyal to the cause
                                have proved. And in their foreheads now is seen The signature of the redeemed. 4.
                                Assembled thus around the Throne, Their heavenly Parentage they own, As Father, Mother,
                                in their place, The new and living Church to grace. The children of tho heavenly
                                Twain,-Both sons and daughters swell the strain ; Sweet music floats upon the air, And
                                all is pure rejoicing there. The mighty contest now is past; The glorious prize is won
                                at last; Enslaved no more by powers of sin, The spirit, Christ, now reigns within. Upon
                                their heads are crowns of gold, And palms within their hands they hold ; Their vestures
                                are of spotless white, Prepared by purity of life. 5. O may the glory there displayed,
                                To earth's dominions be conveyed, That her inhabitants may share The glory of Mount Zion
                                fair. Salvation's sound! O may it roll Throughout the earth from pole to pole, Till
                                Peace shall spread her wings of love, On earth, as in the worlds above.</p></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">is Leptothrix vuccalis, appears under the microscope as a gray, finely-granular mass,
                                with delicate and stiff filaments erected above the surface. It attains the greatest
                                growth in the interstices of the teeth. An examination of the teeth of forty persons of
                                different professions and habits of living, showed that on almost all of them there were
                                vegetable fungi and animal parasites. In proportion to the want of cleanliness were the
                                parasites. The " moral " of all this is that if we would preserve our teeth we must keep
                                them very clean. The ordinary means of cleaning them will not do, as the parasites do
                                not appear to be unfavorably affected by common or uncommon dentifrices. "We must use
                                soap," says a writer on this subject, "as an ingredient in our dentifrices, or in
                                addition to them. It is not necessary to employ any of the so-called ' dental soaps.' We
                                have found by experience that the imported white castile soap, which is probably the
                                purest soap made in the world,—a fact worth remembering in other connections,—is quite
                                tasteless, or at least has no unpleasant taste. Rub the wet tooth-brush over a piece of
                                this soap before dipping it into the dentifrice you use, and you have the most perfect
                                combination for thorough cleansing of the teeth and destroying the obnoxious fungus. We
                                assume, of course, that the dentifrice itself is not one that injures the teeth, as many
                                of those in common use do."</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Small-pox cure" TEIform="index"/>Small-pox Cure</head><p TEIform="p">The following was sent to the Liverpool Mercury by Edward Aine: "I am willing to risk my
                                reputation as a public man if the worst case of small-pox cannot be cured in three days
                                simply by the use of cream of tartar. One ounce of cream of tartar, dissolved in a pint
                                of water, drank at intervals when cold, is a certain, never-failing remedy. It has cured
                                thousands, never leaves a mark, never causes blindness, and avoids tedious lingering."
                                [The above remedy for the most-dreaded of diseases has been going the rounds of the
                                press for some time, but we have received the authority of a reliable octogenarian, that
                                a family of nine, in Canada, was attacked with it, four dying before trying the above,
                                and five recovering by its timely application. Should it prove so invariably, we may
                                gladly dispense with Jenner's disgusting discovery. Ed.]</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Removing freckles" TEIform="index"/>Removing Freckles</head><p TEIform="p">The Christian Union says: "Horseradish grated into a cup of cold sour milk—let it stand
                                twelve hours, then strain and apply two or three times a day—will remove freckles from
                                hands or face in a short time. Or, one ounce lemon-juice mixed with a quarter of a
                                drachm of pulverized borax and half a drachm of sugar, will also remove freckles. Keep
                                the lotion in a glass bottle corked tightly a few days before using and apply to the
                                freckles occasionally, and it will soon remove them."</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To remove dandruff" TEIform="index"/>To Remove Dandruff</head><p TEIform="p">Some people are disfigured, and are commonly considered to be unclean, by the appearance
                                of much dandruff. Take an ounce of flour of sulphur, added to a quart of soft water.
                                Shake thoroughly. In twenty-four hours pour off the liquid, washing the head every other
                                day until relieved.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="For ear-ache" TEIform="index"/>For Ear-ache</head><p TEIform="p">Take a bit of cotton, spread it flatly, sprinkle with black pepper, do it up in a wad,
                                dip in sweet oil, and insert in the ear. This is a happy and almost instantaneous
                                relief. The same remedy applied to the cavity of an aching tooth gives immediate
                            relief.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Removing warts" TEIform="index"/>Removing Warts</head><p TEIform="p">Oil of cinnamon will cause the disappearance of warts, however hard, large, or dense they
                                may be. The application gives rise to neither pain nor suppuration. A lady removed
                                thirty off her hands with five cents' worth of the oil.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>LIFE THOUGHTS</head><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Every human spirit bears the impress..." TEIform="index"/>Every human spirit bears the impress...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Every human spirit bears the impress within itself of every thought, feeling, emotion,
                                word, and action of life.</p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If calumny assails you, don't turn moody and misanthropic..." TEIform="index"/>If calumny assails you, don't turn moody and misanthropic...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">If calumny assails you, don't turn moody and misanthropic. Bide your time. Disprove the
                                slander if you can ; if not, live it down. </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Truth is a good thing, but it is very unpopular..." TEIform="index"/>Truth is a good thing, but it is very unpopular...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Truth is a good thing, but it is very unpopular; and as to the naked truth, it is
                                absolutely shocking. The majority of people will not look at it twice. </p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A key to Heaven" TEIform="index"/>A key to Heaven
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">People make a great mistake about Heaven. They think it begins up yonder, but
                                        it really begins down here. If you can be happy in the basement story, you are
                                        fitted to enjoy the happiness of the upper stories. But if you whine and moan
                                        here, Heaven itself can't change your mood.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New York herald" TEIform="index"/>N. Y. Herald.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A Turk once took a piece of white cloth to a dyer to have it dyed black..." TEIform="index"/>A Turk once took a piece of white cloth to a dyer to have it dyed black...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A Turk once took a piece of white cloth to a dyer to have it dyed black. He was so
                                pleased with the result, that after a time he went to him with a piece of black cloth,
                                and asked to have it made white. But the dyer answered : "A piece of white cloth is like
                                a man's reputation ; it can be dyed black, but you cannot make it white again." </p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What distinguishes a man as superior to his fellows, is greater..." TEIform="index"/>What distinguishes a man as superior to his fellows, is greater...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">What distinguishes a man as superior perior to his fellows, is greater
                                        goodness, stronger and clearer intellect, so that he speaks and acts according
                                        to the dictates of reason, not under the impulse of passion and prejudice ; in
                                        fine, does not fly into a rage when anybody disagrees with him.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New York sun" TEIform="index"/>N. Y. Sun.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Of the thirty-one persons condemned to death in France in 1875..." TEIform="index"/>Of the thirty-one persons condemned to death in France in 1875...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Of the thirty-one persons condemned to death in France in 1875, but one had received a
                                good school education, only four could write, and the remaining twenty-six were
                                illiterate. </p></div3><div3 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="President White, of Cornell University, admits that the lady pupils average ten per cent, better on..." TEIform="index"/>President White, of Cornell University, admits that the lady pupils average ten per cent, better on...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">President White, of Cornell University, admits that the lady pupils average ten per cent,
                                better on the examination papers than the young men. </p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Punch, in his dictionary, gives the definition of the word 'conscience:'..." TEIform="index"/>Punch, in his dictionary, gives the definition of the word 'conscience:'...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Punch, in his dictionary, gives the definition of the word "conscience:" "My rule for
                                another man's conduct."</p></div3></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>