<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm0907" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title><editor role="editor" TEIform="editor"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/></editor></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">9</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">7</biblScope><date value="18790701" TEIform="date">July 1879</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">145-168</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="9" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="7" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                <pb id="p1"/>
                    <p> JULY, 1879. MANIFESTO. (OFFICIAL MONTHLY.) G. A. LOMAS, Editor. Published by the United Societies, OUR HOME AT
                        CANTERBURY, N. H. "And they shall turn to you for a testimony:" ''Go fir each the Kingdom of God!" G. B. AVERY,
                        PUBLISHER. Vol. IX No. 7. 60 Cents Per Annum. The Shaker ADDRESS AMi COMMUNICATIONS TO " The Shaker Manifesto,
                        Shakers, N.D." </p>

                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --><pb n="145" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Respiration" TEIform="index"/>RESPIRATION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>MARTHA J. ANDERSON</byline><p TEIform="p"> One of the many important functions performed by the vital organs of the human system is
                            that of respiration. Much has been wisely said concerning the necessity of breathing pure
                            air, of keeping well-ventilated houses, and of removing the causes which infect the
                            atmosphere with foul and poisonous vapors ; while as yet comparatively little attention has
                            been given to the subject of lung development. It is true that many eminent vocalists by
                            correct culture and persevering effort, have attained grand results in this direction; but
                            it should not exclusively belong to a thorough musical training ; the masses need more
                            light, and practical knowledge on this subject. To learn how to breathe is the grand acme of
                            success in attaining perfect health. With feeble lung power there is a correspondingly weak
                            circulation, and vitalization of the blood; consequently a general debility of the whole
                            system. Those who breathe superficially, often clamor for copious draughts of air, when
                            their contracted lungs are not capable of utilizing a pint of the same ; while the deep
                            breather feels perfectly comfortable, because in the enjoyment of the equilibrium of organic
                            forces. Personsof weak constitution or sedentary habit naturally incline to bend forward,
                            and unless great care is taken the shoulders become permanently rounded, the chest narrow,
                            and the lungs compressed, making them an easy prey to disease. One needs to understand the
                            construction of the breathing apparatus and the relation its healthful action bears to the
                            whole animal mechanism, in order to comprehend the proper method of development. The organs
                            of respiration lie within the thorax or chest; they are connected with the trachea or
                            windpipe, the ramifications of which are called bronchial tubes ; these, branching off into
                            an infinite multitude, finally terminate in small cells ; millions of them form the " soft
                            and elastic" substance of the lungs, which are capable of great dilation or compression."
                            They are divided into five parts called lobes, three of which lie on the right and two on
                            the left of the thoracic cavity. Each of the myriad vesicles forms a cap or terminus of some
                            small blood vessel, thousands of which course their way over and through the transparent
                            membrane which forms the delicate covering of the lungs. Through all these veins and
                            arteries—some of which are finer than a hair—the entire blood of the system passes, and
                            meets with a chemical change. How necessary then that the lungs should be expanded to their
                            uttermost capacity, that every minute compartment may receive its due quantity of oxygen,
                            which, coming in contact with the venous blood, converts its dark hue to bright vermillion,
                            when the arteries take it up and convey it with its life-giving properties to every part of
                            the frame. For healthful chest conditions, begin with sensible treatment of the throat—the
                            doorway to the lungs—this, even externally, should be dealt with properly, allowing no undue
                            wrapping thereon. Even in the coldest weather an unnatural heat created on the surface,
                            makes the internal membranes tender, and superinduces sensitiveness and disease in the
                            glands and laryngeal cavity. Experience has taught many that <pb n="146" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 146 THE
                            SHAKER MANIFESTO. to toughen the throat is to strengthen the lungs. A cold water bath,
                            followed by brisk rubbing, every morning, has proved efficacious in the process. Next, an
                            erect carriage of the body, with the shoulders well thrown back, wards off predisposition to
                            pulmonic weakness, and certainly adds to personal grace and dignity. " God made man upright
                            " in more than one meaning of the word, and it is only in violation of moral and
                            physiological law, that he stoops to lower conditions of body and mind. Let it be well
                            understood that the chest may be enlarged many degrees by muscular exercise, and at the same
                            time the lungs be dwarfed within. Their size and power is only increased by deep breathing.
                            The most powerful muscle of respiration is the diaphragm ; to learn its use is to acquire a
                            mighty force for the inhalation and exhalation of the air; a strength that gives the voice
                            its volume and endurance ; and, when the mucous membrane is in ahealthful condition, it
                            increases its pui-e resonant tone. Without a knowledge of its use, the strain and vocal
                            pressure comes on the muscles of the throat and larynx, which soon become diseased or
                            disabled. This is why so many voices fail or lose their musical tone at an early age. Let
                            our system of ventilation be better studied and scientifically arranged—as it is now in a
                            few of our buildings—that good and not evil may result, as is frequently the case, from
                            counter currents of cold or damp air, blowing directly on any part of the body, especially
                            on the back of the head or neck. When fully immersed in the out-door atmosphere, it will
                            benefit all to take full deep inspirations, with elevated chest, until by expansion, we can
                            feel that every portion of our lungs is inflated with the pressure of the air. If there was
                            better lung development there would be less consumption, dyspepsia, and their many attendant
                            evils, which afflict humanity and perplex the doctors. Let every young person take
                            particular notice of how they breathe, as well as what they breathe, and most of them will
                            find themselves quite deficient in the effort and the art. All may improve with a little
                            thought and a great deal of exertion. In the course of one year, by regular practice, good
                            results may be wrought, the effects of which will be a general improvement of health. Mount
                            Lebanon N. Y.. </p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Freeman's faith" TEIform="index"/>FREEMAN'S FAITH</head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Barnstable, May 10, 1879" TEIform="index"/></dateline><p TEIform="p">A TOUCHING LETTER FROM HIS WIFE DESCRIBES THE FATAL FANATICISM WHICH MADE HIM SLAY HIS CHILD
                            — A DELUSIVE EXPECTATION OF MIRACLE. [From the N. Y. Herald.] <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Natick, Mass., May 17, 1879. The following letter has been received by a
                                    sister-in-law of Mrs. Freeman since the latter went to jail, which shows that she
                                    believed as implicitly in God's command for the sacrifice of the child as the father
                                    did : implicitly in God's command for the sacrifice of the child as the father did :
                                    Barnstable, May 10, 1879. Dear Sisters—We have received your letters. I had looked
                                    for one for a long time. I never thought it would find us here. Am glad to know you
                                    are well. We are in need of nothing, but we thank you for your kind thoughts for our
                                    comfort. I have no doubt you suffer for us. I cannot tell you how it all came to be.
                                    You know how dearly we both loved our precious little one. We have tried for more
                                    than a year to live entirely devoted to God and to the good of others. We had given
                                    up dress, the desire for money, and every thing that was not pure in purpose. You
                                    would hardly have believed it was Charlie. He never was profane ; had not drank
                                    since I knew him, and was one of the best of husbands and fathers. A LIFE OF PRAYER.
                                    But now he commenced a life of prayer and faith in God, and I with him. He read his
                                    bible every spare moment, and his whole life was spent in Christian, earnest work
                                    for good ; and his whole aim, not neglecting other duties, was to win souls to
                                    Christ and seek himself eternal life. One trial of our faith came after another, and
                                    God blessed us very much the more we trusted him. By and by there came a week and
                                    more of great <pb n="147" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. and new trials. Charlie
                                    did not sleep, nor eat scarcely, for nearly two weeks. A TRIAL OF FAITH. During this
                                    time of painful trial he felt that God required him to have the faith of Abraham.
                                    You know what that was in regard to Isaac. He could not get away from it. The more
                                    he tried the more it came home to him. At last he said to the Lord he would be
                                    willing to bear the test. He thought that would be all that God would ask. That
                                    seemed to end it for the day. That night it came to him more powerfully. He could
                                    not help it. Oh ! God alone knows how I suffered ; but having such great faith in
                                    God to believe He would stop him just as He did Abraham—that it was only a trial of
                                    faith—knowing, as I did. Charlie's life and love, his fear to disobey God, and that
                                    he had Abraham's faith, I could not hinder him. But neither of us thought God would
                                    suffer her to be touched any more than that the day would fail to come. A MIRACLE
                                    EXPECTED. We thought God would see our faith and give us some token of acceptance.
                                    We believed God would thunder from Sinai before any harm should come to our darling.
                                    But when I found my precious Edie gone, oh, Father how I felt! But comfort seemed to
                                    come again. Abraham believed God would raise Isaac, and so we felt that it was God's
                                    plan to take her so as to raise her from the dead and thus show his mighty power and
                                    love. We did believe He would do this in order to show the world that the God of
                                    Abraham, of Isaac and of Jacob still lives, and so wake up the frozen Church of God
                                    to its duties, the church so married to the world that there is scarcely any
                                    difference between the two. We believed this to be and that Edie would yet go with
                                    Charlie to preach the gospel of the kingdom. What a power she would be ; what glory
                                    to His cause! Elijah, Elisha, Christ and the Apostles raised the dead, and why
                                    should not God do it now as then ? We believed He would. But the time has so far
                                    passed and we are here. A CLAIM OF INNOCENCE. God knows we are innocent of any
                                    crime. Charlie still thinks God is going to manifest His power and glory and himself
                                    be justified in the eyes of the world. God grant it may be so ! Oh, you cannot know
                                    my sorrow ! It almost breaks my heart. My dear, dear Edie ! Charlie is innocent. Oh,
                                    he is of any crime, but I am afraid it was of mistaken faith in God. Dear Lord! help
                                    us in our need. HATTIE</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New York herald" TEIform="index"/>N. Y. Herald</bibl></cit></p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hattie" TEIform="persName">HATTIE</persName></byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="World a stage, the Shakers the spectators" TEIform="index"/>THE WORLD A STAGE, THE SHAKERS
                            THE SPECTATORS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>Elder Evans</byline><p TEIform="p"> Critical Comments on the Above. That is the way we view it. The passing panorama of national
                            and political events and the ever shifting scenes in the mental and spiritual atmosphere of
                            humanity are, to us, matters of intense interest. Abstract ideas are of immense importance
                            to a people. If "as a man thinketh, so is he,1' will not a nation's practical life, sooner
                            or later, be the exponent — the outcome — of its abstract ideas? A short time ago Hell was
                            enacted on the world's stage. The getting up was elaborate, the scenes grand, the acting
                            exciting to the last degree. The characters were editors, priests, lawyers, with pope,
                            cardinals and the holy inquisition in the background. God is logical and so are his
                            ministers. As Mary of England remarked when rebuked for her religious zeal in torturing
                            heretics, " Is it any more cruel for me to subject the mortal body to exquisite pain for a
                            short time, than it will be for God to cast their souls into hell-fire for an endless
                            eternity. I afflict them temporarily to cause repentance by which they may be saved from
                            afflictions infinite in extent and infinite in duration." Is not that logical, and is it not
                            the basis of all religious persecution ? Prom the abstract idea that God punishes sinners in
                            doing like Him, they think they do both God and humanity good service. Thus are their tender
                            mercies cruel. Should people who have been exhausting resources of theology and science to
                            raise the devil — incarnate him — make a great ado over him when they have been successful ?
                            147 <pb n="148" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 148 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. In people, who believe the God of the
                            Hebrews was the Deity, the foundation is laid, the seed is sown for all that flows logically
                            from that premise. Is it not the very essence of religion to make them worshipers like their
                            God ? Did Freeman do any more than any orthodox would do; were they not made-believers, but
                            genuine believers, like Miller, Moody and Freeman? Awake to righteousness and sin not. If
                            the God of Abraham was the Deity, and he had a right to do what we know was absolutely wrong
                            — order Abraham to sacrifice Isaac, and then substitute a lamb for him—why could he not
                            order Freeman to sacrifice his five-year old child to him ? The clergy have been teaching
                            Freeman, all his life, that all dead bodies can and will be raised to life again — why
                            should he not believe them ? They have been teaching him the doctrine of human sacrifice as
                            lying at the very foundation of Christianity. He believed and acted upon the belief—If God
                            killed his own and only begotten Son, why should not Freeman kill his daughter ? The wild
                            fowl come home to roost! 0, consistency, art thou not a jewel!! Did not the God of Abraham
                            order his descendants to sacrifice unto him whole nations of living, breathing, human
                            beings, and then curse them for letting their humanity overcome their theology ? Would
                            Comstock, as agent of Orthodoxy, shrink from the consequences of logical deduction from his
                            premises ? Is not society resting quietly on a bed of Orthodox dynamite ? A little more
                            concussion than Kiddle's book is creating, and some bolder man than Moody or Comstock will
                            rise up, and declare that the eternal salvation of one human soul from eternal hell is of
                            more importance than the freedom of person, press and conscience, in all the States of our
                            Union ! Crush out the 'Truth Seeker," imprison Bennett,ostracize Kiddle, and we shall have
                            the peace of Warsaw — the calm quiet (if the vaults are deep enough and the walls are thick
                            enough to deaden the cries and groans, and absorb the blood of the victims,) of the " Holy
                            Inquisition ! ! " We have got the Tombs now. There is no peace for the wicked, nor for those
                            who believe in wicked principles. There is, to-day, no safety to any man nor woman in
                            America, but in eternal vigilance and eternal truth and j ustice. If all of human beings
                            born, or to be born, could not be saved except by murder — the murder of their own Creator —
                            if the atoning blood of innocence must be shed for the wicked, I would take my fate into my
                            own hands and denounce the whole system of Orthodox theology, with all its wars, fightings
                            and blood-sheddings, whether for food or fury — its physical resurrection, land monopoly,
                            chattel and wages slavery, including sex slavery — its horrible assumption of power over
                            human belief, or unbelief. Let all parties unite to carry out the American idea of a purely
                            secular government that shall protect each man and woman in the pursuit of happiness, so
                            long as each assumes no unjust powers over other men and women. Let each be his or her own
                            standard of Orthodoxy. Secure to the Atheist the same rights as to the Trinitarian, Deist or
                            Polytheist, and let the play go on — the Shakers are the spectators.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Return of 'the wanderer'" TEIform="index"/>RETURN OF THE WANDERER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Andrews, Watson" TEIform="persName"/>WATSON ANDREWS&gt;</byline><p TEIform="p"> (See May No.) I returned to the home of my fathers, When age and experience were mine ; When
                            sin. and its consequent sorrow, Had banished me from the Divine : When light was a pain to
                            the vision, And melody only a din ; When taste, had been sated with pleasure, And feeling,
                            been poisoned by sin. When odors, were shorn of their nectar, And health coursed but feebly
                            each vein; When, the world behind me, a phantom, I cared not for ocean, nor plain. When Fear
                            pointed out to the future, And Regret brooded over the past, When Disease moaned the pains
                            of the present, — The tares and the tears reaped at last— Then I turned from the ways of my
                            wandering — I turned from the sins of my youth — And sought in the pool of repentance, The
                            gospel of Christ, in its truth. I found in " the valley of Achor," The door of the soul's
                            only hope — Relief from the load of the sinner, The darkness wherein he must grope. The
                            light beamed again on my vision, <pb n="149" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. 149 And life
                            coursed anew every vein ; The light and the life of the Spirit, Found alone on the heavenly
                            plain. Then Purity called me her brother ; And Wisdom appointed my way ; And Hope smiling
                            looked to the future, And Fear fled, defeated, away. Then Justice appeared with her balance
                            ; And Habit preferred her demands ; And Doubt plead her case, and her sister — Despondency—
                            folded her hands. Then Faith, volunteered for the rescue ; And Truth, brought her logic to
                            bear ; And Will, stood opposed to temptation And Confidence, banished Despair. Now, freed
                            from the slavery of passion, And cleansed from the virus of wrong, I dwell in a region of
                            gladness, The home of a purified throng. Remote from the halls of the mighty, Remote from
                            the dungeons of crime, In a life all unknown to the millions Whose joys, depend not upon
                            Time. They soar as the flight of the eagle, As free as the wind o'er the wave, In a
                            spiritual joy and gladness, That, knows neither death nor the grave. And here, as the
                            seasons pass o'er me, With light ever beaming anew, I feel, ever nearer and nearer,
                            Approaching, the pure and the true. Each day has its discipline for me, Some new, pleasing
                            lesson to give, Thus duty is found to be pleasure — The pleasure of learning to live — Thus
                            upward and onward forever The soul in its infinite way, Has still an eternal to-morrow, For
                            righting the wrongs of to-day. Thus life becomes joyous endeavor, And Time and Eternity one
                            ; The soul cries, in transports of gladness, Thy will, oh, my Parents, is done. Thy gospel
                            is preached to the nations, Thy peace is established on Earth ; And souls are made heirs of
                            salvation, Joint heirs, in the holy, new birth. North Union, 0.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Saviours" TEIform="index"/>SAVIOURS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/>ANTOINETTE DOOLITTLE</byline><p TEIform="p">" Saviours," heavenly-minded just men and women—" shall come up on Mount Zion to judge "
                            unrighteous men and women in the earthly order—" The Mt. of Esau." Thus said an inspired
                            prophet of olden time. There have been many schools of learning established with able
                            mentors; also inspired evangelists raised up from time to time, but not many saviours.
                            Prophets, al] through the gone by ages, when using their spiritual telescopes, saw many
                            beautiful and marvelous things that would come to pass, or be revealed in the fullness of
                            time. Optically viewed, those marked events were brought very near, almost within the grasp.
                            They saw a coming Messiah—a deliverer. Believers in prophecies were hopeful and expectant,
                            and looked for a helper to come speedily. After waiting long, and the vision still tarried,
                            and not understanding that a thousand years with the Lord is as one day, they became weary
                            with waiting and impatient of delay. The prophets and patriarchal leaders passed away from
                            mortal sight, and the cry arose among the remaining," Where is the promise of his coming?
                            For since the fathers fell asleep, all things continue as they were." Every age has its
                            prophets and prophetesses who foretell future events, some true, and some false ; but
                            comparatively few are endowed with the gift of true discernment, to know how to divide
                            between the two, and place each where they justly belong. If all modern prophecies were
                            collated and bound in one book, what a stupendous volume it would make, and who would be
                            able to decipher it ? Babylon would be its proper name. Yet by it, new avenues of thought
                            are opened, new life impulses are given. But thousands are still crying for the real bread
                            of life—soul sustenance which they cannot reach. What is the matter 1 Ah ! truly we have
                            many teachers, many learned theologians and prophets, but not many self-denying workers like
                            Jesus and Ann who are willing to take the same cross which they bore, and be baptized with
                            the same soul-saving, uplifting powers that enabled them to become saviours to other souls,
                            as well as teachers. There is a marked difference between those who stand to point the way
                            and they who lead the way. The former may be prophets but the latter may be both saviours
                            and prophets. Our most urgent need at the present time is practical workers, who will not
                            only say, but do—co-operate with redemptive agencies that are at work—and hasten the coming
                            of more saviours, who will be lifted up from <pb n="150" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 150 THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. the low plane of selfish loves and desires, and draw many other souls unto them.
                            Unto such the coming of the Lord will not be, nor seem to be afar off; they feel that His
                            promises are sure ; their fulfillment certain in His own good time. The unregenerate human
                            heart is prone to forget God, to distrust His faithfulness in regard to pledges given, and
                            while waiting for their accomplishment, to wander after strange gods, and hew to themselves
                            cisterns that cannot hold the waters of life. But in the sequel they find it true that
                            without the guidance and preserving influences of higher intelligences, " All flesh is as
                            the grass that vvithereth, and the flower that fadeth." The Psalmist said " I have seen the
                            wicked in greater power, and spreading himself like a green bay tree; yet he passed away and
                            could not be found. But I have not seen the righteous forsaken nor his seed beggingbread.
                            The inheritance of the upright shall be his forever." Blessed are they who keep the gospel
                            testimony through the sunshine and the storm ; they are more precious than fine gold, and
                            will be numbered with priceless jewels in the heavenly kingdom. Their end on earth is peace,
                            and joyful will be the welcome to their home in heaven.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beautiful things" TEIform="index"/>BEAUTIFUL THINGS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Horton, Lewis" TEIform="persName"/>LEWIS HORTON</byline><p TEIform="p"> Beautiful words are blossoms and flowers, That grow in the gardens of God ; While mercy and
                            love, in beautiful showers Make blooming the paths we have trod. Beautiful thoughts ennoble
                            the mind, And make our lives pleasant and bright; Gems of the soul are jewels we find In the
                            paths of spiritual light. Beautiful deeds bring happiness here, And cheer the sad heart on
                            its way ; Tho' but a smile, a glance, or a tear, They lead to an eternal day. Beautiful
                            souls are the bright and the pure, The kind, the loving, and true ; White-robed they will
                            be, where treasures endure. When earth and the heavens are new. Beautiful lives—in the
                            angelic sphere— Which bedeck fair memory's hall, With beautiful scenes from every thing
                            dear, In Him who reigns over all. Enfield, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Blessings" TEIform="index"/>BLESSINGS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, Catharine" TEIform="persName"/>CATHARINE ALLEN</byline><p TEIform="p"> God scatters blessings with a liberal hand, And those who seek his gifts thro' sacrifice Of
                            selfish loves, and all their worthless gain, Will find that angels bring them in disguise.
                            Then forms which through the mists of morning grey Appeared like crosses, heavy to be borne
                            Up duty's rugged path, will melt away, And change their guise beneath the rising" sun Of
                            cheerfulness, and self-forsaking love. And then, like stars whose glory brighter glows, As
                            shades of evening deepen in the sky, They'll gather lustre as the day declines, Till gems of
                            peace and purity are formed, To place within the temple memory rears. And these with time,
                            will not grow old and dim ; The gifts that God bestows increase their worth. 'Tis thus that
                            he awardeth recompense To souls who offer, while in seed or bud, Those pleasures false whose
                            blossoms fade so soon, Then quickly yield the fruit of bitterness. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ideal and real" TEIform="index"/>IDEAL AND REAL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Collins, Elva F." TEIform="persName"/>ELVA F. COLLINS</byline><p TEIform="p"> Too many in this day of fictitious literature, sham, policies, theologies, and spurious
                            imitations of genuine thought, religion and truth from cultivated, or inherent abnormal
                            cravings, and tastes—tend to soar away on airy clouds, fabricated or imaginary poetry,
                            sentimental music, fanciful and romantic reading, or exhibit the fast and changeable
                            disposition of the age, in the choice and manufacture of gay flimsy apparel that has neither
                            substance nor durability. That this is the drift of the populace, as well as the higher
                            classes is generally admitted, even by those engaged in the same, who acknowledge themselves
                            bound one by another in conformity to fashion. To certain classes the fleecy cloud sailing
                            in azure sky, the crystal dewdrop on the flower, or blade reflecting the dazzle of the sun,
                            or the blended hues of the pearly sea shell—and hundreds of other beauties in nature—create
                            in the mind a spell of en- <pb n="151" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 151 chantment;
                            causing a vague longing for something that is ever beyond the grasp, a dreamy 3*earniug' to
                            be a cloud, a bird, a dewdrop, or any thing other than a human being destined to the
                            struggles, disappointed hopes, fleeting joys and lingering sorrows of life, founded more
                            upon ideality than reality. To another class all the beautiful features of creation impress
                            the mind with the sublimity of their creator, whose grander and nobler handiwork these but
                            symbolize. Thus it is in all science andart,umusicand literature, theory and practice ; the
                            choice or acceptance of either, indicates the character of a person. Music is possessed of a
                            language, deeper than words can express ! The operatic, sentimental, martial, profane, or
                            vulgar, pensive or funereal, or the harmonious strains of praise, worship, thanksgiving,
                            religious or ecstatic, all find their fountains in the hearts of the varied characters,
                            combined in the human family, having power over the listener to exalt or debase, and a
                            corresponding application may be made to every toil or pleasure pursued by mankind. False
                            airs and superficialness in society are disgusting to those seeking friendship that has
                            warmth of soul, and fidelity of purpose ; or a social relationship with those whose honest
                            aims would lead them to benefit others, by sowing such seed by the wayside as they would joy
                            to see harvested by other hands when they scan earth with immortal eyes. But how many float
                            upon the surface of popular opinion, hoping to conceal from public view the sandy foundation
                            upon which their house rests ; and which must crumble away in remorse and chagrin when the
                            tempest of. retributive justice sweeps over them with its rude blast. The infinitude of
                            God's provisions for our happiness may not all be counted among the more attractive pursuits
                            of the intellectual mind, the fruit of all hand labor is the true service of God. The
                            restless distaste in any one for a continued routine of monotonous employ proves that we
                            were designed to have all our faculties brought into use, which should develop the soul for
                            the future, and the body for use while in time. Let the student's or musician's weary brain,
                            the sculptor's, artist's, or penman's hand, and all engaged in the multifarious occupations
                            that strain mental, and nerve tissue, be relieved by an intermission of hearty, physical
                            labor, and both will be better appreciated by the performer. While we render thanks for
                            every good gift shared in its turn, may we not pray in earnest for the day to hasten when
                            the false and fictitious, leading so many over the road of foolish search for the unreal,
                            will teach all that nothing will abide but the real labor of charity and benevolence
                            bestowed on the needy ? To shrink from the practical duties of life does not sweeten the
                            enjoyment of pastime pleasures. Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Invocation to purity" TEIform="index"/>INVOCATION TO PURITY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cornell, Jane" TEIform="persName"/>JANE CORNELL</byline><p TEIform="p"> O heaven-born spirit on whose radiant brow, The impress of Gfod's very nature rests ; From
                            whose clear eyes shines forth a holy light From which the demon vice draws back abashed ;
                            Whose presence brings an atmosphere of heaven. To thee I longing, pleading cry, For thee my
                            spirit yearneth ; To thee my whole heart turneth ; With answering grace draw nigh. Spirit of
                            purity within my heart, Sacred to thee an altar wiJl I rear ; Where daily, willing sacrifice
                            I make, Of passions that rebel against thy sway, And human loves that turn the heart from
                            thee. And when before this shrine I bend, And up to thy bright spheres, Incense of prayers
                            and tears From the soul's censor swung, ascend, Oh spirit come ! Accept the sacrifice,
                            Consume the offering with celestial fire ; And with thy cleansing power my soul baptize,
                            Free me from carnal passion's cruel strife; And from the wily tempter's snare, Purge me from
                            stains of earth; And for the heavenly birth, My struggling, suppliant soul prepare. Shakers,
                            N. Y.</p></div2><pb n="152" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Catholicism" TEIform="index"/>CATHOLICISM</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Eads, H. L." TEIform="persName"/>H. L. Eads</byline><p TEIform="p">[A Roman Catholic priest, taking umbrage at the positions maintained in a recent sermon by
                            Elder H. L. Eads, the Elder writes the following rejoinder to the Louisville
                            Courier-Journal. It is easy to know from this reply the objections made by the Catholic. Ed.
                            S. M.]</p><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I see by your last Saturday's paper that a Catholic is after Eads but..." TEIform="index"/>I see by your last Saturday's paper that a Catholic is after Eads but...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">I see by your last Saturday's paper that a Catholic is after Eads. but, like Burns'
                                de'il, " he comes incog." Such hardly deserve respectful notice. They are like the
                                savage, who, fearing to meet his antagonist, prefers to fight with his own carcass
                                behind a tree. But, as there is a serious vein running through his review, I will make
                                an effort to find him. His first charge is that Eads ''does not state the Catholic
                                doctrine, but quite the contrary." He should have added the words, " as I understand
                                it." It would take a brain of greater caliber than either his or mine to state the
                                doctrine as all understand it. He cites me to Epiphaneus and others, with whom I am
                                somewhat familiar. It is a little singular, however, that he should especially name
                                Epiphaneus, as he was one of the first to throw cold water on the " heavenly mystery "
                                so strongly and feelingly contended for. In the earliest days of the Judaizing
                                Christians, they believed that among the score of gospels that were written the Hebrew
                                text of St. Matthew was the most authentic and reliable account of the doings and
                                sayings of Jesus and His apostles. Of this, Epiphaneus says, it did not contain the two
                                first chapters that were afterward found in the Greek copy concerning the miraculous
                                conception and slaughter of infants in Bethlehem, but that it, the Hebrew copy, began at
                                Jesus' baptism, at which point the oldest of the Greek copies now extant also begins.
                                This plainly shows that this story was an after interpolation in St. Matthew's gospel,
                                put into the Greek copy for the purpose of proselyting the Gentiles. No one can read
                                carefully the history of the Church without realizing the fact that it blows both hot
                                and cold to suit conditions. In fact, one of the chapters in the Fathers' writings is
                                headed: "How Par We May be Justified in Lying for the Benefit of the Church." I brought
                                no charges against the Fathers, but against the present generation. Still there is
                                enough at- hand against them to damn a nation. The most senseless wranglings, strifes,
                                contentions, as it were, about nothing ; cruel and bloody wars among themselves, even
                                drenching in blood the sepulcher of Christ on account of a little difference of opinion
                                about two natures in him, venting the most relentless fury upon others; racks, tortures,
                                dungeons, fagots and flames, all _ie at the door of the Church unatoned for, and even
                                to-day we have evidence of latent fire beneath her smouldering embers. But I am happy to
                                say there has been great improvement upon old conditions. But 'tis best sometimes to
                                look back at the " hole of the pit from whence we were digged," lest we become too
                                proud. My reviewer speaks gravely of the " heavenly mystery accomplished in Mary." If it
                                was heavenly why had she to go to the priest, confess and offer up her little turtle
                                doves ? But of miracles I feel a leaning toward a certain French writer (M. Littre), who
                                says : "An experience which nothing has ever occurred to contradict has taught that
                                every miraculous story had its origin in vivid imagination, in complaisant credulity, in
                                ignorance of natural laws. With all the research that has been made, no miracle has ever
                                been wrought where it could be proved." But this of Mary, I think, was design, and might
                                come under the head of " lying for the benefit of ttie church." Now, a heavenly thing
                                needs neither mystery, confession nor sacrifice. There is a way in which every thing is
                                done, and when that is learned the mystery ceases. But there is no mystery attending the
                                manner in which Mary conceived, heavenly or otherwise. One would find it much more
                                difficult to state precisely how a prestidigatator could get a good sized potato in his
                                nose and take it out again in the presence of many witnesses than it would be to tell
                                how Mary conceived. I have yet to learn what benefit a mystery can be to any one. I am
                                somewhat familiar with my reviewer's quotations, which are correct, and he is right in
                                saying volumes could be filled with quotations, and he might have added that many
                                contradictions could also be found. But as he gives me a friendly caution not to bear
                                false witness against my neighbor, it becomes my duty either to substantiate or withdraw
                                my charges. In doing this I must take my reviewer back to the first thing that had the
                                tendency to fasten the quadruple god-head in my mind. It seems that the head of the
                                Church, Pope Pio Nino, nearly a quarter of a century ago, had some misgivings about the
                                possibility of Christ being immaculate, while his mother was tainted ; and, from the
                                conclusion to which he arrived he must have reasoned after the following manner :
                                First—An immaculate being could not come from a maculate mother. Second—But Jesus was
                                immaculate. Third—Mary was the mother of Jesus. Ergo, Mary was immaculate. Thinking the
                                logic sound and irrefutable he summoned a council at Rome to ratify it. Had Pope Pius
                                only taken the second thought, and the true one, that it was possible for the maculate
                                to become immaculate, he might have been saved all the trouble and expense of the
                                assembling of that council, <pb n="153" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 153 and have
                                kept truth on his side. But it was ratified, the Papal bull issued, and all who would
                                not acknowledge it were accounted heretics. But he failed to tell us how Mary came to be
                                immaculate and free from taint. His bull did not make her so. He seemed not to know that
                                it would have been just as easy to have declared Jesus to be free from taint, while Mary
                                was not, as to declare Mary to be free while her parents were not. If a little taint in
                                Mary would have tainted Jesus, a little taint in Mary's parents would have tainted her,
                                the bull to the contrary notwithstanding. So the Pope's declaration was as unnecessary
                                as it was untrue. A lie believed by the whole world does not make it truth. But the
                                whole Catholic Church, with a few honorable exceptions, raised the right hand and said
                                true ! true! 0 holy Father! So the Church has one more lie to defend than it had before.
                                Why did not some of the famous councils think of this ruse to get Mary free from taint
                                Cakya Mouni, a great reformer, whose existence is not doubted, is said to have come into
                                theworld without taint. Could Mary have been traced to him, the announcement of her
                                purity would not have been surprising. The " heavenly mystery" attending his entrance
                                into the world is thus stated: "He was conceived without stain, born painlessly at the
                                foot of a tree—welcomed at his birth by holy personages—was tempted by the
                                devil—surrounded himself with disciples, and performed miracles without number," etc. I
                                cannot prove it, but I have little doubt but what the two added chapters containing the
                                " heavenly mystery " had their origin here. It was a marvel to me at the time of Pio's
                                council, while he was stealthily getting Mary into the God-head, that even my good and.
                                intelligent friend, Bishop Purcell, of Cincinnati, could not see that Mary could no more
                                be free from taint while her parents were tainted than that Jesus could be free while
                                Mary was tainted. The declaration of the Pope aforesaid, that she was free, did not make
                                her so. Thus my good reviewing Catholic, the Pope lied, and you are compelled to say you
                                believe the lie, on pain of being counted heretical, if not of being excommunicated.
                                Although the Pope did not issue a papal bull declarative of the fact, still this was
                                equal to such declaration, as she was made immaculate and equal with the Son ; and why
                                not, since she was the mother of God ? The mother of God certainly has a right to be one
                                of the God family ; and Pio Nino had with his council as much right to install Mary as
                                the Nicene Council had to install the Son, or that of Constantinople had to include the
                                Holy Ghost. But I have evidence from the very hot-bed of the Church corroborating the
                                view I took of the matter John Ernest Renan, a born Catholic, and an able and truthful
                                defender, says in his Relig. Hist, and Criticism, page 223 : '" St. Peter, a fisherman
                                of Galilee, has ruled the world for a thousand years ; Mary, a humble woman of Nazareth,
                                has ascended through successive and continually enhancing hyperbole of generations till
                                she also reached the bosom of the Trinity! Nevertheless, we say it boldly, it is never
                                chance that singles out an individual to be idealized." And further, pp. 334 and 335 : "
                                On what has the meditation of Christian piety, the imagination of enthusiasts, preferred
                                to exercise itself V Is it on the Trinity, on the Holy Spirit, on the controversial
                                dogmas which are received as sealed formulas ? No ; it is on the little child, Santo
                                Bambino^ in his manger. * * It is on Mary. Mary has sufficed to satisfy the craving for
                                love in ten centuries of ascetics ; Mary has entered by full title into the Trinity.
                                (Italics mine.) She far excels that third forgotten person, the Holy Spirit, with
                                neither lovers nor adorers. She completes the divine family,for it would have been a
                                marvel if the feminine element, in its triumph, had not succeeded in reaching even the
                                bosom of God, and between the Father and Son introducing the mother." Thus making Mary
                                the wife of God No. 1, and the Holy Spirit the wife of God No. 2, all in keeping with
                                the lower-floor church practices. If the councils of Nice and Constantinople had only
                                had Pio there to introduce Mary, it would have prevented weeks of squabbling about the
                                sex of the Holy Spirit and whose wife she should be. They had no alternative but to
                                change her to the masculine gender. Now they can give back her gender, as God No. 1 is
                                supplied. But Renan goes further. He says : " By its varied mysteries, and especially by
                                its worship of the Virgin and the saints, Catholicism meets the need of outward
                                demonstration and of plastic art which is so strong in the south of Europe." (R. Hist.,
                                p. 316.) I would now ask whom should I believe—one without a name who denies the Godship
                                of Mary and the worship of the saints, or a man of uncommon ability, who publishes a
                                book and gives his name to the world and risks his honor for veracity and truth. On
                                which side does the greatest amount of evidence lie ? Who now is the false witness ? I
                                plead justification for my declaration on the grounds above stated. Nay, my good
                                Catholic, acknowledge your mistake or give us your name. I can but admire the ingenuity
                                of Pope Pio, even though it detract from his truthfulness. I cannot think it possible
                                that so enlightened and able a writer as Renan, and one so well posted in Catholicism,
                                can be mistaken. He could have no cause to misrepresent anything he seemed to love so
                                well, and since he is so open and above-board, I am bound to believe he has told us the
                                truth. My reviewer says he <pb n="154" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 154 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. " fails to
                                see wherein it concerns the ' lowerfloor churches'—the question of two infinite beings."
                                It should have occurred to him that the question was intended only for those who
                                differed from him in not believing that God made the devil, but that he was a
                                selfexistence independent of God. Their name is legion who so believe both in and out of
                                his Church. The postulate of my friend that God had created Spirit Angels in the spirit
                                world previous to the formation of this, who turned into devils and whose captain
                                through his wiles (by the assistance of a snake), accomplished the fall of Adam and Eve,
                                stands greatly in need of proof. If the devil and his angels could not have accomplished
                                it without the assistance of a snake three, six or twenty feet long, the whole host of
                                them are not very dangerous. I must, before closing, return my thanks to " Catholic "
                                for his suggestion to consult those two primers and the children's catechism in order to
                                become fully posted in regard to the faith and belief of the Church, so that I may not
                                hereafter be liable to the charge of bearingfalse witness against my neighbor.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Philosophy of Shakerism" TEIform="index"/>PHILOSOPHY OF SHAKERISM</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Overton, C. M." TEIform="persName"/>C. M. OVERTON</byline><p TEIform="p"> Social life is a subject of social law, and social law is as rigid and unbending as physical
                            law. So a true life in society becomes a thing of science. The first mandate of social law
                            is: be just. That is, do only that which you have a clear right to do. What has one a right
                            to do ? Any thing he can do in his own sphere, " at his own cost." God made man free, and
                            does not interfere with his volition. Man in America follows up the idea, granting certain
                            rights as " inalienable" to the individual. Within this sphere of inalienable right, man may
                            do as he pleases, being sole judge of the right and wrong of his own actions. Getting out of
                            that sphere, his sovereignty ceases. He is a trespasser on the sphere of another, and must
                            stop. He must go back to his own territory and repair all damages caused by liis raid on his
                            neighbor. These principles are basic ; lying at the foundation of a true, social order. Let
                            us apply them in one direction, that of sex, and see where they will lead us. Men and women
                            who have not violated this law of social justice in their sexual deportment, are free, in "
                            the pursuit of happiness," to marry, carrying with them into the new relations these
                            principles, the first of which is, " Be j list." How ? Act at your own cost. How ? Keep in
                            your own sphere, till invited out of it. Every woman has aright to chalk a line about her
                            personality into which no man has a right to pass unbidden. But you say she has invited you
                            by the very fact of marriage. She has invited you to come nearer than others ; perhaps, to
                            come within the sacred circle marked out. But has she invited you to stay there forever?
                            Nay, the wife who understands herself makes no such invitation. You are on a visit. You
                            cannot tell how much that visit may have "' cost " your hostess already. You cannot tell
                            whether your presence will ever again prove desirable. If you wish to be a gentleman and
                            observe the law of social justice you will take a Shaker distance and keep it till you are
                            again invited to come nearer. The right to be a celibate is an individual right, which
                            either party in marriage may at any time claim ; but all other obligations remain the same.
                            Marriage is a community of interests ; and when either partner takes a celibate position it
                            becomes a community of celibates with the same interests and obligations as before. There is
                            thus one, and only one legitimate divorce, into a celibate community— the continuance of the
                            family, or the merging of the single family into a compound family which takes up and
                            carries on all private family obligations. All second marriages involving disintegration —
                            the abandonment of partner and children—are 'fraudulent and void. Yet society is to-day
                            almost disbanded through the inroads of that infinite swindle — modern divorce. But perhaps
                            even this unblushing fraud is preferable to the abominations of marriage—a system in which
                            woman has no rights which a husband is bound to respect. We are by this time prepared to see
                            something of the philosophy of the Shaker system — that it is not a mere whim, nor caprice,
                            fanaticism, nor asceticism — an unrelated excrescence on the social structure ; but that it
                            bears a definite relation to, and enters as a dominant feature into the very heart of
                            existing society. If science held sway ; if <pb n="155" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 155
                            justice bore rule ; if courtesy were observed ; if women were not slaves, appendages ;
                            things ; how many husbands could to-day be any thing but Shakers 1 If the marriage of Christ
                            as it was " in the beginning " prevailed, instead of that of the lawyers— how many families
                            but would be Shaker families 1 Placing Shaker claims on no higher grounds than human rights,
                            simply justice; we yet say that the paucity of numbers among believers is a most startling
                            commentary on the moral status of society. That scarcity is due to the fact that justice,
                            courtesy, decency, even, is everywhere ignored, and the dearest of human rights, the most
                            sacred of womanly instincts, trodden under foot of men. It is proof that our science is a
                            sham, our religion a farce, our refinement and culture the shallowest veneering, and the
                            very word civilization the most stinging and bitter sarcasm that a being of any attainment
                            indecency could fling at the boors and barbarians that go to make Up " society." North
                            Union, 0.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cross, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>THE CROSS, NO 2</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName"/>WM, H. BUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p">That which we call life is of various grades, from the lowest to the highest, from the
                            grossest to the most refined. It is so in human beings as well as in other forms of life.
                            The classification made by the modern psychologist is quite different from that which Jesus
                            and the apostles used. These made the broad distinction of carnal and spiritual, or,
                            sometimes, of sensuous and spiritual, regarding them as the extremes of each other, the
                            former belonging to man's temporal, the latter to his eternal state. The sensuous man may
                            become depraved or " dead in trespasses and sins ; " the spiritual man alone has the
                            heavenly or eternal life within himself, and this in its perfection is the essential life of
                            the Infinite God. The word psychicos, in 1st Corinthians, II, 14, translated in our English
                            version, natural should have been rendered sensuous or sensual, as in James III, 15.
                            Whatever is produced in accordance with Divine law is natural, whether the sensuous,
                            intellectual, moral or spiritual conditions of living beings. Its opposite term is
                            unnatural. " The sensuous person," says Paul, " does not accept the things of the Spirit of
                            God, nor can lie discern them ; but the spiritual person discerns all." This accords with
                            the words of Jesus to Nicodemus : " That which is born of the flesh is flesh, and that which
                            is born of the Spirit is spirit; ye must be born from above another." The sensuous life in
                            all its grades is necessarily the lower, but the spiritual, the higher life. The language of
                            Jesus is highly figurative, yet not too strong for the actual truth he intended to convey to
                            the mind. Equally figurative is that used by him in the doctrine of the cross. The cross of
                            wood was designed for the execution of criminals ; that which Jesus meant when he said, " He
                            that taketh not his cross and followeth after me is not worthy of me," Matt. X, 38, was for
                            the purpose of putting an end to the carnal or sensuous life in the person, so that the
                            spiritual might take its place. Hence the propriety of the words— " He that loseth his
                            (carnal) life for my sake shall find it "—that is, the spiritual. Only the cross of Christ
                            is efficacious for attaining the spiritual life, that is, the very cross which Jesus himself
                            bore. The apostle Paul says of Christians, " Our old man has been crucified with his, that
                            the body of sin might be destroyed." Rom. VI, 6. " For, as to his dying, he died to sin
                            once." 10. This accords with the whole train of his reasoning, whether he makes use of
                            baptism as a figure, of planting and growth, or of death and burial. " So many of us as were
                            baptized into Jesus Christ were baptized into his death." " We have been planted together in
                            the likeness of his death, we shall be also in the likeness of his resurrection." "We are
                            heirs of God, heirs together with Christ, if we suffer with him, that we may be glorified
                            together." Bearing the same cross, then, that Jesus bore, constitutes discipleship to which
                            is annexed spiritual and eternal life, and not the mere belief that he suffered on the cross
                            of the malefactor to expiate the sins of others. Sonyea, N. Y..</p></div2><pb n="156" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakerism among the great lights" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERISM AMONG THE GREAT LIGHTS</head><p TEIform="p">[The following letter came from one of the best minds of this age. As a writer, lecturer,
                                and reasoner, he stands very prominent. The second letter of Bro. D. Frazer to him
                                explains itself. This correspondence shows the drift of human thought.—Ed. S. M.]</p><div4 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Daniel Frazer, Dear Sir : I have read with much pleasure and admiration the 'Divine Afflatus'..." TEIform="index"/>Daniel Frazer, Dear Sir : I have read with much pleasure and admiration the 'Divine Afflatus'...
                                </head><p TEIform="p">Daniel Frazer, Dear Sir : I have read with much pleasure and admiration the " Divine
                                    Afflatus ; " and by addressing Mr. John Whiteley learned your authorship of that
                                    remarkable pamphlet. As Shakerism appears to me one of the most successful of all
                                    attempts to realize the religion of Jesus Christ, I would be glad to see your plan
                                    more actively employed. The history of the Dual element of Shakerism appears to me
                                    (if correctly informed) very imperfectly elucidated as yet. I would also like to see
                                    it more distinctly set forth (if possible), that Shakers in adopting a life of
                                    celibacy as the highest ideal of religion do not condemn as necessarily wicked or
                                    impure the life of marriage pursued by sincere Christians. The assertion of
                                    necessary and inevitable sin, crime or impurity in marriage, is an attack upon the
                                    divine order or divine wisdom which places the parties in a false position. It is my
                                    impression that Shakers generally have fallen into that error, for which there seems
                                    to be no necessity, and which I am sure is not the sentiment of heaven. Yours
                                    cordially, </p><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, New York" TEIform="index"/>New York City</dateline><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., J. R." TEIform="persName"/>J. R. B.</byline></div4><div4 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reply" TEIform="index"/>Reply, Respected Professor...</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, D." TEIform="persName"/>D. Fraser</byline><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon, June 24, 1879" TEIform="index"/>Mount Lebanon, N. Y.,
                                    June 24, 1879</dateline><p TEIform="p">Respected Professor : Your kind favor came duly. One of the happy signs of the times
                                    is, that the life of our people ia being appreciated by yourself and by other
                                    leading minds. We have some reason to think that they are forming and leading public
                                    sentiment in the direction of a higher life than now commonly prevails. When such
                                    minds first feel the importance of, and bearings of the life we manifest, the
                                    exclamation is, " Why do we not make ourselves more known ? " We like that feeling
                                    and would rather encourage it. Our attitude to the propagative order is simply this
                                    : " That which is animal is first, and afterward that which is divine." Every thing
                                    in its order, but no mixing up, " lest the rents be made worse." For that degree of
                                    resurrection or "Evolution," out of the animal we have attained, and stand in the
                                    life and love thereof, is to us a rich treasure of many things. One of the
                                    outgrowths of the Divine life is property in common ; this springs up of itself ;
                                    does not need to be manufactured. And those who accept this life, even at the last
                                    hour, may be with all others equal possessors. Our example and teachings have done
                                    something, showing, as they do, that private property is not compatible with the
                                    Christ life. To buy and sell land, is to monopolize it ; and has done more to turn
                                    this world into a hell; to destroy the integrity of the propagative order; to induce
                                    prostitution, and to open the flood-gates of physical and moral maladies, than can
                                    be easily estimated. Of land, every person should have a share, subject to neither
                                    sale nor mortgage. I remember the case of a man who attended one of our meetings.
                                    After he came out he exclaimed : " How insignificant my property seems to me ! " Had
                                    he abode in this feeling, and engrafted it into his natural selfhood, the fruit
                                    would have been divine ; and in the process of " Evolution," would finally have
                                    superseded the whole growth of the animal man, even as a graft does a tree, if the
                                    sprouts are kept down. As long as the conventionalities of society run in the line
                                    they now do, in regard to land and usury, evolution will be slow, and the millions
                                    will remain wages—slaves, commodities ; glutting the markets of the world to their
                                    own destitution. To change this, to elevate the law, and smooth down the high, is to
                                    prepare the way for the advent of a divine humanity. The going forth of the Divine
                                    Afflatus, whether in one or many, is to us refreshing. But humanity as we find it,
                                    is so en- <pb n="157" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 157 grossed with its animal
                                    surroundings, that when there is a breathing forth, the animal in man absorbs it,
                                    and lie goes forth in the wilderness, preaching from spiritual illumination, without
                                    the divine life to sustain the teachings. The present time is prolific in such
                                    manifestations. A few months ago, a person visited us; he had read the " Afflatus,"
                                    and had been teaching of the light he stood in; but found he could not sustain
                                    himself, and came with the object of receiving strength to do so. Had he come and
                                    laid down all his procreative proclivities, and his desires for private property,
                                    and earnestly baptized himself with the divine element, and then waited till endowed
                                    with power to communicate in wisdom, good results might have followed without
                                    serious detriment to himself. The organic law, external form, and mode of procedure
                                    of our form of social life are manifestations of duality as established in the
                                    nature of things. No doubt this rich field will be entered upon by minds like your
                                    own, when gathered into that order of things which creates all things anew. I am
                                    pleased with the spirit of the inclosed printed matter. " To embody religion instead
                                    of theology; and the Divine Spirit instead of the human dogma ; " and of course to
                                    substitute the sentiment of universal love, for that of me and mine, is exactly what
                                    is needed. The so-called Churches of to-day are not the lineal descendants of the
                                    Pentecostal Church. The descendant of every organism has all the attributes of its
                                    predecessor. These churches have not property in common ; do not live virgin lives ;
                                    do not abstain from war; they hold or hire slaves of some kind ; are guilty of
                                    usurious practices and other financial abominations. They are not conscientious in
                                    the matter of obeying the teachings of hygienic law. Of their awful violations of
                                    procreative law, I would prefer not to defile this sheet by alluding to them. Again,
                                    with regard to the marriage order, our order—a virgin life—is its complement, and is
                                    one of the results of the unfolding of the germs of divine ' life in humanity.
                                    Hence, no antagonism exists between them. English writers on population on being
                                    reviewed by Nathan Allen, Mass., concluded from their conflicting theories, that the
                                    law of population had not yet been reached. We are led to presume that this
                                    important problem can only be solved by procreative and concurrent laws being kept ;
                                    then physical, mental, and spiritual elevation, will qualify tens of thousands to
                                    rise into, and finjoy that form of social life wherein " they neither marry nor are
                                    given in marriage." But if there is not an elevation above the propagative order,
                                    the same results will commonly take place, as lately occurred from famine in China.
                                    We foresaw and described just such a scene about ten years ago ; and have no
                                    hesitation in stating, that similar catastrophies are approaching, and in the near
                                    coming ages overwhelmingly so. Sincerely your friend,</p></div4></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New church movement" TEIform="index"/>THE NEW CHURCH MOVEMENT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, D." TEIform="persName"/>D. FRASER</byline><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon, June 17, 1879" TEIform="index"/>Mount Lebanon, Columbia
                                Co., N. Y., June 17, 1879.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Respected Professor — Yours, inclosing a beautiful hymn came to hand. The facts relative
                                to the history of the Pentecostal Church, as far as I can learn, are quite fragmentary.
                                It existed about two hundred years. No doubt, in preserving the integrity of a virgin
                                life, troubles had to be met. On a certain occasion, young widows were excluded, they "
                                waxing wanton" against one of the conditions of a divine life, " would marry." The rapid
                                spread of Christian ideas and sentiments amid persecutions utterly precluded the
                                possibility of gathering the numerous converts into the order of the Jewish Christian
                                Church. Hence arose the Gentile-outercourt Church; its descendants constituted the
                                present so-called Christian world. You have the honor to be seeking to introduce a
                                higher, social and governmental life than Gentile Christianity has ever been able to
                                afford. It is well to have a definite conception of what we wish to obtain, and how to
                                bring about the end in view. Before the mani- <pb n="158" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 158 THE SHAKER
                                MANIFESTO. festation of the divine life in Jesus Christ, there were but two paths for
                                humanity to walk in ; now, there are three : The first is, eat, irrespective of dietetic
                                law, propagate, irrespective of times and seasons, and of providential laws. Use
                                property and power to take advantage of the neighbor, irrespective of moral law and the
                                happiness of individuals, or of society. In short, act as now do the so-called Christian
                                world. Second path: Fulfill all moral, hygienic and providential laws. Eat and breathe,
                                so as never to be sick, nor to communicate disease. Propagate so that the children will
                                all come in genial weather. And when there is more population than can be cared for,
                                cease propagating. Dress for use, and not for fashion. Have you a farm ? Love your
                                neighbor as yourself, and help him to one. Is he shiftless? Be a father to him. The
                                third way is: Live as Jesus Christ did; bring forth a form of social life, wherein the
                                greatest are the servants; wherein there is neither rich nor poor; and where animal
                                emotions are superseded by those of angelic life. The em.otional forces to whicli woman
                                yields herself, and man sustains her in, determines the altitude of humanity. Ann Lee
                                would not give place to the emotions of her lower selfhood; and was sustained therein by
                                males correspondingly impressed. The result is a Virgin Church, having a civilization,
                                of its own. The destiny of this church is to fulfill all the requirements of divine law.
                                We are but in the morning of our day, yet by lowly, and unobtrusive instrumentalities, a
                                wonderful work has been done. Those whose eyes have -been opened to perceive the force
                                of divine, spiritual affinities, will know that the civilization of the heavens,
                                creating an angelic form of human, social life, has been with us. If it is your wish to
                                elevate society, and include the reproductive element, then the keystone of your social
                                arch will be the enfranchisement of woman. At present, as in the past, her desire is to
                                a husband, and, of course, he rules over her; and of necessity her conceptions are
                                increased, and consequently there are physical, and social troubles in abundance. But if
                                her preeminent desire is to fulfill procreative and auxiliary laws, as above indicated,
                                then a new era can be introduced. Man cannot then rule, both being subject to law. Then
                                use and the fitness of things, not lust, will be the rule. Freedom to change from one
                                man or woman to another, is not enfranchisement I am happy in being your friend,</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="For the intemperate—is this a truth?" TEIform="index"/>FOR THE INTEMPERATE—IS THIS A
                                TRUTH</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="C., S. F." TEIform="persName"/>S. F. C.</byline><p TEIform="p">Editor Manifesto: I was pleased to read Mr. Grosvenor's theory for the treatment of
                                inebriety published in the June edition of the Manifesto, but while I fully concur with
                                him in regard to the efficiency of moral suasion, and the benefits arising from
                                sympathetic reasoning with persons just entering the downward course, I have little
                                faith in the application of this doctrine to chronic cases of inebriety, and much less
                                when considered as a healing power for dipsomania. It would be just as reasonable to
                                expect a consumptive person to cease coughing or expectorating because he had made
                                promises to that effect. As well ask the wind to cease blowing, as to ask the
                                dipsomaniac to immediately abandon stimulants without being controlled and treated
                                medicinally, although medicine alone will never effect a cure. This language is strong,
                                but the experience of myself and others will bear me out in these assertions. Dr. Albert
                                Day, superintendent of the Washingtonian Home, 41 Waltham St., Boston, has treated
                                nearly 7,000 cases of inebriety, and is justly considered authority on the subject. From
                                his last annual report I make the following extract in support of my statements: " For
                                forty years I have been an observer and participant in the temperance reform in its
                                various periodical phases. It has sometimes taken on a political form, then a religious
                                tone ; but I can safely say that any movement to check drunkenness which does not
                                include entire physiological rest to each case, is devoid of all elements of success.
                                    <pb n="159" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 159 I am so confirmed in this view that
                                I do not hesitate to say that I know of no individual case of inebriety that has been
                                cured in any other way than from the basis indicated. The direct path to inebriety is a
                                pathological one, and when this point is reached the whole condition is one of disease.
                                Hence, the return to perfect sobriety must be physiological. All healthful conditions
                                must be observed, and the path which leads up to true reform, or cure, can only be
                                pursued by strict conformity to the laws of health." Any thing that assists in
                                ameliorating the condition of the intemperate is a blessing, but there is a difference
                                between drunkenness and inebriety that perhaps Mr. Grosvenor does not recognize. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker leaven" TEIform="index"/>SHAKER LEAVEN</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">It is a fact, observed by multitudes, that there never was a period of time when the
                                .principles of Shakerism Avere more attractive than now. There never was a Lime when the
                                lives which all good Shakers live were less bug-bears, or had so little hindrance of
                                "the lions in the way" as at present. People are getting sufficiently liberal to read of
                                the Shakers. By reading, they realize that there is reason in their peculiar principles,
                                for Shakers, at least, to live them out and preach them. The interest which so many are
                                taking, in keeping themselves informed as to what Shakerism teaches, is the first step
                                toward beinginstructed by them, and converted to them! To be sure, the light which
                                Shaker principles let in to any soul, dissipates the dark problems which early
                                educations have caused us to exhibit a very cherished regard for, even if these are most
                                untrue. One measure of Shaker theology will, with a little careful interest, leaven the
                                whole lump to a Shaker line of thought, and to a Shaker's line of life. To tne
                                sensualist, whose heaven is in the engagements of the lusts of the flesh and of the
                                world's pleasures, Shaker leaven is as safe and agreeable as a heavy charge of
                                nitroglycerine ignited; and, viewing it as such, a, safe distance is attempted, with
                                slurs and sneers, with perhaps vituperative ridicule cast from the distance. Time was,
                                when many so engaged, and found hearers and imitators — when Shakers were worthy only of
                                the words ridicule and disgust. Not so now; the first and best of the citizens of the
                                world are conversant with Shaker polity, and have the largest respect for the lives of
                                those who live after the doctrine! And distance does not make a place of safety for the
                                sensualist! Somehow, in God's appointed way, the leaven reaches such, willing or
                                unwilling though they be, and brings them into deep waters of trouble, while it makes
                                plentiful the exclamations of thousands'— friends and enemies alike — "this was the life
                                of Jesus, the Christ!" Redemtion comes by Tribulation. We know of none who can take the
                                credit of the distribution of Shaker doctrine to the extent it now circulates. Surely,
                                while many have preached it, and written its truths abundantly, large credit is due to
                                those who, living so quietly secluded from the world's clamor and pleasures, in Shaker
                                homes at duty, have none the less been powerful in influence to the conviction of many
                                souls. When we think how vastlv different <pb n="160" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 160 THE SHAKER
                                MANIFESTO. are present creeds from olden, " orthodox " opinions: regarding the
                                "Atonement ;" " Physical Resurrection ; " " Heaven and Hell;" with a stubborn belief
                                substituting a pure and honest life; and when we find professors of the Christian
                                religion, questioning whether Marriage and Reproduction, Private Property, War and
                                Political Issues, with the selfish run of life permitted, and encouraged by the
                                churches, are as Christian in themselves and results, as were the Master's life and
                                teachings, and the lives of those who did follow Him, then sit down, thank God for the
                                change for the expressed doubts; for the blessed results of reason upon a humanity
                                destined for heaven; for the finger of God that has pointed, and still points, "''the
                                way, the truth and the life" of Jesus Christ, as credentials and passports to a place in
                                the heavens, for those who have followed Him in life. Let us thank God for the leaven of
                                Shakerism. For it has, at least, opened the eyes of all who will see, and determined for
                                them that if they hopefully expect to enter heaven, where saints are living so nearly as
                                the Shakers do here, they had better commence the practices of Virgin Celibacy, Peace,
                                and a United Inheritance without delay. </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes" TEIform="index"/>NOTES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">This Number. — We present in this issue of The Manifesto many valuable contributions, for
                                those capable of thoughtful engagements. Few but will be struck by the tone of the
                                spiritual thunderbolt among antichristian "orthodoxies" found in "The World a Stage,
                                etc.," by Elder Evans. The " Correspondence " department suggests several ideas — among
                                others, one in which we fully coincide—that on the temperance subject, demanding as a
                                cure for inebriates a radical, physiological change of habits. Let those who question
                                this conclusion, get Elder F. W. Evans' opinions upon it. The balance of the department
                                represents some very important and kindly queries and answers. "Catholicism". is almost
                                severe; but it will do good to have the Shaker idea understood. " The Philosophy of
                                Shakerism,"— we almost need to apologize for its plainness— shows that well-regulated
                                relations of Marriage are "not far from the kingdom of" Shakerism! Let those who will to
                                marry, keep the laws of nature, and they will choose Shaker life in preference to the
                                onerous, yet righteous rules of reproduction. Let every one who breathes, study
                                Respiration; and likewise remember that these views, the results of experience, come
                                from a Shaker girl, whose sweet poetry and song, education and training have all come
                                from the Shakers. " Return of the Wandered," sequel to " The Ways of the Wanderer," is
                                an especially pretty contribution; and speaks so truly and feelingly the real truth of
                                so many lives as turn from self and self-indulgence, to the self-sacrificing,
                                life-example of Jesus, the Christ. u Saviours " is a valuable theme, and happily
                                rendered by our first novitiate Eldress. " The Real and Ideal" speaks much of truth to
                                us. What a pretty spirit pervades "the Indian poem ! The original poetry is pretty <pb n="161" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 161 and means something every time. Oar
                                music for July will sing its own praise, and it is worthy of its accomplished author. On
                                the whole, may it not be called a Banner No. ?</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Church and state union" TEIform="index"/>Church and State Union</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">There has not been such a violation of human rights enacted, since the days of the
                                Inquisition, as the trial of D. M. Bennett, of the Truth Meeker, exhibited. Every
                                feature, that would aid in presenting a favorable appearance to his "fault," was ruled
                                out by a United States judge, in the interest of the churchal party. The " fault" was in
                                mailing a copy of a pamphlet, containing testimony so plain and strong against sexual
                                immoralities and abuses, though, in our opinion, advocating other errors as a reform,
                                that the persecutors of Bennett, dubbing it " obscene," moved heaven and earth to secure
                                a verdict of guilty. Shakers do not fellowship the freelove principles of " Cupid's
                                Yokes," nor do they fellowship the infidelity of " The Truth Seeker," while we protest
                                against the inconsistency of Bennett's trial. Under such ruling, by judicial
                                inconsistency, the Bible, Shaker books and pamphlets, and thousands of others, are
                                obscene and unmailable. The testimony of Jesus cannot, according to such erroneous
                                decisions, circulate through the mails. So terribly in earnest appears the church, in
                                its determination to rule the state, that gags for those who dare to preach Christ, may
                                not be only things of the past. We pray the President to interfere, and pardon Bennett,
                                thus offering a protest to clerical domination, judicial inconsistency, and Comestock
                                persecution.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Courtesy" TEIform="index"/>Courtesy</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We are deeply moved at the very courteous treatment received at the hands of our
                                Spiritualistic Contemporaries, The R. P. Journal, Banner of Light and Texas
                                Spiritualist. These journals seem not to tire in quoting from our columns with credit;
                                and have so many good words to say about us, that we feel under many obligations to
                                them, which we do not know how to cancel. The secular press deserves a large share of
                                gratitude from us, for only kindly mention and encouragement. And while we receive the
                                silent courtesy of the various Church organs, with now and then a shy observation, we
                                are ever grateful for the courteous treatment. The Am. Socialist has many, and only good
                                words for us.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Old faith and the new" TEIform="index"/>The Old Faith and the New</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The God of Israel was to them a bloody God. The blood of beasts, birds and human beings
                                their God demanded of them, or they thought he did, and they obeyed. Paul, in trying to
                                harmonize the old, bloody faith, with the gospel of the new dispensation, engrafted the
                                bloody atonement doctrine upon Christianity, making a falsity of it. As a consequence,
                                those who cling to the old faith in confidence, think God a bloody being, who even
                                murdered, or permitted the murder of his own Son, as an off set for sins committed by
                                others. It is a sorrowful truth that in this late day of unusual intelligence,
                                Christians should not see and believe, universally, that the only atonement demanded by,
                                or accepted of God, is to renounce a sinful life and go and sin no more. This is the new
                                faith. <pb n="162" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 162 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. Let the people accept the new
                                faith ; rejecting the necessity of shedding the blood of Jesus, or the blood of any
                                animal or bird, and return to God by following the life of Jesus, the Christ; or "follow
                                Paul, as lie fulloivcd Christ," and rejecting all permissions of anybody to live
                                differently than did Jesus, thus find an at-one-ment with God. The letter from the wife
                                of Freeman (who believing in a bloody God, murdered his child, as he thought by God's
                                direction), tells a sad story. There is great source for gratification to reason, that
                                the people are losingfaith in such a bloody God, else we should have abundant
                                repetitions of deeds like Freeman's. Still there are some, who still demand for
                                themselves a bloody God to worship, and such should be watched as idiots or lunatics.
                                Freeman, according to his wife's description, was too good a man for such a God as he
                                believed in.</p></div3><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>KIND WORDS TO US</head><div4 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I am really disappointed in The Shaker Manifesto..." TEIform="index"/>I am really disappointed in The Shaker Manifesto...
                                </head><p TEIform="p">" I am really disappointed in The Shaker Manifesto. It is a better paper than I had
                                    ever expected to see ! I like the June No. very well. Some numbers back, and I
                                    believe the March JSrO. particularly, I thought to be the Banker No. ; but they are
                                    all getting to be Banner Numbers. Pleased! I am very much pleased with its course. I
                                    am fully persuaded now, that it will do the work whereunto it is called."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Eads, H. L." TEIform="persName"/>Elder H. L. Eads</byline></div4><div4 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is the talk of all here, that the June No. of The Manifesto..." TEIform="index"/>It is the talk of all here, that the June No. of The Manifesto...
                                </head><p TEIform="p">"It is the talk of all here, that the June No. of The Manifesto is a very excellent
                                    and interesting one. That it keeps improving in its successive issues. We all
                                    certainly wish you much success in conducting it, and that it may do all the good
                                    its most ardent friends can desire."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., W. H." TEIform="persName"/>W. H. B. </byline><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Sonyea" TEIform="index"/>Sonyea,N. Y..</dateline></div4><div4 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The June no. is at hand, weighty with truth and more luminous with..." TEIform="index"/>The June no. is at hand, weighty with truth and more luminous with...
                                </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="P., C." TEIform="persName"/>C. P.</byline><p TEIform="p">"The June No. is at hand, weighty with truth and more luminous with the light of
                                    truth than ever before. Each No. gives me additional pleasure."</p><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Bemis Hights" TEIform="index"/>Bemis Hights, N. Y.</dateline></div4></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>The Children's Grotto</head><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Esquah opwahgon or messages beyond the river" TEIform="index"/>ESQUAH OPWAHGON OR
                                MESSAGES BEYOND THE RIVER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sproat, Granville T." TEIform="persName"/>GRANVILLE T. SPROAT</byline><p TEIform="p"> The Indians, as death approaches one of their number, gather around him, in a circle in
                                the wigwam, to take with him the last smoke (esguah opioahgon), before his departure to
                                the Land of Souls. They also send messages of love to their friends waiting for them on
                                the other side of the river, as described in the following lines : We have gathered in
                                your wigwam, brother The old friends and the true. We have brought with us the pipe of
                                peace, The last to smoke with you, Here is Manitoba, brave and strong, And Ahkewazine
                                old ; And Oristoonah of the hills, The hunter swift and bold. The sun is setting in the
                                west, The forest paths grow dim ; The wishtonwish among the pines, 1 Sings its low,
                                dirge-like hymn. Your sun is setting too, brother, The day is almost o'er ; And long the
                                journey that you tread, Toward the dark river's shore. Long is the journey dark and
                                drear, O'er mountain, hill and moor, Across the distant prairie, where The restless
                                waters roar. 2. We will build the watch fire bright and high, 3 To light you on your way
                                ; Lest in that land of night and gloom, Your weary feet should stray. And when you reach
                                the roaring river, 4 Fear not the pole to tread; For braver heart ne'er traveled there,
                                Among the glorious dead. Our loved ones wait to meet you there, The faithful and the
                                true. Oh\ long and lovingly they have watched, And waited there for you. And when you
                                reach the Camp of Souls — Home of the loved — the dead, Oh ! treasure us within your
                                heart, Who soon that path must tread ! Walk often by the river's shore, And watch upon
                                the strand, For us, who soon must cross the flood, To reach the Spirit Land. 5. %\xz
                                m,ll <pb n="163" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 163 Tell Miontonomo, the good. His
                                children love to hear, And treasure up the name they love, With reverence and fear; Tell
                                Kejemindedo, the brave.. The warriors sing his praise ; There is none so fearless or so
                                bold, In all the after days. Tell Magwahgahbundah, the wise, The tribes with pride
                                repeat The words of wisdom that they heard, While sitting at his feet. Tell the great
                                healer, Muskoda, His skill and mystic lore Still ring in songs through all the land, By
                                every wigwam door. We will lay within your narrow cell, Brave store of all that's sweet,
                                Fruits of the chase, and moccasins To clothe your way-worn feet; Water from the purest
                                mountain rills, To cheer you on your way ; And bow and spear for the hunter's hand, And
                                chieftain's war plumes gay. 6 And now the sun has set, brother, Your journey just begun
                                ; We dress you in the paint of death. 7 Tour earthly work is done. Farewell, farewell !
                                we utter it With brave hearts, one and all, Farewell! 'tis the Death Spirit calls—8
                                Brother attend his call. 1. The whippoorwill. The Indians describe it as always hovering
                                round the wigwam when the spirit is departing, and giving warning of some one soon going
                                on his journey to the Land of Souls. 2. This prairie is described by the Indians as very
                                dark and gloomy, without the light of the sun or moon, and the trail across it is very
                                narrow, winding among shrubs and long grass, and clumps of the prickly cactus, which
                                wounds the feet of the traveler who is not well shod and prepared for the journey. He
                                also sometimes loses his way, and wanders about in the dark for many days with nothing
                                to eat. This, however, only happens to the cowardly and unfaithful ones, who did not
                                their duty in this world, and whose feet staggered long before they set out on their
                                last and perilous journey. 3. The Indians keep a fire burning three days and nights on
                                the graves of their friends, to light them on their way over the dark prairie. 4. This
                                river is situated beyond the great prairie over which the spirit passes on its journey
                                to the Land of Souls. It is very deep and rapid and abounds with whirlpools. A pole lies
                                stretched across it, floating and swaying with a swift currrent, the good In dian walks
                                over securely supported by his Manito, or guardian spirit. The bad. one hardly keeps his
                                footing, and often falls off into the river, where he struggles for a long time in the
                                water, until rescued by some friendly spirit. 5. The spirit, after crossing the river,
                                cannot enter the Camp of Souls, till some one of its former friends comes out to welcome
                                it and invite it in. Hence they charge their dying friends not to forget them, but to be
                                always on the look out for them who are so soon to follow them over the prairie and
                                across the river. 6. The Indians lay within the graves of their friends, abundant
                                provisions for the journey. They also lay their bows and arrows beside them. This they
                                do lest they should lose their way over the prairie and their provisions should fail,
                                and they would have to subsist many days by hunting the few wild beasts that roam over
                                its dark and desolate domains. 7. The Indians paint their friends with, the paint of
                                death before they leave them— the face half black, half white. This they do that their
                                former friends may know, when they meet them over the river, that they departed with the
                                love and veneration of those whom they have left behind them, who thus performed for
                                them the last kind offices for the dead. 8. Death (neboit) is a spirit that comes and
                                steals away the breath. It belongs tc a large class of lesser evil spirits, all subject
                                to Manche Manito, the Great Evil Spirit. Canaan, N. Y.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wanted, a boy!" TEIform="index"/>WANTED, A BOY!</head><p TEIform="p">A tradesman once advertised in the morning papers for a boy to work in the shop, run
                                errands, and make himself generally useful. In a few hours the shop was thronged with
                                boys of all ages, sizes, sorts and conditions, all wanting to find a situation. The
                                shopkeeper only wanted one boy, but how to get the right one was the great difficulty.
                                He thought he must find some plan to lessen the number of applicants, and give him a
                                better opportunity of selecting a good one. So he sent them a^away, and thought the
                                matter over a little. The next morning the papers contained the following advertisement
                                : " WANTED, A BOY WHO OBEYS HIS MOTHER !" Now, then, thought the tradesman, I shall <pb n="164" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 164 THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. see soon who will apply. He also put up
                                a bill in his window with these words on. And how many do you suppose did come '? The
                                story is that there were only two of all the numerous boys seeking employment in that
                                big city who felt that they could honestly come and say, " 1 obey my mother." The crowd
                                of lads was indeed quickly thinned out most effectually, and the tradesman had not much
                                trouble in selecting a boy. Such boys as these — boys that obey their mothers —are in
                                great demand. My little boy, if you saw an advertisement for such a boy, could you
                                truthfully go and offer yourself for the situation ? If not, I fear there is something
                                wrong about you. Look to the matter; seek the Lord's salvation; be an obedient son, and
                                God will bless you.—Children's Friend.</p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A little girl once said, 'Grandma, only little children tell stories..." TEIform="index"/>A little girl once said, 'Grandma, only little children tell stories...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A little girl once said, " Grandma, only little children tell stories. Big people only
                                make mistakes, but it sounds to me very like stories sometimes."</p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A little fellow, on going for the first time to church..." TEIform="index"/>A little fellow, on going for the first time to church...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A little fellow, on going for the first time to church where the pews were very high, was
                                asked, on coming out, what he did in the church, when he replied, " I went into a
                                cupboard and took a seat on a shelf."</p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A little girl who was somewhat out of sorts..." TEIform="index"/>A little girl who was somewhat out of sorts...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A little girl who was somewhat out of sorts, but whose exact ailment no one had been able
                                to discover, amended her evening prayer of "God bless papa and mamma," by adding " and
                                cure me if there's any thing the matter with me."</p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A pair of scissors was lost, and the little one suggested that a prayer..." TEIform="index"/>A pair of scissors was lost, and the little one suggested that a prayer...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A pair of scissors was lost, and the little one suggested that a prayer be said, asking
                                that they might be found. There was, however, a lurking consciousness that there ought
                                to be a combination of prayer and work, so the youthful philosopher said, " Now, mother,
                                I'm tired ; so I'll pray while you hunt."</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Noise of the fingers" TEIform="index"/>The Noise of the Fingers</head><p TEIform="p">In the carrent number of the Medical Record, Dr. Hammond says that when you poke the end
                                of your finger in your ear the roaring noise you hear is the sound of the circulation of
                                your finger, which is a fact as any one can demonstrate for himself by first putting his
                                fingers in his ears, and then stopping them up with other substance. Try it, and think
                                what a wonder of a thing your body is that even the points of our fingers are such busy
                                workshops that they roar like a small Niagara. The roaring is probably more than the
                                circulation of the blood. It is the noise of all the vital processes together—the
                                tearing down and building up processes that are always going forvvard in every living1
                                body from conception to death.</p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="For the boys" TEIform="index"/>For the Boys</head><p TEIform="p">A certain man, who is very rich now, was very poor when he was a boy. When asked how he
                                got his riches, he said: " My father taught me never to play till my work was finished,
                                and never to spend my money until I had earned it. If I had but an hour's work in the
                                day, I must do that the first thing, and in an hour. And after this I was allowed to
                                play; and then I could play with much more pleasure than if I had the thought of an
                                unfinished task before my mind. I early formed the habit of doing every thing in time,
                                and it soon became easy to do so. It is to this I owe my prosperity."</p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A clergyman was annoyed by people talking and giggling..." TEIform="index"/>A clergyman was annoyed by people talking and giggling...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A clergyman was annoyed by people talking and giggling. He paused, looked at the
                                disturbers, and said : " I am always afraid to reprove those who misbehave, for this
                                reason : Some years since, as I was preaching, a young man who sat before me was
                                constantly laughing, talking and making uncouth grimaces. I paused and administered a
                                severe rebuke. After the close of the service, a gentleman said to me : ' Sir, you have
                                made a great mistake ; that young man was an idiot.' Since then I have always been
                                afraid to i-eprove those who misbehave themselves in chapel, lest I should repeat that
                                mistake, and reprove another idiot."</p></div3></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Information received in Washington is to the effect that a plan has..." TEIform="index"/>Information received in Washington is to the effect that a plan has...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Information received in Washington is to the effect that a plan has actually been completed
                            by leading Jews for the purchase of Palestine. The details are not given, but it is
                            confidently asserted that the long-cherished scheme of Jewish patriots is about to be
                            accomplished.</p></div2><pb n="165" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society Record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>TRANSITIONS</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Van Valkenburgh, Elizabeth" TEIform="index"/>Elizabeth Van Valkenburg</head><p TEIform="p">At Sonyea, N. Y., May 8th, h, aged 69 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hammond, Lucy" TEIform="index"/>Lucy Hammond</head><p TEIform="p">At Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., June 5th, , aged 88 years. " Another faithful, well-tried
                                    pilgrim, gone to rest in the enjoyment of the rewards of a well-spent life."— {Polly
                                    Lewis.</p></div4></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Received" TEIform="index"/>RECEIVED</head><p TEIform="p"> From James Goodwin, $5.00. From a friend, $1.00, to be used to circulate The Manifesto.
                                Eldress Harriet Goodwin, so long and lovingly known at Mt. Lebanon, goes to Alfred, Me.,
                                to live and to bless the people by her presence. Eldress Paulina Bates, and Hannah Ann
                                Agnew are laboring in the Society of Philadelphia. Elder Evans lectures at Lake
                                Pleasant, in August.</p></div3><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>THOUGHTS FOR TO-DAY</head><div4 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Abstract Christianity" TEIform="index"/>Abstract Christianity</head><p TEIform="p">It is well to remember that an abstract Christianity is neither useful nor beautiful.
                                    The value of it is only seen when it becomes a habit of living. The most shapely and
                                    beautiful garment loses its symmetry and beauty when it is cast off, and laid upon a
                                    couch or hung on a peg. Let it be put on by its owner, and you at once perceive its
                                    comeliness. Something like this is true of the religion of Christ. It is not meant
                                    to be judged or criticised apart from the lives of men. But when the robe of
                                    Christ's righteousness is put on and worn its beauty is revealed to all
                                    beholders.—Sunday Afternoon.</p></div4><div4 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Holiness of life" TEIform="index"/>Holiness of Life</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Barnes, Albert" TEIform="persName"/>Albert Barnes</byline><p TEIform="p">A man who has been redeemed by the blood of the Son of God should be pure. He who is
                                    an heir of life should be holy. He who is attended by celestial beings, and who is
                                    soon—he knows not how soon—to be translated to heaven, should be holy. Are angels my
                                    attendants ? Then I should walk worthy of my companionship. Am I so soon to go and
                                    dwell with angels? Then I should be pure. Are these feet so soon to tread the courts
                                    of heaven ? Is this tongue so soon to unite with heavenly beings in praising God ?
                                    Are these eyes so soon to look on the throne of eternal glory and on the ascended
                                    redeemer ? Then these feet, and eyes and lips should be pure and holy, and I should
                                    be dead to the world, and live for heaven.</p></div4><div4 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prevention of vice" TEIform="index"/>Prevention of Vice</head><p TEIform="p">" Thai well thought it very unfair to influence a child's mind by inculcating any
                                    opinions before it had come to years of discretion to choose for itself. I showed
                                    him my garden, and told him it was a botanical garden. " How so?" said he; "it is
                                    covered with weeds." O, I replied, that is only because it has not yet come to its
                                    age of discretion and choice. The weeds you see have taken the liberty to grow, and
                                    thought it unfair in me to prejudice the soil in favor of roses and
                                strawberries."</p></div4></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Photographs" TEIform="index"/>PHOTOGRAPHS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Publishers" TEIform="persName"/>The Publishers</byline><p TEIform="p">As the Gospel of Christ is prohibitory of worldly vanity, pride, and ambition for the
                                distinction of certain members of the Household of faith above their Brethren and
                                Sisters, and as the temporal property of the Shaker Community is all consecrated to the
                                support of its people in the service of God in the use, simply, of those things that are
                                needful and profitable unto righteousness, and the promulgation of the Gospel Testimony,
                                its publishers deem the use of Societies' funds for the procurement of photographs to be
                                in contravention of that sacred consecration, and as militating against that harmony,
                                meekness, love and fraternal equality which characterizes the true members of the Church
                                of Christ. Our motto should be personalities absorbed by principles. </p></div3></div2><pb n="166" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Aspiration" TEIform="index"/>ASPIRATION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Reed, C. G." TEIform="persName"/>C. G. Reed</byline><p TEIform="p"> Center, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. 1. O Heav'n sweet empire of my song, Celestial clime of heav'nly
                            bliss, 2. Let earth her wealth and splendor boast, Her coronets and wreaths display, 3.
                            There is a realm where all is pure, Where naught but virtue sheds perfume, 4. Elysian fields
                            their glories bright, Resplendent on my vision shed, Realm of the pure angelic throng,
                            Bright land of glowing happiness. Her heroes, kings and nobles toast,—¦ Ephemeral glories of
                            a day. Where living peace is ever sure, Where joys eternal are in bloom. Where virgin souls
                            in cloudless light, Among these fadeless beauties tread. My soul is thrilled with love
                            divine, Sweet joys around my heart entwine, This pomp is all a transient joy, Far higher
                            themes my tho'ts employ, I work to gain the blest domain, Where souls redeemed in triumph
                            reign, O Hallow'd Spirits! Blissful Clime! I crave your happiness sublime, My spirit soars
                            to spheres a bove, Where all is harmony I contemplate the spheres above, Where all is
                            harmony Transporting in the spheres above, Where all is harmony A birthright in the spheres
                            above, Where all is harmony and love, and love, and love, and .love, <pb n="167" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/>
                            My spirit soars to spheres above, Where all is liarmony and love. I contemplate the spheres
                            above, Where all is harmony and love. Transporting in the spheres above, Where all is
                            harmony and love. A birthright in tha spheres above, Where all is harmony and love.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>Home Topics</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Warts" TEIform="index"/>Warts</head><p TEIform="p">A friend of ours asserted that by rubbing warts with lard two or three times a day,
                                either those on persons or cattle, they will disappear in a short time.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cockroaches, croton bugs, etc." TEIform="index"/>Cockroaches, Croton Bugs, etc</head><p TEIform="p">The Scientific American says : "A mixture, composed of 1 part of powdered borax and 2
                                parts of powdered sugar, sprinkled upon the floor where they frequent, will soon
                                eradicate them."</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker sisters" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Sisters</head><p TEIform="p"> say that there is a better remedy for dispelling red ants than the chalk mark. It is
                                camphor. Saturate a piece of sponge or cloth with spirits of camphor, or wrap a few
                                small lumps of the gum in paper, and place where they inhabit. The disagreeable pests
                                are thus entirely banished.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cure for deafness" TEIform="index"/>Cure for Deafness</head><p TEIform="p">Some time ago an old lady recommended the use of heated hoi's oil dropping it into the
                                ear internally one or more times daily, and above all to persevere in its use, and it
                                would certainly help me. This simple remedy I have faithfully employed, and I now hear
                                as well as I ever did in my life. This oil is very penetrating and in the case mentioned
                                acted remedially by softening the indurated earwax, which is no doubt the cause of
                                deafness in more instances than is generally supposed.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>Agricultural</head><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is the opinion of the best farmers that potatoes..." TEIform="index"/>It is the opinion of the best farmers that potatoes...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">It is the opinion of the best farmers that potatoes, if planted five inches deep, are
                                better without hilling.</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Keep only good stock" TEIform="index"/>Keep only Good Stock</head><p TEIform="p">Get the best and never keep a poor cow the second year. No man can afford to keep a cow
                                that will not make from 200 to 220 pounds of butter or its equivalent in cheese every
                                year.</p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Coal oil and insects" TEIform="index"/>Coal Oil and Insects</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., J." TEIform="persName"/>J. A.</byline><p TEIform="p">I discovered several years ago, if charcoal was soaked in coal oil, and a piece as large
                                as a hickory nut was placed beside plants liable to be destroyed by worms, bugs or other
                                insect pests, security was insured aganst their ravages so long as the odor of the oil
                                was given off. I report this for what it is worth. , Atlanta, Ga. [Would not this
                                practice banish vermin from hens' nests ?]</p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wherein consists the success of farming" TEIform="index"/>Wherein Consists the Success
                                of Farming</head><p TEIform="p"> Successful farming demands the breeding and rearing of farm animals of some kind, not
                                only for daily products, meat, wool and increase, but for manure. Farmyard manure must
                                always remain the standard fertilizer, while experience in this country has shown, that,
                                under skillful hands, it may be supplemented by commercial fertil izers. It is claimed,
                                however, by good English farmers, that many of the artificial fertilizers act chiefly as
                                a stimulant, and after ^anxz gapits. <pb n="168" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/> 168 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. a
                                time the land refuses to answer the spur. This is most apparent on the poor and lighter
                                soils, but even strong land loses heart unless a fair proportion of farm-yard manure is
                                applied. The loudest agricultural complaints in Great Britain are from districts where
                                scientific farming has been carried to its highest pitch, such as the Scotch Lothians
                                and in Norfolk. It is highly important that, in the purchase of artificial fertilizers,
                                farmers should deal only with those houses of established reputation. Bowker ;gt Co. of
                                Boston and New York i such a firm.</p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sulphur a remedy for the striped bugs" TEIform="index"/>Sulphur a Remedy for the
                                Striped Bugs</head><p TEIform="p">I have read of various remedies for this pest. The best remedy I have ever tried is
                                sulphur. I have used it with success for the last three years. Dust the plants well with
                                it. The best time is when the dew is on the young plants. No one need be afraid to put
                                it on, for it will not injure the plants. It is also a good remedy to prevent insects
                                from injuring young cabbage plants.—A Farmer, Vermillion Co., hid.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Faith or works?" TEIform="index"/>FAITH OR WORKS ?</head><p TEIform="p">Up to the death of Nicholas, Jews in Russia were not allowed to possess land, to give
                            evidence in civil suits, nor to inhabit the holy cities of Kiew and Moscow. They were
                            obliged to wear a particular garb, and out of every family, one child was taken by the State
                            to be educated as a Christian at his parents' cost. Yet this is the nation that is
                            prosecuting a relentless war in the name of religion. The Jewish religion is as much
                            superior to that of the Greek Church as a philosopher's intellect is superior to that of the
                            idiot. In barbarous Turkey, the Jew is protected in his religious liberty, while in
                            fanatical Greek countries, it is thought to be no sin to murder men, women and children of
                            the Jewish race. The doctrine of faiths instead of works has caused untold misery to the
                            human race. The religion of mankind, in this particular, needs to be entirely reversed, and
                            the people taught that their religion will be judged, not only on earth, but in heaven, by
                            What they do, and not by what they profess.—Benison News.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sympathetic" TEIform="index"/>SYMPATHETIC</head><p TEIform="p">Passing through one of our workshops lately, we came across the little piece of poetry copied
                            below. We wish we knew its authorship. We found it lying on the worktable of one, who had
                            lately parted with an erring brother ; and its bespotted surface told of falling drops, that
                            gave relief to pent-up grief, and of a love that would win him back again. We here confess
                            that we " borrowed " it, and thus make restitution.—Ed. S. M. " If widely he has gone
                            astray, And dark excess has marked his way, 'Tie pitiful — but yet beware, Reform must come
                            from kindly care. Forbid thy parting lips, to move But in the gentle tones of love. Though
                            sadly his young heart hath erred, Speak not to him a bitter word. " The lowering frown he
                            will not bear, Thy venomed eludings will not hear, The ardent spirit will not brook The
                            stinging tooth of sharp rebuke. Thou would st not goad the restless steed To calm his fire
                            or check his speed — Then let no angry words be heard — Speak not to him a bitter word. " Go
                            kindly to him — make him feel Your heart yearns deeply for his weal. Tell him the dangers
                            thick, that lay Around his widely devious way,— So shalt thou win him, call him back, Prom
                            pleasure's smooth, seductive track, And warnings, thou hast mildly given, May guide the
                            wanderer up to heaven."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Temperance" TEIform="index"/>TEMPERANCE</head><p TEIform="p">By the City Treasurer's report, the goodly Philadelphia city has over five thousand licensed
                            grog-shops, with probably three thousand selling without license. This, allowing fifteen
                            feet front for each shop, would stretch twenty-four miles. Barnum, the great showman, was in
                            Philadelphia, and being a strong temperance man, made an address to a large meeting of
                            citizens on the immense waste caused by intoxicating drinks. Saying, that if they would give
                            him the money thus spent in Philadelphia he would engage to pay all the city taxes, all the
                            expense of the police, courts and prisons, all the costs of street repairs, and of lighting
                            the city lamps; all the expense of sustaining the schools and churches of the city and would
                            give every man, woman and child two new suits of lothes every year ; and that he would make
                            money by so doing.—Ex.</p></div2><!--
                    <pb id="p29"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>