<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ss0408" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">Shaker and Shakeress</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Society</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Mount Lebanon, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">4</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">8</biblScope><date value="18740801" TEIform="date">August 1874</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">57-64</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="4" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="57" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="8" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!-- <p>Vol. IV. No. 8. PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETY. F. W. EVANS, _ _ T . -. _ _. _ _ __ ; ^_ . EmTOR Mt. Lebanon, Col.
                        Co. N. Y. August, 1874: Fifty Cents per annum.</p>
                    --><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gods" TEIform="index"/>GODS</head><p TEIform="p">" I said, Ye are Gods," John x., 34. Who said? In Bible times, if not now, all the nations,
                            and most of the peoples, had their Gods. They were " called Gods," because those, unto whom
                            these Gods ministered, took them so to be ; each believing his God was the very Deity— so
                            did John the Revelator. The lower down, in the scale of soul travel, men and women were, the
                            more fully were they confirmed in the idea, that every thing spiritual — supernatural — was
                            direct from Deity. Physical phenomena, as thunder and lightning, earthquakes and epidemics,
                            were often believed to be the voice of God, or arbitrary visitations of his displeasure,
                            independent of human agency, or natural causation. When the Gentile Roman Centurion saw
                            Jesus exercising authority over disembodied spirits, and likened him unto himself, who, as a
                            military officer, had soldiers under him, to whom he issued commands, and was obeyed, Jesus
                            declared, " I have not found so great faith, no, not in Israel." A Gentile was discovered,
                            who was more learned — better educated, in the knowledge of the Spirit world, and the Laws
                            which there obtain, than any Jew ; Jesus alone excepted. Jesus was an extraordinary man. His
                            love of truth and goodness was so simple and intense, that it resurrected him up, into the
                            Heaven of all Heavens. He loved righteousness, and hated iniquity, to that degree, that it
                            exalted him above the sectarian prejudices and national pride of his people and day. He
                            could detect evil, even among the Pharisees — the highest professors — and discover good in
                            the Infidel Saducees, Samaritans and Gentiles. This religious condition of soul, necessarily
                            made him an enlightened spiritualist. He communed, socially, with Moses and Elias, and, no
                            doubt, with thousands of others of the saints and prophets of earth, long ago departed. He
                            spoke of having " bread to eat," beyond the comprehension of his disciples — Talked of "ten
                            legions of Angels," and what help they could be to him. The Spirit World was open to his
                            vision, from the hells into which the antediluvians had immersed themselves; up to the
                            universal Christ Heavens. He was born Jesus ; j ust as Napoleon was born Napoleon. When a
                            boy, at school in Corsica, Napoleon played war, with forts of snow, and cannon of frozen
                            water. He was Napoleon. As a boy, Jesus learned to obey his earthly parents. As a Jew, he
                            was obedient to John the Baptist. And then, as a spiritual man — a prophet — he learned
                            obedience to the Christ Spirits, and became the Messiah. Those Spirits were drawing him
                            inward and upward, through all the spheres in the Spirit world, causing him to say," If I be
                            lifted up — resurrected — I will draw all men unto me," as fast as I can. The Devils, in the
                            Hells, and the Cherubim and Seraphim, in the Holy of Holies, were before him. He opened the
                            everlasting gates of Truth, to all nations, kindreds, tongues and people — to all souls, in
                            all worlds. He was a King — a Priest—a Prophet. He was just what every other soul becomes,
                            who comes into the same soul-condition—"Kings and priests unto God," over others who have
                            not yet attained unto that high religious estate — a simple love of truth and goodness — of
                            God. Moses was God to Pharaoh, as the Israelites were Gods to the Egyptians — "I said ye are
                            Gods, but ye shall die like men." The God of Abram, Isaac and Jacob was the God of Moses ;
                            and the God of Moses belonged to an Order in the Spirit World, who acted as " Angels of the
                            Lord, and unto whom the word of God came," from the spheres above, even from the Lord their
                            God. The prophetic order existed in Israel and in all nations. It was universal. Melchisidec
                            was a prophet, and was Abram's superior—his elder. Yet Melchisidec was not even a Hebrew,
                            but a Gentile. He was what " anti-christians " call a Heathen. Jethro was a prophet, who
                            instructed Moses and the whole Jewish Priesthood, in the art of civil government. He was
                            their religious superior. Yet Jethro was a Gentile — an Ethiopian Heathen, who would not be
                            allowed the rights of American citizenship, until the Civil Rights Bill, of Sumner, becomes
                            American Law. Jesus said, to the spiritually ignorant Jews, " If he, called them Gods, unto
                            whom the word of God came," from spheres still above them ; why call ye me a blasphemer, who
                            claim to be only a son of God, and just what, even your own selves, by obedience, might
                            become? The Prophetic Order of human souls, to which Enoch, Melchisidec, Jethro, Baalam,
                            Samuel, Elijah, Isaiah, John Baptist, Jesus, and " the Two Witnesses," down to George Fox,
                            and James and Jane Wardley belonged, were Spiritual Media. When in their highest spiritual,
                            religious condition, they were Mediums of Christ Spirits. At other times, they were capable,
                            like Baalam, of being mediums for Spirits of lower Orders. Prophets were expected to love
                            truth, better than they loved life itself. They were often sent to reprove Priests and
                            Kings, who had the power of life and death over them. They instructed and reproved Levites,
                            who were mediums of the God of Israel; as they did the constituted authorities — media — of
                            the Gods of other nations — the powers that be. These often put them to death, as Herod did
                            John, striving to drown the truth, in the blood of Prophets and Martyrs — so that Jesus
                            inquired of the Jews, " Which of the Prophets have your fathers not stoned, or killed, when
                            they were sent unto them ? " sent by the rock— Christ — who thus "followed them," in all
                            their deviations and wandering, in the wilderness of sin ? And it was thus that the word of
                            God came to them that were called Gods — even to the God of the Hebrews, and the Gods many
                            and the Lords many, of the so-called Heathen nations of Earth.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Universal love" TEIform="index"/>UNIVERSAL LOVE</head><p TEIform="p">Junk 16th, 1841, I felt impressed with a wonderful sense of universal love. I had a clear
                            manifestation that all good, all love comes from God, and is God; for the reason that "
                            there is none good but One G-od;" and that " God is Love." This love is infinite, extend-
                            ing itself, at least potentially, everywhere ; and can only be excluded from the experience
                            and enjoyment of any soul, by the repulsive force of the selfish principle. Who ever is go-
                            verned by this intense selfishness, has circumscribed feelings and ends of his own to
                            pursue, which are out of harmony with universal love; and he therefore rejects and shuts it
                            out as an enemy. Yea, though it may be offered to, and approved by his better judgment, if
                            he is determined to pursue his own selfish ends, he only hates and resists it most where it
                            is most manifested. This may be plainly seen in the conduct of the Jews against the highest
                            manifestation of love that has ever been presented to the contemplation and acceptance of
                            man, in the person of Jesus. This love then is the universal medium of harmony to all
                            intelligences who will truly renounce all selfishness, self-seeking schemes and devote
                            themselves wholly to do and suffer the will of God, and minister to the equal good of all
                            his creatures. All such are brought into a holy union and harmony, and whatever may be the
                            distance, as to space, which separates them, their state is one, and they are, by this
                            universal medium, brought into contact, to dwell in one Center. This union — this holy
                            sympathy — this sublime and endearing relation to all the good and the pure in the universe,
                            is plainly seen and felt by those who are let into its sphere ; and truly every perception
                            of goodness and glory that ever entered the mind of man before, sinks into nothing when once
                            this is enjoyed. As this love is infinite, it surrounds, and really does, in some degree,
                            permeate every intelligent being. But those who are in the selfish prin- ciple, are thereby
                            prevented from perceiving its presence, or enjoying its happifying influence, in a greater
                            or less degree, as their selfishness is more or less intense. While my soul was wrapt in
                            this sphere of love, my affections seemed not only in union and sym- pathy with all the good
                            and the pure in the <pb n="58" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 58 SHAKER -A.ND universe, but to have a compassion
                            and benevolence which ardently desired the redemption and happiness of every intelligent
                            being, however debased by selfishness. Nor could I conceive of one single being so totally
                            wrapped up in self as entirely to exclude all influence of the universal Love ; and this
                            little spark was so much of God, and made the possessor appear lovely. Yea, that little
                            spark appeared sufficient, if cherished, to light up a fire in the soul that would consume
                            the most intense spheres of the selfish principle, and ultimately unite the soul to the
                            sphere of universal harmony. This made all souls appear lovely, as they evidently appeared
                            the objects of God's love, belonging to Him ; living in His universe; supported in existence
                            by His power; constantly upheld by His love from sinking still lower into the black abyss of
                            selfishness; and rendered as happy as they would permit themselves to be made. Another
                            consideration which made all these appear more or less lovely was, that they were all
                            equally under the care and providential government of God, and there appeared no discrete
                            degrees in the gradation from the most dense sphere of self love, up to the confines of the
                            sphere of universal harmony ; though there was a vast difference between the two extremes.
                            Indeed, the evil seemed so inconsiderable in the whole universe, when compared with the
                            Infinite Goodness, that it was swallowed up in universal beauty and brightness, and seemed
                            as nothing. This was undoubtedly viewing the bright side of the picture; yet, of this I am
                            certain from experience, that however much real or supposed evil there may be in the
                            universe, God may so fully inform and possess the soul with his Goodness and Love, and thus
                            so completely happify and deliver it from all sense of evil, that it could not be more so if
                            evil were really banished from the universe. And I apprehend that so far as I, as an
                            individual, am concerned, with the evil that exists, I have only to see more specially to
                            the destruction of that portion which exists in myself. Whenever this work is effected, and
                            my soul shall be brought into complete submission to, and union with, the Divine nature, and
                            filled with impartial love to all souls, then, if there be evil existing in the universe, it
                            will not be evil to me. There is no good but in God, no evil but selfishness and that which
                            flows from it. As far and as fast as we recede from the selfish sphere, we enter into God
                            and come into harmony with all the good in the universe. Our souls are enlarged ; our love
                            is expanded, and partaking of the divine nature, we possess as it were a kind of ubiquity.
                            Our love is co-extensive with the dominions of God; because, loving God supremely, we love
                            whatsoever He loves and owns as his. Thus, as the apostle John says, " God is love, and he
                            that dwelleth in love, dwelleth in God, and God in him." Oh, my soul, what has selfishness
                            ever done for thee, but make thee wretched, shut out of thee the Universal Good and led thee
                            to forsake thy Father's house and suffer famine in a far country ? Then, at last, arise and
                            go to thy Father — hate and deny selfishness in all its instances. When thou art emptied of
                            sin and self thou wilt be filled with the infinite good and be enabled to love God with all
                            thy heart, and thy neighbor — every creature of God — as thy self. Thus, thou wilt enter
                            into the sphere of Universal Harmony and Eternal Peace.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pelham, R. W." TEIform="persName"/>R. W. Pelliam, Union Village, Ohio</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A man diseased in body can have little joy of his wealth..." TEIform="index"/>A man diseased in body can have little joy of his wealth...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A man diseased in body can have little joy of his wealth, be it ever so much. A golden crown
                            cannot cure the headache uor a velvet slipper give ease to the gout, nor a purple robe fray
                            away a burning fever. A sick man is alike sick, wheresoever you lay him —on a bed of gold or
                            on a pad of straw; with a silk quilt or a sorry rag on him. So no more can riches, gold and
                            silver, land and living, had a man much more than ever any man had, minister unto him much
                            joy; yea, or any true or sound joy at all, where the mind is distract and discontent.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="National sins" TEIform="index"/>NATIONAL SINS</head><p TEIform="p">The constant use of superfine flour bread by the American people, is a prolific source of
                            trouble in the flesh, and also in the bones, of the American nation. Its immediate effect is
                            clogging the system with effete matter, through the constipation of the bowels. Its remote
                            effects are legion. Children raised upon it exclusively can never come to much, as doers of
                            good works, though they may expend inherited energy; for it takes a few generations to waste
                            the physical powers of a healthy ancestry. This, the real genuine Yankees are rapidly doing,
                            and becoming extinct. They have ignored hygiene and physiology, to make paper money, and
                            themselves are liable to perish with that money. Dyspepsia is their father, debility their
                            mother, and their brethren and sisters are colds, fevers and unmentionable maladies calling
                            for incomprehensible doctors and mysterious remedies. Give" children and youth bone-making
                            material — bran-bread, milk and oat meal, with plenty of good vegetables and abundance of
                            fruits. They will prefer to play with the lambs rather than to eat them. Digestion is
                            necessary to individual existence, yet it wears out the stomach and ends in death. Progress
                            is equally necessary to the existence of an organization, but it is also destructive of old
                            things. Better is a dinner of herbs with love and peace, than a stalled ox, and contention
                            therewith; because love helps digestion, while cold indifference benumbs the whole digestive
                            machinery. Our forefathers and mothers fought the lusts of generation, while laboring under
                            the disadvantage of physiological lusts, from which we are, in good part, released. If they
                            traveled twenty miles an hour, it was by an expenditure of skill and labor we may not equal.
                            We can go sixty miles an hour — three times as fast. Are we their superiors in either case ?
                            Our spiritual ancestors used food and drinks that stimulated the reproductive powers. Unless
                            we avoid such food and drinks, we shall not take up our crosses as successfully as they did.
                            No one calls in question the fact that certain drinks affect the mental and spiritual status
                            of those who use them. Why should it then be thought incredible that certain kinds of food
                            do also affect the mental and spiritual status of men and women ? Dr. Whitlaw declares that
                            all the prohibited articles of diet, under Moses, produced in those who used them, un
                            physiological conditions, tending to immorality, and to an unspiritual frame of mind,
                            unhealthy to the soul, no less than to the body, and that this is the scientific law upon
                            which " the law" rested. The Jews received the command. We are beginning to discover the
                            science — the reason of the command.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="An examination of the flesh of one of the Indiana victims..." TEIform="index"/>An examination of the flesh of one of the Indiana victims...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">An examination of the flesh of one of the Indiana victims of trichinse disclosed millions of
                            the creatures coiling and uncoiling in the tissues. Such reports are calculated to give us
                            all a truly Mosaic horror of pork and pork eaters. </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True greatness consists in doing what deserves to be written, or writing that deserves to be                                 read, and in making mankind happier and better for your life" TEIform="index"/>True greatness consists in doing what deserves to be written...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">True greatness consists in doing what deserves to be written, or writing that deserves to be
                            read, and in making mankind happier and better for your life. </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="No manners are so fine as the most awkward manifestations of good will toward men" TEIform="index"/>No manners are so fine as the most awkward manifestations of good will toward men
                        </head><p TEIform="p">No manners are so fine as the most awkward manifestations of good will toward men.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Peace and war" TEIform="index"/>PEACE AND WAR</head><p TEIform="p">' Peace on earth, and good will to men," was proclaimed by the Angels, who came to the
                            Shepherds, bringing the glad tidings, that a Saviour was born. The lowly Nazarene preached
                            the Gospel of Peace and good will, eighteen hundred years ago, and has been worshiped as a
                            God. But, how few have followed him in deed and in truth — like him, denying all un-
                            godliness and every worldly lust ? Many pretend to believe in the teaching of Jesus, but in
                            their works deny him. These draw nigh unto him, with their lips, but their hearts are far
                            from the truth. They will stand up and declare their belief in Jesus Christ, and, in the
                            next breath, excite the members of their churches to go and kill their brethren on the other
                            side of some range of mountains, or waste of waters — thus preaching in direct opposition to
                            the teaching of one they so highly extol. '' From whence came wars and fighting ? Come they
                            not of the lusts that war in your members?" So long as the lustful passions have
                            pre-eminence over the more God-like part, so long will the day of universal peace be
                            deferred. In time of war, the armies, of each side, pray to the same God — the God of war —
                            to assist them in conquering the opposite party. If their God answered their prayers it
                            would result in the destruction of both armies. Their prayers would exterminate them. O,
                            wicked and adulterous generation! Ye ask and receive not, because ye ask amiss, that ye may
                            consume it upon your lusts, and consume each other. In prosperity, man is never content, On
                            some kind of trouble, he ever is bent. Peace brings him riches, these beget pride, A vain,
                            haughty spirit, o'er others to ride; Pride begets war, with its horror and waste, This, down
                            to poverty, brings man, in haste ; Poverty humbles, and lowers his pride. Humility leads him
                            to work and provide ; To mind his own business, from wrangling cease, Which brings him
                            again, to plenty and peace, He seldom rests here, the same round he'll go, The cause never
                            learning of comfort nor woe. " He that ruleth his own Spirit is greater than he that taketh
                            a city " — and finds a much better reward.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="De Graw, Willis" TEIform="persName"/>Willis De Graw, Groveland, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Union" TEIform="index"/>UNION</head><p TEIform="p">" But one thing is needful." Luke 10, 42. Happy, most happy the soul, who can simply bring
                            all things into union. To center in one point, more than one object, perplexes the mind.
                            Double minded we stand and pause where we shall first begin, and neglect both. What is the
                            one thing needful ? It is plain our Saviour means the soul keeping close company with
                            himself. This Mary did. She sat at his feet and heard his word. Every thing else is but
                            cumbering work compared with this. This one thing comprises all the holiness, happiness and
                            heavenly mindedness of the soul. If we have the presence of Christ's spirit, guilty fears
                            vanish, dejecting doubts are scattered, legal terrors silenced, anxious cares subside,
                            strong temptations lose their force. Satan is resisted, afflictions sweetened, turbulent
                            passions calmed, raging corruptions subdued, pride is brought down, humility excited, peace
                            with God enjoyed, holiness promoted, fear of death conquered, hell chased away, the prospect
                            of glory in the full fruition of truth is aspired unto. Earth loses its charms. Heaven is in
                            the heart — to be free from sin becomes the one desire of the soul. Say, 0 Christian, what
                            one thing else can produce so many blessed effects as close communion with God ? Is not this
                            the one thing, above all others, needful ? Needful at all times and in all seasons. Needful
                            in the hour of prosperity and in the day of adversity. Needful in the solemn hour of death,
                            and in the tremendous day of judgment. 0, if this one thing is maintained in the soul,
                            Believer, you may live as you list, and do what you please ; for sweet communion with holy
                            souls in Christ ever subjects the will, attracts the affections, and be<pb n="59" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/>
                            SHAKEEESS. 59 gets holy conformity to rules and orders needful for the protection of the "
                            household of faith." You will not list, you cannot like, you dare not follow any thing
                            contrary to your Gospel Brethren and. Sisters, while you live near to and dwell in holy
                            fellowship with them. Thus, religion is brought to a single point. Holiness and happiness
                            are resolved into one thing. Love thy neighbor as thyself, each one seeking another's wealth
                            — goods — and not his own. Here is but one faith to make you holy and happy But there are a
                            thousand things to prevent this. 0 may this one thing—needful — Gospel Union — rise superior
                            to all! Think, 0 my soul, of Mary's choice. Remember the Saviour's approbation of it. Choose
                            thou also this good part, which shall never be taken away. Sit thou at the feet of the
                            Saviours of to-day, as did Mary in her day.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Vann, Walter" TEIform="persName"/>Walter Vann, Pleasant Hill, Ky.</byline></div2><div2 type="history" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ancient Ireland" TEIform="index"/>ANCIENT IRELAND</head><p TEIform="p">Irish law threw a shield around the woman's weakness. It never robbed her of her property and
                            self-respect under pretense of making her more completely one with her husband. Such was the
                            Celtic sense of equality. The property she brought to her husband in marriage remained her
                            own, and could not be disposed of without her permission. How different the spirit of this
                            provision from that of the law which makes a woman little less than a chattel, and
                            magnanimously makes her husband her lord aud master, and, it might be added, her proprietor.
                            The luxury of poor law unions was unknown in ancient Ireland. Apart from the authority of
                            the old poem, in which a tourist of the day (the seventh century), giving a description,
                            social and topographical, of Ireland, says: " I traveled its fruitful provinces round, And
                            in every one of the five I found Alike in church and in palace hall, Abundant apparel and
                            food for all." The orphan was not victimized like another "Ginx's baby," by being thrown
                            mercilessly on the parish. The law provided for his adoption and support in some family in
                            the neighborhood to which his parents had belonged. It is somewhat singular that the most
                            recent suggestion in behalf of destitute children tend in the direction of a system similar
                            to that which prevailed in Ireland more than a thousand years ago. Yet this is the country
                            which English writers, in their ignorance and self-conceit, have been pleased to call
                            "barbarous," and on which they pretend a benefit was conferred when it was brought under the
                            tyranny of the feudal law. -Christianized. A prominent feature in the legal system was the
                            law of fosterage. By this law the children of nobles and gentry were placed in families of
                            respectable persons of inferior rank to be brought up as their own. The different ranks of
                            society were thus cemented and bound together by ties which in our colder and less emotional
                            age can hardly be understood. Class distinctions, if not abolished, were made the means of
                            uniting the members of the community in bonds of mutual loyalty and brotherhood more secure
                            than the most stringent laws could ever have created. Among no other people that we know of
                            was the sentiment of affection made so subservient to the stability of society. It is
                            interesting at the present time, when the possession of land has become one of the great
                            questions of the day, to know how it stood in the times of our Celtic ancestors. Absolute
                            possession of land among them was a thing unknown. Even the chief, or kinir, was regarded as
                            holding the portion he enjoyed merely by virtue of his office, and for the term of his
                            office. Throughout all the grades of proprietorship the idea that the occupiers of land held
                            it by a sort of trusteeship for the benefit of the tribe of which he was a member,
                            prevailed. It may seem somewhat singular, within hearing of the arrogant assumptions of
                            landlords in Ireland, to say, that a document exactly similar lies at the root of the
                            English law of real property. " The first thing," says an eminent writer on the subject, "
                            for the student of English law to do is to get rid of the idea that there is such a thing
                            known to it as absolute ownership of land." English law regards the sovereign, in other
                            words, the representative of the nation, as the only absolute owner, and the ordinary
                            landlord as merely a trustee, holding it for the nation's benefit. How imperfectly this
                            doctrine is understood or carried out, it is not necessary to describe. Tn ancient Ireland,
                            however, the theory was not only acknowledged, but put in practice. — Ex.</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sutton - a subordinate on a railway train" TEIform="index"/>SUTTON - a subordinate on a
                            railway train</head><p TEIform="p">" The conductor, " " sent him to the rear to flag another train coming up behind. On his way
                            he fell on the track, and was run over by five cars and the caboose. His legs were
                            completely cut off above the knee, but, remembering his orders, he cleared the track of the
                            dismembered portions of his own body, and taking a flag out of his pocket, waved it until he
                            had stopped the approaching train. Without this, a collision would have been
                        inevitable."</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Telling experience" TEIform="index"/>TELLING EXPERIENCE</head><p TEIform="p">Beloved Editors : In perusing your precious little paper, I came to the piece —" All these
                            things shall be added unto you." I read it with astonishment and deep interest. It led me to
                            reflection. Upon reviewing my life, for the last fifty years, I can, with humble gratitude
                            to God, truly say, that, notwithstanding my many short-comings, it has been a practical
                            demonstration of the truth of that scripture. I was born in England, of poor, but Godfearing
                            parents. Was put to work at seven years of age. No education, except what a Sabbath-school
                            afforded. There I learned to love, read and study the sacred scriptures. I had faith in God.
                            That led me to face a frowning world, by a religious profession, when only fifteen years of
                            age. My motto was, " Seek ye first the Kingdom of Heaven and its Righteousness, and all
                            these things shall be added unto you." I was encouraged by the glorious example of many
                            spiritual heroes, in scripture records. I passed through many trials and persecutions. I
                            followed on to know the Lord, whom I was seeking, early in life. I had the means of saving a
                            little money, to give me a start in life. In my twelfth year, my natural mother died. Life
                            has passed roughly with me since that event. Now, I am thankful that I have found a Heavenly
                            Mother who loves me as her son. When, in a far country I received indefinite tidings, that
                            in America, there was a second, and brighter manifestation of Christ, than that which
                            occurred in Jewry 1800 years ago, I felt that it was the call of God, to my soul. Then came
                            a test of my faith, of a practical character. I had not the means of transportation thither.
                            Here was a problem to be solved. Having lived in two excellent families, some eight years
                            previous to my marriage, I went and laid the matter before them. They had religious union
                            with my desired search for the Kingdom of Heaven upon Earth, and freely gave me eleven
                            sovereigns, over $50 —, and sent me more, after my arrival in America. It came just when I
                            was sick in body, and grieved in spirit, at the loss of a little boy, two and a half years
                            old. Then I visited the Shakers at Watervliet, Montgomery county, Ohio. This visit, after
                            coming so far to make it, I had dreaded and deferred, fearing I might be deluded, as I had
                            no definite reliable knowledge of their faith, nor of the lives it produced. My Visit.— In a
                            few days I began to receive internal evidence that I had, in fact, found the " Kingdom
                            come," for which I had been so long praying. I had also occular demonstration — not " in
                            deep sleep and in the visions of the night," but when wide awake. I was powerfully shaken,
                            while in bed, and heard a voice, saying — "This is what you asked in prayer. If you can
                            accept it, upon my terms, well. If not, that is the end of all your praying." I arose, and
                            on my knees, promised God, and covenanted with myself, to be " strictly obedient to the
                            Heavenly vision." Next morning, I went to the Elders and con- fessed to God, my sins. I was
                            blest — never before did the Sun shine so brightly, as on that, to me, joyful morning. The
                            whole creation looked beautiful. Nor was my rejoicing evanescent. To this day, " my cup of
                            salvation—of blessing—runneth over. Blessed be the Lord; for he hath heard the voice of my
                            supplication. I have been helped. Save, O Lord, thine inheritance. Rule and Exalt it
                            forever." My conclusion is, that simple obedience to God's requirements insures the actual
                            fulfillment of his engagements, and we have the happy experience, that by this Second Gospel
                            testimony, the ax is laid at the root of the tree of evil, which causes all of human woe.
                            Nothing short of a deep sense of duty to God, and obligation to my fellow creatures, could
                            induce me to make this public confession of faith. I am thankful for a resting place. " Thou
                            shalt not see a fierce people, a people of a deeper speech than thou cans't perceive ; of
                            stammering tongue, that thou cans't not understand." "Look upon Zion, the city of our
                            solemnities ; thine eyes shall see Jeru- salem, a quiet habitation." — Isa. 33.18. But I
                            congratulate you on the mountain. " In the last days, the mountain of the Lord's house shall
                            be established on the top of the mountain — exalted above the hills. Many people shall say,
                            Let us go up to the mountain of the Lord — to the House of the God of Jacob, and He will
                            teach us of His ways, and we will walk in His paths ; for out of Zion shall go forth the
                            Law, and the word of the Lord, from Jerusalem." Isa. 22. I have sent the Shaker and
                            Shakeress to the families I lived with, in England, and hope they will be as noble as the
                            ancient Bereans who " daily searched the scriptures, to see whether these things were so, or
                            not so." But, if in this life they reject my testimony, when they enter the Spirit world,
                            and " their souls waik in dry places," I hope it may prove to be a seed ; and that then they
                            will lay hold of eternal life — that they may understand the scriptures, when they say
                            (Ezekiel, 22, 24): " Thus saith the Lord God ; I myself will take of the marrow of the high
                            cedar, and will set it; I will crop off a tender twig from the top of the branches thereof,
                            and I will plant it on a mountain, high and eminent. On the high mountains of Israel will I
                            plant it, and it shall shoot forth into brandies, and shall bear fruit; and it shall become
                            a great cedar, and all birds shall dwell under it; and every fowl shall make its nest under
                            the shadow of the branches thereof. And all the trees of the country shall know, that I, the
                            Lord, have brought down the high tree, and exalted the low tree ; and have dried up the
                            green tree, and have caused the dry tree to nourish. I the Lord have spoken and done it. And
                            more are the children of the barren — Shaker celibate Ann Lee — than of the married, wife,
                            saith the Lord." One of those children,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Vann, F." TEIform="persName"/>F. Vann, Watervliet, O.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Write" TEIform="index"/>WRITE</head><p TEIform="p">The Spirit says, "Write" —What shall I write? — "Write what oometh unto thee." Now, more than
                            ever before, is soul atmosphere permeated with elements of progress — of human elevation —
                            more than ever before, are the old heavens — old religious organizations, creeds and forms,
                            on which men did rely — being dissolved—the elements, thereof, melting with fervent heat.
                            Henceforth, will men and women work out their salvation, instead of having it rubbed in from
                            the outside. New Heavens are being formed in the Souls of the People. In the souls of such
                            as aspire to the purity of Angels. No darkness in the New Heavens — neither act, word,
                            feeling nor thought, that will not bear the searching light. Who will ascend the hill of the
                            Lord ? Who will be living stones, builded into the Living Temple of the Living God ?
                            Splendid opportunity now, to draw the highest prize. What of the old Earth — the generative
                            order f That, too, has become affected. The fact is — the old Heavens, and Earth — religion
                            and generation — have been so mixed up, compounded and confounded, that both are sick, past
                            recovery. No D. D.'s nor M. D.'s can resuscitate them. We must have new earth, as well as
                            new heavens. In the New Earth — new order of generation, use is the motto — the cardinal —
                            the organic law — no abuse — no prostitution of generative organs. Those, whose aspirations
                            reached not to the highest prize — the new Heavens —may find a field, lower doAvn — in the
                            new Earth. We do not say they will get lower-priced article. We only say they will get an
                            article not worth so much. What per cent, of what is called humanity, will aspire to the new
                            Heaven — what per cent to the new Earth remains to be seen. The remainder, through delicacy,
                            we'll call debris — of no account.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prentis, Oliver" TEIform="persName"/>Oliver Prentis, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><pb n="60" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers in Lynn" TEIform="index"/>THE SHAKERS IN LYNN</head><p TEIform="p">Having seen, by the papers, the Shakers were to speak in Lynn, I took the cars, Sunday p. m.
                            May 31, and there found Elder Vance, from Maine, and Elders John Whitely and William
                            Leonard, of Harvard, Mass. ; Catharine B. Walker and other Sisters gathered at Oxford Hall,
                            occupied by the Supervisors. Elder Wm. Leonard spoke at some length on the confession of
                            sins, to Elders and Elderesses, and was listened to with marked attention. The meeting was
                            addressed by Elder Vance, and by J. M. Peebles, the champion of Spiritualism, setting forth
                            the doctrine of practical religion, by good works, and of doing to others, as we would
                            others should do to us, taking the Bible and Inspiration as our only rule of faith and
                            practice. The singing was truly delightful and enchanting ; the faces of the audience seemed
                            to shine with admiration. In the evening, Elder Vance spoke, at some length, on the true
                            marriage question, as taught in the Scriptures — and as practiced at the present day,
                            showing the absurdities and misery growing out of the latter. Sister C. B. Walker gave a
                            deeply interesting account of her experience — why she became a Shakeress. She spoke in a
                            clear tone of voice, that seemed to carry conviction to the hearts of all present. Every
                            word seemed to be clothed with inspiration and love. She said it would be impossible to
                            convey to the human soul the joy and peace of mind that thrilled her heart, in
                            self-consecration to Shaker faith. I never saw an audience so completely spell-bound and
                            delighted as on that occasion. The time has fully come, I think, for the Shakers to go out
                            into the world, and let their light shine. The world is in darkness and needs the light. I
                            have visited, and been conversant, with the Shakers, more than a score of years, and have
                            ever found them truthfnl, kind and honest.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sargant, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Sargant, Boston</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We reap what we sow" TEIform="index"/>We reap what we sow
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Preuss, H. Clay" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">WE REAP WHAT WE SOW. By H. Clay Preuss. For pleasure or pain, for weal or for
                                    woe, ' Tis the law of our being — we reap what we sow, We may try to evade them —
                                    may do what we will — But our acts, like our shadows, will follow us still. The
                                    world is a wonderful chemist, be sure, And detects in a moment the base or the pure
                                    ; We may boast of our claims to genius or birth, But the world takes a man for just
                                    what he's worth. We start in the race for fortune or fame, And then when we fail the
                                    world bears the blame But nine times in ten, ' tis plain to be seen, There's a "
                                    screw somewhere loose " in the human machine. Are you wearied and worn in this hard
                                    earthly strife? Do you yearn for affection to sweeten your life ? Remember this
                                    great truth has often been proved — We must make ourselves lovable would we be
                                    loved. Though life may appear as a desolate track, Yet the bread that we cast on the
                                    waters comes back; This law was enacted by Heaven above, That like attracts like and
                                    love begets love. We are proud of our mansions of mortar and stone, In our gardens
                                    are flowers from every zone; But the beautiful graces that blossom within, Grow
                                    shriveled and die in the Upas of sin. We make ourselves heroes and martyrs for gold
                                    Till health becomes broken and youth becomes old; Ah ! did we the same for beautiful
                                    love, Our lives might be music for angels above. We reap what we sow — oh I
                                    wonderful trtith ; A truth hard to learn in the days of our youth ; But at last it
                                    shines out as " the hand on the wall," For the world has its debit and credit for
                                    all.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Industrial age" TEIform="index"/>The Industrial Age.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="There is a terrible epidemic of trichina among the swine..." TEIform="index"/>There is a terrible epidemic of trichina among the swine...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">There is a terrible epidemic of trichina among the swine of Kaskaskia Bottom, Illinois. It is
                            estimated that not less than from 10,000 to 15,000 hogs have died of this disease in that
                            neighborhood within the past nine months.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Counsel for youths" TEIform="index"/>COUNSEL FOR YOUTHS</head><p TEIform="p">THOUGHTS. Beloved Youth in Zion. If you keep your thoughts pure, and bring them into com-
                            plete subjection to the obedience of Christ, then your life will be blameless. The in-
                            dulgence of sinful thoughts and desires produces sinful actions. " When lust hath conceived
                            it bringeth forth sin." James 1st. 15th. The pleasurable contemplation of a sinful deed is
                            often followed by its commission. Never permit yourselves to pause and consider the pleasure
                            or profit you might derive from this or that sin, but close your minds against the evil
                            suggestion at once, as you would lock and bolt your doors against rob- bers. If our parents
                            had not stood parleying with temptation and admiring the forbidden fruit, this earth might
                            be a paradise. No one becomes a depraved and abandoned character all at once. The mind first
                            becomes corrupted. The wicked suggestion is indulged and revolved in the thoughts, until it
                            loses its hideous appearance, and the anticipated gain, or pleasure, seems to outweigh the
                            evils of the transgression. Your vain imaginations are apt to paint sensual pleasures in gay
                            and dazzling colors. Beware! It is the serpent's charm! Look not upon the picture, neither
                            allow the tempter to gain a lodgment in your hearts. Meet the enemy at the threshold and
                            expel evil from your minds. Destroy it, or it will destroy you ! As a rule, the more
                            familiar you become with sin, the less hateful it appears. Therefore the more completely you
                            preserve your minds from sinful thoughts, the better. Never permit yourselves to read any
                            thing unchaste, or immoral ; nor allow your minds to become familiar with the details of
                            crime ; but direct your thoughts toward pure and holy subjects. Contemplate the spotless
                            characters of our Saviours — Jesus and Mother — and their successors; who have bequeathed to
                            you a rich inheritance of holy precepts and examples ; and walk in their footsteps ; so
                            shall your lives be virtuous and happy. Take care of your thoughts, and your actions will
                            take care of themselves.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt, Enfield, Ct.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Temperance" TEIform="index"/>TEMPERANCE</head><p TEIform="p">Editors of the Shaker and Shakeress : Knowing that you take an interest in every degree of
                            moral and spiritual reform going on in the world, which has for its object the elevation of
                            our race, we thought we would let you know how the temperance cause is progressing in
                            Cleveland. This institution seems to be conducted almost exclusively by women, and has, ever
                            since its inauguration, except being backed by some clergy of all denominations, and these
                            two elements combined are giving the temperance cause an impetus hitherto unknown, and these
                            again backed by the invisible, are very fast becoming a power in the land against the demon
                            intemperance. That the Temperance cause in Cleveland is gradually gaining strength every
                            day, is evident from the following resolutions passed at a mass meeting held recently,
                            published in the Cleveland Herald of the 16th inst., from which we make the following
                            extracts. " Resolved, That this movement be continued as it was begun, animated only by the
                            spirit of kindness, and guided only by the law of love, toward those who sell intoxicating
                            liquors. Resolved, That we manifest warm interest in those who habitually drink, and we will
                            not cease to labor for their reformation, by prayer, by personal kindness, and by proper
                            attention. Resolved, That through grace, the success attending the women of Cleveland, in
                            their work of the last eight Aveeks, is most gratifying, and is without a parallel in any
                            previous history of moral reform. Resolved, That we favor the establishing of drinking
                            fountains (water of course) in our streets, at suitable intervals, throughout every section
                            of our city." When a praying band of women visited a saloon on the road leading from the
                            city to our settlement, we felt to say in our heart, " God bless the women/ " This is their
                            peculiar mission — because they are chosen for this purpose, and they have our union,
                            sympathy and prayers.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescott, James S." TEIform="persName"/>Elder James S. Prescott, North Union, O.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Novels" TEIform="index"/>NOVELS</head><p TEIform="p">What is the secret of the fascination of novels and novel reading ? There is, in human souls,
                            a germinal conception of a latent power of enjoyment — happiness — not yet attained unto. As
                            one said, of an evil experience — " That, which I greatly feared, has come upon me "— thus
                            showing that he had formed an imagination of it. So it is with a good experience. That,
                            which I conceived, in mind, and desired, is actualized in my life. We are saved by hope. We
                            live, by anticipating something, which will, in the future, be fruition. Novels are the
                            world's prophecies. The spirit of prophecy is the life of the Christian. The just shall live
                            by faith. Hence, the Christian needs no novels. As truth is stranger than fiction, so is
                            prophecy superior to novels. Keligious meetings, abounding in the Gifts of the Spirit, are
                            far more wonderful, fascinating and absorbing, than any theatrical exhi- bition— even as
                            spiritualistic phenomena are superior to the acts of the necromancers, the substance, to the
                            shadows, or the true science of government, which will result in the Mil- lennium, to the
                            arts of the time-serving politician. The love of stimulation — of excitement of the senses,
                            is only the measure of capacity, for enjoying spiritual things, objective to the spiritual
                            senses. Each vice is as the shadow of the corresponding virtue. Vice, like stealing, shows
                            the desire to possess, and the ability to enjoy, that which cannot be rigJitfiilly possessed
                            except by honest acquisition. To be enjoyed, it must be earned. Novel reading, alcoholic
                            drinks, and improperly stimulating food, are like unto a man drawing upon a bank, wherein he
                            has no funds. He is simply borrowing — contracting a debt, which may leave him a prisoner in
                            some jail, out of which he may not come till he has paid the uttermost farthing. Be real. Be
                            true. Draw not upon fancy, for the good you may gain, by honest toil and unremitting
                            industry. Be sober — be vigilant — an unregulated imagination will waste the powers of
                            enjoyment ere life has fairly commenced.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notice" TEIform="index"/>Notice</head><p TEIform="p">— To me, the Temperance movement appears so important as to almost include every other. I
                            feel a deep interest in every thing that tends to diminish the great and growing evil of
                            intoxicating drinks. Righteousness exalteth a nation, but sin is a reproach to any people. I
                            would that every bar-room and drinking saloon was banished from the face of the earth, or
                            turned into something useful. For half a century I have advocated the cause of temperance in
                            all things, and in that time, have experienced but a few days of sickness. I am thankful for
                            our little Monthly. It bears a true testimony, sifted, screened and purified — a little here
                            and a little there. Every contribution is like a sparkling gem, or a diamond, bright, sharp
                            and flinty. The Editors have my blessing and love.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hayden, Clark" TEIform="persName"/>Clark Hayden, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><pb n="61" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakeress: ministerial agency" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERESS: MINISTERIAL AGENCY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">All natural children in their infant and childhood state need guides and guardians. With- out
                            such guardians, they could not long exist; being not only dependent upon them for food and
                            raiment, but they lean upon them — tell their trials — and look to them for counsel. And
                            where can we find a man, or woman, who, when in trouble, or pain, either mental or physical,
                            does not seek relief from some sympathizing friend in visible form ? If physically diseased,
                            do they not ask to find a physician that will understand their condition and point out a
                            remedy? It would not satisfy them to believe that skillful physicians, or healing media
                            lived on earth centuries ago; they want some person, tangible to their external senses, that
                            they can see, and feel; to whom they can speak and from whom they can receive a response.
                            The natural is a figure of the spiritual. Jesus said, "Except ye receive the Kingdom as
                            little children, ye shall in no case enter therein." Spiritual children are as dependent for
                            aid and counsel as the natural; and have need of teachers and guides who are higher in the
                            scale of virtue and intelligence than themselves. Jesus was a healing medium; he cured
                            physical diseases, and cast devils, or evils, out of souls. God works through Agents, and
                            the lesser is dependent upon the greater. There is a connecting chain of intelligences from
                            the lower to the higher, until by progressive degrees, human souls rise into the divine
                            spheres of light and love, where inharmony cannot enter. It is claimed that God is
                            Omnipresent — is in all places,— and in all things. If we admit that He is everywhere in his
                            own creation, yet he is not seen and felt for the same purpose. We see Him in the stars, in
                            the different strata of soils, in clouds, or in the song of birds ; we hear Him in loud
                            peals of thunder, and feel Him as a Power, riding the whirlwind and directing the storm ; in
                            all this, there is method — Order. But in dealing with human beings, we see that God has
                            reasoned with man and woman, through intelligent agencies, all down through the ages. He has
                            appointed ministers and elders who have been as gods to the people, for the time being.
                            Moses was a god unto Aaron — a law-giver to the Israelites. He was a medium for spiritual
                            communication to those who were less progressed than himself — a link in the chain. And the
                            laws which he received from disembodied spirits, or angels, for the people, although
                            imperfect, were the best that they were prepared to receive ; and sufficient unto that day,
                            was the good thereof. The Levitical Priesthood were appointed media, through whom the higher
                            intelligences could reach the lower ; and vice versa. It was God's altar of sacrifice for
                            the people. To the order of priesthood, they brought their sacrifices for sins committed,
                            and thus showed their deeds, and through the priests sought remission. Here we see that the
                            principle of oral confession, to anointed witnesses, was acknowledged ; a mercy seat was
                            established in a certain place ; and there God promised to meet and commune with the people,
                            through the order of the priesthood. The same law held good through the order of the
                            Prophets, who were mediators between the more and less progressed intelligences, in both
                            worlds, the mundane and the celestial. Jesus of Nazareth, who was baptized with the
                            Christ-Spirit, was a teacher of a still higher law and became the High Priest of a New
                            Dispensation. He did not condemn the law, nor did he abolish the ordinance of oral
                            confession ; but when he went with the multitude to the river Jordan, where John, his
                            forerunner, had pitched his tent, for the purpose of attending to those who came to him
                            confessing and repenting of their sins,— seeking to be immersed in the cleansing waters of
                            that river,— did he not give unmistakable proof of his faith in the confession of sin to
                            God's witnesses ? What were the keys that he gave to Peter when he appointed him to be the
                            first Leader of his little flock, that he was about to leave, when he said to him, " What ye
                            bind on earth shall be bound in heaven; and what ye loose on earth shall be loosed in heaven
                            ; and whosesoever sins ye remit, they are remitted unto them." Did he not appoint a
                            succession of the confessional through his apostles at that time ? It is written, that under
                            the preaching of Paul, "Fear (or conviction) fell upon the people and many came and showed
                            their deeds." Jesus said of himself, " / am the light of the world." He also said to his
                            disciples, " Ye are the light of the world." They who live in sin, and choose to continue
                            therein will not " bring their deeds to the light, lest they be reproved." Such persons give
                            evidence that they love darkness, rather than light. They who desire to accept Christ as a
                            whole Saviour, in the dual order of male and female, are thankful to approach the mercy-seat
                            that was prefigured under the Law ; but is now a living reality in the Gospel dispensation.
                            It is the '' door of hope," through which many have entered, and found salvation and
                            strength, through the power of the Christ-Spirit, in both male and female. Now the wings of
                            the cherubim and seraphim touch each other. Appointed ministers of the New Covenant, watch
                            over and guard the mercy seat, where perpetual communion is held, between saints on earth
                            and saints in heaven ; and a holy bond of union is formed, which cannot be broken.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christianity" TEIform="index"/>CHRISTIANITY</head><p TEIform="p">Jesus of Nazareth, the founder or exponent of Christianity, came from the exclusive Order of
                            Essenes, and became the corner stone of a more perfect system than had yet obtained among
                            that sect. He opened a new fountain of inspiration to priests and people ; and advanced the
                            great work of progress toward the millennium of humanity. In practical life he was a pattern
                            of holiness ; and all orders of people have admired him in his virgin character, even if
                            they were not willing to follow his example in that respect. Although, at the time of the
                            first advent of the Christ-Spirit on earth — embodied in the baptized Jesus — the civil
                            governments were not sufficiently progressed, nor the people prepared for the permanent
                            establishing of a Christian Pentecostal Church upon a basis that could stand; yet, from that
                            time unto the present, effective forces have been at work to prepare the way for a new
                            heavens and earth that would be based upon the Rock — Sexual purity — Non-resistance — Love
                            to God and to neighbor, which would be manifest by an equal distribution of all things that
                            pertain to physical life. Those principles, when received and reduced to practice, will give
                            freedom from many vexing troubles which attend those who live in the generative order.
                            Strange as it may appear, to the more spiritually progressed, whenever the higher Christian
                            order and work is perceived and accepted by Truth seekers, there is mourning in the land ;
                            especially in the nominal churches ; and indeed, all who love the world and the things
                            thereof, mourn, because the Gospel testimony is like a sharp sword, proceeding from the
                            mouth of those who bear it, to slay the carnal mind. Those who rise above the generative
                            plane of life receive divine inspiration and power from the inner, or Seventh heaven, where
                            souls, aggregated as Christ's ministers, pass through the spheres of God's creation,
                            whenever and wherever sent.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Knight, J. D." TEIform="persName"/>J. D. Knight, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Zion must be pure" TEIform="index"/>ZION MUST BE PURE</head><p TEIform="p">If the Church of Christ's Second Appearing is to be as a " city upon a hill," giving light to
                            the world, then, how great is the necessity of maintaining a swift testimony against every
                            form of evil within her own borders. How can the higher " Law go forth from Zion," that
                            shall be a teacher of truth and purity to others, unless those individuals who form the
                            collective body within her gates, make a practical application of that law to their own
                            lives ? Zion must be pure. God will surely purge His floor; the wheat He will garner, and
                            the chaff will be blown away by the winds of truth. Those who are willing that the Gospel
                            fire shall burn in their hearts, to consume the false and give room for the true, will make
                            themselves worthy to eat at the Lord's table, and to drink of the pure crystal waters which
                            flow from His eternal fountain. But they wh© live in carnal pleasure — serve the tabernacle
                            — have no right to partake at the Lord's table." The Holy Spirit is waiting and calling upon
                            all to make ready for an increase of spiritual truth, by greater sacrifices of that which is
                            selfish and worldly. The good shepherd and shepherdess of souls stand ready to enfold the
                            innocent lambs in the arms of love, and they will lead them into living pastures which are
                            evergreen and growing, being warmed and vivified by the sun of righteousness. Oh, glorious,
                            happy day! God speed the rising sun; Haste to the fields in bright array, Ye laborers, every
                            one. There's work for each to do ; No soul should idle stand ; God's numbered ones are few,
                            And each should lend a hand. Flinch not, nor doubtful feel — The Angels cheer you on, To
                            tread with strength and zeal, The path the Saints have gone. For armies from above Have
                            reinforced our bands ; The banners, Truth and Love, They bear with fearless hands. Let
                            hypocrites beware! The battle will not cease, Till Zion's borders fair, Proclaim for love
                            and pease. Till every soul is sealed To God and to His truth ; Till justice is revealed,
                            From aged down to youth. Till, written on each face Is Father's holy name ; And, Mother's
                            love hath place Throughout the heart's domain. The harvest fields are white; Then, let us
                            all awake ; From off our raiment bright, The dust of slumber shake. The blessed morn is
                            here, Dull night hath died away ; Brave hearts, with purpose clear, Shall toil in this new
                            day.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Johnson, J." TEIform="persName"/>J. Johnson, West Pittsfield, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The gentlest spirits, when provoked..." TEIform="index"/>The gentlest spirits, when provoked...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The gentlest spirits, when provoked, are the most determined. The reason may be that, not
                            taking up resolutions lightly, their very deliberation makes them the more immovable; and
                            then, when a point is clear and self-evident, how can one with patience think of entering
                            into an argument of contention upon it? Beware the fury of a patient man !</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ex." TEIform="persName"/>Ex.</byline></div2><pb n="62" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New creation" TEIform="index"/>THE NEW CREATION</head><p TEIform="p">" In thee and in thy seed shall all the nations of the earth be blessed." This sublime oath
                            and sacred promise was made by the God of Israel to Abraham the father of tile faith of the
                            New Creation. It embodies a law that has been gradually unfolding in each of the four
                            Dispensations of God's love, and grace to man. These had to succeed each other until the
                            mystery of God was fully revealed — finished. In the ministration, by Angels, of the Law of
                            types and shadows, the ten commandments were written by the finger of God, in Hebrew
                            characters, on two tables of stone, because they could not be contained by one table only.
                            It prophesied the two Christian Dispensations— Jewish and Gentile—male and female. And the
                            sacrifice of beasts — male and female — pointed in the same direction. The male beast was
                            slain first to make an atonement for animal physical sin, and then the female beast was
                            slain as a peace offering. Saviours came forth from Judah and Edom with garments died in
                            blood — the generative life—see Zach. (vi. 13), "He shall build the temple of the Lord, and
                            He shall bear the glory ;" — the woman is the glory of the man — and " He shall sit and rule
                            upon his throne, and the counsel of peace shall be between them both." Jesus of Bethlehem,
                            and Ann of Manchester, were heirs of the faith of Abraham appointed to accomplish the
                            purposes of God, included in the oath, that all the nations of the earth should be blessed
                            in his seed. The seed of the spiritual woman would bruise the head of the sensual nature of
                            fallen man—the lust of generation—by resurrection out of the generative Order, thus creating
                            a spiritual woman. They became the parents of the New Creation which is based upon death to
                            the work of physical, animal propagation. Life is sacrificed and hated —the carnal life and
                            all it produces is forsaken, and a new life, even " eternal life " is revealed. In place of
                            the natural there is the spiritual Parentage with its Brothers and Sisters, and a household
                            of faith where all property is " in common," thus constituting the true Church of the
                            Christ-Spirit, the Temple of God. The soul that receives this word of faith has the
                            beginning of the New Creation in itself, just as it began in the first son, Jesus, and in
                            the first daughter, Ann. They were the first born of the Christ Parentage, first of many
                            brethren and sisters ; for to as many as receive the Christ-Spirit, they give power to
                            become the sons and daughters of God. Obedience brings the soul under God's everlasting
                            covenant. To enter the kingdom of heaven upon earth, we must become like the first elder
                            brother and sister in all things. Let the word of life have free course in our souls, and
                            let every thing go that would bind us down to the earthly order of generation, and its
                            concomitants. As the natural child in its infancy knows little of its earthly parentage, and
                            increases in understanding as it grows in years, so is it with spiritual children; they
                            attain to the measure of the stature of men and women in Christ Jesus, and in Christ Ann, by
                            slow degrees. The natural elements in man and woman must be burned up by the baptism of the
                            Christ-Spirit — melted with the fervent heat of spiritual love, which is as fire to earthly,
                            carnal loves and affections, cares and interests. Then the Bridegroom and bride are revealed
                            to their true sons and daughters. Thus the souls of all true believers find in the hour of
                            tribulation, that they have an anchor sure and steadfast," and they know in whom and in what
                            they have believed. Even their bodies become pure, fit temples for souls to dwell in,
                            through the chastening virtue of self-denial. As sin entered into the world by the agency
                            and co-operation of male and female, why should it not also be removed by their union in the
                            Truth, as co-workers together with God?</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ervin, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>Eldress Anna Ervin, Enfield, Ct.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Knowledge" TEIform="index"/>KNOWLEDGE</head><p TEIform="p">That " knowledge is power," to a certain extent, we cannot deny. According to bible his-
                            tory, a thirst for knowledge was the prime cause of the fall of our first parents, who were
                            placed to dress and keep the beautiful garden called " Eden." All that was needful for man's
                            sustenance — all that he could use and not profane, was freely offered to him without
                            constraint; but there was a prohibition placed upon one tree called the tree of knoicledge,
                            and he seemed to desire to eat of the fruit of that tree more than of all the other trees ;
                            although a heavy penalty hung over him, if by disobedience he violated the injunction given
                            him. As we trace the ancestral line of history back to the original progenitors of our race,
                            can we not deu-ct the same disposition in all their lineal descendants, to crave knowledge
                            of things that will afford present gratification to the senses, irrespective of law and
                            order, notwithstanding the voice of God speaks to them through the conscience, saying " eat
                            not lest ye die ? " Obedience to truth is a life pre server. Disobedience gives pain and is
                            a life destroyer. The desire for knowledge in the human heart, when sought within the limit
                            of law, and guided by wisdom that applies knowledge to use, is God-given, and is in
                            conformity to his designs for the elevation and progress of humanity ; and is laudable in
                            the highest degree. We wonder when we contemplate what the united intellect of men and
                            women, in the mundane and super-mundane spheres, have accomplished, in revealing the hidden
                            mysteries of science. To effect this work, lofty mountains have been scaled, deep caverns
                            have been penetrated, great oceans have been fathomed, by which a knowledge of animate and
                            inanimate things on the land and in the seas has been attained. The wild lands of America
                            and the jungles of Africa have been explored, and the religious manners and customs of all
                            civilized and socalled savage nations have been investigated. The mausoleums of past ages
                            have been entered, the remains of ancient sculpture and art have been examined, and the
                            fossil remains of men and animals have been dug from the earth. The encyclopedias and halls
                            of science of to-day tell, in part, of the success of the searches and researches that have
                            been made in quest of knowledge. And as the facilities for accumulating knowledge are
                            increased, the desires are enhanced for more ; and at the present time great efforts are
                            made to penetrate the ice-bound regions of the North, at the peril of life and property, in
                            search of an open sea at the poles, if such sea exist. While men and women by searching have
                            found out God, to a marked degree, as manifested in the outward visible creation, so that
                            they can describe the course of the stars, send messages from country to country with
                            lightning speed, under the waves of the mighty ocean as well as over hill and dale; and the
                            iron horse has found its way through the hitherto trackless regions of the far West,
                            carrying untold treasures of wealth, the products of industry, from the Atlantic to the
                            Pacific coasts ; still there is much sorrow and mourning in the land; for the rich are
                            increasing in wealth and luxurious habits of life, and the poorer classes are depressed in
                            proportion. War, intemperance, sensuality and crime are filling the land and destroying the
                            vital energies of the people. Corruption and fraud are found in the churches, in the
                            legislative halls of the nation, and all down through society from the highest to the lowest
                            ranks. The wisdom that cometh from above, that will cause men and women to fear God and work
                            righteousness, has been ignored or lost sight of to a great extent. It seems to have been
                            forgotten, or never understood, that sooner or later God will require a strict account of
                            every thought, word and deed ; and that in the light of his judgment all will stand approved
                            or condemned before him.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Rhoda R." TEIform="persName"/>Rhoda R. Hollister, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Great effort from great motives is the best definition of a happy life" TEIform="index"/>Great effort from great motives is the best definition of a happy life
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Great effort from great motives is the best definition of a happy life.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beloved Eldress Antoinette:" TEIform="index"/>Beloved Eldress Antoinette :</head><p TEIform="p">In perusing a late number of the Shaker and Shakeress, I was deeply interested and
                                edified with the article headed " Courage Toilers." As I view the present condition of
                                society, the aspect presents cause for great courage and patient toiling, on the part of
                                those who possess wisdom, and have the ability to work for the elevation and redemption
                                of the human race. There is need that every effort be directed to aid the Gospel work;
                                that Truth may triumph, and the voice of Reason and Conscience may be heard. We should
                                not be encouraged, if we feel that the work progresses slowly ; rather let us enter into
                                the sublime patience of the Lord, and trust Him to weave our little threads (one at a
                                time) into the great web, though the whole pattern is not shown us. God's people must be
                                willing to labor and wait for the fruit; remembering that one day with the Lord is as a
                                thousand years, and that the grand harvest of the ages shall come to its reaping in good
                                time, and the day shall broaden into a thousand years, and the thousand shall show one
                                perfect and finished day. I realize that I am but as a grain of sand, possessing neither
                                large talent, nor power. But my sympathy and prayers are enlisted in the glorious cause
                                of advancing truth ; and I will strive to " let Patience have her perfect work," and
                                bring forth her celestial fruits. Angels bless the patient in spirit, and let us all be
                                co-laborers with them; and while we toil to sow the good seed, and look around us for
                                duties to perform, let us look up to a higher source for strength to discharge those
                                duties, and for our reward. Our Captain and Pattern said, " Lo, I am with you always!"
                                With such a promise to cheer us onward, why should we not willingly toil and pray —
                                trusting in humble confidence — giving our hearts to God in grateful adoration ?</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Witham, Maria" TEIform="persName"/>Maria Witham, Enfield, Ct.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Self-denial" TEIform="index"/>SELF-DENIAL</head><p TEIform="p"> If we make progress God-ward, it will be through self-denial, the opposite of self-indul-
                            gence. The all-wise God has given laws to regulate and govern our actions. If we study and
                            obey those laws we shall find protection, and be saved from the sorrows and troubles that
                            all feel who violate them. We, as dependent beings, are but small particles in God's
                            universe of intelligence, and can do nothing without the aid of his Spirit to quicken and
                            animate our souls. We may be endowed with intellect and natural talent, but unless we
                            cultivate the moral and spiritual part of our being, we do not answer the design for which
                            we were created, and shall be accountable for the non-improvement of our highest faculties.
                            If we realize our dependence, and in childlike simplicity ask assistance, believing that He
                            who hears the cry of the raven, and clothes the lily of the vale, will also hear and reward
                            us if we diligently seek, then we shall realize the truth of the promise,"Ask and ye shall
                            receive." By denying the cravings of the carnal mind we triumph over the lower passions
                            which yield no abiding pleasure, and make room in our hearts for God's Spirit to dwell,
                            which, by degrees, will educate and lead us into all truth and teach that we were created
                            for a noble purpose — to find and occupy a sphere above the animal plane. Laying aside
                            worldly wisdom and seeking through child-like innocence and trust, for the wisdom of God,
                            the understanding becomes enlightened, and doubts and fears are dispelled from the mind. We
                            find that it requires strong faith and as great self-denial in us (as it did in Abraham of
                            old) to make a full sacrifice and^ivi the whole heart to God. But those who thus dedicate
                            all will receive a great reward. Their souls will be as a watered garden, they will be
                            neither barren nor unfruitful, but will eat and drink of living bread and waters and thirst
                            no more.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Middleton, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>Mary Middleton, Union Village, Ohio</byline></div2><pb n="63" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beauty" TEIform="index"/>BEAUTY</head><p TEIform="p">In what does real beauty consist ? There is a beauty in personal form and feature ; and there
                            are many beauties in Nature and Art, but the highest, crowning beauty of all is, that of
                            souls, made pure by obedience to truth, and love to holiness. Untarnished by sin — faithful
                            in every duty — they shine with a brightness that nought but purity of life can give. The
                            soul that has subdued, in itself, all that is evil, and is moved and governed by high and
                            holy motives, looking beyond natural things, to the Divine Spirit, for light, life and
                            strength; who freely consecrates time, talents and strength of body and mind, to the service
                            of God, attains to a high degree of holiness and forms a type of soul beauty. It is not
                            enough for us to perceive, admire, and love such beauty in others; we should labor to follow
                            their example and unfold the true and beautiful in our own characters ; and manifest our
                            love to God, by cheerfully sacrificing that which is self-pleasing, for the good of others.
                            To soothe and comfort the weary — bind up the broken spirit and gently lead the erring into
                            the path of truth and right should be our highest aim. This will make the soul beautiful!</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Martin, Florence" TEIform="persName"/>Florence Martin, Union Village, O.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Peace at last" TEIform="index"/>PEACE AT LAST</head><p TEIform="p">I sought in vain for comfort, in pleasures of the world; I saw its brightest visions turn to
                            mis'ries untold; I walk'd through scenes of sorrow, trusting earthly pow'r, To sustain my
                            fainting spirit in the trying hour. I've made (Oh! God forgive me) idols on the earth, And
                            worship'd them, forsaking things of greater worth ; But all those things have vanish'd, and
                            in sorrow deep Left me alone — forsaken — to wander and to weep. Now, rays of light are
                            shining; in the distance I can see Hope, Religion,— many treasures indeed are left to me ;
                            Forsaking earthly pleasures, I turn to thee OGod! And humbly walk before thee in the path
                            that Jesus trod. Now, joy and consolation, my wearied soul has found, In seeking full
                            salvation on Zion's holy ground; Devoting all my efforts to serve and worship God, I'll bow
                            in true submission, and bless his chast'ning rod. He has led me out of bondage — sooth'd me
                            with his love — And taught me to prepare for a heav'nly home above.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To the temperance band" TEIform="index"/>TO THE TEMPERANCE BAND</head><p TEIform="p">We unto you in kindly greeting, Waft our blessing and our love ; Praying that each temperance
                            meeting, Will to souls a blessing prove. Ask for aid, it will be given ; Guardian friends
                            are hovering near ; Look to God for strength and comfort, He the cause will guide and cheer.
                            Seraphims of love and mercy, Go before and chant the song, Beaming light, truth and
                            conviction; This will make your army strong. Hear ye not the voice of Angels, Hovering o'er
                            each valiant band, Speaking love and inspiration, Giving strength to heart and hand ?
                            Persevere, perform your mission, God resery'd this work for you, Many souls in deep
                            contrition, Will your path with blessings strew. Pear ye not; fulfill your duty, Angels
                            chant the song of life! Female messengers of mercy, Will subdue the stormy strife.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Riley, Nancy P." TEIform="persName"/>Nancy P. Riley, W. Pittsfield, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pure love" TEIform="index"/>PURE LOVE</head><p TEIform="p">Pure Love is a celestial gem; nothing earthborn can compare with it. Love contains within
                            itself the germs of all other gifts and graces. Purity of heart, Charity which suffers long,
                            mercy and forgiveness are all found in love's embraces, and are the legitimate fruits which
                            flow therefrom. May I be clothed with the beautiful spirit of love ; may it constitute my
                            chief adorning while I dwell in an earthly form, and fit me for the companionship of pure
                            spirits in the land of light and love! Then with the wise virgins of our own time, I shall
                            be prepared to go forth bearing the lamp of truth in my hand that will shed light upon the
                            pathway of the pilgrim traveler, and shall be ready to make efforts to raise the fallen, and
                            point them to the path of virtue — the straight and narrow way that leads to happiness — to
                            the Fountain of all good.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitely, Mary A." TEIform="persName"/>Mary A. Whitely, Shirley, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thy work" TEIform="index"/>THY WORK</head><p TEIform="p">A constant dropping of the good Will wear away the stony heart, Where flame of fire, and
                            deluge flood, Could not vitality impart. Continue then thy little deeds Of kindness, love,
                            and sweet control; For greatest gifts are to the needs, And highest love is to the soul.
                            Pray on, work on; the light is near, A perfect light and life in God ; Thou hast no earthly
                            ill to fear, When with the truth thy feet are shod. The dawn of day that bursts in light, Is
                            hid behind one lonely hill; The sun ascends and flees the night, That we may work with God's
                            pure will. And where is God ? by things well seen We trace the order of his place; In male
                            and female to redeem, And lead the chosen heirs of grace. Endued with wisdom and with love,
                            Whose attributes they jointly share; Uplifting souls to realms above, Two powers as one for
                            Zion care.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>Mary Whitcher, Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Laws of health" TEIform="index"/>LAWS OF HEALTH</head><p TEIform="p">Dr. Everett, a graduate of the University of Pennsylvania, has been lecturing to the citizens
                            of Newburg on the laws of health. He claims that health, moral character, and the temperance
                            question depend upon physiology ; that diseased conditions of the nervous system render
                            people peevish and profane, and establish the demand for alcoholic stimulants. The doctor
                            argues that so long as mothers and children are fed upon pickles, pepper and other
                            irritants, there will be an after demand for strong coffee and tea, tobacco and alcohol ;
                            that our temperance agitation is a practical failure, because we do not have it on
                            scientific principles — that is, that the food question is at the base of the temperance
                            question. The appetite grows by what it is fed on, and highly seasoned and stim- ulating
                            food indulged in for a series of years naturally begets an appetite for something still more
                            stimulating.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Women's physiological society" TEIform="index"/>WOMEN'S PHYSIOLOGICAL SOCIETY</head><p TEIform="p">The movement of the ladies to organize and sustain a Physiological Society in this city is
                            certainly deserving of praise. That such a society should be talked about here is a good
                            sign, and that it is progressing and gives promise of long life is a matter of
                            congratulation. How to dress healthfully, to eat hygienically, and to live in all things
                            temperately is what the society proposes to teach, and that the ladies are determined to
                            accomplish their purpose is evidenced by their zeal and enthusiasm in the undertaking. How
                            much wiser such an effort is than the at present useless plans of the women is to be found
                            in this fact, that these ladies have started out to reform themselves. They propose to begin
                            at their own tables, at their own firesides, and with their own toilettes. They will
                            simplify their costumes, and being strong as a society they will grow strong as individuals.
                            This they tell us, in the reports of their meetings, they intend to do, and seeing how much
                            is to be done in the line they have chosen we prefer to believe that they are in earnest.
                            They have made a great move forward when they acknowledge that the dress of women requires
                            social legislation, and with this acknowledgment volunteered, and the as voluntary promise
                            of a change for the bettejr, there is certainly reason for public gratification.— Ex.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If some men died and others did not, death would indeed be a most mortifying evil" TEIform="index"/>If some men died and others did not, death would indeed be a most mortifying evil
                        </head><p TEIform="p">If some men died and others did not, death would indeed be a most mortifying evil.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="[Bruyere]" TEIform="persName"/>[Bruyere.]</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Temperance cause" TEIform="index"/>THE TEMPERANCE CAUSE</head><p TEIform="p">May God bless the woman's righteous war between rum and reform, and bring forth victory by
                            laying low earth's deadliest enemies — intoxicating liquor and lust! Like fiery demons — red
                            dragons — they enter many peaceful home-circles to despoil and lay waste ; breeding therein
                            a writhing, wretched mass of wild scorpions, to corrode, poison and bring to the very death,
                            all hope of peace and prosperity. Thereby many noble forms are leveled to the dust, no more
                            to rise, but are shrouded in shame — covered with a pall of black despair. Again, God bless
                            the women crusaders who have engaged in the temperance cause. That work is committed to
                            their trust. Love and Prayer are the means — the spiritual weapons — by which they must work
                            and win. May they produce mighty results in the glorious reform so much needed. Ah! woman,
                            worthy worker! Every one who is struggling against intemperance, and for emancipation from
                            the slavery of sin, is worthy. God is your Leader, and we have faith that He will give you
                            the victory. The Shaker Sisterhood are with you in spirit, and reach forth the hand of
                            fellowship to all who are conscientiously engaged in the work, regardless of station,
                            wealth, color, or sect; and with you we uplift our voices in prayer, that God will speed the
                            good time coming when truth and righteousness shall reign throughout the whole earth; when
                            peace shall nil the land with joy and gladness, and mortals dwell together in unity as sons
                            and daughters of the New Creation of God — blest by Angels of light and love — children of
                            one heavenly Parentage. Once more we say, God bless the workers in the Temperance cause, and
                            speed the glorious end.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Signal light" TEIform="index"/>SIGNAL LIGHT</head><p TEIform="p">Ts my bark launch'd on an unknown sea Dividing time from eternity? Without chart, or compass,
                            by which to steer, Must I toss on these waves of hope and fear? In vain I look ahead for a
                            light; The foam crested billows alone meet my sight! O 1 where shall I turn for a skillful
                            hand, To pilot me safe to the better land? 0 that a dove from some isle of the sea — Would
                            bring as to Noah — a message to me ! But no dove appears —no mast can I spy — To awaken the
                            hope, that a haven is nigh. And, while I am looking in vain for a sail— 1 tremble with fear,
                            my bark is so frail; So I lift up my voice, and supplicate aid From that Power, whose
                            mandate the sea hath obeyed. Thou Almighty Power, thy help I implore ! Guide safely my bark
                            'till my voyage is o'er! And whatever course thy hand shall direct, I'll trustingly steer,
                            if thou wilt protect. But what is that glory which bursts on my sight? Though far in the
                            distance, 'tis heaven's pure light; A signal on high is hung out for me, It is the bright
                            beacon of purity. Can that be a mirage, I see through the haze. The beautiful landscape that
                            now meets my gaze. With soft-tinted flowers, and fruit-laden trees, And groves with green
                            foliage sway'd by the breeze? Ah, soon shall my soul its reality test! Devotion secures me
                            the haven of rest; That soul-cheering thought has inspir'd my mind To buffet these billows,
                            that haven to find.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Persons, A. E." TEIform="persName"/>A. E. Persons, Harvard, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Never despair" TEIform="index"/>NEVER DESPAIR</head><p TEIform="p">These are the hopeful words of the Christian. Yet there are times, when even hopeful, trust-
                            ing Christians have felt sinkings, akin to despair. Jesus, on the cross, cried " My God, my
                            God, why hast thou forsaken me?" Yet God is ever nigh to aid suffering, humble spirits,
                            though he permits their trials to prove them and show them their dependence on Him. It is
                            often, when the cloud, is darkest, that the sun suddenly shines forth. Aid does not always
                            come as we look for it, in our own natural wisdom ; but in ways that convince us of the
                            watchfulness of our good Heavenly Parents over us. It is through severe trials and
                            tribulations that the saints are tried as gold.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ervin, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>Anna Ervin, Enfield, Ct.</byline></div2><pb n="64" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Keys of revelation" TEIform="index"/>KEYS OF REVELATION</head><p TEIform="p">1. The type of life progressive, Viewed by a seer of old, The pure and shining way, The
                            messengers of heaven Ee visit earth today. To the enlightened vision In meaning
                            doth unfold. Ascending and de Bcending They come, O earth! to bless thee, Their loving
                            mission hail! They sow beside all waters The seed that cannot fail, Truth's precious germs
                            upspringing Shall fruit immortal bear, Rich prophecy of blessing Which many souls will
                            share. The ministry of angels Shall light the darkened land, 'Till earth's benighted
                            children God's power will understand; 'Till Babel towers of error To their foundations reel,
                            And gilded temple glories A mighty shook will feel. 4. The keys of Revelation, Which long
                            were doomed to rust, Now open the golden portals Of saving faith and trust; The soul unfolds
                            her opinions To rise from nature's gloom, For strength of resurrection Lies not within her
                            tomb.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Item" TEIform="index"/>An Item</head><p TEIform="p">— The day has overtaken us wherein we have the happy privilege to be participants in the
                            increase of Christ's Kingdom. In what line of action will that increase manifest itself ?
                            Will it be in forms of belief, about which graceless bigots fight ? or in a right life,
                            which all can commend, and about which all can agree. If in a right life, what may be the
                            laws which govern that life? The laws of that life are threefold. First. Divine law,
                            manifested by benevolence, mercy and aspirations God-ward. Second. Moral law — love your
                            neighbor as yourself. Third. Hygienic law — do nothing against your own body. The increase
                            of Christ's Kingdom will apply these laws to all the ramifications of human emotion, thought
                            and action, till there is nothing in us that is not of God.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="F., D." TEIform="persName"/>D. F.</byline></div2><div2 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Best pathfinders" TEIform="index"/>The Best Pathfinders</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Do my young Americans know who are the best pathfinders on the American
                                    continent, the great original pathfinders of the West ? I'll tell you. They are the
                                    buffaloes. Yes, sir, it's true. Hear what a correspondent of St. Nicholas writes
                                    with the quill of a dear graygoose friend of mine: As the frosts of winter destroy
                                    their pastures in the north, so the heats of summer parch those in the south, and
                                    the buffaloes must, each spring and autumn, take long journeys in search of fresh
                                    feeding grounds. The large size and weight of these somewhat clumsy explorers make
                                    it rather difficult for them to cross the mountains, so they seek out for themselves
                                    the most practicable routes; and hunters and emigrants have found that a "
                                    buffalo-track " offers the surest and safest path for men and horses. The best
                                    passes in the Cumberland and Rocky mountains, and the regions of the Yellowstone,
                                    and the Colorado, have oeen discovered by following the trail of these sagacious
                                    animals. I know this is so, for the great traveler, Humboldt, once wrote : " In this
                                    way the humble buffalo has filled a most important part in facilitating geographical
                                    discovery in mountainous regions, otherwise as trackless as the Arctic wastes, as
                                    the sands of Sahara." </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Jack-in-the-pulpit" TEIform="index"/>Jack-in-the-Pulpit</bibl></cit> St. Nicholas for December.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rule" TEIform="index"/>Rule</head><p TEIform="p">Eat that which is the best until you love it the best.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to have sound teeth" TEIform="index"/>How to Have Sound Teeth</head><p TEIform="p">The Science of Health says : <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Mushes, gruels, puddings and soups maybe made hygienically. But they should also
                                    be eaten hygienically. They must be chewed, not bolted. The nursing infant
                                    masticates its mother's milk, for which purpose it takes it slowly, drop by drop.
                                    Mastication is for the purpose of insalivation. Unless food is properly insalivated,
                                    it cannot be well digested. The teeth are the finest, densest structure of the body,
                                    and this means they are intended for hard work. Eat solid food at every meal; and
                                    when you take semi-liquid, or very soft food of any kind, eat very slowly and take a
                                    bit of hard bread, crackers, a green apple, or something similar, with it. Then will
                                    your stomach please and be pleased, and your teeth, like your eyes and nose, and
                                    fingers and toes, will remain to bless and comfort you to the last. If all persons,
                                    after being weaned, would only chew their food enough, we would hear very little of
                                    aching and rotten teeth, and dentists would be nowhere."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Science of health" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New saint" TEIform="index"/>A New Saint</head><p TEIform="p">Among the deceased men and women, good, bad and indifferent, canonized by the present "
                            venerable prisoner " of the Vatican, and set forth for the prayers of the faithful as
                            intercessors with God, is Peter Arbaes. Being Inquisitor General of the Spanish Inquisi-
                            tion, he won golden opinions by the zeal, selfdenial and faithfulness with which he burned
                            heretical men, women and babies. The Ninth Pius seems as unlucky in his saints as in his
                            dogmas. But tastes always have differed, and Peter Arbaes is not the first red-handed wretch
                            who has been canonized. "'In the prosecution of the examinations,'we are told in the Acta
                            Sanctorum, 'no groans nor cries could move him; in the execution of the dreadful sentence he
                            was turned aside neither by prayers nor tears.' It was in the age when Columbus was
                            preparing to reveal anew world, and when knowledge was already teaching humanity to kings
                            and nobles, that our modern saint was sentencing women and feeble children to the flames,
                            and was filling happy households with intolerable dread ; was searching for his victims with
                            barbarous assiduity, and stood among his fellow-citizens dripping with gore. Hated no doubt
                            like Torquemada, who liever went unarmed —feared with more than mortal dread —the Chief
                            Inquisitor pursued his career of bloodshed unchecked for several years, and deserved the
                            highest approval of his ruthless church. At last came his martyrdom, or rather the
                            inadequate punishment for his enormous crimes. He was assassinated in the church of
                            Saragossa by two young men, the father of one of whom had been imprisoned, and the sister of
                            the other burned at the stake. "Such is a Roman Catholic saint and martyr! The murderer of
                            the innocent is held up to his clergy by Pius IX as an example worthy of imitation, and the
                            most horrible form of blind fanaticism receives the sanction of the infallible Pope."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="C., C. I." TEIform="persName"/>C. I. C.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My guardians" TEIform="index"/>MY GUARDIANS</head><p TEIform="p">Unseen hands are daily sowing Precious seed of love and care; In my soul I feel them
                            growing,— Germs of truth develop there. And I know the source is heaven — Whence these
                            treasures come to me ; Though by impress they be given, Or through mortal agency. Let me
                            hold a claim upon you,— Spirit friends released from time; Deal to me of wisdom, prudence,
                            Strength and love, from purer clime. I, so weak and erring, daily Need a watchful Savior
                            near; Such be thou to guide my footsteps, Keep my spirit free and pure. Teach me lessons
                            true and holy,— Rudiments of higher life; Fit my soul to dwell with angels When I cease the
                            mortal strife. Teach me, while on earth I journey, How to live with saints below; — How to
                            keep my union sacred, And in heavenly graces grow.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Martin, Elizabeth" TEIform="persName"/>Elizabeth Martin, Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sometime ago petitions were addressed to Congress..." TEIform="index"/>Sometime ago petitions were addressed to Congress...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Sometime ago petitions were addressed to Congress, asking for an amendment to the Con-
                            stitution of the United States, so that that instrument should contain " an acknowledgment
                            of Almighty God and the Christian religion." These petitions were referred to the Judiciary
                            Committee of the House, and last week that body presented an adverse report thereon. The
                            Committee say that the matter was the subject of grave deliberation on the part of the
                            framers of the Constitution, who finally quite unanimously agreed that, inasmuch as this
                            country was to be the home of the people of all nations, pagan as well as Christian, it was
                            inexpedient to put any thing in the Constitution which might be construed as a reference
                            to-any religious creed or doctrine. The Committee are opposed to any change at the present
                            time, and ask to be discharged from further consideration of the subject. This, we suppose,
                            ends the matter for the present. </p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>