<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2210" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">28</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">22</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">10</biblScope><date value="18921001" TEIform="date">October 1892</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">217-240</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="22" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="10" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
OCTOBER.
THE
MANIFESTO
Published by the United Societies.
VOL. XXII.
"For what is a man profited, if he shall gain the whole world, and
lose his own soul ? or what shall a man give in exchange for
his soul."Matt. XVI., 26.
Canterbury, N. H.
1892.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
TTIE  MANIFESTO.
CONTENTS.
Page.
hhakensm,       -          -          -          -          -         217
The Bible, Xo.->,                          .          .          .     21!)
Certificate of ( oiin,niation.        -          -         220
Letter:b\ YV. Evans,              -           -          -      "
T. Kvans,              -           -           -         222
Honesty,            -                                            iifi
They Say,   - -....         227
A Literary Curiosity,         ...                     "
K.!it->rial."               -                       -           -           -         228
Life KtMK'weil,            ...           -                 231
Home Xotes.        ._.._"
Let Bygones bo Bygones.             -           -                  237
()ur M'other ia Deity,   -          -          -          -         238
Deaths,            .*....                      "
MusicJordan,   - - - - -         230
Books & Papers,        ....                  240
Scientific American
Agency for
CAVEATS,
 TRADE MARKS,
DESIGN PATENTS
COPYRIGHTS, etc
For information and free Handbook write to
MUNN & CO., 361 Broadway, New York.
Oldest bureau for securing patents in America.
Every patent taken out by us is brought before
the public by a notice given free of charge in. the
Largest circulation of any scientific paper in the
world. Splendidly illustrated. No intelligent
man should be without it. "Weekly, S3.00 a
year; $1.50 six months. Address MUNN & CO.,
Publishers, 361 Broadway, New York.
The Celebrated
BAND  INSTRUMENTS,
8nars and Baa9 Drums, Fires,   Ptccoios, Clarionets. Cynv
Dais and all other instruments pertaining toBrass Bands and Drum Corps.
THE 0BHV1SB
JOHN F. 8TRATTON & SON,
43   &   45   Walker   Street.   NEW   YORK.
If toc cannot get them op toot
local  dealers,   we  whx  find 60mb
WA!   OF  8UVPLYING   TOU  wIlB THE
STRATTON
RUSSrAN  CUT
VIOLIN STRINGS.
Deatos send for Catalogue and Price List
JOHN F   STRATTON & SON,
 M usic al Me r cha nt> i ;; e.
fi a 4.1 Walker Su.        NEW Y0KK
AGENTS WANTED
ON
Salary
OK
Commission,
FOR
JOHN L. STODDARD'S
GLIMPSES OF THE WORLD,"
THE    WORLD'S   COLUMBIAN
EXPOSITION,    MEN  AND ISSUES
OF '92.
BEST BOOKS.  BEST SYSTEM.
BEST TERMS.
,\elclress-Willey & Co., 195-197
State St., Springfield, Mass.
E. C. Morris & Co.
64 Sudbury St.,  Boston, Kass.
FIRE AND BIMLAR-PROOF SAFES.
Bank Safes, Bank Vaults, Bank Vault
Doors, and Deposit Work of all kinds.
The Best Safe in the World.   750,000 in use.
Always preserve their content*
150 sold in Lynn, Mass., since that great tiro
where f>0 of our .safes were subject to intense
heat, preserving' their con tents.
Champion Record also in the Great Chicago Fire in 1871, in the Great Boston Firt in
1872, and in all the great tires since. Send
for circulars.        Agents Wanted.
Vol. XXII.
OCTOBER, 1892.
No. 10.--><pb n="217" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakerism" TEIform="index"/> SHAKERISM.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo G." TEIform="persName"/> Alonzo G. Hollister.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Under this caption in a paper of the far West, are remarks which seem to ask for a reply.
                            Dr. Allyn says, "If the object of a Shaker life is to provide a comfortable home for those
                            who are physiologically disqualified to become parents of healthy children, it seems to be a
                            sensible one. But writers do not announce this as the object." Of course not, because that
                            would not be true. And is that the only sensible object a stranger can see in a Shaker life,
                            or is it merely thrown out as a feeler to invite discussion ? If said object were sufficient
                            inducement to live the Shaker life, I doubt not but there would now be from five to ten
                            thousand Shakers for every one existing.. It is questionable if such a motive would have
                            sufficient cohesive attraction to hold ^ a community of working people together in the
                            present state of human evolution. The object of a Shaker life, is purely religious and
                            spiritual. It is not in any sense an appendage nor supplement to the social life of the
                            world, but is an advance step in evolution and spiritual growth, both as it regards the
                            individual and his associations. They look upon the passional life of the world, and upon
                            the relations growing out of marriage as rudimental and transitory, and as being detrimental
                            to the true interest and happiness of a large class of individuals, even in its most
                            prosperous state. They view the higher mental and spiritual planes of existence,which all
                            animal and partial affections, all earthly and selfish desires, all physical methods of
                            propagation and their attendant delights are utterly debarred from entering,as open prizes
                            offered to all who will voluntarily sacrifice the lower and transitory, in conformity with
                            the laws of the higher and permanent. We say it requires the best manhood and womanhood, the
                            morally developed and clearest sighted, the pure intentioned, strong-willed, firm in purpose
                            and long enduring, self-abnegating and level-headed men and women to fill the ideal of a
                            Shaker life and make it a success. With wise and competent leaders, of unbending rectitude
                            and integrity of purpose, for teachers and guides, some persons of inferior character but
                            morally inclined, can be made over into new creatures, providing there is willingness in the
                                <pb n="218" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> subject to co-operate and be formed anew after the pattern of the
                            ideal set forth by the leaders. The Shaker system is yet in its infancy, and can not in its
                            present stage of growth become a lying-in hospital for incurables ; nor a nursery for those
                            imperfectly organized, who need the constant supervising care of such as imprudently gave
                            them defective organizations. Neither at present, is it an asylum for those who have
                            consumed to a stump their mental and physical energies in the dissipation of carnal
                            pleasure. Not from any unwillingness to aid the unfortunate, but because k would be taking
                            the burden from where it justly belongs, to work its own cure, to where it would be too
                            heavy to bear, nor remedy its cause. If "writers tell how much literature they have in their
                            libraries, how comfortable they are, their dietetic habits and how they elect their
                            leaders," it is because there is request for that kind of information. The object of Shaker
                            life is selfconquest ; salvation from all wrong doing, from selfishness, to be utterly rid
                            of the carnal life and will, through a perfect moral, intellectual and spiritual obedience
                            to the commandments of God, as taught by Christ Jesus and his messengers, and approved by
                            rational understanding. It is to die to the corrupt, fluctuating, passionate, conflicting,
                            mutating and transient, pleasure seeking animal life of the world, that we may be
                            resurrected and created anew in the pure, perfect, heavenly and eternal life of the angelic
                            societies, whose greatest delight is in serving, and ministering to the happiness of others.
                            "We believe this course of life produces the highest order of spiritual teachers and
                            ministers of righteousness, harmony and healing, who diffuse the light of the only true and
                            endless life upon all the children of men that are prepared to profit thereby. It can be
                            demonstrated by facts, and by philosophic reasoning, and is co-attested by esoteric
                            Buddhism, by thaumaturgists, and by prophetic seers of the best moral character, that the
                            highest spiritual attainments can be acquired only by virgin chastity and continence, and
                            the total crucifixion of the passions and appetites of the carnal mind. Physical trainers
                            demonstrate that continence and subjugation of appetite and passion to the rule of reason,
                            are necessary to the best health and efficiency even of the body. Shaker life enables many
                            to do this who do not possess more than ordinary natural talent, but whose dominant desire
                            is to live a sinless life, in accord with their purest ideal, approved by a couscience which
                            will not acquit till their best is done. Whoever feels that the perpetuation of the species
                            is a moral duty incumbent on him or her, should seek a partner of like opinion, and
                            discharge that obligation to the best of his abilitj, never infringing on the right of
                            offspring to be well born and wisely educated. Shakers being called out from the world for a
                            specific purpose, by the Intelligence which is supposed to have created the world and
                            ordained the laws by which it should for a time be peopled, consider themselves released
                            from that obligation, if such it <pb n="219" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> be, both by their call, and by
                            assuming higher obligations, if they have not previously taken part in that business. If it
                            be argued that propagation is a universal law, we reply that some of its forms and methods
                            are not universal, and as before stated, that physical passions and methods are totally
                            excluded from the higher mental and spiritual planes of life. It will be readily
                            comprehended from the foregoing premises, that any who are satisfied with themselves and the
                            world as they are by their natural birth; who wish not to forsake worldly ways and
                            relationships, nor to change their natural dispositions, unless they be somewhat superior to
                            the average moral btandard of the world, would not make congruous and acceptable members of
                            a Christian or Shaker Community. Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bible. no. 2" TEIform="index"/> THE BIBLE. No. 2.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Eads, H. L." TEIform="persName"/> H. L. EADS.</byline><p TEIform="p"> We must all enter the narrow way, single file, through the confessional, giving our lives,
                            judgment and will in obedience to God and his Order. The only alteration possible is to take
                            a strip from the broad way and add it to the narrow and make it wide enough for two ; and if
                            this is better, why did not Christ think of it ? I am further cited to books which are
                            considered authority, that make a distinction between the "Bible" and "God's word," and it
                            is thought by some that the Bible itself makes some such distinction by saying the word of
                            God is spiritual, quick, piercing, powerful, sharper than a two-edged sword. This is very
                            true, and this very word is contained in both the Old and New Testament Scriptures. When
                            Nathan said to David, "Thou art the man !" this was God's inspired word. The idea conveyed
                            by that God-spoken word pierced him to the heart, causing him to prostrate himself and
                            writhe in agony and tears. The inquirer quotes the prophet: ' 'Is not my word like as fire
                            and like a hammer which breaks the rock in pieces ?" and then adds the Bible is not these ;
                            mistaken again; this is precisely what the Bible is composed of, the "words are like swords
                            and fire in the bones, etc.," take all such away and there would be but little Bible left.
                            Remember words can not be entities. Let me place it syllogistically before you: 1 am still
                            asked : If all Bibles were destroyed, would that destroy God's word ? Not at all. It would
                            take from the world that part of his word therein contained that could not be remembered.
                            But God could produce the same identical word through a second Ezra. I now think it is
                            clearly proven that the Bible contains God's inspired word; but in order to show that it
                            contains only a fraction of God's word, I am cited to the apostle John, who said :"If all
                            things that Jesus said were written, the world could not contain the books." It would be
                            more clear if it read : The world would not contain them. The apostle did not mean that
                            there would not be room on the globe for them, but that the world the people of the
                            worldcould not <pb n="220" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> bear the testimony; they would destroy them. If Jesus
                            had talked from that day to this the globe could contain them all printed in large pica, ten
                            feet deep, and room to spare. Again I am asked: "Is it correct to say that we are founded on
                            the scriptures of the New Testament ?" I answer it is ; for no other foundation can man lay.
                            Whatever of God's word may be found throughout the earth, the highest and best is that given
                            through Jesus, the Christ. O, the riches of the truth, wisdom and knowledge, that have been
                            poured upon the world through that instrumentality ! It is unfathomable ; at every touch a
                            new flash penetrates the honest, inquiring mind, and every knee should bow and every tongue
                            should confess this to the honor and glory of God. In support of this I have the honor of
                            quoting B. B. Dunla vy : "Whosoever cuts loose from the Biblethe Old and New Testaments,
                            which are the only safe anchor for the salvation of a lost worldhe will cast his feeble
                            barque upon the angry waves of fanaticism, to be stranded upon the first rocks or breakers
                            he may encounter. Such a course would carry the world back to where Jesus found it, in
                            darkness and ignorance, and even worse, for then they had hopes of a Messiah ; now they
                            would be without hope." This quotation, I consider contains plain truth. We need not look
                            for some new revelation, or new way of redemption, since what Christ has given will save to
                            the uttermost all who will acceptput it in the practice of their daily livesmore than this
                            no new revelation can do. Therefore, I say, with the text, other, or better, foundation can
                            no man lay than that is laid, which is Jesus Christ. South Union, Ky.</p></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Office of The Guiding Star Publishing House, 3619 Cottage Grove Avenue, Chicago, June 26th. 1892" TEIform="index"/> Office of The Guiding Star Publishing House, 3619 Cottage Grove Avenue, Chicago, June
                            26th. 1892.</head><p TEIform="p">Mount Lebanon, N. Y. July 3, 1892. Certificate of Confirmation of the election of Victoria
                            Gratia (Mrs. Annie G. Ordway) to the Presiding Office of the Gynecato of the Koreshan Unity.
                            We hereby declare our confirmation of the acceptance of Victoria, into our body as a member
                            of the North Family of Shakers at Mount Lebanon, N. Y., and our approval of her election to
                            the office, Shepherdess of the Gynecato of the Koreshan Unity, and we do hereby commission
                            her to Publish the Gospel of Sexual Holiness, as ordained in the body of Christian
                            Believers, called Shakers, and as in the same manner taught by the Koreshan Unity. In
                            approval of her appointment, election and ratification to her appointment we ordaiu by the
                            affixing of our signatures ( In Witness </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, Frederick W.; Offord, Daniel; White, Anna; Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>Frederick W. Evans. Daniel Offord. Anna White. Martha J. Anderson.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dearly Beloved Br. Cyrus:--We have received the document you sent..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Dearly Beloved Br. Cyrus:--We have received the document you sent...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon, July 4, 1892" TEIform="index"/>Mount Lebanon, July 4, 1892.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dearly Beloved Br. Cyrus :We have received the document you sent by the sisters requesting
                            our endorsement, and the ordination of Annie G. Ordway as an Eldress in the community which
                            you are forming. This will make Cyrus and Annie <pb n="221" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> the Leaders and Elders
                            of the New Order. A nursing father and a nursing mother to those who will confess and
                            forsake all their sins that come to their remembrance. "I take to witness the grace of the
                            people for to come, (said a prophet) for they shall call their sins to remembrance and
                            acknowledge them." I did stand in some little doubt, not as to whether you had received a
                            call of the Spirit to gather a prepared people upon the foundation of the testimony of
                            Christ's Second Appearing in the female order of humanity, but as to the use you would make
                            of it: Jesus said, "all who came before me were thieves and robbers," by which expression,
                            we understand that from Moses to John the Baptist, than whom a greater prophet had not
                            arisen, all had more or less taken the gift of the spirit to make of themselves some "great
                            one," building up themselves as did Moses. "Shall I bring water out of this rock for you, ye
                            rebels ?" Even Jesus after his temple exercise, remembered the Scripture, "the zeal of thy
                            house hath eaten me up" (as a Christian) eaten up his Christianity, as for the time being he
                            was under the inspiration of the God of Israel, the God of the temple. The Christ spirit
                            reproved and convicted him and he learned obedience by what he suffered. Then the disciples
                            asked him to call fire down from heaven to kill the villagers $ who refused to receive them,
                            as had done Elias; he replied: "the Son of man hath not come to destroy men's lives, as the
                            Jews destroyed the Canaanites and as Elias killed a company, but to save their souls from
                            the sensuality and lust which produce all murders and all wars. The wonderful document you
                            have sent for us to sign, clears up the little doubt and plainly shows you as a Christian
                            and that it is not your intention to "set up a post by God's post" and to build up yourself
                            with, the spiritual truths revealed to open the second degree of the seven that will
                            constitute the full testimony of Christ's Second Appearing. Each degree will have its own
                            peculiar testimony against certain forms of evilits thunder. In this way will the man of sin
                            be revealed, and the sins of Babylon set forth singly and its opposite virtue declared.
                            Sexual sensuality will be removed by sexual celibacy and purity. The physical resurrection
                            will be displaced by the rising, as did Jesus, while still in the body, up into the Christ
                            life far above generation in its purest form of simple procreation as practiced by a line of
                            preternatural births in prophets and prophetesses, under the law of Moses, which did not
                            make the Comers thereunto perfect. Competitive private property will yield to "all things in
                            common;" and land monopoly to "no right to land only in usufruct." These things the Shakers
                            have preached and practiced for the last one hundred years ; and now as a progressive
                            people- ask "what lack I yet ?" Why are we apparently so stationary? The Koreshans are
                            opening the second degree of the seven; they, if faithful, will add thereunto vegetarianism,
                            abstinence from eating flesh-meat of any kind, sheep, kine, fowl, fish, hogs. Land
                            limitation, recognizing the fact that a community has no more right <pb n="222" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> to
                            land-monopoly than has an individual. As Jefferson said : "No man has right to land only in
                            usufruct." Entire abstinence from alcoholic drink's from brandy to cider; from shaving; from
                            coffee, tea, opium; from all poisonous medicines and from bleeding; from tobacco. And they
                            will hold work as religious worship. "At the first, Wisdom, revealed in the Motherhood of
                            God, leadeth her children by crooked paths and brings fear and dread upon them, torments
                            them by her laws until she can trust their souls, then she returns the straight way unto
                            them, comforts and shows them her secrets." A spiritually prepared people in the world will
                            begin with the Second Cycle. ' 'Gather my saints together, those who have made a covenant
                            with me by sacrifice." They will come from the west, east, north and south for the gospel
                            testimony as held by Believers and will receive the kingdom as little children. They need
                            not come, all, physically to Mount Lebanon any more than all creation will go to Judea, to
                            Jerusalem, to this temple, "this mountain" to worship. God is spirit, and those who worship
                            him in spirit and truth can do it in any part of the earth as well as on this Mount Lebanon.
                            The Shaker Communities began poor, suffered persecution. When they prospered they bought all
                            the land that joined them to the extent of their means, supposing they were thus redeeming
                            the earth. As they monopolized land they cultivated it by hired world's men, also many began
                            to gather from lower motivesthe loaves and fishes; people who wanted a home ; widows and
                            widowers with their children. As these children by hundreds became men and women they
                            married, having more or less condemnation for casting off their faith of celibacy according
                            as they had received. They went out from amongst us because they were not of us. Thus Shaker
                            Societies have become eleemosynary institutionspoor-houses in a degree, and we are land
                            poor. But a great work has been done and is progressing rapidly. The spirit world is
                            helping. We want Koresh to adopt and to be in the power of the first cycle and in the
                            increase of the second cycle ; want his people to be as much better than that in the old
                            Societies of Shakers as they can attain unto. There is no law against truth, goodness,
                            godliness. In the gospel travel, the first may be last and the last first. Who shall be the
                            least, not who shall be the greatest, is our aim, our labor. And we shall pray that you,
                            dear people, may clean escape all the evils, corruptions and abominations of the world
                            inherent in your own natures, the products of fleshly lusts that war against the soul. The
                            kingdom shall not be given to another people, but of its increase to order and establish it
                            in judgment there shall be no end.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, Frederick W." TEIform="persName"/> Frederick W. Evans.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="H. S. R.--San Francisco, Cal.  Dear Friend, Neighbor, Brother..." TEIform="index"/>
                            H. S. R.--San Francisco, Cal.  Dear Friend, Neighbor, Brother...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New Hampshire, East Canterbury, August 1892" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury, N. H.
                            Aug. 1892.</dateline><p TEIform="p">H. S. R.San Francisco, Cal. Dear Friend, Neighbor, Brother : Your letter of the 7th. inst.,
                            to Elder Henry Blinn gives me the opportunity <pb n="223" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> to write 37ou a line; a
                            line, first of all of congratulation on your commencement,a four-year commencement of trying
                            to become a better man, and your hitherto successful journey is an admitted advance upon
                            what you regard as the ordinary, church-going, Christian sinner. The exposition of practical
                            Christianity contained in our pamphlets that you obtained from Br. D., and to which you
                            allude as having given you general satisfaction, is quite a correct index of the character
                            of the daily lives of our people. As requested in your letter, we will all gladly unite in
                            taking both you and yours, lovingly and tenderly into our prayers to God for your full
                            salvation. That all the missteps of life can be fully recovered is in no case impossible,
                            else, hope would become engulfed in the whirlpool of despair. We live in the sober days of
                            soul evolution, that bring us away from the theories of religion, to religion itself, for
                            Theology, however finely spun out by learned Doctors of Divinity is not religion. True
                            religion brings us to, and keeps us writhin, the pale of the gospel of Jesus Christ, the
                            gospel of the New Testament. In these sacred chronicles, we find that every thing that is
                            asserted of him, is also asserted, in one form or another of his disciples, and in an equal
                            degree, of all true Christians. Does Jesus claim that he is one with the Father ? He also
                            prays that his disciples may be one with him and with God. In his high and perfect life
                            there was admittedly no room for evil thoughts or unworthy motives, and we are led to think
                            of him as the one sinless soul. In the gospel, he turns to his disciples,and to us and with
                            perfect confidence says, "Be ye perfect, even as your Father in heaven is perfect." The
                            divinity of Christ was a quality of the soul, not a supernatural power with which he is said
                            by some to be endowed as the second person in the Trinity. His divinity was a divinity of
                            character, the true divinity to which the humblest of his faithful followers may attain. If
                            Jesus could be pure in heart, resist temptation, suffer unjustly without complaint, lay down
                            his life for the truth, and all this in the character of an example to his followers, the
                            revelation of the gospel is the inspiring truth that God is incarnate in every human soul,
                            the true "light that lighteth every man that cometh into the wrorld," and it is the duty of
                            us all, alike, to accept this light for the guidance of our lives, and so become
                            participators of the Second Coming of Jesus Christ. That he knew full well, a few only would
                            receive his sayings, and that lie left it to their own option to choose or refuse them, is
                            evident in the saying : ' 'He that is able to receive it, let him receive it." The fact
                            remains that both he and his disciples denied themselves of all the carnal w'orks of the
                            flesh. They were neither married nor were given in marriage, and they lived a communal life,
                            "having all things in common, none saying that aught of the things which he possessed were
                            his own." This gospel that was not a matter of compulsion, but of free choice, meant
                            something. To every <pb n="224" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> self-denying soul, "that had left house, or
                            brethren, or sisters, or father, or mother, or wife, or children, or lands" for its sake, it
                            meant that he shall receive "an hundred fold now in this time, houses, and brethren and
                            sisters, and mothers, and children and lands, with persecution, and in the world to come
                            eternal life." In sundry times and divers manners, God has raised up witnesses to effect his
                            purposes. The Quakers were faithful, although they did not bear the full gospel testimony
                            concerning the root of human depravity. The French prophets of both sexes in 1688, numbering
                            about six hundred, gave themselves out to be inspired by the Holy Ghost, receiving the
                            spirit and testimony of the highest truth; their sayings being heard with reverent attention
                            and awe. In 1706 three or four of them came to England, bringing with them their prophetic
                            spirit, and before that year closed, this small number had been increased to as many hundred
                            of both sexes in and about London. Their prophetic inspiration was so active that they
                            foretold the near approach of the kingdom of the Messiah, the grand jubilee, the new heavens
                            and the new earth, by the delivery of about five hundred prophetic warnings, and that these
                            things were on the very eve of realization. A small body of people, who had been baptized
                            into the divine spirit, formed themselves into a Society in 1747, and eleven years
                            afterward, Ann Lee, accepted their testimony, being baptized with them into the same
                            inspiration. She received a deeper revelation of the divine Presence which the little
                            Society accepted as light from God. This spirit and testimony of higher truth has never
                            since been wanting, although not confined to any particular sect of people. Many earnest
                            souls who looked for the Second Coming of Christ have received this spirit, by whatever name
                            they have been known among men. Let me apply this brief history of truth's dawning light.
                            Although the foundation of the human race in the old creation is one man, it is not one man
                            alone. The man is not without the woman, nor the woman without the man. In like manner is
                            the foundation of the new creation. Jesus Christ in his single manhood could not in the
                            nature, the relation and order of things, be alone. In the primitive Church, woman had no
                            place. She was not permitted either to speak or to teach. Her time had not yet come. The
                            first appearance of Christthe "Christ of the Ages,"was in the man. He was alone. "He trod
                            the wine-press alone." To render redemption complete, the scheme of redemption must reach
                            fully to woman, the seat where sin first appeared. The Second Appearance of Christ,the
                            "Christ of the Ages,"in the very nature, the relation, the order of things should be in the
                            woman. The spirit and power which created man, inspired the prophets, that dwelt in Jesus,
                            that was given to the Apostles, and which was prophetically spoken of as a woman travailing
                            with child, was revealed' in a woman,a woman anointed of God to reveal the mystery of
                            iniquity, <pb n="225" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> and to finish the work of man's final redemption. History
                            finds her nowhere else than in the hnmble instrument, Ann Lee, who, by her travail of soul,
                            suffering and obedience, became the first-born of many Sisters in the new creation. The
                            existence of woman as an entity in the world, has, outside this church, never yet been
                            acknowledged. True, her rights have been and are canvassed, and a few of them tardily
                            accorded, but the franchise of life is a masculine franchise, and that alone. The only
                            recognition of woman is, that she is given in marriage, the evil eye of lust superadding the
                            licensed freedom of marriage, amplification, divorce-wedlock. Outside this universally
                            charmed circle, she becomes but a useless chattel. But the clarion voice of the gospel is
                            heard echoing the voice of the first creation, "It is not good that the man be alone, I will
                            make him a helpmeet for him," the voice however adding with gospel emphasis, "in the
                            regeneration, they neither marry nor are given in marriage." Lust is swallowed up in
                            victory, paradise is regained, and love, pure as the heavens triumphs over every fleshly
                            foe. See'st thou, dear Brother, in all this the Millennium's pure light, the latter day's
                            glory, shining upon thy pathway, beckoning thee to walk therein? If so, I think you will
                            have arrived at the answer to your query as to the "position that Ann Lee occupies in the
                            Society, and the idea of a Mother spirit." "Sooner or later each hidden deed, Wrought in a
                            darkness where none can read. But leaving its track on the wings of Time, Shall stand
                            confessed, for a light sublime, Will arise at last when the night is done, And truth shall
                            shine as another sun." Your Brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, Thomas" TEIform="persName"/> Thomas Evans.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Sister in Christ:--Being the guardian of Br. A's..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Dear Sister in Christ:--Being the guardian of Br. A's...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Pacific Grove, August 24, 1892" TEIform="index"/>Pacific Grove, Aug. 24, 1892.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Sister isr Christ:Being the guardian of Br. A's little family, I had the pleasure of
                            reading C's letter. He was delighted that one so far away should be so thoughtful to write
                            him such a sweet letter. He intends answering soon. May you accept my appreciation and
                            gratitude for Christian love and interest so sweetly manifested toward the family, and the
                            dear Lord reward your kind effort. For some time past, I have heard and read considerable of
                            my friends in the East. I love them dearly already, believing them to be the true followers
                            of our blessed Master. I have long wanted to open a correspondence with some dear one among
                            you, yourself being the first I have heard directly from, I take it to be the leading of the
                            spirit and deem it my sweet privilege to take advantage of the opportunity thus offered to
                            become acquainted with one or more of your Society. Your letter was a most needful one to
                            our little folks, as they are just entering the Christian life, having been among
                            unbelievers all the time until in the past two years. A lone parent, especially a father,
                            can do very little towards Christian education and training of children, when situated in
                            the midst of an unbelieving community. As natural children, they love their father dearly,
                            but dimly understand spiritual love. I bless God, their minds and hearts are being awakened
                            to divine truth. Nature is beautiful all about, filling us with inspiration of joy and
                            freedom in the Lord. It is here in our home, we are taking up the practice of reading and
                            appropriating to ourselves the truth as we find it explained in the "Millennial Church." <pb n="226" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> The Lord sweetly blesses us through this means. Since reading the
                            lives of the United Believers, I could long to be with you. The Lord willing, I may sometime
                            have the opportunity of visiting your pretty home. In the meantime, I ask the prayers of the
                            beloved, that I may be endowed with more of the Holy Spirit to do the blessed will of our
                            heavenly Father, in all things. Our little family join me in sincere love to you and all our
                            dear friends. Yours in the love of truth.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="O." TEIform="persName"/> O- - - -</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Honesty" TEIform="index"/> HONESTY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fredrick, Henry W." TEIform="persName"/>Henry W. Fredrick.</byline><p TEIform="p">In order to come strictly up to this foundation of all virtues, we must not only speak the
                            truth, but in all our looks and deportment we must act the truth, and be punctually honest
                            and just in all our dealings. The deep principle of honesty and integrity should begin to be
                            laid in the earliest stages of childhood. If we visit gardens of flowers, orchards of fruit,
                            or places where there are many luxuries to tempt the appetite, then we should scorn to crave
                            or attempt to take any thing that is not freely presented to us. If we are entrusted with
                            money, or any thing of value, do strictly as directed, and always render an exact account of
                            every thing that is entrusted to us. We should never work underhanded schemes to obtain
                            favors, conveniences or privileges ; if we do we will sooner or later be marked by upright
                            people as a suspicious character. If we have cultivated an upright, honest spirit in early
                            life, it will give us confidence in ourselves, and we will be blessed with the universal
                            approbation of every one around us. As we advance in years we may safely be entrusted with
                            any amount of property, because people will always say, there is an honest man and I am not
                            afraid to trust him. Our reputation will be abroad and spread widely, and in our experience
                            and comparison with men we shall realize the truth of the maxim, "An honest man is the
                            noblest work of God." There is a peace and tranquillity that never slumbers in the minds of
                            those who have strictly practiced through life, honest integrity and uprightness of dealing,
                            which the knavish and dishonest never know. The former are never harrowed with those pangs
                            of conscience to which the latter must be subject. The honest citizen of any class or grade,
                            holds up his head in the full congregation, standing nobly upon Ms own integrity and good
                            reputation, however his abilities, qualifications, or deficiencies may be criticised. Here
                            is one bulwark that is invulnerable. When weighed in the balances of judgment, he may have
                            short-comings and imperfections, but he has never wronged the rich or poor. He knows it and
                            they know it. He has injured no man in person or property. In health or sickness, in joy or
                            tribulation, this reflection abides with him in life, supports him through the vale of
                            death, and exists with him beyond the tomb. Persons who have from early life taken this
                            honorable course, are often shocked and pained, especially in later years, by seeing and
                            hearing the sad, <pb n="227" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> disgraceful end of many of their old companions who
                            had early inclined to dishonesty. The pilferer has become a confirmed thief and ends his
                            career in the penitentiary or on the gallows. The knave has become a hard-hearted swindler,
                            a pirate or an outlaw. Boys who would rob orchards, cheat their companions or make false
                            returns when sent on an errand, have been turned adrift as unworthy, dishonest apprentices
                            or pilfering clerks, and with a ruined reputation. Many who have sought and found the path
                            of uprightness, and have from the morning of childhood, labored to walk in it, in honesty
                            and punctuality, have thus laid the foundation of an entirely different character. And upon
                            this character they have stood and surveyed such wrecks of humanity in the meridian of life,
                            with souls filled with sorrow for those who were once dear to them, yet grateful to our
                            heavenly Father for their own protection from the small beginnings which result in so much
                            misery and degradation. Let us all bear in mind the oft repeated sentence, "Honesty is the
                            best policy." Dayton, Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="They say" TEIform="index"/> THEY SAY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hopkins, Margarett" TEIform="persName"/> Margarett Hopkins.</byline><p TEIform="p"> (Contributed by Maria Witham.) What heart that throbs without some pain; What day that's
                            gone can come again, What troubles come, what sorrows fall, Into the pathway of us all.
                            Trample with scorn this serpent foe, That meets us all where'er we go; Lock fast the door of
                            house and heart, Speak kindly or without remark. Find life too grand, the years too fleet,
                            To plant sharp thorns in others feet; Come out, come up, keep far above, All words that mean
                            not Peace and Love. I would that Woman work, and pray, To fill her place as best she may,
                            And scatter seeds of love each day, For heaven will hold no dread they say.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Literary curiosity" TEIform="index"/> A LITERARY CURIOSITY.</head><p TEIform="p"> [Contributed by Genevieve DeGraw.] "The following is one of the most remarkable compositions
                            we have ever met with. It evinces an ingenuity peculiarly its own. The initial capital
                            letters spell "My boast is in the glorious cross of Christ." The words in italics, when read
                            on the left side from top to bottom, and on the right side from bottom to top, form the
                            Lord's Prayer, complete:"<cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> Make known the gospel truth, our Father King, Yield up thy grace, dear .Father
                                    from above, Bless us with hearts which feelingly can sing, "Our life thou art for
                                    ever God of Love." Assuage our grief in love for Christ we pray, Since the Prince of
                                    Heaven and glory died Took all our sins and hallowed the display, Infant 6e-ing,
                                    first a man and then was crucified. Stupendous God! thy grace and power make known;
                                    In Jesus' name let all the world rejoice, Now labor in thy heavenly kingdom own,
                                    That blessed kingdom, for thy saints the choice. How vile to come to thee is all our
                                    cry; Enemies to thyself and all that's thine; Graceless our will, we live for
                                    vanity; Loathing the very &amp;e-ing, evil in design, O God, thy wifcL be done
                                    from earth to heaven; Reclining on the gospel, let us live, In earth from sin,
                                    deliver-eA and forgiven, Oh! as th3rself but teach us to forgive, Unless its power
                                    temptation doth destroy; Sure is our fall into the depth of woe, Carnal in mind,
                                    we've not a glimpse of joy Raised against heaven; in us no hope we know, O give us
                                    grace and lead us on thy way; Shine on us with thy love and give us peace Self and
                                    this sin that rise against us stay, Oh! grant each day our trespass-es may cease;
                                    Forgive our evil deeds that oft we do; Convince us daily of them to our shame; Help
                                    us with heavenly bread, forgive us, too, Righteous Lord, and we'll adore thy name In
                                    thy forgive-ness we as saints can die, Since for us and our trespasses so high, Thy
                                    Son, our Savior, died on Calvary</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p><pb n="228" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p"> THE MANIFESTO. OCTOBER, 1893. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is published by the
                            "United Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued
                            regularly by the Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the
                            religious views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. All
                            communications should be addressed to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. One
                            copy per year, postage paid, .75 " " six months, " " .40 Send for sample copy, free. Entered
                            at the Post Office at East Canterbury, N. H., as second-class matter.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial.</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="When it is understood that the Truth will make..." TEIform="index"/>
                                When it is understood that the Truth will make...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> When it is understood that the Truth will make the life of man free, agreeably to the
                                declaration of Jesus, then it will be found that those who wish to assert their freedom,
                                in the best and deepest sense of the word, will seek diligently to find the Truth. Those
                                who seek like those who run for the prize, may all be rewarded in proportion to the
                                interest which they have manifested, and the sacrifices which they have made. Although
                                Truth may represent to us so much of Deity, and seemingly be so far beyond our limited
                                comprehension, while in its fullness, yet we may have this consolation, that in its
                                omnipresence it touches every finite being. If, as some are inclined to think, God is so
                                far, so very far away, even beyond the most distant stars, how very strange it is that
                                we can not pass outside of all the good influences of God. So soon as we are willing to
                                commence the making of strait paths in the spirit of righteousness, we shall find that
                                the kingdom of God is near at hand. It is the divine inflowing of a baptism that has
                                come down from God out of heaven, and is making its pleasant abode with men. Going on
                                toward God, has become one of the familiar terms to be used by those who believe that we
                                may reach better conditions, as individuals, as Communities and as nations, by the
                                acceptance of more knowledge than may constitute our present heavenly happiness. To go
                                toward God, is simply to forsake that which we know to be wrong, and then learn that
                                which we know to be right. It needs no scientific formula to mystify the mind, nor
                                scripture puzzling problems, through which one must wander on toward righteousness, or
                                that will assure him that "the faith once delivered to the saints," has been radically
                                changed. When the messenger of God came in the name of a prophet and reTERMS. <pb n="229" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> buked the chosen Israel for walking in forbidden paths, he could
                                give them no clearer nor more practical message than this. ''Cease to do evil and learn
                                to do well." Then came the ministers of the New Covenant, with corresponding
                                instruction. More light brought more evidence that the work of God among men was moving
                                on, and Paul could stimulate his Brethren to more interest and a dearer abiding hope, as
                                he assured them of his confidence in the cross of Christ. "I am persuaded that neither
                                death nor life, nor angels, nor principalities, nor powers, nor things present, nor
                                things to come, shall be able to separate us from the love of God which is in Christ
                                Jesus." Then comes the voice of God's great messenger, so clearly expressed and so
                                decided in its utterance, that the willing listener, even though he be of a simple mind,
                                may fully understand the work he is to accept and see the highway over which he is to
                                walk. "Except your righteousness shall exceed the righteousness of the Scribes and
                                Pharisees, you shall not enter into the kingdom of heaven." When a man "sits alone with
                                his conscience" and in silent communion with this word of God, he may be led to say as
                                did the first Believers. "Let names and sects and parties, Accost my ears no more ; My
                                ever blessed Savior, , Forever I'll adore." It is a new life in God, a new and growing
                                life that becomes of the first importance; the making of strait paths, which will lead
                                us "to live soberly, righteously and godly in this present world," never forgetting that
                                we must deny ourselves of "all ungodliness and every worldly lust." With this
                                preparation of the gospel of Christ, Believers have nothing to fear. Their triumph is as
                                sure as the heavens. "God's love is at the helm, We shall outride the storm ; Whose life
                                is in the light, Can fear no earthly harm. The passage may be long, Ere truth o'er error
                                rise ; But they are always strong Who make no compromise."</p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We publish in this number of the Manifesto an article..." TEIform="index"/>
                            We publish in this number of the Manifesto an article...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> We publish in this number of the Manifesto an article forwarded by Elder Frederic Evans,
                            having reference to the Koreshans of Chicago. As so many inquiries are being made, bearing
                            upon this subject, we present the following for the better information of our readers. The
                            Shakers are interested in every religious movement that comes forward for the greater peace
                            and happiness of individuals, and for the general good of humanity. This same interest would
                            be manifested toward any class of people who gave evidence of increasing light from God, and
                            the Shakers would wish for them the best of prosperity. If <pb n="230" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> their zeal
                            and Christian self-denial bears the genuine stamp of the Christ of God, no reason could be
                            given whv their success in life should not be assured, and they be allowed to occupy a place
                            among those who are working for God in the cause of human progress. The Koreshans are not
                            Shakers in the exact definition of the word Shaker. They accept the foundation principles of
                            Believers, Celibacy, community of goods, peace, temperance adding thereunto vegetarianism.
                            As we understand the Koreshans do not come under the direct Leadership of the Shakers, and
                            the Elders newly appointed are Elders only of the Koreshan unity. Dr. Cyrus Teed, the
                            leading spirit of the little community who is known by his people as Koresh, and his
                            followers Koreshans, visited the Believers at Mount Lebanon, N. Y., and took the initiatory
                            step before the witnesses of God in that place. This gave Dr. Teed the fellowship of the
                            Believers of the novitiate order. At a later date Mrs. Annie G. Ordway visited Mount Lebanon,
                            and was by the people of that place, accepted as a sister, and after her confirmation to the
                            office of an Elder, she returned to Chicago. Of this act Elder Frederic writes, "This will
                            make Cyrus and Annie the leaders and Elders of the New Order." In the Flaming Sword of Aug.
                            13, the position of this people is defined quite clearly, and this statement being accepted,
                            there can be no farther doubt of the place occupied by either the Shakers or the Koreshans,
                            especially, in the minds of the above named. "Koreshanity has an outer court, I do not know
                            that Shakerism has. The Shakers are a glorious people, and there is no place in the world,
                            where greater protection can be afforded from the lusts of the flesh. Koreshanity is the
                            opening of another stage of evolution beyond Shakerism, but in no way conflicts with it. In
                            fact we regard ourselves as the outcome of the old celibate bodies of the United States, the
                            principal one of which is Shakerism." If Koreshanity is beyond Shakerism, it certainly is
                            not Shakerism, but if this new body can manifest a testimony that will more effectually
                            separate them from the children of this world, and if they will more devotedly deny
                            themselves of all ungodliness and every worldly lust, than the Shakers have done, then we
                            must admit that they occupy a place nearer the standard, and having a greater fullness of
                            the gospel of Christ, they are well worthy to go on victoriously, while we as Brothers and
                            Sisters can wish them Godspeed. The theology of the Koreshans is more peculiar, if possible,
                            than is that of the Shakers, and certainly quite unlike it. But as theology is generally
                            very plentiful and cheap, <pb n="231" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> this need not make much difference. Those
                            who may become interested to follow either order through this phase of their life, would do
                            well to subscribe for the "Flaming Sword" and learn of the Koreshans, or take the Manifesto
                            and become acquainted with the Shakers. Even this statement of the newly arisen party may
                            not be wholly lost on our Communities, and the voice of the Apostle should be heard among us
                            in the full force of its utterance, as it was in the Primitive Church. "Be not deceived, God
                            is not mocked ; for whatsoever a man soweth that shall he also reap. He that soweth to his
                            flesh shall of the flesh reap corruption; but he that soweth to the Spirit, shall of the
                            Spirit reap life everlasting." To lose this testimony wre lose our right to an entrance into
                            the Holy City, and in our lukewarmness are in danger of being cast out from the presence of
                            our God.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life renewed" TEIform="index"/> LIFE RENEWED.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/> Mary Whitcher.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Be care and kindness to my fellow-man Deeply inwoven in each future plan, Be trust in God
                            with hands intent to do Their part my theme with heart sincere and true. Much care to live
                            correctly every day Must mark the prospect of the "Better way." Let life at morn, at noon
                            and even's close Alike be heeded for the soul's repose. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/> NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mount Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/> Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> Average of Weather at Mount Lebanon. August. Thermometer. Bain. 1891. 69.15 3. 13-16in.
                                1892. 66.1 5in. Highest Temp, during this mo. 90. Lowest " " " " 52. Total Rainfall " "
                                " Sin. Number of rainy days " " 10 C. G. E. North Family. Sept. 1892. Another month has
                                rolled around, bringing its varied scenes and changes, both external and internal. On
                                the Sunday of Aug. 21st. we had the most notable gathering at our meeting-house that has
                                been for over thirty years. The importance and significance of the chief feature of that
                                meeting, viz. the uniting of the virgin celibate body of Koreshans and Believers, will
                                be understood and appreciated more in the future than it is at present. This is one of
                                the internal scenes that will more and more portray and convey the truth of the
                                everlasting gospel, that will save and regenerate a corrupt fallen world; which gospel
                                we are called to live, and to minister wherever we go. On the 8th. inst. we had a little
                                external scene which was very interesting, and presented an object lesson that will
                                claim our attention for at least one year. A company of twelve Brethren and Sisters took
                                a little outing; not for worldly pleasure or to get food to feed a carnal nature, but
                                for a change of scenery, and to gather good and minister the gospel, by shedding a
                                saving influence on all whom we met. To this end our very thoughtful and progressive
                                Eldress Anna gathered quite a large selection of Shaker literature for us to distribute.
                                The course laid out for us to travel was a trip down the Hudson, from Albany to
                                Poughkeepsie on the day boat. We left home at 5-15 a. m. riding six miles to Canaan
                                depot in order to reach Albany in time for the boat. <pb n="232" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> In Albany we
                                had time to purchase some fruit, which, with the crackers &amp;c. that we had with
                                us, and the addition of some ice cream, hot water, &amp;c. which we got on board, we
                                had a meal of which angels could partake, without having their finer senses shocked, or
                                their consciences wounded by reason of violating the sixth commandment. The day was
                                lovely; and when all were nicely situated on board, we arranged our tracts in order,
                                preparatory for distribution. Some there were who would not look at our ideas or accept
                                our offers; others (a few only) were very much interested, and partially converted. Who
                                can tell where the seed will spring up, sown on the waters of the Hudson on the notable
                                8th. of September. I esteem it a very great privilege to be in company with those who
                                not only have on the external garb of a Shaker, and are not ashamed of it, but who also
                                possess the spirit of the true disciple and are bold to maintain and defend the living
                                faith of the gospel. On our return we made a short tarry in the city of Hudson. Here we
                                had presented, both to our external and internal perception, an object lesson well
                                calculated to kindle the fires of gospel zeal to the consuming point. In a short (five
                                minutes) walk, we counted fifteen saloons; and children, very numerous, besmeared with
                                dirt, in ragged clothes, and in a continual baptism of vicious influences emanating from
                                their surroundings. A large number followed us, giving vent to the pent-up forces of
                                ignorance and vice by inharmonious sounds, gestures and grimaces till we were seated in
                                the car. Here they congregated, some playing, others staring, and all portraying in
                                their countenances more or less of the unholy conditions under which they were brought
                                into existence. It was proposed to sing: so we sang "Christian Love." This caused a
                                halt, and intuitively the evil began to disappear and the angel of good peeped out. We
                                opened more windows and sang: "Weary not, O Christian Pilgrim." " This opened their
                                little hearts and Sister Martha spoke a few words in her loving winsome manner, when'
                                the car started and we said good bye. They responded in united chorus,good bye. AVho
                                could witness such a scene, having the living faith ot Christ's and Mother's gospel, and
                                not have their zeal renewed to greater efforts to disseminate the saving power of God's
                                love, and work and never tire of building up the kingdom of heaven on the earth. Should
                                we not in all our journeyings, and especially in our business relations and
                                transactions, carry therewith, and into, the religion of Mother's gospel? Every thing we
                                put our hands or hearts to do should be imbued with truth, honesty and righteousness
                                according to the exceeding standard of our great and glorious cause. The Sept. Manifesto
                                is an exceedingly interesting one. Glad the music was counted worthy of repetition,
                                though we would rather have seen a new piece. D. O.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watervliet, New York" TEIform="index"/> Watervliet, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> Second Family. The weather has been unusually cool for this season of the year, but no
                                frost to do any harm thus far. The past week the weather has been all we could ask for
                                securing crops. We have more fruit than was expected, especially of plums and pears.
                                Apples will be a fair crop. We are busy canning tomatoes and drying sweet corn. Elder
                                Joseph and Elder Alexander Work gave us a call. Sisters Matilda Reed and Minerva
                                Reynolds of the Church family, Mount Lebanon, made us a pleasant visit. We are always
                                pleased to see our gospel kindred, especially so when they are like those whom we have
                                mentioned, worthy toiling souls who have made the full sacrifice, and have consecrated
                                their time and talents and all they possessed for the good of the cause. May we be
                                worthy to claim relationship with such in this life, then we need not fear the future.</p><pb n="233" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/> Shaker Station, Conn.</head><p TEIform="p"> Sept. 1892. The golden autumn has arrived with all its beauty, and precious freight. The
                                weather is cool and frost has been feared the past few days. Co.n is being cut down, and
                                we expect a very good yield. Potatoes are a very good quality but not a great quantity.
                                Blackberries are abundant. Fruit is a failure, not any apples to speak of in our
                                orchards. But seedtime and harvest have come in their season, according to promise. We
                                hear the song of the reaper pouring forth his joy as he stands amid the plentiful crops
                                that crown his labors. And are not his feelings those of confidence and trust, in a
                                higher power that assures him of a golden harvest in its season. Bountiful Father!
                                praise to thee for thy kind, and generous .providence. Thou hast not permitted the
                                promise of springto die, but hast watched over the seeds and tender plants, and kept
                                away the destroying frost, and the blighting mildew. And as the hour is near at hand
                                when the Husbandman shall gather in his harvest, it becomes us to be ready and laden
                                with fruit. In the midst of plenty we are often reminded of those who live in poverty
                                and desolation. And why? because they are unwilling to make the sacrifice required to
                                live this pure life that the Believer enjoys. A good home, with pleasant arrangements
                                and comforts. We would that more were willing to accept the invitation of the gospel.
                                "Come unto me all ye that labor and are heavy laden and I will give you rest." M.
                                Witham. The Apostle says, Labor therefore, to make your calling and election sure. Not
                                only to be called, but to be Christians. The labor is a great and unceasing one, and a
                                self-denying one, but the reward is also great. The rules for the work are plainly laid
                                down, as is also the way of ascertaining when one has acquired the right of being called
                                by this blessed name. "For the fruit of the Spirit is love, joy, peace, long-suffering,
                                goodness, faith, meekness." Those who are striving for these virtues, and are true
                                Christians, are assured that "neither things present nor things to come shall separate
                                them from the love of God." A first-class hen-house" does not make first-class hens.
                                Unless gravel is sharp it is valueless for hens. Hence hens prefer sharp shells or grit
                                to round gravel. The reason they eat more shells or grit when laying is because, when
                                laying, more food is required, and consequently more digestion and assimilation. It pays
                                to give fowls the best of care. Kindness to the hens returns through the egg basket. The
                                Cochin is a good layer, very hardy, unexceptionable as a mother and not given to
                                excessive incubation and good for the table. Ground or broken bone is one of the best
                                substances that can be fed to hens. Fowls that moult late should be disposed of and
                                their places filled with pullets. D. Orcutt.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/> West Pittsfield, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p"> Sept, 1892. "The great ocean is in a constant state of evaporation. It gives back what
                                it receives, and sends up its waters in mists to gather in clouds; and so there is rain
                                on the fields and storms on the mountains, and beauty and greenness everywhere." We are
                                constrained to quote this beautiful aphorism enunciated by the renowned H. W. Beecher,
                                now in immortal realms, because of the freshness and verdancy of field and forest, now
                                in this glorious autumn season, largely attributable to the refreshing rains of summer.
                                Our grass crop nearly equaled that of last year, which was considered good. Potatoes
                                yielded well, but decay is upon them. We find our supply of apples larger than we had
                                anticipated. Shall have a sufficiency for home use, with perhaps a small surplus. Pears
                                and small fruits not as plentiful as in some former seasons. For some unknown cause our
                                blackberry harvest did not compare in quantity with that of last year. Yet how manifold
                                are our <pb n="234" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> blessings, and how our hearts should expand with
                                thankfulness. What time could be more appropriate for rendering especial praise and
                                thanks to the beneficent dispenser of all good and perfect gifts, than the blessed
                                harvest season? Weather of the past few days was so nearly perfect, that the veil which
                                hides from view the spirit world seemed to be lifted, and we felt as the late venerable
                                expressed it, "That the airs of heaven blew o'er us." Love and good-will to our kind
                                Editor and corps of assistants. The peace of heaven be with you. J. L. S.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ayer, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/> Ayer, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p"> Sept. 1892. We do not know, good Editor, but that we may digress, or run a little one
                                side from the usual course of our Home Notes. By speaking oi the flowers, or as one has
                                said, of the beautiful side of life, which some may look upon as grown merely to please
                                the eye; we think that down deep in God's beautiful work of nature we shall see in the
                                flowers a pleasant refining influence, which will more or less refine even the elements
                                of our own being. We have found to our great satisfaction, when weary with the toils of
                                the day, that a walk among the flowers has afforded a restful inspiration, and may help,
                                so to speak, to lubricate the human machinery for the coming day. September finds the
                                flower garden in its greatest beauty, and this speaks of the care that it has received
                                during the summer. A little flower bed within the limits of our dooryard, so prettily
                                sheltered, has been kept in this nice order all the season. Not a wTeed has been allowed
                                to mature at the expense of the beautiful flowers, and the good Sister who has charge of
                                this labor of love, enjoys the reward of her constant care. Others may have gardens
                                where the following quotation may be appropriate, but it does not even touch this little
                                consecrated spot. "I passed by the garden of the slothful, and I saw that it was
                                overgrown with weeds." We were now enjoying a lesson of thought, and silently comparing
                                this pretty scene with the spiritual garden of the soul, in which may bloom all the
                                choice plants of that heavenly land. We thought of a virtuous life and the great care
                                and cultivation needed to protect these plants that belong to the garden of God. These
                                flowers of the soul were Honesty, Purity, Meekness and Love. Their beauty was in
                                proportion to the consecrated life of the careful gardener, and these spiritual gifts
                                were more attractive than even the beautiful flowers of our earthly gardens. These are
                                the treasures that we are securing on the other side of the Jordan, in the mansions of
                                the blest, and in the coming bye and bye we shall see how well we have kept our garden
                                free from weeds. September finds harvesting all done. We have cut five acres of the best
                                ensilage, and it is well'stored in the silo. In all we have about one hundred tons.
                                Potatoes are coming in, good. Apple crop small. The Sisters are giving a sisterly care
                                to the herbs which are coming in. The selling of milk seems to be very active in
                                Middlesex Co., and we have stepped into the ring, which seems to be far better and more
                                profitable than making and selling butter. A. D. B.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/> East Canterbury, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p"> Weather Kecord, for August, 1892. Highest Temp, during the mo. 89. Lowest " " " " 43.
                                Mean " " " " 75.6 Mean maximum and minimum 67.1 Total precipitation 11.16 in. Greatest "
                                in 24 consecutive hours 4.75 in. Number of days in which .01 in. or more fell, 13. N. A.
                                Bbiggs.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/> Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p"> r Sept. 1892. In our communal relations when sustained upon honor to the best and
                                highest interests thereof, we feel that paramount to all other considerations, is the
                                one <pb n="235" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> grand service of doing good to our Brethren and Sisters,
                                combined with consecrated efforts to make our homes more and more like the habitations
                                of saints whose lives are given to the glory of God. So while we prepare a few items for
                                the coming month, we are pleased to note that much care and labor has been expended in
                                this direction during the present season. Added to the painting of our laundry and
                                dairy, there is painting and repairing being clone upon our stone dwelling, changing its
                                former aspect very perceptibly, besides minor improvements elsewhere. We spent a very
                                pleasant season with our Sisters from Harvard, Mass. Our sympathy, love and interest in
                                their behalf, was broadened and strengthened by the visit. Summer boarders who have
                                thronged our village in quest of pleasure at the expense of time and labor given to
                                entertain them, have now gone to their homes, and we are at liberty to gather the fruits
                                of our fields and gardens, which, by the way, have yielded us a good supply. Plums of
                                all kinds are quite abundant. Tomatoes a good yield also. Our apple and potato crop will
                                be far less than in former seasons; supposed to have been injured by heavy rains in the
                                early summer. Two of our Sisters, Isabella Russell and Henrietta Spooner were away the
                                past week attending a Fair held some twelve miles from our village. They carried with
                                them small articles made chiefly by the Sisters, which found ready sale; so they felt
                                amply, paid for the time and labor spent. Health in our Society about as usual; no
                                calamity to bring distress upon our family and friends. With such blessings to crown our
                                daily toil we can not fail to give thanks to the Giver of all good. J. E.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Alfred, Maine" TEIform="index"/> Alfred, Me.</head><p TEIform="p"> Sept. 1892. Beloved Elpeb Hejstry:I had hoped before it came time to write you again,
                                our unwelcome visitor, whooping-cough, would have left us, but not so, it is still with
                                us and bids fair to remain all winter. However, some are feeling much better, and others
                                hope to before long. Our annual excursion occurred August 30th. Twenty-seven persons,
                                including children, took the 1 a. m. train for Portland, then took the steamer for
                                Peak's Island, arriving there about half-past nine. It was a very pretty place and there
                                were quite a number of curious things to be seen which pleased the little folks. There
                                was a black bear, a peacock, monkeys, squirrels, white mice, fan-tailed pigeons, some
                                guinea pigs and a Punch and Judy show. We spent three hours on the Island, then returned
                                to the city to view the wonders there, the greatest of which were found in the five and
                                ten cent stores. At 5-30 we started for home, very much pleased with the day's
                                enjoyment, but oh! so tired and very, very thankful that we had a good clean home to
                                return to. Such days spent in pleasure seeking often bring a blessing. The contrast
                                between the many homes we see and our own clean and comfortable home makes us more
                                thankful for our Zion home at least. But those who have come to years of understanding
                                realize that it is the blessed gospel of Christ and Mother that gives us this clean,
                                happy home. A short time since we had the pleasure of meeting three of our gospel
                                friends from Harvard, Mass., Eldress Louisa Green, Sisters Marcia Bullard and Florence
                                Foye. Their tarry was short yet we enjoyed a beautiful season with them. The first two
                                named are faithful mothers in Israel, having embraced the faith in early days and lived
                                strictly to the principles of the gospel; they now can sing and speak of the goodness of
                                God and the blessedness of his holy way. The younger Sister seemed to have started out
                                with a correct understanding of what is required to become a child of God, and expressed
                                a strong determination to accomplish the work. Brethren have nearly finished harvesting
                                potatoes. Four acres yielded about six hundred bushels, and am glad to say they are free
                                from decay. Our ten acres <pb n="236" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> of ensilage corn averages fourteen feet
                                high. Brethren commence cutting it this week. Our beloved Eldress Harriet is now with
                                us, also Sister Mary Ella Douglass of Gloucester. We are overjoyed to meet her once
                                more. If our prayers are answered she will receive health and strength and live many
                                years to' bless her Zion home. She is a true and faithful Sister and much loved by all.
                                Of such we have none too many. F. C.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers were in town" TEIform="index"/> THE SHAKERS WERE IN TOWN.</head><p TEIform="p"> The quaint people who were seen on the streets yesterday were the Alfred Shakers who
                                came on their annual picnic to the islands. The men "wore broad-brimmed hats and plain
                                clothes, while the women wTere quite generally dressed in plain gray dresses, with the
                                plain skirts, short waists and shoulder capes of long ago. Almost invariably their heads
                                were covered with the peculiar bonnets known as "shakers." Several young girls of the
                                party wore hats more like the hats of the world's people. These young girls have been
                                adopted by the Shakers, and are expected in time to become members of the order. Elder
                                Vance had charge of the party, and late yesterday afternoon was quite conspicuous as he
                                marched on ahead of the double file of quaintly dressed sisters who followed demurely.
                                Their appearance excited considerable curiosity and comment, and not a few expressions
                                of good will from those who have had dealings with the Shakers. For they are an upright
                                people, universally respected.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine" TEIform="index"/> Sabbathday Lake, Me.</head><p TEIform="p"> Sept. 1892. We who live ' 'way down east'' come to have another chat through the columns
                                of our monthly messenger and to assure you that we are thankful for the spiritual food
                                it contains. Long may it live to proclaim the truth unto every nation, and long may the
                                good Editor be sustained in the great work which he is so faithfully performing. We have
                                had another interchange of gospel love and union with our good Sisters from Harvard,
                                Eldress Louisa Green and Sister Marcia Bullard, who have not only been a blessing to
                                Harvard for a number of years past, but their early days of faithful service were spent
                                at Mount Lebanon, our Mother Church. Thus they are able ministers of the power of God unto
                                salvation and we were greatly blest by their presence with us. Also for the good young
                                Sister, Florence Foye, who accompanied them to this place, we gained a great deal of
                                love. Not long since a special invitation was sent to our Leaders, by the Proprietors of
                                the Poland Spring Hotel for our little girls all to come there and take dinner, and
                                liberty was granted. So they sent one of their coaches named the James G. Blaine to take
                                them there. They were accompanied by their teachers, and made very happy by the notice
                                they received. Before dinner was announced a concert was given them in music hall, and
                                they also went up on the elevator to the tower which commands a view of all the
                                surrounding country. They were then taken through the domestic departments. When they
                                were called to dinner, such a floral display ! Flowers everywhere! The girls selected
                                what they wanted from the Menu, and "tarried long o'er the 'Poland Water.' " After
                                dinner they visited the famous Spring and bbl'ing house, rested under the shady trees in
                                the park where they sung and recited pieces to the many guests who gathered around them.
                                One piece which they sung to the proprietors gave quite an effect; "Inasmuch as ye have
                                done it to the least of these, Ye have done it unto me &amp;c." Then they visited
                                the Indians, and admired their pretty baskets. At 4-30 p. m. the James G. Blaine took
                                the happy company home, made none the worse for the day's outing. In the evening they
                                had a visit with the Harvard Sisters at the Office, and one of the little girls was
                                heard to say: "Seems to me we little girls are having a good many privileges lately."
                                Our beloved Eldress Harriet thought it would be interesting to other Believers to know
                                of this day's pleasure for the children, so we have written it. Usual health prevails at
                                our home. A. S. C.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dayton, Ohio" TEIform="index"/> Dayton, Ohio.</head><p TEIform="p"> Aug. 1892. We have very dry weather; need rain. But we will not murmur as we have been
                                blest with a large wheat crop. This averaged twenty-five bushels to the acre. <pb n="237" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> We are putting in two hot air furnaces purchased from the Dayton
                                Furnace &amp; Foundry Co. I think they are among the best furnaces that are made. We
                                have also been improving our Dwelling by putting in new sash in the front part and
                                adding a veranda on the front. So when our linoleum carpets are down in the halls and
                                our walls papered or painted, we shall have closed a good job. The health at Watervliet
                                is generally pretty good. The Sisters have had a large amount of cooking to do for the
                                past two weeks for the working men and it is pretty hard work. When they get all through
                                with cooking it will be easier. The Brethren help the Sisters in the Laundry, and
                                sometimes in the cooking department, while we have so many men at work. Elder Joseph
                                Slingerland spent two days with us recently, and a Brother, Leander Divine, from Union
                                Village made us a visit last week. We are also having about one hundred rods of smooth
                                wire fence put on the farm. H. W. F.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Canaan, New York" TEIform="index"/> Canaan, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> Sept. 1892. The golden harvest time has come, and every one must be busy to secure the
                                blessings vouchsafed to us, or they will be lost; and every one is happy in consecrating
                                self, and giving their strength to build up and support our Zion home, and so we feel a
                                glow of love in our hearts for gospel friends and therefore send happy greetings to our
                                dear kindred. If any people on earth have cause to be happy, we above all others possess
                                this boon. With temporal blessings sufficient for our comfort, and the beauties of
                                nature to delight us, and what is far superior to these, the gift of salvation, whereby
                                we are freed from the thralldom of sin and consequently its sufferings. The testimony of
                                eternal truth is sounded among us with its glorious increase. Not only have we abolished
                                tobacco and pork but no longer do we slay any poor innocent helpless animal to gratify a
                                depraved appetite. Good sweet oatmeal, graham and corn bread, with nicely cooked
                                vegetables and fruit will satisfy any one in a normal condition. We must have an object
                                in view through life, considering results and act accordingly. This idea formed in the
                                minds of the young will destroy the relish for tea and coffee and break up that
                                pernicious and injurious habit of eating between meals, and teach us to carefully
                                masticate the food before swallowing it. It will also regulate matters in regard to
                                dress so that comfort, utility and economy will be combined with symmetry. Our gospel
                                testimony must take cognizance of all our doings or it fails to perfect us. Br. Cyrus
                                Teed, of the Koreshan Unity, made us a visit and delivered a very interesting lecture.
                                We are much pleased to have made his acquaintance. Since last Oct. we have added six to
                                our number, five being children, the youngest six yrs. old, she and her brother eight
                                yrs. old have never tasted animal food. Their mother is a strict vegetarian and desires
                                her children to be brought up as such, not allowing them food aside from their meals. We
                                regret that any of the children of this world are wiser than the children of light. The
                                potato bugs ar.e devouring many of our tomatoes; they eat both green and ripe. Who will
                                deliver us from Egyptian plagues by teaching us more perfect methods of agriculture that
                                so much hard lalor may not be fruitless. E. O.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let bygones be bygones" TEIform="index"/> LET BYGONES BE BYGONES.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> Let bygones be bygones. Oh, try to forget: If one has e'er wronged thee, why
                                    cherish regret? Let the memory painful far from thee depart, Lot bygones be bygones,
                                    nor burden thy heart. Let bygones be bygones. If one gave a slight, Let it pass, as
                                    at morn pass the dreams of the night. The burden o'er heavy will grow, if eac'.i day
                                        <pb n="238" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> You gather and garner each slight by the way. Let bygones
                                    be bygones. Why plait for thy brow The thorns of the Past in a crown for the Now? Go
                                    gather the roses that bloom by the way, They'll yield thorns sufficient for the
                                    crowns of to-day. Let bygones be bygones. No room's in thy heart, For this day with
                                    its joy and that with its smart, Fill up fullest measure at the joy wells to-day,
                                    Xor quaff at the founts that erst bittered thy way. If bygones be bygones thou nobly
                                    canst bear, Each day what it brings thee of sorrow or care, While the burden too
                                    weighty will grow for thy back, If the Past with the Present is borne in thy pack.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Woman's work" TEIform="index"/>Woman's Work.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our mother in deity" TEIform="index"/> OUR MOTHER IN DEITY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wayne, Sophia" TEIform="persName"/> Sophia Wayne.</byline><p TEIform="p"> A Mother in Deity! beautiful faith That to all true Believers is given; Our hope in this
                            life, our comfort in death Is the thought of a Mother in heaven. When Jesus the righteous,
                            of heaven-born mind Came to tell us of glories above, His words to the penitent always were
                            kind, He was taught by our Mother of love. Oh kind loving Mother, to whom we oft pray, And
                            trust in Her power of forgiving. Such thoughts are a blessing, our comfort and stay, And
                            will guide us along on our heavenly way, For we know our petitions by night or by day Will
                            be heard by our Mother in heaven. Balston Spa, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.
                        </head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Taylor, Fanny" TEIform="index"/>Fanny Taylor
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Fanny Taylor, at Mount Lebanon, N. Y. Aug. 17, 1892. Age 86 yrs. 6 mo. We say to her: Go,
                                dear Sister, with the angels; Go and dwell with the unseen; Thou hast reared a noble
                                structure, Palace fit for any queen. Go in peace, the angels call thee; Enter in the
                                joyous rest. Take thy seat 'mid queens and princes, For by heaven thy soul is blest. ,T.
                                E. S. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="DeGroat, Orpha W." TEIform="index"/>Orpha W. DeGroat
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Orpha W. DeGroat at Sonyea, N. Y.. Aug. 19, 1892. Age 83 yrs. 5 mo. 27 days. She
                                possessed a lovely spirit, and in her life was exemplified a beautiful old age. She
                                loved and blessed all; and kept up an interest in the affairs of life to the very last.
                                Always an agreeable companion, she was ready to converse intelligently on any proper
                                subject. Her presence was a blessing in the family. Among her papers was found the
                                following original prayer, which her friends would be pleased to see published in her
                                memory. O heavenly Father and Mother, we entreat of Thee to guard and protect us
                                continually; we are aware of our own inability to move heavenward without the help and
                                strength which is ministered to us by Thy holy angels and justified spirits who daily
                                surround us to bless us when good and condemn us when wrong. Most earnestly I entreat of
                                the kind mediums of strength and protection to guard us continually. Do inspire us to do
                                that which our conscience dictates. O may the young of the fold be protected from the
                                wiles of the enemy of souls. Keep them, oh! keep them for Thine honor and glory. May
                                they have wisdom beyond their years to detect evil and power to avoid it. O Lord, may
                                those who have lived many years have power and strength of spirit to bear them up under
                                the many difficulties of old age, knowing the time is nearing wlien they will put off
                                the old tenement in which they have dwelt so long, and be arrayed in garments which
                                their lives here have merited. O ye heavenly ministers, do grant the prayer of this
                                little supplicant. Orpha. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beal, Thomas" TEIform="index"/>Thomas Beal
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Thomas Beal at Shakers, N. Y. Aug. 20, 1892. Age 84 yrs. 9 mo.
                                2 days. Br. Thomas has been a faithful, devoted toiler in the vineyard of the Lord for
                                nearly forty years, and has, no doubt, gained a rich inheritance in the mansions of the
                                just. ' O. B. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Evans, Emily S." TEIform="index"/>Emily S. Evans
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Emily S. Evans, at East Canterbury, N. H., Aug. 26, 1892. Age 7 yrs. 7
                                mo.</p></div3><pb n="239" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Jordan" TEIform="index"/> JORDAN.</head><p TEIform="p"> " Come unto me all ye that labour and are heavy laden and I will give yourest."Matt., xi.,
                            28. Canterbury, N. H. What saith the Spirit to the poor and oppressed? "Come unto me and I
                            will give you rest. Are ye heavy laden, have ye fallen by the way? Jordan hath the power of
                            healing. Brave ye the billows now and again, Healing from blindness, from sorrow and pain, O
                            be persuaded the waters to try, God in his mercy is dealing."</p><pb n="240" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ladies' home journal" TEIform="index"/>The Ladies' Home Journal
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Mr. Howells intends spending Ms summer in a quiet nook in New England, devoting a large
                                portion of his time to the writing of his novel of American girl-life, to be published
                                in the Autumn in The Ladies1 Horn". Journal. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New England magazine" TEIform="index"/>New England Magazine
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Edwin D. Mead, the eminent publicist and
                                lecturer, discusses the recent Homestead disturbances with fearless vigor and candor in
                                the September New England Magazine. He deals with Homestead and the press, the pulpit
                                and the politicians, and comes to the conclusion that it will be a bad day for the
                                American Republic if the masses of working men ever come to believe that the State
                                stands behind our millionaire barons, ready to crush those whom they would crush into
                                obedience. It is an article that all real thinkers, especially among wage-earners, will
                                read with interest. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Anti-infidel library" TEIform="index"/>The Anti-Infidel Library
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Through the kindness of H. L. Hastings of Boston, Mass., we have
                                received several pamphlets of "The Anti-Infidel Library" on modern spiritualism, by YVm.
                                TJamsoy. TheBooks :ire very interesting and instructive anil would be a valuable
                                acquisition in the hands of either a Christian or an Infidel. To follow after all the
                                spiritual manifestations of this age, with the idea of securing a profitable prize,
                                would be as futile as to search for the bag of gold at the end of the rainbow. Jesus
                                taught a system of spiritualism that will be safe for any one to follow. It was his life
                                element, and in it he taught his disciples to worship God in spirit and in truth, and to
                                lay up spiritual treasures in heaven, where rust could not corrupt. A spiritualism that
                                will teach men "to live soberly, righteously and godly in this present world" is well
                                worth our study, but if it fails to do this, it should have a qualifying name to avoid
                                mistakes. Too much deception has already been practiced and too many simple minds duped,
                                to warrant the acceptance of i;ll the tricks of legerdemain that have been palmed off in
                                the name of the spirits. Send to H. L. Hastings, 47 Cornhill, Boston, Mass., and obtain
                                some good books.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>
                                Phrenological Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> In the Phrenological Journal and Science of Health for September the
                                favored readers of that veteran monthly will rind the customary variety of good things
                                drawn from human life, some of which are especially striking and valuable. A running
                                commentary on the four candidates for President, with their portraits, is given. Three
                                distinguished criminals are contrasted. Physical Morals, a very acute and interesting
                                analysis, will receive the attention of the reflective. There are two excellent articles
                                on the application of practical mental science. Child Culture is more than usually rich.
                                Every parent should read slowly "Which was Eight?" and get a working idea as to the
                                treatment of inquisitive children. An Infant's Reflections, too, contains more sober
                                truth than its apparent humor. Science of Health department can be earnestly commended.
                                It always has seasonable advice and help. Another admirable contribution to the Moral
                                Education series graces the editorials, and many bits of things fill in the occasional
                                spaces to a nicety. The Journal is published at $1.50 a year, 15 cents a number, and is
                                offered six months "on trial" for only 50 cents. Address Fowler &amp; Wells Co., 26
                                East Twenty-first street, Xew York. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="World's Columbian exposition illustrated" TEIform="index"/>
                                THE WORLD'S COLUMBIAN EXPOSITION ILLUSTRATED,
                            </head><p TEIform="p">THE WORLD'S COLUMBIAN EXPOSITION ILLUSTRATED, . For
                                September. As the date for the dedication of the Exposition draws nearer, this popular
                                magazine grows in worth and beauty. This is the last of the monthly issues. Until the
                                opening of the Exposition it will appear twice a month, and during the Exposition,
                                weekly. This number contains full-page portraits of two prominent Exposition officials,
                                namely: Hon. James W. Haines, national commissioner from Nevada, who was prominently
                                connected with the Centennial Exposition at Philadelphia, and Hon. Thomas Smith,
                                national commissioner from New Jersey and member of the Board of Control. These are
                                direct reproductions of photographs on copper plate, and the work is done with marvelous
                                skill. A very prominent feature is the appearance of several state buildings and
                                portraits of the prominent state board members of Nebraska, Iowa and Ohio. There is an
                                autograph letter from the Pope pertaining to the National Catholic Educational Exhibit,
                                and a beautiful engraving of the statue of Patriotism which will adorn the
                                Administration building. The leading article is entitled, "The Bible, the Sabbath, the
                                Exposition and the Constitution of the United States." It is an investigation of the
                                question "Is the Bible authority for closing the World's Columbian Exposition 'on the
                                first day of the week, commonly called Sunday'? " A negative reply is given very
                                pointedly yet exhaustively. The article is bound to create discussion, but the arguments
                                are conclusive. Price 25 cents. Publishers announce their "Special Great Offer"
                                including all copies from July to January, ten in number, for only 1.50. This offer will
                                be withdrawn within a short time. They also will present each subscriber for the entire
                                issue at $12, one of the souvenir coins appropriated by Congress for the Exposition.
                                Address, J. B. Campbell, publisher, 159 &amp; 161 Adams St., Chicago, 111., U. S. A.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/>Hall's Journal of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Hall's Journal of Health. Sept. Contents. Proper food for children; The Human Ear; Skin
                                Diseases; Natural Beauty; The Gulf Stream; Canning Fruit; Sleep; Poverty of the Blood;
                                Heat as a Remedial Agent; The Baby; P^arache; Science of Ventilation; Begin the Day
                                Aright; Gout: Care of the Finger Nails; etc., etc. Office 340 West 59th. St., New York
                                City. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Same old serpent" TEIform="index"/>The same old
                                Serpent
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> 
                                FOR TEMPERANCE WORKERS. A very suggestive little leaflet illustrating"The same old
                                Serpent." It also gives instructions for organizing "Covenant Bands." Address W. H.
                                Brearley, 933 Third Ave., Detroit, Mich.</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
A GREAT WORK.
The most magnificent illustrated work ever
placed before the public for lovers of the
beautiful in nature and art, has been issued
under the auspices of The Natural Science
Association of America, 114 Fifth Avenue,
New York. An association not for gain or
profit, which is supported entirely by voluntary contributions in carrying out its object:
"To disseminate and promote natural science
information."
We refer to The Birds of North America. It
contains one hundred and nineteen artistically engraved plates, on which are represented all our birds, in their various colors of
plumage, and botanical surroundings, true to
nature. The text gives a clear and interesting account of their habits and characteristics. The systematic table, arranged according to the classification adopted by the American Ornithologist's Union, includes all.the
additions and corrections of our North American species which have been made to date,
with an index to page, plate and figure of
each species according to the A. O.U. number.
This superb work was undertaken to supply
the want in America of a good illustrated
work on Ornithology at a reasonable price.
Audubon's magnificent book, originally sold
at a thousand dollars, is now very scarce, and
only rich men can afford to buy it. An edition
of Wilson's work is now to be'had of a Philadelphia publisher for about a hundred dollars.
Baird's "North American Birds," of which
three volumes have appeared, is sold at
twenty dollars per volume, the plates, however, showing only the heads of the birds.
The public is now offered a work in every
way worthy of the subject, and attainable by
all lovers of birds, at the exceedingly low
price of $40.00, handsomely and substantially
bound in fine half bindings, or $45.00 for fine
full bindingsRussia, Seal or Turkey Morocco.
it is emphatically an original work, original
in design and execution, and whether in letter
press, illustrations or price, it is unapproached
by any thing of its kind in existence.
It is recommended by the highest scientific, ecclesiastic and educational authority as
being the most attractive, mpritorio.is. linrc
and ennobling exposition of our ornithology
yet given to the public.
Dr. Elliot Coues, author of "Birds of the
North-West," says: "It is a really notable
work." Prof. 0." -J- Maynard, author of the
"Birds of Eastern North America," says: "It
contains the best pictures of the species
which I have ever seen." Thomas G. Gentry,
author of "Life Histories of Birds," and "Nests
and Eggs of Birds of the United States," says:
"It is the cheapest and best publication on
ornithology in this country. The drawings
are of a very high order, and rivals in beauty
of design a'nd finish the more costly work's
published abroad or in this country. It should
be found in our homes and in our libraries
generally.
This edition of the work -which is limited
to one thousand copies, is being subscribed
for readily for use for the Holidays, the good
reason as Dr. Theodore Gill, a member of the
National Academy of Sciences, says: "It is
not only a nieretorious volume, but is altogether so handsome as to make it a very appropriate presentation book or ornament for
the family table."
We bespeak for it your kind and favorable
consideration as being a very useful and appropriate addition to the home anl reference
library, an 1 for presentation purposes generally, 'samples of plates and text can be had,
by'sending -2o cents in postage stamps, to the
above named address.
JOHN F. STRATTO f & SON,
43 & 45 Walker St.              N E W YORK.
MUSICALPOteME RCHAN DISE,
ViolinSt   Guitars,   Banjos,
Accordeons,  Harmonicas, &c.
AH kinds of STRINGS, jetc, etc.
A A'ortnai ( oursc  'i
for  1 tuckers.      *
20   Complete   Courses f
for   Student and    Teacher.     All  instruc- ;
tion   by mail.  Send stamp for  catalogue. |jj
American     Correspondence      College, $sj
S. Dansvillk, New York.           
GOOD AGENTS WANTED FO
By MARY LOWE DICKINSON,
Gen'l Secretary " King's
A Radical, Rational  and Racy
Reform Paper.
The bitter foe of every form of social abuse
in church and state, the expositor of Koreslianity, which is primitive Christianity revived, and the promulgator of an equitable
system of exchange which is destined to revolutionize commercial methods and
Crush  the Iniquitous  Money Power
SAMPLE    COPY    FREE.
The (Mini Star Pi. House,
3319 Cottage Grov3 Avanus.
CHICAGO, ILL.
Onward Christian
Soldiers
Daughters and Sons."
A Full Account of "Tne Epwortn l^easue," by the
Rev. J. F. Berry; "Christian Endeavor," by the
Rev. Francis E. 'Clark; "Baptise Young People's
Union," by Rev. J. M.Coon; "Woman'sChristian
Temperance Union," by Frances J. Barnes; and
'Chautauqua Circles," by KateF. Kimball. \'
Books in One.Profusely Illustrated.-Portraits of 1ienc!>rs. Handsome Illuminated
Cover. AGENTS ARE COINING MONEY.
Second Edition Now in Press.
. . Great Offer for the Next Thirty Dnys . .
THE FLAMING SWORD
Write for f'oniidentinl Terms to
The Brodix Publ'ng Co., Washington, D. C.
Piosdbc us Free
let Ota
Send 12 2-ct. Stamps
for postage & pack'g
<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure.
A cream of tartar baking Powder.   Highest of   all   in   leavening   strength.Latest
United States Got'ernment Food Heport.
Royal Baking Powder Co., IOC Wall St., N. Y.
JOHN   F.   STRATTON   &.   SON'S
CELEBRATED
Importeriofand Wholesale Dealers in nil kinds of
MUSICAL   .MERCHANDISE,
Viohns, Guitars, Banjos, Mandolines, Accordeons,
Harmonicas, Ac, all kinds of Strings, etc.etc.
43 * 45 Walker St.,                   NEW YORK.
7ride-awake workers   everywhere for
"3H3?P'3 PHOTOS UPHS of ; WOJLD"
the greatest book .oa earth; co?t'n>; $100,003;
retail at ?:}.-2), cms'i o iiistall|inents; innmino li illustrated
ciri-uliirs aaa T-.M'tiiri froe; daily
output o-ver 1500 volumes. Ag-entti wild with
Miect'.-;;-!.      -*fr.  Thus.  L.  3r.-\R"riN,  of   CentreAVoo.ster, O., $23 in 40 minutes; Rev..T.Howard
Madison, Lyons, N. Y.,  sift 101 in 7 hours;   a bonanza; in a g n i fi c e n t
outfit onlv 1.00.
Books on credit.
Freight paid. A !. GLOBE BIBLE PUBLISHING
CO,, 723 Chestnut St., Phila., Pa., or 358 Dearborn
St., Chicago, 111.
f/R oo in WW oo A MONTH can be
i/Wi 10 Mm mado working for us.
Persons preferred who can furnish a horse
and give their whole time to the business.
Spare moments may be profitably employed
also. A few vacancies in towns and cities.
B. Y. JOHNSON & CO., 26th. and Main St..
Richmond, Ya.
THE   ALTRUIST.
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is published by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all
their property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing
officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. 50 cents a year;
specimen copy free. Address A. Longley,
901 Olive St.,   St. Louis, Mo
THE HOLIDAY GUT BOOK!
"The Birds of North America."
A magnificent imperial quarto volume. Contains one hundred and NINETEEN engraved
plates, representing all our birds, colored from
nature, including a reliable and interesting
acceunt of their habits and characteristics.
Edition limited to 1,000. Subscribe early
and secure a copy for the holidays.
The "work is sold to subscribers, bound handsomely and substantially, at following net
prices; fine Russia Seal, or Turkey Morocco
half bindings, gold gilt edges $40.00; full bindings, same materials, $45.00
ENCOMIUMS IE0M THE PEESS.
"A superb Work."Publisher's Weekly.
"A great work."National Teacher.
"A magnificent Ornithological Work."Turf,
Field and Farm.
"It is oue of the most ambitious publications
ever attempted in this country or abroad."
Cleveland Leader.
"It is a marvel of beauty and excellence."
Ohio State Journal.
"No work evincing such perfect care and finish, at suah a reasonable rate, has ever been
published either in this country or abroad."
Inter-Ocean, Chicago.
save
TIME, STRENGTH)
AND PATIENCE |
By
Using
>USY WORK
SERIES.
A copy, FREE, of Nonnal Instructor, tlie best educational
paper in America,will give full particulars. Uans-ville, K.,
SHEPPS
vule, Tex
;h. ale are!
-;"11 in nine
PHOTOGRAPHS
lays;
MissSose
Adams,
WANTED
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>