<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2806" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">20</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">28</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">6</biblScope><date value="18980601" TEIform="date">June 1898</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">81-96</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="28" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="6" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
THE
MANIFESTO
JUNE,    1898.
A CONCISE HISTORY OF THE
SHAKERS.
Just Published.     The book is printed
with large type  and on excellent paper.
It contains  130 pages and has
ILLUSTRATIONS
of the Shakers and their
A SUMMARY VIEW
OF  THE
MILLENNIAL   CHURCH,
OK
"United   Society   of  Believers"
It treats of the Rise and Progress of the
Society, together with the general Principles of the Faith and Testimony.
Price, 50 cis.
The  work gives quite an extended account of the Several SOCIETIES,, their
organization and general management.
Price,  50 cts.
THE ALTRUIST..
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is publisht by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all their
property in common, all the men and
women having equal riglits in electing officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. 50 cents a year;
specimen copy free. Address A. Longley, 1719 Franklin Ave, St. Louis, Mo.
BRIEF EXPOSITION
OF  THE
Principles and Regulations
of the
SOCIETY   OF   BELIEVER.
Price, 10 cts.
AND
SH AKERISM.
A synopsis of Theology of the United   Society  of   Believers   in   Christ's
Second Appearing.    Illustrated.
By Giles B. Avery.
Price,  15cts.
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE   MA NI FES TO.
"THE LIGHT OF  THE WORLD
OR OUR SAVIOR IN ART"
Cost over $100,000 to publish. Contains nearly 200 full-page engnivin,t>'8 of our Savior, by
the Great Masters. It is not a life of Christ,
but an exhibit of all the great Masters' iiieals
of the Christ. No other book like it ever published. Agents are taking from three to
twenty orders daily. The book is so beautiful that when people see it they want it. Publisher! less than a year and alreawy in it- twenty-fifth edition, some editions t-onoi.-ting of
IS,500 books. The presses are running day
and night to till orders. (It has never been
sold in this territory.) A peru.-alof the pictures of this book i/like taking a tour among
the great art galleries of Kurope. The Hermitage, Prado, Uffizi, Pitti, Louvre, Vatican,
National of London, National of Berlin, Belvidere and other celebrated European, ait
galleries, have all placed tl eir rarest and
greatest treasures at our disposal that they
might be reproduced for this superb work.
"FIRST GLANCE AT THE PICTURES
BROUGHT TEARS TO MY EYES," says one.
"Cleared $150 first week's work with the
book," says another. Many men and women
buying and paying for homes from their sue
cei- with tlii's groat work. Also man or
woman, of good church standing, can secure
position of manager here to do office work
aii.l correspuniiiiig with agents in this terri
tory. Address for full particulars A. 1'. T.
Elder, Publisher, 189 Michigan Ave., Chicago,
111 , First Floor.
Man or Woman, of good Church standing
to act as Manager here and do office work
and correspondence at their home. Business already built up and established here.
Salary $900. Enclose self-addressed
stamped envelope for our terms to A. P.
T. Elder, General Manager, 189 Michigan
Avenue, Chicago, III., First Floor.
HUMAN NATURE
is an illustrated Monthly, now only 50 cts.
per    year,    devoted   to   PHRENOLOGY.
PHYSIOGNOMY, HEALTH, MEDICAL
& SOCIAL REFORM.
Would you like a copy?
Send 5 cts. for Sample to Prof. Haddock,
Phrenologist, 1016 Market St.,
San Francisco, Cal.
WITHOUT   DOUBT
THE BEST FAMILY  PAPER  PUBLISHED
IS   THE
NEW   YORK   WEEKLY   WITNESS.
16 Pages.   Only   q>l a year.
E          TSS
Has a very wide scope, comprising as it
does the following departments:
Editorials,
Spirit of" the Press,
Scientific and Instructive.
The Odd and Uncommon,
Our Country's* Hope,
Foreign News,
A Talk With the Doctor,
Around the Hearth.
Little Men and Women.
Weekly Articles by George R. Scott
Talmage's Sermon,
Money and Business,
World-Wide Field,
Our FamiSj Story.
JFarm and Garden,
market lteport#,
SABBATH READING.
16 Pages.   Only 5O C3iits a Yoar.
An Inter-denominational Weekly Paper.
Sabbath Reading is solely religious.
No news; no politics. A grand paper
for the truth-seeker.    It contains:
Editorial.
Christian Endeavor Topic.
Epworth League 'Topic,
Saoltatai-School Lesson,
Choice  Poetry,
Good Stories,
Reports o" Missions,
Mothers' Sallath Afternoon
fVith the Children,
And a mass of matter  carefully  selected.
Send for free sample copies of Witness
and Sabbath Reading. And send for
free sample pages of our Bagster's Bible.
Address
JOHNDOUaALL&CO., 150 Nassau Street, New York.
WONDERFUL strange REVELATIONS,
DANIEL'S & STJOHN'S
PROPHECIES.
48 page pamphlet.    Price 10 cts.
13 for $1.00.
Address,   H. B. Beab, Pbeston, Ohio.
WANTED
By   Old     Established
HouseHigh     Grade--><pb n="81" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Offering" TEIform="index"/>THE OFFERING.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>By Elder Henry C. Blinn.</byline><p TEIform="p">THERE may be many of these incidents found in the "Good Book," that have for years awakened
                            thought and possibly may have led some to step forward into a better life. Jesus was not a
                            man to sit in the chimney corner and write homilies for little sinners. He was an active
                            worker. He was interested in doing good as well as being good. He was acquainted with the
                            rich as well as with the poor, and by this peculiar instance which we now have in mind, we
                            may well understand that he had some insight into the subtlety of the human heart. While on
                            one of his errands of mercy he made a visit to the temple. Possibly his little company made
                            a slight contribution to the fund that was for the support of that sacred place. We have
                            learned from the Scriptures that Jesus and the disciples readily paid their taxes, and we
                            also remember how curiously he obtained the money, at one time, for this purpose. The little
                            company all took seats near the treasury, to observe the people as they cast in their money.
                            All classes were moving along, having this one object first in mind, and to be approbated by
                            the priests, for their generosity. Jesus evidently knew some of the rich Jews as readily as
                            we know the wealthy people of our state or nation. But the special feature in this case,
                            that made the lesson so valuable for the disciples, was that they might see the offerings
                            made by the poor Jews. It was the Lord's treasury and every person was expected to
                            contribute the <pb n="82" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 82 THE MANIFESTO. amount of their tithe, so that those
                            who had but little of this world's goods could give only their due proportion. Following
                            closely in the rear of those who were drest in "purple and fine linen," was a poor widow. As
                            she past the sacred treasury there fell from her feeble but generous hand, only two mites.
                            It was a mere pittance. Possibly in value, one mill of United States money. As we think of
                            those dominant priests who watched with eager eyes the gifts that were contributed, it
                            becomes questionable if they would have thankt her for the offering. Some persons at the
                            present day, think it is decidedly mean to pass one cent only, into the contribution box,
                            and say that it ought to be refused. It may be that such churches have no poor widows, who
                            visit them for prayers or for consolation, and on that account an offering from the poor is
                            ruled out. When we learn that some twenty-four thousand priests lived in Jerusalem, and were
                            supported by the offerings made at the temple, we do not wonder at their anxiety for the
                            money that was contributed. Jesus, however, was acquainted with all the circumstances of the
                            case, and he could not let the favorable opportunity pass without a special notice. His
                            disciples must have the benefit of this remarkable act. "And he saw also a certain poor
                            widow cast'ng in thither two mites. And he said, of a truth I say unto you, that this poor
                            widow hath cast in more than they all; for all these have of their abundance cast in unto
                            the offerings of God: but she of her penury hath cast in all the living that she had." What
                            do we learn from this lesson? Was it written for our instruction in righteousness ? As the
                            disciples had progrest but a short distance from the selfishness of the world, they were not
                            over anxious to make sacrifices either for God or for the temple. No more anxious than we
                            should be. Professing as we do a more exalted religious call, having a clearer understanding
                            of the duties that are incumbent upon those who live in the light, does our faithfulness
                            excel or even equal that of the disciples of two thousand years ago? To them it was said,
                            "Thou shalt love the Lord thy God with all thy heart, and with all thy soul, and with all
                            thy strength, and with all thy mind ; and thy neighbor as thyself." This left but little
                            room for a selfish interest. Live for God and for humanity is the duty of man. All this
                            discipline was necessary to establish a kingdom of God on the earth, and the whole history
                            of the Jews was only a preliminary work to one that was greater,a work of self-denial and
                            the cross. The spirit and testimony of Jesus Christ was long anticipated. One of the
                            prophets had said that it would be in its purifying process, like unto a refiner's fire and
                            for making people neat and clean, soul and body, it would have an effect quite like that of
                            fuller's soap upon a soiled garment. It was to be a new day, and men were to worship a new
                            and living God. <pb n="83" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> TRE MANIFESTO. 83 Idol gods of wood and stone were to
                            be cast away. To the multitudes of deities that presided over the affairs of this world,
                            every thing, good and bad had been offered. Men treated their gods as they treated each
                            other. If the gods acceded to all their wishes, they were feasted, but if they failed to do
                            this, they were scourged or pulled down from their sacred places. Jesus taught a better
                            lesson, Render to Caesar, said he, that which belongs to Caesar, and then offer that
                            sacrifice to God which is in the interest of your spiritual lives. Jesus taught his
                            disciples the necessity of giving their whole life to God,"All that a man hath," said he,
                            "yea, and his own life also." Modern Christianity however, has seen fit to bring in a bill
                            of betterments. That old way of two thousand years ago was well enough for those stiffnecked
                            Jews and even for the apostles. People did not know so much in that age, and were filled
                            with superstitious notions. But there can be only this one way. To follow Christ, we must do
                            as he did, live as he lived. Be crucified to the elements of the world. Selfishness in the
                            present is the same as selfishness in the past, and to make ClTrist the author of our
                            selfish, religious views which may cover any amount of uncleanness, is placing the religion
                            of to-day, far below that which was preacht in the desert of Arabia some three thousand
                            years ago. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Angel visitation" TEIform="index"/>ANGEL VISITATION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Clark, George W." TEIform="persName"/>By Elder George W. Clark.</byline><p TEIform="p"> the land of the Leal they come, the silent visitors, more often un seen than seen, unfelt
                            than felt, tho occasionally the vail is lifted and we see behind it, and we catch a glimpse
                            of this wonderful land and its inhabitants. It was so at the time of which we speak. The
                            labors of the day having been faithfully performed we had retired to our couch, and as usual
                            directed our thoughts to the Invisible Source of all sources, and to spirit agencies to whom
                            we are indebted for spiritual gifts and sustenance. We began to query in our mind after this
                            manner,are material objects at all times visible to spirits, or must they first become
                            endowed with sight to see them, the same as certain organisms here are given sight to see
                            things behind the vail which others not so endowed can not see. Whether walls or closed
                            doors are obstacles in the way of their ingress or egress; and whether they really see as
                            one person would see another. Suddenly, while thus ruminating, a spirit form appeared but a
                            few feet distant, revealing distinctly the head and face of a Shaker sister. The figure wore
                            one of our ordinary Shaker bonnets. We eagerly scanned the features to ascertain if it were
                            some one whom we had known in earth life but not being able to recognize her, we askt, What
                            was her mission ? Instantly she FROM <pb n="84" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 84: THE MANIFESTO. raised her arms
                            and pointed upward to a beautiful star, and in a clear impressive tone said "Come up
                            higher." We had not noticed the star until she spoke. It was almost directly overhead and
                            seemed to be quite a distance from us. It resembled one of our brightest constellations tho
                            it was not; for the position we occupied afforded a limited view of the sky. In order to see
                            the heavenly bodies overhead we must resort to the window. A striking peculiarity of the
                            vision was, that while looting directly at the figure in front of us we could see the star
                            at the same time as plainly as tho we regarded that and nothing else, and yet it was
                            directly overhead while the form was in front, so that the lines of vision were at right
                            angles to each other. The figure was visible for a moment or more and then disappeared. The
                            relation of spirit to matter is yet an unsolved question, but one thing is as clear and
                            bright to our mind as was that beautiful star and the angelic spirit to our vision,That
                            there is in the invisible realms of the Eternal, a heavenly home for all who earnestly seek
                            to find it and who cheerfully make sacrifices here to obtain a glorious reward hereafter.
                            True, our work is before us, and our reward is with us in this stage of existence, but as it
                            is written, "Eye hath not seen, nor ear heard, neither have entered into the heart of man,
                            the things which God hath prepared for them that love him." While the vision tarried, there
                            came a wave of inspiration, which thrilled our whole being and gave rise to the following
                            lines : There's a higher more glorious life to obtain Than e'er can be found upon earth's
                            broad domain, Where angels with joy their voices upraise, In ravishing, soul-thrilling
                            paeans of praise. Oh would that their chorus might sound far and near, It would help lift
                            the burden, give comfort and cheer, Dispel the vague fancies that oft come and go Like the
                            tides of the sea as they ebb to and fro. Come higher, up higher, away from the world, Let
                            purity's banner be widely unfurled, Arise from the vain, fleeting pleasures of time, . Tread
                            firmly the narrow way mortals must climb. A highway is cast up'tis beautifully clean Made
                            sacred and pure by love's holy sheen, Where the feet of the conqueror often hath trod As he
                            wended his way up this mountain of God. The thorns and the briars may oft wound and pierce,
                            And beasts of the forest all eager and fierce Attack on the way; but the balsam is there,
                            And purity, peace, are shielded by prayer. Oh come, come away, again we repeat, The immortal
                            life is worth more than meat. Yea, upward we'll soar with you, spirit friend, And ever prove
                            faithful and true to the end. Enfield, Conn.</p></div2><pb n="85" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bethesda" TEIform="index"/>BETHESDA.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Vinneo, Cora C." TEIform="persName"/>By Cora C. Vinneo.</byline><p TEIform="p">Without the Holy City's ponderous gate, Lay bright Bethesda's sweet refreshing pool, Whose
                            waters gusht from hidden fountains cool. , Beside its banks lay stricken ones whom fate Had
                            made to suffer, there to watch and wait Till God's good Angel came, as was its rule, To
                            bring the gift unknown to man or school, That would restore the sick and desolate. We all
                            have sin and weakness and distress, That need the healing of the cleansing wave; That need
                            the power of the Angel's touch. We all must pray for comfort and redress, Must seek the help
                            that mighty is to save, We can not serve our Savior overmuch. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes from the diary of William Deming..." TEIform="index"/>Notes from the Diary of William Deming...</head><p TEIform="p">[Notes from the Diary of
                            William Deming, of Hancock, Mass, who with Brother Eliab Harlow of New Lebanon, N. Y.
                            visited the Believers at Union Village, Ohio, Pleasant Hill and South Union, Ky.]
                            ON the 21st of May 1810, William Deming and Eliab Harlow, were sent by the Society at New
                            Lebanon, to visit the Believers in Ohio and Kentucky. The distance from New Lebanon, N. Y.
                            to Union Village, Ohio, was seven hundred and fifty-five miles. This journey was to be made
                            on horseback, as much of the way no roads had been made for carriages at that early date.
                            They were enabled, however, to reach some public or private house every night, where they
                            could secure good food and a comfortable resting place. Their zigzag journey becomes
                            interesting as it is so different from what it would.be at the present date, 1898. At night,
                            on the first day, they put up at Stocking's tavern in Hudson, a distance of twenty-eight
                            miles from New Lebanon. Then crost the North River at Catskill and reacht the village of
                            Kingston. The third night they were in Montgomery. On the 24th of May they past the Groshen
                            Court House and reacht Brooktown. On the 25th, they left the state of New York and entered
                            New Jersey, and at night were in the town of Hardwick. From New Jersey they past into the
                            state of Pennsylvania and stopt at Easton Hotel. For the first time, during the journey,
                            they now mention the crossing of a toll-bridge. They next past through a Moravian town and
                            at night stopt at the village of Kutestown. The next day they reacht Mayorstown and on the
                            29 th of <pb n="86" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 86 THE MANIFESTO. May they were in Harrisburg, and were
                            pleased to note that the house kept by Jeremiah Rees was ''a place of good entertainment."
                            They now crost the Susquehanna river and reacht the village of Shippingsburg. The journey
                            took them over the Blue Ridge Mountains and over Sideling and Race Hills, to the tavern kept
                            at the foot of Dry Ridge. After riding some thirty-seven miles farther they rested for the
                            night. While passing over Mount Pleasant a large rattlesnake lay coiled by the side of the
                            road. Providing a safe place for the horses, the Brethren obtained some weapons from an old
                            fence, and soon put the venomous reptile where it could do no harm. This night they rested
                            in South Huntington. After crossing Monongahela river, and getting their clothes very wet
                            and muddy, they rode on till they reacht the village in AVashington. On June 5th they
                            entered the state of Virginia and crost the Ohio river, at the ferry, and remained at that
                            place during the night. Their next stop was at Morristown. Leaving this place they past
                            through Cambridge and over another toll-bridge and rested for the night in Union township.
                            They next crost the Muskingum river and stopt at Redding. The next day they past through
                            Lancaster and rested at night in Pickaway. Then crost the Scioto river, and at night rested
                            in Fairfi"ld. Altho they were nearly at their journey's end and had traveled some twenty
                            miles they made this special note,"It was by the worst road that ever any man would desire
                            to see." When they reacht the village of Vernon and made preparations to rest for the night,
                            it must have been with thankful hearts for the protecting care of a kind Providence. On the
                            12th of June which was the last day of the journey and was to be about twenty miles, they
                            crost the little Miami river and then past through the village of Lebanon, which was only a
                            few miles from Believers. A kind and hearty welcome was extended to the Brethren on reaching
                            the family where Elder David Darrow lived. There was great cause of gratitude for the safe
                            arrival of the Brethren, after making such an extended journey of seven hundred and
                            fifty-five miles. These Brethren, altho so far from home were not wholly among strangers, as
                            several Brethren and Sisters had been sent to Union Village, as early as 1805, from the
                            Society of New Lebanon. June 13. As this diary was written by Brother William Deming there
                            is but little said about Brother Eliab Harlow altho he was evidently in the company most of
                            the time. It is a curious fact that the first building which the Brethren visited for
                            inspection was the Meeting House. The early Shakers manifested a very commendable zeal in
                            providing a place for public worship, as a building of the first importance in the interests
                            of the Society. They next visited the saw-mill and learned that the Shakers hauled and sawed
                            their own lumber for the several buildings which they were proposing to build. A visit to
                            the tannery also assured them that they manufactured their own <pb n="87" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. 87 leather and were also able to sell to those not of the Community. William
                            entered at once into the duties of the place and became an interested and profitable
                            visitor. One day he accompanied the Brethren to the woods, to obtain a load of butternut
                            bark and the next day he was at work in the sawmill. He assisted them in laying the sills to
                            the new dwelling and then in the drawing of stones for building purposes. As Brother Eliab
                            was a very skillful physician, he was evidently more or less occupied in the duties of his
                            special office. The visit at Turtle Creek, as Union Village was then called, lasted till the
                            11th of July. A Public Service was held on each Sabbath. The preachers were Elder Benjamin
                            S. Youngs and Richard McNemar. Two Brethren from Busro were at Union Village on a visit,
                            Robert Gill and John Stoven. John had been taken prisoner by the Indians, several times and
                            through them suffered much abuse. It was fear of these Indian raids that caused the
                            Believers to leave their settlement in Busro. On the 11th of July the Brethren from New
                            Lebanon left Union Village for Pleasant Hill, Ky. in company with Joseph Allen. It was a
                            journey of four days. "The land on which the Believers have settled is very excellent, but
                            rather uneven, stony in some places and everywhere a solid body of rock underneath. On the
                            21st of July, I accompanied eight Brethren to Salt River, on a fishing excursion. We waded
                            in the water for six hours and caught forty-eight little fishes. They were bull-heads, perch
                            and flat-sides." "With Brother Joseph we visited the Deer Park of Col. Thomson. He had five
                            elk and forty deer." "The Meeting House was not finisht and I assisted Samuel Hooser, who
                            was at work on the building, during one day. We visited several families of Believers who
                            had not yet moved to the Community and enjoyed a very profitable time." The settlement at
                            Pleasant Hill, at that date was called Shawnee Run. July 30. The Brethren left for South
                            Union or Jasper and reacht that place on the evening of the third day. On this trip they
                            forded the Rolling Fork, Green River, Little Barren River and Big Barren River. They visited
                            two caves and went in about ten rods and pi'onounced them beautiful sights. A visit was made
                            to the families of Elisha Thomas, John Rankin and Samuel Edes. "We entered one cave that was
                            forty feet deep. At the bottom of this cave was a swift rushing. stream. It was a river in
                            the earth." "On the Sabbath we attended the Public Service, but some of the spectators
                            behaved very rudely." On the 7th of August the Brethren left Jasper and directed their
                            course homeward. They past by a mound that had recently been uncovered. It proved to be very
                            interesting. Trees were growing on it that measured some thirty inches in diameter. The
                            mound was thirty feet high and forty rods in <pb n="88" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 88 THE MANIFESTO.
                            circumference near the ground. On the 9th of August they again reacht Shawnee Run or
                            Pleasant Hill and remained there till the 21st, when they moved on to Union Village where
                            they arrived at evening on the 23rd. The distance traveled since leaving Ohio was five
                            hundred and fifty-eight miles, and the expenses $7.48 The Brethren remained at Union Village
                            till the 13th of September when they left that place for home, returning by the same route
                            that was taken on their journey west. Two Sisters who had been visiting at Union Village
                            returned with them to New Lebanon, where they all arrived in safety at noon on the 3rd of
                            October. They had traveled during their journey two thousand two hundred and eighty-seven
                            miles, and their expenses were $65.43</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Safely anchored" TEIform="index"/>SAFELY ANCHORED.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cummings, Ada S." TEIform="persName"/>By Ada S. Cummings.</byline><p TEIform="p">[ Written for Brother Samuel Kendrick.] 
                            All was quiet in the Harbor, Evening shades were close at hand, Where the ever restless
                            waters Beat upon the silv'ry sand. And the sun was slowly sinking 'Neath the cloud's
                            resplendent rim, When a barque from life's long journey To the port, came sailing in. Now
                            throw out the anchoring hawser And make fast the sturdy barque, Which has stood through
                            storm and danger, Out upon life's ocean, dark 1 For unto the port of Heaven Comes the craft,
                            all safe at last; Oh how grandly o'er the billows Has it rode thro' tempest's blast! Thus,
                            within the twilight's gloaming, Many ships come sailing in; Sailing in from storm and
                            danger, There a place of rest to win Where the wicked cease from troubling And the weary are
                            set free. Safe, within the golden harbor, Where the many mansions be. There, beneath the
                            glimmering shadows Of the sunset's borderland, <pb n="89" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 89 Where
                            the ever murmuring waters Beat upon the shining strand ; There, our barques will some time
                            anchor To the moorings on the shore, Where the beacon from the Lighthouse Sheds its rays
                            forevermore. There the weary sailors gather When their sun sinks in the West, And the
                            Captain,Christ, our Father, Gives to them their well-earned rest. There they dwell beside
                            the river, Safe within the port of Love, Firmly anchored to the Haven, In their happy home
                            above. Sabbathday Lake, Me.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Friendly warning" TEIform="index"/>A FRIENDLY WARNING</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Breedlove, Virgie" TEIform="persName"/>By Virgie Breedlove.</byline><p TEIform="p">EVEN tho there should exist in every Community, one or more of that . very unpleasant class
                            known as mischief-makers, our duty to Society becomes more imperative, as we walk among them
                            to see that we are not brought under the same influence. As we would avoid a scorpion
                            through fear of its deadly poison, so we would avoid the influence of an habitual
                            mischief-maker, who destroys the happiness of Society Some have compared these unpleasant
                            busybodies, to the "Stormy Petrels" of the ocean, as their presence is quite certain of a
                            forth-coming storm. But while the little bird is innocent of doing any harm, the man or
                            woman who engenders strife by exaggeration, or by false representations is a sad affliction
                            to any society. By some eminent minds this is clast as a disease, and sanitary means should
                            be used to bring about the return of a better state. Sometimes their very presence is an
                            indication of trouble. Their word is not reliable, they twist and contort the simplest
                            remark, till it becomes entirely changed. Sometimes these persons are known to misrepresent
                            even their best friends, and in this way not only injure others, but bring great harm upon
                            themselves. Truly "the tongue can no man tame; it is an unruly evil, full of deadly poison,"
                            especially if it becomes the medium of the social mischief-maker. South Union, Ky.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nothing great, nothing curious..." TEIform="index"/>Nothing great, nothing curious...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Nothing great, nothing curious, nothing marvelous, nor even miraculous in creatures, tends in
                            the least to effect the work of regeneration. This is wrought by daily self-denial,
                            mortification and suffering: by quietly and patiently doing and suffering the will of God,
                            and rejecting our own.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="P., R. W." TEIform="persName"/>R. W. P.</byline></div2><pb n="90" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. JUNE, 1898. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is publisht by the "United
                            Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued regularly by
                            the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the reKgious
                            views of the Ordeii and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. Address all communications
                            to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. TER.MS. One copy one year, postage paid.
                            .50 A cross in the margin will show that your subscription has closed. Remittances for
                            subscription by Money Order should be on the Post Office at Concord, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">April. Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. Thermometer. Rain. Snow. 1897. 45.77 3.5 in. 4
                                in. 1898. 42. 3.125 " 8 " Highest Temp, during this mo. 66 above 0. Lowest " " " " 18 "
                                " Number of rainy days " " 10 " " snowy " " " 4 " " clear " " " 9 " " cloudy" " " 7 May,
                                1898. The spring has put on its vernal attire. The green fields are decked with yellow
                                and white floral tints, and violets open their petals to variegate the sombre green. Ths
                                trees are opening their blossoms to afford labor for the busy bees to gather honey all
                                the day from every opening flower. The husbandmen are busy turning the greensward and
                                putting in the seed for the. future harvest of cereals and vegetables, the life
                                sustaining products of man and beast. The planting and sowing is risky business this
                                spring, we are having so much rainy weather, but with all the hinderances we are making
                                progress. We have started a new strawberry bed of between two thousand and three
                                thousand plants which chiefly are the Bubach No. 5 with an admixture of Lovett as
                                fertilizers. The medicine business is our chief source of revenue in the Brethren's line
                                of industries. The Sisters have a variety of fancy work which furnishes them with
                                needful cash. The Brethren and Sisters work harmoniously in bearing the burdens of life,
                                in this they are the light of the world. They stand on a plane of equality in things
                                spiritual and temporal. At present, the available help of both Brethren and Sisters is
                                employed in divesting two hundred coon skins of fur and hair. This tries the texture of
                                the skin on the hands of the workmen; but as the Irishman said; "Sure for the money it
                                must be done." This fur-pulling uses up the best part of three weeks. With all the
                                burdens to keep the mortal temples in uprightness we endeavor to keep our spiritual
                                sanctums fitted for the entrance into the home eternal in the Heavens, so that we may be
                                made welcome by the denizens of the Christ sphere, the realm of supernal glory. At
                                present we have living ministers among us who keep the gospel furnace flaming hot for
                                the consuming of sin of every name and nature. The health of the family is evidently
                                good as all attend to taking their daily rations, and are ready and willing to use their
                                strength where it is felt they can do the most good. Blessed are they that can love and
                                bless both with heart and hands for they shall be crowned with life eternal. Calvin G.
                                Reed. <pb n="91" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 91 South Family. May, 1898. Live, love, laugh
                                and joyous be Grand truths in nature quickly see Learn the music in the air Which is
                                floating every where. Note the beauty of each plant Know that God to each does grant
                                Special care all of his own To each rock and tiny stone. On Tuesday evening April 12th,
                                in the Hall of the Church family, Dr. Peebles lectured on his circuit around the world.
                                Many went to hear him tell of scenes and people he had seen. It was strangely charming
                                to hear about his foreign travels, first to far Australia's shores and their ways and
                                peculiar style of living, as the Bushmen apart from culture and civilization. Of the
                                heathen and their life, of India, that land of wondrous fame; of the Brahmans and
                                Buddhists. He witnessed many scenes of the Brahmans wondrous skill; the power they have
                                to move material things by their will. Some books, he said, were laid upon a table in a
                                room where sat a wise old Brahman who beckoned to them to move across the floor to him
                                saying, "come, come," when instantly the table rockt and the books moved along the floor
                                and stopt just where the Doctor stood. He took them up, examined them, and found thej
                                were real books. At the close of the lecture the congregation sang that grand old
                                melody, "God is infinitely able to sustain the weak and feeble." On April 13, we held a
                                meeting and Dr. Peebles spoke again, which made the people glad. Singing and speaking
                                was in order, and not a few spirits of departed friends were present. We marcht the good
                                inspiring march and sung the old songs;the same sweet songs we used to sing when we were
                                young. That meeting we will not soon forget. Among the fine entertainments of the season
                                we record the Arbor Day exhibition by the public school. The dialogs and recitations
                                were of the very best; all original,the work of Sister Ada Brown the Principal of the
                                school. Each part was perfectly executed, the singing was commendable. Sister Eosetta
                                Stevens presided at the organ. A pretty piece was sung entitled "You Know Where the
                                Violets Grow" words and music by Sister Eosetta, assistant teacher. At the close of the
                                exercises the National air was sung by the school and the scholars marcht away a merry
                                band. Representatives from all the families were present to participate in the loyal
                                spirit of the day. Genevieve DeGraiv.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station, Conn.</head><p TEIform="p">North Family. May, 1898. Mark our ways, how noiseless A)l, and sweetly voiceless, Tho the
                                March winds pipe to make our passage clear; Not a whisper tells Where our small seed
                                dwells, Nor is known the moment green whan our tips appear. We thread th? earth in
                                silence, In silence build our bowers, And leaf by leaf in silence show, till we laugh
                                atop sweet flowers. Again the earth has donned her emerald robe, and seems to have quite
                                forgotten the pure mantle she so recently wore. Cherry-trees are white with bloom, and
                                peach-trees promise a harvest. The orchards are much improved by the skillful use of the
                                pruning-knife. Fruit trees past their days of bloom, and others unserviceable have been
                                hewn down, and in their s,tead have set out one hundred and ten cherry and plum trees.
                                We have also set out a large bed of asparagus. Our Sister Florence Staples who was so
                                successful in the cultivation of currants in Canaan, has already commenced her favorite
                                employment with five-hundred slips. Future prospects are bright. "We fear not the coming
                                time," but while we are progressing and prospering in temporal affairs, we earnestly
                                pray that we may not slight the spiritual; as it is for the growth <pb n="92" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/>
                                92 THE MANIFESTO. of the spirit, and for the attainment of all virtue, that we have
                                banded ourselves together and we serve the Lord with gladness. Edith Shufelt.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">May, 1898. The effort that is being made to bring the different religious beliefs into a
                                closer communion is a commendable one. The World's Congress of Eeligions, held in 1893
                                was an educator on the line of progressive thought, and the one to be held in India, the
                                present year, will be a continuation of the work which is removing the angularities and
                                overreaching the boundaries of that exclusiveness which for so many centuries has been
                                the cause of the contentions that have arisen among the \arious beliefs. That the call
                                should come from one representing a belief that antedates our own by many centuries is
                                evidence that "the world moves onward and the light grows stronger." Certainly good must
                                come by a comparison of ideas which will help remove the rust and mould that have
                                collected through ages of exclusiveness. The workers on the farm and garden are renewing
                                their activity and sowing the good seed. At present we are having a superabundance of
                                rain which is retarding the progress of spring work; but before the close of the season
                                we may be calling for rain, so we will accept what comes and be thankful. We enjoy the
                                perusal of the home circle notes; it seems like a personal communion with our friends,
                                and the thoughts exprest by those who are striving to sustain the publication of our
                                Monthly are accepted with pleasure. Hamilton DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">May, 1898. Easteb-day will long remain indelible on memory's page. Our chapel was well
                                decorated with evergreens, vines, plants and flowers, while the varied exercises given,
                                afforded invited friends and ourselves, a feast of good things. Making Easter, A day
                                bright with music, emblematic of tho't, Sacred mementos of Christ, whose life bro'f The
                                glad tidings of love, purity and sweet peace, Fruits of a kingdom that e'er will
                                increase In that sphere where truth rules and blest justice bears sway, Where night is
                                eclipst with brightness of day; Where the ensign of freedom e'er floats o'er the land,
                                Where service to God, means service to man, Thus resurrecting from the darkened tombs of
                                sin, Souls bright with hope, all glorious within, Christ's mission on earth as his
                                teachings portray, Was to raise a standard and pave a way, Whereby to resurrect from
                                error's dark niglit, A gospel of love, liberty and light, Of industry, equality, justice
                                and truth, Heaven's high estate for aged and youth. Our maple harvest fell below last
                                year's record, yielding but one hundred and ninety gallons of syrup. While in operation
                                companies of three to thirty of our young people, spent a few hours at the camp,
                                indulging in the much prized "chopsticks," (maple candy cooled on snow) swinging and
                                having a good time. As I write the word camp, thought contrasts the peaceful
                                significance of ours to the turbulent ones of the brave, liberty aspiring Cubans and our
                                own American army. There opens to my vision the hor- / rors on sea and land and already
                                occurred and must happen before the red, white and blue with one star can float in
                                freedom. I turn from our dark National war scene and cast upon the banner of Society
                                news, the bright picture revealing the appointment of Elder William Briggs to our
                                ministerial order and whose Enfield kindred give the salute,It is well and could not be
                                bettered. Elder Henry whose long period of service to East Canterbury and Enfield,
                                should be untaxt with extra Society weight as he enamels the closing records of his
                                earth life with the gold of eternal <pb n="93" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 93
                                faithfulness. Unnecessary taxation of one's mental and physical structure when nearing
                                the immortal sphere is not conducive to a cheery entrance where joy and sweet rest are
                                as luxuriant in growth as seeds in peculiarly rich soil. George H. Baxter.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Sabbathday Lake, Me.</head><p TEIform="p">May, 1898. This is a beautiful morning but the bleak, cold wind seems unwilling to go and
                                is roaring wildly among the branches of the trees. April has been very cold and rainy
                                and we farmers and gardeners are much disappointed in the tarry occasioned by the cold
                                weather, after such a warm and delightful March, but we now hope for better days. In the
                                meantime, we have been busy, Sisters on the fancy work for sale and both Brethren and
                                Sisters in the greenhouse, days at a time, transplanting celery, cabbage and flower
                                seedlings and over eight hundred dozen tomato plants have been transplanted twice. This
                                is pleasant work when blest with plenty of sunshine but the dull days that we have been
                                having the past month have almost given us "the blues." During the past week the Sisters
                                have set out a thousand strawberry plants and sown part of the sweet peas. The Brethren
                                have set a row of maple trees on the west side of the road through our village which
                                adds much to the beauty of the place. Our good aged father Samuel Kendrick has left us
                                for his home in "Mansions of Light" and while we miss him very much no doubt his
                                influence for good will still remain. Ada S. Cummin gs.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Narcoossee, Florida" TEIform="index"/> Narcoossee, Fla.</head><p TEIform="p">May, 1898. It may not be too much to say that difficulty assists in the strengthening and
                                conserving of human power, altho it may seem to the individual like passing over a rocky
                                mountain to find a pleasant valley. It is quite true that the force which is used to
                                break down the opposition, becomes in the future so changed that it enables us to face
                                new difficulties with much greater power. Through this we are beginning to-find what may
                                be required of us to form a home in a new country. Could we have shared the experience
                                we now have, when we moved to Florida, we might, at this date, be able to sing the
                                Victor's song. To-day the clouds have a more beautiful silver lining than ever before.
                                Knowledge lias been gained by our failures and our difficulties. If there is to be any
                                more Florida or Georgia movements we should suggest, that we look well to our laurels,
                                and move slowly. We should obtain correct information in regard to the people, and then
                                of the land we are to cultivate. During the past three months we have experienced a
                                severe drought. The lakes have less water and we are able to ploi gh nearly two acres of
                                muck land, and shall plant it with northern potatoes. Our table is now supplied with
                                sweet potatoes, beans, cabbage and lettuce, direct from our garden, and on April 22,
                                Brother Benjamin brought in the first ear of corn. At times we hear rumors of war, but
                                it does not mar our peace. We are able to hold our meetings and to follow the voice of
                                conscience. We are Believers in our quiet and humole life, and are not moved by the
                                sound of war, altho it has come so near. We are studying diligently the spirit of true
                                heroism, where the burdens of life are cheerfully borne and sacrifices willingly made.
                                Andrew Barrett.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="history" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Turnkey, no. 1" TEIform="index"/>THE TURNKEY. No. 1</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/>By Elder H. C. Blinn.</byline><p TEIform="p">And now I am wondering if you ever saw a "Turnkey." It is a curious, little surgical
                            instrument formerly used by the Dentists. It may be some six inches long <pb n="94" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. and weighs not over an ounce or two. The shaft of the instrument is bent
                            at right angles with the handle and opposite to the fulcrum. The instrument received this
                            name from the manner in which it was used. One turn of the hand was the only motion marle in
                            extracting a tooth,hence the name. Forceps were not generally used till about 3 880, and
                            even then the Dentists held tenacicusly to the key, by saying that all the teeth could not
                            be extracted with the forceps. Persons sometimes love to tell marvelous stories of the
                            wonderful instruments of torture which they have seen in some foreign country, and yet we
                            have one in our own home that has won a markt distinction through a long series of years.
                            Who invented the Turnkey? History is fortunate in that it leaves us to conjecture. Some say
                            the credit or discredit should be awarded to Garengeot, who lived in Europe, but as the
                            "Dental Canthook" is also said to have been invented in Europe, the whole matter of
                            inventions may be open to doubt. If the writer of the book of Genesis had inserted so much
                            as one paragraph about aching teeth we should have believed at once, that some son of Cain,
                            as they were all cunning workmen, made this wonderful instrument. And yet, neither Jabal nor
                            Jubal nor Tubal may have ever seen a Turnkey. Possibly it may have been invented at the time
                            when men were studying for forms of exquisite torture, to make other men deny their faith in
                            a just God. It would no doubt, have been a valuable acquisition to the set of tools used for
                            that purpose. History is positive in reference to the use of pincers for pulling out the
                            finger nails and toe nails of the condemned, and like their notable descendant, Snyder, they
                            may have used these same tools in the extraction of teeth. We may, after all, be obliged to
                            credit a more modern page of history, and look among the peaceable yeomen of the old country
                            for this now discarded instrument. Dr. Fitch thinks that an interest must have been taken in
                            the care, in the usefulness and beauty, as well as in the general appearance of the teeth
                            from the earliest age of man. That even then some means were provided to correct deformities
                            and to extract broken or decayed teeth. In his Dental Surgery, page 7 he says: "That the
                            Natural History of the teeth, so far as regarded their development, and their Anatomy as far
                            as concerned their form, external appearance and insertion in the jaws, must necessarily
                            have been known to the earliest races of men." With the Brahmans, the care of cleaning their
                            teeth is coeval with the date of their religion. The early Greeks had a class whom they
                            spoke of as Physicians or Surgeon Dentists. They have also spoken of artificial teeth as a
                            common occurrence. Martial, a Greek poet, says;"Are you not ashamed to purchase [artificial]
                            teeth and hair, but what will you do for an eye, as there are none to sell." In the "Dark
                            Ages" came a night of ignorance, and much of science and art was hid from sight. On the
                            return of learning at a later date, with other things came the better knowledge of the
                            teeth, and in 1563 Eustachius publisht his first work on Dentistry. Other works followed
                            this, and by 1171 a long list could be named that treated more or less fully upon the
                            Anatomy and use and abuse of natural and artificial teeth. One of these dark age physicians
                            was consulted in regard to a swelling of the cheek, and decided it was a tumor. The tumor
                            however, proved to be an accumulation of tartar. He then procured a hammer and chisel and
                            went to work. The tooth and tartar were soon dislodged, and the specimen was sent to the
                            Academy of Surgery in 1189 where it can be seen, as well as the error of the surgeon. We
                            have still another line for investigation, and it seems to be quite favorable. If we could
                            establish the date of the in94 <pb n="95" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 95 vention of the
                            "Canthook," I think there would be no doubt about the "Turnkey." They evidently were brought
                            out, on the same day. One would almost think that they were invented by a man who hauled
                            logs or workt in a saw-mill, as they bear so close a resemblance to one of the tools which
                            these men use. In the rolling of logs, levers of different patterns are used, but the most
                            efficient instrument in this work is the Canthook. When it is fastened to a log it does not
                            easily quit its hold, and with its long handle it affords a powerful leverage. (To be
                            continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My home" TEIform="index"/>MY HOME.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bird, William" TEIform="persName"/>By William Bird</byline><p TEIform="p">Take me home to the place Where I first saw the light, To my dear Shaker friends take me
                            home, Where they sing with delight, And praise God, day and night, To my loved Shaker
                            friends take me home. In that good Shaker Home Where they learn to serve the Lord, Where
                            they do his holy will And praise in one accord. Here they live as SisterBrother And serve
                            the Lord together Rejoicing in his work all the day. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beginning the day" TEIform="index"/>BEGINNING THE DAY.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> Oub early hours tune all the rest of the day. Broken, discordant, or disfigured
                                    days are possible largely because we have not learned to protect their beginnings.
                                    We trust to chance to get through the day. Against such dangers a devotional habit
                                    is the surest and most natural protection. An appeal to our own experience reveals
                                    that only as we have made it a rule to pray have we prayed effectively. To respect
                                    this rule rather than our moods is the only guarantee of secure and steady living.,
                                    We may say as little as we please about our devotional habits, but a Christian life
                                    which can rely upon itself is sure to have them. There is a sustained power in the
                                    life Avhich carefully observes its devotions, and nowhere do we need them more than
                                    at the beginning of each mysterious new day, with all its unknown dangers and
                                    blessings.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="S. S. Times" TEIform="index"/>S. S. Times.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Child's voice" TEIform="index"/>THE CHILD'S VOICE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Massey, Arthur E." TEIform="persName"/>By Jr.hur E. Mnssey.</byline><p TEIform="p">The voice of a child In a wilderness wild Came floating on dew laden air, It rivaled all
                            sound, And made my heart bound, Till all things lookt wondrously fair. The heavens seemed
                            brighter, My steps grew much lighter, I breathed a soul prayer void of speech; 'Twas the
                            voice of Great AUM Spake through that child form, A sweet lesson my sad soul to teach. It
                            said; "Be a child, Pure, humble and mild, Consider the lilies of earth, Bid all care depart,
                            That Christ in thy heart May now seal thy Spiritual birth " Narcoossee, Fla.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The confession of sin to God..." TEIform="index"/>The confession of sin to God...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The confession of sin to God, is one of the foundation principles of the Shaker Church. It is
                            taught from Genesis to Revelation and in Christ's church must be a ruling feature. An
                            unconfest Christian would be quite like the description of old Babylon, as given by the
                            Revelator,"The habitation of demons, and the hold of every foul spirit, and a cage of every
                            unclean and hateful bird."</p></div2><div2 type="history" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In the days of Slavery..." TEIform="index"/>In the days of Slavery...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> the days of Slavery, Canaan New Hampshire Academy was broken up for the
                                    unpardonable sin of admitting a few colored pupils on equal terms with the white, by
                                    vote of the people in legal town meeting assembled. The edifice was lifted from its
                                    foundations, and by three hundred men and a hundred yoke of oxen was hauled out of
                                    tow.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Acts of Anti-Slavery Apostles" TEIform="index"/>Acts of Anti-Slavery
                                Apostles.</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="96" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>OUR EXCHANGES.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Living epistle" TEIform="index"/>The Living Epistle
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Living Epistle is an Evangelical Monthly Magazine devoted to Biblical Knowledge,
                                Scriptural Holiness and Pure Literature. J. C. Hornberger, Editor. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Teachers' journal" TEIform="index"/>The Teachers"
                                Journal
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Teachers"
                                Journal, is publisht by the Rev. P. Anstadt &amp; Sons, at York, Penn. It contains
                                the International Sund;iy School Lessons, with extended explanatory notes, also
                                blackboard illustrations. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tribes" TEIform="index"/>The Tribes
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Tribes is a Journal devoted to the exposition of the
                                prophesies, concerning the Twelve Tribes of Israel, in the light of sacred and secular
                                history. E. Harrington, Editor. Denver, Col. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spirit of truth" TEIform="index"/>The Spirit of Truth
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Spirit of Truth is an official paper
                                of the World's Universal Congress of Angels. Edited by Thomas Cook, as the medium who
                                shall not speak for himself; but whatsoever he shall hear, that shall he speak. Publisht
                                at Hot Springs, Ark.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kendrick, Samuel" TEIform="index"/>Samuel Kendrick
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Samuel Kendrick, at Sabbathday Lake, Me. April 22, 1898. Age 86 years 6 mo. and 1 day.
                                Having been faithful to the end, we know a crown awaits him. W. D. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gregory, Sophia" TEIform="index"/>Sophia Gregory
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Sophia Gregory, at
                                Pleasant Hill, Ky. April 27, 1898. Age 88 years and 9 mo. Sister Sophia entered the
                                Society when a small child. Her parents were among the pioneers. She was faithful in all
                                her duties, and devoted to the cause of right. J. W. S. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="George, Irena" TEIform="index"/>Irena George
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Irena George, at Enfield, N. H.
                                May 22, 1898. Age 91 years 1 mo. and 13 clays. She had been with the Society from a
                                child and had given all the years of active life, to the interests of the consecrated
                                Home, and to the maintenance of those principles which are its foundation. She is
                                gathered home, as a sheaf fully ripe for the Harvester! R. C.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Law of vibrations" TEIform="index"/>The Law of Vibrations
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Law of Vibrations in I Am Science, by T. J. Shelton. In this little work of nearly a
                                hundred pages, the author has given a full illustration of the work of healing in which
                                he is engaged. To understand it fully, one must carefully study what is written.
                                Publisht at Little Rock, Ark. Price 25 cts. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Small families" TEIform="index"/>Small Families
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Small Families by H. L. Hastings. In this
                                little work of less than thirty pages there is a fund of information collected from the
                                Bible especially, which may prove a safe and sure guide to the interested reader.
                                Brother Hastings is an able advocate for the cause he has espoused, and if he can
                                persuade those who have either large or small families, to bring up their children "in
                                the admonition of the Lord," he will do a wonderful work on the earth. H. L. Hastings,
                                47 Cornhill, Boston, Mass. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Journal of Hygeio-Therapy" TEIform="index"/>The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy. The Science of Life; The
                                Preparation of Food; The Slaughter of the Birds; Law and Medicine; The Science of
                                Phrenology. Dr. T. V. Gifford &amp; Co. Kokomo, Ind. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Outlook" TEIform="index"/>The
                                Outlook
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The May Magazine Number of The
                                Outlook has on its cover a fine portrait of Commodore Dewey, and nearly twenty pages are
                                devoted to a historical account of the war and to editorial comment thereon. The article
                                on "The Parks and the People," by Samuel Parsons, Jr. ex-Superintendent of the New York
                                Parks, is accompanied by numerous charming pictures now first printed, of scenes in
                                Central Park, Prospect Park, and Morningside Park. The fiction for the number is also
                                distinctively of a seasonable character; the author is Maria Louise Pool, and the title
                                is "In Sappin' Time." It may also be specially noted that the month's installment of Dr.
                                Edward Everett Hale's "James Russell Lowell and His Friends" contains some beautiful
                                photographs made for The Outlook, of Elmwood in the early spring. Other features of this
                                Magazine Number are; An article on "Mr. Stedman as a poet," with a full-page portrait;
                                an article by Clifton Johnson on "English Inns," illustrated by photographs taken by the
                                author; an article on "The New Polychrome Bible," by Professor Francis Brown, of Union
                                Seminary; an article on "Municipal Water-Works," by Mr. M. N. Baker, of "The Engineering
                                News;" a readable paper by Mr. Charles M. Skinner on "Animal Life;" and several other
                                light sketches, poems and articles, besides the usual reviews, news departments, and
                                editorials. ($3 a year. The Outlook Company ^ 287 Fourth Avenue, New York.) </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Popular monthly" TEIform="index"/>Popular Monthly
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A stirring
                                poem on Cuba, by Joaquin Miller, opens the May number of Frank Leslie's Popular Monthly.
                                If there are any Americans who do not wish the freedom of the Cu-</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p19"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
bans, a reading of this poem will quickly
bring them into line.   This magazine contains much of great timely interest.    ""Naval
Warfare of To-day" is an elaborate article,
giving the most complete and best illustrated description of this mueh-tsilked-uf topic
that has yet appeared.    It is written by Frederick Stone Daniel, mill is t'.ccompsinied by
more than twenty-five half-tone cuts of all
the leading warships in our navy, iiu-ludii g
a beautiful water-color frontispiece of the
battleship Maine, recently destroyed in Havana harbor.   Another timely paper is one on
"The National Congress of Mothers," the most
important of the so called "women's movements," and which is to hold its second annual gathering next month.   It also is well il
lustrated.   The article on Andrew Jackson
this month is by Francis Worcester Doughty,
ami treats of the "Medallic History" of Old
Hickory, describing the medals, coins and
store-cards that were struck to commemorate
some important acts of the General and President.   The illustrations include reproductions
of these medals and coins and some unfamiliar portraits.   There is an interesting description of the Reformed Church in America,
by David James Burrell, D. D., the sixth in
the series on the religious denominations in
this country; Bacon's Rebellion, which markt
the beginning of liberty in Virginia, forr.is the
subject of a graphic pa pur by Dr. Lewis K.
Harley ; Galveston, the "Island Cit> " of Texas, comes in lor an exhaustive and profusely
illustrated article by Charles Thomas Logan;
and the United Slates Consul at Martinique
describes the city of St. Pierre.    There are
several very clever short stories, a department for boys and girls, and other features.
Frank Leslie's Publishing House, X.  )'.
The Phrenological Journal and Science
of Health for May begins with a character
sketch of Dr. Charles A. Berry, of England.
He is the pastor of one of the largest Congregational chinches in England.   Phrenotypes
No. 23, by H. S. Drayton, M. D.     This has a
portrait of M. Diamandi as an illustration of
numbers.   "He was asked, how many seconds
there are in eighty-seven centuries, taking
leap years into account.   He answers almost
at once and without writing a single figure."
Phrenology and its Utility by Thomas Timson.   What is Quality by Jules Buchel; A
Short Lesson on Hope by K. Terry.   In the
Public Eye, by J. A. Fowler.   The portraits of
Mrs. C. S. Robinson and Mrs. Mary Wood-Allen, M. D. accompany this article.   The Amateur Phrenological Club, by Elsie C. Smith;
The Healing Art, by Susanna W. Dodds, M. I).
Child Culture, by Uncle Joseph.   This is beautifully illustrated; Honest Jimmie, etc. etc.
Fowler & Wells Co. 27 East 21st St. New York.
The authorship of the much-discussed "Inner Experiences of aCabinet Member's Wife,"
printed in The Ladies' Home Journal, will be
revealed in the June issue of that magazine,
when the name of Anna Farquhar will appear
as the author.   It is surmised that the domestic experiences described in these letters were
those of Mrs. W. 1.1. II. Miller, wife of the Attorney-General in President Harrison's Cabinet,since Miss Farquhar is known to be a
personal frien.l of the Miller family, and to
have spent considerable time with them in
Washington during their official resilience
there.    The author of thes    letters was born
and raised in Indianapolis, in neighborly relations with the Harrison an 1 Miller families,
but foi ten years past she has lived a studious
professional life in Ni;w York, London an I
lioston.    She is now co'.iii"ct''d with the editorial staff of The !U,sU>n 'I'mus: >-ipt.    In addition
to her "Cabinet Mcinuer s Wife" letters she
! as published one novel"A Singer's Hrait"
and another one is about to be issued.    She
is a young woman, exceedingly clever, and
only her closest frieu Is have known her connection with the Washington letters which
have attracted such wi le attention.
k Visit to the
EMkmm
of EAST CANTERBURY, N. H.
LLOYD II. CIIAXni.KK. U. S. 
Liberally Illustrated with luilf tone
pictures of persons and places.
The Village of EAST CANTERBURY
is situated in one of the loveliest spots of
New Hampshire, and is high enough to
overlook the surrounding country.
Price,   15 cts.
Address    H. C. Blinn,
East Canterbury, N. H.
Sketches of Shakers and Shakeiusm. A synopsis of the United Society of Believeks in Christ's Second
Appearing. Illustrated. By Giles
B. A very.    Price 15 cts.
<pb n="" id="p20"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
Royal makes the food pure,
wholesome and delicious.
50   YEARS'
EXPERIENCE
f
Trade Marks
Designs
Copyrights &c.
Anyone sending a sketch and description may
quickly ascertain our opinion free whether an
invention is probably patentable. Communications strictly confidential. Handbook on Patents
sent free. Oldest agency for securing patents.
Patents taken through Munn & Co. receive
special notice, without charge, in the
Scientific flmerieam
A handsomely illustrated weekly. largest circulation of any scientific journal. Terms, $3 a
year; four months, $1.   Sold by all newsdealers.
MUNN Co.361Broadwa>' New York
Branch Office, 625 F St., Washington, D. C.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure
HOW TO MAKE MONEY!
If you are out of employment and want
a position paying you from $50 to $ 100
monthly clear above expenses by working
regularly, or, if you want to increase your
present income from $200 to $500 yearly,
by working at odd times write the GLOBE
CO. 723 Chestnut St. Phila., Pa. stating
age, whether married or single, last or
present employment, and you can learn
how to make more money easier and
faster than you ever made before in your
life.
AUTHORISED   RULES
OF
THE   SHAKER   COMMUNITY,
The religious basis of the Okdee must
be a foundation resting on the principle of
righteousness, which principle is God.
This should rule the life of the individual for the protection of his own soul, for
the peace of the family and as an evidence
of his upright standing before the world.
Pric, 10 cts.
SHAKER HAMAMELIS
(WITCHHAZEL,)
.A. remedy fox Cuts, Burns, Scalds,
Headache Sore Throat and all
oases of external inflammation
Taken internally for Bowel
Complaint, Bleeding of the
Lungs or Bowels, and for
all aches and pains.
For use externally, bathe the parts and
lay on a cloth wet with the Extract,    Internally, take one half teaspoonful three
times a day.    Use hot or cold.
Ask your druggist for it or send your
order to Abthtjk Bruce.
East Canterbury, N. H.
ROYAL BAKING POWDER CO., NEW YORK.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>