<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm1712" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">23</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">17</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">12</biblScope><date value="18871201" TEIform="date">December 1887</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">265-288</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="17" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="12" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!-- 
<pb id="p1"/>
DECEMBER.
MANIFESTO.
Published by the United Societies,
"Every plant which my heavenly Father hath not planted shall be rooted
up."- -Matt, xv., 13.
Canterbury, N. H.
1887.
THE
<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE MANIFESTO.

NEW HOME SEWING MACHINE - -GE,MASS.
Chicago -30 UNiON SQUARE.NX-   DALLAS,
1                   ATLANTA  GA               TEX
ST LOUSSjMO.
'SAWF~AM''ICCO.C.ALj
The Testimony of Christ's Second Appeaking, exemplified by the principles and
practice of the true Church of Christ.
History of the progressive work of God,
extending from the creation of man to the
"Harvest," comprising the Four Dispensations now consummating in the Millennial
Church.          pp 650         Pricef 1.50
Address, Manifesto, Shaker Village, N. H.
THE  ALTRUIST
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property,
united labor, Community homes, and equal
rights to all. It is published by the Mutual
Aid Community, whose members all live and
work together, and hold all their property in
common, all the men and women having
equal rights in electing officers and deciding
all business affairs by their majority vote.
50 cents a year; specimen copy free. Address A. Longley, Editor, 213 N. 8th St.,
St. Louis, Mo.
Any person who wants paying work as local or traveling agent for warranted nursery
stock should apply at once to James E.
Whitney, Nurseryman, Rochester, N. Y.
No experience is necessary, and complete
outfit is furnished free. Steady work the
year round and all stock warranted to be in
good condition.
Dobbin's Electric Soap.
THE BEST FAMILY SOAP
- - - - - - -IN THE WORLD.- - - - - -It is Strictly Pure, Duifira in duality.
rflHE  original formula   for which we paid $50,000
11 twenty years ago has never been modified or
I    changed in the slightest. This soap is idenI    tical   in    quality   to-day    with   that
I   niade twenty years ag'o
A        IT contains  nothing' that can  injure
I the finest fabric.   It brightens "colors
and bleaches whites.
IT washes flannels   ..nd blankets as no other
soap in the world does- -without shrinking- -
leaving them soft and white and like new.
HEAD THIS  TWICE.
THERE is a great saving- of time, of labor,
of fuel, and of the fabric, where Dobbins' Electric Soap is used according*to directions.
OSTE trial   will demonstrate its great merit.
It will pay you to make that trial.
^   IKE  all Hest tiling's, it is extensively imiJLA tated and counterfeited.
Beware of Imitations.
INSIST upon Dot- -l- -in- -'   Electric.   Don't take
i Magnetic,   Electro-Magic, Philadelphia Electric,
or any other fraud, simply because it is cheap. They
will ruin clothes, and are dear at any price.   Ask for
- - - - - -HOBBIWS'  ELECTRIC- - - - -and take no other. Nearly every grocer from Maine
to Mexico keeps it in stock. If yours hasn't it, he
will order from his nearest wholesale grocer.
READ carefully the inside wrapper around each
bar, and be careful to follow directions
on each outside wrapper.   You cannot afford to
wait longer before  trying lor yourself this old, reliable, and truly wonderful
Dobbins' X Electric X Soap.
The Divine Afflatus :    A force in History.                                Price   10 cts.
Address, Manifesto, Shaker Village, N. H.-
<pb n="" id="p"/>
Vol. XVIII.
DECEMBER,  1887.
No.  12. --><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gospel testimony of Mother Ann Lee and the elders, William Lee and James Whittaker no. 21" TEIform="index"/> The Gospel Testimony of Mother Ann Lee and the Elders, William Lee and James Whittaker.
                            No. 21.</head><p TEIform="p"> Published expressly for the several Communities of Believers in 1816. Re-written by Henry C.
                            Blinn. The Elders return to Harvard. On the 30th of April 1783, Mother Ann and the Elders
                            left Ashfield, and passing through Petersham, tarried there one night. The next day they
                            reached Harvard. They visited the Believers in that vicinity, and in the neighboring towns.
                            Destined as they were to suffer persecution, they were soon called to prepare for a new and
                            trying scene. Mother Ann was warned, in vision, several days before the event, which took
                            place on the first of June. The Elders, at this time, were at the house of Jeremiah Willard.
                            Elder James Whittaker made the remark, "There will be a great persecution, for I have seen
                            the figure of a persecuting man." The circumstances which gave rise to this affliction were
                            as follows ;- -Sarah Turner had married a deaf man by the name of Jude Carter. Sarah having
                            gained a love for the Believers, was anxious to live their manber of life and her husband
                            appeared to be equally interested. Jude had a fancy for silver buckles on his shoes and also
                            for silver knee buckles, but Sarah urged him to sell them and to buy something that would be
                            of more use in the family. He replied, by signs, that other people wore silver buckles and
                            it could be no harm for him to wear them. The next day they went to the city of Boston,
                            where he sold his buckles. Oti their return she prevailed on him to have his hair cut, he
                            consented to have it cut, as she directed, which was accordingly done. Jude seemed quite
                            well pleased with his new friends, for a few hours, but suddenly becoming offended, he left
                            the place without even giving his wife the knowledge of his departure. So soon as she
                            learned what he had done, she returned to her home, accompanied by some of the Brethren and
                            Sisters. In passing through the village of Harvard, Jude made a grevious complaint, by
                            signs, that the Shakers had robbed him of his silver buckles, cut off his hair and taken
                            away his wife. This furnished sufficient foundation for those who were watching for an
                            occasion to persecute the Believers without<pb n="266" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 266 THE MANIFESTO.
                            inquiring into the true state of the case. Secret measures were taken to raise a mob, of
                            which the Shakers had no knowledge till the people appeared in mob array at Elijah Wilds, in
                            Shirley, on Sabbath evening, June 1, 1783. They guarded every door a^d window, and no person
                            was permitted to go in or out. The Believers were engaged in religious service, but retired
                            from the room, ho soon as they learned of the presence of the mob. The leaders of this
                            lawless company were Phineas Farnsworth, James Pollard. Elisha Folium and Asa Houghton. With
                            them were a company of base characters from the towns of Harvard, Roxbury and Bolton. Like
                            the men of Sodom they attempted to enter the house by pressing hard against the door. This,
                            the Brethren on the inside prevented. David Meacham was in an adjoining building. Seeing the
                            mob he attempted to force his way through the crowd and enter the main dwelling but was
                            unable, lie then attempted to reason with the mob on the impropriety and unlawfulness of
                            such proceedings, and inquired the cause of their coming in such a manner. He urge I, in his
                            remarks, the testimony of truth, the liberty of conscience and the duty of Christians. A
                            large number of persons gathered around him and gave good attention to what was said, which
                            soon caused a disunion among themselves. The leaders nf the mob on seeing the effect of
                            David's lecture, took hold of him with violence and thrust him into the house with this
                            remark.- -"You shall not preach any more to the people." Although the mob had ordered that
                            no one should leave the house, they permitted one of the Believers to return to her home to
                            take charge of her infant. After attending to this duty, and opportunity offering, she sent
                            word to the officers of the town, of the lawless mob that was gathered at the house of
                            Elijah Wilds in Shirley. The mob continued at the place all night, with much railing and
                            unbecoming behavior; but committed no personal injury till the next morning. At an early
                            hour the leaders demanded that Mother Ann and the Elders should come out. This they refused
                            to do, but consented that four persons might come in. Four accordingly entered the house.
                            They were soon invited to breakfast which invitation they quite readily accepted. Elijah
                            Wilds, by advice of Mother Av::,, carried brea 1 and cheese to the mob, and many of them
                            very readily accepted it. Elder James Whittaker who was anxious to appeal to their better
                            feelings said, "I must go and speak the word of the Lord to this large company of meu." He
                            went from the house, accompanied by some of the Brethren aud spoke to them as follows ; "Why
                            have you come here in such numbers? What have we done? Have we hurt or injured your persons
                            or property? If we have, make us sensible of it aud we will make you due satisfaction."' At
                            these words the mob broke into a rage and seized Elder James by the collar. The Brethren
                            instantly stepped forth to rescue him from their merciless hands. In the struggle he cried
                            out,- - "Father, Lord of heaven and earth, forgive them, O forgive them for they know not
                            what they do." Thomas Buckmour the Grand Jury-<pb n="267" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 267 man
                            of the town aud James Parker a Justice of peace arrived at this time and immediately
                            commanded the mob to desist from troubling the Shakers. For a very brief time only the word
                            from the officers quieted ihis lawless company. The mob still continued to increase and it
                            was not till after several hours of contest with the Believers and the peace officers, that
                            the leaders of the crowd consented to give up their unlawful demands, upon the following
                            conditions. "Tf the two Elders, William Lee and James Whittaker will go with us to Harvard,
                            we will leave your Mother Ann, and withdraw in a peaceable manner. "We promise, upon our
                            honor, to treat the Elders with kindness and civility and they shall not be hurt." Upon
                            these conditions the Elders consented to go with them. David Meacham, Calvin Harlovv aud
                            several other Brethren accompanied the Elders. On entering the town of Harvard, the mob
                            manifested a renewed degree of temper and commanded that all the Shakers, except the two
                            Elders should return to Shirley. David Meacham aud Calvin Harlow did not choose to obey this
                            tyrannical order and refused to return. The mob immediately seized the horses, upon which
                            the Brethren rode, and would not allow them to advance. Calvin and David leaped from their
                            horses, and forced their way through the lawless crowd, and hastened on to meet the Elders,
                            who had called at the house of Jeremiah Willard. A faint hope had occupied the minds of the
                            Believers, thxt in the house of an honorable and respected citizen they would be
                            comparatively safe from all harm. In this, however, they were again, to be sadly
                            disappointed. Regardless of the order, by the owner of the residence, not to enter his
                            house, and irrespective of the laws of civil society the mob broke into the house and
                            inhumanly dragged Jeremiah from it, by his feet. They then went through the building as only
                            infuriated beings could go, aud seized the Elders, forced them violently into the street,
                            and to the place where the main body of the mob were stationed. Plans were now laid for the
                            execution of their premeditated designs, and the speaker announced ;- -"James Whittaker and
                            William Lee shall be tied to a tree, and be whipped !" David Meacham and Calvin Harlow were
                            then seized and thrown upon the ground and held fast by ruffianly hands till the barbarous
                            deed was accomplished. Elder James was divested of his clothing, to his waist, and tied to a
                            tree, when Isaac Whitney, with sticks, that had been cut for this special purpose, began the
                            cruel work of scourging an innocent and God fearing man. As the number of strokes had not
                            been limited, the fearful, lacerating work continued till the flesh was bruised to a jelly,
                            and his back a gore of blood. Satisfied with their own savagery, they untied the good Elder,
                            and allowed him to go. Still furious in their evil work, they seized Elder William Lee
                            intending to have him subjected to the same form of cruel treatment. Elder William asked the
                            privilege to receive, what his persecutors chose to inflict, while on his knees, and the
                            whippers began as in the former case. Elder James, already so cruelly beaten, placed himself
                            so as to shield<pb n="268" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 268 THE MANIFESTO. Elder William from the strokes.
                            Several others followed this genuine Christian example, and among the number was a woman of
                            God, Bethiah Willard. At this display of self-sacrifice, the rage of the persecutors
                            increased and the Believers were inhumanly beaten without regard to age or sex. Bethiah
                            carried the wounds inflicted at that time on her head and face till the day of her death.
                            Evidently frightened at their own abusive treatment, of these innocent people, the mob began
                            to disperse and soon left the suffering objects of their cruelty, to take care of
                            themselves. After these persecuting Christians had left the Believers, Elder James broke
                            forth in the ministration of a new song, and all kneeled in prayer. The company then went to
                            the residence of Jeremiah Willard, and received the best of (are. The Elders and the two
                            Brethren who came from Shirley soon took their horses, and returned to report to other dear
                            friends, the severe persecution through which they had passed. Elder James iu speaking to
                            the Brethren and Sisters, said, ki 1 have been abused ; and it is not for any wrong that I
                            have done to them. It is for the gospel's sake. I have nothing against them for what they
                            have done to me. They were ignorant and knew not what manner of spirit governed them." All
                            the Believers then kneeled in prayer to God, that he would forgive their bloody persecutors,
                            - -' Father forgive them for they know not what they do." "This" taid Mother Ann, "is the
                            life of the gospel, and we should be thankful that we are counted worthy to suffer
                            persecution for Christ's sake." It was subsequently learned that no one in the mob was a
                            resident of the town of Shirley. Many of the citizens were displeased with the transactions.
                        </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life in Christ" TEIform="index"/> LIFE IN CHRIST.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName"/> ABRAHAM PERKINS.</byline><p TEIform="p"> What is to be done to inherit eternal life? What is to be done to be saved? This is a
                            problem of the greatest importance, commanding man's highest interest and his best and
                            fullest powers to solve. The question is simple in its nature, and its solution easily
                            found, setting aside self, the ruling passion of the heart. Honest living is the answer
                            which embraces all the duties of life, physical, moral and spiritual. As the sparks fly
                            upwards, so is man prone to evil. Whoever knows his own heart, knows it to be selfish ;
                            knows that his inclinations tend largely to the indulgence of the animal part of his
                            creation ; knows that his proclivities lead to corruption. Consequently, he can but. realize
                            that Self is the judgment seat for consultation and representation, and the tribunal for
                            decision, and therefore the God of this world, whose mischiefs are cropping out in a
                            multitude of ways. Our manners, our habits, our conver sation and acts are witnesses of our
                            life and character, and demonstrate our positive leauiug, whether towards that which
                            ennobles and elevates, or to that which is low, degrading and groveling. To the young who
                            are emerging from childhood to manhood, the period of their existence iu which habits of
                            life are generally formed and character almost universally established, allow me to say,-
                            -if you would respect yourselves and command the respect and confidence of others, if you
                            would honor yourselves and truly honor society, you must live and be governed by principle ;
                            thus, in your life, you will give the evidence<pb n="269" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 269 of
                            honesty of purpose. A life governed by the law of Moses leads directly to Christian
                            conditions, spiritual life and resurrection. That law is a schoolmaster to briug us to
                            Christ. The true Israelite in his life, unmistakably typifies Christian character and life;
                            and the ordinances and principles of that law show precisely what is to be practiced in the
                            resurrection order. Witness the order of the priesthood and confessional of the Mosaic
                            dispensation. The priests ministered at the altar and were the expounders and teachers of
                            the law. They were the mediators between the people and Almighty God. They siood before them
                            as God, as the Scriptures declare, and to them made their confessions as unto God, and also
                            how confession was to be made ; as in the case of Achan, when Joshua bid him "Give glory
                            unto the Lord God of Israel, and make confession unto him, and tell me (Joshua) what thou
                            hast done ; hide it not from me." Josh, vii., 19. The antitype, Christ Jesus, who
                            commissioned and gave power to the Apostles to loose and bind, that is, to remit or retain,
                            justify or condemn, authorized this same power to be transmitted to their successors in that
                            order. "Many came and confessed and showed their deeds" before a human witness in the gospel
                            dispensation just as Achan did under the law. We learu the order of instruction in the law
                            of Christ in the case of Cornelius, of Cesarea. Acts x., 5, 6 ; also Romans x., 10. " W^ith
                            the mouth confession is made unto salvation." The testimony of John the Baptist, was
                            repentance unto the remission of sin by confession ; and Jesus taught repentance and belief
                            in his gospel. Mark, i., 15. Hence if the church of Christ is the light of the world, if
                            there we are to find our union and fellowship with saints, and our relation to God, let us
                            give place to reason and learu the lessons of redemption from 1he teachiugs of Jesus in and
                            through the order of his appointment. He who hath a heart to feel, ears to hear, eyes to see
                            and conviction that commands obedience, let him manifest the principles of truth and
                            honesty, come out from the world and follow Christ, supporting as he did the honest, virgin
                            character. Enfield, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Trust in God and do the right" TEIform="index"/>TRUST IN GOD AND DO THE RIGHT
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Courage, brother! do not stumble, Though thy path
                                    is dark as night, There's a star to guide the humble : Trust in God and do the
                                    right. Let the road be long and dreary, And its ending out of sight, Foot it
                                    bravely, strong or weary : Trust in God and do the right. Perish policy and cunning,
                                    Perish all that fears the light Whether losing, whether winning : Trust in God and
                                    do the right. Trust no forms of guilty passion, Fiends that look like angels bright,
                                    Trust no custom, school or fashion : Trust in God and do the right. Some will hate
                                    thee, some will love thee, Some will natter, some will slight; Cease from man and
                                    look above thee : Trust in God and do the right. Simple rule and safest guiding,
                                    Inward peace and inward light, Star upon our path abiding : Trust in God and do the
                                    right. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="The Catholic" TEIform="index"/>The Catholic.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I am convinced that genuineness of deportment and manner..." TEIform="index"/>
                            I am convinced that genuineness of deportment and manner...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> I am convinced that genuineness of deportment and manner springs from inward purity of
                            character.- -</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Baker, A. I." TEIform="persName"/>A. I. Baker.</byline></div2><pb n="270" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Treatise on theology no. 3" TEIform="index"/> A TREATISE ON THEOLOGY. No. 3.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS.</byline><p TEIform="p"> 50. "The angels (of the fourth heaven) are the reapers," who are to go forth at the "end of
                            the world." One of them visited Jesus. But in the second appearing, there would be a general
                            influx of those holy reaping angels, to cut men from the earth, and to administer the
                            resurrection power. "But unto the angals (of the first, second and third heavens) hath he
                            not put in subjection the world whereof we speak"- -the Christ world? On the contrary, the
                            children of the resurrection would "judge angels," that is, the generative angels, by
                            preaching to them the things pertaining to the Gospel; which things even "the angels desire
                            to look iuto." 51. Jesus is made so much "better than the angels," that they came at his
                            birth and "worshiped" him. These could not have been of the same order of angels as those
                            who came and ministered unto him. It appears to me that they t&gt;re the angels who will
                            minister the work of judgment and conviction in the coming religious revivals ; and
                            therefore there will then be something more radical- -a testimony against all "fleshly
                            lusts, which war against the soul." 52. Jesus alluded to these pure angels, when he said : "
                            Hereafter ye shall see the angels of God ascending and descending upon the Son of Man"- -
                            upon those who should "stand with the Lamb on Mount Zion," in virgin purity. 53. Of John the
                            Baptist, Jesus said : "If ye will receive it, this is Elias that was to come." Elias lived
                            under the second dispensation ; but, as a prophet, he was inspired by angels from the third
                            heaven ; the same ministered unto John. 54. Ann, as had been Jesus, was ministered to by
                            angels from the fourth Leaven ; being their first and second appearing upon earth. 55. Do
                            any of us believe that John the Baptist was Elias? Not at all. Now, when we put the man
                            Jesus for the spirit of Christ, who inspired him, and yet deny that John was really either
                            Elias, or the spirit who inspired him, notwithstanding the plainest declaration of Jesus
                            himself that John was Elias, do we not "strain at the gnat and swallow the camel" at one
                            gulp ? 56. When Peter says of Jesus, "Thou art the Christ," it is by some deemed conclusive
                            that the man Jesus is the very Christ. But when this same Christ tells Peter that he will
                            build his church upon him, we are coolly informed that Jesus did not mean the man Peter, but
                            that spirit which inspired him ; as in the instance where he calls Peter, Satan ; he did not
                            mean that for Peter, but for the evil spirit. 57. But, good friends, I think that if Peter
                            did imagine that Jesus was the primitive Christ, he was as much mistaken as were those who
                            thought John was Elias ; or that Peter was to be (as the Roman Catholic church holds) the
                            foundation of the Christian church. 58. I have no objection to the Apostles, and all those
                            of past dispensations, calling Jesus the Christ, for so he was to them. But I deny that they
                            are any more the rightful teachers and instructors of the second Christian church, than were
                            the disciples of Moses their rightful teachers and instructors. 59. 1 earnestly contend for
                            the revelation and gift of our own church and dispensation, as being more worthy of our
                            confidence than are all the Bibles and books in existence.<pb n="271" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> Yea, more
                            than that, I claim that the truths of the present revelation are far better sustained by
                            Scripture records, than are any errors which we may have imbibed. 60. Antichristian
                            enslavement and subordinatiou to the ''letter," kills and creates discrepancies aud
                            contrariety of sentiment on doctrinal matters. 61 j It cannot be expected that, as a people,
                            we have had sufficient time to travel entirely away from Bibles and creeds aud commentaries,
                            and the opposite extreme, infidelism. But I believe that, ere long, another degree of the
                            Gospel will open ; and that a fire will be kindled in Zion and a furnace in Jerusalem, that
                            will consume error, and cause the watchmen to "see eye to eye." 62. The debris of the past
                            degree obstructs and prevents new openings of Gospel truth, which ministering spirits are
                            laden with. They are waiting for au entrance into the hearts of the children of the Most
                            High. What can they do without, until those within are imbued with the truths they are
                            commissioned to dispense? 63. But, to return from this dreaming, it surprises me to see
                            writings that were addressed to the poor Gentiles, who had to be fed with milk, because they
                            could not bear meat (the truth,) quoted as infallible authority upou doctrinal matters
                            pertaining to the Millennial church. 64. The foundation of anti-Christ is the letter- -the
                            record. Jesus Christ was the true church. The apostles were the foundation of the Jewish
                            Christian church; Peter, of the Gentile Christian church; Constantine, of the Roman Catholic
                            church; Luther and Calvin, of the Protestant churches. Kach of them one degree below the
                            other ; till we come down to the largely adulterated Christianity of the Chinese rebels. 65.
                            The foundation of the Christian church, in Jesus, and also in Ann, was Christ revealed in
                            them ; a living revelation, that opened an entrance, and gave access to the resurrection
                            heaven, from whence the reaping angels descend and ascend continually upon its true members.
                            66. The Apostle Paul, writing to the Eptiesians, speaks to them on this wise : "Ye have
                            heard of the dispensation of the grace of God, which is given me to you- -ward; how that, by
                            revelation (not by the Scriptures) he made known unto me the mystery * * which in other ages
                            was not made known umo the sons of men, as it is now revealed unto his holy Apostles and
                            Prophets by his spirit." 67. Paul further says: "We speak the wisdom of God in a mystery,
                            even the hidden wisdom which God ordained before the Avorld, unto our glory." Again: "Eye
                            hath not" (hitherto) "seen, nor ear heard, neither have entered into the heart of man, the
                            things which God hath prepared for them that love him. But God hath revealed them unto us by
                            his spirit; for the spirit searcheth all things, yea, even the deep things of God." Mi.
                            Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="As the sun gives both shine and shower..." TEIform="index"/>
                            As the sun gives both shine and shower...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> As the sun gives both shine and shower, so should the true love of our friends give us the
                            needful refreshments of reproof, as well as the smile of approbation.- -</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Galver, A. J." TEIform="persName"/>A. J. Galver.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mildness is an ornament to friendship" TEIform="index"/>Mildness is an ornament to friendship
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Mildness is an ornament to friendship.</p></div2><pb n="272" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beloved elder Henry, I copy the following..." TEIform="index"/>Beloved elder Henry, I copy the following...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Editor of Manifesto. Beloved Elder Henry ;- -I copy the following from letter of a
                            correspondent, in Sacramento, Cal., I. H. Burbank. Dear Cousin ;- -The reading matter you
                            have sent me has been very interesting to me and also to our cousin, Clara B. who recently
                            visited me from Oakland, Cal. She enjoyed much satisfaction in reading the Manifestos, as
                            she never before could learn much about your people, and has always desired to. I have still
                            all the numbers you have sent me and of late they have given a better insight of the gospel
                            doctrines of your people, or Community, than formerly, i think. And again, C. C. Lerned, of
                            Hopkinton, N. H. writes me thus, My Dear Friend ;- -In answer to your inquiry regarding
                            those Monthly magazines I would say, that we take great pleasure in reading their pages,
                            also in mailing them to friends south and west, many of these persons being interested in
                            the origin and progress of your religious organizations. At any time convenient, we will be
                            pleased to receive The Manifesto. And I would add my own testimony of approval of matter and
                            manner of arrangement in the pages of The Manifesto. The subjects, in general, being treated
                            in a clear and comprehensive style so that any ordinary mind can readily read and understand
                            their import. The serial, of The Gospel Testimony of Mother Ann Lee and the Elders, William
                            Lee and James Whittaker, is opportune in its publication, and will no doubt lead to a
                            clearer understanding of the object and aims of our religious institutions, from the
                            commencement, than could otherwise be obtained. The Trumpet of Truth gives no uncertain
                            sound, that reverberates through the columns of The Manifesto. And may it continue to sound
                            till it thrill the soul of humanity to a realization of the necessity of more fully
                            observing, God given physical laws, and the unfolding of psychological powers, to the
                            salvation of body and soul from sin, and the noisome pestilence that stalks through the
                            universe unimpeded.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hastings, Harriet" TEIform="persName"/> Harriet Hastings.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Advice to the young no. 2" TEIform="index"/> ADVICE TO THE YOUNG. No. 2.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Shepard, Harriet" TEIform="persName"/> HARRIET SHEPARD. </byline><p TEIform="p">Speaking of a young friend, the philanthropic Howard said, uShe taught me to forget myself
                            and live for my neighbor." Her frequent visits to the needy were benevolent, but the result
                            was illimitable and perpetual. When Henry Martin was entreated by all the eagerness and
                            tenderness of a loving sister to stay with her, he answered : " Sister, the Savior you
                            taught me to love has a work for me among the heathen, and I shall go to it, trusting your
                            prayers and his love will sustain me." Such exhortations and patterns are swelling fountains
                            whence flow many fruitful streams whose wholesome excitement is realized throughout
                            Christendom. Such plants of righteousness, purity and peace will bloom both in this life and
                            in the world to come. While we are reflecting on the weighty subject of consecration, so
                            sacred to the heart and recollection, we would that a feeling of benevolence worthy of the
                            day in which we live, and a kind regard for the unfortunate take possession of your mind and
                            rule your actions. To be wavering between good intentions and their non-performance is the
                                calam-<pb n="273" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> ity of some. To be truly serviceable, persistent and
                            continued effort must impress your every career. Let thy fixed aim and desire be to do right
                            and compel wrong to yield thereunto. " Then, what though thy smiles fade and tears come in
                            their stead, and the world frown darkly on thee, if so there be no clouds betweeu thee and
                            thy God?" "It is important that the expression of the face be sweet and cheerful; but it
                            cannot be unless you are kind, contented and loving. Remember, if you squander the golden
                            hours of youth, without studying to become useful, good and pure, you will not, in after
                            years, be very likely to reform. The clothes you wear today cover a fading form which cannot
                            live always as the soul does. Live truly, and in living weave a rich and beautiful garment
                            for your soul, which shall never grow old, but brighten while ages come and go." North
                            Union, Ohio. </p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Esteemed friend, Louis Basting: Gladly would I write to you..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Esteemed friend, Louis Basting: Gladly would I write to you...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Austria, Vienna, June 1887" TEIform="index"/> Vienna, Austria, June, 1887.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Esteemed Friend, Louis Basting :- - Gladly would I write to you in the English language, but
                            you must still have some patience. I understand your writing quite well, and I beg you to
                            continue to address me in English; by that means 1 shall learn in two respects and my
                            gratitude shall be two-fold. I sincerely thank you for your kind words ; they have given me
                            much joy. Gladly do I discern from them that my being, feelings and thoughts are not
                            incomprehensible to you. And since you understand me, I indulge the hope that when I arrive
                            at your honored community and feel the elevating influences of the brotherhood and
                            sisterhood, what is imperfect in me will become perfect, and I shall experience the
                            happiness of being one with you and yours in heart and mind. Be assured that I am possessed
                            of a deep earnestness for the cause and that I consider it my "life's labor" to devote my
                            feelings and emotions to the practical work it demands. When I come to you I expect to find
                            friends and counselors to assist me in that endeavor. You are quite right when you say that
                            saintship may be acquired in the Catholic church, but that the masses are far removed from
                            it and are likely to remain so. This deplorable state is partly caused by the spirit and
                            example of the teachers, partly by the institutions of human society, which appear to be
                            hostile to all unselfish, spiritual aspirations. The leaders at Rome are so much engaged in
                            politics and the asserti; n of claims to temporal power, that the practical realization of
                            the doctrine and life of Christ are overlooked, and their words and formal ceremonies remain
                            without effect. The office and calling of our priests is not a God-given profession, but an
                            acquired, learned trade. No wonder that there is so little of inspiration, love and grace,
                            and that both priests and people are lacking the elements of the truly moral and Christian
                            life. Oh, all that I feel with you and am deeply pained that it is so. Could I but haVe
                            found one place or order among all the many so-called Christians, where the example of the
                            Savior really lives, I should have acknowledged it with joy, sought it out and imitated it.
                            But it does not exist among these Christians. But now blooms the only home of genuine,
                            resurrected, ancient Christian-<pb n="274" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/>ity in far-away America, among the
                            Shakers ! But I believe that it will again possess the heart of the world, for life is ever
                            and ever breaking away from the old, decaying world and pushing into a new land, the cradle
                            of future histories. There dwell the Shakers in a new valley of the rejuvenated, sacred
                            Jordan river, overshadowed by the new Mount Lebanon ; there, like John, the fore-runner of
                            our Lord and Savior, to teach, baptize and cleanse- -a living example to future generations.
                            It is an exalted vocation to fulfil; it is everyone's duty who is seeking to know and follow
                            Christ, to unite with them and be a pillar and support to sustain that beautiful communion
                            that it may continue from age to age above the falling nations and peoples, victoriously,
                            unchangeably faithful to preserve the kingdom of God on earth for those who are hungering
                            and thirsting after righteousness. 0 blessed communion of souls ! Why should not the
                            blessing of God, and peace and happiness, be in the hearts of those whose life-work is to do
                            deeds of love to each other? Do not blame me, dear friend, if I give way to my feelings, but
                            I believe to be upon the right road even if I cannot find the right word. 1 fully
                            acknowledge the obligation of celibacy, and of obedience and subjection to the counsel of
                            Elders ; a Christian community cannot exist without these fundamental principles. I see that
                            and I admire the discernment of those wise men, and especially of that enlightened woman,
                            who were the founders of that system. Is not the very first principle of the genuine,
                            Christian doctrine found in the words of the Redeemer; "If thou wilt be perfect, go and sell
                            that thou hast and give to the poor, and thou shalt have treasure in heaven, and come and
                            follow me." Therefore is voluntary poverty, humility and cross-bearing included in the
                            invitation of Christ. That he who lays down his own sensual life and denies himself of all
                            worldly lusts, for Christ's sake, seeking for better things, will no longer desire to return
                            to the worldly life and run anew the road of suffering, and can in this world already bring
                            his soul to God without division or partition is certain ; and the result of all is chastity
                            and unselfishness in celibacy. Therefore let my life prove what my heart knows and feels. To
                            do that work requires strength, charity, patience and above all, the grace of God. I am
                            sincerely yours, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="S., J." TEIform="persName"/>J. S. </byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="J. S. Dear friend and brother; How glad I was to receive..." TEIform="index"/>
                            J. S. Dear friend and brother; How glad I was to receive...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon, August 1887" TEIform="index"/> Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., Aug. 1887.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> J. S. Dear Friend and Brother;- - How glad I was to receive your lette", I cannot express.
                            Surely, the angels of God must have been with you that you can so clearly comprehend the
                            necessary requirements for living the higlier life, as well as to be able to see the beauty
                            and glory resulting there from. Only one word of caution might be useful, and even that your
                            just conception may have anticipated. But since you compare the mission of Believers to that
                            of John the Baptist, allow me to continue the figure still further. Jesus said, concerning
                            John, ;' What went you out for to see ? A man dressed in rich garments ? He is a prophet and
                            more than a prophet. Among them born of woman none is greater than he,<pb n="275" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/>
                            THE MANIFESTO. 2 To but the least in the kingdom of heaven (who is born of the spirit) is
                            greater than John." John was a child of poverty, whose home was the desert, whose clothing
                            and food were of the rudest and coars-i est kiud ; but he presented great truths. Neither
                            are Believers a people of wealth and opulence, possessing the luxuries and refinements of
                            modern life. They are a plain, simple people, having comfortable homes and thj needful
                            things of life. Nor are they perfect in all respects concerning spiritual and moral things.
                            H'&gt;w can they be? Since, when we come from the world, however good our intentions may
                            be, we have clinging to us habits, customs, modes of thought, the effects of wrong
                            education, and many other things that are incompatible with the higher life, but that cannot
                            be dropped and overcome at once. Hence the Savior likened the kingdom of heaven on earth to
                            the growing corn, requiring time and the concurrence of proper conditions before maturity is
                            re'ached. I hope I am making myself understood. While you are building houses in the great
                            city of Vienna we are endeavoring to raise a glorious temple under the guidance of the
                            Master Architect who will ''lay judgmeut to the line and righteousness to the plummet." The
                            foundations are laid broad and deep and strong enough to withstand the shock of ages and the
                            corroding tooth of time. But the superstructure is not finished ; more laborers are needed.
                            Accept the love and best wishes of Your friend and brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Basting, Louis" TEIform="persName"/> Louis Basting.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Duty is ours, results, God's" TEIform="index"/>Duty is ours, results, God's
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Duty is ours, results, God's.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our enemy" TEIform="index"/> OUR ENEMY.</head><p TEIform="p"> Not long since I was looking at a little book containing some of the sayings of a good old
                            man, who is called a saint by the church of which he was a bright and shining light, and
                            amorm other good words which I read there were those : " there is no worse enemy nor one
                            more troublesome to the soul than thou art thyself, if thou be not in harmony with the
                            spirit." Can it be denied but what the good old man wrote an indisputable truth when he
                            penned those words? What worse enemy can any human being have than one's self if not in
                            harmony with the spirit of good, of love, of purity, of the Christ spirit which embodies all
                            that there is of good? What is it that makes the wretchedness, the sorrow, the sin of this
                            life but that we are not in harmony with this spirit which is "first pure, then peaceable,"
                            and which gives all good to those who cease to repel it and become harmonious with it. If a
                            man or a woman desires or hopes to be a conqueror of that enemy how is the victory to be
                            obtained? Is it not by ''turning the sword within," and slaying the worldly, carnal nature
                            which is always watchful, always alert, never resting, never sleeping, but always ready to
                            use any means to acheive a triumph over the better part the diviner portion of our nature?
                            We must "turn the battle to the gate," we must be always on guard with our equipments ready,
                            our weapons of spiritual warfare in good order and thus be realy to defeat and- crush the
                            foe who is striving to overcome us. We must as the good apostle said "take unto us the whole
                            armor of God." And how can we best<pb n="276" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 276 THE MANIFESTO. fight this
                            battle and have the assurance that we shall win the victory ? Is it not by being busy in
                            good works, by being ever constant in that best and loudest of all preaching, practice, so
                            that "others seeing our good works may glorify our Father ;" by living upright, loving, pure
                            lives, in short the Christ life ; for that is the way to glorify our Father. Shall we not be
                            in harmony with the spirit if we adopt and live up to that best of all teachings as
                            promulgated by him whom we claim to have been the first and best of Shakers, to "-love the
                            Lord thy God with all thy heart and mind and strength and thy neighbor as thyself." If we do
                            this, if conscientiously and faithfully we strive to be true to duty and to "do unto others
                            as we would that they should do unto us" we surely shall come off conquerors. "There's a
                            battle to be fought Between the soul and sin ;" a battle in which we require all the
                            spiritual strength which we can attain unto ; and let us fight it bravely, trustingly,
                            steadily; never resting, never laying aside our armor till we are sure we have won the
                            victory ; till we can truly say " I have fought the good fight, I have finished my course, I
                            have kept the faitL. We shall assuredly know when that glorious time has come, there will be
                            no uncertainty then, for the "still, small voice" within which we call conscience, but which
                            is the voice of God will surely say to the victor "well done, good and faithful one."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A." TEIform="persName"/> "A." Canterbury, N. H. </byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The reason that we so often misjudge people..." TEIform="index"/>The reason that we so often misjudge people...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> The reason that we so often misjudge people, is that we take our own standpoint to judge
                            from.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Duty" TEIform="index"/> DUTY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whiteley, John" TEIform="persName"/> JOHN WHITELEY. </byline><p TEIform="p">Think oft, of your dutj to God, Though sorely afflicted you be; Not through fear of the rod,
                            Nor yet because danger you see. Think more of your duty to man- - Your brothers and sisters
                            on earth; The surest of ways that you can Prove your claim to heavenly birth. Fail not in
                            your duty to do, Nor yet in your duty to know; Words may be well, prayer \h, too; But add to
                            them works, and keep low. The true "faith which worketh by love," Has no ne^d for fear of
                            the rod; Our duty, below or above, Will lead us in safety to God. Shirley, Mass. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Honorable age" TEIform="index"/> HONORABLE AGE</head><p TEIform="p">"Honorable age is not that which standeth in length of time."- -Apocrypha. The age which
                            stands in honor Flows not through mold of time, Nor measured by the length of years That run
                            in rythmic chime; But wisdom crowns the hoary head, And marks the gifted sage, While an
                            unspotted life on earth, Is honorable age.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. A.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Exhortations of Ignatius bishop of Antioch" TEIform="index"/> EXHORTATIONS OF IGNATIUS,
                            BISHOP OF ANTIOCH.</head><p TEIform="p">[Contributed by Elder G. B. Avery.] Ignatius was martyred at Rome, by being thrown to the
                            wild beasts in the Roman Amphitheatre, in the year 107. While on his way from Smyrna to
                            Rome, to be martyred, he wrote the following Exhortations. These papers were found and first
                            publised by Arch Bishop Usher from two old manuscripts, their first publication was in the
                            year 1647.- - -<pb n="277" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/>Exhortations of Ignatius to the Christian Church at
                            Ephesus. "Neglect not assemblies for thanksgiving and prayer; for, when you assiduously
                            attend on these things the powers of Satan are demolished, and his pernicious kingdom is
                            dissolved by the unamity of your faith.- -Remember me, as Jesus Christ also does you.- -Pray
                            for the Church in Syria, whence I am led, bound, to Rome. Lay aside the old bitter leaven
                            and be transformed into a new leaven, which is of Christ; therefore, being his disciples,
                            let us learn to live according to Christianity. Be studious of that best of all blessings-
                            -unity !" IGNATIFS LETTER TO POLYCAKP''I Exhort thee by the grace with which thou art
                            clothed to apply thyself to the course of duty, and to admonish all, that they may all be
                            saved.- -Do justice to thy station with all diligence, both temporal and spiritual.- -Be
                            studious of that best of all blessings,- -unity. Bear with all, as, also, the Lord with
                            thee.- -Bear with all in charity, as indeed thou dost.- -Find time for prayer, without
                            ceasing. Ask for more understanding than thou hast at present; Watch, and possess a spirit
                            ever attentive.- -Speak to each separately, as Almighty God shall enable thee to do.- -Bear
                            with the diseases of all as a perfect combatant.- -The more labor, the more reward. If thou
                            love only the obedient disciples, thou evinceth no grace. Rather bring into orderly
                            subjection the turbulent, through meekness. Every wound is not cured by the same method of
                            application.- -Watch as a divine wrestler ; thy theme is eternal life, and immortaliLet not
                            those who seem as experienced Christians, and are yet unsound in the faith stagger thee :
                            stand firm as an anvil continually struck.- -It is the character of a great wrestler to be
                            mangled, and yet to conquer. Be more studious than thou art; Consider the times, and expect
                            Him who is above all time, who is unconnected with time, the Invisible One, made visible for
                            us :- -the impassable, but passable for us, who bore all sorts of sufferings for us.- - Let
                            not widows be neglectad ; Next to the Lord, do thou take care of them. Let nothing be done
                            without thy cognisance.- -Do thou nothing without the mind of God.- -Let assemblies be more
                            frequently held, seek out all by name. * * * * If any can remain in chastity, for the honor
                            of the Lord, let them do so without boasting ; if they boast, they are lost! And, if the man
                            set himself above the Bishop, he is lost." </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My faith" TEIform="index"/> MY FAITH
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Brown, E. E." TEIform="persName"/>MRS. E. E. BROWN
                        </byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">I trust in God; whatever ills Around my pathway
                                    fall, Whatever clouds obscure ray sun, God sends and guides them all. I am not wise
                                    to frame a creed, Or talk of things divine ; I know not where 'twixt good and ill,
                                    To draw a boundary line. I cannot tell what saints shall nil His glorious courts
                                    above, I only know this one blest truth ; That God is boundless love. And knowing
                                    this, I cannot fix The limits of his grace,<pb n="278" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 278 THE MANIFESTO.
                                    Or tell what souls have strayed beyond The light of his dear face. So in my faith I
                                    vest content, Where'er my lot may fall; I cannot wander far from Him Who.-e care is
                                    over all. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Acrostic" TEIform="index"/> ACROSTIC.</head><p TEIform="p"> Exhortations from " The Sermon on the Mount." Matthew, Give to him that asketh thee and from
                            him thai would borrow of thee turn not thou away, v., 42. Enter ye in at the straight gate,
                            vii., 13. No man can serve two masters, yi., 24. Every good tree bringeth forth good fruit,
                            vii., 17. Verily I say unto thee thou shalt by no means come out thence till thou hast paid
                            the uttermost farthing, v., 26. Agree with thine adversary quickly while thou art in the way
                            with him. v., 25. M oreover when ye fast be not as the hypocrites of a sad countenance, vi.,
                            16. Ask and it shall be given you, seek and ye shall find; knock and it shall be opened unto
                            you. vii. 7., Rejoice and be exceeding glad for great is your reward in heaven, v., 12. The
                            light of the body is the eye. vi., 22. |f thine eye be single thy whole body shall be full
                            ol light, vi., 22. Not every one that saith.unto, me Lord, Lord, shalj enter into the
                            kingdom of heaven, but he that doeth the will of my Father, vii., 21. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.
                        </p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Children:--'Blessed are the peacemakers. Denying self makes peace..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Dear Children:--'Blessed are the peacemakers. Denying self makes peace...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Connecticut, Enfield, 1887" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, Conn., 1887.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Children :- -"Blessed are the peacemakers." Denying self makes peace. Follow Christ, who
                            sought not to please Him-" self, and be partakers of His peace, which He gives unto those
                            who imitate His example. The pure in heart find peace within. Strive for purity, patience,
                            and peace. Growing in virtue is growing in peace, as time speeds on will virtue increase.
                            ''To be carnally minded is death, but to be spiritually minded is life and peace. " Behold
                            the upright, for the end of such is peace. Pleasant and peaceful are Wisdom's ways. Walk
                            therein. "Let the peace of God rule in your hearts." This is an absolute command; therefore
                            do not despair of peace as if it were unattainable, when you are commanded to let it rule in
                            your hearts. Make room in your hearts for the peace of God to enter. Say to the angry waves
                            of passion and rebellion, "Peace be still 1" Breathe more of the pure air of heaven, and be
                            strengthened by the sweet songs of peace the angels sing. Submission to God's will cannot
                            fail to bring peace to your spirits. Keep your hearts pure, your as-irations holy, your
                            thoughts humble and inild, your souls ever open heavenward, and you will be enriched with
                            the fruits of the Spirit, which are love, joy, and peace. " Let your lives be peaceful and
                            true, or else be sure you will it rue. " Do your best toward increasing the knowledge of and
                            making more real the advent of " Peace on earth, good will to men. " In purity of life, in
                            meekness and humility, in silent, brave, trusting endurance, a strength of spirit will be
                            given you to rise through affliction and suffering to peace. Your Brother, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Friendly notice" TEIform="index"/>FRlENDLY NOTICE.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The other day I, [Editor of the Albany Argus,]met Elder Frederick W. Evans, of
                                    the Shaker Community at Mount Lebanon, He seemed to have been benefited by his.
                                    English trip, concerning the results of which he waxed most eloquent. The Argus
                                    published an account of his reception meeting, with the addresses of Dr. Peebles and
                                    the Elder giving a report of their mission. Naturally this was largely concerned
                                    with the doings of these preachers, but the result of their earnest words is only
                                    now becoming manifest. From letters and papers received from the other side, it is
                                    seen that they made lasting impressions, and that their arguments have been
                                    discussed and pondered, to the effect of making more converts. The Elder said to me
                                    : " We brought over a few with us, and left a goodly number preparing to come as
                                    soon as they can settle business affairs. But what I hope to see is the Shaker order
                                    established in England. There is where it properly belongs. The governmental
                                    upheaval is the indication that the time has come tp abolish church and state."
                                    Owing to our proximity to their leading settlement, Albanians have always been,<pb n="279" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> familiar with the tenets of their ordei. We cannot quite
                                    realize how striking these ideas must seem when promulgated to those in other lands.
                                    Not a few of the great intellects have been strangely interested in, and drawn to
                                    the Shaker faith. Twenty years ago Hepworth Dixon wrote: "The people are like their
                                    village, soft in speech, demure in bearing, gentle in face, a people seeming to be
                                    at peace not only with themselves, but with nature and with heaven." And again :
                                    "After spending a few days among them, seeing them at their meals and at their
                                    prayers, in their private amusements and in their household work, I found myself
                                    thinking that if any chance were to throw me down, and I were sick in spirit, broken
                                    in health, there would be few female faces next after my own wife and kin that would
                                    be pleasanter to see about my bed. Life appears to move on in Mount Lebanon in an
                                    easy kind of rhythm; order, temperance, frugality, worship, every one seems busy,
                                    every one tranquil." Still further he adds: "Measured against the millions of
                                    Christian people in the United States, six or seven thousand Shakers may appear of
                                    small account ; and this would be truth if strength of spiritual and moral forces
                                    could be told in figures, but one man with ideas may be worth a parliament or army."
                                    The full force of such a tribute will be understood when it is remembered that these
                                    virtues are not predicted of individuals, but of a sect. Could equal tribute be paid
                                    to Christians, as a body?</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Albany Argus" TEIform="index"/>The Albany Argus.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Twenty impolite things" TEIform="index"/>TWENTY IMPOLITE THINGS.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">1. Loud and boisterous laughing. 2. Reading when others are talking. 3. Talking
                                    when others are reading. 4. Cutting finger nails in company. 5. Joking others in
                                    company. 6. Gazing rudely at strangers. 7. Leaving a stranger without a seat. 8.
                                    Making yourself hero of your own story. 9. Reading aloud in company without being
                                    asked. 10. Spitting about the house- -smoking or chewing. 11. Leaving church before
                                    worship is over. 12. Whispering or laughing in the house of God. 13. A want of
                                    respect and reverence for seniors. 14. Correcting older persons than yourseli
                                    especially parents. 15. Receiving a present without an expression of gratitude. 16.
                                    Not listening to what one is saying in company. 17. Commencing to eat as soon as you
                                    get to the table. 18. Answering questions that have been put to others. 19.
                                    Commencing talking before others have finished speaking. 20. Laughing at the
                                    mistakes of others.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Earth" TEIform="index"/>The Earth.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The first effect of tobacco taken in any manner..." TEIform="index"/>The first effect of tobacco taken in any manner...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> The first effect of tobacco taken in any manner, is upon the mucous membrane of the lip-*,
                            mouth and throat, which soon impairs their healthy condition, and creates a desire for other
                            narcotics, especially alcohol. Most drunkards commence with tobacco. From these the disease
                            extends upwards into the nostrils, and down into the stomach and also into the air vessels
                            of the lungs; these membranes become thickened, their secretions are changed, and the first
                            stage of digestion which should begin in the mouth is seriously interfered with ; if
                            continued, dyspepsia, or chronic inflammation&gt;.ei1sues. The cure for all these is
                            abstinence from the poison. Let it alone and you will get well.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Childs, Henry T." TEIform="persName"/>Henry T. Childs.</byline></div2><div2 type="nationalnews" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bible from a printer's standpoint" TEIform="index"/>The Bible from a Printer's Standpoint.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Printers might like to know that the entire Scriptures contain 2,275,260 ems in
                                    diamond and 2,807,840 ems in nonpareil. It would take a printer a year and a half to
                                    put the Scriptures in type, at the rate of 5,000 ems per day. The quantity of metal
                                    required in nonpareil would be about 6,500 pounds, in bourgeois 13,000, and in pica
                                    26,000 pounds. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Baltimore labor free press" TEIform="index"/>Baltimore Labor Free Press.</bibl></cit></p><pb n="280" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p"> THE MANIFESTO. DECEMBER, Office of publication. The Manifesto is published at Shaker Village
                            Mer. Co., N. H. All articles for publication should be addressed to Henry C. Blinn, and all
                            letters on financial business to A. Y. Coehran. .75 .40 One copy per year, postage paid, '
                            six months, " " Send for specimen copy, free.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>NOTES.</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good will to man" TEIform="index"/>GOOD WILL TO MAN.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">It is with feelings of gratitude that we find ourselves penning these lines for the Dec.
                                Manifesto. The twelve months that have been given to fill out the full year, with buds
                                and flowers and fruitage will soon have passed peacefully into the land of shades. Each
                                season has borne precious treasures for the good of mankind and in these seasons we have
                                shared abundantly the many gifts that came from the hand of our Heavenly Father, and
                                Mother,- -God. New interests will now be developed, new life demanded and an earnest,
                                prayerful attention to the needs of humanity, our work of gospel love. It was in the
                                beautiful spirit of this same love element that Jesus impressed this truth upon his
                                disciples. God maketh his sun to rise on the evil and on the good, and sendeth rain on
                                the just and on the unjust. We marvel at this great condescension of our God, as it is
                                in striking contrast with the selfishness that is in man, where the strong dominate over
                                the weak, and where the rich live in luxury at the expense of the poor. However, fair or
                                faulty we may have presented ourselves before God or man, we have been privileged to
                                gather in vessels of our own preparing, and through God's infinite love, preserve those
                                gifts which have held us to some extent, under the care and protection of an over-ruling
                                Providence. Although "we may not have whereof to boast," we have seen the light of God's
                                truth and heard the voice of the messengers of love, the gospel testimony of Jesus
                                Christ. It has whispered this unerring test to our souls.- -"All that a man hath, yea
                                and his own life also," must be given to secure the promised reward. Volumes of nicely
                                adjusted theology, or tomes of speculative Christianity may be beautifully written, but
                                their value would be as the value of dust, when righteousness or a pure heart was
                                demanded. The wants of humanity are such that there is no time to waste in non-essential
                                speculation. We must work while the day lasts, for the night will certainly overtake us,
                                in which no man can work. That we have been sheltered from over whelming calamities a,nd
                                are still spared to enjoy the immunities of life, - -That we have been blessed with the
                                fruitage of honest labor, and can say with the apostle, "We owe no man anything, but to
                                love one another; for he that loveth another hath fulfilled the law." We find in these
                                subjects many good gifts over which we may rejoice with thanksgiving and praise. On
                                every hand the goodness of God is seen in its unfolding beauty, fully and freely
                                    TERMS<pb n="281" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> proffered to the willing heart and to the obedient mind.
                                The time has been when men accredited themselves with rights to divine favor as special
                                privileges for something which they may have said or done. This assumption has paved the
                                way for countless forms of cruel persecution, to be inflicted upon the less powerful
                                class. Whatever may have been brought down through the ages, by legendary lore, or
                                retained by any form of tradition, we rest assured that the laws which G-od has establi
                                shed in his wisdom, will act, harmoniously, irrespective of " names or sects or
                                parties." Divine love can be no respecter of persons, only so far as they work iu
                                harmony with the law of right. Hearts that are unclean cannot be wholly suitable for the
                                preservation of divine gifts, and interests that are divided between righteousness and
                                selfishness can never secure peace or prosperity to the individual. Increasing with the
                                light that has come into the world, we shall see in all clearness the manifestations of
                                God's work. Every year, month and day presents to us some unfoldment of spirit power,
                                some demonstration of God's love to man, and some duty where the cross and the crown can
                                bring victory for right and make on earth a paradise of God.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="nationalnews" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Amour mission in Chicago..." TEIform="index"/>The Amour mission in Chicago...</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The Amour mission in Chicago is a great religious and benevolent enterprise,
                                        conducted on a somewhat novel plan. The late Joseph Amour bequeathed $100,000 to
                                        establish it, and his brother Philip D. Amour, feeling that the amount was
                                        inadequate to the work which might be done, added $300,000 to it.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Boston Journal" TEIform="index"/>- -Boston Journal. </bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary</head><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Uses of borax" TEIform="index"/>USES OF BORAX
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> A cup of powdered borax on your wash, stand will do
                                        wonders in the way of softening the skin. If you have been working in the
                                        garden, or doing anything about the house which has tended to make your hands
                                        rough, when you wash them dip your fingers in the borax and rub your hands well
                                        with it. Bo. rax (pulverized) sprinkled plentifully around the haunts of water
                                        bugs will drive them away. Cockroaches also will yield to thi- - treatment and
                                        depart. The safest and best thing also for washing the hair is a moderately
                                        strong solution of borax in water. Pure water should be used immediately after
                                        washing with the borax and water. The washerwomen of Holland and Belgium, who
                                        get up their linen so beautifully white, use refined borax as washing powder
                                        instead of soda, in the proportion of one large handful of borax powder to about
                                        ten gallons of boiling waterThey thus save in soap nearly half All the washing
                                        establishments adopt the same mode. For laces, cambrics, etc., an extra quantity
                                        of the powder is used, and for crinolines, (requiring to be made stiff,) a
                                        strong solution is necessary. Borax being a neutral salt, does not in the
                                        slightest degree injure the texture of the linen; its effect is to soften the
                                        hardest water, and, therefore, it should be kept on every toilet table. To the
                                        taste it is rather sweet; but not at all unpleasant, is an excellent dentrifice,
                                        and in hot countries is em. ployed in combination with tartaric acid and
                                        bi-carbonate of soda as a cooling beverage. Good tea cannot be made with hard
                                        water ; but all. water may be made soft by adding a teaspoonful of borax powder
                                        to an ordinary sized kettle of water, in which it should boil. The saving in the
                                        quantity of tea used will be at least one-fifth. Our lady readers who have not
                                        used borax have been losing a great help and comfort. If once tested, none will
                                        be without it on the toilet table. It removes stains and dirt from the hands
                                        better than soap, and at the same time softens and smooths the skin. It is
                                        excellent for wash.<pb n="282" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 282 THE MANIFESTO. ing laces, and
                                        will, without injury, cleanse brushes and combs in a few moments. It extracts
                                        dirt from articles of delicate texture without rubbing, it being1 only necessary
                                        to put them to co'ak in a solution of borax over night, and to rinse them in the
                                        morning. Two tablespoonfuls of pulverized borax dissolved in a quart of water,
                                        to which add enough water to cover a pair of blankets, will cleanse them
                                        beautifully. It also saves great labor in washing paint.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/>Hall's Journal of Health</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A bad breath may be cured as follows..." TEIform="index"/>A bad breath may be cured as follows...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> A bad bkeath may be cured as follows, no matter what the cause: Three hours
                                        after breakfast a teaspoonful of the following mix. ture: Chlorate of potassa,
                                        two drachms; sweetened water, four ounces: wash the month occasionally with a
                                        similar mixture, and the breath will be as sweet as an infant's of two months. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/>Hall's Journal of Health.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Educated Chinaman gives his reasons for preffering the heathen belief" TEIform="index"/>An
                            Educated Chinaman Gives His Reasons for Preferring the Heathen Belief.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Foo, Wong Chin" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> Wong Chin Foo, lias written a letter to the North American Review explaining his faith, or
                            why he is a heathen. He starts with saying that he was born and raised a Heathen, and up to
                            the age of seventeen practiced its moral and religious code, and "my conscience was clear,
                            and my hopes as to future life were undimmed by distracting doubt." At this age he was
                            transferred "to the midst of our showy Christian civilization, and was bewildered by the
                            multiplicity of sects, each one claiming a monopoly of the only and narrow road to heaven."
                            "I looked into Presbyterianism," he says <cit TEIform="cit"><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="North American review" TEIform="index"/></bibl><quote TEIform="quote">"only to retreat shudderingly from a belief in a merciless God who had long
                                    foreordained most of the helpless human race to an eternal hell. To preach such a
                                    doctrine to intelligent heathen would only raise in their minds doubts of my sanity,
                                    if they did not believe I was lying. Then I dipped into Baptist doctrines, but found
                                    so many sects therein, of different 'shell,' warring over the merits of cold-water
                                    initiation and the method and time of using it, that I became disgusted with such
                                    trivialities; and the question of close communu n or not only impressed me that some
                                    were very stingy and exclusive with their bit of bread and wine, and others a little
                                    less so. Methodism struck me as a thunder-and-lightning religion- -all profession
                                    and noise. You struck it, or it struck you, like a spasm,- - -and so you
                                    'experienced' religion. The Congregationalists deterred me with their starchiness
                                    and self-conscious true goodness, and their desire only for hightoned affiliates.
                                    Unitarianism seemed all doubt, doubting even itself. A number of other Protestant
                                    sects based on some novelty or eccentricity- -like Quakerism- -I found not worth a
                                    serious study by the non-Christian. But on one point this mass of Protestant
                                    dissension cordially agreed, and that was in the united hatred of Catholicism, the
                                    older form of Christianity. And Catholicism returned with interest the animosity. It
                                    haughtily declared itself the only true church, outside of which there was no
                                    salvation- -for Protestants especially; that its chief prelate was the personal
                                    representative of God on earth, and that he was infallible. Here was religious
                                    unity, power and authority with a vengeance. But, in chorus, my solicitous
                                    Protestant friends beseeched me not to touch Catholicism, declaring it was worse
                                    than my heathenism- -in which I agreed; but the same line of argument also convinced
                                    me that Protestantism stood in the same category. In fact, the more I studied
                                    Christianity in its various phases,, and listened to the animadversions of one sect
                                    upon another, the more it all seemed tome 'sounding brass and tinkling cymbals. ' '
                                    " Call us heathens if you will, the Chinese are still superior in social
                                    administration and social order. Among 400,000,000 of Chinese there are fewer
                                    murders and robberies in a year than there are in New York State. . . . Christians
                                    are continually fussing about religion ; they build great churches and make long
                                    prayers, and yet there is more wickedness in the neighborhood of a single church
                                    district of one thousand people than among one million heathen, churchless and
                                    unsermonized. Christian talk is long and loud about how to be good and act
                                        charitably.<pb n="283" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> It is all charity and no fraternity- -'there,
                                    dog, take your crust and be thankful!' And is it, therefore, any wonder there is
                                    more heart-breaking and suicides in the single State of New York in a year than in
                                    all China?" " The difference between the heathen and the Christian is that the
                                    heathen does good for the sake of doing good. With the Christian, what little good
                                    he does is for immediate honor and for future reward; he lends to the Lord and wants
                                    compound interest. In fact, the Christian is the worthy heir of his religious
                                    ancestors. The heathen does much and says little about it; the Christian does little
                                    good, but when he does he wpnts it in the papers and on his tombstone. Love men for
                                    the good they do you is a practical Christian idea, not for the good you should do
                                    them as a matter of human duty. So Christians love the heathen; yes, the heathen's
                                    possessions, and in proportion to these the Christian's love grows in intensity.
                                    When the English wanted the Chinamen's gold and trade, they said they wanted ' to
                                    open China for their missionaries.' And opium was the chief, in fact, only,
                                    missionary they looked after, when they forced the ports open. And this imfamous
                                    Christian introduction among Chinamen has done more injury, social and moral, in
                                    China than all the humanitarian agencies of Christianity could remedy in two hundred
                                    years. And on you, Christians, and on your greed of gold, we lay the burden of the
                                    crimes resulting; of tens of millions of honest, useful men and women sent thereby
                                    to premature death after a short, miserable life, beside the physical and moral
                                    prostration it entails even where it does not prematurely kill! And this great
                                    national curse was thrust on us at the point of Christian bayonets. And you wonder
                                    why we are heathen? The only positive point Christians have impressed on heathenism
                                    is that they would sacrifice religion, honor, principle, as they do life, for-
                                    -gold. And then they sanctimoniously tell the poor heathen : ' You must save your
                                    soul by believing as we do!' " " On the whole, the Christian way strikes us as
                                    decidedly an unnatural one; it is every one for himself- -parents and children even.
                                    Imagine my feelings, if my own son, whom I loved better than my own life, for whom I
                                    had sacrificed all my comforts and luxury, should, through some selfish motive, go
                                    to law with me to get his share .prematurely of my property, and even have me
                                    declared a lunatic, or have me arrested and imprisoned, to subserve his interest or
                                    intrigue? Is this a rare Christian case? Can it bs charged against heathenism? We
                                    heathen are a God-fearing race. Aye, we believe the whole universecreation-
                                    -whatever exists and has existed- - is of God and in God; that, figuratively, the
                                    thunder is His voice and the lightning His mighty hands; that everything we du and
                                    contemplate doing is seen and known by Him ; that he has created this and other
                                    worlds to effectuate beneficent, not merciless, designs, and that all that He has
                                    done is for the steady, progressive benefit of the creatures whom He endowed with
                                    life and sensibility, and to whom as a consequence He owes and gives paternal care,
                                    and will give paternal compensation and justice; yet His voice will threaten and His
                                    mighty hand chastise those who deliberately disobey His sacred laws and their duty
                                    to their fellow man. ' Do unto others as you wish they would do unto you,' or ' Love
                                    your neighbor as yourself,' is the great divine law which Christians and heathen
                                    alike hold, but which the Christians ignore. This is what keeps me the heathen I am
                                    ! And I earnestly invite the Christians of America to come to Confucius."</quote></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="O wisdom! thou has truly said, when as..." TEIform="index"/>O wisdom! thou has truly said, when as...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">0 Wisdom ! thou has truly said, when as The culminating point of honor due, Thou gavest
                            preference unto conquered self.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Calver, A. J." TEIform="persName"/>A. J. Calver. </byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Blessed is the man who forgiveth those who trespass against..." TEIform="index"/>Blessed is the man who forgiveth those who trespass against...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Blessed is the man who forgiveth those who trespass against him, who is kind to the unkind,
                            charitable to his censors, loving to his enemies; for he is perfect as God is perfect, and
                            he shall inherit the tree of life forever.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Griffiths, W. C." TEIform="persName"/>W. C. Griffiths.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The serene, silent beauty of a holy life is the most..." TEIform="index"/>
                            The serene, silent beauty of a holy life is the most...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The serene, silent beauty of a holy life is the most powerful influence in the
                                    world next to the almightiness of the Spirit of God.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Spurgeon" TEIform="index"/>Spurgeon.</bibl></cit></p><pb n="284" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>
                                The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/>
                                Hall's Journal of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Alden's manifold cyclopedia" TEIform="index"/>
                                Alden's Manifold Cyclopedia
                            </head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="R. P. journal" TEIform="index"/>
                                R.P. Journal
                            </head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Social ethics" TEIform="index"/>
                                Social Ethics
                            </head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Truth" TEIform="index"/>
                                The Truth
                            </head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">The Phrenological Journal and Science or Health. Contents : Nov. Pundita Ramabai;
                                Metaphysics or Phrenology,'- - Which? Some Notable Characters of the Day; Mesmerism
                                Forty years ago; The Wealth of Southern Pines; The Human Organization and Religion;
                                Going to John; A Girl's Problem ; Comic Side of Animal Life; Julius Caspar's
                                Temperament; Health Experience of an aged Man; Pulmonary Consumption; Patent Medicines,
                                etc., etc. Fowler &amp; We Is Co. 775 Broadway, N. Y. $2. a year. Hall's Journal of
                                Health. Nov. Contents; A Remarkable Verification ; Shakers and Shakerism ; Cancer; What
                                Every Girl Ought to Learn; Electrical Mechanism; Use of Toilet Soap; Forewarning; Mind
                                Cure; The Olive Tree; The Seybert Commission, etc., etc. Office 206 Broadway, N. Y. $1.
                                per year. 'h Manifold Cyclopedia. Volume I. of this work, now on our table, abundantly
                                fulfills the promises of the publisher's prospectus. It is a really handsome volume of
                                640 pages, half Morocco binding, large type, profusely illustrated, and yet sold for the
                                price of 65 cents; cloth binding only 50 cent*- -postage 11 cents extra. Large discounts
                                even from these prices are allowed to early subscribers. It is to be issued in about
                                thirty volumes. The Manifold Cyclopedia is, in many ways, unlike any other Cyclopedia.
                                It undertakes to present a BUrvey of the entire circle of knowledge, whether of WORDS or
                                of THINGS, thus combining the characteristics of a Cyclopedia and a Dictionary,
                                including in its vocabulary every word which has any claim to a place in the English
                                language. Its form of publication is as unique as its plan- -the "Ideal Edition " its
                                publisher calls it, and the popular verdict seem-; to sustain his claim. It certainly is
                                delightfully convenient. It will not be strange if this proves to be the great popular
                                cyclopedia. It certainly is worthy of examination by all searchers after knowledge. The
                                publisher sends specimen pages free to any applicant. John B. Alden, Publisher, 393
                                Pearl St., New York, or Lakeside Building, Chicago. There is no subject that has a
                                firmer hold upon the mind than that which teaches of a life beyond the boundary of time.
                                Whether intuitive or brought out by education, it has an influence upon the race of
                                mankind that has come to stay. Simple minded and unprincipled characters have also
                                presented their side of this wonderful work, and their followers are "a multitude." With
                                all these conflicting views it is refreshing to find a paper, like the R. P. Journal,
                                that cuts a straight path through the whole, and carefully and correctly informs its
                                many readers how the religious world moves. Published by John C. Bundy. No. 92 La Salle
                                St. Chicago, 111. $2.50 a year. Social Ethics. This is the title of a pamphlet
                                containing the addresses o C. H. Kitchell, E. H. Benn and Wm. M. McLaury, M. D. on the
                                subject of Social Evil. They were read before the Society of Medical Jurisprudence, at
                                the Academy of Medicine, in the cdtv of New York. It is, indeed, pleasant to know that
                                the warning voices of good men may be heard, from time to time urging the necessity of a
                                more careful observance of (iod's laws. The sad and often fearful penalties that are
                                brought upon man through ignorance of his own being, or through willful transgression,
                                makes the journey of this life one of sorrow instead of happiness. Dr. McLaury and the
                                other writers deal with the subject like officers who are contending against an almost
                                overwhelming foe, and the struggle must terminate in victory or death. The addresses-
                                are well worthy of a careful perusal by all who are interested in the growth of right
                                over wrong. Truth, a magazine of Christian Science. This is a new work. Vol. I., No. I.
                                Edited by Mary H. Plunkett. A few words from the Editors introduction may show what is
                                intended. " We desire to m ke practical the prophetic announcement that has come down
                                all the ages." ' Know the Truth and the Truth shall make you free.1 "We desire you to
                                know that you are no longer under the bondage of sickness, sin and death- -that
                                sickness, sin and death are but symbols in the moving law of negation : and that in the
                                white light of Science they will entirely disappear from human consciousness," We wish
                                the best of success to every class who are the ministers of kind words to those in
                                sorrow, or who are able to heal the sick of their infirmaties. Published by Truth
                                Publishing Co., Chicago, 111.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">Errata- -In Nov, Manifesto, on page 255 All our life service.- - -read, All our lip
                        service.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="When Death, the great reconciler, has come it is never..." TEIform="index"/>
                            When Death, the great reconciler, has come it is never...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">When Death, the great reconciler, has come it is never our tenderness that we repent of, but
                            our severity.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Eliot, George" TEIform="persName"/>George Eliot.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The pleasure of doing good is the only one that never wears out" TEIform="index"/>
                            The pleasure of doing good is the only one that never wears out
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The pleasure of doing good is the only one that never wears out.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anon" TEIform="persName"/>Anon.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Eaton, J. Greene" TEIform="index"/>
                                J. Greene Eaton
                            </head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beals, Isaac" TEIform="index"/>
                                Isaac Beals
                            </head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lowd, Sophia M." TEIform="index"/>
                                Sophia M. Lowd
                            </head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ellis, Abram T." TEIform="index"/>
                                Abram T. Ellis
                            </head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">J. Greene Eaton, at Enfield, N. H Oct. 12, 1887. Age 75 yrs. and 5 mo. Elder Isaac Beals
                                of Novitiate order, Union Village, Ohio. Oct. 12, 1887. Age 83 yrs. 6 mo. and 10 days
                                Sophia M. Lowd, at Canterbury, N. H. Oct. 19, 1887. Age, 75 yrs. 5 mo. and 17 days.
                                Abram T. Ellis, at Watervliet, N. Y. Oct. 25, 1887. Age 74 yrs. 7 mo. and 23 Has lived
                                in the Community twelve years. days.</p></div3></div2><!--
                    <pb n="285" id="p23"/> INDEX. Absent, Speak not evil of the Agnus Dei, Again, Acrostic, An Aim Aright, Army, Salvation
                    Advice, Age, Honorable Acrostic, B. Bullard, Eldress H. Belief, My Brotherhood, Christian Born again, Be ye Baptism,
                    Beyond, The Bible Cla s, From the Bloomberg, Johanah A tribute to Battles of Shaking, Bible, The Borax, Uses of Breath,
                    Bad C. Christianity, Command, The first Cloud lifted, The Cease to do evil, Childhood, Shaker Carr, Martha A. Communism,
                    Spiritual Christianity, Children, From the Cross, Joy in the Communism, Christian 82, 117, Christ, The cross of Cory,
                    Zipporah Testimony of Consolation, Cross, The Changed Conviction, Sweet Contentment, Conference, Evening Christ, Coming
                    to Page. 19 22 103 174 240 261, 272 276 262, 278 7 60 68 79 80 81 95 125 223 279 281 282 3 32 36 40 45, 116 46 52 64 47,
                    95 57 138, 165 88 90 93 155 173 174 180 183 Page. Consolation, Our 208 Creation, Crown of 238 Cross, A full 244
                    Cathedral, St. Patrick's 250 Church and its Promises, 256 Christ, Life in 268 Chinaman, Educated 282 D. Doolittle,
                    Antoinette 13 Dyspepsia, The way to cure 17 Duty first, pleasure afterward, 28 Devotional, 93 Day to Day, 167 Discourse,
                    Public 171, 197 Dosing, A mania for 185 Discourse, 212 Duty, 276 JES. Education, 19 Evans, F. W. 30, 67 Expansion,
                    Necessity of 57 Equality, 70 Eyes, Sore 137 Education, 175 Enemy, Our 275 Exhortations, 276 W. Fraser, D. Fallen Being,
                    Is man a Food, Water in Friendship, Faith and Works, Faith, Favor, God's Faith, Food, Improper Fashion, Friend, Voice of
                    a Faith and Hope, Faith, Living 43 89 104 108 109 144 158 185 20C 211 215 230 A.<pb n="286" id="p24"/> 286 THE MANIFESTO
                    Forgiveness, 254 Live for something. 67 Father, Our " Life, The mission of angelic 102 Food Adulterations, 258 Lewis, A
                    130 Friends in Spirit Land, 264 Light, 136 Faith, My 277 Law, 144 Friendly Notice, 278 Love, Christian 156 Letter, N G.
                    Danforth 162 Daniel Offord 163, 177 God, The kingdom of Gtoug 53 14.9 " Hamilton De Graw Love, A Tribute of 165 168 God,
                    Living with 168 Letter, Elijah Myrick, 176 Gifts, The Best 184 F. W. Evans, 177 Giving, The Art of Gratitude, 208 244 J.
                    M. Peebles, Life, Tree of 179 181 God, Trust in 269 Language, The English 187 Good Will to Man, 280 Letter, C. L.
                    Nelson, 190 " H. Wormhout, 200, 228 EC. " C. Marseilles, 202 " Louis Basting, 202, 247, 274 Hindering, 10 " Daniel
                    Orcutt, 204, 278 Home, From 11 " H. Hastings, 272 Hinges, Little 24 J. S. 273 Hammond, Prudence, Testimony of 33 Love,
                    True 219 Holy Living, Rules for 39 Love, Universal 223 Heart, A Chapel in the 86 Life, An Exemplary 226 Homes, A peril
                    to our 131 Letter, L. R. 247 Habits, Good and Bad 141 Lord, The fear of the 259 Hcme, That Ideal 160 How Easy it is 181
                    Heaven. A Star from 223 Manners, Washington's code of 23 Honorable Age, 276 Mud, Come out of the 53 Might have been, 87
                    X. May, Prayer in 109 Imagination and Disease, 42 Man, Thou art the 157 Influences, Surrounding 104 Missionaries, The
                    Shaker 163 Ill-Temper, 135 Meetings, Farewell 234 Income, Enormous 263 Miracles, Wonderful 236 - -T. Mission Amour, 281
                    Johnson, Eldress Julia 39 Jealousy, 151 New Year, The 16 Note of J. S. P. 29 K. Not far, 30 Non-essentials or
                    essentials, 112 Kelly, M. A. Tribute of Love to 12 No Time to Waste, 201 Keep thy Garments Pure, 236 Ninety barrels a
                    day, 239 Now, 263 Lord, Sabbath of the 13 O. Life is what we make it, 24 Orcutt, Daniel 22, 124 Liberty enlightening the
                    world, 38, 78 One thing I know, 69 Light, The river of 47 One at a time, 79<pb n="287" id="p25"/> THE MANIFESTO. 287
                    Spirits, Ardent 259 Speak no Evil, 262 Promise, Sure 7 Sword of Heaven, 264 Peace, 11 Pick, Ernest 15, 66 T. Praise and
                    Thanksgiving, 29 Text, The Parson's 22 Petitions, 93 Testimony, The Gospel 1, 25, 49, 73 , 97 Prayer, 103 121, 145, 169,
                    193, 217, 241, 265 Probation, Future 105 The Hour and the Year, 18 Pronunciamento, A Shaker's 123 Transition, A heavenly
                    44 Persevere, 157 Translations, Amended 76 Prayer, 204 True and Faithful, 79 Prayer and Potatoes, 209 Truth, 108 Pearl
                    of Great Price, 215 Temperance, 110 Pork as Food, 233 Thought, 111 Perseverance, 253 Theology, Juvenile " Prophet, A 258
                    Temperance, A plea for 113 Property, 264 Thought, Morning 125 Things worth considering, 156 Trifles, Beware of 159
                    Resolve, Christian 19 Tobacco created, 161 Rheumatism and Diet, 42 The truly so, 167 Revivals, 58 Temptation, Continuing
                    in 189 Rest. God's 63 Talk, People will 192 Revelation. 72 Taught, As Jesus 199 Race. Condition and Destiny of our
                    Religion, Practical 100 111 Turner, Jethro, Testimony of Thanks, 205 211 Row, Hoe your own 119 Truth, 215 Relation,
                    Family Reckoning, Our Daily Rheumatism, 149 159 161 Theology, 219, 244, Teacher, The Truth, 270 232 239 Religion, Reply,
                    Whitworth's - - 182 185 Thought for Others, Tobacco, 263 279 Reverie, 199 Twenty Impolite things, Retrospection, 204 XJ.
                    Respect yourself, 219 Unbelief, Causes of 60 Unto you it is given &c, 105 S. Uniform, Why we wear 214 Unrest,
                    261 Stickney, A. C. 36 Sleeping room, The Ideal 65 Sproat, G. T. Tribute of affection to 87 Virtues, Christian 29
                    Self-Cure, 89 Vegetables, Living on 142 Strife, 110 Vegetarian, 168 Suffering, 132 Sowing and Reaping, 133 "W. Success,
                    140 Words, Beautiful 23 Soul, A God-like 167 Way, On the 69 Simplicity, 188 World, Keeping unspotted from 70 Scientific
                    and Practical, 211 Words, Kind 72, 96, 144, 167, 192, 216 Sea, Storm at 223 240, 264 Story, The Old 240 Work, The new
                        125<pb n="288" id="p26"/> 288 THE MANIFESTO. Wright, Lucy, Testimony of World bright, How to make the Well, Cast not
                    dirt into the War, Word, Preach the Words, Y. Young friends, Address to Youth, Address to MUSIC. Keep Away, Life's
                    Victories, Redemption's Song, The Glad Song, Sweet Peace, DEATHS. Avery, Julia Ann Avery, Eliza Allander, William
                    Allard, Roselinda Blakey, Polly Boston, Eldress Susan Brackett, Elder Charles Bloomberg, Johanah Brettenstien, Alice
                    Beals, Elder Isaac 126 130 133 110 210 215 125 151 20 94 143 191 237 72 192 264 72 96 120 264 284 Clapp, Harriet
                    Callaway, Matilda Chandler, Olive Cochran, Nancy Champlain, Polly Davis, Eliza Doolittle, Eldress Antoinette Ellis,
                    Abram T. Eaton, Greene Freehart, Eunice Gilman, Ransom Gould, Sarah Gillespie, Eldress Mary A. Huntington, Eunice Lowd,
                    Sophia Montgomery, Murtle Price, Ann Pease, Martha Pearsons, Leander A. Parkhurst, Hannah Richmond, Galen Sproat,
                    Granville T. Smith, Susan Salisbury, Lavinia Stewart, Sally Maria Thomas, Eliza Thurstin, Mary J. Whittaker, John White,
                    Nehemiah 48 72 96 216 240 48 284 216 24 48 144 264 284 96 24 120 216 96 144 168 216 24 144 24 96<pb n="289" id="p27"/>

THE  MANIFESTOPOWDER
Absolutely Pure.
This powder never varies. A marvel of
purity, strength and wholesomeness. More
economical than the ordinary kinds, and
cannot be sold in competition with the multitude of low test, short weight, alum or phosphate powders. Sold only in cans. Royal
Baking Powder Co., 106 Wall-st., N. Y.
MEDAL.   MACHINES.
NEW I0S2 S2A2H .L3SJCULTU3AI. W02ES
1st. Premiums at all Competitive   Trials
Railway, Cliain andleverHoiw I*- - - -vier- -,Tlir- -*sliers and Clcanern, Tl- -r- -'i- -lt- -*r- -
& Shakers, Clover IffuSlem, Feed Cutter- -, TTlieel Horse Bah- - - - -, H- -iw B- -it- -hforlts, Shingle Machine*, Straw Preserving1 Rye Threshers, Portable Ml earn-Engines, Cider and WineMiiis anil Presses,
Dog and Fony Powers, I>isc Marrow*
& Springy Tooth   Marrows.     " Rofoinson's Hay Press, of four sizes- Will
work as easy with one horse, as
others with two. Made with Steel
Gearing which can not be broken."
WHEELER & MELICK Co.,
aibasy, ar. y.
Send stamp for Circular and report of Centennial
trial.
A MONTH   and BOARD Guaranteed
3 Young Men or Ladies in each  country,
and highest commission paid (often $150
a month)    WEW BOOK, already on
TIDAL WAVE RT^^TW^ W'n'S'.'P Cl
OF SUCCESS  Ut33    ff Vil JJJii Ji- -53>
in North and South America, at the Ice-Bound
Poles, over the lands of the Midnight Sun, under the
Equator, through the Dark Continent, among the Old
Temples of India, in the Flowery Kingdoms of China
and Japan, amid the ruins of Incas, Aztecs and Zuni, within Canons, Cliff Buildings, and Gardens of
the Gods, on the Isles of the Sea, and in all parts of
the globe. 300 engravings, Low Price. Quick Sales.
Send for Circular. P, W. Ziegler, & Co,, 720 Chestnut St. Philadelphia, Pa.
The Cosmopolitan
The handsomest, most entertaining, low price,
illustrated family magazine in the world.
($2.50 per year, with a $2.25 premium
free.) Sixty-four beautifully printed pages in
each number, filled with short stories, sketches,
travels, adventures, bright and brief scientific
and literary articles, by distinguished American
and foreign writers, such as Julian Hawthorne,
Harriet Prescott Spofford, George Parsons
Lathrop, Louise Chandler Moulton, J. Macdonald Oxley, Ella Wheeler Wilcox, H. H.
Boyesen, Catherine Owen, Rev. R. Heber
Newton, Alphonse Daudet, Paul Heyse, Count
Tolstoi, Th. Dostoivsky, William Westall and
many others. Also entertaining JUVENILE
and invaluable HOUSEHOLD departments.
One or more illustrated articles and several fullpage engravings in every number.
A Shannon   Letter and
Bill File or a Shannon
Sheet-Music Binder
Free Jto   every
Subscriber.
These premiums sell
everywhere for $2.25
each. The File is the most
perfect device ever invented for the preservation and
classification (alphabetically and according to date)
of all letters, bills, etc.
Any paper can be referred
to, taken out and put back
without disturbing the
others. With the "Binder
one can insert or take out
any piece of music without
disturbing any other sheet.
Get SAMPLE COPY at NEWS STAND or
send 20 Cents to publishers.
A3ENTS WANTED. BIS COMMISSIONS PAID.
Schlicht & Field Co., Rochester, N. Y.
A Shaker's Answer to the oft repeated
question, " what will become of the World if
all become Shakers? "           Price   10 cts.
The Life and Gospel Experience of
Mother Ann Lee.                  Price  10 cts.
Address, Manifesto, Shaker Village, N. H.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
IN THE SELECTION OF
A CHOICE GIFT
For Pastor, Parent, Teacher, Child, or
Friend,hot li elegance and usefulness will be found
combined in a copy of Webster's Unabridged.
siues luuijy other valuable features, it, contains
A Dictionary
of 118,000 Words, 3000 Engravings,
A Gazetteer of the World
locating and describing 25,000 Places,
of nearly 10,000 Noted Persons,
AH in One Book.
3000 more Words and nearly 2000 more Illustrations than any other American Dictionary.
Sold by all Booksellers.   Pamphlet free.
G. & C. MERRIAM & CO., Pub'rs, Springfield, Mass.
er Forty years*
perience    in   the
reparation of more
han One Hundred
Thousand applications for patents in
the United Slates mod Foreign countries, the publishers of the Scientific
American continue to act as solicitors
for patents, caveats, trade-marks, copy________ rights, etc., for the United States, and
to obtain patents in Canada, England, France,
Germany, and all other countries Their experience is unequaled and their facilities are unsurpassed.
Drawings and specifications prepared and filed
in the Patent Office on short notice. Terms very
reasonable. No charge for examination of models
or drawings    Advice by mail tree
Patents obtained through M u nniCo.are noticed
inthe SCIENTIFIC AMERICAN, which has
the largest circulation and is the most influential
newspaper of its kind published in the world.
The advantages of such a notice every patentee
understands.
This large and splendidly illustrated newspaper
is published WEEKLY*'. $3.00 a year, and is
admitted to be the best paper devoted to science,
mechanics, inventions, engineering works, and
other departments of industrial progress, published in any country. It contains the names of
all patentees and title of every invention patented
each week. Try it four months for one dollar.
Sold by all newsdealers.
If you have an invention to  patent write to
Munn <fc Co., publishers of Scientific American,
861 Broadway, New York.
Handbook about patents mailed frea.
Plain Evidences by which the True
Church of Christ may be known and distinguished from all others.
Price  20 cts.
Address, Manifesto, Shaker Village, N. H.
THE BACKUS WATER MOTOR,
We have one of eleven inches,  new,
that we will sell at a bargain.
Pub.   MANIFESTO.
Recitations for Christmas. Selected aud arranged by Margret Holmes.
This lirtlc work of one hundred and twenty pages,
is a repository for many beautiful poems, aud also
contains extract? from the writings of those who
have held the feast of Christmas in loving remembrance. The fortunate possessor of the little book
will at: once be introduced into the company of Wm.
D. Ilowells, N. P. Willis, Phoebe Gary, Julia Goddard, and many others.
Published by Charles A. Bates, Indianapolis, Ind.
Price, 25 cents.
Plain Talks upon Practical Religion.
Being candid answers for earnest  inquirers.
By Geo. A. Lomas.
Price   10 cts.
Shaker   Sermons.          Scripto-rational.
Containing the substance of Shaker Theology ; together with replies and criticisms, logically and clearly set forth.
Fourth Edition.           By H. L. Eads.
pp 320.                       Price $1.50
A summary view of the '' Millennial
Church " or United Society of Believers.
It treats of the Rise and Progress of the
Society, together with the general principles
of the Faith and Testimony.
pp 354                           Price 50 cts.
Address Manifesto, Shaker Village, N. H.
A Biographical 'Dictionary
<pb n="" id="p"/>
 --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>