<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ss0411" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">Shaker and Shakeress</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Society</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Mount Lebanon, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">4</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">11</biblScope><date value="18741101" TEIform="date">November 1874</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">81-88</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="4" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="81" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="11" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--  
                       <p>Vol. IV. No. 11. MONTHILYo PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETY. F. W. EVANS, Lebanon, Col. Co. N. Y. November, 1874,.
                        Editor. Fifty Cents per annum.</p>
                   --><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Evolution" TEIform="index"/>EVOLUTION</head><p TEIform="p">Will Shakerism, if successful in its missionary designs, run the world out ? Will it
                            exterminate the race? Nay, Shakerism is the result of Evolution—the fruit of the tree of
                            Humanity — Orderly Generation and prospective Regeneration. The Law and the Prophets were
                            until John, the last and greatest of the Prophets, who baptized Jesus with the Christ
                            Spirit, and he became a Christian. Then the Kingdom of Heaven was preached, and all men
                            progress toward it. All, born into this world, die. All who die, unresurrected from the
                            generative Order, will, in some of the hours of eternity, become Shakers. If right for some,
                            while in the body, to rise, in the Resurrection Order, is it wrong for all others not to so
                            rise ? Or, if right for the many to live and perpetuate life, is it wrong for the few not to
                            propagate ? Is there any Law — of God— under which, to abstain from physical parentage, is a
                            right and a duty ? or can a man, or woman live a celibate life, in thought, word and deed,
                            and be a perfectly developed human being — comfortable, useful and happy ? And can a man, or
                            woman become, to the highest degree, spiritualized, without refraining from amativeness on
                            the physical plane ? May flesh and spirit be united and constitute Christian husband, wife,
                            father, mother, brothers, sisters, sons, daughters, houses and lands, on the Earth, as in
                            Protestantism ? If generation be right, per se, is celibacy wrong? If Celibacy be right,per
                            se,\s generation wrong ? Or are both right — each in its own Order — being different stages,
                            phases, or cycles of human progress, under the Law of Evolution ? Or, is there but one plane
                            of being, in this world, and one heaven and one hell, in the next ? And, at death, do all go
                            to one, or the other ? If so, will children, who die before and after birth, with no
                            developed character — having done neither good nor evil —all be in a lake of fire and
                            brimstone, for eternity ? Or will they be in a Paradise of glorious felicity, for which they
                            are equally unprepared, and of which they are quite as undeserving? Are the millions of
                            Heathens, so called in theological and unhumanitarian contempt, all consigned to the
                            aforesaid lake ? The principal difference between marrying, fighting,
                            private-property-holding Christians, and these Heathens, consists in points of belief.
                            Comparing the Trinity, Atonement,Vicarious sacrifices, Physical Resurrection, Justification
                            by faith without good actions, etc., with Buddhist Theology, the difference is largely in
                            favor of the latter. Shaker Probation, after death, solves knotty problems, and justifies
                            the way of God to man. How can persons believe right, unless they have the will to do right
                            ? Condition determines capacity. In Physiology, persons, who eat, drink, breathe, exercise
                            bodily and mental powers, to their best perception of right today, may, to-morrow, see that
                            in all these they were wrong. To receive Truth, in the love of truth, unbiased by
                            educational prepossession — to observe facts, gather ideas, compare, deduce and arrange,
                            with the view to build up a system of truthful conduct, is noble. The reverse — using facts,
                            ideas, knowledge, to sustain preconceived theory, for short-sighted, selfish purposes and
                            habits, is ignoble. Thus, truth may be held in unrighteousness, and the Grace of God turned
                            to licentiousness, war and covetousness. Persecution, for mere belief, arises from
                            unprogressed selfhood — fear of consequences that might flow from the admission of new
                            truth. As the Catholic Priesthood feared the consequences of admitting that the earth
                            revolved upon its axis, as Protestant Clergy and Doctors opposed Harvey's circulation of the
                            blood, and now dispute the records of Geology, even as Paine disputed their Bible records,
                            so does Tyndall paralyze generative Christianity, with discharges from the Battery of
                            Scientific Truth.</p></div2><div2 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beautiful lawns" TEIform="index"/>BEAUTIFUL LAWNS</head><p TEIform="p">Is there any intelligent Believer that does not admire a neatly kept lawn; whether the lawn
                            be at home or abroad ? A short article on the subject might not be out of place, among the
                            readers of our monthly, from one who has devoted a good deal of labor from his own muscles
                            in that direction. Our family Order, when obeyed by the inmates of our communities, is a
                            protection from the accumulation of unsightly rubbish in our dooryards, by disallowing
                            liquids or garbage to be thrown out of the windows, to lodge around the house. I claim to be
                            an admirer of the beautiful, but, have never yet been able to see beauty in ever so choice a
                            flower or shrub left to grow up surrounded with coarse rank weeds, or to be choked with
                            grass. Nothing of an earthly nature have I more admired than those palace-like residences,
                            with their neatly appointed lawns, which may be found along Euclid street, Cleveland. It may
                            be said these are the homes of the merchant-princes, who have made fortunes by banking,
                            merchandising and other speculations, which our faith and religious lives debar us from,
                            therefore, we may not hope to have such beautiful lawns. Admitted, but does that debar us
                            from improvement ? Sometime since I was one of a company who made an extensive journey among
                            our societies, and although most of the families were well off, for comfortable and even
                            elegant dwellings and shops ; yea, and some very good frame country barns, quite up with the
                            general improvement of the neighborhood, yet the dooryards were not quite as neat, for
                            Believers, as I could wish. There were flowers and shrubbery not well kept, that marred the
                            appearance of the dooryards rather more than they improved them. It is singular what an
                            influence our education has on us. One of our brethren — a man of taste and an appreciative
                            observer of nature, says to one of our old Deacons, who had been a pioneer in western life
                            and was educated to study the value of cows and hogs, — Brother Jacob, do you hear that bird
                            sing ? Jacob listened, but the merry twitter of the little songster was not sufficient to
                            arrest the good Deacon's attention. They passed along to the piggery, where a little grunter
                            had got fast in the fence where he had been trying his ingenuity to shift his quarters.
                            Brother Jacob do you hear that pig squeal ? O ! yea, I can hear that. Just so is it with
                            most persons, who arrange a home. They have eyes to see and ears to hear, and faculties to
                            arrange for the important details, but the polish they do not seem capable of putting on,
                            nor of appreciating. Some people will go to any amount of expense in building a beautiful
                            mansion, but their taste, in out-buildings and laying off grounds, is wofully deficient. We
                            say our predecessors did not attain to all that was true, and we might admit neither did
                            they attain to all the knowledge in the world of beauty. Nay, they had their work to do and
                            did it well and faithfully, and it is our privilege to not only follow the beaten track they
                            pursued, but to progress beyond. I can see no godliness in slovenliness nor untidiness,
                            whether it be in the house, on the farm, or among the rough weeds in the dooryard. It is
                            surprising, what one brother, with a refined taste, could accomplish in his spare hours. At
                            first like our moral imperfections, he would have to give close attention, to not let the
                            weeds grow and go to seed. But a few years application would make his task a pleasurable
                            exercise. Hoping to draw attention to this subject, and thereby awaken a greater amount of
                            interest, in lawn dressing, was the object of the writer. And now, in conclusion, let us
                            keep the weeds from going to seed. And if we cannot afford time to keep the shrubbery and
                            flower-beds as they should be kept, let us <pb n="82" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> omit them, and let their
                            place be occupied by the green smooth grass.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Reynolds, W." TEIform="persName"/>Elder W. Reynolds, Union Village, O.</byline></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A century ago, it was said, 'The time has come for the Lord's House..." TEIform="index"/>A century ago, it was said, 'The time has come for the Lord's House...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/>Ed.</byline><p TEIform="p">[A century ago, it was said, " The time has come for the Lord's House — the Second Temple— to
                            be built." Henceforth, let the Courts of the Lord's House — the dooryards — be made
                            fruitful. The small fruits can be raised, in Believer's lawns, which have, hitherto,
                            remained a barren waste. The food of trees therein abounds, and ought to be utilized. The
                            blossoms, in spring — foliage, in summer, and fruit, in autumn, please the eye, comfort the
                            spirit and cheer the heart of all beholders and partakers. Thus, the product of combustion,
                            by fires and breathing, will be turned, from a curse, into a rich blessing. —Ed.]</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Law and gospel" TEIform="index"/>LAW AND GOSPEL</head><p TEIform="p">Along the highways of progress, whether civil or religious, lie the debris of old customs,
                            creeds, habits, forms and ceremonies — effete Gods and theologies. Their days of usefulness
                            are passed. The good they did possess has been used. Something better has taken their place.
                            Bodies corporate, civil, or religious, as well as individual, to maintain healthy inner life
                            and outward organization, must possess the power to eject effete matters, and grasp and
                            assimilate the present living truth. The forms, creeds, beliefs and Gods of the past, had,
                            in their day, a measure of vitality, which made them useful. Supplanted by higher truths and
                            forms, the old are obstructions only. What was truly glorious, is as vital for all future,
                            as in its first unfoldment. The Jews were said to be a people of types and shadows. Very
                            remarkable types they were. Let us glance at their code. To change their habits, their
                            tutelar deity keeps them in the wilderness forty years, on purely vegetable diet, which each
                            man, woman and child gathered for him and herself. With two exceptions, none but those born
                            on the journey enter Canaan. From landless slaves in Egypt, they become landholders in
                            Canaan. Every man and woman having a right in the soil, from which they could not be ousted,
                            except for a brief period. They are instructed how to cultivate the earth, what to eat, how
                            to raise it and how to cook it. They were forbidden intermarrying with surrounding nations,
                            and lending money — .product of labor—upon usury — eating of blood, fat and certain meats.
                            The results were — no sickness — no blight on crops, famine, caterpillar, unseasonable rain,
                            nor frost, no monopolies, no poor. Means are employed to accomplish purposes. A school, with
                            Moses for teacher, to educate souls for something higher — for Christ. After professedly
                            following Christ for 1800 years, in endless theologies and forms, is it not a wonder we do
                            not possess one of the characteristics of our preliminary education ? Would not the world be
                            better, to-day, with less false theology and more health — fewer lawless lawyers and more
                            equity — less monopoly and sexuality, and more honest toil with celibacy ? We are so
                            insatiably, sensually selfish, that there is hardly a living thing, on the earth or under
                            the water, which is not made to cater to our depraved appetites—consequently we are clad,
                            from head to foot, internally and externally, with loathsome and debilitating diseases. For
                            1800 years, we have been building grand theological castles for our souls, in eternity, and
                            sending our poor bodies to present perdition. Theological systems have, one after another,
                            crumbled away. Temples, built on sandy foundations, have toppled over. Is it not about time
                            to dig down to the rock and make our foundation sure and permanent in physiological truth,
                            before we attempt another structure in the air — the Temple of the second degree. In other
                            words—if we want Christ, the higher educator, had we not better, first, pay more attention
                            to Moses, our original schoolmaster 1 In the name of common sense, let us learn and remember
                            our A, B, C, in earthly things, if we would have the ethics and higher classics of Religion.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Smith, Thomas" TEIform="persName"/>Thomas Smith, Canaan, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Letters from the East" TEIform="index"/>LETTERS FROM THE EAST</head><p TEIform="p">James M. Peebles in writing letters to the Banner of Light during his late protracted
                            journey, treats of the alleged impracticability of reformers and of Christian teachings
                            before the advent of Jesus, in this manner: Apollonus of Tyana, the rival of the Nazarene,
                            was a mediumistic " mendicant;" Cleanthes was a "vagrant;" Jesus "impracticable." These are
                            the frisky judgments of pert, mole-eyed men ! Seen from the slough of selfishness and
                            measured by a miser's standard, Jesus was decidedly impracticable. Listen : " Lay not up for
                            yourselves treasures on earth " — " When thou makest a dinner or supper, call not thy
                            friends, thy brethren, thy kinsmen, nor rich neighbors to the feast, but call the poor, the
                            maimed, the lame and the blind."—¦ Nothing to a vain externalist could be more
                            unnatural—nothing more egregiously impracticable to fashionable, pharisaic worldlings! The
                            beautiful hymn of Cleanthes to Jupiter, from which Paul quoted this to the Athenians— " For
                            we are also his offspring," will live on the page of poesy forever. And yet, poor,
                            kind-hearted Cleanthes, who gratuitously taught philosophy and religion, was, upon the
                            complaint of an envious and pompous Greek, brought before the tribunal of Arcophagus and
                            charged with having no visible means of support. Shadow-days have their
                            compensations—justice is ultimately done. The moral teachings of Jesus and Cleanthes' hymn
                            are in literature immortal, while the names and memories of their persecutors are rotting to
                            nothingness in a resurrectionless oblivion. Jesus was born a peasant. Mary was gjod and
                            pure-minded. Joseph was a country carpenter. Judea, geographically insignificant and
                            numerically small, was at this time in a condition of political and religious decadence. The
                            whole land had nothing to inspire faith. Its Shekinah was eclipsed, its prophets dumb, and
                            its very memories like the embalmed mummies of Mizraim. An alien race sat upon the Syrian
                            throne. A Eoman official presided in the Judgment Hall. Roman soldiers paraded the streets,
                            Roman officers levied and collected the taxes, and Roman coins circulated in the markets.
                            The Jews at this period were narrow, selfish, proud. Hatred of Gentiles was a virtue ; help
                            for suffering foreigners little better than a crime. Religion was a form; fasts fashionable,
                            and a broad, cosmopolitan charity unknown. Jesus lacked early culture. John and James were
                            scholars. Though uneducated in dialectics and the classics, Jesus was nevertheless
                            clairvoyant, clairaudient and marvelously intuitional. Accompanied by a legion of heavenly
                            angels, he stood above human laws—a law unto himself— unique, emotional, incomparable. The
                            schools of the Rabbis being but conservatories of traditions, Jesus, inspired by his
                            spirit-guides, traveled in foreign countries—Egypt, Assyria, Persia, studying the mysteries
                            of the seers, and listening to the voices of ascended gods. He sat at the feet of religious
                            mystics, magi, and gymnosophists; Plato at the feet of orators and logicians. Jesus, whose
                            daily psalm was love, whose touch was a blessing, and presence a benediction, cultivated the
                            sympathetic, the self-denying, the religious faculties; but Plato the perceptive and the
                            philosophical. Centuries have rolled into the abysmal past. Now millions march under the
                            banner of the Cross, made memorable by the martyrdom of that religious enthusiast and
                            radical Palestinian reformer. The once thorn-crowned Jesus Christ is now companioned -with
                            those celestial angels, the presence of which make radiant the kingdom of God. The
                            pre-eminent greatness of Jesus consisted in his fine harmonial organization; in a constant
                            overshadowing of angelic influences; in the depth of his spirituality and love; in the
                            keenness of his moral perceptions ; in the expansiveness and warmth of his sympathies; in
                            his unshadowed sincerity of heart; in his deep schooling into the spiritual gifts of
                            Essenian circles and Egyptian mysteries; in his soul-pervading spirit of obedience to the
                            mandates of right manifest in himself; in his unwearied, self-forgetting, self-sacrificing
                            devotion to the welfare of universal humanity, and his perfect trust in God. CHRISTIAN
                            TEACHINGS BEFORE THE TIME OF JESUS CHRIST. The patriarch Abraham, when returning from the
                            "slaughter of the kings," convicted of the sin of war, met Melchisedec, King of Salem,
                            priest of the most high God, and received his blessing. Abraham, conscious of the
                            superiority of this soconsidered "heathen" King of Salem, King of Peace, paid tithes, giving
                            him at once "a tenth of all." But "who was Melchisedec?" Why, he was the king of some
                            contiguous nation—the peaceking of Salem, the baptized of Christ—in a word, a Christian!
                            This Christ-spirit, or Christ-principle, is truly "without father or mother, without
                            descent, having neither beginning of. days nor end of life—a continually abiding priest."
                            There were Christians in those pre-historic periods; Christians in golden ages past;
                            Christians long before the Old Testament patriarchs traversed the plains of Shinar, and
                            Christians who spoke the ancient and mellifluous Sanscrit. Many of the most genuine and
                            self-sacrificing Christians on earth to-day are Brahmins and Buddhists. All great souls,
                            under whatever skies, and in whatever period of antiquity, baptized by the Christspirit of
                            peace, purity and love, and illumined by the Divine Reason, were Christians ! Bigandet, the
                            Roman Catholic Bishop of Eamatha, and apostolic Vicar of Ava and Pegu, says (Life of Buddha,
                            p. 494): "There are many moral precepts equally commanded and enforced in common by both the
                            Buddhist and Christian creeds. It will not be deemed rash to assert that most of the moral
                            truths prescribed by the gospel are to be met with in the Buddhistic Scriptures. * * * In
                            reading the particulars of the life of the last Buddha, Gaudama, it is impossible not to
                            feel reminded of many circumstances relating to our Saviour's life, such as it has been
                            sketched out by the evangelists." St. Augustine, treating of the origin of Christianity,
                            affirms that— " The thing itself, which is now called the Christian Religion, really was
                            known to the ancients, nor was wanting at any time from the beginning of the human race,
                            until the time when Chi-ist came in the flesh; from whence the true religion, which had
                            previously existed, began to be called Christian: and this in our day is called the
                            Christian religion, not as having been wanting in former times, but having in latter times
                            received its name." The Emperor Hadrian, writing to Servianus while visiting Alexandria and
                            referring to the religion of the old Egyptians, assures us that— "The worshipers of Serapis
                            are also Christians; for T find that the priests devoted to him call themselves the bishops
                            of Christ." Clemens Alexandrinus, so eminent in the early church, admitted that— " Those who
                            lived according to the true Logos, were really Christians, though they have been thought to
                            be Atheists, as Socrates and Heraclitus among the Greeks." The Rev. Dr. dimming, of London,
                            in his discourse upon the " Citizens of the New Jerusalem," says: "It is a mistake to
                            suppose that Christianity began only eighteen hundred years ago; it began SHAKER AND 82 <pb n="83" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> 8HAKEEESS. 83 nearly six thousand years ago; it was preached amid the
                            wrecks of Eden." The learned Baboo Keshub Chunder Sen, whom I have met several times both in
                            London and Calcutta, said in a discourse just previous to leaving England for India: "The
                            Hindoo, therefore, who believes in God, is a Christian. If purity, truth and self-denial are
                            Christian virtues, then Christianity is everywhere where these virtues are to be found,
                            without regard to whether the possessors are called Christians. Hindoos or Mahometans. Hence
                            it comes that many Hindoos are far better Christians than manj; who call themselves so. The
                            result of my visit is, I came as a Hindoo, I return a confirmed Hindoo. I have not accepted
                            one doctrine which did not previously exist in my mind." This rational position lifts the
                            Christianity of the ages out of the slough of sect—out of the realm of the partial, and
                            places it upon the basic foundation of the universal. Seen from this sublime altitude, all
                            true resurrected celibate, communistic, Peace-practicing Spiritualists are Christians,
                            recognizing the evangelist's affirmation that "Christ had a glory with the Father before the
                            world was;" and, furthermore, that "Christ is the chief among ten thousand, and the one
                            altogether lovely!" A Christian, then, is one who has been baptized with the Christ Spirit,
                            and who lives in continued obedience to its inspirations.</p><byline TEIform="byline"> —<persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/>Ed.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Serious questions of the hour" TEIform="index"/>SERIOUS QUESTIONS OF THE HOUR</head><p TEIform="p">War — Peace. — " My kingdom is not of this world." Can Christians fight, or in any manner
                            abet war 1 Was there ever a Christian, from the days of Jesus, to the days of Geo.
                            Washington, and thence down to Gen. Grant, that could engage in physical warfare, in any
                            cause whatsoever ? Not one. " Whence come wars and fightings ? " Come they from causes that
                            grace the anti-Christian and disgrace the Christian profession ? Where can be the reason of
                            calling any member of a national army, " a Christian soldier 1" Taking the principle of
                            Christian peace into serious consideration, does not even the name of militia, still more
                            the practice, forfeit the title of Christian ? What can the people be thinking of, to admit,
                            for a moment, that any soldier in physical warfare can be a Christian ? Who are those who
                            aid and abet war ? Children of the world. Selfishness. — Does Christianity admit of private
                            property ? It does not; never did. Do Christian Churches permit distinctions of dress, diet,
                            or other comforts, among the members? Never. Are there any rich or poor Christians ? None
                            whatever. Why are there so many rich, and, particularly, why are there so many poor, in the
                            so-called Christian Churches of to-day ? Because such Churches are not Christian. Can these
                            be Brethren and Sisters of Christ while faring so unequally ? Never. Why are there no rich
                            nor poor in Christ's Church 1 The formerly rich, " lay down " their plenty; the formerly
                            poor do likewise with their poverty, and hence, share equally. Who, then, are the rich and
                            poor ? The Children of «?iresurrection, who will give up neither their riches nor poverty
                            for the gospel's sake. Who amass fortunes, and live in palatial residences? Unfeeling men
                            and women, erroneously termed Christians, who are careless of how many are made
                            correspondingly poor. Who are the mountains and valleys of scripture ? The rich and poor.
                            What is the mission of Christianity to such ? To bring down the mountains ; raise up the
                            valleys — inaugurate an equality — none possessed aught he could call his own. What
                            wonderful phenomena accompany conversions to Christianity ? Mine becomes Ours! Riches and
                            Poverty, with their miseries, disappear. Marriage — Celibacy. — Did Christians marry in the
                            days of Jesus ? Not at all, nor since. What did the married, to become Christians ? They
                            became as though they were not married — brethren and sisters. What did Jesus teach
                            concerning marriage ? That it was the practice of the children of the world, and did not
                            belong to the Heavens of Christians, on earth, or elsewhere. Who was and is the Resurrection
                            ? Christ. The Children of the Resurrection, of Christ, are first known by the fact that they
                            do not marry. Secondly, they do not sin any more. Thirdly, they are as the Angels. Do the
                            Angels marry, or engage in any lasciviousness 1 Can Christians ? The Primitive Christian
                            Church was a Celibate organization. Who have prostituted this Church to the filthiness of
                            the flesh ? The Children of this world. Wherein, alone, can genuine, unadulterated
                            Christianity obtain ? Among celibates only. Wherein do we observe the most marked contrasts,
                            between the early Church of the Apostles, and present, popular Christianity ? In the
                            reversal, by the latter, of the whole economy of the Primitive Church. In that, they were
                            unbound from marital relations, private property, fleshly lusts and their results. In
                            popular, so-called Christianity, these things are encouraged, practiced as sacraments;
                            results, "it would be a shame to speak of the things done by such in secret." Christians do
                            not marry; they retain, or regain, their virgin estate, and remain unspotted from the world.
                            Who then are Christians 1 Those who follow the Lamb — Christ — whithersoever this Spirit led
                            Jesus. From War, Marriage, Private Property, to the Higher Life.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/>Elder O. A. Lomas, Watervliet, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Communism" TEIform="index"/>COMMUNISM</head><p TEIform="p">And all that believed were together and had all things common. — Acts, 2: 44. While there are
                            many theories and notions too absurd for sound minds to credit, and others, to say the
                            least, quite doubtful, there still remain many facts, beyond all peradventure. These are at
                            once embraced by all truth loving souls. Of such is the scripture above quoted. Believers in
                            the days of Jesus were neither avaricious, nor monopolizers. Their love for each other cast
                            out all selfishness, and their possessions flowed together. Their tender and mutual regard
                            for the common weal, allowed no one to call aught he had his own, in an exclusive sense, "
                            but they had all things common." The candid reading of Acts, 2 : 4142 and 4: 31-37, must
                            convince all sane persons of these facts. Nor will any one dare to intimate that these
                            Christians did wrong in thus providing for the wants of each out of their common store. How
                            natural that their overflowing love for each other should thus flow their earthly goods into
                            an unselfish pile. In thus loving and living did they go beyond the Law and the Gospel ? Did
                            not, and does not each enjoin that we love our neighbor as ourselves ? How then could or can
                            such heart-searching injunctions be fulfilled short of doing just what these true Christians
                            did ? All this is conceded by those who ignore and indeed contravene their example. But they
                            say, the peculiar circumstances of these early disciples demanded this community of goods.
                            Such special pleaders, not to say quibblers, are of the earth earthy. Like the old Ox fable
                            between the Farmer and the Lawyer, they say " and if," clinging to the letter and sticking
                            to the Devil's maxim " circumstances alter cases." Destitute themselves of principle, such
                            pharisaical interpreters try hard to construe communism out of genuine Christians whose
                            unfeigned love has left us this heavenly example. Not by constraint of great destitution and
                            suffering did these beloved followers of the meek and lowly Jesus put their possessions at
                            the Apostles' feet; but from their supreme love to their Heavenly Father and Mother, and
                            their fellow Christians. He who, out of his own selfish heart, so misinterprets their
                            motives, is little short of a slanderer. Some say, " Persecutions and destitution compelled
                            the communistic practice." Commentators and Preachers thus try to interpret away this
                            blessed example and excuse the avarice of themselves and flocks. Persecutions never created
                            a peculiar people, zealous of good works. The profoundly learned and noble Paul has
                            testified that " the love of money is the root of all evil," that corrupt men suppose " that
                            gain is godliness ;" that such as " will be rich fall into temptation and a snare, and into
                            many foolish and hurtful lusts which drown men in destruction and perdition * * * piercing
                            them through with many sorrows." The cure for all this is not " temporary circumstances,"
                            but forsaking all for Christ's sake and the weal of his true followers. This is simply what
                            the Shakers do, which beyond all peradventure must be right. Did they refuse to do this they
                            would not do as Christ and his disciples did, and of course refuse to follow him. As the
                            principle is not only general but universal, all who fail to do likewise fail to love their
                            neighbor as they love themselves. In the next number I may show the blessings which flow
                            from having things in common.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, W." TEIform="persName"/>W. Perkins, Pleasant Hill, Ky.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Truth" TEIform="index"/>TRUTH</head><p TEIform="p">Truth in a qualified sense, may be considered as the foundation of the Universe. There are a
                            diversity of Truths; when classified, they would come under the head of Scientific, Moral,
                            Theological and Spiritual; each, and all, in their multifarious forms have a bearing upon
                            the human mind, and help to make the real man or woman. The Moralist seeks Truth, the
                            application of which will elevate man in his social relations, and make him a better citizen
                            — wiser — more just and honest in his dealings with his fellow men — temperate in all things
                            — sober and considerate in word and action, neither giving nor taking offense; but reducing
                            the beautiful theories which he has conceived to practice; i. e. be governed by the law of
                            right. The Scientist, in his department of labor, probes and searches the bowels of the
                            earth — dives into the depths of the Ocean — scans the illimitable stellar regions to obtain
                            knowledge and understanding of things hitherto hidden from mental, and optic vision ; thus
                            educating the race to a truer conception of the Divine mind. Without such knowledge, we
                            should have very crude and imperfect ideas of the earth under our feet, or of the heavens
                            above us. The Theologian, who is honest and sincere in his searchings after religious Truth,
                            and is prompted by noble sentiments and high aspirations to save immortal souls, will be
                            blest in his efforts, and help to progress humanity. But in this broad field, there has been
                            great diversity of opinions, many speculations and conflicting ideas, arising from different
                            organisms, being constitutionally diverse in modes of thought, and the capacity to
                            comprehend spiritual Truth, which is ever developing and revealing new forms of life and
                            beauty, through psychological forces. Hence we find some theological disputants forming
                            Deities after their own modes of thought, having parts and passions like themselves; and
                            creating a system as contradictory, as it is inconsistent ; representing God as being at one
                            time moved by love ; at another time by anger, jealousy, moods and tempers which we would
                            hardly be willing to own that ourselves were governed by. If we judge of Deity by external
                            manifestations, we must conclude that He and She are the perfect embodiment of Wisdom <pb n="84" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 8HAKEE and Love in the broadest sense and most significant application.
                            The Father and Mother of the Universe of Mind and Matter. Truth, like precious gems lie
                            scattered here and there to be gathered and appropriated by whomsoever found. Real religious
                            spiritual Truth which flows from the deep emotional and devotional feelings of the soul, and
                            reaches to the inner realms of divine light and life rises above and is superior to all
                            other truth — or it is the great center to which all other truths converge. There is Power
                            in it, which few have as yet even dreamed of — a power emanating from the throne of Deity !
                            and who shall withstand its mighty influence 1 It will eventually progress humanity to the
                            condition, and position in the scale of being, that they were created to occupy — Lords of
                            creation — ruling, not by animal'force, but through love, which is the most potent force
                            known in the realm of mind. It will subdue all opposing forces in its course of action, till
                            God shall finally be all in all—the center and circumference — the Alpha and Omega. Blessed
                            f orevermore shall be this power that permeates all things animate and inanimate ! To it we
                            bow in reverence and filial love. With Truth for our motto we will march on to perfect
                            victory ; and love shall be one of our guiding stars in our onward progress home to God.
                            Love's a fountain deep and pure ; Love will make us firm and sure; Love will banish every
                            wrong, Love we'll make our constant song. Hail all hail! the pow'r of Love, Wafted from the
                            spheres above, Joining every heart in one, Father, mother, daughter, son. May we ever keep
                            in view How this love creates anew Every trusting, pleading soul, Under its benign control.
                            It doth brighten as our sight, Opes to catch new rays of light 'Mid the changing scenes of
                            life 'Mid the conflicts and the strife. Love shall ever be my theme ; Blessed pow'r on which
                            to lean : And on this consecrated spot, I give this pledge, refuse it not.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Rayson, Timothy" TEIform="persName"/>Timothy Rayson, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Strong drink" TEIform="index"/>STRONG DRINK</head><p TEIform="p">Beloved Editok.—I was led to the follow ing thoughts by reading, in a late journal, an
                            estimate of the extent of the " curse " by the retail traffic of ardent spirits in the
                            United States and Territories in 1873, as follows: " Number of places licensed to sell
                            intoxicating drink, 150,000 ; persons employed in those ' hells,' 300,000; annual cost of
                            liquor to satisfy and increase depraved appetites, $400,000,000! The same author estimates
                            the number of clergymen and school-teachers in the country at 200,000." Thus, while one
                            class are laboring to advance the people in moral and spiritual life, the other, and by far
                            the greater portion, are plying the work of Death ! Now, when it is considered that the
                            above estimate is based upon the amount of money expended for liquor retailed, which
                            probably does not include more than one-half the amount sold, and when we reflect that the
                            time lost, fines paid, etc., would amount to as much more, the enormous waste of money
                            yearly, for that which produces only evil and crime, is truly appalling! This hydra monster
                            (intemperance), besides sending thousand of people to prison and a drunkard's grave, reduces
                            thousands of children to a state worse than orphans, and spreads misery, disease, crime and
                            premature death throughout the country! Truly, " the sword hath slain its millions; strong
                            drink, its tens of millions." If people will not be moved by the moral and social aspects of
                            the case, will they not heed the pecuniary loss ? Think of it, all ye who yield to the
                            seductive influence of the " cup " of Devils, inflaming your brain with deadly poison! Think
                            of it, O! ye guzzlers who complain of enormous taxation and " hard times," and find the
                            remedy for the burdens you complain of in your own hands.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt, Enfield, Conn.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, August 23, 1874" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, Aug. 23,1874</head><p TEIform="p">Brother Daniel Orcutt : You say, " If you keep your thoughts pure, and bring them nto
                            complete subjection to the obedience of Christ — God — Good — then will your life be
                            blameless.'" Beloved counselor, if every young person in Zion, reaped as much benefit from
                            your contribution in the August S. &amp; S., as I did, you would have cause to rejoice
                            that you had written to such good effect. I thank you for it from the bottom of my heart, I
                            love the spirit that prompted you to write it. I read it carefully over and over again, and
                            finally came to the conclusion that it had been written especially for my benefit. I am
                            eighteen years of age, and have been among Believers some seven months. My experience here
                            and elsewhere tells me, that it is harboring evil thoughts and imaginations, that prove
                            disastrous stumbling blocks to the youth of Zion. The young and untraveled are apt to pride
                            themselves on their deliverance from temptation, and not to hold their calling with
                            sufficient sacredness, forgetting the duty they owe to those who have done so much to create
                            and sustain the pure atmosphere into which they have been providentially brought. After
                            having been here long enough to conquer and get the ascendency of some bad habits, which
                            they never should have acquired; they begin to feel as if they had done about all that was
                            to be expected of them, and then they ruminate after this manner. All praise to me ! for the
                            manly way in which / have delivered myself from vice. I have now so fully recovered myself
                            that the Devil can never reclaim me; therefore I can read any book, paper or pamphlet
                            without its injuring me. Satan knows our weakest points and there he directs his power. I am
                            sorry to say I am stating my own case ; but, I think human nature is much alike all over. To
                            be continually cultivating a simple, lowly, dependent, and thankful feeling, is, I find,
                            youth's surest safeguard against impure imaginations. Pledging myself to be more watchful,
                            and thankful to you for your counsel to " Youths of Zion," I am happy to sign myself One of
                            them.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Gorham, Theodore" TEIform="persName"/>Theodore Gorham, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Who are Christians?" TEIform="index"/>WHO ARE CHRISTIANS ?</head><p TEIform="p">None but those who follow Christ in the regeneration. Jesus said, " Take my yoke upon you and
                            learn of me, for I am meek and lowly of heart, and ye shall find rest to your souls." A
                            beautiful promise, to such as wish to become meek and lowly, take up a daily cross and live
                            the life of Christ and the Apostles. We learn of Christ that to become his disciples, we
                            must come out from the world, forsake the lust of the flesh, the lust of the eye and the
                            pride of life. These are of the world. We believe the Saviour meant what he spake when he
                            said," Except a man forsake all that he hath he cannot be my disciple." Again " Except a man
                            forsake father, mother, wife and children, houses and lands, and his own life also, he
                            cannot be my disciple." The Apostle said, " We look for a New Heaven and a New Earth,
                            wherein dwelleth righteousness." Generation, husband and wife, with selfishness, pertain not
                            to the New Heaven. There is no half-way station between generation and regeneration. All are
                            living in one element or the other. Christ came to establish a new principle, that of loving
                            our neighbor as ourselves. This is the test of discipleship. There is, in the world, what
                            passes for love—but with more propriety, it might be called by another name —lust. We read "
                            Old things shall be done away, and all things become new" —of God. The marriage relation, as
                            it generally exists, is as old as when Adam and Eve, in disobedience, begat Cain. Poor,
                            frail humanity has, by similar means—disobedience—been raising Cains ever since. Christ
                            comes as a refiner—to cleanse, purify and make us fit Temples of the Holy Spirit. Do some
                            choose darkness, rather than light ? Why ? Is it because their deeds are evil, and they
                            prefer to do evil ? They, who are in the light, love the light, that it may be manifest,
                            their works are wrought in God. Christians are called to be light to the world—to have no
                            fellowship with works of darkness. The writer has heard some, who claim to be Christians,
                            say—" I sin daily." I didn't dispute them—nor do I dispute Jesus, when he says, " He that
                            committeth sin is of the devil." As none can serve two masters, the devil must have the
                            first claim to all sinning Christians. " With the heart man believeth—with the mouth
                            confession is made, unto salvation." If there be any, who can't cease sinning, is it not
                            because they have not made honest confession, of past sins, and repented of them ? By honest
                            confession, in the Divinely appointed Order, we receive power to say, " Get behind me, satan
                            "—and are obeyed. To Purity-loving minds, the way is open, to Salvation from sin.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Maybe, Simon" TEIform="persName"/>Elder Simon Maybe, Hancock, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The relations of friendship that have been so long and steadfastly maintained between the                                 Canadian                                 Indians..." TEIform="index"/>The relations of friendship that have been so long and steadfastly maintained...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The relations of friendship that have been so long and steadfastly maintained between the
                            Canadian Indians and the Colonial government were given fresh and gratifying prominence by
                            the recent visit of Earl Dufferin, the Governor-General of the dominion, among them. The
                            respectful, even affectionate reception given him at Ookneeka by 3,000 industrious,
                            intelligent, well-fed and happy Indians, who, having been established in certain definite
                            rights and privileges had long trusted the power that guaranteed them, was a strong contrast
                            to the suspicion and hate born of our contradictory American policy, which is every day
                            getting us deeper and deeper into trouble and complication. He went among them to show the
                            personal interest he took in all classes coming under his administration, and renew those
                            pledges that had been so long and so faithfully kept. He assured them that they should not
                            be violently forced into the white man's rigid mode of life, but mapped out for them an
                            attractive path of peaceful progress, and pointed to a higher plane of development which in
                            time he expected they would reach. The comfortable and contented condition in which he found
                            his wards was a refutation of the idea that the Indians are incapable of civilization, and a
                            rebuke to those who hold it. While Lord Dufferin was travelling among the red men of his
                            dominion, noting their condition for himself, and giving them good advice, the President of
                            the United States was on a junketing trip, and the National forces were prospecting among
                            the Black Hills, where they had no business, inasmuch as they constructively broke faith
                            with the Indians by being there, and unnecessarily made enemies where the English policy
                            would long ago have found friends. </p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The advocates of vegetarianism make out a plausible case..." TEIform="index"/>The advocates of vegetarianism make out a plausible case...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The advocates of vegetarianism make out a plausible case for their theory. They
                                    say the Scotch and Irish contrive to breed some of the finest specimens of men and
                                    women in the world on vegetable diet, and we have heard it stated that the Scotch
                                    have shown symptoms of degeneration in cases where they have abandoned the
                                    oldfashioned oat-meal porridge in favor of the modern dietary of butcher's meat and
                                    tea. Again, the Finns, who are mostly vegetarians in ttieir diet, are a well-grown
                                    race, while the flesh-eating Laplanders, inhabiting the same climate, are almost
                                    dwarfs. Further, it is claimed that vegetarians enjoy especial immunity from
                                    sickness, and are rarely if ever attacked by epidemic disease. The adoption of
                                    vegetarianism puts an end at once to much of the torture inflicted on the brute
                                    creation, the bleeding of calves, the crimping of cod, the skinning of eels, the
                                    boiling alive of shell-fish, besides all the more legitimate butchery of the
                                    slaughter-house ; and it saves people from the risk of illness produced by eating
                                    tainted or diseased meat.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Golden age" TEIform="index"/>Golden Age.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Drunkenness" TEIform="index"/>Drunkenness.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Things are no doubt bad as regards the vicious indulgence in stimulants, and
                                    seemingly worse they grow as the means of expenditure become more plentiful, and the
                                    more idle time is at disposal. But in such ind.ulgence there is no particular
                                    novelty. Excesses in gindrinking became alarmingly prevalent in England about 1735,
                                    followed by agonizing poverty and wretchedness. Listen to what Smollett says of the
                                    period: " The populace of London were sunk into the most brutal degeneracy by
                                    drinking to excess the pernicious spirit called gin, which was sold so cheap that
                                    the lowest class of the people could afford to indulge themselves in one continued
                                    state of intoxication, to the destruction of all morals and order. Such a shameful
                                    degree of profligacy prevailed that the retailers of this poisonous compound set up
                                    painted boards in public, inviting people to be drunk for the small expense of one
                                    penny; assuring them that they might be dead drunk for two-pence, and have straw for
                                    nothing. They accordingly provided cellars and places strewed with straw, to which
                                    they conveyed those wretches who were overwhelmed with intoxication. In these dismal
                                    caverns they lay until they recovered some use of their faculties, and then they had
                                    recourse to the same mischievous potion; thus consuming their health and ruining
                                    their families, in hideous receptacles of vice, resounding with riot and
                                    execration."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Chamber's journal" TEIform="index"/>Chamber's Journal</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="85" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakeress: meed" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERESS: MEED</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">11 One generation passeth away, and another generation cometh." Generations that have passed,
                            and are passing away, have made their records. Would that all might have as truthful
                            testimonials of a virtuous and godly life — of strong faith in God — and of the increasing
                            revelation of His will to humanity, as our aged friend and sister, to whom we gladly give
                            space in our columns to speak for herself. Thus would Order and Justice be established in
                            all things pertaining to body and soul. She has spent a long life of usefulness, in being
                            good and doing good. Already she is reaping what she has sown ; peace and blessing is her
                            just inheritance. When the lamp of life shall cease to burn, and she lies down upon her
                            couch to the " sleep that knows no waking " here, we are confident she will be gathered to
                            her fathers and mothers in the land of souls, there to continue the life which she commenced
                            in the earth sphere. Such spirits never die.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ayer, August 16, 1874" TEIform="index"/>Ayer, August 16th, 1874</head><p TEIform="p">Dearly Beloved Bldress Antoinette : As I have been deeply interested in reading the richly
                            stored columns of the Shaker and Shakeress, I feel that it will not be showing due respect
                            to one who has labored and toiled so assiduously as you have, in spreading light, not to
                            comply with your request, however incompetent I may feel to do so. The development of new
                            Truths concerning the Millennial Order, is a subject that is inexhaustible ; but those
                            without the pale of Shakerdom do not seem far enough advanced to comprehend them; and those
                            subjects, within the scope of their understanding, are, with me, nearly exhausted. There is
                            one, however, though of very ancient date, which absorbs my feelings at present and one
                            which seems to demand more attention than ever has been given it. We read that " God shall
                            bring every work into judgment, with every secret thing, whether it be good or whether it be
                            evil." This being the case, we would ask, is it duly considered, even by those who intend to
                            walk uprightly ? Are there not many things said and done that would be withheld, were it
                            realized that a penalty was attached to each word and act ? Would hard and unkind feelings
                            be harbored if it was borne in mind that they must be repented of ? Were the silent monitor
                            within permitted to control, should we behold so much violence and fraud as now ? Would poor
                            widows, orphans, sewing girls, etc., be toiling early and late for a mere pittance, scarcely
                            sufficient to supply them with food and clothing, of the poorest kind, and often be
                            compelled to wait even for this till starvation stares them in the face ? Or, would there be
                            so many of the laboring class out of employ, whose families are suffering for the
                            necessaries of life, if those who now withhold from them the means of subsistence were to
                            realize the consequence of refusing their aid ? And where would be those dens of vice and
                            crime, in a few years to come, if those who are now approaching them would stop and reflect,
                            that for every sinful act they must yet be brought to judgment? Is it not time for
                            conscience to be more fully awakened on this all-important subject, and to feel that those
                            passages of scripture relating to it are something more than empty words ? Let each one ask
                            his or her own conscience before speaking or acting, especially on matters of importance :
                            Will this be right ? Am I about to speak or act from motives of Truth and Uprightness, or
                            from sinister or selfish motives, and thereby make for myself work for repentance ? With a
                            daily consciousness that a true record is kept of all our thoughts, words and actions, how
                            can we act contrary to the Divine monitor — conscience ? To do so must show a great lack of
                            wisdom and forethought, for be assured, that all souls will find, either in this life or
                            that beyond, that every thought, word and action of their earth life is engraved on the
                            tablets of their hearts, as with the point of a diamond, and from this record will they be
                            judged, their own consciences hearing witness for or against them. For a further proof of
                            the foregoing statement, please call to mind the various accounts of those who have been
                            resuscitated from drowning, or rescued from immediate death, and it will be found that their
                            whole lives were spread out before them instantaneously, even to the most trifling
                            incidents, which had passed from memory for years. I am not of the number who are sitting by
                            the wayside, waiting for God and our Heavenly Parents to do some great work for us, but am
                            laboring to keep my bark so that the sail can catch every little breeze that will help to
                            waft me onward and upward. I hail with joy all true reform, whether physical or spiritual,
                            feeling that one is closely allied to the other; and although too far advanced in life to
                            make much progress in the former, I believe it will not be long ere the progressive portion
                            of society, both in and out of Zion, will see the necessity of a more simple mode of living,
                            and wholly eschew all stimulating food and drink. I do not believe we were made to subsist
                            on animal food. Vegetables and pure water were designed by our Creator for our sustenance.
                            And before we are fully re-instated in Divine favor we shall have to return to this as well
                            as all other laws which God has given for the benefit of the race. But they are so fallen
                            that they must be led, step by step, out of the state into which they have been plunging
                            themselves for centuries. And in this is manifest God's goodness and love ; for should all
                            the digressions from the true standard — Divine Code — be at once presented before its view,
                            no soul would have either strength or courage to even make an effort to rise. I rejoice to
                            see light so fast increasing among mankind, preparing many for millennial harvesting. God
                            has commenced His work of emancipation, through His agents, whom His angels are daily
                            inspiring with more light and knowledge of His laws, and this work will continue and
                            increase till all souls are brought to the knowledge of the truth, and set free from the
                            shackles of anti-christian superstition and darkness. I see the stones preparing in the
                            mount to build up her temple. They will yet be brought together without the sound of " axe
                            or hammer," the clashing of discordant elements. Our foundation is sure. But is it not very
                            essential what materials are used in rearing the fabric? Must not such be selected as will
                            stand the storms and tempests of coming ages ? These are questions which bear heavily upon
                            my mind; but I forbear, knowing my earthly pilgrimage must soon close, having now passed my
                            four score years ; and I would far rather depart than remain to clog the wheels of true
                            progression in any of its evolutions.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bathrick, Eunice" TEIform="persName"/>Eunice Bathrick</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gates of Heaven" TEIform="index"/>"GATES OF HEAVEN."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Offord, Ann; Byrdsall, Charlotte; Anderson, Martha J.; Soule, Melissa; and Cleveland, Margaret" TEIform="persName"/>One of the items, of the enjoyable entertainment, in the Pine Grove, on the border of the
                            beautiful little Lake in the land of Canaan, at the annual Social Gathering of the Novitiate
                            Order of Mt. Lebanon, August 19th, was the following Colloquy by and between Ann Offord,
                            Charlotte Byrdsall, Martha J. Anderson, Melissa Sotjle, and Margaret Cleveland.</byline><p TEIform="p">Martha. — What is Religion? has often been asked. Is it strange that such query should arise
                            in intelligent minds, when there has ever existed such a contrariety of opinions respecting
                            its true spirit ? History abounds with records of bitter strife, animosity and devastating
                            wars, all in consequence of difference in religious views. One might judge that what is
                            claimed as the religious principle in human nature, is only a power to awaken, rather than
                            to control and subdue, the gross passions and propensities. It would seem that there is no
                            zeal so ardent, no spirit so unrelenting, as that which is inspired through preconceived
                            ideas of what is right, and a desire to control the consciences of others. Such intense
                            fervor has produced the torture-room — the gibbet — and the rack ; while thousands of
                            innocent martyrs have perished in the flames of its diabolical wrath. With this view of what
                            has been termed Religion, is it to be wondered at that there are so many infidels and
                            skeptics? Ann. — Not at all; but Religion has a broader basis than mere belief. It is a soul
                            element, the outgrowth of high ennobling faculties — Veneration, Spirituality and Hope.
                            Through Veneration we seek some object for worship ; through Spirituality comes holy
                            aspiration for goodness — a desire to become like our ideal — while Hope ever presents the
                            prospect of immortality and blissful existence. Char. — Just here we must make a distinction
                            between Theology and Religion. In reviewing ancient and modern history, we clearly perceive
                            that all conflict and strife have arisen from a difference in belief, and not from the truly
                            religious element in humanity. Melissa.— That is a proper consideration; a theme that has
                            more, or less engaged heart and mind from the earliest history of our race. We need to have
                            clear conceptions of truth, which will enable us to consider that human beings, in their
                            varied degrees of intellectual and spiritual progress, naturally entertain antagonistic
                            ideas of God. Without the light of revelation we mistake the letter for the spirit,
                            proselyting zeal for virtue ; a hatred of persons for love of God. Margaret.— All forms of
                            life have their progressive stages of growth and development. Thus it is with the human
                            race. From low organisms, have been evolved increasing degrees of intellectuality and
                            spirituality, through which we trace higher and higher forms of religion,— proving that
                            Reason and Conscience combine in true conceptions of the Divine Mind, as manifested in
                            higher life and being. The uncivilized and barbarous races still cling to their crude
                            representations of Deity ; and their forms of worship are expressive of sensual and
                            passional emotion. Ann. — Heart-sickening are the scenes of idolatrous worship, described in
                            history. People were seemingly led by blind ignorance,without the aid of reason and
                            knowledge ; the sensual dynasty instead of morality and virtue reigned supreme. Martha — The
                            Feticism of Western Africa lingers to-day, while its intellectual antipode, <pb n="86" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 86 8HAKEE manifested in the highest type of scientifically enlightened manhood
                            — Tyndall — perceives God as the great unfathomable, without bound or limit, the grand
                            centre of inextinguishable light and glory, whence proceeded life, love, and the continuous
                            creations of mind and. matter ; yet, impersonal. To Believers, the Christ Spirits reveal God
                            as Wisdom and Love — Our Heavenly Father and Mother. Melissa. — From Polytheism to
                            Monotheism we can trace the progress of thought and an increasing degree of revelation. As
                            far back as Abraham we read that his mission was to introduce the worship of the one true
                            God, and to break up the forms of idolatry then existing. This he did not effectually
                            accomplish ; for, notwithstanding his faithful and earnest exhortations, even his relatives
                            clung to their idolatrous worship, and for many years after, Mecca was the only place where
                            the doctrine of one God was taught. " Many worshiped the spirits of the stars whom they
                            called the sons and daughters of God." To them God was an abstraction. The Gods of their own
                            creation were the popular objects of worship. Margaret.— This illustrates the tenacity with
                            which mankind cling to traditional ideas. Truth has ever battled her way through error's
                            legions, but the ground she has gained is clear, and as there is a " growth in grace " and
                            in reason, her way is made easier. Char.— Many sins in all ages, have been disguised under a
                            profession of Eeligion. Under that cloak Sodom sinned. David, called the man after God's own
                            heart, gloried in sexual indulgence — and Solomon, with all his wisdom and knowledge,
                            reveled in carnality. Greece, with her learning, reared temples which were devoted to
                            infamous purposes, and Rome added to the list by her degrading festivities. England, also,
                            with her Church and State government, has produced a score of ignoble rulers, like the
                            eighth Henry, and her history is stained with the blood of martyrs, who were sacrificed for
                            what was deemed heresy. Their religion was a prostitution of virtue. The God they worshiped
                            sanctioned war. His very breath would blight the germs of true religon. Ann.— The so-called
                            Christian nations of Europe, who profess to follow Jesus — the highest ideal of perfected
                            life—whose example has illumined many sin-darkened souls — are warring nations; and their
                            religious history, instead of wearing the laurels of peace and purity gained by the self
                            Conqueror, is blackened with crime. Their religious life and practice, fall below the
                            standard of the Buddhists and Brahmins of the East, for they do not stand in warlike
                            antagonism with brethren of the same faith, nor of any other faith. Martha.— I have been
                            interested in reading some accounts of the origin of the three great Religions of the East,
                            Brahmanism, Buddhism and Mohammedanism. Around those strongly fortified systems cluster much
                            that is traditional and legendary ; but their great central truths are effective in binding
                            upon their devotees certain moral and religious obligations, which have elevated them above
                            gross idolatry, and, in some respects, such as honesty in dealing, and pure morality, they
                            eclipse many sects of professing Christians. Not that their faith is superior, but their
                            practice is more in accordance with their faith. Margaret,— We will here repeat the eight
                            steps arising from the four sublime truths that form the basis of Buddhism, which when
                            perfectly attained, the soul reaches that inexpressible condition called " Nirvana," the
                            meaning of which cannot be explained, but evidently conveys the idea of perfection — an
                            inner consciousness of rest from conflict — corresponding with the Christian's heaven, or
                            kingdom of God. The first step is Right belief, or the correct faith. Second. Right
                            judgment, or wise application of that faith, to life. Third. Right utterance, or perfect
                            truth, in all we say and do. F'ourth. — Right motives, or proposing always a proper end and
                            aim. Fifth. Right occupation, or an outward life not involving sin. Sixth. Right obedience,
                            or faithful observance of duty. Seventh. Right memory, or a proper recollection of past
                            conduct. Eighth. Right meditation, or keeping the mind fixed on permanent truth. Ann.— I
                            think that would be a good code of morals for any people, whatever their profession. Some
                            physiological truth was also inculcated in their system. The application of the
                            unconditional command, " Thou shalt not kill," has much to do with softening the manners of
                            the Mongols. They are not a fierce people, and are decidedly opposed to war. Melissa.— There
                            is indeed much of interest in the history of those religious Powers. In some respects they,
                            who call themselves Christians, may learn of them. We cannot pass over the fact that
                            Buddhism, with its errors and superstitions, has neither deceived, nor persecuted — has not
                            formed inquisitions, nor possessed and cultivated feelings of antipathy toward those who
                            profess other faiths — believing that all manifestations of Religion are but an outgrowth of
                            one true faith. Char.— " The heart of man is not innately vile." It only awaits the law of
                            progress, and the increasing light of revelation, in physiological, scientific and spiritual
                            truth, to lead it from the contracted cell state of ignorance, to the pure light of true
                            Religion. It is pleasant to review the history of the past, and gather the gems of Wisdom
                            and Goodness, which the Spirit of Truth has scattered along the pathway of human progress.
                            As the poet beautifully and truthfully expresses it:— " God sends his teachers unto every
                            age, To every clime and every race of men, With revelations fitted to their growth And shape
                            of mind ; nor gives the realm of Truth Into the selfish rule of one sole race. Therefore
                            each form of worship that hath swayed The life of man, and given it to grasp The master key
                            of knowledge. Reverence, Enfolds some germs of goodness and of right." Martha. — It is true
                            that every age and race have had their inspired prophets and teachers; this is God's method
                            of improving mankind. No truth that has ever been revealed will be lost; it may drop off its
                            old forms, but will be re-incarnated in new ones, fitted to the growth and comprehension of
                            the minds of men. Thus we trace Infinite Wisdom and Love working their way through the
                            frailties — passions — conscious longings and aspirations of finite beings. Ann. — Under the
                            laws of evolution, Scientists tell us that species of animals and genera of plants have been
                            perfected ; that the earth is going through constant changes from lower to higher forms of
                            life. A corresponding condition must exist in the higher realm of mind and spirit; for the
                            worlds of mind and matter stand in a correlative position, and are acted upon by the laws of
                            causation, proceeding from the primal fountain of all progress. There is no retrogression.
                            Life moves spirally, ever up and up. Change, growth and development are stamped on all
                            created things. Margaret. — Then, it is by the law of evolution that we account for the
                            liberalizing influences which permeate society and give, to all, the unmolested right to
                            their own conscientious belief; for certainly we live in a time, when the eternal gates of
                            truth are ajar, and we catch glimpses of light which bespeak regenerated life in the
                            political, social and religious worlds. Melissa. — There is great need of reorganization,
                            and renovation, in all the departments of life. We have cause of gratitude, that much has
                            already been done to expand religious thought, and establish just civil government. We who
                            live under the blessing of Republican institutions, feel not the restrictions felt by those
                            whose lot is cast in lands where Church and State, combined, bear rule, crushing spiritual
                            freedom. It is evident there is a power a,t work, even in the old world, which will
                            silently, but effectually, burst the chains of tyranny that have so long fettered the minds
                            and consciences of men. Martha. —¦ It does not seem much like it, when we consider the
                            course that Russia has latelv taken with the Menonites. Char. — There will be turnings and
                            overturnings, and much injustice will yet be done; but the general aspect and signs, as they
                            appear, are encouraging. Margaret. — I was glad to hear that the great question which has
                            agitated the public mind for some time past, concerning the proposed sectarian amendment of
                            the Constitution, has been so wisely settled; evincing that those to whom it was referred
                            comprehended the evil that would result from the recognition of church creeds and dogmas, in
                            an infidel — materialistic — constitution. A constitution oblivious of religious sects.
                            Martha. — I wonder if Solomon ever had such complex questions to tax and perplex his
                            superior judgment. I think it requires great skill in this day to guide the helm of the Ship
                            of State, that she may not founder, and be submerged in the sea of political intrigue and
                            social problems. Ann. — That judicial decision will lift a great weight off the minds of
                            liberal reformers and freethinkers of our day. A few years ago it might have been decided in
                            favor of Sectarianism. But, thank God, the Seers of our time have had the moral courage to
                            lift their voices, and dip their pens in the living inspiration of truth — denounce the
                            error, and prevent the fatal step, which would inevitably have led to war and bloodshed. We
                            now rejoice in the happy consummation of their efforts for humanity's good. Melissa. — I
                            think modern Spiritualism has been a powerful wedge driven by an unseen hand, to split the
                            knotty questions of human rights and privileges — breaking up old forms — bringing forth
                            increasing revelations of truth, which are completely revising old orthodox conceptions of
                            the mystery of godliness, and of future rewards and punishments. Ann. — Spiritualism is
                            becoming popular. It has made rapid advances. We now hear of seances in royal palaces.
                            Eminent scientists after thorough investigation, fail to give proof against the genuineness
                            of its phenomena. Men of all professions, whose strength of mind and character give them
                            high position, have been convinced of its facts. Who can say unseen intelligences are not
                            effective in producing right impressions in reference to important questions which agitate
                            the public mind in regard to civil polity, as well as Religion ? Can we not see an
                            overruling power ir» the triumph of right so lately achieved ? One of the prophets foretold,
                            that in the latter day, " God would set up a kingdom which would never be destroyed," and
                            that it would be a refuge for all nations. How could such a kingdom exist except under an
                            infidel, or more properly, a materialistic, form of government ? Char.— It could not; but
                            there is another point I wish to refer to. Do we not observe that as Spiritualism becomes
                            popular, spiritual wickedness increases? While the doors are open to the spirit-world, and
                            there is free communication, all classes of spirits find access to mixed circles, and varied
                            conditions. It is written, When the sods of God came to worship, satan came also, clearly
                            indicating that where the avenues are open, evil seeks to find entrance. Thus has it been
                            through the long career of Spiritualism — the good and evil have ministered through
                            imperfect media. Those who, while on earth, knew only a life of sensuality, have not
                            quenched the fires of passion, by the dissolution of the body. They hover over and obsess
                            mortals, with carnal desires and soul-destroying doctrines ; and many, at the present time,
                            while under the power of diabolical influences, are bold in the assertion that it is right
                            to live in the unrestrained indulgence of the sexual functions, without regard to the law of
                            use, to conditions, seasons, or restrictive bonds of the matrimonial relation. Children,
                            too, are strengthened in the ways of self-destruction, until it would seem that the race is
                            hurrying into the vortex of sensuality. Margaret. — From a high moral and spiritual point of
                            observation, we can clearly discern the evil that is rolling over the earth, from this
                            source, like a mighty flood, and it should be a warning to us, to raise higher the unerring
                            standard of Purity, and to hold it with a still firmer grasp, that it may be preserved
                            untarnished through all conflicts, while AND <pb n="87" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> 8HAKBEESS. 87 the faithful
                            are contending with the dragon power — lust — which has drawn down so many of the stars of
                            the old heavens to darkness and sorrow. Martha. — Spiritualism has done a good work, and it
                            has had its evil phases, which it is right to consider. For want of proper guidance, many
                            have been led astray. If communication should be held with the living spirits of a century
                            ago — who boldly shook themselves from the chains of British tyranny, through sacrifice of
                            life and property — and wrote the immortal Declaration of Independence, while the burning
                            fires of freedom glowed in their souls; would there not be some stirring communications ?
                            Would it not be wise to employ Franklin (who is no doubt still active in his scientific
                            pursuits,) to establish an electric line of communication between some of the Congressional
                            courts in the Spirit world, and the Capitol of our great country, that an earthly government
                            may be established, under just legislation and sound policy, instead of bartering principles
                            for gold, and yielding the weight of national claims and duties to selfish aims and
                            purposes'? What a change would thus be wrought! Char.— That is true; Spiritualism, if
                            comprehended, would be of great value to the human race ; but it must be understood as a
                            Science, not as a Religion. It does not contain the power of salvation, but enlightens the
                            understanding—gives clear views of the inner state of existence — and imparts the hope of
                            salvation — It is the Angel of Light. See Rev. 18. Melissa.— I think that if Spiritism were
                            substituted for Spiritualism, it would better express the external revealments and marvelous
                            manifestations of psychical force, operative on material things. Margaret.— It would most
                            certainly. The question occurs to my mind, How is it that we make the assertion, that the
                            founders of our government were infidel, when history speaks differently ? Washington was
                            said to be a man of faith and prayer, and I have read many sketches of their lives, which
                            clearly indicate that they were possessed of deep religious feeling. Ann.— They may have
                            been deeply religious, and yet have been infidel to the popular forms of religious belief,
                            preferring that every one should give expression to his and her own conscientious opinions.
                            Martha.— There have always been those who were deemed irreligious, because they made no
                            profession of unity with church organizations, but whose lives, in reality, comported more
                            with goodness and truth, than many who weekly attend church, rehearse prayers, and
                            mournfully attest to the truth of being great sinners, yet change not their characters.
                            Char. —Cheerfulness is Religion's companion, and happy are they who are under her influence.
                            I believe we have all been more or less impressed with the sombre aspect of Religion, in our
                            early days. In attending the religious meetings of different denominations, even when a
                            child, if I saw any of the church members cheerful, I thought they should be lost in silence
                            and solemnity, or they were not living according to their profession. This was the effect of
                            an anti-christian education. Melissa. — We have all been under the same deadening dogmas ;
                            but many persons, who are brought up within the pale of the Church become infidel to its
                            views, when they arrive at an age to think, j udge and decide for themselves. Margaret. —
                            Truth gleams over the earth, and occasionally there are minds prepared to advance beyond the
                            common mould of thought. Such receive new revelations, and go before the people, like John
                            the Baptist, sowing seed, that shall perfect fruit for the Millennial harvest. Melissa.— It
                            is right that we should be prepared for the increase of truth, and recognize a growth of
                            mind in the outside world; but it would seem that the truly religious element is at a low
                            ebb. At least there is very little power of conviction at work in the hearts of the people,
                            at the present time. " The multitudes rush to and fro in quest of knowledge " and yet lack
                            that knowledge — wisdom — which saves from sin in its many destructive forms. Martha. — A
                            truly religious life, no vain ambition, nor tyrannical rule can overthrow ; as was proved by
                            Jesus, Mother Ann, Madame Guion, Fenelon, and many other bright lights, which the
                            persecutor's rage could not extinguish. Margaret. — Though many have been nobly devoted to
                            Truth, and have suffered for its sake, I would that there were many more to impart zeal for
                            holy things. The present generations seem destitute of energy and true fervor of spirit.
                            Their attention is turned to the external. Religion, with them, is theoretical, and assumes
                            the form of Sentimentalism, rather than practical virtue. Even among us, zeal — the true
                            Christ-baptism — that lifts above the vain and unreal, into the conscious realms of untiring
                            spiritual action, is, at times, deficient. Ann. — " Vanity of vanities " might be inscribed
                            on the present phase of life. " The lust of the flesh, the lust of the eye and pride of life
                            " have unlimited sway among the people. A distaste for enjoyment in truthful realities gives
                            the young a thirst for exciting pleasure — frivolous reading—false notions of
                            dress—stimulating diet — an altogether artificial mode of living. The primitive simplicity
                            of our forefathers is lost sight of, and consequently there is degeneracy and effeminacy.
                            Martha. — We cannot wonder at this. Could we accurately discern the signs of the times, we
                            should conclude we were about entering upon a new epoch. The revolutions in Science, presage
                            the upheaval of the spiritual elements. Ere long, a mighty wave of inspiration shall flood
                            the earth, awakening the latent germs of spirituality, and producing a revival — an
                            outpouring of the Spirit, that shall turn the tide of life into the channel of reality, and
                            effect a work of righteousness. Melissa. — The Religion greatly needed is strength to subdue
                            me and mine — the selfish principle in the human heart — to extirpate war and establish
                            peace — to create a sphere of universal love, from which shall emanate kindness, even toward
                            the animal creation; and wliicli will admit of no law in violation of equality and right.
                            Char. — Must history ever repeat itself in individuals, as well as nations? Shall the
                            inordinate thirst for power produce war and bloodshed, through all time ? Must life be
                            sacrificed for human sustenance, when God's beneficent hand has spread the fields, and given
                            the seed that will pi-oduce a golden harvest of precious grain, and luscious fruit, for
                            food, ample to supply the muscle and brain of those who earn their sweets? Must some toil
                            beneath the ban of poverty, beyond their strength, for a mere pittance, to sustain others in
                            luxury and idleness, because Mammon hath not elevated them to its standard ? These are the
                            questions which arise in the mind, when we behold the extremes of life, and the wrong usages
                            of society. Melissa.— When the higher and more spiritual forces control, those troubles will
                            cease. The elements of nature, when stilled beneath that power, will bring no more the
                            revolutions of error and sin. Evils will increase before that event. Society will feel the
                            full force of wrong doing; and arousing to a realizing sense of surrounding conditions,
                            will, by the help of the good Spirit effect a great change ; firstly by individuals
                            bettering their own lives. Ann.—" Lord what shall I do to be saved ? " is ever the cry of a
                            convicted soul. We may comprehend principles —theorize intellectually — and behold, afar
                            off, the glory and beauty of a life of virtue and goodness; but, unless the heart be touched
                            by the fire of truth, and a practical work of reformation be begun in the soul, we shall in
                            no wise realize the fulfillment of a perfected life. Margaret.— There are wise lessons of
                            instruction which we may gather, from the experience of preceding ages, and perfect by the
                            spirit of inspiration. Martha. — The gold and silver threads of inspiration and revelation,
                            are interwoven through the long woof of human experience. At no period of time has the
                            Divine Spirit left mankind entirely to the guidance of frail human nature. According to our
                            power and capacity, we are constituted guardians of goodness, and while we uplift the
                            standard of our day, and live to the law of obedience, we shall be as stars to guide others
                            to the truth, who in their turn will do likewise. Thus the car of Progress is slowly but
                            surely advanced toward the golden age of perfected knowledge — Religion. Melissa. — As we
                            believe, the time draws near, when many will be led to Mt. Zion, under spiritual awakening ;
                            should we not be more zealous in performing our own work, that we be not unfaithful stewards
                            in the house of God, nor have our birthright taken from us ? We have every opportunity for
                            spiritual growth and advancement, and of all people should be the most religious. According
                            to our light and understanding so will be our judgment. Margaret. — Religion is a theme on
                            which much has been said and written, yet comparatively few have comprehended its true
                            meaning, or practically lived out its spirit. Of all people, Believers are most favorably
                            conditioned to illustrate it in its full meaning, in the every day duties of life. According
                            to the precept, " Labor is worship and prayer," ours is a life religion. Ann. — And all may
                            possess this gospel, without money or price. They to whom we look as our exemplars in
                            virtue, meekness and every good grace, were poor. No outward advantages distinguished them
                            from the common people ; and no worldly honor gave them dominion. Their superiority was in
                            their life work ; their glory, that of the self-conqueror— their honor that which cometh
                            from God. Melissa. — It is well for all to consider for what end and purpose they are
                            living. Man's earthly existence is like a shadow flitting over the rainbow. As the ages
                            glide away, the sons and daughters of men, the youth in life's green spring, and they who go
                            in the full strength of years, the aged and the infant, shall one by one be gathered to the
                            land of souls. Life is uncertain; but wThen based upon true principles, we can brave the
                            storms and tempests that may come ; for Religion is our anchor ; and when we have finished
                            our work in time, angels will bear us in safety to our immortal home; and we shall rest in
                            the tranquillity and confidence of those " who wrap the drapery of their couch about them
                            and lie down to pleasant dreams." Char. — We appear and disappear, as sunbeams, through the
                            clouds. The thousands who walk the earth to-day will vanish as the dew. The plants that
                            blossom but to fade, have as firm claim on life as the proud monarch who sways the scepter
                            of power in the earth ; but through all life's changes, Religion is the hope of the human
                            heart. Martha. — The noble Athenian philosopher said to his disciple " He may bury my body,
                            but let him not think he buries Socrates." So in reviewing the past history of the race, we
                            see that Truth stands in the same relation to man that the Soul does to the Body. It has had
                            many forms, which have been subject to transmutation. But Truth — the very soul of existence
                            — remains the same, yesterday, now and forever. Genuine belief helps to form true modes of
                            thought; yet, however absurd any form of belief may appear to us, we are bound, in the name
                            of Religion, to respect every sincere opinion. Religion, whatever form it may wear—be it
                            enshrined in the mysticism of Heathen Mythology, or enthroned in ideals of pure Reason — we
                            should regard in the same reverent spirit. Margaret.— It has been said "there have been but
                            few voices, in the world, and many echoes." The same desires, questionings, aspirations and
                            hopes have moved the human heart and mind, only varying in form, according to the growth of
                            the ages. It is interesting to candid, reflective persons, to glean from the vast fields of
                            spiritual knowledge and experience precious seeds of Truth, to sow in the soil of their own
                            hearts, that it may by culture, bring forth a hundred fold of good, that they may have
                            wherewith to scatter blessings over the earth.</p></div2><pb n="88" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beams of light" TEIform="index"/>BEAMS OF LIGHT</head><p TEIform="p">1. When the glory of light beams over our way, From bright souls in regions above; The forms
                            of the near, the true and the dear, Who've pass'd from our sight, ere the day turn'd to
                            night, Are seen flitting round us in love. And when we are weary and worn with life-toil, We
                            feel their soft presence in peace. They brighten the hours, which ever are ours, To rightly
                            improve, as onward we move, To the land where sorrow will cease. "Tis thus we are
                            strengthened to journey below, O, gladly we walk by the faith of today, And bear with true
                            pleasure each care, And banish all darkness of mind, For bright is the thought, with
                            happiness fraught, Tor in that fair land, where the purified stand, Of communion sweet, when
                            the hriurs shall fleet, Our faith will be sight, and in its pure light, That hold us
                            earth-labor to share. "We'll crave not the joys left behind.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editor's Desk, August 19, 1874" TEIform="index"/>Editor's Desk, August 19, 1874</head><p TEIform="p">Dearly Beloved Mother Eunice — I have just read critically your letter and accompanying
                            article, of the 16th inst., to Eldress Ant'e. They impress me on this wise, that Eunice is a
                            genuine Shaker, who has the life of God in her own soul. A. child and sister of Mother Ann.
                            You have life in yourself as she had. You have not only heen baptized with the Christ
                            Spirit, but have traveled — increased with the increase of God. You have not gone to sleep
                            on the enchanted ground—'the success of the first cycle. You heard and obeyed the voice of
                            the first thunder — testimony. And now you hear the voice of the second thunder beginning to
                            sound. What a blessing to you! And what a blessing you are to the work of God in thus
                            connecting the past and the present — the first and second degrees. While it is unreasonable
                            to expect those of the first degree to be pioneers in the second, their blessing is
                            heavenly. Of all the thousands who came out of Egypt only two entered Canaan. Only two
                            retained the life of God in their souls to that degree, that they could be leaders in the
                            army of the Lord, to fight the new class of enemies of the Lord in the land of Canaan — the
                            Promised land itself ! !</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="River" TEIform="index"/>THE RIVER</head><p TEIform="p">I'm descending the banks of a beautiful river, That flows by the storm beaten island of time
                            ; And I'm watching the waves with their unceasing quiver, That ripple and dance on its bosom
                            sublime. And I'm watching the life-boats, just crossing the river, That follow each other
                            and all disappear, While above the strange music that swells there forever. The call of the
                            boatmen distinctly I hear. I am thinking of friends, who've passed over the river, Those
                            near ones, those dear ones, so blessed to me, Did feelings of dread seize their spirits ? Ah
                            never ! 'Tis the Kiver of Life to those who are free. I am thinking of those who've passed
                            over the river, Whose vestments concealed the dark spirit within ; If true hope was theirs,
                            as an anchor? Nay never I 'Tis the River of Death to souls hid in sin. And, I ask, do I fear
                            to pass over the river? Should the boatman soon call, could I readily sa3% That my soul is
                            prepared to meet Father and Mother? Or would I ashamed and abashed, answer Nay ! Sometime I
                            shall go to the banks of that river, And I shall return from its brink nevermore, Its tide
                            may run cold, yet my soul will not shiver. There's sunshine and rest on the opposite shore.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Shultz, Maria L." TEIform="persName"/>Maria L. Shultz, Canaan, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers" TEIform="index"/>THE SHAKERS</head><p TEIform="p">Jefferson Democrat. Esteemed editor, in the brief conversation we had the other day, you
                            asked me some questions about the Shakers, remarking at the same time that you had " heard
                            some pretty hard tales about them." I had not time then to answer your questions definitely,
                            yet you will doubtless remember that the few statements I made were in defense of the Shaker
                            order. After we parted I was meditating upon the import of the questions you had with so
                            much candor asked me, and wondering why it was that the multitudes of people in the
                            world,who are so intelligent upon general subjects, should have such limited knowledge, and
                            such mistaken opinions respecting a body of Christian professors, whose teachings have been
                            freely offered to the people for a hundred years. The Divine law is, " Ask, and ye shall
                            receive." You have, asked, and I offer to let all who read your paper know that Shakers are
                            an interesting class of Christian people. There are many sects and divisions of people all
                            claiming the right and title to the name " Christian." If obeying the precepts of Jesus, and
                            endeavoring to follow his example on earth, will give any people the right to be called "
                            Christians," there is no religious body of people on earth who have a more perfect right to
                            the Christian name than the Shakers have, and none who can more rationally prove their faith
                            and their mode of life to be correct, by Scripture texts, than the Shakers can. Those hard
                            tales which many persons hear about the Shakers are not true, they are merely started by
                            those who love to gossip about their neighbors. It could not harm an editor, or lawyer, or
                            doctor, or preacher, or granger, or republican, or democrat, or merchant, or mechanic, or
                            farmer, or any of "the rest of mankind," (male or female) if they would correctly inform
                            themselves how and why the Shakers differ from other professors of Christianity. I will not
                            prolong this article, but will say in conclusion, that if you are disposed to ask any
                            questions through your paper on the subject, they shall be in a kind spirit briefly
                            answered. Or if the citizens of Hillsboro (or any other town in Jefferson county) would like
                            to listen for an hour to a lecture upon the subject of Shakerism, they can be (most likely)
                            accommodated. With kind regards,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Nichelson, V." TEIform="persName"/>V. Nichelson</byline></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In our last issue, in the question, 'Had not Believers...'..." TEIform="index"/>In our last issue, in the question, 'Had not Believers...'...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">In our last issue, in the question, " Had not Believers as good a right to make fools of
                            themselves, for a little season, about two Books, as the Antichristians had to do it for
                            ages ?' For Christ's sake' " was omitted.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ed." TEIform="persName"/>Ed.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Should we explore this spacious earth..." TEIform="index"/>Should we explore this spacious earth...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Should we explore this spacious earth, And view its contents o'er and o'er, Renew again our
                            diligence Add search the sea from shore to shore; How vain, alas ! our search would be, If
                            happiness we seek to find, It can't be found on land or sea, Except we have it in the mind.
                            'Tis there our choicest treasures lie, Abroad for joys we need not roam, Nor stretch our
                            sense beyond the sky, Our greatest heaven is at home.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Granger, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>Anna Granger, Enfield, Conn.</byline></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sudden warming" TEIform="index"/>Sudden Warming</head><p TEIform="p"> A very dangerous, yet a very common winter practice, is that of sudden warming when very
                            cold. We frequently read in the papers of little children falling down dead on suddenly
                            going to the heated stove after a long, cold walk. Others are injured seriously who have no
                            guess at the real cause of the difficulty. Every intelligent person knows that a frozen limb
                            will become dead flesh if suddenly warmed. The temperature must be raised very slowly. The
                            limb must be put into cold instead of warm water, or be rubbed with snow. When the limbs are
                            half frozen, they cannot resist the injurious effect of sudden warming. Convulsions in
                            children occasionally occur; many more are made suddenly faint and sick without knowing the
                            cause; the eyesight is often particularly affected, and people call it " snow blindness."
                            All skin difficulties are greatly aggravated by sudden warming, and sometimes very painful
                            ones are induced. It is generally thought that chilblains are caused by the severe cold, but
                            the true cause is sudden warming after they have been very cold. It seems as if this
                            distressing malady were largely on the increase — even very little children suffer from it.
                            Too great care cannot be taken in this matter of warming cold feet slowly, and by friction
                            rather than by putting them near the fire. Sudden warming, too, makes the whole system so
                            subject to cold for a long time afterward that extra garments are always needed, and then
                            the frame shivers in what was once very comfortable temperature. Physicians have observed
                            this in their cases, and say that they have sometimes suffered in this way for years from a
                            single act of such imprudence. Use proper precaution on your own part, and watch carefully
                            over your children, who of course follow their natural impulse to rush to the fire when very
                            cold.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Blanchard, Zilpha" TEIform="index"/>Zilpha Blanchard
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Blanchard, Zilpha" TEIform="persName">Zilpha Blanchard</persName>, deceased, January
                                23,1874, aged 45 years, Enfield, Conn.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dexter, Albert" TEIform="index"/>Albert Dexter
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Dexter, Albert" TEIform="persName">Albert Dexter</persName>, deceased, May 30,1874, aged 16
                                years, Enfield, Conn.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Monfort, Peggy" TEIform="index"/>Peggy Monfort
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Monfort, Peggy" TEIform="persName">Peggy Monfort</persName>, deceased, August 23,1874, aged
                                91 years, Pleasant Hill, Ky.</p></div3></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>