<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm1708" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">23</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">17</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">08</biblScope><date value="18870801" TEIform="date">August 1887</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">169-192</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="17" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="08" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!-- 
<pb id="p1"/>
AUGUST.
THE
MANIFESTO
PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES,
" Every plant which my heavenly Father bath not planted shall be rooted
up. "- -Matt,  xv.,  13,
Canterbury, N. H.
1887.

<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
CONTEXTS.
The Gospel Testimony, So-. IT.
Public  Discourse.
Sweet Conviction,
An Acrostic,           -          Aim Aright,       Contentment,
Education,
Letter,- -E. Myrick,
Letter,- -D. Oflbrd,
Ocean "Voyage,        ...
Letter,- -J. M. Peebles,
Conference, .                            , How easy it is,
Tree of Life,
Religion,
Coming to Christ,
Notes,- -The Best Gifts,
Improper Food,
Mania for Oosing,
Whitworth's Reply,
The English Language,
Simplicity,
Continuing in Temptation,
Letter,- - -C. L, Nelson,
Music,- -The Glad Song,
Books & Papers,
Kind Words,
People will Talk,      - -
Deaths,    -          169
171
173
174
175
1TO
17T
179
180
181
182
183
184
185
187
188
190
1- -1
192
MEDAL   MACHINES.
NSW 70SS STAl'S ASBICULTUSAL WOKS.
1st. Premiums at all Competitive  Trials
Railway, Cliain and L- -rerHon- - Powers, Threshers and Cleaners, Threshers
& Shakers, Clover Hullers, Feed Cutters, "Wheel Horse Rakes, Horse Pitchforks, 
Shingle machines, Straw Preserving1 Rye Threshers, Portable Steam-Eng-ines, Cider and Wine mills and Presses,
Dog1 and Four Powers, Disc Harrows
& Springy Tooth   Harrows.     " Robinson's Hay Press, of four sizes- Will
work as easy with one horse, as
others with two. Made with Steel
Gearing which can not be broken."
WHEELER & MELICKCo.,
AIBAIfY, W. Y.
Send stamp for Circular and report of Centennial
trial.
SHORT HINTS
- - - - - - -O1V- - - - - -SOCIAL ETIQUETTE,
Compiled from the latest and best works
on the subject by "Aunt Matilda.'"
PRICE, 40 cents.
THIS book should be in every
  family desirous of knowing "the proper thing to do."
We all desire to behave properly and to know what is the best
school of manners. What shall
we teach our children, that they
may go out into the world well
bred men and women?
"SHORT HINTS" contains
the answer and will be mailed
to any  address,  postage   prepaid on receipt of price.
special
Until further notice we will
mail each of our friends a copy
of the above valuable book
gratis and free of postage, if
the}r will mail us 15 wrappers
of Dobbins' Electric Soap.
By folding up the wrappers
as you would a newspaper, the
postage will only be 2cts.
Always put your full name
and address on the out side of
the bundle and write the word
"Etiquette" also, and then we
will know who sends it.
I. L. CRAGIN & Co..
PHILADELPHIA, PENN'A.
" The QUILL " is working diligently from
week to week to interest its readers in the
events of the day and at the same time informs them of the advantages of working
for the cause of temperance. It is published
every week in Philadelphia, for $1.00 per yr.
As it has enlisted in a good cause we hope it
may become victorious for right over wrong.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
Vol.  XVII.
ATJG-TTST,  1887.
No. 8. --><pb n="169" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gospel testimony of Mother Ann Lee and the elders, William Lee and James Whittaker no. 17" TEIform="index"/> 
                            The Gospel Testimony of Mother Ann Lee and the Elders, William Lee and James Whittaker.
                            No. 17.</head><p TEIform="p"> Published expressly for the several Communities of Believers in 1816. Re-written by Henry 0.
                            Blinn. Industry, Prudence, Cleanliness, Economy, etc. Mother Ann and the Elders instruct ed
                            the Believers very carefully, in regard to the management of their temporal duties. All
                            should be industriously engaged, and while their hands were employed in manual labor, they
                            must also give their hearts to God. They should use the things of this world as not abusing
                            them. While they were instructed that nothing should be lost or wasted through carelessness,
                            they were at the same time to avoid covetousness. A kind and a charitable spirit should be
                            manifested toward the poor and unfortunate children of this world. They urged the necessity
                            of this very important rule. Whatever may be your trials or privations, never run in debt to
                            the world, as by so doing you make yourselves slaves to the world. These things were
                            enjoined as essential to the securing of a spiritual blessing. It was held forth as a
                            doctrinal truth that those who were unfaithful in their temporal interests, could not find
                            the blessing and protection of God in their spiritual life. All were stimulated to make a
                            wise use of their time and talents in temporal duties as essentially necessary in order to
                            inherit the true riches. Mother Ana while, giving advice to one of the young Believers,
                            remarked, " Be faithful to keep the gospel. Be neat and industrieus. Have everything in your
                            house arranged in order and in neatness. Prepare your food in that manner that tho.se who
                            partake of it may bless you with thankful hearts. Keep a strict watch over the words you
                            speak, that you may not treat others unkindly nor cast on them unpleasant re flections. Let
                            your words be few and seasoned with grace. " To another company she spoke as follows :- -''
                            Return to your homes and put your hands at work, and give your hearts to God, for if you are
                            not faithful in the unrighteous mammon, how can you expect to be entrusted with the true
                            riches?" " Many will come to the Church and receive the gifts of God and then
                            <pb n="170" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> through carelessness and idleness lose or waste them away. This is not right,
                            you should be faithful, that when yo:i come the next time, you may bring spiritual strength
                            and not bring weakness." " Let your apparel be modest as becomes the people of God, and
                            teach the same to your families. Labor for a meek and quiet spirit that others may see your
                            good works and be able to glorify your Father in heaven. Let thj children of this world have
                            all your jewelry, your gold beads, silver buckles, sleeve studs, rings etc., as upon such
                            things they place their hearts, but the children of God do not need them." '; Remember the
                            poor and needy, the widow and the fatherless, and give bread to the hungry and clothes to
                            the destitute. Jesus has said, 'Give to him that asketh.' Put away all covetousness and be
                            prepared for the gospel of Christ, for the time will come when it will be preached to all
                            nations, and 'many will come to Zioa to hear the word of the Lord.' " Some of the persons
                            that visited Mother Ann and the Elders, had entertained that singular notion, that the end
                            of the world was near at hand, and through this were neglecting their families and their
                            property. Mother Ann said to them,- -"Go to your homes, plough and plant your fields, set
                            out your orchards, raise your stock and make provisions for a livelihood as though you
                            expected to live a thousand years, and gather something with which to do good. Take care of
                            what you have ; provide places for all your things and learn to be neat and prudent. " To a
                            brother who had contracted a debt and thought he must sell his farm to cancel it, she said,-
                            -You should not sell your farm that you may pay your debts, Nay. The people of God do not
                            sell their farms to pay their debts, but they put their hands at work, and give their hearts
                            to God, and gather something by their industry Avith which to pay their debts and keep their
                            farms." L' As you become involved in debt, you not only bring yourself into bondage but also
                            your family, and at the same time bring distress upon your creditors. Such evil management
                            will bring sad loss to the soul till the creditors all are paid, in full, and the soul finds
                            repentance." wt As we have given our souls to God, let us kneel in pra&gt;er, asking
                            that He will spare our lives ti!l we have repented of all our sins, for those who leave this
                            world in their sins, must pass through intense sufferings. Remember the cries of those who
                            are in need and in affliction, that when you are in need, God may hear your cries." - - - -
                            You should walk uprightly like men an I women of God. You ought to love and lear God in all
                            you do. Open and shut the doors carefully, and walk with gentleness about the house."'
                            Mother A nn was very thoughtful about the preservation of the health of Believers, and
                            counseled them to be temperate in all things. '"You should keep your health and strength,
                            with which to serve God. Be charitable. If 1 owned the whole world, 1 would turn it all into
                            joyfulness, and not say to the poor, Be ye warmed and be ye clothed, without giving them the
                            means wherewith to do it." Father James Whittaker then took the Bible and read as follows ;-
                            -t% Be ye doers of the word and not hearers only,<pb n="171" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> deceiving yourselves
                            ; For if any be a hearer of the word, and not a doer, he is like unto a man beholding his
                            natural face in a glass. For he beholdeth himself and goeth his way, and strait way
                            forgetteth what manner of man he was. But whoso looketh iuto the perfect law of liberty and
                            continueth therein, he being not a forgetful hearer, but a doer of the word, this man shall
                            be blessed in his deeds." wk If any man among you seem to be religious and bridleth not his
                            tongue, but deceiveth his own heart, that man's religion is vain. Pure religion and
                            undefiled before God the Father is this. To visit the fatherless and widows in their
                            affliction and to keep himself unspotted from the world. " </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Public discourse" TEIform="index"/> PUBLIC DISCOURSE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="McNemar, Richard" TEIform="persName"/> BY RICHARD MC. NEMAR.</byline><p TEIform="p"> "For the law was given by Moses; but grace and truth came by Jesus Christ." Akd in the first
                            place, of the law. "The law was given by Moses." Moses was not the Christ, therefore he had
                            not the substance. Nevertheless, the law was the greatest dispensation and deepest
                            ministration ever given or known, either before, or in the time of its operation. And it had
                            its work to do, and its purpose to answer; for although it could not bring salvation, or
                            minister it to the people, not having the substance of heavenly things, it had the shadow,
                            and was a useful figure for the time then being, at least such was the tabernacle in which
                            the law was deposited. "Which was a figure for the time then present; or which time were
                            offered both gifts and sacrifices which could not perfect him that did the service, as
                            pertaining to the conscience." Salvation therefore, was not by the law, for notwithstanding
                            the knowledge of sin, to a certain degree, was by the law, yet the knowledge of salvation
                            was never found by that means. To elucidate this subject, we may attend to a few passages of
                            Scripture. "What then, are we better than they? Nay, in no wise ; for we have before proved
                            that both Jews and Gentiles are all under sin. As it is written, there is none righteous,
                            not even one ; there is none that understandeth, there is none that seeketh after God. They
                            are all gone out of the way, they are together become unprofitable, there is not one that
                            doeth good, no, not one. Their throat is an open sepulchre ; they have beguiled with their
                            tongues ; the poison of asps is under their lips ; whose mouth is full of cursing and
                            bitterness ; their feet are swift to shed blood ; destruction and misery are in their ways ;
                            and they have not known the way of peace ; the fear of God is not before their eyes. Now we
                            know that whatsoever things the law saith, it speaketh to them that are under the law; that
                            every mouth may be stopped, and all the world may become guilty before God. Therefore, by
                            the deeds of the law no flesh shall be justified in his sight; for by the law is the
                            acknowledgement of sin." This scripture is a plain and unequivocal declaration that
                            salvation was not known by the law ; although it gave, to a certain extent, the knowledge of
                            sin, and produced the acknowledgement of it, from time to time. "But I had not known sin,
                            unless by the law." "But if the ministration of death written, engraven on stones, was in
                            glory, so that the children of Israel could<pb n="172" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> not steadfastly behold the
                            face of Moses for the glory of his face, which glory is done away ; how shall not the
                            ministration of the spirit be in glory ! For if the ministration of condemnation was glory,
                            how much more doth the ministration of righteousness exceed in glory." This was the
                            ministration of Moses ; a ministration of death and condemnation ; and this was the law, for
                            the law was given by Moses, and by it was the knowledge of sin, to a certain extent, and
                            therefore it was a ministration of death, but not of life, of the Spirit, for it did not
                            take away sin as pertaining to the conscience ; for it was not possible that the blood of
                            bulls and of goats should take away sin. " Probably no difficulty will occur in satisfying
                            the mind, that justification, as pertaining to the conscience, or salvation from sin, was
                            not gained by the law ; the Scriptures, on that point, are too explicit to leave room to
                            doubt. The subject may assume another appearance, and have a very different bearing on the
                            minds of the people, when it is stated, that neither did any of the people, under the law,
                            or during that dispensation, find salvation. Before Christ came into the world, no man
                            entered heaven. " How shall ye believe if I tell you heavenly things? and no man hath
                            ascended up to heaven, but he that came down from heaven, even the son of man who is in
                            heaven ;" none but Jesus Christ, and for this good reason that none was fitted for heaven ;
                            neither had the way to heaven been opened. As pertaining to redemption from the nature of
                            sin, the Jews were on a level with the Gentiles,- -"by nature children of wrath even as
                            others." Eph. ii., 3. "What then, are we better than they ? Nay, in no wise : for we have
                            before proved that both Jews and Gentiles are all under sin." And the black catalogue which
                            followed, as quoted before, is applied to the Jews as well as the Gentiles, as is evident
                            from the closing of the subject. "Now we know that whatsoever things the law saith, it
                            speaketh to them that are under the law, that every mouth may be stopped, and all the world
                            become guilty before God ;" not only the Gentile, but also the Jew. The nature of all was
                            the same, though some in every age, went deeper into sin than others. Now, under this
                            influence and government, the Jews, with all their privileges, could not enter into the life
                            of the spirit, or of heaven. The Jews were, "by nature the children of wrath as well as
                            others :" and no law or rule had been appointed to them, by which they could overcome that
                            nature, the root of all sin. Christ the Savior, had not yet appeared, ami could they have
                            been saved before he came, his coming, offices, and work had been unnecessary and he had
                            lost his honor and triumph. "Now if a law had been given able to communicate lift, verily,
                            righteousness had been by the law," and Moses would have had the crown; for "the law was
                            given by Moses." "I do not frustrate the grace of God, fur if righteousness were by the law,
                            then Christ hath died in vain." "If therefore, perfection were by the Levitical priesthood,
                            what farther need was there that auother priest should be raised up, after the order of
                            Melchisedec, and not be called after the order of Aaron ? For the priesthood being
                            transposed, there is made of necessity a transposition also of the law."
                            <pb n="173" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> The priesthood passed from Aaron to Christ, and the law also, from the shadow to the
                            substance. These testimonies are abundantly sufficient to show that under the law was no
                            perfect redemption, and therefore none saved, or fully redeemed. But a prevailing sentiment,
                            untaught in the Scriptures, and unwarranted by revelation, is extensively embraced in the
                            Christian world, and become the false refuge of souls on this subject, which is, That
                            notwithstanding justification and redemption were not found by the law, yet the people wire
                            saved in that day by a work of the spirit, which went deeper than the law, and was made
                            effectual through faith in Christ to come ; and that it was necessary that Christ should
                            come, suffer, die, and do all the things that "he did, to give their laith confirmation in
                            truth, and settle their salvation on a permauent basis. Why did not the apostle see the
                            existence, and understand the efficacy of that plan, when standing in the light of
                            revelation, and under the influence and guidance of the spirit of inspiration? Why did he
                            reason so inclusively and even falsely? for his reasoning was sophistical, indeed, when he
                            argued the impossibility of salvation, from the insufficiency of the law, and the Levitica'
                            priesthood, if they had, or could have experienced the efficacy of a deeper work than the
                            law. His reasoning was preposterous, to suppose, when he argued that it was unnecessary that
                            another priest should be raised up after the order of Melchisedec, if perfection hat been by
                            the Levitical priesthood, provided a plan had existed on which per fection could have been
                            attained; espe cially admitting that plan was dependent &gt;u the coming of Christ for
                            its efficiency, and its efficacy was by faith in that which was to come. For him, therefore,
                            on that supposition, to have argued, saying, What further need was there that another (that
                            is Christ) should be raised up? would aave been sophistical and false reasoning. Union
                            Village, 0. (TO BE COKTINUED.) </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sweet conviction" TEIform="index"/> SWEET CONVICTION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Buckingham, Joseph" TEIform="persName"/> JOSEPH BUCKINGHAM. </byline><p TEIform="p">Come sweet conviction, reign in me. Spare not thy chast'ning rod, Forsake me not, lest I
                            forget The precious way of God. Conviction is a father's gift To mortals here below, Shows
                            them the wretched state they're in, Exposed to signal woe. Confessing is a glorious work. It
                            makes the angels sing, To see each soul on fire of truth, Exposing ev'ry sin. This is a
                            precious gift of God, It stains all human pride; It drives the devil from the soul, Leaves
                            him no place to hide. Forsaking is the richest gift It is the power of God, It turns the
                            sinner short about, Into the heav'nly road. This is the resurrection power Which God has
                            freely etiven. It frees the soul from every lust, And leads it up to Heaven. O sacred truth,
                            come dwell in me, And make me strong to fight, The devil and his wicked hosts In darkest
                            hours of night; Help me to cleanse my vessel clean From all impurity, That I may stand
                            before God's throne From all pollutions free.<pb n="174" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/>O thankfulness come fill
                            my soul That I may truly hate The filthy state of fallen man And all his deeds forsake, Help
                            me to hate my nature base Which God will never own, Nor can it be conformed at last, To His
                            Beloved Son. 0 help my soul Almighty God, Through Christ, thy precious son That I may
                            honestly repent Of ev'ry sin or wrong. Help me to find new life and peace, And in obedience
                            shine, And then all praise and glory shall Forevermore be thine. Watervliet, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="An acrostic. Shaker Manifesto" TEIform="index"/> AN ACROSTIC. SHAKER MANIFESTO.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Buckingham, A. D." TEIform="persName"/> ELDER A. D. BUCKINGHAM. </byline><p TEIform="p">The Shaker Manifesto, in appearance so small Has this goodly motto, "Go preach the kingdom"
                            to all t Embarrassed by none, it obeyetb the call. Sailing out in deep waters where dangers
                            assail, Heavy surges are breaking, and darkness prevails, Adding trials and conflicts, the
                            Truth to maintain, Keeping boldly at work, for humanity's gain. Ever prayerful and humble
                            while trusting in God, Reviving new courage by proclaiming His Word. Making paths of bright
                            sunshine, and happier days All along thro' Life's strange and mysterious ways. Never
                            flinching in purpose,- -upholding the Bight, In the many or few who are seeking true light,
                            Forgiving, forgetting all injuries past. Espousing no baneful emotions that blast: Sincerely
                            inviting all souls who aspire To rise, and keep rising, still higher and higher, Out of
                            worldly dissensions- -unholy desire. Watervliet, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Aim aright" TEIform="index"/>AIM ARIGHT.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hastings, Marcia E." TEIform="persName"/>MARCIA E, HASTINGS,</byline><p TEIform="p"> It should be our aim to appreciate and love every person and every good quality. We should
                            seek these qualities, look for them instead of looking for defects, unless for the purpose
                            of helping to correct in a kindly, loving manner. Not scornfully spurn, if for protection's
                            sake we must avoid intimacy with contaminating associates. Perhaps nearly every person has
                            some way or ways that are disagreeable and unlovely to others ; let us each watch our own
                            dispositions and try to so order them as not to offend or annoy sensible well-bred persons.
                            Labor to exercise forbearance and loving consideration toward those who we think, (perhaps
                            conceitedly.) are not so high in moral or intellectual attainments as ourselves, not of such
                            noble parentage and excellent inherent propensities. If we can justly perceive that we have
                            been more favored in the matter of transmission from parents enlightened and conscientious,
                            who cared for the welfare of their children, guarded and shielded them from vice and vicious
                            associates, prayed with them and earnestly for them, let us be humbly thankful for our lot
                            and inheritance. Manifest the superior acceptance by our careful godly deportment and
                            large-hearteduess ; thus honor our parents in the Lord. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Contentment" TEIform="index"/> CONTENTMENT.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Barry, Ruth" TEIform="persName"/> RUTH BABRY.</byline><p TEIform="p"> It has been truly said that '"a contented mind is a continual feast." We would ask what
                            constitutes contentment? Is it wealth, by means of which every want can be gratified and
                            every appetite filled to satiety? It needs but little observation to convince us that it is
                            not thus obtained ; for we know that those who hold the highest positions that the world can
                            bestow upon mortals ; even those who wear kingly crowns, wielding the sceptre of unlimited
                            power over millions of subjects, have not this<pb n="175" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> priceless boon. Regal
                            splendor, with all its luxuries, cannot bring contentment to its possessors. In every
                            station of life, we see a lack of restfulness and calm content, which condition is the
                            result of the sway of human passions. How truthfully spake one of old, " The wicked are like
                            the troubled sea, whose waters cast up mire and dirt continually." The great ones of the
                            earth constantly brood over some real or imaginary evil which threatens with direful
                            consequences ; and even war is often occasioned by some trivial circumstance that is
                            aggravated by blind human passion ; and untold misery and ruin is the result. Neither is
                            satisfaction found among those who cccupy humbler positions in life. The poor envy the rich,
                            and the rich oppress the weak. All classes of society have their trials and grievances,
                            which bring distress and blight, and mar the peace and comfort of many lives. The whole
                            fabric of society is built upon false foundations, of unrighteousness and
                            self-aggrandizement; injustice and oppression are alike grounded in human nature, whether
                            the individual is high or low. There are doubtless, times when many enjoy temporary
                            releasement from that which causes their many troubles ; but such seasons are like the oases
                            in the desert, few and far between. And now we ask, is the desideratum attainable to any
                            while living the earth life? We answer, Yea! Those who will crucify the flesh with all its
                            sinful purposes and desires, bear a daily cross, and practice self-denial in all things that
                            would bring loss and misery to their soul by their indulgence ; doing in all things unto
                            others as we would have them do unto us, may find, possess and enjoy this desirable
                            blessing. Here in our beautiful Zion home, can just such a life be lived, as will bring the
                            greatest good in all things ; for its foundations are laid in purity, justice and truth ;
                            and, according to our understanding, it is impossible to attain to a high degree of
                            spiritual harmony, only in the fraternal and blessed relation which souls form in the
                            kingdom of Christ. Those who have truly forsaken all to become his disciples, enjoy the
                            fulness of unselfish love, and possess the meed of sweet contentment and abiding peace. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Education" TEIform="index"/> EDUCATION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bushnell, Richard" TEIform="persName"/>RICHARD BUSHNELL,</byline><p TEIform="p"> Is not education one of the inalienable rights of human beings ? If society allows children
                            to be born, is it not the duty of society to make existence a blessing? Good parentage, good
                            care, food, clothing, lodging and good schooling- -education- -that shall develop all the
                            self-supporting faculties of body and mind. When will society become rational, act
                            rationally, in relation to the continuance of the race ? Was not Moses right upon this
                            subject? He superintended propagation from beginning to end. Light and right is modesty.
                            Lycurgus brought the same science to bear upon raising human beings that the moderns do in
                            raising animals, t There are some sixty Shaker families, who have been taking and educating
                            children for about one hundred years.<pb n="176" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> Thousands of these children have
                            gone out from among them when they became of adult age. But few of these ever became paupers
                            or criminals. Being educated in a community they learn how to do a great variety of things.
                            The boys learn to manage cows, sheep, horses, poultry ; how to work on the farm, garden,
                            orchards, and how to turn their hands to almost every kind of mechanical work, such as
                            carpentering, blacksmithing, shoemaking, etc. In a family of sixty people, almost everything
                            can be done by the members, who have been educated in the family from raising and cooking
                            the food, to plumbing the buildings. Why should not public industrial schools be
                            self-supporting communities, like Shaker societies? War, pauperism and crime would soon be
                            matters of history, with slavery and the inquisition. The suggestion of the "- -Tribune" to
                            use the accumulating funds of the government to feed, clothe, house and educate the children
                            of the country in industrial schools, is just what is needed ; not more soldiers, more
                            pensions, more Monitors, more forts, and guns of large calibre. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Elder H. C. Blinn, editor of the Manifesto: The July number has..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Elder H. C. Blinn, editor of the Manifesto: The July number has...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Massachusetts, Ayer, July 1887" TEIform="index"/> Ayer. Mass.. July 1887.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Elder H. C. Blinn, Editor of The Manifesto :- -The July number has much that is interesting,
                            encouraging, instructive and suggestive. Interesting and encouraging in the account of *the
                            very friendly, welcome reception of the missionaries in the old world, bearing the same
                            testimony for which our ancestors were driven from England to this then struggling country
                            for freedom from the despotism of church and state, akin to the jaws of a wild beast. Here
                            again to be hunted by the imported cubs of that same beast, until an infidel government was
                            formed which knew neither kings nor priests, but in whose secular hand was a naming sword
                            turning every way to guard the sacred rights of man, and on whose banner was the brightest
                            ensign of freedom that ever blessed the earth. And may not the most ardent look back (with
                            no fear of that fabled Lot of Salt) on the dial of time and feel grateful for what doubt and
                            investigation have done, despite their foes, faith and finality. Instructive, indeed, is
                            that inspired pen that pricks the vain and heartless bubble of jealousy, that obstinate foe
                            to human happiness, ihxtcoiling serpent with restless tongue, glittering eyes and cruel
                            fangs. It always carries a concealed dagger to defend the love of self. Let its service be
                            the service of warning and never entertain it as a visitor. It would fain come to stay and
                            80 inflate the imagination that you would become an exile surrounded by uou'd be friends
                            only for your ugly companion. Jealousy is both cause and effect, aggressor and victim ;
                            while favoritism is both soil and fertilizer fur the poisonous weed. Beware of both and be
                            nobly free. And ask, "'is my soul delighted when others are blessed, and do I their
                            happiness seek ? " There is enough of warning to form a resolution in every young mind to
                            subdue, bind, yea, kill this "' basest wolf that travels the devil's forest round."
                            Cultivate at home what you would admire in a visitor. If jealousy will live, either on
                            favoritism or fancy, chain<pb n="177" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> it at home, aud starve it out. Never vex
                            your friends with the apprehension of mad dogs. Suggestive is the query, "What of the future
                            of Shakerism?" 1 am at one with the writer of that splendid article. If a sacred regard and
                            rigid adherence to first principles had been the rule, "the simplicity in which Ann Lee
                            established them, the Shaker societies would now be a great power in the social, industrial,
                            political and religious world." Personal adoration will never atone for lack of living
                            principles. Improved methods of cultivating the soil will bring an acceptable harvest, while
                            the stars will shine without our praise or prayers. " Divine things can never die." Compare
                            one hundred years ago with now, and be grateful that the assumed deities have retired from
                            the affairs of men ; that the noblest and best are permitted to live and bless this green
                            beautiful earth, that their blood is not required "for Christ's sake."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, Elijah" TEIform="persName"/> Elijah Myrick.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beloved elder Henry: I enclose another letter..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Beloved elder Henry: I enclose another letter...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon, July 1887" TEIform="index"/> Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., July, 1887.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Beloved Elder Henry :- -I enclose another letter received from over the waters. We have also
                            received letters from Manchester and London, all of which go to show that there is a state
                            of preparation for the establishment of our order in England and Scotland. I should like to
                            see the Shaker Order started in England and Scotland on a strictly vegetarian basis; the
                            people over there are ready for it, and without hired help. The hireling system in a
                            community is antagonistic to the growth of Christian Brotherhood ; hence destructive of our
                            Christian Community. It seems to me so rational that a people living a spiritual, angelic
                            life in thought and imagination, should have a diet that corresponds with their soul food,
                            and a business that is in harmony with the angelic life of the gospel we are called to live.
                            Everything about the slaughtering of animals is repulsive to the finer feelings of the soul,
                            and a fruitful source of disease to our mortal bodies, which should be full of health
                            without a mark of Egypt upon them. Then should we truly honor and glorify God in our bodies.
                            We are called to look to Jesus, as the captain and pattern of our salvation. Was he ever
                            sick? He gave his disciples instructions to heal the sick. This power over physical
                            infirmity, belongs to the gospel of Christ and must be in our possession before we shall be
                            perfect in the divine life. The July MANIFESTO is good, came all right, but rather late
                            which we attributed to your waiting the printing of the letter from Glasgow. Hope the
                            enclosed will be in time for the August number. In kindest love, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Offord, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Offord. </byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Steamer state of Georgia, out at sea" TEIform="index"/> Steamer State of Georgia, out at sea,</head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="June 3, 1887" TEIform="index"/> June 3rd., 1887.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Beloved Bk. Daniel :- -I was very sorry we missed seeing you, or rather you seeing us as we
                            left the pier. We were engaged talking below, and did not realize that we were slipping out
                            until too late. When we went on deck we could see you but you could not see us. After we
                            were fairly started a fog set in; the wind rose and the sea was rough. Half the people were
                            sea-sick, including James and the young man who accompanied him. I was in a doubtful
                            condition for a few minutes, but my stomach being in good condition, nothing needed to come
                            up, the food was all digestible. I ate but little and kept on deck, acquiring the use of my
                            kneejoints and sea-legs, to take the jar off' the stomach, as the springs take the jolt from
                            the body of the carriage. It is the unusual shake to the stomach that stops digestion,
                            causing sea-sickness. 2 o'clock. Still enveloped in mist, have to keep the fog-horn going
                            and a double watch. Have just opened a letter from Elder Harvey, he writes like himself.
                            Talks about "old age." I was never younger than I am now, in my spirit. That being so will
                                not<pb n="178" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> inspiring spirits quicken my mortal body, even if I were as
                            good as dead, as easy as they could materialize a form? 4 o'clock, P M. A large steamer
                            passes away in the distance, just visible to the eye. June 4th. Had a good night's rest,
                            nothing of importance transpires. 5th. The sea air is cold was obliged to put on an extra
                            pair of woolen pants. Three sails in sight at once, and a whale is seen. 6th. An iceberg in
                            sight this morning, another whale goes by. Have a musical entertainment in the cabin this
                            evening. James is not at all well, keeps his berth most of the time. I am in excellent
                            health. The eating is an interesting study, there is evidently some connection between
                            eating and theology. 7th. An iceberg twice the height of the ship's mast in sight, it is a
                            magnificent spectacle, majestic and grand in its icy coldness. Several whales were seen
                            during the day. We are twelve hundred miles out in mid ocean, going at the rate of twelve
                            knots an hour. Towards night more icebergs float in sight In response to a call from captain
                            and passengers I delivered a lecture in the evening, occupied about an hour and a quarter.
                            It was well received. Thanks voted, and the captain congratulated me as achieving a success.
                            A general feeling of satisfaction expressed the following day. The sea air has cleared my
                            voice, and my hearing improves slowly. My voice now sounds natural which is a comfort. 8th.
                            Chilly this morning. Winter clothing would have been in order. The ship rolled heavily all
                            night. James was quite sick. John attended to him. I hope he will soon recover. I am quite
                            comfortable. The passengers complain that they cannot sleep, the waves rock me to sleep.
                            James says he cannot obtain vegetable food while lecturing in different places, and is
                            consequently obliged to eat some animal food, and suffers for it. I am now better able to
                            care for him than he for me; perhaps on land it will be reversed. It is colder in England
                            than in our climate, at least the sun's rays are not so fierce in summer. We must bear this
                            in mind when we come with a company to the British Isles. The harvest field is great and the
                            laborers few. Let us pray that the Lord of the harvest will send forth more reapers. Is the
                            harvest field fully ripe? Do the laborers exist? Where are they? The sea has been tolerably
                            smooth to-day. I saw a flock of Sea Gulls, one lighted on the water, the rest gathered to it
                            and they floated along like ducks on a pond. 9th. Quite rough this morning, but not
                            tempestuous. I have plenty of exercise, and an abundance of fresh air, but no bread that is
                            either wholesome or nutritious. . Were it not for the nice crackers that the good sisters
                            have provided, I should be in a bad fix. As it is if I could have one North family meal I
                            could get along nicely for two days. For breakfast I ate two potatoes and a piece of white
                            bread toast. G o'clock P. M. The sea more tumultuous than heretofore, the deck is quite
                            unnavigable, and I am obliged to stay below. The fountain pen is a notable invention. For
                            use when traveling it is unequalled. I find it very convenient, have had it filled but once
                            since leaving home ; and the blank book Br. Daniel gave me is just what I need, it opens so
                            nicely. Home seems far, far away and the time of absence about one month. 11th. A quiet
                            night. Temperature 55 degrees. James is convalescent. In the evening he lectures on
                            Palestine, the passengers listen attentively and seem well pleased. The captain is friendly
                            and cheerful. Half past four P. M. have run three hundred miles. A large ship passes. The
                            sea is rough and the vessel rolls, yet still we lunge ahead, without delay or disaster.
                            12th. I arose at three o'clock this morning went on deck, sea quite calm. There was a large
                            steamer in sight. It seems pleasant to see something, if it is only a bird or fish. For
                            breakfast only crackers to eat not even a potato. I am improving in health each day; my
                            brain is getting rested, so that I begin to feel natural and comfortable. We expect to see
                            land by night, and to-morrow to be in Glasgow. 13th. Coast of Ireland in sight. I should
                            like another day or two, not quite sick of the sea yet. At twelve o'clock eat our last
                            dinner on board the vessel, a very good meal. Land about three o'clock at Greenock, take
                            <pb n="179" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> cars to Glasgow. I have written some about our first meeting or
                            gathering; it was a revival. I have never witnessed the like before. It reminded me of the
                            time when in company with Elder Richard, we met the spirits in New York, through the early
                            mediumship of the Fox girls. We could feel them as tangibly as if they had been in the body.
                            Ii the family could have heard what the spirits said through two or three fine young men
                            mediums present, they would have been delighted and astonished. They would not doubt but
                            that our mission had its beginning in the spirit world, whatever may be the result, the
                            powers above are at work for us and with us. We are spending the forenoon writing. I am
                            sorry to send you such a broken account of our journey, but you get it just as I wrote it on
                            the restless sea. I shall try to keep you posted of our future movements. The gospel ought
                            to be founded in Scotland and England; but who is equal to so important and vast a movement?
                            Can we keep the gospel and preach it too? If we keep it and hold our organizations intact we
                            cannot preach it all over creation. A postal card has just been received, stating that a
                            deputation will call at five o'clock P. M. to make arrangements for meetings, and another
                            party will be here at 6 o'clock. Two meetings already appointed for Sabbath ; so you see we
                            are not left unnoticed. Dear brother Daniel, I trust that the good angels who have sent us
                            from you, will be with you and more than compensate you, for our absence a short time. My
                            love and blessing are yours, and my continual prayer is that a gift of divine wisdom may
                            rest upon you. Love to the beloved Ministry, to every one of the Brethren and Sisters. Your
                            friend and brother, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Daniel, Dear brother: You will, no doubt..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Dear Daniel, Dear brother: You will, no doubt...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Scotland, Glasgow" TEIform="index"/> Glasgow, Scotland, Saturday.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Elder Daniel, Dear Brother:- - You will, no doubt, be exceedingly anxious to know how Elder
                            Frederick gets along, and how he stands the labors, and how the work opens. Perhaps I cannot
                            do better than to say that yesterday was the Queen's Jubilee day, and so with a little party
                            we went out to Mr. Neilson's house, examining his fine library, and engaging in conversation
                            upon the work and doctrines of Believers. Those present seemed deeply interested. There is a
                            spirit of inquiry everywhere. In the evening, a party of from forty to fifty met us at the
                            hotel, organized into a meeting, when the Elder gave a full exposition of the faith of
                            Believers. They listened with intense interest. His words seemed to have a deep effect.
                            After the address, there followed a conference of inquiry, very harmonious and interesting.
                            Muuy seemed to be inquiring the way to Zion. Night before last, we held another very
                            interesting meeting in the hall of the hotel, a good many friends- -mostly spiritualists-
                            -coming in, when the Elder again spoke with great power, and in the demonstration of the
                            spirit. This discourse of his was very interesting, giving the practical workings of
                            Shakerism in America. The times seem propitious, and I think we came in the right time. The
                            country is in commotion, and the people are crying out for a better state of things. I think
                            the mission must result in great good, and in a gathei'ing. The Elder gets pretty tired ;
                            but his health remains quite good, considering his advanced age. The work goes bravely on. I
                            shall do what I can to help Elder Frederick during our stay. Love to all. Most cordially
                            yours, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Peebles, J. M." TEIform="persName"/>J. M. Peebles. </byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The word that has gone forth can never be recalled" TEIform="index"/>
                            The word that has gone forth can never be recalled
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> The word that has gone forth can never be recalled.</p></div2><pb n="180" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Text selected for evening conference" TEIform="index"/> TEXT selected for Evening Conference.</head><p TEIform="p"> " Verily, verily, I say unto you, Except a corn of wheat fall into the ground and die, it
                            abideth alone; but if it die, it bringeth forth much fruit." My Dear Associates ;-
                            -Agreeably to my promise, I this evening present you my simple version of the wonderful text
                            quoted last week for our consideration, together with the valuable lessons it suggested to
                            my thought while pondering the truths it embodies. I presume you are each aware of the long
                            established fact in the vegetable world, that every perfect seed contains the germ of a
                            future plant similar to itself. Thus the corn of wheat instanced by our Savior was evidently
                            supposed by him to contain all the elements necessary for the future wheat plant; and also
                            that such acted upon by proper agencies must apparently die, or change, in order to live
                            again in a uew form ; for remember, "except it die. if abideth alone." In the wheat kernel
                            also we find that there is stored a substance which is evidently intended to nourish the
                            life principle of the future plant. This substance, when ground, is known as flour. All
                            ripened seeds, so Botany teaches, are miniature plants, living yet sleeping, but carefully
                            sealed up for better transportation in future. If a seed continued to remain intact or
                            impervious to moisture, it may sleep on for a series of years, thus, as the text reads, "it
                            abideth alone." On the contrary, if rightly conditioned, it will eventually commence its
                            wonderful development aad growth. Let us folloAv the curious phenomena as witnessed in plant
                            life. Take an acorn for instance, which, perchance, having fallen into its approximate soil,
                            and which having lain a certain time, anon bursts its shell where a tiny radicle may be seen
                            peeping out from between its prison walls. Soon very soon however, the radicle becomes a
                            rootlet and speedily directs its course downward; next the plumule shoots forth a little
                            stem above the soil with a bud at its top, directing its course upward toward air and
                            sunlight; meanwhile the rootlet continues to lengthen, enters the soil and divides into
                            branches and fibers, all completely covered with fibrils. Through the latter our miniature
                            plant draws nourishment from the soil. It no longer depending upon the parent seed for
                            support, strikes deeper and deeper into the fertile earth, while the little bud mentioned is
                            mounting higher and higher toward the light and gradually unfolding into stem, leaf and
                            blossom. Thus is marvelously consummated the great miracle of growth in the vegetable world
                            ; a miracle which all the wise men of the past or present could neither imitate nor perform.
                            From this process of apparent death and subsequent life in the plant, it seems that we can
                            draw a clearer inference from the Savior's meaning as applied to our spiritual unfoldment;
                            and also that a similar process must be operative in the development and growth of that germ
                            of immortality which exists in every "Temple of the living God." This vital principle, which
                            every human being possesses, needs the divine light of truth and holy influences to attract
                            it heavenward ; while the physical still remains a tenant of earth. Removed from these
                            influences by inherent selfishness the mind is like the kernel of wheat which abideth alone,
                            however long it may continue to exist.<pb n="181" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE They whose spiritual
                            faculties are never quickened into a divine consciousness of duty, as immortals, may be said
                            to sleep like the plant, and consequently such experience no change, no advance in a higher
                            life ; no real growth in Christian charity, love and fellowship. To die daily then to
                            selfish loves, tastes and appetites is the only way to live anew and bring forth fruit
                            worthy the Christian character and name. Your sister.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stickney, A. C." TEIform="persName"/> A. C. Stickney.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How easy it is" TEIform="index"/>HOW EASY IT IS
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> How easy it is to spoil a day! The tho'tless words of a cherished
                                    friend, The selfish act of a child at play, The strength of a will that will not
                                    bend, The slight of a comrade, the scorn of a foe, The smile that is full of bitter
                                    things- - They all can tarnish its golden glow, And take the grace from its airy
                                    wings. How easy it is to spoil a day By the force of a tho't we did not check.
                                    Little by little we mould the clay, And little flaws may the vessel wreck. The
                                    careless waste of a white-winged hour, That held the blessing we long had sougiit,
                                    The sudden loss of wealth and power, And lo ! the day is with ill inwrought. How
                                    easy it is to spoil a life!- - And many are spoiled ere well begun- - In home light
                                    darkened by sin and strife, Or downward course of a cherished one ; By toil that
                                    robs the form of its grace, And undermines till health gives way; By the peevish
                                    temper, the frowning face, The hopes that go, and the cares that stay. A day is too
                                    long to spend in vain, Some good should come as the hours go by ; Some tangled maze
                                    may be made more plain, Some lower'd glance may be raised on high. And life is too
                                    short to spoil like this, If only a prelude, it may be sweet; Let us bind together
                                    its thrt ad of bliss, And nourish the flowers around our feet. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="story" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tree of life" TEIform="index"/> THE TREE OF LIFE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pick, Ernest" TEIform="persName"/> ERNEST PICK.</byline><p TEIform="p"> I. There stood an apple-tree in a beautiful orchard. Its roots were firmly buried in a
                            fertile soil and wide spreading limbs and branches made it a beautifully shaped tree under
                            the shade of which it was sweet to rest. It promised abundant fruits delicious to the taste.
                            The owner of the orchard was a very good-hearted man and Mr. Too Easy was his name. He did
                            not take great care of the apple-tree and allowed the sprouts to grow and go as they liked
                            and in a couple of years the tree looked like a small wilderness. For the sprouts had taken
                            all the place, excluding the sun-light, many limbs were crooked, many dead altogether. At
                            spring-time caterpillars built their nests and the worms crawled all over the tree
                            destroying the leaves. Harvest-time came and though the apple-tree still offered plenty of
                            shade there were no fruits. II. In course of time Mr. Too Easy was obliged to sell his
                            property and Mr. More Energy purchased it. And then you ought to have seen the heavytrimming
                            our tree experienced. The sprouts were cut off, the crooked limbs and the dead wood cut off,
                            the limbs hindering the rays of the sun were cut off and every by-way limb, small though it
                            be, was clipped off mercilessly. Soon the old good tree stood there in its former comely
                            shape, the lights of the heaven poured into the centre quickening the sap to a vivid
                            circulation. When at spring-time worms tried to build their homes there clipper and pole
                            <pb n="182" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> were after them and the nasty worms were clipped off, burned and
                            trampled down. Harvest time came and our apple-tree needed not be ashamed of its own
                            existence, it offered abundance of fruit ; an adornment to itself, a joy and blessing to
                            man, an embodiment of the Creative Power of Goodness. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religion" TEIform="index"/> RELIGION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wilson, Sarah F." TEIform="persName"/>SARAH F. WILSON.</byline><p TEIform="p">What is it? A written creed or formal statement of belief having little or no direct
                            influence upon the life of an individual ? We think that the Apostle James gave a fit answer
                            to the question, when he stated that "Pure religion and undefiled before God and the Father
                            is to visit the fatherless and widows in their affliction and to keep himself unspotted from
                            the world. " This declaration signifies active service and self abnegation, so much like the
                            example of him who said,- -" Inasmuch as ye have done it unto one of the least of these my
                            brethren ye have done it unto me. " Without even a personal experience one may readily
                            discern that pure religion in the sight of God, consists in that indwelling element of
                            righteousness which manifests itself in ministering to the needy of every name and nature.
                            To be fitted for this divine mission will be the ambition of every disciple of Christ. I
                            think that the time will come to all, whose souls have been lighted by the truths of the
                            Gospel, to be sent into every city or condition of life, to preach by example and precept
                            the testimony of Christ. Before this work can be accomplished individually, selfish loves
                            and worldly ambitions must be dethroned by daily sacrifice and an increasing love to work
                            for God in this direction whi'e the satisfaction from the Father, realized through a clear
                            conscience, is far superior to human praise. St. Paul left us this injunction.- -" Put on
                            the whole armor of God that ye may be able to stand against the wiles of the Devil." Eph.
                            vii., 11. This being a spiritual armor, or true religion which will hold us unspotted from
                            the world, the price for obtaining it must be paid b/ individual effort and those who win
                            the breastplate of righteousness, and are shod with the preparation of the gospel of peace
                            can stand securely and with no selfish aims in life are able to keep "unspotted from the
                            world." How important then to obtain this whole armor of God, which includes not only the
                            helmet of salvation, but the sword of the Spirit, which is the word of God. Our Savior has
                            said,- - " And I, when I be lifted up from the earth will draw all men unto me." Although he
                            mingled with all classes of people, yet he was not contaminated with their sinful ways. His
                            mission was that of a Physician. Those received him the most gladly who were in affliction.
                            We have no record that the Savior ever despised one whom the Father sent to him to be healed
                            or cleansed, however vile with disease. All men were, indeed drawn unto him, some to
                            persecute and a few to hear and obey his teachings. Will not all who become true followers
                            of Christ, and are lifted up from the earth, resurrected from its sinful elements, be as
                            lights attracting and reflecting righteousness ? I am certain that it is a test of true
                            discipleship to minister to each grade or class of<pb n="183" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> the suffering, to
                            abound in charity and good works and still maintain an unsullied purity in spite of worldly
                            surroundings. One cannot be tempted from without unless there is a corresponding element
                            within to invite temptation and thus would I pray with the Psalmist,- - "Search me O God and
                            know my heart, try me and know my thoughts, and see if there be any wicked way in me and
                            lead me in the way everlasting." Canterbury, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Coming to Christ" TEIform="index"/> COMING TO CHRIST.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, Jessie" TEIform="persName"/> JESSIE EVANS.</byline><p TEIform="p">Many young persons who desire to enter the churches of to-day, often make the resolution "To
                            come to Christ," an assurance being felt that in this exertion they shall become worthy to
                            hold a place among respectable Christians anyvvheie. But what is it to come to Christ? In
                            this question and in its truthful answer is contained the true secret of successful
                            discipleship. Christ is the anointing spiri' of God which clothed, crowned and prepared the
                            son of man called Jesus for his heavenly mission of saving souls from sin. Seventeen hundred
                            years after his advent, we hold that the same Christ spirit was manifested through the
                            instrumentality of Mother Ami Lee who was also divinely commissioned to teach by precept and
                            practice the perfect way of holy living, and how best to secure our freedom from the
                            thralldom of sin. That the divine spirit of good rested upon the souls of these "two
                            witnesses of God" we fully believe, and also that every disciple who lives agreeably to the
                            testimony of eternal truth which they taught and practiced will be saved- -a testimony which
                            is to-day as a flame of fire against evil and as a beam of light to the weary wanderer
                            seeking entrance to the portals of rest from sin. It is this Christ spirit alone which is
                            able to resurrect the soul from earthly loves, gross appetites and low desires. Minds ruled
                            by its power are made able to become symmetrical in character and thus to develop a true
                            manhood and womanhood in Christ. Though it holds them to the cross of crucifixion which
                            Jesus bore and subjects them to the persecution and suffering which was Mother Aim Lee's
                            daily portion, yet, "When the battle is o'er, and the victory won," what supreme
                            satisfaction shall come in the "still small voice," giving us assurance that our own work is
                            "well done," and then will be presented a new and blessed field of labor in the saving of
                            other immortal souls. Jesus said, "If any man will come after me, let him deny himself, and
                            take up his cross daily, and follow me." We need add no more. Young disciples, you who would
                            find the "strait and narrow way" to life eternal, you who ask in anxious sincerity for the
                            "bread and water of life," here is the criterion of the soul's salvation." "Let him deny
                            himself of all ungodliness" and come to the Christ spirit which allows no selfish interest
                            to take possession of the sold, or any ungodly thought, word or action to claim the time and
                            abilities which should be devoted to the service of God. Canterbury, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God of nature's laws..." TEIform="index"/>God of nature's laws...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> The God of nature's laws, Is God enough to fear,- - For whoso doeth ill, The consequence
                            must bear.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W.</byline></div2><pb n="184" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>NOTES. </head><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> MANIFESTO. AUGUST, Office of publication. The Manifesto is published at Shaker Village,
                                Mer. Co. N. H. All articles for publication should be addressed to Henry C. Blinn, and
                                all letters on financial business to A. Y. Cochran. One copy per year, postage paid, " "
                                six months, " Send for specimen copy, free. .75 .40</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Best gifts" TEIform="index"/> THE BEST GIFTS,</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> The apostle, so earnest in his exhortations and so solicitous for the protection and
                                redemption of all who entered the church of Christ, would have us "covet earnestly the
                                best gifts;" gifts which were a ministration of light and life to those who loved the
                                peaceable fruits of righteousness. He would have us learn that Christ was the spirit of
                                wisdom, and that the manifestation of this spirit was in harmony with the laws of God.
                                That the church or spiritual body must harmonize in all its parts, as did the natural
                                body. Inharmony produced confusion. There were diverse gifts, and yet they were all of
                                the same spirit. All could not become apostles, neither could all be prophets,, nor
                                teachers nor be able to manifest the gift of healing. No one would dispute but that all
                                these beautiful gifts belonged to the church of God, and were calculated to inspire the
                                mind for good and for God. With a little observation we may find many lessons in our
                                midst equally as potent. In the diffusion of God's blessing among those whom we are
                                pleased to denominate as his children, we find one gifted in prayer, another in
                                exhortation, and another in singing. One is especially prudent in the things of this
                                world, while another has great care for the treasures of the kingdom of God. Some are
                                abundantly blessed with faith, and are led to believe that all things will work for good
                                to those who love the Lord. That every gift be it large or small may be harmoniously
                                adjusted. That human nature is about the same now as it was in the days of the apostle,
                                and that good calculation urges every one to covet earnestly the best gifts, that are to
                                be found among men, for it is better to be intelligent than to be ignorant, better to be
                                honest than to be deceitful, and far better to use the things of this world as not
                                abusing them, than to be wealthy and covetous, to be in power and be tyrannical or to
                                obtain a titled name among men and then expect everybody to do homage. All of these may
                                be gifts but only the best should be coveted. And after these have been attained the
                                apostle says, I will show unto you a more excellent way. Have charity, have love. It is
                                the manifestation of universal good will to men. We must bear in mind that the members
                                of the apostle's church had already destroyed their idols, which is more than can be
                                said of all Christian churches, and had refused even the invitation to sit at the
                                idolater's table. They could prophesy of wonderful things that would come to pass,
                                especially upon the THE 1887. TERMS.<pb n="185" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> ungodly; they could work
                                miracles, heal the sick, speak with tongues and yet they remained uncharitable as a
                                church. Universal good-will to man, and love to God is no less than the gospel of good
                                news, no less than the testimony of Jesus Christ which is to save the world,- -and this
                                is love,- -bearing all things, enduring all things, thinking no evil, but rejoicing in
                                the truth. To indulge in an unkind criticism in regard to each other is very
                                uncharitable. It generates evil influences, and largely multiplies sin upon the earth.
                                If the gospel of Jesus Christ is the best gift of God to man, there love and charity
                                stand promineut among the divine lessons which the disciple is privileged to learn.
                                Whoever has in possession these beautiful gifts, should extend them and allow their own
                                lives to be so moulded into the better state, that those who see the changed conditions
                                from ig norance to intelligence may thankfully and with pleasure glorify God. Whosoever
                                worketh righteousness is righteous, and as many as are led by the spirit of God they are
                                the sons and daughters of God. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary. </head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Improper food, improper ventilation..." TEIform="index"/>Improper food, improper ventilation...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> Improper food, improper ventilation, causing accumulated waste matter to be
                                        retained in the human system is the essential cause of nine-tenths of all the
                                        sickness in the world. It is strange that in this age of general enlightenment
                                        the doctors can think of no other causes of sickness and death than climate.
                                        Climate, weather, heat or cold are merely inciting influences which modify the
                                        forms of disease, but do not originate them. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Hygeio therapy" TEIform="index"/>Hygeio Therapy.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mania for dosing" TEIform="index"/>A Mania for Dosing
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> It is about time to organize a movement for preventing
                                        the intemperate use of "temperance drinks. " The manner in which mineral waters,
                                        acid phosphate, " nerve food, " and " lactart" are swallowed at all hours of the
                                        day, and by all sorts of men, with no real knowledge of their nature or effects,
                                        is quite astonishing, and in many cases, no doubt, almost as pernicious, as the
                                        habit which it in a measure supercedes- - the taking of the matinal cocktail,
                                        the midday beer, and the postprandial wine or spirits. Much of this guzzling is
                                        due to the mania for dosing, which is almost a national characteristic. If,
                                        owing to improper eating or any other cause, a man " doesn't feel just right, "
                                        the first thing he does is to take a drink of something, hit or miss, while, if
                                        he "feels bad, " a dose of patent medicine, or some other nostrum follows. Some
                                        of the preparations are, perhaps, harmless, but others are obviously of so
                                        potent a nature that they should be used sparingly, and commonly only upon the
                                        advice of a physician. To burn the stomach with acids, or purge the bowels with
                                        mineral drinks, in the hap-hazard manner often indulged in, is to trifle
                                        recklessly with the health. For a person in an approximately normal condition
                                        there is no need of either stimulants, tonics, " nerve foods, " purgatives, or
                                        other disturbers of nature. Good plain food, fruit in abundance, milk, eggs,
                                        with a moderate supply of water that is cool, without being iced, or tea and
                                        coffee for those who must have " something else," constitute a summer regimen
                                        that is not improved by dosing of any sort. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/> Hall's Journal of Health.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Whitworth's reply to Westbrook" TEIform="index"/>Whitworth's reply to Westbrook.
                        </head><p TEIform="p">[Contributed by Elder H. L. Eads.] <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> R. B. Westbrook challenges me to an array of
                                    passages from the utterance of Jesus as against those of Cicero, Seneca, etc.,
                                    touching the universal brotherhood of man. Of what avail? If I ignored the prior
                                    claims of these ancient moralists, it was because I preferred the substance to the
                                    shadow. Glimmerings towards the great truth of human brotherhood had come to the
                                    minds of Cicero, Seneca, and others, it is true. But<pb n="186" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> they were
                                    merely rudimentary, lacking the very soul that could alone culminate in the
                                    universal bond reached by Christ. It was not in the nature of the moral system of
                                    ethics they taught to attain to any such result. They reached to no higher aim than
                                    education of the reasoning faculties. They appealed to the intellect, not to the
                                    feelings; to the head, not to the heart. How was it possible that true conception of
                                    universal brotherhood could grow from this? Did appeals to the intellect ever make a
                                    bad man good? No man so depraved who will not agree that right is better than wrong;
                                    and yet in spite of all the moral ethics that were ever taught, not excepting the
                                    Sermon on the Mount, he will keep straight on in his selfish career of wickedness as
                                    if no such moral teaching had been uttered; hence, if it was to his interest to hold
                                    a fellow being in bondage, or pppress him for his own profit, no teachings of Cicero
                                    nor any of the other ancient philosophers would ever lead to the universal bond of
                                    brotherly love that was first offered by Jesus in his scheme of human salvation. Let
                                    us take a brief estimate of the world's condition from the earliest periods to the
                                    time of Cicero. All the way down the normal condition of mankind was one of
                                    incessant war. Homer shows that a man was only safe in his life and possessions so
                                    long as the strength of his right arm could defend them. The moment he lost vigor
                                    from age or infirmity, he was in danger of being stripped by marauding neighbors.
                                    The universal rule of rapine and murder was shown by Ulysses when he landed on the
                                    coast of Thracia and found a city, he instantly killed and plundered the people; not
                                    because he had any quarrel with them. It was simply in accord with the universal
                                    spirit of the world's inhabitants. As with wild beasts, the moment two strangers met
                                    they fought to the death. All men not bound by ties of family were at deadly enmity.
                                    When families became banded into tribes, they warred on sight with every other
                                    tribe, and all they did not kill, reduced to hopeless servitude- - men, women and
                                    children, and their offspring after them. So when tribes became joined into nations,
                                    there was the one perpetual system of rapine and bloodshed, and conquered peoples
                                    doomed to slavery. With the Roman empire came the first approach to wider
                                    acknowledgement of human brotherhood, undoubtedly emanating from the moral teaching
                                    of Cicero and kindred philosophers. After a long course of brutal conquest,
                                    subjugated nations were joined under one common government, and the rights of
                                    citizenship extended to those not of Roman blood. Eminent men of Rome were of
                                    foreign extraction. Aurelius, Trajan, Seneca and Martial were Spaniards; Severus was
                                    an African, and many of the leading jurists were of oriental extraction. From this
                                    grew a sort of brotherly unity among nations heretofore engaged in perpetual war.
                                    Then came what poets were pleased to call the golden age. Was it such a state of
                                    universal brotherly love as Jesus sought to establish? The able writer of "Ecce
                                    Homo" tersely states : "It was something worse than an iron age. Never did men live
                                    under such a crushing sense of degradation; never did they look back with such
                                    bitter regret; never were the vices that spring out of despair so rife; never was
                                    sensuality cultivated so methodically; never was calumny so abundant or so gross. If
                                    morality depended on laws, or happiness be measured by comfort, this would have been
                                    the most glorious era in the past history of mankind. In fact it was one of the
                                    meanest." Add to this, that the great mass of the people were held in absolute
                                    bondage. The Greek nation, the home of the great moral philosophers, with all its
                                    learning and love of art, was rotten to the core with licentiousness and human
                                    degradation. Did it enter the conception of any of these sages to offer thp hand of
                                    fellowship to the down-crushed helots, to bind up their broken wounds, to say "Come
                                    with me to enjoy the common fatherhood of God?" What living principle of universal
                                    brotherhood did Cicero or Seneca impart to these? Jesus attained no high excellence
                                    of learning ; but his great soul yearned to lift the lowly and oppressed into the
                                    realm of light that comes from righteousness. Like Jesus, Socrates had his
                                    disciples. To what purpose? Enable them, as isolated individuals, to draw correct
                                    conclusions between right and wrong. If their hearts chanced to be
                                    <pb n="187" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE selfishly cold or -ensually impure, how was this to make them
                                    better, or cement the ties of brotherly love! The very superiority of educated
                                    intellect that lifted Cicero and Ms compeers among the philosophers to their high
                                    standard of excellence was built on the cruel oppression and debasement of the great
                                    mass of the people. What of human brotherhood was there in this? The very fact that
                                    he was content to enjoy his lofty position and superior privileges with no pity for
                                    the groaning helots on whose sweat and Mood he was held above the common plane of
                                    humanity, gives ample proof that no true conception of universal brotherhood had
                                    touched his heart. Jesus was the first to give living force to this true conception
                                    when he uttered his sublime prayer: "Our Father, who art in Heaven." Hereon lay the
                                    only rock of salvation on which universal love in humanity could possibly rest. It
                                    took in the Jew and Gentile, the Christian and the Pagan, bond and free; in a word,
                                    the whole earth's people into one family, the children of one heavenly father, equal
                                    heirs of righteousness to the kingdom of God. Best of all, Jesus lived what he
                                    taught. His wonderful career was summed up in a single sentence. He went about doing
                                    good. He healed the sick, fed the hungry, and spoke such words of brotherly love as
                                    have thrilled to the core of heart with cheer and comfoit through all the world. His
                                    whole mission was one of blessing to mankind. What record have we that Cicero or
                                    Seneca ever stepped aside from their proud elevation on the forum to bind up the
                                    bruised spirit of some lowly stricken one? Not in all their teaching, admirable as
                                    much of it was, can be found such teaching to brotherly love as this : "Love your
                                    enemies, bless them that curse you, do good to them that hate you, and pray for them
                                    that despitefully use you and persecute you, that ye may be the children of your
                                    Father which is in Heaven." Could this spirit prevail and not cement all humanity
                                    into universal brotherhood? Say it is beyond the power of frail humanity to fully
                                    reach so high a plane. It tends irresistibly to the peace and love that bring all
                                    men into brotherhood. Jesus not only taught it, but lived it, and gave up his life
                                    for it. The quality of a thing is best seen in its results. A good tree is known by
                                    its fruits. What are the fruits that have come from the teaching of Cicero? You find
                                    it in the cultivation of intellect in high grade schools and colleges. To the aim of
                                    broadening conception of universal human brotherhood? I trow not. Scarcely one in
                                    ten thousand of the mass of the people have heard the name of Cicero; not one in a
                                    hundred thousand have been moved to rule their life's conduct to righteous living by
                                    anything he ever uttered. But the name of Jesus is known of all men in the civilized
                                    world; and for his grand life work and death he is revered and worshiped by the king
                                    on his throne, by great statesmen like Gladstone, such eminent men of science as
                                    Herschel and Sir Isaac Newton, down to the humblest laborer in his beggared hut, the
                                    crushed slave beneath the cruel lash of a master. Even the mighty Napoleon was
                                    constrained to say, when composing the grandeur of Jesus' mission and sccomplishment
                                    against his own, that the Nazarene must have been divine. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Religio-Philosophical journal" TEIform="index"/>Religio-Philosophical Journal.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="English language" TEIform="index"/>THE ENGLISH LANGUAGE
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> The history of the development and growth of the English
                                    language, may be traced in the numerous versions of the Old and New Testaments, as
                                    found in manuscripts and old printed volumes. The following are specimens : In the
                                    Durham book, translated 950, the Lord's Prayer reads : Fader uren thu arth in
                                    hoefnum, sie gehalgud noma thin ; to cymeth ric thin ; sie willo thin susels in
                                    heofne &amp; in earthe, &amp;c. In the Ormulum, translated about 1225, John
                                    i., 35 reads : Thffirafiterr onn an otherr dagg [day] Stod sannt Johar. Bapptisste.
                                    Tweggen [two] stodenn thasr with th hirnm Off his Learninngenihhtess [Disciples]
                                    Richard Rolla, about 1325 translated the Twenty-third psalm after the following
                                    style :<pb n="188" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> Oin lord gouerneth me u 1 nothynge to aiy slial
                                    wantestede of pasturethar he me sette. In the water of the hotytijt firth he me
                                    brought; my soule he turnyde, etc. Wycliffv, 1380, translated Matthew vi,. 24, as
                                    follows : No man may serue to two lordlft, forsotho outlier he sehal hate the toon
                                    and lone the other, outher he sehal susteyne the toon and disj)ise the totlier. Ye
                                    mowne not serve to God and richessis. In Tyndale's Bible, 1580, Genesis xliii., 11,
                                    was rendered thus : Than their father Israel sayde unto the, yf it must nedes be so
                                    now : than do thus, take of the best frutes of the lande in your vesselles, and
                                    brynge the man a present, a curtesie bawlme, and a curtesie of hony spyces and
                                    myrre, dates and almondes. In Coverdale's Bible, 1535, Mark xiv., 1 is thus printed:
                                    An after two dayes was Easter, and the daies of swete bred. And ye hye prestes
                                    &amp; scrybes sought how they might take him with disceate &amp; put him to
                                    death But they sayde : Not in the feast daye, lest there be an uproure in the
                                    people. The same passage was printed in the great Bible, 1539. thus : After two
                                    dayes was Easter and the dayes of swete breed. And the hye prestes and thscribes
                                    sought how they myghte take him by crafte &amp; put Him to deeth. But they
                                    sayde. Not in the feast daye. leest any busynes aryse amonge the people. In the
                                    Douay Bible, 1609, Genesis xliii, 12, is rendered as follows : Duble money also
                                    carie with you, and recarie that you founde in your saekes, lest perhaps it was done
                                    by an errour. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Student's journal" TEIform="index"/>Student's Journal. </bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Simplicity" TEIform="index"/> SIMPLICITY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Burger, Martha" TEIform="persName"/> MARTHA BURGER.</byline><p TEIform="p"> What, may I ask, can be more beautiful and becoming to those who daily live the Christian
                            life, than true simplicity ? Those who are obedient to their highest convictions of ri^ht,
                            and have entered the kingdom of heaven as little children, dependent upon their spiritual
                            guides, and have gathered a gift of gospel simplicity, can testify that it is not only one
                            of the most beautiful adornments, but a very important and essential virtue. It helps mould
                            the character. It produces plainness of speech, of dress and equipage. I have always
                            entertained a high regard for the primitive Quakers, because of their simple ways and
                            manners. They were sincere in their devotion to the truth, and suffered imprisonments and
                            persecutions for it, enduring agony of spirit beyoud that which some in this day, who are
                            blest with a greater decree of light, would be willing to bear ; and these persecutions were
                            brought on chiefly by their refusing to conform to the customs and fashions of the world. As
                            Believers in Christ's second appearing we are called to come up still higher, on to a
                            spiritual plane beyond that of any other people in past dispensations, because our light is
                            greater, and the advantages for practically carrying out our faith, superior. Then, does it
                            not become us as true followers of Christ to bear more cross, practice more self-denial, and
                            in every way and in every thing increase in Godlike simplicity, that we may increase in
                            spiritual power, and be ministers of salvation to the children of men? When we look upon
                            those who have spent years in the service of God, adorned with a beautiful mantle of
                            simplicity, we covet the same. Such are angel ministers, without ostentation or soulless
                            mannerisms, or jewels to deck the mortal form. How they contrast with those who are living
                            in sin, who<pb n="189" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> strive to make up their lack of character and spiritual
                            substance, by decorating their bodies with showy garments corresponding to their perverted
                            and artificial life. "And, oh in that future and lovelier sphere, Where all is made right
                            that so puzzles us here; Where the glare and the glitter and tinsel of Time Shall fade in
                            the light of that region sublime, Where the soul disenchanted of flesh and of sense,
                            Unscreened by its trappings, and shows and pretence) Must be clothed for the life and the
                            service above, With purity, truthfulness, meekness and lore. Oh, daughters of earth! foolish
                            virgins beware Lest in that upper realm you have nothing to wear." Give me my simple Shaker
                            dress without any superfluous additions, and let my manners bespeak the simplicity of a
                            Godly life. If in our hearts we aspire after true righteousness we shall esteem personal
                            embellishments of small account. Our desire will be to be clothed with the "ornaments of a
                            meek and quiet spirit," and to appear before Grd and his ministering angels in pure, clean
                            garments, that will commend us to their kindly keeping. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Continuing in temptation" TEIform="index"/> CONTINUING IN TEMPTATION. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Danforth, Nancy G." TEIform="persName"/>NANCY G. DANFORTH.</byline><p TEIform="p"> "Ye are they who have continued with me in my temptations. " This was spoken to the
                            disciples a short time before the crucifixion. They had not been called at the time of the
                            temptation in the wilderness, as Jesus had not then commenced to preach the gospel. He had
                            not said to any one, " Follow me. " Still they had stood with him in his temptations. They
                            had witnessed the strife in his spirit, when he made the scourge and drove the money
                            changers from the temple ; also when it was said that he was angry '' being grieved for the
                            hardness of their hearts. " He had labored among them and sought to inspire them with a
                            knowledge of his mission on the earth, but they were so encased in an armor of
                            self-righteousness that they would not receive his word ; therefore his righteous soul was
                            vexed with their stupiditv. Again when in the weakness of humanity he prayed ; "Let this cup
                            pass from me," they also witnessed the humble submission with which he bowed to his Father's
                            will. It was in this dependent spirit that he was enabled to say " I have overcome the
                            world, " the worldly within the human heart which placed him within the reach of temptation.
                            When he had triumphed, he could say, "The prince of this world cometh and hath nothing in
                            me." There was no outward display of strife or bloodshed to obtain this great victory,
                            nought but the constant daily self denial all the way along until the warfare ended, his
                            disciples had been with him, and had not deserted him during the struggle. From this we also
                            may learn a lesson. Whenever we see a brother or sister under temptation or trial, we should
                            continue with such in the spirit of love, and aid them all in our power, with a kind look,
                            an encouraging word, or an earnest prayer, and not turn from them and judge harshly or
                            condemn ; for we know not the struggle of the soul for victory. Let us therefore, as
                            Christian believers, continue with those in temptations realizing that by our influence,
                            souls may be saved or lost. Many times the spirit is willing but the flesh is weak.
                            Canterbury, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="He is the most powerful who can govern himself" TEIform="index"/>
                            He is the most powerful who can govern himself
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> He is the most powerful who can govern himself.</p></div2><pb n="190" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Br. Cooke: All your letters arrived..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Dear Br. Cooke: All your letters arrived...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Kentucky, South Union" TEIform="index"/> South Union. Ky.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Dear Bit. Cooke :- -All your liters arrived .safely aud arc acknowledged. There are
                            inquiries respecting your health aud I am j.leas - - to letirtl that you are improving. I
                            hope to live to see that the seed which you plant is neither rotted in the ground, nor
                            picked up by the fowls of the air. You are right, encourage no one to come to our home for
                            the '- - loaves and fishes." But if you can find any good people who are willing; to take a
                            strong aud perpetual yoke upon their necks, and who are ready to renounce the devil and all
                            his works, the pomp and vanities of this wicked world, and all the sinful lusts of the
                            flesh, and feel like keeping God's holy will and commandments, and walk in the same all the
                            days of their lives, we say, let them come, even at the risk of great disappointment. True,
                            this is no ordinary vow. and it is sad to know how few keep it ; yet every one should feel
                            that he bears this yoke, aud that if he breaks it or throws it away, it is at the risk of
                            his final destruction. My purpose is to bear the evils and calamities of life, with less
                            pain of spirit, to murmur against no dispensation of Providence, to bear ingratitude and
                            unkindness, as things beyond my control, and though friends and confidents should fail, to
                            depend more upon my everlasting friend, who never can fail, and who to the unkindly treated,
                            will cause all such things to work together for their good. As to wicked men we must suffer
                            them, for the wicked will do wickedly, that is their nature, and from them nothing can be
                            expected. I no longer like strange company of any kind, not that I have fallen out with the
                            world, for I feel nothing of t' e misanthrope. If God wills it I am willing to live on here
                            to the day of my departure. I am ready to spend and be spent for the salvation of good men,
                            and in manv things I think I am gaining the victory. It is hard to swim against the stream.
                            I have labored to be useful. I have suffered and not fair ted ; but still, I may truly say
                            that I have been an unprofitable servant. 1 trust the Almighty will have compassion upon my
                            failings,- - smile upon the little good I have done and make it a blessing to myself as well
                            as to others. The testimony of eternal life makes but little headway through the ranks of
                            the world. The cause is apparent. A lukewarmness and selfishness prevails, until scarcely
                            enough are left to light the lamp of God or to keep watch in the city by night. If '^order
                            is the first law of heaven," how ruinous the want will appear in all things to which its
                            influence reaches. Want of method 'ind order is like the withering blast of the desert, it
                            ruins every green thing. As everything should have its place, so every place should have its
                            proper occupant. "Go to" my brother, sound the trumpet, gather in well drilled soldiers and
                            the victory is ours. The time has arrived, the mighty struggle has commenced. All the
                            outworks of corruption must be carried and the battle turned to the gate. May God keep you
                            from the pestilence that worketh in darkness, as well as the destruction that wasteth at
                            noon-day, is the prayer of your friend and brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Nelson, C. L." TEIform="persName"/> C. L. Nelson.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Resist the first beginnings of evil" TEIform="index"/>Resist the first beginnings of evil
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Resist the first beginnings of evil.</p></div2><pb n="191" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Glad song" TEIform="index"/> THE GLAD SONG.</head><p TEIform="p"> ENFIELD, N. H. Beautiful and lovely are thy courts O Zion! Purity is written on thy
                            walls, Purity and Love, Holiness, Holiness unto the Lord. Come Zion's inmates, swell ye the
                            song, The glad song of triumph and praise, For now is come salvation, the kingdom of our
                            God, Glorious fulness of days.</p></div2><pb n="192" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers
                        </head><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>Phrenological Journal and
                                Science of Health</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/>Hall's Journal of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gilman's historical readers" TEIform="index"/>Gilman's Historical Readers</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> The Phrenological Jouknal and Science of Health. July, Contents : John G. Saxe ; The
                                Future of Phrenology; Familiar talks with young readers; A Summer on Puget's sound;
                                History of Block Books; The Victorian Jubice; A GUI's Problem; The bottomless jug; From
                                Life; The Croaker Sistei-s; One Phase of Social Science; Conformity to Law; Dysentery;
                                Postures of the Body; Notes in Science, Poetry, etc., etc. Fowler &amp; Wells Co.,
                                775 Broadway, N. Y. Hall's Journal of Health. July, Contents: Psyeometry; Physiognomy of
                                the nose; Bathing, its agency in Therapeutics; Epistaxis, or bleeding of the Nose;
                                Language of the Hand; Physiognomy illustrated; A curious Pathological Phenomenon; A New
                                Remedy for Burns; Physical Decay of Cities; The Vassar Girls; Spiders; Wonderful
                                Discoveries ; Relation of Exercise to Health; Food Adulterations, etc., etc. Office 206
                                Broadway, N. Y. Oilman's Historical Readers. By Arthur Oilman, M. A. The Publishers
                                inform us that the Readers are given to the public that the youngest readers, in schools
                                and families, may obtain a simple and clear account of the growth of our Nation, and of
                                the events that preceded its birth on the continent of America. They are based upon the
                                works of the latest and best historical students. Peace and not war, is the subject of
                                the Readers,- - patriotism and not sectionalism. The series includes three volumes,- -1.
                                The Discovery and Exploration of America.- -2. The Colonization of America.- -3. The
                                making of the American Nation. No. 1, from the romantic nature of its story, is
                                appropriate for the use of the youngest pupi's. No. 2, is more difficult, and the style
                                is naturally adapted to the slight progress that ought to be made in using No. 1.- -No.
                                3, is still larger, and as it discusses the principles of government, and the great
                                topics that have engaged the attention of the American people during the last century,
                                it may be used by a class a little more advanced. All are printed in large type and are
                                strongly bound for the use of schools. Published by the Interstate Pub. Co. Chicago and
                                Boston. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>KIND WORDS.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To editor Manifesto; The board..." TEIform="index"/>To editor Manifesto; The board...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Califorinia, Sacramento, June 1887" TEIform="index"/> Sacramento Free Library, June 1887.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> To Editor Manifesto;- -The Board of Trustees of Sacramento Free Library desire to return
                                their thanks for your generous donation of your Magazine, The Manifesto. The Magazine
                                has been placed on our table since sent, with the other publications, free to the
                                reading public. Eespectfully, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Gerrish, S. H." TEIform="persName"/>S. H. Gerrish, Sect.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Self-exaltation is the fool's Paradise" TEIform="index"/>Self-exaltation is the fool's Paradise
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Self-exaltation is the fool's Paradise. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="People will talk" TEIform="index"/>PEOPLE WILL TALK
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> You may get through the world, But 'twill be very slow; If you
                                    listen to all That is said as you go ; You'll be worried and fretted And kept in a
                                    stew, For meddlesome tongues Will have something to do, For people will talk. If
                                    generous and noble, They'll vent out their spleen, You'll hear some loud hints, That
                                    your selfish and mean ; If upright and honest, And fair as the day, They'll call you
                                    a rogue, In a sly sneaking way, For people will talk. And then if you show The least
                                    boldness of heart, Or the least inclination To take your own part, They'll call you
                                    an upstart, Conceited and vain. But keep straight ahead, Don't stop to explain. For
                                    people will talk If you dress in the fashion, Don't hope to escape, For they
                                    criticise then In a different shape ; You're ahead of your means. Or your tailor's
                                    unpaid, But mind your own business, There's naught to be made, For people will talk.
                                    Now the best way to do, Is to do as you please, For your own mind, if you have one,
                                    Will then be at ease ; Of course you will meet With all sorts of abuse, But don't
                                    think to stop them, It ain't any use, For people will talk.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.
                        </head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Allander, William" TEIform="index"/>William Allander</head><p TEIform="p"> William Allander of Center Family, Union Village, Ohio, July 13, 1887. Age 67 yrs. 2
                                mos. and 25 days. 192</p></div3></div2><pb n="193" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><!--  THE MANIFESTO. Absolutory PtweThis powder never varirs. A marvel of
                    purity, strength and wholosomeness. More economical than the ordinary kinds, and cannot be sold in
                    competition with the multitude of low test, short weight, alum or phosphate powders. Sold only in
                    cant. Royal Baking Powder Co., 10(1 Wali-M.. N. Y. . Dhib egetable. Flower, K;eid Plants, Bulbs
                    Imp'em'.s. C D h DhibW CATALOGUE , p IZ ft", IJP- - C D fc~ IT* hy mau on ar>^' '- - - -ntion. M l\LL
                    Don't neglect writing for it. HIRAM SIBLEY & CO. ROCHESTER N. Y. 322-326 E. ll.in - -t.
                    CHICAGO, ILL 12-11 IT. Clark St. CHEAP Reading, Semi 10 cents and receive 6 back numbers of THE HOME
                    COMPANION, no two alike, filled with good reading for all homes. Address, The Home Companion, Troy,
                    N. H. A MONTH and BOARD Guaranteed 3 ^ imug Al-en or Ladies in each country, and hig'ii st
                    coininis-ion paid (often $150 a month ) SS**' JBOOJK alrei.dy on TIDAL WAVE OF SUCCESS in North and
                    South America, at the Ice-Bound Poles, over the lands of tlieMidnight Sun, under the Equator,
                    through the Dark Continent, among the Old Temples of India, in tin- Flowery Kingdoms of China and
                    Japan, amid the ruins of Inoas, / ztr.cs and Zun:, within Canons, Cliff Building*, and G-ardens of
                    the Gods, on the Isles of the Sea, and in all pans of the, globe. 300 engravings, I/no.Pncc Quick
                    Sales. Se nd for Circular, p. W. Ziegler, & Co,, 720 Chstinut St, Philadelphia, Pa, AGENTS
                    WANTED to seU ' EE INISCENCST' of 60 YEABS in the NATIO'JAL METROPOLIS, BEN PERLEY POORE
                    Illustrating the Wit, Humor, and Eccentricities of noted c- - -lel- -ritie- -. vIl richly iIIuntratvtl
                    treat of inner Society History, from "ye olden lime" to the wedding of Cleveland. Won(lerfully
                    Pounliir. Agents report rajeifl .- -iitlt's. Address fur circular and terms. UVBB1BD KSSOS., I'ub's,
                    Boston, Mass. NEVER 0UT0F ORDER. NEW HOME SEWING MACHINE aQRftMCE,M/^S. QH'|CLLGO ~ 30 UNi0N
                    SQUARE.N*- DiiLi:^S' BY<pb n="" id="p"/>
                    
HIE  MAMFESTO.
The Cosmopolitan
The handsomest, most entertaining, low price,
illustrated family magazine in the world. - -
($2.50 per year, with a $2.25 premium
free.) Sixty-four beautifully printed pages in
each number, filled with short stories, sketches,
travels, adventures, bright and brief scientific
and literary articles, by distinguished American
and foreign writers, such as Julian Hawthorne,
Harriet Prescott Spofford, George Parsons
Lathrop, Louise Chandler Moulton, J. Macdonald Oxley, Ella Wheeler Wilcox, H. H.
Boyesen, Catherine Owen, Rev. R. Heber
Newton, Alphonse Daudet, Paul Heyse, Count
Tolstoi, Th. Dostoivsky, William Westall and
many others. Also entertaining JUVElVIIiE
and invaluable HOUSEHOLD departments.
One or more illustrated articles and several fullpage engravings in every number.
A Shannon   Letter and
Bill File or a Shannon
Sheet-Music Binder
Free   to   every
Subscriber.
These    premiums    sell
everywhere   for   $2.25
each.   The File is the most
perfect device ever invented for the preservation and
classification   (alphabetically and according to date)
of all   letters,   bills, etc.
Any paper can be referred
to, taken out and put back
without    disturbing    the
others.    With the Binder
 one can insert or take out
i^       any piece of music without
Ua- -&f< $ 2-25.      disturbing any other sheet.
Get SAMPLE COPY at NEWS STAND or
send 20 Cents to publishers.
AGENTS WANTED. BIB COMMISSIONS PAID.
Schlicht & Field Co., Rochester, N. Y.
After Forty years'
preparation of more
than One Hundred
Thousand applications for patents in
the United States and Foreign countries, the publishers of the Scientifio
American continue to act as solicitors
for patents, caveats, trade-marks, copy- - - - - - - - - - - - - - rights, etc., for the United States, and
to obtain patents in Canada, England, France,
Germany, and all other countries Their experience is unequaled and their facilities are unsurpassed.
Drawings and specifications prepared and filed
in the Patent Office on short notice.   Terms very
reasonable.   No charge for examination of models
or drawings     Advice by mail free
Patents obtained through M arniiOo.are noticed
fatents obtained tnrougn .viuniKiiuu.areuuwueu
inthe SCIENTIFIC AMERICAN,, which has
;he largest circulation and is the most influential
tit
newspaper of its kind published in the world.
The advantages of such a notice every patentee
understands.
This large and splendidly illustrated newspaper
is published WEEKLY at $3.00 a year, and ia
admitted to be the best paper devoted to science,
mechanics, inventions, engineering works, and
other departments of industrial progress, published in any country. It contains the names of
all patentees and title of every invention patented
each week. Try it four months for one dollar.
Sold by all newsdealers.
If you have an invention to patent write to
Munn & Co., publishers of Scientifio American,
861 Broadway, New York.
Handbook about patents mailed free.
THE BACKUS WATER MOTOR,
We have  one of eleven  inches,   new,
that we will sell at a bargain.
Pub.   MANIFESTO.
AMERICAN ENTERPRISE.
No invention of the nineteenth century
ln> worked a greater revolution in household
cononiv or conf-rred more of a benefit on
humanity than the sewing machine.
The fi.'st productions w.>re crude and uncouth in the extreme, and it was reserved
fir American t-kill and ingenuity to bring
forth a machine of any practical  value.
In order to appreciate the great advancrnent which has taken place it is only necessary to compare one of the machines built
during the infancy of the invention with one
of the latest improved '"Light-Running New
Home."
All the really good points contained in
other machines have been utilized in its construction. Many new improvements and devices have also been added, the result of
which is a machine as nearly perfect as it is
possible to make one.
For simplicity, durability, ease of management and capacity for work, 
the "Light-Running New Home " has no rival, and the happy possessor of one may rest assured that
he or she has the very best the world affords.
See advertisement on another page of
this paper.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
 --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>