<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0109" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Mount Lebanon Bishopric</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Albany, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">1</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">9</biblScope><date value="18710901" TEIform="date">September 1871</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">65-72</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="1" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="65" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="9" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">" I WILL SHAKB ALL NATIOXS, AND TIIK DESIRE OF ALL NATIONS SHALL COME ; AND I WILL FILL TIIIS
                        HOUSE WITH GLORY, SAITII THE LORD." Published Monthly, by, and under the direction of the Mt.
                        Lebanon Bishopric, Vol. I. SHAKERS, ALBANY CO., N. Y., SEPTEMBER, 1871. No. 9.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Which shall we worship—person or principles?" TEIform="index"/>Which shall we worship—Person
                            or Principles?</head><p TEIform="p">Was Jesus a Shaker ? The people caMed Shakers do not confine their conduct of ¦i-ife within
                            the circle of extreme self-denial, because any individual preceding them has chosen so to
                            live; nor because any individual has taught self-denial as salvation. Their lives are the
                            results of active principles, being thoroughly wrought out, regardless of who has declared
                            them right, or who may proclaim them erroneous. If satisfactory results are reached, it is a
                            matter of small consequence to us, whether John the Baptist failed, or Jesus succeeded.
                            Among hero-worshippers, the Shakers will never be classed, for they are guided in their
                            conduct by no man nor woman that ever lived; considering every man as good as Jesus, who
                            lives as obediently to the Christ principles as he did ; and honoring, equally well with
                            Mother Ann Lee, she who as thoroughly lives to righteousness and dies to sinfulness as did
                            the founder of the Shaker fraternity. We believe in the multiplicity of Christs; are
                            individually aiming to be Christs; and have full faith in the possibility of becoming as
                            good as Jesus was, and as perfect as he is kj the heme cf his Father. We love the principles
                            that made him the Anointed, or Christ; and believing that " like causes produce like
                            effects" in religious life, as truly as in worldly philosophy, we have clothed our lives
                            with these principles, and are successfully achieving the regenerative, Christian trans*
                            formation—and we find that it pays, to some five, t?o others ten, and to many one
                            hundred-fold of superior joys to thos« it cuts off by self-denial. We call ourselves
                            Christians, and rightfully too, because we have chosen as our pattern, the principles that
                            made Jesus, the Christ—"the first-born of many brethren " yet to be born; and not because of
                            any personal attachment to the m-axi Jesus, for some particular act of courtesy on his part.
                            Jesus never did us a personal favor that we know of; while the Spirit Christ has blessed him
                            with salvation and redemption, and will do—is doing the same for us. This Spirit xoe
                            worship; this Spirit is an emanation from our Father and Mother—God ! This same Spirit
                            visited Ann Lee, and transformed her Gentile nature into Christian sainthood, the same as it
                            had regenerated a Jewish disposition in Jesus, making it a pioneer in Chris- tianity !
                            We'love Jesus, for his faithfulness to principles he believed to be true ; for dying in
                            their defense, rather than saving his physical and sensual life, which was in his power to
                            do, by truculently proving false to the principles that wei-e his salvation; and
                            faithfulness to which, will alone be the salvation of the race. -Had Jesus proved false to
                            his commission, he would have merited our religious reprobation, as consistently as Benedict
                            Arnold deserved political denunciation from the American people. The people of the United
                            States mistakenly revere the name of George Washington-—it is to the principles that guided
                            kirn, they mean to do political homage. Had Washington proved a traitor, the principles
                            would have sought out another, who would have been the agent through whom freedom from
                            political and religious thraldom would have been effected. While rational Christians will
                            ever have cause for respecting Jesus, they will not be Christians because he became one, but
                            because of their deep love for the principles by which he overcame the world; and through
                            which, active principles they may all " go and do likewise." Were there any consistency in
                            the theory of the vicarious atonement; if the blood of Jesus' physical body was any more
                            powerful for salvation than that of any other being— Jew or Gentile—in this degree only,
                            would we be warranted in substituting the person, for the heavenly principles of
                            Christianity, in our devotional worship. The medicine which made Jesus, the Christ, is the
                            panacea for all the ills the soul has inherited or may contract; and will make of eacti and
                            all, Christs, as truly as Jesus became so, by their taking the same prescription —being
                            obedient to the same beautiful, resurrecting principles. And until the fact (?) is make
                            apparent, that Jesus took the medicine, and we are saved in consequence, let our standard of
                            worship be the principles of a godly life, while the personalities who carry them out, come
                            in for our secondary respect. Jesus, having carried out the soul-elevating principles of the
                            Christ Spirit, became thereby the ensample by which others might learn of the principles,
                            and how they can be successfully prosecuted for the redemption of human loss. As Jesus
                            became a Christian by obedience to principles of the heavenly world, so we may safely take
                            Jesus for our guide in making our Christian progres. By substituting the person for the true
                            principles worthy of worship, the majority of mankind have become pro- fessional idolaters,
                            forgetful, or indifferent of their duty as true Christians. They worship the man Jestis,
                            while they hate the principles of self-denial by which he became the Christ! They worship
                            the medium of the good Spirit operating two thousand years ago, "while they are disgusted
                            with the motive power that made that medium then, and similar mediums to-day ! That motive
                            power was and is, the principles of Self-denial. They made Jesus what he became ; they have
                            made the Shakers what they are; and will the lives of Jesus and the Shakers bear comparison
                            ? Jesus was a Jew ; and, tinvisited by the progressive Christ, would have engaged in Jewish
                            life, and followed Jewish customs. He would have married him a wife, or many of them, as was
                            the practice. He abstained—he lived a virgin life. Herein, have the Shakers followed the
                            guidance of the same principles. Has popular Christianity ? The Jews revelled in the bloody
                            exploits of war1—Jesus refrained entirely from war—so have, and do the Shakers. Have popular
                            Christians ? The Jews were emulous of each other in worldly honor and riches ,• Jesus, as a
                            Jew, would have attempted to have been the richest, just as the majority of professional
                            Christians do to-day; but he could not, while obedient to the Christ principle of equality.
                            His counsels -on this subject were the very reverse -of Jewish customs, and of present
                            popular Christianity. " My Church has neither rich nor poor—all are equally comfortable,''
                            is the testimony of Jesus— <pb n="66" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 66 T II E SHAKEE was the practice of
                            Jesus—and the Shakers engage in the same laudable enterprise. There has ever been wealth
                            enough in the world to make all very comfortable rf and whoso indulges in the least
                            extravagance, is amenable before the law of Christ, of robbing his neighbor and adding to
                            the miseries of life ! Truly, it will be worth a journey to the Spirit land, to see the
                            Dives and the Lazarus principles meet; to see the'kings and beggars; the tyrants and
                            down-trodden ;. Bacchuses and Father Matthews ; libertines ami virgins, all presenting
                            themselves for reward, "according as their works have been." And now, will Shaker testimony,
                            principles and life, compare with the same that governed Jesus ? If so, was Jesus a Shaker
                            ?Or, are the Shakers Christians ? In the degree that there is comparison between the
                            principles of the Primitive Christian Church and the Modern Shaker Church, is not one as
                            worthy of encomiums as the other? And yet, while millions are worshipping Jesus, they are as
                            truly ignoring Christian principles ! And did Jesus live upon the earth to-day, preach the
                            same gospel that ho did two thousand years ago, there would be a popular falling off of
                            worshipful masks ; and if the times would not permit popular Christians to crucify him, as
                            they would desire to do, he would be shunned and ridiculed by them, and as he walked the
                            streets, fingers would rise, and tongues exclaim, " There goes a Shaker! " *</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Labor is worship" TEIform="index"/>Labor is Worship</head><p TEIform="p">Part Second. The testimony handed down from Jesus regulates labor in all Christian Churches.
                            Paul says to the Thessalonians, "We hear that there are some among you disorderly, working
                            not at all, but are buisy bodies. Now such we command by our Lord Jesus Christ (by his
                            authority), that with quietness they work and eat their own bread." Paul was a regular
                            member of the Church at Jerusalem; he knew the order which Jesus had revealed to the twelve
                            to regulate temporal and spiritual things. What he hadlearned there he taught as true
                            Christian theology. If work was not required of all able to perform it, would Paul have
                            dared place Jesus as the author of it, and pronounce those disorderly who did not practice
                            it ? If it were not bo, would he have ordered the Church to cut off those who refused to
                            practice it, rich or poor ? How could there have been equity in that Church more than in the
                            Shaker Church without such a rule for all ? With them as with us, the quiet were busy bodies
                            and mischief makers; authors of strife and discord. Industry enjoined as a means to extend
                            Charity. Paul on labor was universal; to the Roman brotherhood he writes: '* Be affectionate
                            one to another with brotherly love; in honor preferring one another. Not slothful in
                            business; fervent in spirit, serving the Lord; distributing to the necessities of the saints
                            ; given to hospitality." Taking the above as the test, can an indolent professor serve the
                            Lord ? Can he be fervent in spirit I From bis own industry he can neither distribute to the
                            necessities of the saints nor perform true hospitality. The Shaker Order proves that as
                            self-denial of spirit, works the soul gradually into the heavenly state, just so, by
                            consecrated physical labor we accumulate means to help support the Church and perform all
                            deeds of Christian liberality and charity. The primitive Church commanded to secure means by
                            labor, to pay all just debts. Paul says to the Church, " We beseech you, brethren, that ye
                            study to be quiet, and to work with your own hands, as we commanded you, that ye walk
                            honestly toward them that are without, that ye lack nothing." The apostle here instructs the
                            Christian to peaceably mind his own business; be honest in his dealings; pay all his just
                            debts; to be industrious and diligent to enable him to do so and stand independent. Mother
                            Ann and her successors said, " Do not overreach in business; right all wrongs, and pay all
                            just debts." This is the true believer's ground; his theology on the virgin life;
                            confession; restitution; penitence and consecrated inheritance; and a Church thus cut off
                            from the world, must have the great principle of honest toil and joint labor to carry out
                            these, and other Christian principles, and exist in competency. Paul parting with his
                            Gentile Brethren. The time arrived that Paul was to bid farewell to the Gentile Churches. He
                            was followed by many leading Elders and others, to the place where he was to take passage.
                            He went to Ephesus and called the Elders of that Church also, to exchange the last friendly
                            greetings. These pillars of the faith had seen him from the commencement of his labors among
                            them, had witnessed his patience in persecution, trials among the false-hearted, and his
                            long-suffering among weaker members of his floek. He met them at the celebrated city
                            Miletus, which lay twelve or fifteen leagues from Ephesus. Here, with many warnings, he
                            showed them the probability that after his return to Jerusalem they would see his face no
                            more. They knew that without price or being a burden, he had committed the gospel to their
                            trust, for which they were to be responsible. In recalling the fruits of his labor he said:
                            " I have coveted no man's, silver, gold, nor apparel. Ye know that these hands have
                            ministered to my necessities; I have showed you that so laboring, ye ought to support the
                            weak; and remember the words of the Lord Jesus, ' It is more blessed to give than to
                            receive.'" The apostle was in an" enviable condition to balance accounts. His poverty and
                            hand labor, connected with his gospel life and ministry, clothed him in raiment clean and
                            white. If any could present a Christ-like standing, and feel his dignity of it, it was Paul
                            at Miletus in the presence of his brethren. How tender must have been the parting scene,
                            "when they all wept and fell on his neck and kissed him, sorrowing most of all for the
                            Words, that they should see his face no more." Scenes lik«this we have witnessedwhen the
                            faithful have been taken away; their just life, virtues, and consecrated toil have so long
                            proved to all their devotion, that like Paul's brethren we have sorrowed most of all, that
                            in this world we should see their faces no more. The Restoration of Dorcas, The restoring to
                            life of Dorcas, by Peter, was his greatest gift. This honor was not reserved for some great
                            teacher or renowned apostle, but for an obscure Sister of Charity, who appears to have
                            purchased material and made garments with her own hands for the destitute. When Peter
                            arrived at that house of mourning, many stood by weeping; and pointed to the works of her
                            hands. The restoration of this disinterested saint, to her labors, sets the broad seal of
                            God's approbation upon consecrated labor in the most beautiful form it could have been
                            handed down through centuries. Conclusion, We are not informed who fabricated the story that
                            poverty caused the hand labor of the apostles ; that when the Churches became wealthy,
                            salaries were substituted for toil. But we do know that the foregoing statements of the
                            first Christian teachers, emphatically contradict it. Their example in this matter was
                            indispensable, as clearly as any other in the Christian faith. This duty carried out,
                            removes want, poverty, indolence; and fills the Church with peace and plenty. It is the
                            great roller, which levels all ranks and distinctions, to one condition. It is the parent of
                            honesty, justice and charity; it opens wide the door to contentment, health and happiness.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leonard, William" TEIform="persName"/>Wm. Leonard</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What is a man, as a Christian?" TEIform="index"/>What is Man, as a Christian?</head><p TEIform="p">A lucid answer to the interrogatory, necessarily requires a knowledge of the Christian
                            character, as illustrated by acknowledged and legitimate authority. The teachings of the
                            founder of the Christian religion, or rather the doctrines of Him who was the exponent of
                            that religion, should be correctly understood. In Christ's sermon on the mount, are to he
                            found truths, unmistakable and instructive; elucidating Christian life and duty. It is ex-
                            plicitly declared in that discourse, that man is commended to God, only by his good works—
                            his righteousness; which must exceed the righteousness of the Pharisees, who were the
                            strictest and most religious sect of the Jews, God's peculiar people, or he shall in no case
                            enter the kingdom of heaven; that by the merits of any being but himself only, can he be
                            saved. To the world, the Christian's light must be the strongest; a light that will shine
                            before all men; and that he shall both do and teach the commandments of God, which lead men
                            to be perfect, even as our Father in heaven is perfect ; that is, to be true to conscience
                            and faithful to convictions of right; to be selfsacrificing, self-denying to all
                            ungodliness; under no circumstances to lose control of himself, or to cease the restraint of
                            his passions ; <pb n="67" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER 67 sever reviling nor speaking evil of
                            smother ; and however another may differ from him in opinion or in caste, never tolerating
                            in his heart the action of a spirit of persecution. The Christian man Is meek, merciful,
                            pure in heart, a peacemaker with all, loving all, eves his enemies ; praying for all, even
                            for those who desgitefully use kim; doing to others whatsoever he would they should do unto
                            him, thereby becoming to the earth, salt which hath not lost its savor. By the language and
                            spirit of the sermon, man, as a Christian, has not the right to take the life of his fellow,
                            neither to be angry with him. It is not his prerogative to reproach him with hard words, to
                            call him fool, or say to him Raca, a term of contempt. He shall not commit an unchaste act,
                            or indulge in his heart a sensation of lust, and stand guiltless before God; and rather than
                            be offended by any member of his body, however dear, as the eye or the hand, and perish by
                            its retention, it would be better to cast it from him. The same authority that calls upon
                            man to purify his imaginations, the thoughts of his heart, demands the purification of his
                            language. The tongue is an uruly member, requiring a strict watch to prevent vulgarisms and
                            profanity. The spirit which takes hold of language, bears equally upon the habits and
                            manners of man ; it takes cognizance of his life, in toto. His office is to watch and pray,
                            and that continually. If he would be forgiven of his trespasses, he must first forgive those
                            who trespass against him; if he would have others love, bless and do good to him, he must
                            first love, bless and do good to them. Of others, it is not his province to judge; all men
                            are known by the fruit of human life. Therefore we have before us a standard, a criterion
                            simple and unclouded, whereby all may know how much they are in possession of the baptism of
                            the spirit of Christ. And let him who is in sympathy with the evils of the present,
                            adulterous generation, who fosters worldly relations and caters to self; who gives
                            encouragement to the gross passions and animal desires of an uncircumcised heart, no more
                            name the name of Christ, or look to Him for atonement, until he finds repentance, and
                            submits to the payment of the utmost farthing, for every willful transgression against known
                            light.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. Perkins, Enfield, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reason" TEIform="index"/>Reason</head><p TEIform="p">It is perfectly legitimate for any person to declare a belief—to say I believe thus or so ;
                            but this is a very different thing from reasoning to prove such belief to be true. No person
                            should enter the precincts of reason for the sole purpose of proving a belief to be true,
                            but they may reason to ascertain whether the belief be'true or false, or whether it contains
                            anything false. Nothing is more dangerous than the pride of self-opinion ; " under this
                            influence men seek applause instead of truth." It has been said, and I believe truly, that
                            "man on earth lives three lives [or has three planes of being], the first, An'mxal; second,
                            Intellectual; third, Spiritual. The first, nurtured by the sun ; the second, by books, and
                            the thoughts of others; the third, by the beams of Deity, ever present in the mind," or, as
                            Pope more properly states at, " God in the mind." There are specific laws by which each
                            should be governed. Of the first, physiologists have given abundant instruction; of the
                            second, philosophers, logicians and orthoepists have spread before us a sea of information,
                            beyond our means and power or necessity to fully explore. In these two fields we cannot
                            lead, " for the children of this world are wiser in their generation than the children of
                            light," But of the third, and by far the most important, I do not hesitate to declare that
                            Believers, or Shakers, stand in the foreground to-day of the whole world, and this is said
                            in no boastin spirit. In support of this declaration, but one evidence will I offer in the
                            words of Christ: " By their fruits shall ye know them." Of the two first, however, the world
                            are in advance of the "children of light," who may well stand, " cap in hand," and take
                            lessons on the laws of health, and laws governingreason on the intellectual plane. But the
                            "children of light" being in the ascendant in spiritual life, should " let their light so
                            shine, that the world seeing their good works may glorify their Father and Mother in
                            heaven." As we proceed on the spiritual plane, we more and more take cognizance of the field
                            of inspiration and revelation, which is the arcana from whence proceeds all soul sustenance.
                            But all inspirations or revelations are not reliable; hence, says Locke: " If reason must
                            not examine the truth of revelation or persuasion by something extrinsical to the
                            persuasions themselves, truth and falsehood will have the same measure, and will not be
                            possible to be distinguished." But he confesses the fallacy of this test, by the following
                            admission : " I gratefully receive, and rejoice in the light of revelation, which sets me at
                            rest in many things, the manner whereof my poor reason can by no means make out for me;"
                            thus admitting some inspirations to be self-poised, above and out of the reach of reason's
                            inquiry, whilst others are of a metaphorical character. For light, knowledge, progress and
                            growth on this spiritual plane, Christ, in his first and second appearing, in his living
                            body, is the pole-star, the magnet to which the needle of every compass should tremblingly
                            point, and every soul submit. For these lofty and sublime inspirations the mediums are not
                            accountable; but it is inadmissible for the uninspired to postulate conditions above
                            reason's inquiry, which it is as contradictory to affirm as to deny—thus adhering to the
                            exploded doctrine, " that I know, without knowing what I know." Such postulates are
                            considered chimerical or fanciful; of such, Hume very pertinently remarks, " nothing is more
                            dangerous to reason than the flights of imagination, and nothing has been more the occasion
                            of mistakes among philosophers." "But," says Hamilton, " the most complex web of thought can
                            be reduced to syllogisms, and when this is done their truth or falsehood, in a logical
                            relation, flashes at once into view." So we may reason logically or illogically from true or
                            false premises Logic does not pretend to unveil the truth of the proposition, but it tells
                            with unerring certainty whether the reasoning is sound or unsound. But, descending from the
                            spiritual to the intellectual life and plane of being, and of pure reason, we should rigidly
                            conform to the laws by which minds in the intellectual world are governed, because, if we do
                            not, they will apply them, and will not admit, as they should not, anything that does not
                            conform to them; hence on such our labors would be entirely lost. As a caution, and for the
                            sake of some who may not be familiar with them, I will here take the liberty to enumerate
                            some of the rules which philosophers include under what they term " The Law of Parcimony,"
                            none of which can in safety be overlooked or negleeted by the correct reasoner, viz.: 1. In
                            pure reason, we should take nothing for granted but what is self-evident. 2. If a known
                            cause is sufficient, we must not postulate an unknown. 3. Introduce nothingoccult into the
                            question. 4. Use no term of varied or doubtful meaning in the same thesis, without defining
                            it. 5. All reasoning depends on two things, viz., analysis and synthesis. 6. AYe should
                            never rest so long as there is aught vague or indefinite in our reasonings; so long as we
                            have not analyzed every notion in its elements, and excluded the possibility of all lurking
                            ambiguity in our expressions. Although we may not arrive at truth, with care we can always
                            avoid self-contradiction. 7. An induction which does not proceed upon a competent analysis,
                            or enumeration of particulars, is either doubtful, improbable or null; for all synthesis
                            depends upon a foregone -analysis for whatever degree of certainty it may pretend to. 8. All
                            parts of the predicate must be parts of the subject, and every element rejected as
                            hypothetical which the analysis does not spontaneously afford. 9. An Ivypothesis to be
                            legitimate is, that the facts in explanation of which it is devised be ascertained really to
                            exist, and be not themselves hypothetical. 10. The fact which a legitimate hypothesis ex-
                            plains must be within the sphere of experience. 11. The phenomenon in question must, by
                            analysis, be reduced to its simplest elements ; and no phenomenon be assumed as elemental
                            which can be reduced to simpler principles, and no elementary phenomenon overlooked, and no
                            foreign or imaginary element interpolated. 12. If the analysis is incomplete, the syn-
                            thesis will be incomplete also, and the conclusion unreliable. 13. .No conclusion must
                            contain more than the premises analyzed. 14. If one cause is sufficient to explain the
                            phenomenon, we should not postulate a second. 15. A legitimate hypothesis must save the
                            phenomenon which it is invented to explain, without exclusion, distortion or diminution. The
                            foregoing rules and selections, if strictly adhered to, are sufficient to secure any
                            reasoner from the shafts of a rational criticism; but if they are ignored and lightly set
                            aside by any, such may be made to feel the power of any capable critic, who may think their
                            productions worthy of a rigid scrutiny.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Eades, H. L." TEIform="persName"/>H. L. Eades, South Union, Ky.</byline></div2><pb n="68" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bread" TEIform="index"/>Bread</head><p TEIform="p">The following article from the conservative Scientific American, is valuable from the source
                            of its origin, as showing a steady growth of common sense on that very common subject —
                            Bread. Something about Bread. "A subject that interests everybody is that of bread-making,
                            and as a general thing there is too much popular ignorance respecting it. In the process of
                            grinding wheat for superfine flour, the outer shell, composed chiefly of gluten, being
                            tenacious and adhesive, comes from the mill in flakes with the bran, and is sifted out,
                            while the starch is pulverized and constitutes the fine flour. Thus the starch, which is the
                            chief element in fine flour, is saved, which contains no food for brain and muscle; and the
                            gluten, containing phosphates and nitrates which furnish support for brain, bone and muscle,
                            is cast away wdth the bran, and is fed to horses, cattle and pigs. And this is the kind of
                            flbur that makes nine-tenths of the bread in the American cities, besides all that is used
                            in cakes, puddings and pastry. A method of making bread from whole wheat, without previously
                            grinding it into flour, has been devised by a Frenchman named Sezile. A Healthy Bread. The
                            most economical and best bread, especially in cold weather, when a hot fire is constantly
                            kept, is what is sometimes called gems, or unleavened biscuits. For this purpose a group of
                            cast iron pans or cups two and a half by three and a half inches each, all made in one
                            cast-, ing, is used. These pans are set on the top of a hot stove and allowed to become
                            almost smoking hot wThen buttered for use. Then with cold water and milk, half-and-half, or
                            with cold water alone, and the colder the better, mix and stir quickly, with a stiff spoon,
                            as much Graham or unbolted wheat-meal as will make a thick batter or thinnish mush; and when
                            the pans are hot, fill them quickly with the thin dough, and let them stand a minute on the
                            stove before putting into a very hot oven, wrhere they should remain twenty or twenty-five
                            minutes until done. If the mixture be neither too thin nor too stiff, and the pans and the
                            oven be hot, you will have twelve as light and wholesome biscuits as any epicure could wish
                            to eat. They may be eaten smoking warm from the oven, as they contain no poisonous chemical
                            elements like yeast bread, which requires cooling to be rid of. They are good cold, or may
                            be warmed in a steam kettle. Anybody, however unskilled in cooking, can learn to make these,
                            light and nice every time. Nice, fresh wheat-meal, very cold wetting quickly done, writh a
                            very hot place to bake them, will insure the best of "luck " always. These, like all other
                            Graham bread, should be fresh every day. For growing children, and those people who work or
                            think, and especially students and sedentary persons, there is no other bread, and scarcely
                            any other single article of food, that equals it. Let the poor who cannot afford to lose
                            fourteen per cent of the grain in the cast-off bran; let those whose bones and muscles are
                            small, tending to rickets and spinal curvature ; let invalids and dyspeptics try it, and
                            they w:ill never go back to superfine bread simply because it looks white and nice, and,
                            when dry, is more pleasant to the mouth than the brown." We have been in the constant use of
                            whole wheat flour for some thirty years, and have but just attained to a satisfactory mode
                            of making bread from it. Many amongst us eat none but unleavened coarse meal-flour bread;
                            and as they think, with a decided advantage to their health.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div2><div2 type="history" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Historical" TEIform="index"/>HISTORICAL</head><p TEIform="p">It will, no doubt, be interesting to many to know of some of the personal trials to which
                            Mother Ann, and her immediate followers, were necessarily subjected. It becomes the faithful
                            historian not to neglect a chapter like the present one. While the Shakers are somewhat
                            noted for their well-loaded tables, choice viands, comfortable buildings, etc., it will do
                            none of us harm to reflect upon the fortitude of those who, " for their faith, endured all
                            things V * In 1788, being the first year I lived at Watervliet, we were brought under great
                            sufferings respecting our temporal concerns. As money was scarce, Believers in general were
                            brought under sufferings; being inpoor circumstances, and Hot being allowed to run in debt,
                            rendered the procuring of subsistence, for the early part of the season, very precarious.
                            Our principal food was rice and milk; sometimes we wrent to the river to procure fish.
                            Sturgeon, and a few other kinds of fish, were everything of meat kind we obtained fora
                            number of months. We had but little and sometimes no bread, butter, nor cheese, but upon
                            this simple fare we subsisted during the spring and summer. Our employments were principally
                            planting, sowing grain, haymaking and harvesting. All our work was very laborious, and at
                            the end of the season we looked more like skeletons than laboring men, being greatly
                            depreciated in weight. We were so faint for some length of time, that, although we could
                            work, we could not run the distance of twenty rods. Our breakfast consisted of a small bowl
                            of porridge ; supper the same; dinner, a small bit of cake, about two-and-a-half inches
                            square, which Aaron Wood cut up and gave to us; this we ate during the days of labor; on
                            Sabbath we ate very little, if anything. One day, Joseph Preston, and another brother, went
                            to the river to catch herring, and Joseph stated that he was so hungry, that he ate two raw
                            fish as soon as they came out of the water! Many times, in the course of the summer, I
                            thought that if I could only get to my mother's swill pail, I would have skimmed it
                            immediately, and thereby appeased my hunger. We had but little house room, and, of course,
                            had to lie upon the floor, having no convenience for lodging. Fifteen of us laid upon the
                            floor in one room; some had one blanket to cover them, while others had none, and nought for
                            a pillow but a handkerchief, or a chair turned down so as to recline upon its back. In this
                            way we lodged during that season. When our crops began to ripen, and potatoes were eatable,
                            wre began to live better, having a supply of milk to eat with our potatoes, boiled or
                            roasted. The same year there was a famine ia the vicinity of Lake George, and large
                            donations of flour, grain, beef and pork, with other necessaries of life, were sent* to the
                            sufferers by the citizens of Albany; myself with others were hired to convey those donations
                            to Crown Point. One day, when we had almost reached our destination, we stopped at a small
                            hut in the woods to obtain a little refreshment. On arriving at the door, we found it was
                            inhabited by a woman and three little children. Making known our business, she replied : " I
                            have not had a mouthful of bread, meat nor potatoes in my house for three months." We asked
                            her what she did subsist upon ? She replied: " When the briar leaves began to grow in the
                            spring, I boiled them and eat thera with milk, for we have one cow to support us; and this
                            is the way that we have lived for three months past." When we had finished our journey, and
                            returned with the products of our labors, we bought grain and flour, which was the first of
                            any consequence wre had been able to obtain during that season. The blessing of God began to
                            smile upon us, and our labors yielded more plentifully than we had expected. We began to
                            prosper in temporal things ; to increase in strength of body, and were more able to praise
                            God for his goodness. Father Joseph Meacham would often exhort believers to bear sufferings
                            with patience and fortitude, encouraging, that the time would come, if they were faithful
                            and industrious, that they and their children, would have a plenty, .and some to give to
                            those who were more needy. These wrords have been verified in a wonderful and striking
                            manner.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Clark, Jonathan" TEIform="persName"/>Jonathan Clark, Harvard</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I think" TEIform="index"/>I Think</head><p TEIform="p">The world demands a gospel of salvation, that will comprehend and meet its present con-
                            ditions, physically and spiritually. No reliance can be placed on any faith in religion that
                            will not bear the severest scientific investigation. No human soul ought to believe in any
                            system of theology that will yield itself subserviently to the demands of human nature
                            depraved; or which can be bought or sold as the commonest merchandise. Let the wThole world
                            have a thorough knowledge of the true Christian faith, that will bring both body and soul up
                            to the highest state of excellence; and may God speed the day.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Price, G. B." TEIform="persName"/>G. B. Price, Shakers, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Young vegetarian" TEIform="index"/>A Young Vegetarian</head><p TEIform="p">Grace Bowers, aged eight years, having eaten no meat nor butter for five years, is healthy
                            and intelligent, always waking up in the morning laughing—an infallible test of good temper.
                            Grace was sent to the Office upon an errand, when one of the Sisters kindly offered her a
                            piece of white bread and butter, with some sugar upon it (not knowing her vegetarian- ism).
                            ''I do not eat white bread nor butter," said Grace. " Well, Grace, what do you eat ?" " I
                            eat brown, unleavened bread; but I do not need anything now, for I have just eaten a good
                            dinner." Any boy or girl who will thus subject appetite to a principle, is laying a solid
                            foundation for a useful character.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div2><pb n="69" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Address" TEIform="index"/>An Address</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/>ANTOINETTE DOOLITTLE</byline><p TEIform="p">My loved gospel kindred, I am happy to meet you in this beautiful, shady grove. We have not
                            met here merely as friends; we hold a nearer relation: to each other. We claim to be
                            brethren and sisters in Christ, helping to form a spiritual household, honoring our hea-
                            venly parents, the great Head of the family, who have raised a standard around which we
                            gather, and under which we cheerfully serve. Purity, peace and liberty is written thereon,
                            and the Prince of all princes has especial charge of it. To those who have not gathered to
                            it, and found protection under its folds, it does not appear beautiful nor symbolical of
                            liberty. But those who have been led by the spirit of truth, and schooled in spiritual
                            philosophy, feel that it signifies to them liberty in its fullest, broadest sense. While the
                            Prince of Peace guards this banner, and those who dwell under it, the war cry, " to arms,"
                            and the doleful sound that comes to many desolate homes, and pierces the hearts of surviving
                            friends, because of the demoniac war forces, which send the arrows of death alike into the
                            palace and cottage, until the whole land is draped in mourning for the loss of loved ones,
                            cannot reach us. I have not many words for this occasion, but I want to make you, my dear
                            brethren and sisters, feel that my heart beats with deep emotions of love for you all; and I
                            hope this may be a season of rejoicing to every one present. Let us take comfort—have an
                            intellectual and social feast, under the direction of the higher law; and it will be like
                            clusters of grapes from the immortal summer land, and wine well refined from dregs; a
                            foretaste of the pure wine which we, if faithful to our high calling, shall drink with
                            Christ and the redeemed of all kindreds and nations, in the perfected kingdom of God. Let us
                            all, by one united effort, raise the standard of Gospel purity a little higher to-day, that
                            it may wave in the pure breezes over us as it has never done before, that our joy may be
                            enhanced and our peace flow like a river. There seems to be something very congenial in the
                            atmosphere in and around this place. Our annual gatherings here, probably, make us feel a
                            little like some of the ancients, who sought out some quiet retreat in the glens, or on the
                            mountains, that they might the more effectualljr consecrate themselves to devotional life
                            and religious fervor; to perform their sacred vows, and drink in the inspiration of the
                            Almighty! So interblended became their feelings with the scenery surrounding them, the sods
                            upon which they had knelt in solemn prayer, and rested their bodies when the curtains of
                            night were drawn around them, the trees that had sheltered them, and even the rocks whereon
                            they had sat in silent meditation, had become so sacred to them, that it was something like
                            parting soul and body when they left those places, so strongly were they attached to them.
                            One is said to have expressed his feelings thus : " O/king of mountains, rich in purifying
                            streams, adieu ! I have passed happy days upon thy heights. I have nourished myself with the
                            delicious fruits thouhast produced, and have quenched my thirst with the clear waters that
                            flow from thy summit. Oh, mountain, free from sin! Like unto a living child, happy on the
                            breast of his father (mother), have I enjoyed myself upon thy bosom." There is something
                            peculiar in meetings in the open air—in God's great temple. As far back as our history
                            reaches, religionists in an especial manner, from time to time, have sought some spot under
                            the blue arched canopy where they could breathe freely, and commune with higher
                            intelligences. And as we look over Bible history, we find recorded upon its pages that God,
                            when He was about to reveal some new truth, or give some new commandment to his servants,
                            and desired to draw near unto them, and draw them nigh unto himself for that purpose, He
                            ealled them to some secluded place in the vale, or on the mountain, away from the
                            multitudinous-throng and busy hum of life, that they might the more easily hear the voices
                            of messengers which He sent unto them, and receive their ministrations of love. For, as God
                            is love, there can nothing emanate from Him but what will eventuate in love, and,in the
                            final issue, be to the soul as the dews of the morning from the everlasting hills. By this,
                            it would seem that there may be clearer perceptions of Divine truth, and the spiritual
                            senses be unfolded and intensified to a greater degree in the vast temple which God hath
                            made, than within the walls of any house built by human hands. When he was about to teach
                            Abraham lessons of faith and obedience, He called him to ascend a mountain, apart from his
                            kindred and country, and there He communed with him, and put his fidelity to the severest
                            test. Not for himself alone, was Abraham's faith tried, but for the race. He was a
                            representative man. He passed through that severe ordeal unscathed, and for his unflinching
                            fidelity to the right he was called Abraham the Faithful. And, today he stands as a beacon
                            light upon that mountain, and as a reproof to this disobedient and faithless generation.
                            Again, when God raised up his servant Moses, through whom He gave a new code of laws to the
                            ancient Jews, instituted a high school of learning, and appointed Moses the principal, He
                            brought him to Mount Sinai, and led him up thither, and, through appointed agencies, poured
                            out his spirit upon him, and Moses there received such manifestations of the Divine presence
                            that the mountain shook, and himself and people quaked with fearand reverential awe. He
                            became a medium of the greatest manifestation of spiritual power upon material things—the
                            most complete blending of spirit and matter—of any upon record, and was the greatest
                            minister of physical truth. We will not tarry longer with the more ancient people, who
                            sought the open temple to make their strongest vows of consecration, and to receive new
                            hopes, new impulses, and new aspirations; we will pass by the prophetic seers, and only, as
                            we journey along, take note that the spiritual waters gradually rose higher and higher,
                            until we find ourselves with Jesus and the twelve. How often did Jesus go forth to some
                            favorite mountain! to a desert place or garden, leading his little band thither, that with
                            them he might pour forth strong cries to his Heavenly Father and Mother! and to teach his
                            disciples important truths concerning the kingdom of God ! And who has ever been able to
                            speak words so rich in principle, so full of promise, so binding upon the conscience, and so
                            free from human taint, as is the sermon on the Mount, which he delivered ? Ah, then the
                            Christ spirit spake as never man spake ! We never tire of reading or repeating that sermon.
                            It has passed the lips of millions, and still it is new. Was it not a lamp lighted from the
                            great source of Light, by direct inspiration at that time, whose light can never be
                            extinguished or hid, and placed upon a hill to illumine the Pilgrim's path down through the
                            ages? How plainly the Christian's duty, life and character is marked out in that sermon. Let
                            its light shine, and may its power be felt! And how profound and heavenly must have been the
                            season when Jesus and his three loved disciples went together to the Mount, where Jesus was
                            transfigured before them, and their vision was opened to see those two spirits— Moses and
                            Elias—with whom he was in communion ! True, they did not fully comprehend the significance
                            of that interview, and Peter thought if they could build tabernacles for Jesus, Moses and
                            Elias, they would take up their abode in that mountain, and there they could often commune
                            with them. Their spiritual emotion was so great that they exclaimed: "It is good to be
                            here!" Who can wonder that they wished to retain those spirits, and the heavenly influence
                            which pervaded their sphere ? Let us seek to draw such pure and heavenly influences around
                            us to-day, that we also may say, " It is good for us to be here !"</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Oral confession" TEIform="index"/>Oral Confession</head><p TEIform="p">Why should I orally confess to man ? is the first and most important question the Christian
                            Shaker is called to answer. On the underlying principles embodied in the right perform- ance
                            of this work, depends the prosperity of the spirit's travel away from the entanglements of
                            sin. As God himself is the breath of life in man, it is evident that all souls have latent
                            within them the motive to begin their progress towards Him, and it becomes the first labor
                            of the teacher of righteousness to inspire souls with the faith that they are the ones
                            called, and promised forgiveness, and they shall have power given to rise in life if they
                            will. " Come unto me all ye weary and heavy laden, and I will give you rest." Souls do not
                            rise from a sinful state without a full knowledge of the effect of sin; the avenues of its
                            approach; and a thorough sense of shame at the digression from the state of innocence
                            implanted in their creation. This requires deep thought; conflicts terribly with the
                            passionate element within, until this knowledge is obtained. This is the first, severest and
                            most important phase of confession, without which any verbal statement is useless, liable to
                            be dishonest and undertaken for mere hope of present absolution, yielding no victory. It is
                            this spirit of close self-examination that has enabled thousands of noble witnesses in <pb n="70" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 70 THE SHAKER. the past and present to contend successfully with evil.
                            To the discerning eye of faith, all the moral virtue, the Christianity and victory over
                            wrong, is the sequence of confession, and without confession of sin there is no real faith
                            in Christ. " Confess your faults one to another," indicates the work of the Primitive
                            Christians; "Now, go thy way and sin no more," implies that sin had been confessed. Is the
                            artless confession of the child to its mother, "I stole the apple," or, "Father, I did tell
                            a lie," less binding on the maturer child, who, with greater experience and strength of
                            spirit, should know and shun the evil before him ? If the humiliation is too great, at what
                            price shall we be bought, and what of the fact, " Except ye become as little children, ye
                            shall in no wise enter the kingdom ? " Man, being made in the image of God, and receiving a
                            breath of His life, we hope to find in all grades of human development evidence of those
                            laws which ultimately are to govern, and lead to happiness. To instance the invol- untary
                            use of the direct statement of facts, as a medium of healing to the wounded spirit, how
                            often do those who are weighed down with grief or guilt, the consequence of some misstep,
                            seek a near friend to help them bear the trial of soul, and what so likely to soothe the
                            mind with a feeling of forgiveness as this knowledge ? " I have honestly appreciated my
                            wrong, and confessed the fact, and God has promised to forgive ;" hereby realizing that " If
                            we confess our sins, He is faithful and just to forgive us our sins, and to cleanse us from
                            all unrighteousness." There is a restraint put upon our desires, by suffering the
                            consequences of violated law, as the sickness and pain inflicted by intemperance; but, does
                            this restraint work a moral elevation above the reach of self-interest ? or, does the
                            spirit's elevation commence where self-interest has finished its work ? We know there is a
                            manner of confession only unto death, in which the carnal mind glories in its shame, or
                            unfeelingly cries, "Lord, thou knowest I am the chief of sinners," and sins accordingly. We
                            have also a faith, eternal as the spirit, in a confession unto life, whereby the soul can
                            disrobe from every sinful element; the lusts of the world; its intemperance, ambitions and
                            pride; its abuse of the beautiful, to corrupt it and bring it under bondage to self. This is
                            the gospel that Jesus sent his disciples into all the world to teach; and in the goodness of
                            God we rejoice that in this, our day, He has proclaimed the same testimony again, by the
                            same spirit now making itself manifest in the followers of, or believers in, the mission of
                            Ann Lee, who confess their sins; nor this alone, but do forsake them, thus engaging in the
                            only acceptable repentance.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Henry" TEIform="persName"/>Henry Hollister, Mt. L.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The advantage of living does not consist in length of days..." TEIform="index"/>The advantage of living does not consist in length of days...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The advantage of living does not consist in length of day3. but in the right improvement of
                            them. There is a treasure which no self-seeking being ever found; which no created hand can
                            bestow or take away; which no outward events or revolutions can destroy. It is an inward
                            consciousness of the presence and participation of the Divine nature, gradually but
                            certainly renewing the soul, purifying the affections, destroying the sensual and building
                            up the heavenly. In a word, it is the conscious, eternal evidence given to the soul by the
                            Divine and infallible voice within, which says : " Behold me, creating all things
                        anew.''</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fair dealing" TEIform="index"/>Fair Dealing</head><p TEIform="p">" Render, therefore, to all their dues."—Paul. Selfishness is a strongly marked trait of
                            human nature. It not only appropriates whatever it can grasp, but refuses to others that
                            which justly belongs to them. Personal freedom seems to it a good, but it is not content
                            with its own; it must deprive as many as possible of their liberties, merely for its own
                            gratification. Wealth it esteems a desirable thing, but far more desirable when it makes the
                            strongest possible contrast with poverty. Honor is an inestimable advantage, but only that
                            sort which inflates its possessor to extraordinary dimensions. Honor that may be possessed
                            equally by all men is to it an absurdity. The degradation of others, the poverty of others,
                            the tears of anguish caused by selfishness, it regards not, only as it may gain some
                            advantage from them. It assumes numerous forms, and decks itself with a variety of costumes,
                            all of which are extremely gratifying to it. In the light of Christ's teaching, what is
                            patriotism, but selfishness under the guise of a principle ennobling human nature ? As often
                            expressed, it is mere diabolism. " Our country, our wrhole country, and nothing but our
                            country." Our country, whether right or wrong—still, "our country." There is no need of
                            arguing that such expressions are contrary to the precepts of Jesus—all will admit it; but
                            is it not true that these express the real spirit of patriotism ? This will be denied by
                            many who advocate an honorable love of country, and claim nothing for the land of their own
                            birth but wrhat they are walling to concede to others. It may be asked, then, where is their
                            patriotism ? They claim for all equal advantages of whatever kind. Has not their patriotism,
                            then, enlarged itself to the love of general humanity ? When the individual ceases to regard
                            his own pleasures, his own liberties, his own welfare as objects to be sought for,
                            regardless of the rights and interests of others, he loses the character of a selfish
                            person, and has acquired that of general benevolence. Patriotism, when it has passed beyond
                            the bounds of Fatherland, and takes the wide world in its embrace, has lost its distinctive
                            character, and may as well abandon its name. But there are many who find it difficult to see
                            any good beyond the narrowr limits of their own country, or even the particular portion of
                            it in which they were born. Hence arise national and sectional prejudices, the fruitful
                            source of wars. This narrow spirit exhibits itself not only in the national divisions among
                            men, but also in their religious parties. Indeed, it is as strongly intrenched within the
                            walls of the various religious bodies, as anywhere else. These walls its eyes cannot pierce,
                            and it will not renture high enough to look over them, or it might behold without, beautiful
                            landscapes of hill and dale, field and forest, and fertilizing streams, equally attractive
                            with anything it can see within. This spirit is invariably strengthened by sectarian
                            organization. Let it be once embodied, and it gains the magnetic force of the whole body.
                            Organization is understood to be the marshalling of force in battle array ; the building of
                            fortresses on inaccessible heights, not only for defense, but for sallying out on favorable
                            occasions against the enemy. Probably one reason why the Spiritualists have persistently
                            refused to organize into one body, is the fear of shutting in among themselves just such
                            narrow prejudices as they see in the various religious organizations, and thereby
                            perpetuating them. And yet it may be a question whether they have avoided these prejudices
                            altogether by refusing to organize. Would that which does not already exist be included in
                            the body, or would organization create it ? They claim to believe in a God of love, just as
                            Jesus Christ did, yet many of them wish it distinctly understood that they have discarded
                            the Christian name. They believe in immortality, as he did, yet say they are not Christians;
                            they admit the fact of intercourse between beings in and out of the body, just as Jesus did,
                            yet they are not Christians. They claim to have enlarged views of Deity; to believe in the
                            ultimate welfare of every individual of the human family; yet the same views have been held
                            for the past century by Unitarians and Universalists—Christian bodies. They take their name
                            from the fact of their having positive evidence of the existence of the human spirit after
                            the death of the body, and of constant intercourse between the dwellers in the spirit world,
                            and those who still have their residence upon the earth. The same has been maintained |from
                            the beginning by Shakers, who accept the name of Christian because originally it signified a
                            believer in God as infinite love ; in immortality, or the unending existence of all human
                            beings ; in eternal life, or the life of God in the soul of man, as the privilege of all who
                            will seek it; and in holiness, as the only means by which eternal life is gained. If
                            Spiritualists can gain it otherwise, then may they with propriety say they are not
                            Christians; if not, is it exactly fair to discard the name, because under it the worst
                            errors and the basest lives have been cloaked ? Would it not be just as consistent to refuse
                            the boon of life altogether because every blessing which God has bestowed upon man has been
                            perverted ? But Jesus Christ, it has been said, has taught nothing better than other sages,
                            who preceded him by centuries, have taught, and there is no propriety in adopting his name
                            to the exclusion of others; it is. therefore, better to reject them all. Nature's God
                            reveals himself impartially to all, and has not given his truth to the exclusive care of any
                            one. That is so, and yet these truths exist in different persons in vastly different
                            degrees. The life of God in Christ was manifested in a degree superior to that which was in
                            those who preceded him, as his spirit and life evinced ; and such as follow him, in wholly
                            discarding the narrow, selfish life, as he did, attain to the same degree of the divine life
                            that he did. " All things are theirs." It is true, the God of impartial love reveals himself
                            to all; it is, then, right to acknowledge him in all. Not in error, nor in vice, which we
                            are all free to combat, but in man as man; in whatever virtuous principle we can discover,
                            whether in the individual or any collection of persons. If all would havemore regard for
                            these, and less for those things which offend their tastes, or, more properly, their
                            prejudices, <pb n="71" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> TH E SH^KEH. 71 there would be fewer wars among the
                            nations, less strife and bitterness among the religious sects, and, in a time not far
                            distant, a degree of harmonious action among all classes that would effect the happiest
                            results. Our ignorance of each other is the cause of many, if not the most of our disputes.
                            Selfish surmisings bring about distrust and enmities. We dare not look each other in the
                            face, hence we cherish respecting each other mere fancies —monsters, in place of the men and
                            women that actually surround us. What though this large body and that, bearing the Christian
                            name, " have caused it to be blasphemed," by reason of their violation of the laws of the
                            Divine Master; they have nevertheless done much to benefit the world, and individuals among
                            them all have been noble examples of every virtue. There are multitudes who have never borne
                            this name, to whom it has not been significant of any special excellence, yet they have
                            blessed the world in many ways. Let us exalt what- ever is good, and cease to dwell on the
                            evil, and then shall we more easily " overcome the evil with the good;" and whatever
                            excellence any of us may have that others have not, will be the more readily acknowledged
                            and accepted.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName"/>Wm. H. Bussell</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My home" TEIform="index"/>My Home</head><p TEIform="p">My Shaker home, my happy home! No spot on earth so dear to me ; And if abroad my thoughts do
                            roam, They soon return again to thee. The trees, the houses and the land, Are pleasant
                            objects to my eyes; And dearer still, a loving band— Companions dear, I love and prize. My
                            faith, more precious still, I find Is that which holds me in this way; Not earth, with all
                            her wealth combined, Can lure me from my home to stray. Most hallowed spot, my Shaker home!
                            My interest and my all ;s in thee! And from thee I will never roam, There's naught on earth
                            so dear to me. And while life's journey I pursue, In my sweet home I love so well, I'll keep
                            my heavenly home in view— My future home, where angels dwell.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Jillson, J. C." TEIform="persName"/>J. C. Jilson, Shirley</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Love" TEIform="index"/>Love</head><p TEIform="p">Hail! lovely one, and teach me what I ask— Whence art thou come, and where is thine abode ?
                            "What climate dost thou favor most ? and where Canst thou ever be found ? Dost thou fix thy
                            Home amidst perpetual flowers, whose soft and Fragrant breath spreads balm upon the dewy air
                            ; Whose beauteous leaves, of velvet touch, cast far and Near a glowing light and hue on all
                            around, Shut in by towering trees, and scented shrubs;—¦ Whence singing birds, with plumage
                            gay, pour Floods of music on the listening ear; causing The heart quite to forget all else ?
                            Dost thou walk ever with the rich and Powerful ones, on velvet carpets spread out for Thy
                            convenience ? looking on naught That can give pain, or cast a shadow on thy Smiling face ?
                            Does pity never stir thy heart ? and is thy Bliss complete when thou art far removed From
                            all who seek thy aid ? or Dost thou dwell in wilds unknown to busy, Bustling feet, where man
                            does sometimes Seek to hide even from himself, and from the Outer world; holding communion
                            with his God, and all the orbs on high ? " Hold! simple one! nor let thy mind be caged And
                            fettered fast with thoughts like these!— My name is Love! From God I came; and to his throne
                            do straight Ascend the blessed Beings, whom my power Hath taught. On earth I also dwell; My
                            power is known to all; and in no destined Spot do I my home locate. In lofty palaces of
                            state I sometimes stray, But oftenest am I found amidst the lowly Ones of earth, whose
                            simple tones make music On mine ear. To truth, indeed, most closely I'm allied, And walk
                            with none who slight her mien, Or cover with a veil her virtuous deeds W ith scornful lip.
                            Strife flees at my Approach, and hides abashed, poor meagre thing, That apes the powerful
                            mind, and seeks Ascendancy as such. / love him not! 'Tvveen me and him a mark is set, And
                            when, like fiery steed of war, anxious To plunge into the strife, led on by human ire With
                            dripping steel—or, like the serpent's Rage, hissing its maddened spite—it rushes On,
                            reckless of friend or foe, there J am not. I leave, in dire distress, such vile abodes, And
                            enter not 'till all is calm, and those Poor ones, whom hate hath served, return And seek for
                            me. Then often bitter tears aro Shed that Jam gone, and in my stead Hate takes a local
                            stand. No genial hand Outstretched to grasp its kind, but callous Heart, and words that
                            wound, embitter all Life's joys. Angels look down with pity on The scene, and mourn that
                            mortal man will Thus his highest peace and comfort spoil. My mission I fulfill. " Peace on
                            the earth, good will to man." is my Continual aim. The prattling infant and the Hoary head
                            alike I claim for mine; and often Lay the shining locks of youth, most trustingly Amidst the
                            silver hair of age: then stand and Point, that all may see how blessed is my work! While
                            Virtue's smiling face assents. I call aloud to all: " Come, enter in my train, And I will
                            give to you more than the earth Doth yield in joy and bliss. The cup which Fell misfortune
                            holds I'll sweeten with a Simple drug, ere proffered to thy lips; and Oft assuage the
                            keenest thirst of pain, and Make thy dying couch feel soft and easy By my gentle touch.
                            Though some my name mistake, or misapply, Or borrow for some selfish end. yet unchanged I
                            remain; and when the counterfeit appears All see it is not me! Companionship with Virtuous
                            deeds alone I hold; and when with Sinful lip my name is spoke, the mask a Single eye can
                            penetrate, and see beneath My borrowed vest a hideous form! Then look for me where I am
                            found, and Listen to my kindly words, for they are True, and unto Heaven will lead thee
                            on.'1</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="White, Aurilla" TEIform="persName"/>Aurilla White, Shakers, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Where is God?" TEIform="index"/>Where is God?</head><p TEIform="p">He's in the kindly faces of parents, teachers, friends, And in the goodly graces which love
                            with chiding blends; He's in the tender sympathy one feels for other's woes, And in the warm
                            affection with which the heart o'erflows. All honest, upright actions, no matter here or
                            there. Bespeak God's glorious presence, and God's peculiar care. He's in the beauteous
                            blossom, and in the whispering breeze, And in the sparkling sunbeams which dance among the
                            trees; He 's in the sounding music of every rippling rill, And in the bird's sweet melody,
                            on. every woodland hill; He 's in the grasses waving so gracefully and green, And in the
                            luscious fruitage of autumn, God is seen. In all, where life is teeming, there God our
                            Father dwells, And with his gracious goodness earth's mighty bosom swells. In the sun's
                            sweet morning rising, in the pearly drops of dew, And the noon-tide's bright effulgence his
                            glorious presence view; When it retires at evening, in gorgeous, grand array, We see therein
                            Jehovah's mysterious majesty! When the gentle moon arises, and unveils her queenly face, She
                            but reflects an image of his wondrous, loving grace; And in the blue, arched heavens,
                            bespangled o'er with gold. Our God's unrivalled beauty and changeless love is told! In the
                            fury of the elements, when thunder shakes the main, And in the silent grandeur of the
                            lightning's lurid flame; In affliction's fearful tempest, in the spirit's peaceful calm,
                            Alike we see our Maker—the loving, Great I Am! Wrhere sin is not, there God is found—in life
                            that's pure and clean, And that theology 's not sound that will not life redeem.
                        Hancock.</p></div2><div2 type="dance" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Should Christians dance?" TEIform="index"/>"Should Christians Dance?"</head><p TEIform="p">A correspondent of The Religious Telescope, Dayton, 0., asks, " Should Christians Dance ?" it
                            answering in the negative, expresses wonder, that any one who believes in giving both soul
                            and body entirely to God's service, should ask such a question. We wonder if it ever read of
                            David's dancing before the ark " with all his might 1" Of the beautiful daughter of the high
                            priest, who went forth with timbrels and dances to greet the conquerors ? Does it recall the
                            circumstance, that when the prodigal son returned, he heard music and dancing ? and that out
                            of that house came one, representing our heavenly Parent, God ? Will it be so good as to
                            read the 12th and 13th verses of 31st Jeremiah, and ponder, particularly long on the latter
                            verse ? We are glad to hear this question asked. Will not some anxious ones inquire, "
                            Should Christians Fight or Marry, or gratify their appetites in unchristian lusts ? should
                            Christians hold private property ? should the Christians of one Church be both rich and poor
                            ? if so, by whose authority or permission ? did the founder of Christianity inaugurate the
                            new doctrine by permitting the above licenses or by abrogating them ?" There are many
                            practices, worse than dancing, in which professional Christians engage without any seeming
                            compunction; but which are disgraceful, and impossible for the practical follower of Christ
                            to endorse. Admitting that David and Miriam were not Christians, yet they are revered by
                            professional Christians, who seem to take no umbrage at their acts. We assert, that
                            Christians do dance; and further, that when professors of Christianity shall all have
                            forsaken their fleshly lusts, their pride, and worldly ambitions generally, they will dance
                            with great joy at their deliverance from these bonds ; and still further, that the clergy of
                            to-day, will be amo?ig the most powerful dancers. *</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Publications, previous to 'The Shaker,'..." TEIform="index"/>Publications, previous to 'The Shaker,'...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Publications, previous to " The Shaker," issued by Believers concerning their doctrines,
                            Avere issued too soon for the appreciation of the world, and may now be laid aside as
                            historical. Something fresh, like new discourses, from the fountain, is always the more
                            palatable. A great many of our fellow beings are now no doubt looking and wishing for
                            something new and higher than the old standard of theology. I have been astonished
                            (particularly in the time of the war) to hear of individuals who had never seen nor heard of
                            the Shakers. So for the sake of sincere souls we are glad to believe " The Shaker " is in
                            season. The information respecting the Shakers in this quar<pb n="72" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER*
                            ter (Ky.) has mostly been founded on slanderous reports. Light hath need to Come out of the
                            East. May not the Eastern world be properly called masculine ? The theory or germ of all
                            arts, sciences, politics, governments and religions that have issued therefrom, never seem
                            to fully develop until they reach the American (or more justly the Columbian) soil. She
                            (America) will take all theories through the ordeal of righteousness, and if not approved,
                            will by her be corrected, modified or expelled from the natal sphere; so that persecution,
                            the engine of extreme intolerance, never can find an abiding foothold on her soil " while
                            the world stands." The fond dreamers of monarchy, aristocracy, slavery, and of vicarious
                            atonement, fore-ordination, election and reprobation, without regard to works; Christians
                            living in sin, and believing in a physical resurrection, are already .disturbed and uneasy
                            in their slumbers by the sound of the gospel trumpet. Think, too, of the foolish theory of
                            being born and regenerated without the co-operation of a Mother ! It is apt to be the case
                            when a child is ignorant of having a Mother, it cannot know much about its Father. All
                            errors are shades or casts of ignorance, and ignorance abides in darkness—sin. Is not
                            Shakerism the only doctrine on earth built on the Spirit, and draweth together and formeth a
                            body ? If this is the case, will not all others divide, subdivide and scatter to the four
                            winds, because of being built on the letter, not on the Spirit ? If the institution of Be-
                            lievers had been thus started it would have gone down long ago. But being neither the
                            planning of man nor woman, it has withstood much prejudice, opposition, persecution, pri-
                            vation, fatigue, hunger and thirst, heat and cold, day and night, adversity and.prosperity.
                            The work is of God, and the eulogy to Him belongs. The " well done " is due in glory to God.
                            Man is but a worm of the dust. We believe that a new cycle and progressive step is rapidly
                            approaching, and can welcome the dawn of a brighter day.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Barnett, John" TEIform="persName"/>John Barnett, Pleasant Hill, Ky.</byline></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Answers to Correspondents" TEIform="index"/>Answers to Correspondents
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Q. Is God a Trinity—Father, Son and Holy Ghost? A. To us, God is a duality, male and female
                            —Heavenly Father, Wisdom, and Comforting Mother Love. Q. "Was not man made in God's image ?
                            A. Certainly; "male and female, God created them." Q. Is not man a trinity—body, soul and
                            spirit ? A. Man, being created in the image of God, is male and female—dual. Q. Is not man a
                            trinity—understanding, wffl, affections ? A. Man has five senses and many affections. Q.
                            Does not Paul say : "May your body, soul and spirit be blameless ?" A. We believe you have
                            quoted correctly. Q. Does not scripture say : " Dividing asunder soul and spirit ?
                            "&gt;. A. It does.' Q. What is the difference between soul and spirit ? A. To which we
                            give an individual opinion, thus: The body is the soul's covering, or house; the soul is to
                            the spirit what the bodjr is to the soul. All created things may have a soul, but the human
                            soul alone contains a spirit. " And God breathed into (the animal) man the breath of life,
                            and he became a living soul." This breath allies man to his Maker closer than aught else.
                            The soul may wander into the ways of the transgressor—become dead through sin. Thus may the
                            soul be corrupted; but the spirit is incorruptible, inapproachable by sin, and this spirit
                            will lead the deadened soul back, through sufferings, to its Maker—God. The spirit and soul
                            are immortal. Q. Ts not God the same yesterday, to-day and forever ? A. We believe God to be
                            eternal—without change. Some of us have had revealed that all that has been called God, has
                            not represented the infinite Creator to perfection. Each cycle passed has had its God—the
                            best known representative spirit. The Jews had theirs— it permitted them to marry, fight,
                            hold private property, etc. The true Christians have their God represented by the Christ
                            spirit to Jesus and others. This representative of God will not permit its subjects to
                            marry, fight, " nor possess aught they can call their own." Under the dispensation of Moses,
                            God permitted and counselled retaliation; but under the more perfect type of the Infinite,
                            the rule is, " Love even your enemies !" The God which Christ represents introduces us to a
                            life that is eternal in the present tense—a virgin life, eternal here, and no change needs
                            occur that it may enter the abodes of the blessed. Not so with those who fight, who are
                            husbands or wives, or who engage in sinfulness. To us, the Spirit Christ is a fitting
                            representative of the Infinite. *</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Mt. Lebanon.—The South Family have been improving the appearance of the village by
                                clapboarding their laundry building — previously plastered externally ; several new
                                slate roofs are noticeable also. Second Family have razed the old landmark south of the
                                dwelling-house—quite an improvement. They have slated the roof of the office-barn,
                                surmounting the same with cupola and a glittering vane, which seems inviting the wind to
                                blow from the right direction. Second Order have repainted their dwelling, rising quite
                                high to do it. They have also re-roofed several buildings. Cart shed has had new founda-
                                tion. Cow barn has been considerably repaired. The Church Family have put on 150 squares
                                of slate this season. We do not like the black paint on their beautiful; new fence.
                                North: This family ig re roofing brick shop, and making many other improvements. Canaan
                                Families are looking beautifully; pnint, with hard labor, have made a wonderful
                                transformation! May God bless lower family—Canaan ! The Society have made a donation of
                                SI,200 to Groveland.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watervliet, New York" TEIform="index"/>Watervliet, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Watervliet.—Company of visitors started for Mt. L. on the 8th. South Family have repainted
                                several buildings, and improved dooryard considerably. Res. Ed. of The Shaker officiated
                                at Mt L. Church, August 6th. This Society donated $800 to Groveland —a brotherly
                                offering.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Groveland, New York" TEIform="index"/>Groveland, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Groveland.—The ground, blackened by the late fire, is already improved by better
                                buildings than those burned. Much regret is felt that the beautiful trees destroyed
                                cannot be restored, only by years of patience. " So God works through the ages—when the
                                old disappears, something better takes its place. ' Be ye followers of God, dear
                                children.' " W. H. B. No one wishes Groveland a streak of good luck, more than The
                                Shaker. </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, Conn.</head><p TEIform="p">ENFIELD, Conn.—Church Family have built a new barn, 50 x 60, and are improving their
                                grass consider- ably. " Our Second Family arc building a large Sisters' shop and
                                wash-house, the progress of which, if noted monthly, would be rather quaint and simple.
                                Good health hei'e." </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shirley, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Shirley, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p"> Shirlei'.— Plenty of rain, of health and of blackberries—the latter twelve miles
                                distant. Early Rose potatoes, an abundant yield—thirteen hills make A bushel! If there
                                is a saint on the earth, the Boston Cultivator makes John Whiteley appear as one! </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watervliet, Ohio" TEIform="index"/>Watervliet, Ohio.</head><p TEIform="p"> Watervliet, O.—Harvest closed, commonly good yield; fmits, excepting berries, very
                                scarce. General health. </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pleasant Hill, Kentucky" TEIform="index"/>Pleasant Hill, Ky.</head><p TEIform="p"> Pleasant HIll.—Eight Swedes landed here on July 30th A protracted drouth .still
                                prevails; late crops and pastures will be very short. I5r. Bufus Bryant is able to walk
                                with staff. Thank him, kindly, for getting better. He intended starting for South Unidn
                                on the 8th August. Hortcncy G. Hooser, one of the earliest settlers of this place, has
                                sent us a communication for October She lately observed, that '' she1 had been trying a
                                long while to make nothing of hereelf, but could not Accomplish it; and would have to
                                abandon it." </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="South Union, Kentucky" TEIform="index"/>South. Union, Ky.</head><p TEIform="p"> SotTH Union.— The boiler for engine,used for pumping water, exploded; injuring engineer
                                Davis considerably. Paint has been doing wonders here. </p></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">Should be glad to get data from each Society by first of each month; unless received by
                                this time, we cannot insert. * Elder F. W. Evans has been successfully prosecuting a
                                course of lectures in London. We have received The Globe containing a good report of
                                one. The Golden Age, the most excellent of N. Y. journals, contained a characteristic
                                letter from him in Aug. 2. We received a letter for THE Shaker from his pen, but too
                                late for publication. He returns on the 24th of August. * </p></div3></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker, monthly journal, devoted to the exposition of religion, acording to Shaker theology" TEIform="index"/>THE SHAKER. MONTHLY JOURNAL, DEVOTED TO THE EXPOSITION OF RELIGION, ACCORDING TO SHAKER
                            THEOLOGY.</head><p TEIform="p">Fifty Cents, Per Annum, in Advance. G. A. Lomas, Resident Editor, Shakers, Albany Co., N. Y.
                        </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Members of society" TEIform="index"/>MEMBERS OF SOCIETY</head><p TEIform="p">Appointed to answer Correspondents, among whom are the Board of Editors. Elder F. W. Evans,
                            Mt. Lebanon, Columbia Co., N. Y. " Issachar Bates, Shakers, N. Y. " Calvin G( Reed, Mt.
                            Morris, Livingston Co., N. Y. " Simon Mabeo, West Pittsfield, Mass. " Stoughton Kellogg,
                            Thompson ville, Conn., Shakers. " Albert Battles, Tyringham, Berkshire Co., Mass. !1 Win,
                            Leonard, Ayer, Mass., Shakers. " John Whiteley, Shirley Village, Middlesex Co., Mass. "
                            Nehemiah Trull, Shaker Village, Merrimack Co., N. H " Henry Cummiugs, Enfield, Grafton Co.,
                            N. H. " John Bi Vance, Alfred, Shakers, York Co., Me. " Alonzo Gilmau, West Gloucester,
                            Cumberland Co., Me., Shakers, " Chas. Clapp, Union Village, Warren Co., O., Shakers. " Ezra
                            Sherman, Preston, Hamilton Co., Ohio, Shakers.' " Stephen Ball, Dayton. Shakers, Ohio. "
                            Jacob Kulp, Pleasant Hill, Mercer Co., Ky. " J. 11. Eadcs, South Union, Logan Co., Ky. " J.
                            S. Prescott, Cleveland, Ohio, Shakers. </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Publications" TEIform="index"/>PUBLICATIONS.</head><p TEIform="p"> Christ's First and Second Appearing Dunlavy's Manifesto Millennial Church - Compendium of
                            Shakerism • Three Discourses on United Interests Tracts free, where postage is paid. *1 25 1
                            25 1 00 0 50 0 50 72</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>