<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2602" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">20</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">East Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">26</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">2</biblScope><date value="18960201" TEIform="date">February 1896</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">25-40</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="26" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="2" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
THE
MANIFESTO
THE   ALTRUIST.
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is published by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all
their property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing
officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. 50 cents a year;
specimen copy free. Address A. Loxgley.
Higbee,   Mo.
Go.od reliable men,   to sell
our    Choice    and     Hardy
Nursery Stock sucli as Fruit
Trees, Roses Shrubs and OrWANTED
namentals. Ladies make this business a success. Easy work, pleasant, light and profitable. Outfit Free. Apply at once, with references, and secure choice of territory.
F.  N.  MAY   COMPANY,
Nurserymen   and   Seedsmen,   Rochester, N. Y.
WANTED SALESMEN
We
want
one or
   two GOOD MEN in each County to take
orders for a Choice line of NURSERY
STOCK or SEED POTATOES- Stock and
Seed guaranteed. We can give you Steady
Employment with Regular Pay. It will
cost you nothing to give it a trial. State when
writing which yor prefer to sell.   Address
The Hawks Nursery Co.,
Rochester, N. Y.
Largest circulation of any scientific paper in the
world. Splendidly illustrated. No intelligent
man should be without it. Weekly, &:$ <0>a
year; gl.50 six months. Address, MTJNN& CO..
Publishers, 3G1 Broadway, New York City.
For information and free Handbook write to
MUNN & CO., 361 Broadway, New York.
Oldest bureau for securing patents in America.
Every patent taken out by us is brourrht before
the public by a notice given free of charge in the
TRADE MARKS9
DESIGN PATENTS,
COPYRIGHTS,   etc.
POUR
By Pressing the Lid.
Tea, and Coffee Pots that pour by the lid without lifting or tipping.     SimpJe beyond  belief.
Practical and artistic.   Send for pamphlet.
THE ASBURY-PAINE MFG. CO., Phila., Pa.
This is a good thingEd.
Scientific American
Agency for  --><pb n="" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Humility" TEIform="index"/>HUMILITY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Kaime, Joanna J." TEIform="persName"/>By Joanna J. Kaime.</byline><p TEIform="p">Within the "vale humility," Life's crystal streams abide, No scorching sun nor parching
                            drought Can stay the living tide; By earnest prayer and trusting love, With faith and works
                            combined The honest seeker after light. This peaceful vale may find. How many fail in growth
                            of soul Who climb the barren height Where worldly elements control And truth is lost to
                            sight. The Christian's faith will ever lead Where meekness lends her charm, For only those
                            who find this grace Shall win the victor's palm. Here in the shadow of God's love Is safety
                            for the soul, Here naught offends nor intercepts The spirit's wise control. I caught a
                            glimpse in youth's bright day Of blessings since made known To-day these are my
                            treasure-store, My everlasting home. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><pb n="25" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Natural and spiritual relations" TEIform="index"/>NATURAL AND SPIRITUAL RELATIONS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>By Martha J. Anderson.</byline><p TEIform="p">'6 V"T THILE he yet talked to the people, behold his mother and his brethVV ren stood without
                            desiring to speak with him. Then one said unto him, Behold, thy mother and thy brethren
                            stand without, desiring to speak with thee. But he answered and said unto him that told him,
                            Who is my mother? and who are my brethren? And he stretched forth his hand toward his
                            disciples and said, Behold my mother and my brethren! For whosoever shall do the will of my
                            Father which is in heaven, the same is my brother and sister and mother." To the natural
                            parent-heart, whose affections are wrapped up in the life and interests of their exclusive
                            familes, this language of the Master sounds harsh and unfeeling, because the narrow range of
                            vision precludes the broader view of life taken by him who has a wider horizon, and sees
                            things in their superior relationship. Not the mere ties of consanguinity, constitute true
                            and lasting friendship ; there is a moral unity that springs from soul sentiments, and this
                            sublime doctrine was emphasized in the text. The mind of Jesus glanced upward from every
                            topic. He loved not his own mother the less, for her heart was in sympathy with his mission.
                            It was as if he had said, "She is truly my mother, and they are my brethren in the higher
                            life ; but not alone she who bore and reaped me, but all who are likewise doing the will of
                            the universal Father and Mother of all souls, who have the well-springs of goodness and
                            truth in their hearts, are my relation." All true union and harmony of spirit springs from
                            moral conditions and not from those human instincts that we hold in common with the animal
                            creation. Sexual love and physical attraction, spring from the sensual naFEBRUARY <pb n="26" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 26 THE MANIFESTO. ture, and is not man's highest estate of happiness The true
                            affection of the natural, should open to our thought the universal love and affection,
                            which, in the progressive state of unfoldtnent, shall exist between all truly good and pure
                            natures. "In Christ there is neither male nor female," which represents a condition of human
                            advancement, when fleshly lusts and desires shall be consumed by the indwelling of God's
                            Spirit. We should always seek in those that are nearest us in kinship of the Mesh, not that
                            which affiliates them to us as natural persons, but that which is to be perpetuated when the
                            body dies; we should strive to lift our heart's affections into the exalted sphere of
                            universal and permanent blending of heart and soul. Have we not all formed social,
                            intellectual and moral affinities that have proved stronger than natural ties ? Soul
                            friendship and comprehensive exchange of thought and feeling unknown in our own family
                            circle, where there is often estrangement because of difference of opinion among the members
                            of the household? There is a growing tendency in this age of alliances, to concentrate for
                            mutual good. There seems to be two spirits at work in opposite directions, one in the form
                            of trusts and monopolies for individual aggrandizement; another in the form of co-operation
                            and guilds for the fraternization and benefit of the masses, who are the wage slaves of the
                            moneyed classes. Progress, like the spiral motion of all things, tends to ever increasing
                            life and activity, which draws humanity in its vortex, for the process of unification of
                            thought and feeling. What seems to be evil in our present state of civilization will
                            eventuate in good. The higher tendencies of human nature have their root in the lower life.
                            There is a wise Parental government over this earth and that same power that rules not only
                            the earth but the heavens also, will through natural evolutionary processes, bring order out
                            of chaos. Think for a moment how many associations are formed for wise and noble purposes,
                            how many men and women are aspiring for, and working toward the ideals of Edenic life. How
                            they are striving to ameliorate misery, studying its causes and applying the remedy for
                            injustice and wrong that is grinding the faces of the poor, creating crime, want and
                            wretchedness. The interchange of kindly services of good-will and active benevolence, binds
                            heart to heart, and in this universal love, mankind feel that they are all brothers and
                            sisters; that the strong must protect the weak and the more fortunate uplift those who have
                            not the impulse or will to rise to superior conditions. Unsanctified passion and not love,
                            produces much of the unhappiness, in family and social circles. If there was more of real
                            love in the natural home life, there would be less evil generated and perpetuated in the
                            world. And no greater work of human love and uplifting can be accomplished than to search
                            out the sources and springs of immorality and licentiousness, <pb n="27" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFES TO. 2 7 which are undermining the sacredness of family, the purity of society, and
                            the stability of the state. We are drifting toward the condition Rome was in previous to her
                            downfall. When the youth are corrupt what have we to hope for? There is no remedy for this
                            laxity of morals, only that man shall be equally culpable, and equally judged and ostracized
                            with woman; sharing with her the disgrace of sinful acts. There are a few individuals who
                            have the courage to cry aloud and spare not, fearing not to lift the veil that screens
                            social uncleanness. Our children are not protected as they should be, even in the sanctity
                            of borne life; their instruction is meager on the most important themes that concern their
                            welfare and happiness especially in the relation of the sexes. When the moral sense is
                            blunted, the avenues of the soul are closed to the receptivity of spiritual truth as taught
                            by Jesus when he said unless a man hate his own life, (the carnal life) he could not be his
                            disciple. Truly has the thought been expressed "Purity of heart and life is the richest
                            human possession." Through this is sustained holy associations in the sphere of divine love.
                            The respect that grows from an appreciation of positive excellence, is a unitizing
                            iufluence, and helps to break down distinctions between men and women. The more interest we
                            take in the good and happiness of the many, and not center our entire thought in our own
                            interests, the more we shall enlarge our sphere of blessing as did the good Master whose
                            whole desire was continual service, and who was ready and willing to lay down his life for
                            his brethren. Mankind are evolving toward the spiritual, through the perfect natural state,
                            where self-restraint and continence, subdues the animal and the savage in their natures,
                            where love engendered in the coronal region of the brain, holds in control the selfish
                            propensities, that develop their foi'ce in the cerebellum or lower portion of the brain. The
                            essence of true religion is chastity and love which bind the soul to God. Human affections
                            are never carried to their exaltation of sweetness and beauty until they are made manifest
                            in the sphere of unselfish devotion. We should be nearer to each other as human beings in
                            those things we have in common with God, than in that we have in common with the animals.
                            All the great natures among mankind that have progressed under the influence of the genial
                            and all-illuminating sun of righteousness, and have shown the color and fruitage of the
                            seed-life of the Christ, have risen unto the resurrection of immortality. Jesus said,"If I
                            be lifted up, I will draw all men unto me." Why are churches divided into sects ? and why do
                            men look coldly on each other? Is it not because they place too much stress on difference of
                            opinion in minor matters, and chill the love of God in their hearts ? They expect to share
                            their heaven in common in the future, and yet drive themselves assun- <pb n="28" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/>
                            28 THE MANIFESTO. der while here. "In Christ there is no schism." His love metes out no
                            bounds nor limits. The only true union and fellowship lies in the interest and upbuilding of
                            a faith in man, "if we love not our brother whom we have seen, how can we love God whom we
                            have not seen." Jesus taught the law of love as expressed in the text, and in contiguous
                            passage, which it would be well for all to read and consider. The outcome would, if
                            practically carried out in every day life, result in the establishment of the Kingdom of
                            heaven, for which he prayed, and which we all have desired might come on the earth. May we
                            all be united in one common cause and kinship; to do good, to carry out the vital spirit of
                            religion which is "Love to God and the neighbor." Then they who do the will of God the same
                            will be our Father and Mother, our brother and sister. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Youthful days" TEIform="index"/>YOUTHFUL DAYS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Breedlove, Virgie" TEIform="persName"/>By Virgie Breedlove.</byline><p TEIform="p">A NOTHER year is to be numbered with the past. Its pleasures, joys -ZTjL and sorrows are
                            being written; some soon to be forgotten while others will ever remain on the tablet of
                            memory. Each day we are borne further from youth's shore. We should all remember that youth
                            is the time to lay a solid foundation for true and real happiness in after life, by the
                            cultivation of the noble powers of mind given us by a wise and beneficent Creator. If we
                            spend the strength and ardor of our youthful days in idly seeking for pleasure, the distant
                            future to which we now look so joyously, will be filled with vain regrets for wasted
                            opportunities and time unimproved. Some of the brightest examples of history show us the
                            wisdom of devoting our early life to the attainment of that knowledge and the cultivation of
                            those graces of heart and mind that may fit us not only for true enjoyments, but make us a
                            blessing to all humanity. South Union, Ky.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Unselfish" TEIform="index"/>UNSELFISH.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cumings, Ann" TEIform="persName"/>By Ann Cumings.</byline><p TEIform="p">"Wherefore I say unto thee, her sins, which are many, are forgiven, for she loved much: but
                            where little is forgiven the same loveth little."Luke, vii., 47. TTTE are told that an
                            acknowledged sinner finds forgiveness, for the reaV V son that she loved much; also that
                            where little is forgiven, the same loveth little. Who that has known what it was to feel
                            that before God, and <pb n="29" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 29 the light of an awakened
                            conscience, he was sinful, and needed the forgiveness of God, can fail to appreciate the
                            worth of this divine blessing, and feel himself under some obligation to extend it to other
                            souls. In John, xxi., 15, Jesus asks, "Simon, son of Jonas, lovest thou me more than these?
                            " We may infer that Simon was surrounded by those who constitute the vine of the earth ;
                            fathei, mother, sister and brother. He said unto him. "Yea, Lord ; thou knowest that I love
                            thee." Then Jesus answered, "Feed my lambs," thus giving a practical demonstration of
                            professed love for him. Thrice the question is repeated, "Lovest thou me?" each time
                            receiving an affirmative answer, Simon is commanded, or requested to prove his love for the
                            Master by feeding his sheep and lambs. How unselfish the return desired, for the love the
                            disciple bore the Master. How unlike the element which seeks to accumulate and appropriate
                            for selfish ends, rather than befriend and minister unto his little ones, in his name. Again
                            Jesus says, "I am the good Shepherd and know my sheep and am known of mine. As the Father
                            knoweth me, even so know I the Father; and I lay down my life for the sheep. And other sheep
                            I have which are not of this fold ; them also I must bring, and they shall hear my voice,
                            and there shall be one fold and one Shepherd."John, x., 14, 15, 16. May we not imagine the
                            millennium very near, if not already come, when all the lost sheep of the house of Israel
                            are found by the good Shepherd, brought home, and there is one fold and one Shepherd?
                            Enfield, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Extract from a testimony spoken by sister Isabella Russell" TEIform="index"/>Extract from a
                            testimony spoken by Sister Isabella Russell, at Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">T 11HE subject of our Communal Home, with its motto "all for each, and -L each for all,"
                            which was so ably treated in our last Sabbath evening Service had the effect to draw from
                            many hearts the silent resolve, to henceforth use all powers of mind and body to make this
                            home so beautiful that no person having shared its benefits would wish to choose interests
                            less broadening in their relations. It is well to keep this "ideal home" before us through
                            all the difficulties of life's journey. Those who have been educated in this Church, and
                            have witnessed the various changes that have taken place within the last fifty years, have
                            realized some bitter disappointments, and have passed through many tssts of our faith in the
                            religion of our Fathers, who have "fought the good fight, and kept the faith," and whom we
                            believe are still on the upward march in the line of spiritual progression. They have left
                            not only their physical bodies, for which they have no further use, but also their errors
                            and miscon- <pb n="30" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 30 THE MANIFESTO. ceptions of the truth as it is understood
                            by the most spiritually enlightened minds of the present day. It is well with us, if our
                            experience has taught us lessons of charity, and forgiveness; if we have learned to be
                            consistent and kind in all our dealings with our fellow beings ; if we have learned to take
                            a deeper, broader view of God and of his dealings with the children of men, ever remembering
                            that "In our Father's house are many mansions" and there are different divisions in the
                            Christian army, all equally indispensable in working out the great plan of salvation. If we
                            have learned this grand truth, then we are better able to reach*the conditions of suffering
                            humanity. It becomes us as a band of Christian workers to "keep step" in the great battle
                            for justice, truth and right, by putting our "hands at work, and giving our hearts to God,"
                            ever maintaining an interest in the spiritual home which is ours by right of inheritance if
                            we are faithful to our early vows of consecration. We should never forget our obligations to
                            those who have laid the foundation of our Church, nor our duty to the teachers of the
                            present day. If our relationship as spiritual Brethren and Sisters is what we claim it to
                            be, then we must continually discountenance every element that is foreign to this grand
                            result,perfect equality. It is not enough to know that the spirit of Christ was made
                            manifest one hundred years ago, through one inspired woman whom we honor with the endearing
                            title of Mother; but we must manifest this same Christian spirit in our lives. Let us ever
                            bear in mind, that no question pertaining to the spiritual, social or financial growth of
                            our Church will be permanently settled until it is done in conformity to the spirit of
                            Christ. When we are filled with the enthusiasm, which our cause demands, we can sing with
                            the spirit and with the understanding, Ye little rills as ye gently move, O waft the breeze
                            of a Savior's love! Ye mighty waves that in majesty roll, Carry the boon to every soul! Tell
                            them that I have come again, And in my kingdom forever shall reign, Where male and female
                            equally stand, United with the angelic band. Already is light dawning upon the world, and
                            many may be found in this enlighted age who, in some respects, are carrying this spirit of
                            equality and the recognition of this divine principle to even greater perfection than we
                            are. But this is no reason why we should renounce the strife, or forsake the field where our
                            Mother fought and won such glorious victories. Rather let us listen to the heavenly
                            footsteps marching to the strains while we sing the song triumphant, "Surely, Christ lias
                            come again." Now is come complete salvation, Perfect order is revealed, Sons and daughters
                            standing equal Eeap with joy the gospel field.</p></div2><pb n="31" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="Section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beloved Elder Henry;--A rumor reaches us..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Beloved Elder Henry;--A rumor reaches us...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Maine, Alfred, January 1896" TEIform="index"/>Alfred, Me. Jan. 1896.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Beloved Elder Henry ;A rumor reaches us that our Manifesto is to be discontinued. I hope
                                if so concluded the conclusion will be reconsidered. This is the feeling of the
                                Societies in Maine. As Home Notes would have nothing of especial interest, will you find
                                room for the following reasons so well stated by Br. Alonzo Hollister in his Morning
                                Star Bible Lessons. Why Believers in the past as well the present appeal to the Bible to
                                sustain their views. I. "Because it is a true and impartial witness that we are guided
                                by the same spirit which inspired the utterance of Ancient Seers, Apostles and Prophets.
                                II. Because nearly all who claim to be Christians, forming a large part of the more
                                enlightened nations profess to receive the Bible as the only test of all religious
                                truth. III. Because many candid people can more readily perceive and acknowledge truth,
                                when they find it agrees with Bible doctrine, than when it stands solely on its own
                                merits. IV. Because only axiomatic truths which are common to all can be firmly
                                established in the mind without witnesses; which means proof by other acknowledged
                                truths which agree with, and confirm it. V. Because the work in which we are engaged, is
                                fulfilling many grand and wonderful predictions recorded in the Bible. A strange work,
                                which the children of men are no wise disposed to believe, though angels declare it to
                                them. VI. Because it is a work, which to minds not experienced in its effects, finds its
                                strongest evidence of being the work of God, in those inspired predictions, and the
                                lives of its subjects. VII. Because the spiritually sensitive feel a substance in the
                                language of the Bible, which speaks to the interior, and can not be found in any book of
                                less spiritual origin. VIII. Because the greater the number of agreeing and truthful
                                witnesses to any doctrine or principle, the stronger and more established it is to the
                                reasonable mind of true understanding." We believe as he does "that nothing is gained by
                                disparaging the Scriptures. A blow aimed at the Bible is a blow at spiritual-mindedness
                                and is liable to recoil with serious loss to the sower of contemptuous remarks thereon."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Vance, John B." TEIform="persName"/>John B. Vance.</byline></div3></div2><pb n="32" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian repose" TEIform="index"/>CHRISTIAN REPOSE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, Oliver C." TEIform="persName"/>By Oliver C. Hampton.</byline><p TEIform="p">"TjlAITH in God, in Christ and Mother is the first requisite toward ClirisJL' tian repose,
                            but it is not the only one. To be sure, without this it is impossible to attain to celestial
                            tranquility, but with this alone, it is also impossible. So long as anything with which the
                            mind is connected seems unpleasant, peace and rest will continue to be wanting. But these
                            unpleasant states of mind can be removed in two ways. First by removing the cause if
                            possible. If this can not be done, then second, by patient, cheerful waiting and endurance.
                            This is mental and spiritual discipline, and though sometimes painful, yet is indispensably
                            necessary for without it Christian repose is out of the question. This discipline is easily
                            found if we will only wait and take it as it comes. Our abnormal conditions may be pain,
                            sorrow, and even agony at times. It may be selfishness, envy or revenge; it may be a desire
                            for carnal indulgences ; but the endurance of this discipline may be made valuable by some
                            relieving considerations which crop out with my experience of later years and afford great
                            comfort at times. If moved to anger, in every instance I feel better and rejoice in my
                            spirit if I give no vent in angry words. Spiritual repose and serenity soon follow. In
                            sorrow, from whatever cause, I ask myself, "Is this normal? Does the spirit of the Lord ever
                            feel sorrowful?" I answer, "Never." Then if "I and my Father are one," this sorrow and agony
                            are abnormal, so "I look to the rock that is higher than I" and ask for a measure of
                            consolation from the infinite store-bouse of all consolation to fill this vaccuum in my
                            spirit. Soon better feelings prevail and sweet Christian repose silently settles upon me
                            like the dew of Herman and as silently, for noise, tumult and war are not favorable to the
                            removal of sorrow. I say from the Bible, "Be still and know that I am God," or, "Stand still
                            and see the salvation of God." So, gradually the sun comes out and the clouds of sorrow take
                            to themselves wings and silently pass away. If anything like envy appear, I say "All the
                            good of the universe is on its way to you and how foolish you must be to envy the little
                            tittle of enjoyment some one has who waited for it for years. Then I try to rejoice in the
                            good fortune of him who was the envied object. Then envy dies and love overflows on all.
                            When low or sensual thoughts intrude upon the mind how beautiful and salutary is prayer. One
                            who seeks shelter in this good gift is soon able to cause low suggestions to flee, even to
                            the uttermost parts of Egypt, leaving the emancipated spirit in profound Christian peace and
                            repose. There is one perpetual consolation that can never wane nor grow faint through our
                            long journey to our destined rest,that is, that these periods of uneasiness and discontent
                            became fewer and fewer, and farther and farther between, in the Christian's life and finally
                            culminate in invulnerable peace and everlasting joy. Union Village, O.</p></div2><pb n="33" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Look before you leap" TEIform="index"/>LOOK BEFORE YOU LEAP.</head><p TEIform="p">OUR experience in life throws us into direct sympathy with the Apostolic preacher and we
                            share with him an anxiety for the protection of the church of God. His love for humanity
                            urged him to present all the dangers that were to be found in the way of their Christian
                            progress. Paul had received the testimony of Jesus and in publishing it had found that while
                            the Greeks lookt upon it as foolishness, it was to him the power of God to salvation. He had
                            preacht its simplicity of, faith and its simplicity of good works to the Romans, to the
                            Corinthians, to the Ephesians, and to many others. In these places he establisht churches
                            "in the unity of the faith and of the knowledge of the son of God." Do you wonder at his
                            anxiety lest thru the cares of the world and in the philosophy of a class of speculative
                            teachers they should be led aT.-ay from the truth? Knowing so well as he did of the dangers
                            that were to be found on every side, his warning voice was distinctly heard among his
                            people. "Beware lest any man spoil you thru philosophy and vain deceit, after the rudiments
                            of the world and not after Christ."Col. ii., 8. This Pagan philosophy would no doubt, spoil
                            some. Whatever may absorb the attention and turn the spiritual interests away from the
                            Kingdom of God, will undoubtedly lead toward a worldly life. That this same philosophy has
                            spoiled many beautiful minds and thrown them from the path which led toward God has all the
                            force of historical evidence. All men do not walk the same road as they go down to
                            perdition. There are a thousand avenues thrown open and filled with enticing allurements,
                            thru which every man may pass that turns from right to wrong or from light to darkness. The
                            school of Alexandria was, no doubt, ruinous to that order of Christianity that was
                            establisht by the sacred teacher, as it made itself busy in amalgamating the doctrines of
                            the Christians and Pagans and by filling the churches with that which was spurious. From
                            that day to this it has had a markt effect upon the Christian world. Osterwald wisely
                            observes"Carnal men could not endure the cross nor divest themselves of the love of wealth
                            and pleasures, and by this means they corrupted the pure doctrine of the gospel. Their pride
                            and presumption prompted them to stand at the head of affairs and they wickedly contrived
                            means by getting into power and assuming an author- <pb n="34" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 34 THE MANIFESTO.
                            ity and expounding the writings of the Apostles by a blind philosophy which carnal men like
                            themselves had invented." Mosheim writes,"These men invented questions about the Christian
                            religion sufficient to perplex and puzzle the whole world." What a comment on the simple
                            testimony of Jesus and on Christianity at that early date. Here is another sad example of
                            the church walking by the side of the world. In this case the church "stoops to conquer" by
                            accepting the friendship of the world, but unfortunately the church has never been able to
                            rise again and stand erect. It is not strange that men were ruined by these flattering forms
                            of philosophy and then thru the deceitfulness of these enticing illustrations. But the end
                            is not yet. Men are at t his day equally perplext and puzzled to determine what is genuine
                            Christianity as taught by Jesus and what may be set down as the spurious innovations of
                            Pagan philosophy. Some who would be good Christians are sadly deceived. They know that the
                            church of Christ must be a pure church and that to be a disciple of Jesus they must fulfill
                            the law of righteousness, agreeably to the sermon on the Mount, and when the voice of God
                            cames to them to enter in at the strait gate they find themselves quite ready to pass into
                            the broad way. They have been flattered by the world, and have foolishly wandered into the
                            elements of a carnal life. They have persuaded themselves that as it was a Christian
                            philosophy it would lead directly to the Holy City. Here comes the danger.Should they fail
                            to fulfill the law of righteousness, they may be spoilt, as they mourn for the old
                            inheritance. Called of God to forsake the world with all its affections and lusts they
                            soothe their consciences by catching at the words of one who offered carnal indulgences to a
                            licentious class of would-be Christians. They had heard the words of Jesus the Christ
                            preacht again and again, but had failed to see the fruits of practical righteousness
                            developt in their own lives. We may readily suppose that the Apostle knew quite well the
                            dangers that were around the church. He knew that the testimony of Jesus had proved amply
                            sufficient for the salvation of those who had accepted it. That it was a religion that
                            entered into the life of man and was manifested thru a living and growing righteousness.
                            That the kingdom of God was obtained thru the sacrifice of every selfish interest. There was
                            nothing mysterious in the requirement and it needed no philosophy of the schools of Pagan
                            wise men to give to it their interpretation. <pb n="35" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 35 It is
                            remarkable how easily one class of men can undo and scatter to the winds that which others
                            have earnestly and prayerfully labored to establish in the heart. The Apostle well
                            understood the operation of this upon the mind and hence his caution to the brethren to
                            beware of that class of men who made it a money business to talk religion. They were not
                            workers of righteousness, interested in the welfare of the race, but they were talkers and
                            Paul saw the danger, that thru their philosophy, and thru their deceitfulness, and thru
                            their ministration of the spirit of the world his brethren might be turned from God. This
                            same danger is as apparent at the present time. It may not be found to be exactly after the
                            manner of this historical record, but it comes as effectually and ruins us as thoroughly.
                            With the light that is now upon the earth and the many degrees of righteousness that are
                            operating in the hearts of men, there exists the same danger lest thru the deceitfulness of
                            this seductive element many faithful souls may be turned from their honorable course as
                            God's workmen and be again lost in the wilderness of sin.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/>H. C. Blinn.</byline></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">3P=Those who are sending The Manifesto to Mrs. Dammer, Mr. Barnett, of Milwaukee, Wis., are
                            informed that they are not taken from the Post Office. TOIL ON. ft3P0uR Publishers have been
                            looking at The Manifesto and then at their- - - - - - - - -but at last concluded to "Toil
                            on" for the present, but to make the paper a little less expensive. 00ERE0TI0N. ISPTn
                            January Manifesto, page 18Conrad Human should read Conrad Auman.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If your purposes are noble..." TEIform="index"/>If your purposes are noble...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">If your purposes are noble, And your heart is brave and true, Then repulses strong or many
                            Can not turn nor weaken you.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., L. S." TEIform="persName"/>L. S. B.</byline></div2><pb n="36" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. FEBRUARY, 1896. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is published by the
                            "United Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued
                            regularly by the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the
                            religi jus views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. Address all
                            communications to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. December. Thermometer. Bain. Snow. 1894. 25.6 34 in.
                                19.25 in. 1895. 31.52 4.5 " 2 Highest Temp, during this mo. 58 above 0 Lowest " " " " 0
                                " " Number of rainy days " " 5 " snowy " " " 3 " " clear " " " 11 " cloudy" " " 12 C. G.
                                Reed. Jan. 1896. "The days begin to lengthen And the cold begins to strengthen." And O
                                how strong it is too. On New Year's Day the mountain brook was "rumbling and tumbling
                                and roaring and pouring" down the hillside, and the air was just cool enough to create
                                one of the prettiest and most interesting panoramas which Nature is pleased to give us.
                                Fringes of transparent ice hung along its margin, while each obstacle to its steady flow
                                was a "thing of beauty." It was a novelty to be roaming the brown hillsides on the first
                                of January, to admire waterfalls etc., and while we liked the mild weather, we knew the
                                cold was somewhere in keeping for us, and desired it to come in its season. But we have
                                no longer any hopes nor fears for an open winter. Old Borealis has pressed the mercury
                                down far into the zeros. Snow has covered the brown hillsides. The brook has gone to
                                sleep i n its tracks, and the ice crop is growing, ready for the near harvest. In "Ten
                                Times One is Ten," by Dr. E. E. Hale, how easily the whole world becomes a common
                                brotherhood, by the simple process of forgetting self, and lifting up those about, into
                                the light of love and kindly deeds. Self-improvement is good, but self-forgetfulness is
                                better. Real good manners and courteous behavior, spring from kindness of heart. The
                                humblest and sweetest of poets, beautifully says: "Hope not the cure of sin till self is
                                dead." Amelia J. Calver. North Family. Jan. At present date the mercury marks zero, but
                                up to the close of the old year the weather continued mild and beautiful, which, with
                                abundant water supply enabled our good Brethren to change the location and appearance of
                                a large woodpile. They have also been hauling gravel with which to improve the road
                                leading to Lebanon Springs. Christmas-tide abounded with joy and blessing. A beautiful
                                tree well hung with gifts was particularly appreciated by the youth and children who
                                helpt in its decoration. Eecitations and offerings from old and young were a pleasant
                                feature of the afternoon. On that occasion we commenced a change long desired by many in
                                the family; two meals on that day and on Sabbaths for the future if found satisfactory.
                                Although our written words may not 1896. <pb n="37" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 37 meet
                                the eye of gospel friends until several weeks of the new year have passed, we hope that
                                some spark of the Divine energy has sped our thought currents outward to mingle with
                                their kindred-tide;the true desires, holy aspirations and earnest resolutions of other
                                hearts to find indeed a New Year in spiritual progress. Strong in faith that "God's work
                                will stand;" debtors to the wise and the unwise, remembering failures and errors of the
                                past only as lessons for the future; forgiving as we would be forgiven; loving as we
                                would be loved, we desire to feel our souls united with all who are working for an
                                increase of righteousness in the earth. Catherine Allen.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">North. Family. Jan. 1896. The festive season of Christinas and New Years have come and
                                gone and with their advent have been renewed the pledges formerly given on such
                                occasions to be more faithful in life's duties and help advance upward the great
                                struggling soul of humanity. We enjoyed on Christinas day with our gospel kindred of the
                                Society a time of spiritual refreshing, many testimonies being given appropriate to the
                                occasion. Meeting was held at the Church at 10 o'clock a. m. Also on New Year's evening
                                by invitation of the Elders of the North family, Society meeting was held at the North,
                                the first one since we came here. It was some two hours long. Opening hymn, "Season of
                                Devotion." It was with great pleasure that we held communion through the Jan. Manifesto
                                with our beloved spiritual Father Elder Abraham Perkins; and it is joy to sit at the
                                feet of such veterans and receive their ministrations. Brother Arthur Bruce of East
                                Canterbury gave us a call for a day or two last month, and if we could have a few more
                                calls from gospel friends at Canterbury and elsewhere how the smiles would illuminate
                                our countenance and with what joy we would labor to minister to their comfort.
                                Anticipation is a beneficial stimulant if the brightest and best in life is looked for;
                                in the coming year we will labor to have this form of it the sun which will illuminate
                                our pathway. Htmi/ton DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harvard, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Harvard, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">Jan. 1896. According to Nature's inexorable laws we have passed the last stepping-stone
                                in the yearly circuit of time. The old year now lies upon his bier, soon to be Luried in
                                the dust of the past, while Boreas howls a mournful dirge in discordant notes. Sorrowful
                                as well as happy memories cluster around the old, while the new born year, is sweetly
                                slumbering upon its couch of joyful promises. Hope's bright star shines upon the future
                                and we journey on, very much as before, till we are another circuit nearer that unknown
                                land, "where the wicked cease from troubling and the weary are at rest." We commemorated
                                Christmas in a manner befitting the day. A morning song announced the hour of rising. In
                                the afternoon the young people entertained us with singing and personified rehearsals.
                                All received some token of kind remembrance and thus the day was happily and profitably
                                spent. May these holidays serve to awaken the latent good in the human heart that the
                                world may be made better by them. In the early part of December winter asserted his
                                powers so strongly that ice eight and nine inches thick was formed. All preparations for
                                harvesting it were made, when the rain descended and in less time than it took to
                                freeze, it was all gone, and we were disappointed. We are now hoping that winter is
                                through his fickleness and we expect better things. Usual health in Society, and all are
                                seeking to do duty in the spirit of "Peace on earth and good-will to men." Marcia M.
                                Bullard.</p></div3><pb n="38" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station, Ct.</head><p TEIform="p">Jan. 1896. "Work while the day lasts," said the Apostle. Let us strive to work for the
                                good of others, to uplift some sinking soul, to strengthen and cheer some sinsick one.
                                or arouse a weak and erring one to better endeavor. "We are bound for heaven go we
                                will." If we make our own heaven we shall be sure to have it. Pure living, kindly acts
                                and loving consideration make of home a heaven that one is in no haste to exchange for
                                heaven above. Each day brings its duty, and we shall have no time to do wrong if we do
                                those things that should be done. It makes the burden lighter on our journey home. Truth
                                and virtue are sure to win. Let us pledge ourselves to be true. The Manifesto is a
                                welcome visitor in our family, I enjoy reading it very much. It is a power for good. Our
                                new corn-husker and fodder-cutter combined, is a success. It will husk 400 bushels a
                                day. Now we can grow more corn. Daniel Orcutt. South Family. Jan. 1896. We have once
                                more been permitted to start out on a New Year. From the past how many memories come
                                thronging into the mind to cheer the swift-winged moments as they pass no more to
                                return. And though we charge to-day with fleetness There is a melancholy sweetness In
                                the name of days gone by. With firm and joyful steps we run the race that is set before
                                us, cheered .onward by a cloud of witnesses who have attained the goal and received the
                                crown. And is there not a voice whose sweet and powerful tones hush into stillness every
                                anxious fear, and promises rest to the way-worn, with submission the truest solace of
                                old age. The past month was unusually pleasant to close the year, and was favorable for
                                out of door work, such as ploughing and preparing the land for^pring also for wood
                                sawing. The greenhouse is fairly successful. We are getting some cucumbers for sale, and
                                tomatoes on the way. Our products sell fairly well and we shall probably cover the
                                expenses incurred in carrying it on this winter. January commenced quite pleasant has
                                changed to cold high winds, but no snow. Health prevails in our midst. With increased
                                zeal for the support of our loved Manifesto and a kindly greeting to all for the coming
                                year. Maria Witham.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To the memory of sister Rhoda Blake" TEIform="index"/>To the Memory of Sister RHODA BLAKE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Agnew, Hannah R." TEIform="persName"/>By Hannah R. Agnew.</byline><p TEIform="p">The ocean may boast of its pearls; Peru, of her silver and gold; Those bound to the things of
                            this world, Rejoice in their wealth, manifold. Keep silence! ye minions of earth; Your glory
                            and boasting are vain Compared with the eternal worth, Which souls by the cross do obtain.
                            Our Sister, the loved one now gone To a land never shadowed by night, As a rose in the blush
                            of the morn, Or a lily of sweetest delight, May bloom on forever, in Paradise fair,
                            Increasing the treasure, now gained; The lights, and the shades, of her life record there,
                            Show the excellence to which she attained. Enough! we have only to say, Our Sister is one of
                            the best; While all that is earthly is passing away, Her soul is eternally blest. Go, thou
                            lovely one, go in sweet peace; Thy work here, is faithfully done; From youth, to old age,
                            pure wealth you've increased, Heaven's Kingdom and crown you have won. Mt. Lebanon, N.
                        Y.</p></div2><pb n="39" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Children:--The salutation is..." TEIform="index"/>Dear Children:--The salutation is...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Connecticut, Shaker Station, January 1896" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station, Ct. Jan.
                            1896.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Deak Children:The salutation is, "A Happy New Year." A year to be glad, not to be bad. How
                            swiftly the years pass away. Make the most of this one. Each day form your own heaven and
                            you will be sure to have it. Happiness comes as you keep good vows. Keep the good
                            resolutions now that you should have kept last year. Some persons are always intending to do
                            better but never find time to begin. Now is your opportunity, do not miss it. Only to-day is
                            yours, wisely improve it. A good life will keep your conscience clear, and why should you
                            live a bad one? Make every day bright with kind words and good deeds. Give beauty and
                            happiness to the future by daily acts of kindness. The self-denying path is the way in which
                            you should walk. Denying self is a Christian duty. The more you subdue wrong the sweeter
                            will be the "Peace be unto you." The brightest jewel that can ever adorn your character is
                            purity. Strive for it with soul earnestness. You will never wish you had done less to win
                            the prize. Watch your thoughts, is advice worth regarding. When the heart is well guarded
                            evil can not enter. Sin not. Pledge yourself to be true. Think not that you can be untrue in
                            trifles and yet be trustworthy in more important things. To deviate from truthfulness in a
                            small degree will harden the heart and lead to greater departures from right. Only those who
                            have done well can expect the "well done." Commit yourself to God for guidance and
                            instruction. How much happier you become when you feel that He is shaping your lives, and
                            you are content to let Him, knowing that not one more trial comes to you than you are able
                            to bear, and that every cross and affliction is for your eternal good; and how much peace it
                            brings to you if you yield your entire will to his blessed keeping. Give thought, care and
                            pains, in forming a noble character, and* create a spiritual atmospere in which it will be
                            good to live. The crown that awaits you is bright, be guided by truth and right.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt.</byline></div2><div2 type="Section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/> KIND WORDS.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Sisters:--I was much pleased..." TEIform="index"/>Dear Sisters:--I was much pleased...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Maine, Sabbathday Lake, November 1895" TEIform="index"/>Sabbathbay Lake, Me. Nov.
                                1895.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Sisters:I was much pleased with those two lovely pictures of Sister L. A. S. that
                                you so kindly sent in my little package of Manifestos. If you should reprint the
                                "History of the Shakers" I would like to be informed. I have but very few of the books
                                left and shall soon send for more. Accept many thanks for your interest in the
                                Missionary labors which are appreciated by every true and devoted soul in our Zion home,
                                and also by the angels in heaven. Your Sister,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Mace, Aurelia G." TEIform="persName"/>Aurelia G. Mace.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">Mackintoshes and Rubber Clothing large commissions can be earned by retailing to users.
                            Sample free. Manufacturer, P. O. 1871 New York.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Strikes" TEIform="index"/>STRIKES.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Strikes are quite proper, only strike right; Strike to so7ne purpose, but not for
                                    a fight; Strike for your manhood, for honor and fame; Strike right and left till you
                                    win a good name; Strike for your freedom from all that is vile; Strike off
                                    companions who seek to beguile; Strike with the hammer, the sledge and the ax;
                                    Strike off bad habits, with troublesome tax; Strike out unaided, depend on no other;
                                    Strike without gloves and your foolishness smother; Strike off the fetters of
                                    fashion and pride; Strike where 'tis best, but let wisdom decide: Strike a good blow
                                    while the iron is hot; Strike and keep striking till you hit the right spot.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Landers, Lydia" TEIform="index"/>Lydia Landers
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Lydia Landers, at Pleasant Hill, Ky. Dec. 25, 1895. Age 93 years and 9 months. Sister
                                Lydia was a faithful, industrious member of the Community for more than forty-five
                                years. J. W. S.</p></div3></div2><pb n="40" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Popular monthly" TEIform="index"/>Popular Monthly
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The "Lee of Virginia" series will begin in the next (February) number of Frank Leslie's
                                Popular Monthly, with the introductory article specially written for it by Mrs. Rogek A.
                                Pryor, upon "The Ancestors of General Robert E. Lee," in P&gt;ngland and in Colonial
                                Virginia, and the times in which they lived. This article, and those to follow, will be
                                profusely illustrated, the whole forming mi authoritative pictorial chronicle of the
                                distinguished family which has given to America so many statesmen, warriors, and types
                                of chivalrous patriotism. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pleasant hours for boys and girls" TEIform="index"/>Pleasant Hours for Boys and Girls
                            </head><p TEIform="p">That bright and entertaining magazine for young people, Frank
                                Leslie's Pleasant Hours for Boys and Girls, has some particularly good things in its
                                January number. There is a beautifully illustrated article on "The United States Naval
                                Cadet," by Joseph Coblentz Groff, which tells how appointments to Annapolis are secured
                                and describes the daily life of the cadets; Charles Frederick Holder contributes a
                                splendid short story about some boys who caught sharks for a living: there is an article
                                telling how a boy may build a low-priced iceboat and learn to sail it, by Wilf. P. Pond;
                                an illustrated New Year's story in verse, by Ethel Hatton; a paper on "Snow Igloos and
                                Images, and How to Make Them," by J. Carter Beard; the continuation of' the two serials
                                by Edward S. Ellis and Jeannette H. Walworth; several other short stories, some tricks
                                and puzzles, and the editors interesting chat on the new books for boys and girls. Mrs.
                                Annie Trumbull Slosson, the author of "Fishin' Jimmy," had a strangely impressive
                                experience, a few years ago, while driving through the Green Mountain country of
                                Vermont. She met a man, a waif, who evidently believed himself to be the Christ. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sunday school times" TEIform="index"/>The Sunday School Times
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Under
                                the title "Through a Glass Darkly," Mrs. Slosson has written for The Sunday School Times
                                of December 21 a sketch of her meeting with this strange character. "No sermon," she
                                writes, no chant, no learned theological treatise, nay, not even the reading of the
                                Gospel story itself, had ever made that lonely life of the Stranger, the man of sorrows
                                and acquainted with grief, such a real thing to me." JOHN D. WATTLES &amp; CO. 1031
                                Walnut St. Philadelphia, Pa. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Journal of Hygeio-Therapy" TEIform="index"/>The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Journal of Hygeio-Theraphy. December. Contents. Life
                                Science Papers, No. 5; The Science of Phrenology; Social Reform; The Devil in the Pie;
                                The Past Year's Work; Vegetarian Banquet; Scrub Children; Vapor Bath; Horticulture;
                                Humaneness, etc. etc. Dr. T. V. Gifford &amp; Co., Kokoino, Ind.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Anti tobacco crusader" TEIform="index"/>The Anti Tobacco
                                Crusader
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Anti Tobacco
                                Crusader, is an interesting and no less valuable quarterly. It has reached No. 17, and
                                should be the New Year visitor in all Christian homes, as a warning against one of the
                                most unpleasant habits. Rum and Tobacco are generally classed as twin evils ami
                                certainly they are quite often found in close companionship. Rum generally enters by way
                                of the back door, while tobacco stands at the front. Christians take the tobacco with
                                them even to the church and poison the air. And then the minister takes it into the
                                pulpit as did the Rev. Solomon Spittle. Published by H. L. Hastings. 47 Cornhill,
                                Boston, Mass.  </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Weekly memorandum calendar" TEIform="index"/>Weekly Memorandum Calendar
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The "Weekly Memorandum Calendar" from the office of Stockbridge and
                                Sanders, "is a thing of beauty and a joy forever," or rather so long as the year 1896
                                may continue with us. Thoughtful minds have ornamented every page with beautiful red
                                figures and then provided ample room for a record of all the good things we might do,
                                and for the anticipated hopes of what we would like to do. Published by Stockbridge and
                                Sanders. No. 1 Depot St. Concord, N. H. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ladies' every sunday" TEIform="index"/>Ladies' Every Saturday
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The publishers of that great Philadelphia
                                literary success, the Ladies' Every Saturday, are offering another popular educational
                                competition with many beautiful Rewards con. sisting of a handsome gold watch, a
                                pneumatic bicycle, pair of genuine diamond ear-rings, handsome silk dress pattern,
                                imported music box, china dinner service, coin silver watch, banquet lamp, fifteen
                                volumes of Dicken's complete works, camera, phonoharps, etc., to those sending the
                                largest lists of words from letters contained in LIBERTY BELL, and not using the same
                                letter in any word more times than it is contained in L I-B-E-RT-Y B-E-L-L. Any of our
                                readers desiring to compete for these prizes, may do so by simply securing a copy of the
                                Ladies' Every Saturday (containing full particulars, etc.) from their newsdealer and
                                enclosing with their list the "competition coupon" cut therefrom, or by sending three
                                two cent stamps direct for a copy of this entertaining thirty-two page publication,
                                containing many letters of thanks from those who have received Rewards in previous
                                contests. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cosmopolitan" TEIform="index"/>Cosmopolitan
                            </head><p TEIform="p">No one ever thought of introducing so expensive a feature as lithographic
                                color work in the days when the leading magazines sold for $4.00 a year and 35 cents a
                                copy. But times change, and the magazines change with them. It has remained for The
                                Cosmopolitan, sold at one dollar a year, to put in an extensive lithographic plant
                                capable of printing 320,000 pages per day (one color.) The January issue presents as a
                                frontispiece a water, color drawing by Eric Pape, illustrating the last story by Robert
                                Louis Stevenson, which has probably never been excelled even in the pages of the finest
                                dollar French periodicals. The cover of The Cosmopolitan is also changed, a drawing of
                                nage length by the famous Paris artist Rossi, in lithographic colors on white paper
                                takes the place of the manilla back with its red stripe. Hereafter the cover is to be a
                                fresh surprise each month.</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p19"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
The Phrenological Journal ,\nd Science
of Health for January, 189(5, leads with a
phrenograph of Dr. M. L. Holbrook, the eminent hygienic author and lecturer of New
York. It is from a personal examination, by
Dr. Beall, and shows many points of agreement between well-known facts of Dr. Holbrook's career ami the developments of his
brain. Another phrenological description
follows of the same man made by Prof. L. N.
Fowler forty two years ago. Written so many
years apart by two men, neither of whom saw
the work of the other until after his own was
made, they afford very interesting material
for comparison. Prof. C. T. Parks explains
some striking peculiarities of eminent women, especially as regards their manner of
holding the hand. Two drawings are given
showing a strong and a weak thumb. Mrs. C.
F. Wells gives an account of her famous
brother, the late Prof. O. 8. Fowler. Many
will be interested in a portrait of John W.
Hildreth, the boy train-wrecker, also an imprint of his hand from which the editor, without knowing whose it was, gave a reading.
A sketch of Harry T. Hayward, the Minnesota murderer, with a table of measurements of
his head will attract attention in the North,
west.
Dr. H. S. Drayton continues his valuable
series on "Practical Psychology." Prof. Nelson Sizer describes "Household Pets" in the
Child Culture Department. The contributions
on hygiene present the usual variety, and the
editorial pages are especially strong. Dr.
Beall replies to a distinguished medical opponent of phrenology, and demonstrates the
utter fallacy of the objector's position, New
York; Fowler & Wells Co., 27 East Twentyfirst street. $1.50 per year. 15 cents single
number.
Ex-President Benjamin Harrison will discuss "The Presidential Office" very comprehensively in his "This Country of Ours" series;
in the forthcoming February Ladies' Home.Journal. He will detail the provisions and methods of electing a Chief Magistrate, and will
have much to say bearing upon the eligibility
of a President for re-election; will give his
views as to the length of the Presidential
term, and express rather decided opinions relative to the annoyance to which Presidents
are subjected from office-seekers. The article
is practical, based upon experience and observation, and is very timely. General Harrison
believes that the fears (expressed by the
framers of our Constitution) that the power
of the office is such as to enable an ambitious
incumbent to secure an indefinite succession
of terms have never been realized. In "practice the popular opinion has limited the eligibility   of   the  President to   one re-election.
But some of our lea ling and most thoughtful
public men have challenged the wisdom of
the four-year term, and have advocated six
years, usually accompanied with a pronibition of a second term. And unless some
method can be devised by which a less considerable part of the four-year term must be
given to hearing applicants for office and to
making appointments, it would be wise to
give the President, by extending the time, a
better chance to show what he can do for the
country.
Among the fruit and flower novelties which
1896 brings us, we notice that the enterprising
and reliable firm of James Vick's Sons, Rochester, N. Y., are already calling attention to
three, which seem to have won great favor
where known. They are the DOUBLE SWEET
PEA, the only one in the world true to name,
"Bride of Niagara," the "Early Leader Tomato," the earliest of all the early tomato
family and sure to become a great favorite,
and the already famous blackberry, the
"RATHBUN."
By the way, readers, are any of you so far
behind the times as not to know "Vick's
Floral Guide?" If an5' of you have never
seen it, send 10 cents to this firm at Rochester,
N. Y., and get a copy. You can deduct this
from the first order lor seeds anu the pleasure
and information their Guide will give you will
certainly induce you to keep up the acquaintance.
We have received a beautiful "Columbia
Pad Calendar" for 1896. Its nice arrangement
is in advance of former years, and presents a
greater charm by its liberal illustrations.
The Calendar can be obtained for five 2-cent
stamps by addressing the Calendar Department of the Pope Manufacturing Company
at Hartford, Conn.
The Pulpit for December has no less than
five sermons by the ministers of Presbyterian,
Congregational and United Evangelical. Each
is the embodiment of the best thoughts that
these Reverend brethren are able to present
to the readers of the Pulpit. The special
theology of these several churches may not
be of so much value to the general reader, but
the matured thoughts and the earnest lessons
on morality, the reverence for God and the
respect for religious subjects are all worthy
of the most careful attention.
Published by G. Holzapfel, Fredericksburg, Pa.
Word and Works for February opens with
a chapter on the moon, and the advice is,
"Ponder these things in your minds, study
the diagrams and above all familiarize yourself with the actual movements of the moon
in the heavens." A correct knowledge of the
moon as learned from Word and Works is far
preferable to the foolish whims that many
entertain. Not only has this number many
valuable articles on the subject of Astronomy
but one writer whose mind is more absorbed in the things of this -world writes about
Gold Bugs, and certainly we shall want to
know all that may be learned about them.
Send ten cents to the Office of Word and
Works, St. Louis, Mo. and read of these wonders of the heavens and the earth.
<pb n="" id="p20"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure.
A ciuiin  or   tartar  baking   powder.
Highest of all in ieav< ning strength.
Latent   United   /States   Government
Food report.
Koyal Baking Powder Oo.
106 Wall St., N. Y.
THE ALTRURIAN
per published by the ALTRURIA CO-OPERATIVE COLONY.    It   is   one   of  the
ablest   reform   journals   now  published.
Price: One Year 50 cents; Six Months, 25
cents; Ten Weeks, 10 cents.    Sample copies, no charge.
Alttiiiia. California.
"William H. 'Bryan, Busincu  Hang'.
[Any of our subscribers who maybe interested in learning more about th"e "Altrurians,"
can obtain a co.py of their interesting paper,
by addressing a postal card, to their Office in
Altruria, Cal. Ed.]
A SUMMARY VIEW
OF  THE
CHURCH,
OB
"United   Society    of    Believers"
It treats of the Bise and Progress of the
Society, together with the general Principles of the Faith and Testimony.
Price 50 cts.
(Established itGi )
fS Oldest, Lavesi. Ke.-t,
A Cheapest and the Only
^ weekly Be- -Paper in all
3 America. 3'! png-> p. 81.00
v> ii year.   Send for t -ce Sample.
SI.00 BEG- 3OOK  FREE
 t. t  ^ , IT) Randolpb 8t
 ^, 111,
Popular Science
NEWS
Nature, Invention,
Bctany, Electricity,
Chemistry, Medicine,
Hygiene
Fonurij BOSTON JOURNAL OF CEBDIBY
Enlarged and. Improved
Contains a large number of Short, Easy,
Practical, Interesting and Popular, Scientific
articles, that can be Appreciated and Enjoyed
by any intelligent reader, even though he
knew little or nothing of Science.
Profusely illustrated  and  Free
from Technicalities
Newsdealers, 10 cts.   $1.00 per year
^"Mention this paper for a sample copy.
Largest Circulation of any
Scientific Paper in the World.
PUBLISHED  MONTHLY  BY
BENJ. LILARD, New York.
A Visit to the
of EAST CANTERBURY,   N. H.
LLOYD II. OI-IAJVIMLiiaiR.U. 8 W
Liberally Illustrated with half tone
pictures of persons and places.
The Village of EAST CANTERBURY
is situated in one of the lovliest spots of
New Hampshire, and is high enough to
overlook the surrounding country.
Price 15 cts.
American Bee Journal
H
E
HEALTH
Is a six-page
weekly   paMILLENNIAL
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>