<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1210" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">12</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">10</biblScope><date value="18821001" TEIform="date">October 1882</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">217-240</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="12" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="10" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                    <pb n="t.p." id="p1"/>
                    <p> VOL. XII. OCTOBER. NO. 10 SHAKER Publislied by the United Societies. home at shirley, mass.
                        "Blessed are those that hear the word of God and keep it" SHAKER VILLAGE, N. H. 1882. OUR</p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>
                        </head>
                        <p> [Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                        --><pb n="217" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><!--
                    <div2 type="none">
                        <p> CONTENTS Longevity of Virgin Celibates, - 217 Shaker's picnic, - 229 Peter Ayers, .... 219 Notes, - - - 230
                            Baptism of Consecration, - 320 Juvenile, .... - 232 Forgiveness, .... 221 Letter Box, ..... 233 Self Conquest,
                            ..... - 222 Deaths,..... - 234 Story of Gideon, .... 222 Tomatoes as Food, 234 A Thought,..... - 223 Salt Point
                            Peace Convention, - 234 Life's Journey, .... 224 Good Bread, ..... 235 Give Him a Lift, .... - 225 Farm and
                            Garden, - 236 Labok, ...... 226 An Industrial Exhibition, 237 Tired of Life, .... , 226 Books and Papers, , - -
                            238 The Two Fires, .... 226 Select,...... 239 Signs of the Times, .... - 227 Music,—Endless Growth, - 240 Life
                            in the Woods, 228 Yol. XII. OCTOBEK, 1882. No. X. .1.1 ¦ </p>
                    </div2>
                    --><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Longevity of virgin celibates" TEIform="index"/>LONGEVITY OF VIRGIN CELIBATES</head><p TEIform="p"> [Wri ten fob The Alpha.] LONGEVITY OF VIRGIN CELIBATES. Editor of The Alpha :—It is with
                            very great pleasure and respect we witness the good work you and co-workers are doing to
                            reform society relative to its social and moral status. The human family., including all
                            nationsi races and tribes, are, and for untold ages have been, in very abnormal conditions
                            relative to the sexual relations of society, as affecting the physical, mental and spiritual
                            conditions of the race; and through the abnormal development of the passional nature, life
                            is not only vastly shortened, but its few fleeting years are loaded with pains, sorrows, and
                            blighted loves, with physical and mental debility and spiritual blindness, in consequence of
                            the enormous expenditure and waste of vital force that makes miserable and wretched the
                            so-called living, and prematurely loads the grave with millions born and unborn. The
                            abnormal passion-fires are transmitted from parents to children, and untold numbers of
                            physically deformed organizations and monstrosities, and idiotic mentalities are foisted
                            upon society, the fruitage of unbridled lust. It is a solemn truth, taught man by the
                            universal laws of nature, manifest in the positive and negative forces of creation,
                            operating in the mineral, vegetable and animal kingdoms combined, that the use, and the only
                            God-ordained use, of these forces, manifest as sex, is reproduction ; and every sexual
                            desire without the pale of this domain, in its normal sphere, confined to the bounds of
                            generative use, is a sore, an ugly ulcer, on creation's organism. Man, as the crowning link
                            in God's creative chain, was not equipped with animal emotion and sexual passion to enable
                            him to degenerate his race, and cast its lot below the four-legged brute creation. These
                            conditions of the race are terrible, but abnormal facts—monstrous blotches on creation's
                            face ! Had mankind always strictly lived in. <pb n="218" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 218 SHAKER MANIFESTO.
                            harmony with nature's laws as God instituted them, generation had been as innocent and
                            shameless a work as eating or drinking, and when the physical bearing powers of the mammal
                            sex were exhausted of reproductive vitality sexual commerce would necessarily end. Then,
                            were man only an animal, his heaven would have been perfected. But the human race is
                            possessed of soulspirit, a spiritual body and its vital force, as well as a physical frame
                            and its vitality. The full development and perfection of man on the physical plane could not
                            fill the demands of his angel nature, hence, had he been true to nature's laws in
                            generation, the period of life in time from the cessation of generation to the death of the
                            physical body would be normally spent in sexual seclusion and purity, while the twain
                            developed the angel life and lived in Edenic innocence, and thus living, would have taken
                            the Kingdom of Heaven by normal climbing of the ladder of progressive evolution. The only
                            just foundation for the plan of taking the Kingdom of Heaven "by violence and force," as
                            inaugurated by Jesus Christ, has its claims based on the fact of man's degraded and abnormal
                            generative life and corrupt sexual relation—drunk with abnormal desires. The violence and
                            force of teetotalism from the indulgence of scortatory sexual desire, abnormal animalism
                            appears to be the only alternative left to man to harvest him into the Kingdom of Heaven
                            state, a condition above the worldly, earthly order—Oman's culminative normal home ! We
                            observe that some of your antipodes in argument relative to tho effects of strict virgin
                            celibacy on the health of physical manhood, have asserted that strict virgin celibacy
                            contributes to atrophy of the muscular system, shortens life, and induces mental imbecility,
                            and refer to the Shakers as exhibitions of the fact. The positive opposite of these
                            assertions being the fact, as demonstrated by the experience of the Shaker Order for a
                            period of over one hundred years, we doubt not you are so interested in the cause of truth,
                            as we are, that you will take pleasure in giving to the public the facts Ave herewith
                            present you, as follows : On witnessing the discussion between yourself and Dr. Foote, Ave
                            sent a circular to each one of our seventeen Shaker societies, soliciting a statement from
                            their records of the average age at demise of both sexes, and each sex separately, of all
                            who have deceased in each society since the date of its inauguration. The following is a
                            condensed statement of their report: In five of the Shaker families in New Lebanon, Columbia
                            county, N. Y., the number of deaths .froin 1848 to 1850 Avas 29 persons, and their average
                            age was 70^ years—this included both sexes. In a list of deaths of 200 persons in the Shaker
                            society of Alfred, York county, Me., 100 of them Avere over 70 years of age ; 37 Avere from
                            80 to 90 years ; 13 from i)0 to 9 7 years ; the average of the 200 is 62 years, 9 months, 6
                            days, 2 hours. These, had been in the society nearly all of their days. They lived as do all
                            true Shakers, a virgin celibate life. In Watervliet society, N. Y., the number of deaths
                            from 1870 to 1880 was 39 ; the average age Avas 73 years. This included both sexes, and
                            those who had been society members most of their lives. <pb n="219" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. 219 Between 50 and GO years ago the Shakers abandoned the use of all distilled
                            liquors except a mere trifle in medicines. About 40 years ago they abandoned all fermented
                            liquors except a trifle in medicine, also the general use of tobacco in every form, except
                            to kill sheep ticks. About the same time they abandoned ali use of pork, and the consequence
                            of these reforms is, there has been only a very few cases of fevers or cancers during the
                            past 40 years—not a tenth part that there was formerly ; in some societies not a case of
                            cancer during the last 40 years. There are at the present time 14 persons in the New
                            Gloucester, Me., Shaker family who are over 70 years of age, and 7 of these are from 79 to
                            89 years of age ; all have good use of their limbs, able to go out of doors, and most of
                            them do yet a good day's work of choice. A similar record could be made in several oilier
                            societies. At Watervliet society, N. Y., there were only 3 deaths during 2 years, in a
                            family numbering from 100 to 120 person".</p></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Peter Ayers" TEIform="index"/> PETER AYERS</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>HENRY C BLINN</byline><p TEIform="p">(Continued fbom last number.) Peter Avers lived with his father about eight years after he
                            embraced the faith as preached by Ann Lee and her followers. Pie then entered the Society at
                            New Lebanon, where he lived four years. On a recent visit to Mt. Lebanon N. Y., I very
                            fortunately found the original bill of goods that he dedicated to the Society at that pl:icj
                            on the 10th of May, 1787 and signed by his own hand. Like most of the early settlers in this
                            country, he ''earned his bread by the sweat of the brow" and was not overburdened with
                            worldly goods. The list is as follows ;— One horse. One wagon, One lot of tackling, Two
                            cows, One, two year old heifer, 27 sheep, 25 pounds of wool. One chaise, 60 lbs. of flax,
                            130 lbs. of tobacco. O,ue axe, One saddle, One sleigh, One pad-lock. One pound worth of
                            pork, 14 bushe's of potatoes. One bed and bedding, 05 bushels of wheat, 1 G bushels of rye,
                            4 bushels of corn, Two sickles, 4 turkeys, 11 hens. One pair of plow irons, 2 chains, Four
                            dollars worth o;' fur, And 16 dollars in money. Peter says, "the above mentioned account is
                            what I brought with me when I came to the Church." When Father Job Bishop was commissioned
                            to organize the Society at Canterbury in 1792, Peter accompanied him, and on the 15th of
                            Feb. of that year, became a member of the Society, where he resided till the time of his
                            death. He was a diligent reader of the Bible and of Believers' publications. He was never at
                            a loss for an appropriate <pb n="220" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 220 SHAKER MANIFESTO. quotation. "'After I
                            laid aside my carnal weapons," said he, "I put on the whole armor of Christ, and commenced a
                            warfare against the world, the flesh and the devil." He had served an apprenticeship at the
                            hatter's trade, and for many yeari-j he was a manufacturer of fur and wool hats for the
                            society. For several years he took, a deep interest in an orchard of 1000 trees, and with
                            one yoke of oxen enclosed the piece with a heavy stone wall, besides raising several vast
                            monumental piles as he cleared the orchard of stone. He was one of the most able men in the
                            work of the hay iield, and mowed* his last swarth the season he was ninety years of age. By
                            many he will be better remembered as the "old hunter." With his two hounds and his trusty,
                            old flint gun, he would follow the trail of the foxes and raccoons from morning till night,
                            through the deep snow, without either food or rest. His outfit, however, was never wholly
                            complete unless he was equipped with a pair of ponderous snow shoes. Should fortune so favor
                            as to award either a fox or a raccoon, he would feel compensated for all the hardship of the
                            day. One year, Peter had a record of 23 foxes 12 raccoons and more than a score of crows.
                            For every fox and crow that he killed, he obtained a bounty from the selectmen of the town,
                            by the presentation of the right ear of the one and the head of the other. The universal
                            habit of dram drinking "for the stomach's sake" and the smoking and chewing of tobacco "for
                            aching heads" became a thorn that sadly afflicted the Community, but when it was proposed to
                            abandon the use of alcohol in 1828, Peter although now sixty eight years of age, not only
                            abstained from the drinking of drams, but with a corresponding zeal, cast his pipe and
                            tobacco box into the fire, and from that day was a free man. In appearance he was quite
                            short, thick set, having a large head, dark eyes, fair complexion, and straight hair. He
                            visited New Lebanon, in company with a brother and several sisters, in 1808, and in 181.2 he
                            made a second journey to the same place. On this last trip he obtained a set of carding
                            machines, which were manufactured at New Lebanon. They Avere placed in one of the mills at
                            Canterbury and were used for some forty years. Never having been afflicted with sickness,
                            till a short time before his decease, our good brother quietly and peacefully breathed his
                            last on the 14th of Sep. 1857 having reached the advanced age of 97 years and 2 days.
                            Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Baptism of consecration" TEIform="index"/>BAPTISM OF CONSECRATION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, Oliver C." TEIform="persName"/>OLIVER C. HAMPTON</byline><p TEIform="p">[REPUBLISHED BY REQUEST.] BAPTISM OF CONSECRATION. OLIVER C. HAMPTON. Sweet inspiration's
                            gilded wings Are hovering near the earth, And in her tuneful voice there rings The song of a
                            new birth— A birth to higher, holier life, The burden of her song; A birth from rudimental
                            strife, And every groveling wrong. My spirit feels her quickening power In every quivering
                            nerve, Forever, from this burning hour, Humanity to serve; To move in God's eternal peace,
                            In ministries of love ; To cause the tears of grief to cease Below me, and above ; <pb n="221" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 221 To make the bow of hope serene; To span the
                            mourner's sky; To rid earth of the monster sin, And every tear to dry. My inner temple first
                            to cleanse, And live a sinless life, Forgiving foes as well as friends, With patience ever
                            rife. Thus peals sweet inspiration's hymn Across the slumbering years, As on our planet's
                            glittering rim, Her angel form appears. She calls to you, she calls to me, To let our l;ght
                            so shine, That men shall be compelled to see, And own a power divine. The records of the
                            fading years May leave no history bright, Of all our labors, pains and tears, Or arduous
                            upward night. What matter, so we work in love, The work God gives us all, We walk serenely,
                            far above Fame's best or basest call. What though our pilgrimage be lone, And little rest we
                            find, Still they are angels of the throne, Who love and bless mankind. A preacher of reform
                            I'll be, And practice -what I preach, • And purpose of my destiny Sin shall not overreach.
                            So shall I walk heaven's heights sublime And bless my fellow man, While I remain in rolling
                            time, And in my weakness, can. To leave for aye the fogs of sense, The rudimental plane, And
                            take my final journey hence, Far holier heights to gain. Need we in starry realms to peer,
                            To find heaven's blest abode? We walk the heights of heaven here, If loving, pure, and good.
                            Ye saints above, ye saints below, Help me my vows to keep. Henceforward in this path to go,
                            Rich gems for heaven to reap— Rich harvests of the souls of men, Ripe for the realms above;
                            Rich spoils to take from earth's domain, By works of peace and love. Union Village,
                        Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Forgiveness" TEIform="index"/> FORGIVENESS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Kidd, E. A." TEIform="persName"/>E. A. KIDD.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Many have taken up this subject and expatiated on its beauties more freely and far better
                            than I can, and yet I have resolved to add a little more to this beautiful character. A
                            forgiving spirit is an emblem of Christianity, a gem that is worth our earnest endeavor to
                            possess. It is essential that all true Christians should possess this spirit, for it
                            manifests the sublime character of our Savior,—Showing forth the deep love and charity which
                            he felt for all mankind. As a Christian's duty lies in Christ's footsteps, so must all
                            Christians become likewise forgiving and charitable even as he was. He taught us to pray,
                            "Forgive us our debts as we forgive our debtors," which reminds me of an item of my own
                            experience, in early youth. I was taught the Lord's prayer and strictly enjoined to repeat
                            it every night before retiring; and although young I was really afraid to say, as we forgive
                            our debtors—without first reflecting whether I had forgiven my companions for any little
                            offence through the day. It is perfectly reasonable and consistent that we should forgive
                            each other, for we are all liable to err, and all want forgiveness, but if we forgive not,
                            how can we expect to be forgiven ? How beautiful was the forgiving spirit of our Savior, so
                            clearly illustrated in his answer to Peter's question. "How oft shall my brother sin against
                            me and I forgive him ? till seven times ? Jesus saith, I say not unto thee until seven times
                            ; but until seventy times seven." Matt, xviii. 21, 22. How sweet to the transgressor's ear
                            must sound the words,- <pb n="222" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 222 SHAKER MANIFESTO. I forgive you. They are
                            as incense from the altar of grace ; like the breath of angels. There are many instances in
                            which revengeful hearts have refused to give utterance to the mild, sweet words of
                            forgiveness, till it was too late; and afterwards regretted- it to the day of their death.
                            Such cases are very sad, but I hope in this enlightened age they are growing loss every day
                            ; for as the world becomes christianized mankind will grow gradually better and better. till
                            the spirit of wrong shall be abolished, and all will see as did Jesus of Nazareth,—the
                            beauty of living like angels. The necessity of preparing in this life for the world to come,
                            by gaining a complete victory over a carnal nature, and by living a life of angelic purity,
                            enables us, to. gain the salvation of our souls, A believe that all who are made acquainted
                            with the sufferings of our Savior and our Mother, will bless their memgr". Even on the cross
                            Jesus grayed, {-Father forgiv'e' them for they know not what they do," and O the numberless
                            sufferings Mother Ann endured, loth in England and America, but she freely forgave all her
                            persecutors. Such is this most excellent character, which beautifies and elevates the soul
                            to a standard of purity and loveliness, and sheds light and peace where-ever it abides. It
                            fills the rocky caverns of earth with sunshine, and beams radiantly on the ocean billows,
                            and O may this treasure be found every-where. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is but one step from companionship to slavery, when one associates with vice" TEIform="index"/>
                            It is but one step from companionship to slavery, when one associates with vice
                        </head><p TEIform="p">It is but one step from companionship to slavery, when one associates with vice.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Self conquest" TEIform="index"/> SELF CONQUEST</head><p TEIform="p"> Of heroes and heroship we hear much; hut there is a spiritual heroism little known; that of
                            man who resolves to conquer himself hardest of all conquests. Impatience, envy, rage,
                            selfishness, eager for success or sullen at defeat, passions of the flesh and passions of
                            the spirit these are his enemies. In the silent depths of the heart he sturdily fights his
                            battle. What he does and what he sutlers no man knoweth : God only knowsNot one bloody day
                            does he fight, at Waterloo or Yorktown and win fame forever; but all through his life does
                            he wage the war and win no fame. Not to lift himself to honor, but to forget himself, to
                            still the throbs of self-conscious disquiet and all selfish passions this is his endeavor.
                            In the midnight and in the morning, in the throng and in the silent hour, ever is it his
                            holy care and prayer to keep all right within him, to keep all just and true, to keep all
                            pure. Loneliness and neglect and sorrow may be upon his path, even as they were upon the
                            path of Christ.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Story of Gideon" TEIform="index"/> THE STORY OF GIDEON</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Elkins, Mary Ellen" TEIform="persName"/>Mary Ellen Elkins</byline><p TEIform="p">As found in Judges, VI, MARY ELLEN ELKlNS. [Written for, and read before the Bible class.] It
                            would seem that the children of Israel did not always learn obedience, even, from what they
                            suffered, for many times before and after this fearful experience, they were sold into the
                            hands of their enemies for the same transgressions. The Lord had been angry with them, on
                            several occasions, if we accept the Biblical language, and led them into captivity; but had
                            as many times been merciful and provided for their deliverance, which was, no doubt, as
                            great as their punishment was severe. Having brought the children of Israel out from the
                            land of the Egyptians, and delivered them from all their oppressors, the Lord gave them this
                            command; "I am the Lord your God; fear not the gods of the Amorites, in whose land ye
                            dwell." Living among an idolatrous people and strongly influenced by their customs and <pb n="223" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. ¦223 practices, it may have been almost beyond
                            human strength to have resisted the temptation to idolatry. Still we believe in the wisdom
                            and.kindness of the Father to that extent that we think He would not have commanded where
                            they were not able to obey. They continued, howover, in the worship of Baal, and to this sin
                            added the manufacturing of idols or strange gods, although they had suffered so long for
                            this same transgression. The mere act of disobedience, though in itself a sin, would seem
                            far less did it not remind us of the awful ingratitude which must have possessed their
                            hearts, that they could have forsaken and forgotten Him who had been their Powerful
                            Deliverer. Having been blest and assisted in times of great need, by friends in this life,
                            should we not feel a grateful obligation? What lesson then, may we learn from the suffering
                            experience of the children of Israel ? who pike us were only children of this world. Let us
                            not forget the Lord our God, as a daily Teacher, or as a superior Intelligence, or even as a
                            friend, servicable to us through the kindness of those who would lead us toward all that is
                            worthy and to which we should attain in this life, as really and as wonderfully as God led
                            the Israelites to the promised land of Canaan. On account of the numbers and the warlike
                            character of the Amorites and Midianites, through whose country the Israelites were obliged
                            to pass, these children of Israel were for a time, obliged to lade themselves in the dens
                            and caves of the mountains for safety. Here they cried unto the Lord in their affliction,
                            and again He appears for their salvation ! He now sends a prophet to show them, reprovingly,
                            the error of their ways ; then, as his agent He calls Gideon from the humble employment of
                            threshing wheat to save them, a nation of twelve thousand individuals, from the oppression
                            of the Midian host. The angel said unto Gideon; "The Lord is with thee." The young warrior,
                            however, was not ready to accept this assertion in full, but proposed a little
                            investigation. O Lord! said he, if this be so why is all this befallen us, and what about
                            the miracles of which our fathers told us, of the Lord bringing us up from the land of
                            Egypt. "Go in this thy might, and thou shalt save Israel, have not I sent thee?" Here the
                            warrior is again found wanting in faith, and says—"0 my Lord, if now I have found grace in
                            thy sight, show me a sign that thou talkest with me." How strange, that after nearly
                            nineteen centuries of Christian teaching, which the world has had, it has grown so little in
                            faith, that to-day we ask for signs and tests, even more than did the warrior of old. Gideon
                            said to the Lord, "Depart not hence I pray thee, until I return and bring a pres ent to set
                            before thee." • Had the Lord merely tarried for him without farther manifesting His
                            presence, would it have afforded sufficient proof to give him hope for his mission? How
                            wisely the Lord dealt with his unbelief by proving abundantly his ability to direct him.
                            Gideon had seen an angel of the Lord, face to face. His reverence and worshipful nature soon
                            found expression in the raising of an altar to the Lord. Are we not in some respects like
                            Gideon? Having received implicit faith and trust in a mediator, either human or divine, and
                            when our gospel parents who stand in the same relation to us, in this life, do we not
                            manifest as affectionate children the devotional feelings of the heart? From this lesson may
                            we learn to discriminate between the true and the false and pay homage alone to that which
                            is virtuous. This we may do in our [own peaceful home, where we find those to whom it is a
                            pleasure to offer the richest treasures of our lives, those who share our reverence and
                            highest esteem. Let us gather instruction from the biblical lessons of the past. Enfield, N.
                            H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thought" TEIform="index"/> A THOUGHT</head><p TEIform="p"> If not for thee, my Father, My work is truly wrought, My courage oft would fail me In
                            bearing as I ought. When no requite appeareth, And Thou thy face hath hid, I trust the hand
                            that rlealeth, And work as conscience bid.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W</byline></div2><pb n="224" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life's journey" TEIform="index"/> LIFE'S JOURNEY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/>ANTOINETTE DOOLITTLE</byline><p TEIform="p">Very few minds are capable of fully appreciating the many blessings with which we are
                            surrounded. We dwell in the midst of peace and plenty, while we hear of wars, floods,
                            earthquakes, pestilence and famine in distant lands ; but under the American flag, which
                            waves in the breezes from the shores of the Atlantic to the Pacific, and claims to protect
                            all who take shelter under its folds, in their civil and religious rights, we at the present
                            time are comparatively free ; for which we have cause of rejoicing ; and those especially
                            who are not bound by traditional and churchal creeds, and are so far made free by obedience
                            to truth, that they can worship God according to their conscience, and highest ideal of what
                            is most acceptable, have reason to give thanks. We find in our Zion home, where we are not
                            deluged in party strife and political contests, the boon of sweet peace ; and in our soul
                            communings heart responds to heart, and we can strengthen the fraternal bonds of a brother
                            and sisterhood in our home of peace, founded upon the broad basis of Universal Love, love to
                            God and to all human souls ! This condition ot things is brought about without the use of
                            carnal weapons but not without deep and earnest soul struggles, which require the whole
                            armor of Christian faith and fortitude, the same in kind that Jesus and his apostles put on
                            and wore while contending against the power of anti-christ within their own hearts, and the
                            apollyon hosts in human form, or those dark spiritual forces which come up from obscure
                            regions, where those spirits dwell wrho hate the light—because of evil deeds—and are ever
                            ready to darken wise counsel, avd destroy every new born child that is sent on errands of
                            mercy as messengers of Truth to the race of men, dwelling on the earth plane. All who are
                            thus equipped, wearing the heavenly shield, are able, and do commune with loving angels from
                            spheres of light, who gather around, both when they wake and when they sleep, and whisper in
                            their ears, "All is well!" Beautiful upon the mountains of justice and holiness are those
                            bright spirits who come with noiseless tread, laden with rich gifts of priceless worth from
                            the infinite Father and Mother, ready and Avilling to bestow freely, upon those who are
                            prepared to receive fruits of the land which lies beyond the scope of the mental vision and
                            is only spiritually discerned ! Such ministrations throw light upon the centuries that are
                            past, and help to solve many mysteries which have hung over the historic pages of ancient
                            date, both sacred and profane, and to give to each in a large measure, their proper place
                            and design ; and help to disabuse the mind, and free it from many absurdities that have
                            hitherto beclouded the understanding, and seemed paradoxical. They also impart vitality,
                            strength and courage to perform the duties of the present, and fill the heart with holy
                            aspirations regarding the future, and inspire with divine and hopeful energy to pursue the
                            journey of life, through the mist, the sunshine and the storm, through all its changing
                            seasons even to the end. The human mind is so constituted that it seldom remains at one
                            point long at a time, but is looking forward, reaching out towards the future. The journey
                            of <pb n="225" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 225 life is analogous to the seasons of the
                            year. Each season has its appropriate work, and its uses ; and it is highly necessary that
                            the functions of each should be performed in proper time, prelusive to that which is to
                            follow. Life, has its stern duties and realities which require energy and will force to
                            perform. When we speak of them in epic language they seem less austere. The poetical vesture
                            with which we clothe them, seems to throw a mellow light over them and helps us to see the
                            bright and beautiful side. Add to the melody of rhythm, musical harmony, and the deep
                            fountains of soul life are stirred, and gush forth in inspired song, and the inner spiritual
                            sight is opened, and we catch glimpses, "through the pearly gates that stand ajar"—a view of
                            our home to be, in the great beyond ! As the seasons of the year roll by, one by one,
                            without jarring commotion as they pass, so is it with the different stages of human
                            existence. Childhood is the springtime of life. There is a joyous expectant feeling, that we
                            all share more or less, in the Spring season, that perhaps we do not so fully realize at any
                            other time. Then, every thing is clothed in youthful beauty ! Sober winter throws off its
                            snowy mantle, ice-bound streams, pierced by rays of the warm sun and genial atmosphere, and
                            gentle zephyrs that blow from the hill-tops, tell us that it is seed-time ; and the new
                            incoming season brings with it joy and gladness. We trace the foot-prints of the gentle
                            nymph clothing the meadow with living green, and strewing beautiful flowers in our pathway.
                            But, would the same season fill our minds with as much joy, were it not for the indwelling
                            hope, that after seed time, and of tilling the soil, a harvest of fruits from the vintage,
                            and heavily laden sheaves would be gathered to supply our needs ? We would measurably enjoy
                            the music of birds and inhale the sweet aroma of flowers, and look with pleasure upon
                            Nature's realm filled with youthful beauty ; but, knowing they would soon pass without
                            bringing a return of something more substantial would create a feeling of sadness. Such is
                            life's journey. We pass through its varying seasons, fulfilling its duties, as best we may,
                            till we come to the evening of the day, and look upon our last setting sun ; then we lie
                            down upon our couch, close our eyes upon earthly scenes and go in search of our fathers and
                            mothers who have passed on before, leaving the fields of labor to incoming generations. Mi.
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Give him a lift" TEIform="index"/> GIVE HIM A LIFT</head><p TEIform="p">Give him a lift! Kneel not in prayer Nor moralize with his despair; The man is down, and his
                            great need Is ready help, not prayer and creed. 'Tis time when the wounds are washed and
                            healed That the inward motive be revealed; But now, whate'er the spirit be, Mere words are
                            but a mockery. One grain of aid just now is more To him than tomes of saintiy lore : If you
                            must pray, pray in your heart, But give him a lift! pray give him a start. The world is full
                            of good advice— Of prayers, of praise, and preaching nice But the generous souls who aid
                            mankind Are scarce as gold, and hard to find. Give like a Christian—speak in deeds; A noble
                            life's the best of creeds; And he shall wear a noble crown Who gives men a lift when they
                            are down.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Reflector, Cornwall" TEIform="persName"/>Cornwall Reflector</byline></div2><pb n="226" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Labor" TEIform="index"/> LABOR</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Charles, Ann E." TEIform="persName"/>ANN E. CHARLES</byline><p TEIform="p">To be happy we must grow an interest in some manual occupation, and in this way have a real
                            love for labor. One of the old philosophers remarked, "If you do not want it for food, you
                            may for physic." Action keeps both soul and body in health, while idleness tempts one to
                            stray from the path of duty where they are liable to fall a prey to the evil one. It would
                            be iar better to well improve our time, by doing all the good we can, remembering at the
                            same time the admonition of our founders, "Hands at work and heart to God." In this we are
                            able to with-stand temptation, and live honestly and honorably before all mankind. It has
                            been our privilege and pleasure to accept with confidence the instruc" tion of those who
                            have walked the "new and living way" before us, and it has been to the soul a right and
                            noble way, and a beautiful work of progression. We have, by no means, been idle spectators,
                            but have observed the marked difference that existed between those who were active and
                            interested in the temporal duties of the Community, and those who were indifferent and
                            negligent. It may not be out of place to make mention of a visionary dream as related by one
                            of the sisters. In this a reference was made to the reward of industry, and a marked
                            demonstration of thankfulness was expressed by the sister who had passed from earth, for all
                            of the interest and care she had manifested in her manual employment. Mt. Lebanon, N.
                        Y..</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tired of life" TEIform="index"/> TIRED OF LIFE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Barr, Lillie E" TEIform="persName"/>LILLIE E. BARR</byline><p TEIform="p">It is the idle tire of life : The idle hearts, that duties shirk; The idle brains, that have
                            no thought; The idle hands that have no work. The good man knows that life is good, And
                            strives to make his own complete: The thoughtful know that it is great; The loving know that
                            it is sweet. Yea, even when life halts with pain, Or falls with anguish by the way, Great
                            souls it patiently detain, And hope, and bear, and humbly pray, Because life is so grand a
                            thing; Because beyond its pain and strife They see a fair eternity That must be bought by
                            noble life. Then, thou who are so "tired of life," Go work, go love, go try to think, Go
                            find some duty, howe'er small, And then beside it do not shrink. Go take thy place ; it may
                            be low, And in the rear of mortal strife, But fill it well, and then I know Thou wilt not
                            say, "I'm tired of life." </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Two fires" TEIform="index"/> THE TWO FIRES</head><p TEIform="p">In the moral and religious acceptation of the term, there are two kinds of fire. The first is
                            the fire that swept through the first Two in the Garden and lost them Paradise, described by
                            the immortal Milton thus—"With lust they burn." What a pity! Are they alone in such burning?
                            That is the fire of Hell—A hell within, of the deepest dip, is its inevitable concomitant.
                            It is the first fire frail mortals feel. "Albeit, that which is first is not Spiritual, but
                            natural, and afterward that which is Spiritual." When, by the Divine Afflatus, the germ of
                            Divinity, in us, is roused to action, we feel another fire, for "Our God is a consuming
                            fire." This is the Heaven Fire. We feel it in the marrow of our bones. We are in the
                            Resurrection now. It must burn in us till the other fire, with all its combustibles, is
                            consumed. It must burn till there is nothing left to hurt or destroy in all our Holy
                            Mountain. Then will the morning stars sing together and the Daughters and Sons of God have a
                            good time generally. Amen. Mt. Lebanon N. Y.. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kindness felt" TEIform="index"/>A kindness felt</head><p TEIform="p"> A kindness felt Doth love enfold; A kindness dealt Is love twice told.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M.W.</byline></div2><pb n="227" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Signs of the times" TEIform="index"/> SIGNS OF THE TIMES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Collins, Elvah F." TEIform="persName"/>ELVAH F. COLLINS</byline><p TEIform="p"> "Lo! there are signs in the heavens, which, all who run may read," say the prophets of the
                            present day, and which are ominous of near changes. What are these signs ? Let us pause and
                            observe. The life example and teachings of Jesus, nearly nineteen hundred years ago, cast as
                            a lump of leaven among a small portion of humanity has so continued to operate that the
                            fermenting process, previous to the spoiling of the mass is thoroughly in a.ction, and means
                            must soon be taken for the saving of the whole. What better illustration could be given of
                            the rolling, surging tide of human beings, that fill this busy world of ours, whose very
                            lives, ambitions, and destinies, seem honey-combed, through the destructive effects and
                            dissatisfaction of mind and soul, created by its inroads upon society? From the active,
                            thinking mind, of which there are increasingly many, outgrowing the swaddling clothes of
                            churchology, come murmurings of unrest ; longings for something more practical, and
                            reliable, than can be found in nominal religion, which has become too fashionable and
                            world-loving, to contain the new wine in its old bottles, and the true substance of
                            spiritual bread in its eucharist. It is true, that temples dedicated to the Lord's worship,
                            have become so elaborate in structure, so embellished with the hard earned pence of the
                            suffering poor, that the coals of sacred fire kindled on the simple altars of the days of
                            early Christianity, after smouldering among the ashes of man made creeds, are about extinct,
                            the breath of inspiration and free thought has been shut out from these walls of elegance,
                            which to the enlightened, appear as skeletons and from which life has long since departed.
                            How many do we meet who will tell us, that the written sermon, read and reread by the hired
                            ministers, has failed even to give interest? That the non-intelligible language of popular
                            choirs, touches not the heart, nor even awakens our aspiration toward the heavenly, and
                            divine ? Are not these signs of Church infidelity, predictive of the first steps toward
                            advance in a new creation ? Look again, and we see strong agitation'of mind upon dietetic
                            reforms. The ripening harvests of dyspeptics, and invalids, grown from the soil of
                            adulterous mixtures as used on the tables, to supply the demands of the appetite, rather
                            than the sustenance of life ; and the multiplicity of poisonous ingredients, coloring
                            materials, compounded, advertised, and sold by those who love money better than principle,
                            to add to a fine appearance, and perverted taste. This subject is awakening many to a sense
                            of serious results. Some are extreme in their enthusiasm for a reform and hold forth a
                            system of living, as far from good judgment, as is the inordinate, or fastidious epicure's,
                            habit of eating; but, as the pendulum set in violent motion, finally finds its equal poise,
                            or balance, so the outcome of both extremes will be the establishment of a system of cooking
                            and eating, which the rational mind can accept as both comfortable, and healthful. (To BE
                            CONTINUED.)</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Every one's life lies within the present; for the past is spent and done with, and the future is uncertain" TEIform="index"/>
                            Every one's life lies within the present; for the past is spent and done with, and the future is uncertain
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Every one's life lies within the present; for the past is spent and done with, and the future
                            is uncertain.</p></div2><pb n="228" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life in the woods" TEIform="index"/> LIFE IN THE WOODS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sproat, Granville T." TEIform="persName"/>GRANVILLE T. SPROAT</byline><p TEIform="p">[Being a narrative of events that occurred during a sojourn of twelve years among the Indians
                            of the North-West.] It was during the summer of 1836, that I started on my journey to visit
                            the Indians of the far North West. I had long been acquainted with the Indians of the border
                            Territories, and, for several years, had taught a school among them, and had long had a
                            desire to visit them in their native forest homes, where they lived uncontaminated by the
                            vices of the white-men. This wish was, at last, gratified. In 1830, they sold the lands
                            which now include the states of Minnesota and Wisconsin, to our Government; and one of the
                            stipulations of the treaty was, that agents should be sent among all those who desired it,
                            to vaccinate them, to prevent the spread of that terrible scourge— the small pox, which had
                            already devastated, and nearly exterminated the once powerful Mandan tribe. I offered my
                            services, and started on my journey, accompanied by an old Indian, for a guide, named,
                            Ma-gwah-gah-bo, (Bear Killer.) My beginning of adventures was with the Ojibway tribe, in the
                            country lying south and west from Lake Superior. With Magwah-gah-bo for a guide, I roamed
                            many a day over those vast plains, and through the wilderness of the North West, traveling
                            by canoes during the summer season, and, in the winter, with our team of six dogs dressed in
                            fantastic little harnesses of red and purple cloth and leather, hung with little bells, for
                            whose music the animals seemed to have a peculiar liking; and drawing a train, or Indian
                            sledge, which is composed of a board of bass wood, lying flat on the snow, with its front
                            end upturned, like the toe of a skate— it being about two feet wide, and twelve feet long.
                            On this we pack ourselves and baggage, and are drawn swiftly over the ice, at the rate of
                            thirty or forty miles a day. We commenced our tour during the summer, in our canoe, and
                            attempted to cross a small bay running up into the south-westeru shores of Lake Superior: It
                            was a beautiful day when we started, and, as we had bu about thirty miles to travel to reach
                            the opposite shore, we apprehended no difficulty; but ere we had got half way across, dark
                            clouds began to gather in the west, and a sudden tempest came on, such as one seldom meets
                            with excepting on the waters of that lake. In a few moments the seas were running mountain
                            high, and our little canoe of about twelve feet in length, was in danger of being swallowed
                            up by the waves. In the midst of all this turmoil, Ma-gwah-gah-bo sat calm and composed,
                            steering the canoe with his little paddle, and chanting to the spirits of the Wind; (Kech-e
                            No-din) at the same time making them an offering, to appease their wrath, scattering
                            tobacco, cut fine and mixed with willow bark, for smoking called nichnecJc, upon the waters.
                            His chant ran something like this ; "Ke-che No-din! Ke-che Nodin! pe-zan, non-gum, neen
                            no-go-min." (Spirits of the strong wind, cease your howling ! sleep in quiet!") But the
                            spirits did not cease their howling. They seemed to howl worse then ever,—nearly upsetting
                            our canoe, as I lay prostrate on the bottom, sometimes standing on my feet, and sometimes on
                            my head, and sometimes nearly thrown out of it. At length, the violence of the storm abated,
                            and we reached the shore in safety; but drenched, and dripping, as though we had, ourselves,
                            been the Water Spirits to whom Ma-gwah-gah-bo had sung his ditty. "The spirits heard my
                            song, and accepted the offering," said he, "but they were very angry. I threw away all my
                            tobacco." "Your spirits must deal very extensively in tobacco," I was about to say; but I
                            checked myself, knowing that nothing so offends a red man as to speak disrespectfully, or
                            with levity, of his belief in the existence of spirits. The Indians believe in a numerous
                            class of spirits, who rule the wind and water, enter into a man, and produce disease—evil
                            spirits whose wrath they, by offerings, attempt to appease. Death is a spirit that comes and
                            steals away the breath. His name is Pagook. There is a spirit for Consumption, a spirit for
                            Fever. Hence they deal in necromancy, and charms, to dispel the evil spirits, and invoke the
                            good ones. They also believe in, and often speak of the return of the spirits of the dead.
                            They <pb n="229" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 229 say that they often see them, and talk
                            with them. One night, Ke-che Be-zhe-ka (Big Buffalo,) chief of the Ojibways, came into my
                            wigwam. He had been with me the evening before and had left late at night, after spending
                            the evening very pleasantly in friendly conversation. The ensuing evening he came in, seated
                            himself, and bowed his head in deep silence, as if wrapped in solemn thought. ilGushken-dum?
                            nah?" was my first question, (Are you sad?) ^Ka-get" (Yes,) replied the old man. "I am sad.
                            Listen!—After leaving your wigwam, last night, as I was going home, I thought I heard
                            footsteps close beside me. I looked. There was my wife." Now, the old man's wife had been
                            dead about a dozen years. "Well, I did not wish to speak with her last night, as I often do.
                            So I drew my blanket far over my face, and walked directly on. Presently I heard footsteps
                            the other side of me. I looked, and there was my daughter." The old man's daughter had been
                            dead twenty years. "I drew my blanket still farther over my face, and went to my wigwam."
                            "Now what does this mean? what do you, Pale Faces, say that it means, when the spirits
                            return again from the Land of Souls?" I replied, "Some of the Pale Faces, but not all of
                            them, do not believe that the spirits return from the Land of Souls." He said, "You Pale
                            Faces are not wise. You understand but little, I will tell you what it means. Two of our
                            number will soon go on their journey across the river. One of them, old; the other in the
                            summer of life. And these spirits come, last night, to give me a warning." (TO BE
                            CONTINUED.)</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker's picnic" TEIform="index"/> SHAKER'S PICNIC</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">On Wednesday the 16th inst., the Harvard and Shirley Shakers joined in picnic, or
                                    social out-door gathering, on the banks of the Nashua and on the grounds of Adolp.
                                    Holden in Ayer. It is a beautiful spot and is well shaded with towering elms,
                                    hickory and willows. Seats had been previously provided, swings put up, and boats in
                                    river. Here sixty Shakers, including children, met to spend the day and the little
                                    ones showed gladness and delight all over their faces. A meeting was called at
                                    eleven o'clock for the purpose of hearing what any one had to say. There was
                                    singing, declamations, speaking, and dialogues. The exercises were very pleasing and
                                    highly interesting. An abrupt adjournment was made to prepare for dinner, which was
                                    served in good taste. The viands were excellent and bountiful, and appetites
                                    remarkable. Soon after dinner a shower came up and caused a little commotion and
                                    hinderance, but was soon over and the bright warm sun dried away the wet, and the
                                    pastime was resumed. Another meeting in the afternoon was held and some new pieces
                                    of music were finely rendered. Dialogues and some excellent selections of reading
                                    followed, which were very interesting. Thus the day was spent and good feeling
                                    prevailed throughout, and the occasion was not only very enjoyable, but it is
                                    thought profitable and useful in many ways, productive of increased strength and
                                    united feeling to struggle on and up life's rugged steep. Near the close an
                                    appalling scene occurred, another shower came up suddenly accompanied with thunder
                                    and lightning, and a terrific gale, Trees were blown down in all directions and in a
                                    small grove where about a dozen horses were tied six trees lay prostrate right among
                                    the horses, and strange to say they did not appear at all frightened, and they all
                                    came out without a scratch. One or two of the party narrowly escaped a fallen tree.
                                    After the gale had subsided the picnic party started for their homes in good spirits
                                    all thankful for the remarkable preservation and for the rain which was very much
                                    needed. In closing this sketch it is resolved that friend Holden, the owner of the
                                    premises, has the sincere and heartfelt thanks of the whole party for neighborly
                                    attention and kindness shown. W.W.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Turner's public spirit" TEIform="index"/>Turner's Public Spirit</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pentecost" TEIform="index"/>Pentecost</head><p TEIform="p">When the Spirit of God was poured out on the day of Pentecost, it equalized earthly riches.
                            Water never runs up stream unless forced. It always seeks its level. So does the "River of
                            the water of life."</p></div2><pb n="230" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Publication" TEIform="index"/>Office of Publication
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> SHAKER MANIFESTO. OCTOBER, 1882. Office of Publication. The "Shaker Manifesto" is published
                            at Shaker Village, Mer. Co., N. H. All business matters connected with the financial
                            department of the paper will be directed to the Publisher of Manifesto, Shaker Village, N.
                            H. All other communications may be addressed, Editor of Manifesto, Shaker Village, N. H. One
                            Copy per. year, Postage paid, .60 six months, " .35 Enclose a two cent stamp for a specimen
                            copy. To avoid mistakes, those who send money, should write the name of their Post Office,
                            County and State. to a.x&gt;vbiitisek.». One inch, one insertion $ 1.00 " " three " each
                            .75 " " six " " .65 " " twelve " " .50 " column ----- ----- ----- 6.00 Larger spaces, rates
                            in same proportion.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes" TEIform="index"/> NOTES</head><p TEIform="p"> "Line upon line and precept upon precept" is the only successful lesson of life. Through
                            this care of the mind comes the daily self-examination. It forms a discipline by which we
                            are learned to speak and to act. It admonishes us to do for ourselves what it would be
                            impossible for others to do for us, to govern our passions, to rule our tongue and to
                            acknowledge every deviation from a correct principle. It stimulates a regard for
                            faithfulness in all temporal duties and through this we learn to "use the things of this
                            world without abusing them." Without this care over the mind there can be but little harmony
                            with goodness, or neatness, or self government. We should prove indifferent teachers in that
                            which we have never learned. Children and youth are to be instructed, and again we learn,
                            that for them it must be "line upon line." A life of care and loving kindness must be
                            exercised in performing this duty. Day after day, and month after month is sometimes
                            required to establish a simple phase of discipline in the mind. It seems a long time to work
                            for such simple results and yet it may be a lesson for eternity. Let us exercise patience in
                            our labors of self-instruction and greater patience in the care and cultivation of others.
                            It is reported that there is an extensive business in England in the manufacture of "gods"
                            for the heathen. While it has been thought necessary by some to send men and women among
                            these worshipers of idols to teach them better things, it may now become equally as
                            necessary to look a little nearer home, and cast the beam out of the Christian eye, that it
                            may be able to see more clearly how to cast out the mote from the heathen eye. The
                            "Christian at Work" publishes the circular of one of these firms. "We beg to offer to our
                            Hindoo clients, images of Yamen, the god of the dead, in bronze, very finely carved, also a
                            collection of images of Narundi." Have a thought for our missionary work ! Retiring so
                            peacefully in our pleasant homes we may without especial care lose sight of the obligation
                            that <pb n="231" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 231 should devolve upon us. In our abundance
                            of the good gifts that serve to make our earthly homes those of care and comfort, and our
                            anticipated hope of a heavenly fruition all that one could desire, we may possibly forget to
                            a certain extent that where much is given, much also will be required. Our fathers and
                            mothers were imbued in a remarkable degree with this divine gift. To it they gave all that
                            they possessed, believing that as God, in his mercy, had called them from the sins of the
                            world, they as faithful servants should call others to the same work. First, however, in
                            this beautiful mission should be an interest for the protection and advancement in and
                            around our own homes. The external appearance makes its impression upon the mind, the
                            dwellings, the farm, the garden, the walls and fences are often more potent in their
                            influence upon visitors or enquirers than either the preaching or the praying. To neglect
                            any of these obligations for that which is more foreign, would, indeed be liable to many
                            objections. Home influences and home interests should be thoroughly studied and a home
                            mission established which should include every member. None are ever so far advanced in life
                            as to be beyond the power of doing good, and none are too young to present an offering that
                            may add to the blessing of our community. Canaan, N. Y. Report of School in District No. 1.
                            The boys' department of this school is conducted by Granville T. Sproat, for thirty years a
                            teacher in several different states of the Union ; and for twelve years, among the Indians
                            of the NorthWest. Object teaching receives a large share of his attention. He teaches ideas
                            instead of words ; and text books have largely given place to oral instruction. In
                            physiology, and natural history, some of his more advanced scholars have made much progress;
                            and one of them, a youth of fifteen, wrote a natural history of bees, their manner of
                            building their cells, and managing the affairs of their community, the history of the queen
                            bee, &amp;c. which he read, and was heard with much interest, on the closing day of the
                            winter term of school. The County Commissioner spoke highly of this school, the progress of
                            the scholars, and the pleasant school-room, its kindergarten appearance, it being fragrant
                            with evergreens in the middle of winter. Length of term, 14 weeks. Average attendance, 11
                            scholars. Summer Term.—Emily Offord is the teacher of the girls' department of this school.
                            Her school comprises many little ones, several of them under 10 years of age. It is
                            conducted chiefly on the plan of Pestallozi. She teaches the alphabet, and combination of
                            letters into words, by means of small cubic blocks, with letters inscribed upon them, thus
                            furnishing amusement as well as instruction. The recent introduction of sectional maps, in
                            the hands of the pupils, gives them a good idea of physical geography. The art of singing is
                            cultivated among her youthful charge, thus giving cheeriness to her labors. On pleasant days
                            in the summer, she often takes her pupils into a neighboring grove, and gives them lessons
                            of instruction among the beautiful scenes of nature. Both school rooms are pleasantly
                            situated, overlooking the well known Shak- <pb n="232" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 232 SHAKER MANIFESTO. er
                            Valley, among the beautiful Berkshire hills. Length of term, 14 weeks. Average attendance 9.
                            GROVELAND, N. Y. The Society at Groveland maintain a select school, and receive no benefit
                            of public money. Number of pupils usually from five to ten. Recitations good, attendance
                            regular, tardiness rare. Length of term from sixteen to eighteen weeks. School taught by
                            Ella E. Winship. Union Village, Ohio. A letter from Elder Oliver Hampton informs us that
                            they have a Board of Examiners and a Board of Education. Neither of these haye visited their
                            school for several years. Elder Oliver is a member of the Board of Education. We also
                            received the following.—The past school year at Union Village opened Sep. 27, 1881 and
                            closed Apr. 21, 1882. It consisted of two terms of thirteen wreeks each. There were forty
                            four pupils enrolled, with an average daily attendance of thirty two and eight tenths.
                            Pamelia Davis, teacher. White Water and Watervliat have no District schools, having fallen
                            below the legal number of pupils to entitle them to a share in the money appropriated for
                            such schools. The children are now instructed at the expense of the family where they
                            reside. </p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="juvenile" TEIform="index"/>Juvenile</head><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Time enough" TEIform="index"/>TIME ENOUGH</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">TIME ENOUGH. Two little squirrels out in the sun, One gathered nuts, the
                                        other had none. "Time enough yet," his constant refrain: "Summer is still only
                                        just on the wane." Listen, my child, while I tell you his fate : He roused him
                                        at last, but he roused him too late. Down fell the snow from the pitiless cloud,
                                        And gave little squirrel a spotless white shroud. Two little boys in a school
                                        room were placed, One always perfect the other disgraced. "Time enough yet for
                                        my learning," he said; "I will climb by and by from the foot to the head."
                                        Listen, my darling, their locks have turned gray; • One as a governor is sitting
                                        to-day; The other, a pauper, looks out at the door Of the almshouse, and idles
                                        his days as of yore. Two kinds of people we meet every day; One is at work, the
                                        other at play, Living uncared for, dying unknown— The busiest hive hath ever a
                                        drone. Tell me, my child, if the squirrels have taught The lesson I long to
                                        impart to your thought; Answer me this, and my story is done, Which of the two
                                        would you be, little one?</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Domestic journal" TEIform="index"/>Domestic Journal</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Try again" TEIform="index"/> Try again.</head><p TEIform="p">—Everybody makes mistakes. Things will not always come out just as we try to make them,
                                because some little wrong thing is done, or something that needs to be done is
                                overlooked. Well, what then? Shall we get discouraged and let things go as they will?
                                Some people do, but such people have a hard life of it; they think themselves very
                                unlucky, and complain of their hard fate. The little fellow who is at work on his
                                example in multiplication finds he has made a mistake; what does he do? Drop his slate
                                and go off fretting and wishing there were no such things as old bothersome figures? No;
                                lie is puzzled, but he knows there is a mistake somewhere, and he means to find out.
                                "Try again" is his motto. He will begin again and go slowly and carefully through all
                                the work. If he does not find the mistake then he will do the same again, running
                                through all the lines of the multiplication table in his mind, or making them by
                                additions <pb n="233" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. on his slate. He will hit on the
                                wrong and get the right, you may be sure. </p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Teacher—Suppose I were to shoot at a tree with five birds on it..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Teacher—Suppose I were to shoot at a tree with five birds on it...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Teacher—Suppose I were to shoot at a tree with five birds on it, and kill three, how many
                                would be left? Three, sir. Teacher—No ; two would be left, you dull boy. No ; there
                                wouldn't. The three shot would be left, and the other two would be flied away.
                                Teacher—Take your seat.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Letter Box</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Editor;—I enjoy reading the letters in..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Dear Editor;—I enjoy reading the letters in...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New Hampshire, Enfield" TEIform="index"/> Enfield, N. H.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Dear Editor;—I enjoy reading the letters in the "Letter Box" and have, wished there
                                might be more written by the numerous children of our household. I am going to school
                                now. Our schoolhouse is surrounded by beautiful maple trees. Our term includes sixteen
                                weeks. My studies are Reading, Spelling, Grammar, Geography, Anatomy and Arithmetic. I
                                like geography and anatomy better than all the others. My home is in a beautiful green
                                valley, partly surrounded by high mountains. At the foot of the valley is the lovely
                                lake Mascoma; it is five miles long and one mile wide. I love my pure religious home
                                where so many kind friends love and teach me how to be good. I hope to become a true
                                woman like the kind Sisters who take care of me. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Isabelle" TEIform="persName"/> Isabelle.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Sister M;—As the girls are invited to..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Dear Sister M;—As the girls are invited to...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New Hampshire, Shaker Village" TEIform="index"/> Shaker Village, N. H.</dateline><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Montague, Marion E." TEIform="persName"/>Marion E. Montague.</byline><p TEIform="p">Dear Sister M;—As the girls are invited to write a letter to each of the sisters, I
                                selected your name. Now dear M. to tell you that I love you, would be nothing new. I was
                                reading the other day that "Love was born in Heaven. It claims its direct genealogy from
                                the great Creator of the Universe." Thus Heaven was first and will be at last its home.
                                It is an amaranthine flower sent to beautify the garden of earth. I will cultivate it,
                                it is so choice a plant. I have ever been a favored child, drinking from the cup which
                                is overflowing with true benevolence: and how can I, after having been thus favored,
                                ever seek or wish any enjoyment, save that which emanates from the portals of Paradise,
                                the inspiration of truth and purity. O, Nay ! I think the ministering angels whose
                                tender guardianship I have shared, would weep, should ingratitude or any evil temptation
                                mar my spirit. I have often pledged with my dear companions, that we would be true
                                virgin sisters, true to our friends and true to our own souls. I have always pictured
                                our place among the white robed angels whose garments are spotless I sometimes fancy
                                myself in future life to be one of those lovely flowers of which Father James Whittaker
                                spoke: "Those who are called by the gospel in childhood and are faithful and obedient,
                                and keep out of sin shall be the flowers of Heaven and the glory of Paradise." What can
                                we contemplate as being more beautiful? And can I doubt for a moment that I shall be the
                                true Christian and overcome the whole world? Nay, this is my purpose in life, and having
                                won the battle I can "sing of the beauty and joy in the way." I truly enjoy a valuable
                                association in life. I form a link in the golden chain which unites our spirits in a
                                sweet and sacred union which is indissolvable. I wish to promise, dear sister, that I
                                will date from to-day an increase in my spiritual growth and culture. My whole heart's
                                affections shall be centred in the Christian principles of my Shaker home where I have
                                been preserved, and my youthful vows of consecration to God so often renewed. My love
                                ever, </p><p TEIform="p">[The writer of the above letter was soon after striken down with a hemorrhage of the
                                lungs, and die'I very suddenly. She was peculiarly gifted as a spiritual child, and we
                                Ixust she finds the fulfillment of her ev ery youthful aspiration.] </p></div3></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A distinguished Japanese traveler in this country writes home..." TEIform="index"/>
                            A distinguished Japanese traveler in this country writes home...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A distinguished Japanese traveler in this country writes home : "The chief branch
                                    of education of young men here is rowing. The people have large boat-houses called
                                    'colleges,' and the principal of these are Yale and Harvard."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Woman's journal" TEIform="index"/>Woman's Journal. </bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="234" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Salt point peace convention" TEIform="index"/>SALT POINT PEACE CONTENTION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p">. This Convention was attended by u delegation of Eleven Brethren and Sisters of the North
                            Family, Mt Lebanon, N. Y.. on the 28th and 27th August, 1882. Owing to rain, the meetings
                            were not so largely attended as usual, but there was a goodly gathering and a liberal supply
                            of speakers, of both sexes. The following was presented by the, Shaker Company. PREAMBLE. In
                            as much as the Nine Millions of Soldiers, said to bo now under arms in the various nations
                            of Christendom, are, in ninly nine cases out of one hundred, landless men, having no home,
                            no inheritance in the earth, no vine or fig-tree to sit under, and that all wars end with a
                            ''material guarantee," the victors taking possession of the land of the conquered nation.
                            Resolved. That our Representatives in the Empire State of N. Y. he requested to cause, if it
                            be possible, the following Land Limitation Law to be passed. Be it Enacted;—That from and
                            after the year 1882, no citizen, or person shall inherit, buy, or become permanently
                            possessed of more than one hundred and sixty acres of land. Heirs of land monopolists, may
                            take possession of lands falling to them: but shall, within one year thereafter, sell, or
                            otherwise dispose of the same, down to the legal limits of l(!0 acres. Were there no
                            landless, homeless people, whence would come the material for Armies and Navies ? In the New
                            Earth. 1st. Let Women become Citizens, that we may have a true Republic. 2nd. Let every
                            Citizen have an inalienable Homestead. 3rd. Should Europe send soldiers to fight Americans,
                            give each soldier one hundred and sixty acre lot of land. For, as a carpenter, or blacksmith
                            works for wages, for a living, so is it with the landless soldiers, they fight for a living.
                            Give them the living, without the fighting, and they will cease to be Soldiers. Mt. Lebanon,
                            N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Smith, Jerusha" TEIform="index"/>Jerusha Smith</head><p TEIform="p"> , at Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. August, 21. Age, 82 years, 5 mo. and 8 days. She closed her
                                earthly pilgrimage as she had lived, full of grace, honor, dignity, firmness and
                                tranquility. She arose in the morning as usual and while sitting at the table for
                                breakfast was paralyzed and became helpless. She was taken immediately to the infirmary,
                                and at the close of three hours, passed quietly to the realm where the wicked cease from
                                troubling and the weary are at rest. C G. Reed. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="home" TEIform="index"/>House-hold</head><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tomatoes as food" TEIform="index"/> TOMATOES AS FOOD.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Tomatoes, remarks an authority, are not without some defects as an article of
                                        food. They are not, like milk, a perfect diet of themselves, and besides, like
                                        most other articles of food, they contain some obnoxious qualities. But they
                                        need not be thrown aside on that account. Nature has provided us with such
                                        sufficient excretory organs that the obnoxious matter in our food, if in
                                        moderate amount, is readily cast out, and the body is protected against any
                                        material injury. Were it not so we should be obliged to throw out of our dietary
                                        many kinds of food now eaten, not only with impunity, but with advantage. Thus,
                                        red cabbage, cherries and peaches contain prussic acid, which is a deadly poison
                                        when taken in sufficient quantity. The very small amount of the poisoning acid
                                        these vegetables contain is cast out of the system without any material injury
                                        to the person using them. A positive good may actually be derived from the use
                                        of food containing some such foreign matter, by way of giving increased activity
                                        and strength to the excretory organs from their exercise in casting such foreign
                                        matter from our bodies, provided the quantity is not so great as to overburden
                                        them. Since we are all the time liable to take in our food substances the
                                        tendency of which is harmful, a good development <pb n="235" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/>of
                                        efficiency in our excretory organs is necessary to protect us against the
                                        pernicious effects which might otherwise occur. Almost every kind of grain and
                                        fruit in use contain more or less things which in a larger amount would prove
                                        hurtful. Unless we closely study our food, we are taking them in when we little
                                        suspect it. A Frenchman, not many years ago, discovered a substance in wheat
                                        bran which under the high heat used in baking, dissolved out and spread over the
                                        crumbs of bread, of which bran forms a part, and discolored it, and hence the
                                        brown stain peculiar to graham bread. But from this discovery such bread has not
                                        been rejected, but continues to be accounted among the most wholesome kinds of
                                        food. Rye is seldom used without containing more or less ergot; but rye bread is
                                        reckoned among the most healthful. Tea contains tannic acid, apples contain
                                        malic acid, lemons and oranges citric acid, no one of which is used either in
                                        nutrition or respiration, but they only become objectionable when used
                                        excessively.—</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Leeds mercury" TEIform="index"/>Leeds Mercury</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good bread" TEIform="index"/>GOOD BREAD.</head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon" TEIform="index"/></dateline><p TEIform="p"> I notice articles upon Graham Bread in the Am. Agriculturist and other papers. Perhaps
                                our experience at the North Family, Mt. Lebanon, ma}r be of some interest and service to
                                the public. For many years we have used bread made from wheat of our own raising. We
                                wash the wheat thoroughly, kiln-dry, grind it ourselves, coarsely, use it unbolted, and
                                bake it in a soapstone oven. No leaven in it. It is good wheaten bread. I doubt whether
                                really good men and women, Christians, can be raised upon poor bread, made of
                                adulterated materials and chemically corrupted by leaven. If a clean thing cannot be
                                brought out of an unclean' then how can a good thing be made out of bad materials? Have
                                not a loaf to spare, (unless to feed the hungry,) a bushel of wheat, nor a barrel of
                                flour to sell at any price. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fruit may be preserved with honey..." TEIform="index"/>Fruit may be preserved with honey...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Fruit may be preserved with honey by putting the fruit first in the can, then pouring
                                honey over it, and seal air-tight; when the honey is poured from the fruit it will have
                                the flavor and appearance of jelly, making a delicious dessert.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If a glass stopper won't move..." TEIform="index"/>If a glass stopper won't move...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">If a glass stopper won't move, hold the neck of the bottle to a flame, or warm it by
                                taking two turns of a sfrlng and see-sawing it. The heat engendered expands the neck of
                                the bottle before a corresponding expansion reaches the stopper. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="An exchange says, to clean out a stovepipe..." TEIform="index"/>An exchange says, to clean out a stovepipe...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> An exchange says, to clean out a stovepipe, place a piece of zinc on the live coals in
                                the stove. The vapor produced by the zinc will carry off the soot by chemical
                                decomposition. Persons who have tried the process claim that it will work every time.
                            </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Red ants may be banished..." TEIform="index"/>Red ants may be banished...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Red ants may be banished from a pantry or store-room by strewing the shelves with a
                                small quantity of cloves, either whole or ground. We use the former, as not so likely to
                                get into the food placed upon the shelves. The cloves should be renewed occasionally, as
                                after a time they lose their strength and efficacy. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A coat of gum copal varnish..." TEIform="index"/>A coat of gum copal varnish...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> A coat of gum copal varnish applied to the soles of boots and shoes, and repeated as it
                                dries until the pores are filled and the surface shines like polished mahogany, will
                                make the sole water-proof, and it lasts three times longer. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If rats are about..." TEIform="index"/>If rats are about...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">If rats are ahout, scatter powdered glass about their holes, or powdered copperas, or
                                fill up the crevices with hard soap, or smear their holes with soft tar, or dip a rat in
                                a cup of tar and let it go, and it will tar-plaster every hole in the house. </p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Apples as food" TEIform="index"/>Apples as food
                            </head><p TEIform="p">.—A raw, mellow apple is digested in an hour and a half, while boiled
                                cabbage requires five hours. Tho most heaitly dessert that can be placed on the table is
                                a baked apple. If eaten frequently at breakfast with coarse bread and 1 titier, without
                                meat or flesh of any kind, it has an rsdrnir- <pb n="236" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 236 SHAKER
                                MANIFESTO. able effect upon the general system, often removing constipation, correcting
                                acidities and cooling off febrile conditions more effectually than the most approved
                                medicines. If families could be induced to substitute them for pies, cakes, and
                                sweetmeats, with which their children are frequently stuffed, there would be a
                                diminution in the total sum of doctor's bills in a single year sufficient to lay in a
                                stock of this delicious fruit for the whole season's use. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A correspondent of New Remedies..." TEIform="index"/>A correspondent of New Remedies...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A correspondent of New Remedies gives the following receipt for a paste for use in
                                prescription books and labels : I dissolve half an ounce of alum in a pint of boiling
                                water : to this I add an equal weight of flour, made smooth in a little cold water, and
                                a few drops of oil of cloves, letting the whole come to a boil. This paste will keep
                                months. I put it in glass, or ordinary ointment jars. </p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Superior remedy for fresh wounds, sprains and bruises" TEIform="index"/> A SUPERIOR
                                REMEDY FOR FRESH WOUNDS, SPRAINS AND BRUISES.</head><p TEIform="p"> Procure a mild, coal fire. Sprinkle it with drops of any kind of animal oil, or grease,
                                or tallow. Hold the effected part over the smoke, say thirty minutes, as hot as can be
                                borne. A good way is to use a large tin tunnel inverted, as it gathers the smoke into a
                                small compass. Hold the wound directly over the tunnel. Whoever will apply this to
                                wounds, sprains, or bruises, two, three, or more times, say once in twelve hours, will
                                find it invaluable to allay pain, to prevent soreness and taking cold, and the recovery
                                will be rapid. This remedy has been practiced in the United Society of Shakers for more
                                than thirty years, with most astonishing success. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To drive a nail into hard wood..." TEIform="index"/>To drive a nail into hard wood...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">To drive a nail into hard wood, as chestnut or seasoned white oak, dip the nail in oil,
                                and it will not fail to go.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To file glass" TEIform="index"/>To file glass
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Keep the file wet with spirits of turpentine or benzine.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To extract stains from silk" TEIform="index"/>To extract stains from silk</head><p TEIform="p">Essence of lemon, one part; spirits of turpentine, five parts. Mix, and apply to the spot
                                by means of a linen rag.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>Farm and Garden</head><div3 type="farmer" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What an acre of land produced" TEIform="index"/> WHAT AN ACRE OF LAND PRODUCED.</head><p TEIform="p"> A farmer living in Maine makes a statement of what he has raisedsthis year on an acre of
                                land—almost enough, we should think, to support a family. He planted one-third of his
                                acre in corn, and he usually produces thirty bushels of good corn. This quantity was
                                sufficient for his family use, and for fattening two or three large hogs. From the same
                                ground on which the corn stood, he raised two or three hundred pumpkins, and an ample
                                supply of beans. From a bed of six rods square he usually obtains sixty bushels of
                                onions; these he sold for one dollar per bushel, which amount purchased his flour for
                                one year. Thus, from one-third of an acre and an onion bed he obtained his breadstuffs
                                and two or three hundred pounds of pork. The remainder of the ground was appropriated to
                                all kinds of vegetables, for both Summer and Winter use. He also had a flower garden,
                                raspberries, currants, gooseberries in great abundance, and also a few choice apple,
                                pear and quince trees. </p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mr. George Connor, of Burlington, considers a ton of corn stalks worth more..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Mr. George Connor, of Burlington, considers a ton of corn stalks worth more...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Mr. George Connor, of Burlington, considers a ton of corn stalks worth more than a ton of
                                hay for cows. He feeds to each milch cow one bushel of finely cut stalks, Wo quarts of
                                bran and two quarts of cobmeal mixed and wet with w ater, both morning and evening. </p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Professor Kedzie, of the Agricultural College of Michigan..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Professor Kedzie, of the Agricultural College of Michigan...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Professor Kedzie, of the Agricultural College of Michigan, an expert chemist, recently
                                said that a paint or wash made of skim milk, thoroughly skimmed, and water brine, will
                                render wood uninflammable, and he proved it by experiment. He said this paint, or
                                whitewash, is durable, very cheap, impervious to water, of agreeable color, and, as it
                                will prevent wood from taking fire, urged its use, particularly on roofs, outbuildings,
                                barns, etc. </p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A Mississippi Farmer dashes cold water into the ears of choking cattle..." TEIform="index"/>
                                A Mississippi Farmer dashes cold water into the ears of choking cattle...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A Mississippi Farmer dashes cold water into the ears of choking cattle. This
                                        causes the animal to shake its head violently, and the muscular action dislodges
                                        the obstruction.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Exchange" TEIform="index"/> Ex.</bibl></cit></p></div3><pb n="237" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Winged guardians" TEIform="index"/> Winged Guardians.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Winged Guardians. The swallow, swift and nighthawk are the guardians of the
                                        atmosphere. They check the increase of insects, that otherwise would overload
                                        it. Woodpeckers and creepers are the guardians of the trunks of trees. Warblers
                                        and flycatchers protect the foliage. Blackbirds, thrushes, crows and larks
                                        protect the soil under the surface. Each tribe has its respective duties to
                                        perform in the economy of nature ; and it is an undoubted fact that, if the
                                        birds were all swept away from off the earth, man could not live upon it,
                                        vegetation would wither and die, and insects would become so numerous that no
                                        living thing could withstand their attacks.—</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="London farmer" TEIform="index"/>London Farmer. </bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bones for poultry" TEIform="index"/> Bones for Poultry.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Bones for the Poultry—The various preparations of pure bones, selected and
                                        prepared, as crushed, granulated, bone meal, etc., for feeding to poultry, are
                                        becoming each year more popular, and deservedly so. The experience of nearly
                                        every one who has given them a faithful trial has bee?- such as to make them
                                        constantly patrons of the most reliable venders, it being invariably found that
                                        by a judicious use of broken or ground new bone the fowls are healthier, more
                                        prolific, stand confinement better, and acquire less bad habits by confinement.
                                        Chickens fed on these preparations to the proper extent will grow to a much
                                        better size, the use of the bone having the effect to postpone the time when the
                                        bones harden or, in common phrase, set. Chicks are, therefore, such for a
                                        greater period, and may be kept growing for a longer time by the use of bone
                                        preparation.—</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New York poultry journal" TEIform="index"/> New York Poultry Journal.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pear" TEIform="index"/> The Pear.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The Pear.—It is a fact well worthy of note that no matter how|poor may be the
                                        season for some one fruit or another, in Pennsylvania at least if not other
                                        States, the pear-tree always has fruit. There are of course some years when
                                        there are more than others, but it is the rarest of all events in this part of
                                        the world for a pear-tree, after it gets to a fair mature bearing age, not to
                                        have on all the pears it is fit for it to bear. The cherry may shrivel, blacken
                                        and fall, and even the apple may be full of promise and yet yield us next to
                                        nothing; but the pear seems to be always on hand. It is true that as a matter
                                        for commercial growers of fruit, the apple will always be king, as we have so
                                        often contended. They can be barreled, sliced and dried, cidered, and saved and
                                        turned to use in so many easy ways, that nothing can compete with it in general
                                        usefulness ; but as an article of luxury there is nothing to beat a good pear.
                                        As a commercial fruit we do not know that much has ever been made of it. Here
                                        and there are large pear orchards returning fair profitable results; but these
                                        are but small numbers in comparison with profitable apple orchards ; and we have
                                        an idea that this will always be. There is no one who has a piece of ground but
                                        ought to have a pear-tree or two, and more than this if he has room. The great
                                        family tree should always be the peartree. It will live for a couple of hundred
                                        years. What fruit-tree will last so long? </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Tribune and farmer" TEIform="index"/>Tribune and Farmer. </bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Art and industrial exhibition in the capital at Washington" TEIform="index"/> AN ART AND
                            INDUSTRIAL EXHIBITION IN THE CAPITOL AT WASHINGTON.</head><p TEIform="p">Under the auspices of the Society of the Army of the Cumberland, for the benefit of the
                            Garfield Monument Fund. The Board of Direction, composed of some of the most prominent names
                            in public life, including members of the Supreme Court, Senators, Members of Congress, Army
                            and Navy officers of high rank, and the first citizens of Washington, send the following to
                            the press: A National Bazaar, Art, and Industrial exposition will be held in the rotunda and
                            adjacent halls, of the National Capitol, at Washington, D. C, November 25th to December 3d,
                            (inclusive), 1882, as authorized by joint resolution of the Senate and House of
                            Eepresentatives, August 7, 1882. The object of this undertaking is to raise funds with which
                            to erect a statue in this city to the memory of General James A. Garfield, late President of
                            the United States, which work is in the hands of a committee of the Society of the Army of
                            the Cumberland, who have already collected for this purpose some twenty thousand dollars and
                            expect, with the results of the exposition, to have a sufficient sum with which to erect a
                            work befitting the great name it is proposed to commemorate. <pb n="238" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/>238
                            S1IAKER MAN 1FESTO. The art exhibition will be under the direction of the leading artists
                            resident in Washington. It is hoped that artists throughout the entire country, professional
                            and amateurs will aid the work by contributing some one work—as a gift to the fund—to be
                            sold for its benefit, and be willing to exhibit others, under such rules and regulations as
                            may be determined by the Board of Direction. All persons desiring to contribute in any way
                            to this great work are cordially invited to do so, and to proceed in such manner as their
                            judgment may dictate. Contributions from the ladies in the way of needle and fancy work are
                            especially invited ar.d anticipated as one of the more prominent features of the exposition.
                            To manufacturers this exhibition offers op portunities second only to the Centennial Ex
                            position. Occurring on the eve of the assem bling of Congress, and at the season of the year
                            when all the foreign representatives arc at their legations, every exhibit will have the
                            attention, not only of our own representatives but of the representatives of all the
                            eivilizec nations, as well as the representatives of the Press, who will gladly make full
                            mention of all worthy exhibits; this, with the fact that each donation or exhibit
                            contributes so much to a work that must commend itself to every patriotic citizen. All
                            exhibits will bear the name of artist, manufacturer, etc., and will remain in place until
                            the close of the exposition. Arrangements for transportation of exhibits are being made, and
                            details will be given on application to the Board of Direction. Rooms 90 to !)(!, Ebbitt
                            House, Washington, D. C.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Liberal minds are open to conviction..." TEIform="index"/>Liberal minds are open to conviction...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Liberal minds are open to conviction. Liberal doctrines are capable of improvement. There are
                            proselytes from atheism, but none from superstition. I have known folks who have never
                            committed a blunder whose hearts are as dry as dust; and others, who have contsantly
                            transgressed, whose sympathies were as warm and as quick as those of an angel</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Burleigh, Celia" TEIform="persName"/>Celia Burleigh</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vice stings us even in our pleasures..." TEIform="index"/>Vice stings us even in our pleasures...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"Vice stings us even in our pleasures, but virtue consoles us even in our pains."</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Every whit pretty" TEIform="index"/>EVERY WHIT PRETTY
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Fly Catcher, The little Birds, The Monarch of the Glen, and The
                                Children at Play, Four very pretty placques, issued by Mbsbbs, C. I. Hood and Co., of
                                Lowell, Mass, and presented to those who purchase the articles that are published on the
                                reversed side of the cards. If the medicines are as pleasant to take as are these
                                ornamental designs, our friends may not be in want of customers. By all means secure one
                                of the neat little placques which may of itself, no doubt, cure a multitude of ills.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal" TEIform="index"/>PHRENOLOGICAL Journal
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Sept. Pub. by Fowler and Wells, 753 Broadway,N. Y.. Contents.
                                Rudolph Yirchow, the Eminent Physiologist, with Portrait, Fishing for men, Education the
                                true principle for Reform, The true wife and the Usurper, Guiteau's brain, Woman in
                                flood and fire, A remarkable Geyser, Illustrated, Are house plants unhealthful ? Kitchen
                                leaflet, Notes in Science and Agriculture, Poetry, Editorial Items, etc., etc. Terms
                                $2.00 per year. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New light of Asia" TEIform="index"/>THE NEW LIGHT OF ASIA
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Arnold, Edwin" TEIform="persName"/>Edwin Arnold</byline><p TEIform="p">"The Iliad of India" some call it, and others
                                liken it to Milton's "Paradise Lost." Whatever terms may be used to describe it, Edwin
                                Arnold's remarkable poem, "The Light of Asia," has certainly won a place among the
                                classics in literature, and the best edition of it will be wanted in every home library.
                                Related to the .religion of India it is not unlike Milton's immortal poem as related to
                                the Christian religion. The new edition just issued by the Useful Knowledge Publishing
                                Company, New York, is perhaps the most beautiful, typographically, which has ever
                                appeared, and is of course far lower in price than any other edition published, which
                                will compare with it, being only 20 cts. ior Utility binding, 30 cts. for the cloth, and
                                40 cts. for the half Russia, or for the extra cloth gilt edges. This edition is
                                especially valuable, and for that reason will displace every other, and cau^e those who
                                are already supplied with other editions to put them aside and take this because of the
                                sketches of the lives of Edwin Arnold, the author, and of Buddha, the subject, and the
                                numerous illustrative notes explaining the many references to persons, places, customs,
                                etc., which arc necessarily enigmatical to any one not deeply versed in the history,
                                religion, and literature of India. These valuable additions are from the pen of Mrs. I.
                                L. Hi,user, a most competent writer, who was for many years a resident of India, and is
                                known as the author of '-The Orient and its People." Enterprising booksellers will
                                supply this edition, and canvassers and club agents are wanted everywhere, to whom very
                                unusual terms and facilities are offered by the publishers.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Herald of health" TEIform="index"/>Herald of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">. September.
                                Pub. by M. L. Holbrook M. D. 13 and 15 Laight St., N. Y. Contents, Malaria and Malarial
                                Diseases, The <pb n="239" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 239 climate of California, Canned
                                Pruit, Health a Duty, The A lanthus Tree, Marriage and Parentage, Sprains treated by
                                Massage, Iced Water, Too careful about Health, Weary Women, Breakfasts, etc., etc.
                                Terms, $1.00 a year. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Golden rule" TEIform="index"/>The Golden Rule
                            </head><p TEIform="p">
                                 A BARE OFFER. I'rani tin' EBi»S»li!»5i«'rs of T3a«»
                                S*o2«3«&gt;i« IRu!l« to th« fifie«»«!ers of The .TM«n5fonto. • The Golden Rule is a
                                weekly non-sectarian, religious family paper, published in Boston, at two dollars a
                                year, and is rated one of the best of its class. Xo paper in the country can excel the
                                Golden Rule in attractiveness and intrinsic value. It is the favorite family paper
                                wherever introduced. It has something for every member of the family, and is always
                                pure, bright, helpful, entertaining, and pre-eminently readable. Whenever a fair trial
                                has been given to the Golden Kule it has almost always secured a permanent subscriber.
                                It is on this ground that a new departure is made in the history of newspaper
                                enterprise. Bead the following offer : To any reader of The MANiFEsto, not voiv a
                                subscriber to the Golden Rule, sending US cents in stamps or offierwise, the Golden Rule
                                will be sent from the time the subscription is received to January 1,1883. Although this
                                sum does not nearly cover the actual expense of the paper thus sent, we know that it
                                will be a good investment in the end, as experience has shown that when the pnper has
                                once gained a foot-hold in a family, it is almost sure to become a constant guest.
                                Newspapers are like people; it takes time to get acquainted with them, but when once an
                                attachment is formed, it is hard to break. Write at once, enclosing 25 cents, and
                                mention The Manifesto. You are sure of four times your money's worth, at least. Address,
                                "The Golden Rule, Boston, Mass." The publishers of The Manifesto cordially endorse all
                                that is claimed above for the Golden Rule. We consider it a paper of rare merit, and our
                                readers will do well to accept so generous an offer.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>Select</head><div3 type="history" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="First watch" TEIform="index"/> The first Watch.</head><p TEIform="p">—At first the watch was about the size of a dessert plate. It had weights and was used as
                                a "pocket clock" The earliest known use of the modern name occurs in the record of 1552,
                                which mentions that Edward vi, had "one larum or watch of iron, the case being likewise
                                of iron gilt. with two plummets of lead.'' The first watch may readily be supposed to
                                have been of rude execution. The first great improvements, the substitution of springs
                                for weights, was in 1560. The earliest springs were not coiled, but only straight pieces
                                of steel. Early watches had only one hand, and being wound up twice a day they could not
                                be expected to keep the time nearer than fifteen or twenty minutes in twelve hours. The
                                dials were of silver and brass, the cases had no crystals, but opened at the back and
                                front, and were four or five inches in diameter. A plain watch cost more than $1,500,
                                and after one was ordered it took a year to make it.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Golden rule" TEIform="index"/>TRY THIS THE GOLDEN RULE</head><p TEIform="p">TRY THIS THE GOLDEN RULE. Best unseetarian Religious Family Weekly; 8 pages, illustrated.
                                On trial to Jan. 1, only 25 cts. Address, (ioi.den Rule, Boston, Mass. </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Learn to say no..." TEIform="index"/>Learn to say no...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Learn to say no. If a man makes a request of you which you cannot grant, tell him so at
                                once. Don't deceive him. It may make him feel unpleasant toward you for the moment only.
                                If you deceive him. he will hate you all his life, if he does not despise you. </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Slander" TEIform="index"/>Slander
                            </head><p TEIform="p">—Against slander there is no defence. Hell cannot boast so foul a fiend, nor man
                                deplore so foul a foe. It stabs with a word, with a nod, with a shruV, with a look, with
                                a smile. It is the pestilence walking in darkness, spreading contagion far and wide,
                                which the most wary traveler cannot avoid. It is the heart-searching dagger of the
                                assassin. It is the poisoned arrow whose wound is incurable. It is as mortal as the
                                .'ting of the deadly arrow ; murder is its employment, innocence its prey, and ruin its
                                sport. </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It was prettily devised of Æsop..." TEIform="index"/>It was prettily devised of Æsop...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">It \vas prettily devised of iEsop, the fly sat upon the axle tree of the chariot wheel,
                                and said, "What a dust do I raise !" So are there some vain persons that, whatsoever
                                goeth it alone or moveth upon greater means, if they have never so little hand in it,
                                they think 'it is they that carry it.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bacon" TEIform="persName"/>—Bacon. </byline></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Judge not that ye be not judged" TEIform="index"/>Judge not that ye be not judged
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Judge not that ye be not judged.</p></div3></div2><pb n="240" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Endless growth" TEIform="index"/> ENDLESS GROWTH.</head><p TEIform="p"> Canterbury, N. H. Ever ehanging, ever aiming Toward a higher better life; Ever Oft reviewing
                            and renewing Consecrations made to God; Oft re Be it evor our eneavor As the sand onr time
                            glass fills, To be learning, ever penting ne'er remoulded by the earning ^enting Potter Is
                            A.t In the the the good believer's strife, testing of his rod. fashion that he wills. Light
                            Mount For unfolding, spirit moulding, Is the law of endless growth; Feeding ing higher
                            drawing nigher To the realms of truth and love, Tracing he knoweth and he doeth What so e'er
                            is wise and just, thought and word and action, From the wells of boundless truth, duty
                            seeing beauty In the laws he doth approve, all, with humble spirit In his keeping place our
                            trust.</p></div2><pb id="p29" TEIform="pb"/><!--
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p30"/>
                            <pb id="p31"/>
                            <pb id="p32"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>