<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2408" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">27</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">East Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">24</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">08</biblScope><date value="18940801" TEIform="date">August 1894</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">173-196</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="24" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="08" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
AUGUST.
THE
MANIFESTO
PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES.
VOL. XXIV.
" Cast thy bread upon the waters ; for thou shalt find it after many days."
Eccl. XI: i.
East Canterbury, N. H.
1894.--><pb n="173" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="History of South Union, Kentucky, no. 10" TEIform="index"/>HISTORY OF SOUTH UNION, KY. No.
                            10.</head><p TEIform="p">HTAECEMBER 4. Rumors are afloat that the Confederacy is intend1 J'vng to include the
                            Believers among those to be drafted. This is to us a day of great anxiety, as it forces some
                            of the Brethren to leave home and go to Union Village, in Ohio. One of the young Brethren
                            became so sensitive on the subject of being forced into the Confederate army, that it
                            unfitted him for business. He then determined to move to a northern state. He traveled to
                            Morgantown, Green River, Hartford and on to Louisville. The Brethren liberally furnished him
                            with money to defray his expenses. At Louisville, he bought two barrels of lard oil and one
                            of kerosine. Several other articles were also purchased at the same time. These he brought
                            on to Owensborough, but we could not get anything through the Confederate army at Bowling
                            Green. A hired colored man was sent to Green River, for the goods, and fortunately returned
                            with them, all safe. Dec. 8. Two soldiers of the Confederacy call, and the morning is very
                            cold. They have a two horse wagon. One of them entered the Trustees' Office and said he
                            would like to buy an overcoat, as it was so cold. One was passed to him which he could have
                            for five dollars. The soldier put the coat on and said it was just a fit, and he was well
                            suited but could only pay two dollars in Confederate notes. The Brethren wished to be paid
                            in good money. He then pocketed his bill and started off saying, "I will not pay anything."
                            Pulling the coat around him, he seemed to view it with much satisfaction, and returning to
                            his wagon, drove off toward Bowling Green. It rather pleased me to see the poor fellow pull
                            the coat about him and see him step off so proudly with the long coat tails switching about
                            his heels. AUGUST <pb n="174" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> 174 THE MANIFESTO. Indeed, I pitied the man, as I
                            believe he would have suffered from the cold, without that extra garment. We now thought it
                            wise to take a little more c .re in regard to lh2 safety of our clothing. As the weather is
                            very mid we had a large number of nice white and also grey blankets that we shouLl not need
                            a* pr sent. Other goods were also carefully laid away, lest in an untimely hour, so.ne of
                            these wandering characters might break into the house-* and steal them. Another soldier
                            asked us to give him a blanket. He was a poo;1 mm, by the name of Clark and lives about four
                            miles distant from our Village. He had joined the southern army and was bgging because he
                            was very needy. We provided him with a good blanket, for which he expressed many thanks. One
                            hundred and fourteen wagons with army stores passed through the Village. These were followed
                            by a company of Cavalry. Then more wagons came along and this tramming was kept up till
                            midnight. One of the Brethren ascertained that not less than twelve hundred camped on our
                            grounds during the night. Jan. 23. The artillery company leave early this morning for
                            Russellville. A large number of army wagons pass during the day. The Sisters are kept busy
                            baking bread and other articles for the soldiers. One company must have some roast turkey,
                            and at seven p. m., a company ordered a chicken stew. Jan. 24. Every thing pertaining to our
                            own home, that can be consistently, is allowed to rest quietly, and the attention of all who
                            are able is engaged in the service of the army. The Brethren are obliged to prepare an extra
                            amount of fire wood and also to spend much time in looking after the multiplied wants of the
                            soldiers. The cars, filled with soldiers, are running day and night. The officers who are
                            with us are ignorant of all this moving of the soldiers from place to place. A train of
                            thirty cars pass the Village, at the close of the day, filled with Infantry. Hideous yells
                            rend the air, till the cars are some distance from us. A company of five armed men ride up
                            to the office, and say they want to buy some cloth, but when they ascertain that a regiment
                            of Cavalry are stationed at our Village they decline the purchase and suddenly leave the
                            place. The Officers say that they were not soldiers, but were robbers, and if any more call
                            while they are on the place they will arrest them. By our kind attention to the soldiers we
                            have gained their good will and they now protect us against marauders. Some fifteen or
                            twenty Officers have been permitted to board at the Trustees' Office, by their urgent
                            request. One day as they were leaving the table, one of the Officers remarked to the Sister
                            present,"Madam, I fear you will kill us with so much good food." She replied:"Better that
                            than with a bullet." While the soldiers were at our home Elder John Rankin and Br. Urban
                            Johns were constantly engaged in attending to their calls and in taking care <pb n="175" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 175 of the premises. Several of our Sisters were sick with the
                            measles which brought an extra labor upon us, and a constant anxiety occupied the mind, for
                            the safety of our property. The unsettled condition of the country was an opportunity for
                            lawless characters to be prowling around, and stealing whatever might fall in their way. At
                            noon an old man partially crazed with excitement, called at the Office and demanded dinner
                            for himself and several Texan Rangers. The Brethren advised him to go to the Hotel, about a
                            mile distant. At this he clinched his fist and threatened to strike Elder John Rankin. He
                            then insisted that the Brethren should furnish nim with a buggy, but being told that we
                            could not, the company left the place, and soon meeting one of the Brethren with a horse and
                            buggy, they took the buggy from him and gave him thirty dollars in Confederate scrip. The
                            Brother took the money and came home and considered himself fortunate to have saved the
                            horse. Jan. 25. The army still remain with us, and seem to consider themselves in good luck
                            to obtain such excellent fare. The Brethren have persuaded the Colonel to send some of the
                            Cavalry to another place as they have consumed and destroyed all the corn, hay and oats that
                            were stored in the barn. In the evening some of the Officers went to the house of Dr. R- - -
                            - - -and demanded him to furnish several hundred weight of beef for the soldiers ; but the
                            doctor was not of the class who gave something for nothing. One day he brought a firkin of
                            butter. On being asked the price he said he should charge fifty cents a pound. The soldiers
                            denounced him as an abolitionist. In a short time Col. Nixon, who may be called a southern
                            gentleman, came along and asked the price of the butter. Dr. R- - - - - -said fifty cents.
                            The Col. took the butter, without any words, and may have paid for it at a later date. The
                            Brethren have opened a little store at the Trustees' Office, and are doing quite a business
                            with the soldiers. Almost every kind of food that we can spare finds a ready sale. The
                            soldiers bring flour and exchange it for bread, or pie or potatoes and seem very grateful.
                            Jan. 26. The beef that was demanded of Dr. R- - - - - -yesterday, has not ride over to his
                            mansion and order his negroes to harness the horses and haul the beef to Shaker town. This
                            is a severe reprimand to the doctor, although he has treated others the same way. He thought
                            it was very uncourteous to send armed men to his house on Sunday, to demand the beef. He did
                            not like the appearance of being forced. The Officer passed the doctor a Confederate note,
                            in payment, and then made sport of him. The family of one of our neighbors are all sick with
                            the measles, and two Sisters go to assist them. Most of our children are confined with the
                            same disease. been sent according to promise, and about twelve armed men and an Officer <pb n="176" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> 176 THE MANIFESTO. Jan. 27. John McC- - - - - -hauled a load of oats
                            to the army. The forage master asked John how many bundles were ou the load. "Five hundred,"
                            said John. Comack said "I do not think there are more than four hundred." "Well," John
                            said,, "suppose you put it down five hundred and I will bring you a bottle of liquor in the
                            morning." The forage master went to Col. Nixon and informed him of the interview. The Col.
                            laughed at Comack, and said he ought, to have had a harder face than to be put off in that
                            way. Poor John, he paid dear for his whistle, as the soldiers laughed at him and called him
                            many unpleasant names for pretending to be a good secesh friend, and then trying to swindle
                            the government that he was professing to support. Jan. 28. Col. Scott leaves with a company
                            of soldiers for Russellville, and we are interested to have them go as soon as consistent.
                            Col. Nixon and one hundred and twenty-one soldiers remain at the Village. Nixon was formerly
                            the Editor of the New Orleans Crescent. Some of the Officers are very much interested in the
                            stock and speak in praise of the herd of cows, and the nice barn in which they are kept. (To
                            be continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beauty" TEIform="index"/>BEAUTY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Reed, Calvin G." TEIform="persName"/>By Calvin G. Reed.</byline><p TEIform="p">Beauty is the reflex of the inner life. What beauty hath the rich and gaudy flower? Or what
                            delight the vernal landscape's robe Of green, bedecked with variegated bloom ; Or the pure
                            azure canopy of heaven; Or twinkling stars that nightly smile upon Us from their spacious
                            dwelling-place on high ; Or purling streams meandering through rich meads, Or tuneful
                            warblers; Or the shady groves ; To those whose inner life feels not the thrill Of harmony,
                            in tint and tone, displayed In the vast realm of Beauty's fadeless spring? The sky is
                            curtained o'er with somberness. And all the brilliant tints and gorgeous hues Shed by the
                            glorious sunbeams radiant light, Are blank and beautiless unto the mind That hath no
                            brilliant sunshine of the heart. What multitudes but seek a hollow joy! Chase phantoms that
                            elude the eager grasp, <pb n="177" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 177 And while they lure, spread
                            disappointment's thorns Along the pathway of their votaries, To pierce the weary feet, or
                            grasping hands, And sting with bitterness the heart's bright hopes, Because they seek
                            through Alchemy for gold, Instead of veins, where, hidden, lies the rich Productive ore,
                            that pays the miner's toil. Ah! if we would the beautiful secure, Awake the powers of mind,
                            of soul, attuned To all the grand sublimities of life. So every heart-pulse beats with
                            Wisdom's laws, Perfecting in us beatific grace, Holiness, and eternal love divine. When the
                            deep fountains of the soul well up With gushing streams of liquid beauty. And all is
                            brilliancy within the heart, The bloom and fruitage of our inner lives, Then will the whole
                            creation, smiling, shed The radiance of its beauteous spirit on Our pure, appreciative
                            minds, in halos Of inspiring power, and symphonies Refulg'ent with the glories of the blest.
                            Then will each bud, each leaf and opening flower, Gain kindly welcome to our loving hearts,
                            Unfolding for us volumes of God's truth, Securely treasured there for us to scan. ' I love
                            the beauteous works of the Divine, Omniscient Architect of worlds unnumbered, Swarming with
                            their myriad hosts of living Forms, from rational to brute, and thence to Floral fields of
                            varied hues, instinct with Life and beauty; all of workmanship divine. I love the Lord of
                            life; Eternal Guide, And Author of the soul immortal, formed To shine with heavenly light,
                            and feast on Glories of bright spheres intrinsically pure. There is a realm of harmony
                            sublime, Where beauties blend with beauties, full of grace And loveliness, pervading every
                            heart With cheerful pleasantness and blissful peace. Those who the inner life make beautiful
                            By education and supernal grace, Will see the beautiful in all God's works; <pb n="178" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> 178 THE MANIFESTO. And feel that happy angels, on their snowWhite pinions,
                            bear them blessings from the spheres Of beauteous bliss, and unalloyed happinss. Then give
                            the mind to Understanding's rule ; The soul to inspirations, that are found Alone in
                            Wisdom's school,all beautiful. All-Wise Creator of the realms of Light, Whose every thought
                            is full of blooming grace, Whose breath is fragrant with supreme delight, And works
                            unnumbered, full of harmony, The effulgence of eternal, sacred truth, Let me now offer at
                            thy sacred shrine, Sweet incense of adoring gratitude; And worship, with unfolded, graceful
                            soul, The God of Beauty who created all. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="Section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beloved Elder Henry;--The following..." TEIform="index"/>Beloved Elder Henry;--The following...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Beloved Elder Henrst;The following is a copy of an ancient document written sixty-four
                                years ago, found among the writings of Elder F. W. Evans and addressed to his natural
                                brother Geo. H. Evans, the great land reformer. I send it to you in hopes of seeing it
                                in another shape later on, being confident that if published in our monthly it will be
                                read by numerous friends of Elder Frederic, with much interest. In those days it cost
                                something to send a letter weighing less than half an ounce, by mail. Twelve and a half
                                cents is written with ink on the outside of the letter, as being the price that was paid
                                for transportation. Now, we should stop and think, twice, before sending a letter
                                costing that much to New York City. This was worth it then and did good; and if you
                                consider the letter worth the printing, it surely is worth the reading.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., A." TEIform="persName"/>A. W.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Brother;--As I have a good deal to say..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Dear Brother;--As I have a good deal to say...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, New Lebanon, June 11, 1830" TEIform="index"/>New Lebanon, N. Y. June 11,
                                1830.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Brother;As I have a good deal to say about this people, I shall commence with them
                                first. When I arrived at the village, after introducing myself, I was shown into a room
                                kept to accommodate strangers. They then inquired my motives for visiting them. I said,
                                "to learn the principles which bind your Society together." A Brother then gave me some
                                cider to drink and soon dinner was ready. I went into a room where was a table loaded
                                with every thing a hungry man could wish, with a Sister to wait upon me. After dinner I
                                saw several of the Brothers. All appeared ready and willing to converse on any subject.
                                They soon discovered that I was a Materialist, although I did not design to let them
                                know it so soon, but I found I could not keep up with them at all on any other ground.
                                Instead of being <pb n="179" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 179 horror struck, as I expected,
                                they congratulated me on being freed from all kinds of religious superstitions that are
                                in the world. I asked them if their system was founded on the Bible. "Nay," said they,
                                "on nothing but principles, yet we bring the Scriptures to those who believe in them in
                                order to convert the m, but to you, who do not believe them, we bring reason to prove
                                our system true, if you are a free inquirer after truth." This was something I did not
                                expect. I unfolded our system of morality, that virtue was happiness, vice, misery; and
                                that the whole pursuit of man should be to make himself happy in this world. All this
                                they said, was the very object of their institution, and that if I would remain long
                                enough to become acquainted with them I should find the truth of those principles proved
                                by demonstration. "But I do not believe," said I, "in any spiritual world, in no
                                salvation, in no heaven nor hell, nor Christ, nor God." They replied, "Salvation is to
                                be happy here, and when you are happy, you are in heaven, when unhappy, in hell. As to a
                                God,you believe in a principle in the world that you call life, nature, goodness. We
                                call this God and believe and can prove to any reasonable man that reason is a part of
                                God and that God operates upon the mind and body of human beings." And this they have
                                proven, to me. In fact, instead of finding an ignorant, superstitious, credulous and
                                illiteral people, I find men of the first talents, education and property, men who have
                                been Robert Owens' intimate friends, and infidels all their lives; men who have been
                                worth from five thousand to ten thousand dollars, and have been engaged in business on
                                the most extensive scale. Now before you call me a fool, or those in this Society, just
                                explain to me the nature of life, and animal magnetism, and then come here and see what
                                you nor I never saw before,a happy people. A people divested of self and acting on the
                                broad principles of justioe, equality, charity, love, not in theory, mind you, but in
                                practice. Do you say it is highly colored, I am bewitched, and wrong? I say, come and
                                see. I give you my word with all my senses keenly alive, that while I have worked with
                                them, talked with them and done nothing but observe them for a week, I pronounce them a
                                perfectly good people, and they reap the effect, which is perfect happiness. They think
                                that Infidels and Materialists are nearer to them than any other people; first, because
                                they are accustomed to reason, and next, as far as they do believe anything it is
                                exactly the same. But you say, "they do not countenance the flesh." Ah! what a pity.
                                What was it made you unhappy but the flesh ? that is at the bottom of all your
                                unhappiness. I shall not undertake to reason with you much yet, though I will mention a
                                few of the chances it offers you. If you will take the trouble to examine into this
                                work, that will be all that is requisite to make you adopt it, and that you can only do
                                fairly, by coming to see us. If you <pb n="180" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> 1 0 THE - MANIFESTO. belonged
                                to this Society, your children would be as well, aye better, brought up than you can do
                                it if you had your thousands ; your wife would become your sister and be no further
                                trouble to you, nor you to her, and you would be healthy and happy. All,, work alike,
                                dress alike, share alike and are alike. All are free. All are nonresistant, returning
                                goo I for evil. They never turn away any one who wishes to better his condition. A bad
                                persou would not live here for a thousand dollars a year, for like a fish out of water
                                he would be out of his element. Here too, are the strongest lvusoueres that I have ever
                                seen, no exceptions, even the women are exceptional; they are unassuming in their
                                manners, sensible in dress and address. That which we have heard about them is
                                absolutely false. I am at no loss now why Ovveus' system did not succeed. I should like
                                you to write and let me know how you take this, you will call it turning Christian. I
                                shall call it becoming happy; 1 have not had to change a single opinion. I shall become
                                a Shaker. Your Shaker Biother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Sister:--We received yours..." TEIform="index"/>Dear Sister:--We received yours...</head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Rhode Island, Providence, May 1894" TEIform="index"/>Providence, R. I. May, 1894.</dateline><p TEIform="p">[Beloved Editob;Please favor the
                                publication of the following letter. Having been recently received from one who is in
                                spirit a Brother with us, we think it may do good to others, who maybe persuaded to "do
                                likewise."]
                                Dear Sister :We received yours, which brought joy and blessing with it, as it was full
                                and laden with good things. We were glad to receive so large a letter with such extended
                                friendship, for it came from and covered the whole family. These remittances are like
                                "angel visits" to our home ; they bring with them blessing and cheer. It would be
                                useless for me to attempt to frame one to equal it, but if we do our best, that is all
                                we can do and all that is required of us. You have had years of experience in the Christ
                                life and have traveled farther in the way, for we have only just started on the heavenly
                                journey, barely left the shore, and we have had to "lay aside every weight" that beset
                                us. How great the load, and how sharp the briers that pierce our feet! My Sister, we
                                were steeped in sin, for it was years we traveled therein, when we thought we were in
                                the right way ; and to "come out from among them," and walk in the shadow of the cross,
                                seemed to be more than we could do. But a careful and prayerful stepping has enabled us
                                to reach thus far. We used to sing when in the Salvation Army, "I have been in the Army
                                so long, and have not grown weary yet," but when the new light of higher truth broke
                                into our soul, we soon found we did, for we became so tired, the way seemed so strait to
                                us, yet our souls longed for more of Christ. Having now tasted and learned that the Lord
                                is good, we find ourselves in water that we can <pb n="181" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO.
                                181 not wade in. We must swim or fall back into the old nature, which we pray may never
                                be the case. Give our love to all the Brethren and Sisters. The advancement we have made
                                has been due to the untiring efforts of our true friends at East Canterbury. We shall
                                never be able to recompense them, but our Heavenly Father will do this in full measure,
                                we know. The times remain about the same, but God has blest our home, in our souls and
                                also in our "basket and store." We have been blest with all things needful through the
                                long winter, and G-od will not forsake us. That we do know. Our kind love ever. Your
                                Brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Elam, William" TEIform="persName"/>Wm. Elam.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beloved Elder Henry:--I have an impression..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Beloved Elder Henry:--I have an impression...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Ohio, White Water, July 1894" TEIform="index"/>White Water, Ohio. July, 1894.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Beloved Elder Henry :I have an impression to pen a few thoughts on a subject that seems
                                of importance. There are many who cry, lo here and lo there. In the last time there
                                should come false Christs who should deceive many, but we are told not to go after them
                                nor follow them. Where the body is, there will the eagles be gathered. The perfect
                                organized church or body was in 1792, under the divine revelation given to Elder Joseph
                                Meacham and Eldress Lucy Wright. This was confirmed and supported by living witnesses
                                and remains as such to the present time. It is written, Search the Scriptures, for in
                                them ye think ye have eternal life. The parables of Jesus seem to be legends of Bible
                                history and were used by him in his public teaching, especially to his chosen disciples
                                who, at times, would ask for the meaning of the parables,of the woman who took some
                                leaven and hid it in three measures of meal. One of the disciples understood it to mean,
                                the falling away of the church in the first appearing, and spoke as follows; Then few
                                will be saved, seeing that he said, Blessed are your eyes, for they see. Strive to enter
                                in at the strait gate, many shall desire and will not be able. Beware of the leaven of
                                the Pharisees. Leaven in the law was considered iniquity. The parable of the marriage
                                spoken of in the xx Chap, of Matthew, reads thus ; A certain King made a marriage for
                                his son. It is spoken of as an event of the past, and I think it refers to the marriage
                                that Abraham made for Isaac, in the xxiv Chap, of Genesis. It was the true type, and was
                                natural. The antitype is given to us in Rev. xix. Let us be glad and rejoice and give
                                honor to him for the marriage of the Lamb is come, and his wife hath made herself ready.
                                And to her was granted that she should be arrayed in fine linen, clean and white, for
                                the fine linen is the righteousness of the saints. Jesus who was the man, Christ the
                                bridegroom, and the bride so beautiful- <pb n="182" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> 182 THE MANIFESTO. ly
                                arrayed was Ann Lee who would be acknowledged as the Mother of all living souls. The
                                Spirit and the Bride say come, and all who will may come and take of the water of life
                                freely. It is written,Strait is the gate and narrow is the way that leads to life and
                                few there be that tind it. Btoad is the way that leads to death and many go in thereat.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ball, Stephen W." TEIform="persName"/>Stephen W. Ball.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My Esteemed Brother in the Faith..." TEIform="index"/>My Esteemed Brother in the Faith...</head><p TEIform="p">[Beloved Elder Henry;Will you
                                please give the extract from a letter of one of our enquirers a place in the Manifesto.
                                I am not at liberty to give names.]
                                My Esteemed Brother in the Faith ;Last year, I wrote a few lines you will excuse me at
                                this time if I open my mind, as it is pressed full. In all the societies of this world I
                                fail to find perfection, but in many are some (more or less) who are true to the core.
                                Having known a little about the Society of Believers, covering a few years, I see a real
                                need of a revival of the inward working and goodly manifestation outwardly, saving and
                                cleansing the whole person, as was the case with Ann Lee. She is reported as saying, "I
                                feel the blood (life) of Jesus Christ coursing all through my being, purifying me unto
                                himself." That, as I understand, is the power of Eternal Life. Has the life or blood of
                                Jesus Christ lost its power? I think I hear you say, Nay, and Isav, Amen. Let me assure
                                you, my brother, there are many men and women out over this wicked world, yes over these
                                New England states, who are by him set apart to live and walk in the Spirit, Holy, and
                                they could be gathered in his Spirit, in his name, to the vacant houses and distressed
                                lands of your Societies. Your only hope seems, that you take up the work afresh, just
                                where Ann Lee was taken from it, and casting down and out all false or perverse spirits,
                                rise up to glorify God in the power of the Holy Spirit. I have no personal thrusts to
                                make, I only write of Shakers, so called, as I have seen them. Sorry to say I have met
                                believers in Robert Ingersoll and modern spiritualists in among your leaders. What would
                                Ann Lee do or say, were she to come back now to the gatherings. I think she would, inf
                                olio wing her precious MasterChrist, drive out, with what was to her power even the fire
                                of the Holy Ghost. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="N., E. E." TEIform="persName"/>E. E. N.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My testimony" TEIform="index"/>MY TESTIMONY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bellmire, William" TEIform="persName"/>By William Bellmire.</byline><p TEIform="p">I FEEL impressed to give a testimony to all whom it may concern, as to my present and future
                            life in the gospel of Jesus the Christ and our blessed Mother Ann who revived this
                            soul-saving plan, which Jesus was the first to inaugurate. He set the example of
                            self-denial, by denying himself of all <pb n="183" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 183 ungodliness
                            and every worldly lust, and said emphatically "Follow me." I feel there is no excuse for me,
                            as I know full well my duty which my calling binds me to; hence I shall hereafter, all the
                            days of my life, live a life of true holiness in word, thought and deed. Thirty years of my
                            life were wasted, by sowing to the flesh. "For he that soweth to "his flesh shall of the
                            flesh reap corruption; but he that soweth to the spirit shall of the spirit reap life
                            everlasting." Gal. vi., 8. In Romans viii., 1, we read "There is therefore now no
                            condemnation to them which are in Christ Jesus, (those who are living and walking as he
                            walked) who walk not after the flesh, but after the spirit." "So then they that are in the
                            flesh (in its demoralizing and degrading works) can not please God." Rom. viii., 8. How
                            often young people entertain the delusive idea that thei'e is surely great enjoyment in a
                            worldly, sensual life, else the whole world would not engage in such a life. But my many
                            years of service in it, have proved that it is a sad failure and prevents you from gaining
                            life eternal. It is easy to hold in submission the rippling rill, but the sturdy billows of
                            the ocean are beyond our control. So it is with all of the passions and appetites of the
                            body, it is easy to control them while in our youth, if we only make the effort; but if we
                            allow them to control us, they become our master and then we become slaves. I shall bear and
                            do bear a testimony against this great sin on every occasion and by so doing I shall
                            ultimately overcome even as he overcame. I often think of a hymn I learned when a youth:
                            "How many souls have wandered from Zion's lovely shore, By yielding here a little and there
                            a little more; For one I am resolved I never will retreat Nor yield to Satan's flattery no
                            matter what I meet" Had I not yielded a little here and a little there to temptation, I
                            would be in your midst to-day. Brethren and Sisters, I desire your prayers, your help and
                            your blessing each day to help me live a consecrated life to God.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The indulgence of malicious feeling..." TEIform="index"/>
                            The indulgence of malicious feeling...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The indulgence of malicious feeling toward but one person, will neutralize the religious
                            efficacy of a hundred acts of charity; and one cherished bigoted feeling towards one
                            Christian denomination, will turn to gall all the cherished love to the brethren.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We who are in official standing..." TEIform="index"/>
                            We who are in official standing...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">We who are in official standing and care, ought to place ourselves at least every hour of the
                            day in the exact condition of those who have to receive the results of our leadership and
                            stewardship. For Heaven's sake let us think of this.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="H., O. C." TEIform="persName"/>O. C. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="There is a much greater delight..." TEIform="index"/>
                            There is a much greater delight...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">There is a much greater delight in extracting a thorn from a neighbors' hand, than in
                            smelling the rose. Try it. If you do not find this to be the case, you are dead and buried
                            in the love of self. </p></div2><pb n="184" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Purity and unity" TEIform="index"/>PURITY AND UNITY. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">IN the writings of one of our gospel fathers, who has long since passed beyond the scenes of
                            time, we find the following remark. "The essential properties of the church of Christ are
                            purity and unity." Indeed, they are the essential properties. The center and circumference
                            of the whole work. In and through them is the life and growth of the soul and closely
                            connected with this comes the life and growth of the church of God. Whatever else may be
                            included in the acceptation of Christian communism, it may easily be seen that a
                            disciplinary order of life will be demanded for the successful continuance of the Society.
                            There must be a standard of purity which shall determine the right to an inheritance of the
                            promises that have been handed down to us from the spiritual position occupied by our divine
                            Teacher, and this standard includes his life. Quite early in his mission he had occasion to
                            impart lessons of instruction to those who came to hear him. "Blessed are the pure in heart,
                            for they shall see God." He was not a stranger to the ways of man. He knew that the heart
                            was deceitful above all things and desperately wicked ; and he also knew that it was
                            necessary for those who had the least desire to live above the elements of the world, to
                            accept a personal government over their thoughts and indeed, over their whole lives. A
                            consecrated person has no more right to think injuriously of his friend or neighbor than he
                            has to speak against them. If God is the observer of the inner man, and holding a record of
                            the thoughts and intents of the heart, then a disciplinary care over every influence must be
                            of the utmost importance. The apostle James was also a careful observer of men and in
                            leading them on to Christ he would have them become, "first pure, then peaceable," after
                            which they would be "easy to be entreated." Nothing nearer to the point nor clearer to the
                            understanding of a seeker after righteousness could be presented. A society resting on any
                            foundation less permanent than this would be in great danger when "the winds blow and the
                            floods come" as it would fail to bear the test. If we have rested on assurances that have
                            been so by tradition, and these may have been all that they wTere purported to have been for
                            those who hungered and thirsted after righteousness, then instead of becoming vitalized by
                            the living word of God, which is able to heal the sick and to raise the dead, we have merely
                            read of those who were soldiers of the cross and shared the pleasure of their well earned
                            reward. <pb n="185" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 185 A vitalized Christianity is all that will
                            bear the rigid investigation of the present day. Assertions are of trifling value whether
                            pertaining to the things that are present with us or to those that are beyond. All that we
                            are must be manifested by the fruits that are developed in the Christian life. No man will
                            accept a statement from mere rumor. He wants the witness of assurance. If the children of
                            this world have a sharper outlook for the interests of the present life, and work with more
                            zeal to secure them, than the children of light do for the treasures that are imperishable,
                            then our privilege in the Christian mission has not been to us what it should have been. It
                            certainly is wise to work while the day lasts. To use the things of this world as not
                            abusing them, and then work for humanity as God may appoint. One day lost through neglect is
                            a sorrowful record, but when this is multiplied by months and years it is fearful to
                            contemplate. All that may be written on this subject brings us again and again to the remark
                            of the good brother, which has been accepted as the introduction for this thought toward
                            successful communism. Jesus in his lesson to the disciples on the same point gave a
                            beautiful illustration from the fruit bearing trees. It was a life picture. The disciples
                            could see the tree, and they understood the manner of its growth. They had seen it in its
                            season of rest and then during the season of bearing fruit. And when Jesus says "A good tree
                            can not bring forth evil fruit, neither can a coirupt tree bring forth good fruit, they, at
                            once, saw the direct application to their own lives. If they as disciples were pure at
                            heart, and maintained a union with each other in the spirit and power of God, there was a
                            sure chance for them to inspire others with the same spirit and to reap the reward of
                            faithful servants. They were equally as certain that an evil tree or a corrupt heart was
                            destruction to their Christian fellowship. As with them so it is with us as a church ;our
                            union to the spirit of God is our only hope of success, and this is no less true of every
                            church, and of every organization that may be formed among men. Even the civil government
                            becomes cognizant of this fact and publishes it before the people. "United we stand, divided
                            we fall." Through the whole history of man there have been abundant lessons which should
                            have been as the voice of warning to those who dare walk in the path of unrighteousness or
                            carelessly pursue a life of indifference.</p></div2><pb n="186" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Higher" TEIform="index"/>HIGHER.</head><p TEIform="p">"Here am I, for thou didst call me."1 Sam. iii., 6. Canterbury, N. H. 1891. Angels call me,
                            call me higher, To a realm of purer thought; Call me to the fountain nigher, Where the gems
                            of truth are wrought. Call me here to love and worship, Here to serve and learn God's way,
                            Rise, my soul, renewed, responsive, Meet the Christ that calls today.</p></div2><pb n="187" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. AUGUST, 1894. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is published by the
                            "United Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued
                            regularly by the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the
                            religious views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. All
                            communications should be addressed to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H.
                            TERMS. One copy per year, postage paid .75 " " six months, " " .40</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. June. Thermometer. Ruin. 1893. 67.8 1.5in. 1894. 63.9
                                1.4" Highest Temp, during this mo. 92. above 0. Lowest " " " " 38. " " Number of rainy
                                days " " 8. )) clear )) i ? 11 4. ) cloudy 17 ? 1 5) 18. r. (7. Heed July, 1894.
                                Growing, growing. Vegetation seems to be on the jump. Just sunshine and shower enough to
                                make a perfect growth. Our hillsides take kindly to every variety of weather. The
                                blasting east storm of May, did not injure the fruit blossoms. Cherries are abundant,
                                large and fair. Two and a half and three inches in circumference, are a common measure
                                of cherries from some trees. One thing to be observed in passing through the fruit
                                orchards is, that whenever a tree fails, either by age or disease, it is removed and a
                                new growth takes its place; thus giving a hope of a continuous supply of fruit. It often
                                costs the pomologist a pang, to hew down a bearing plum or cherry tree, because of the
                                black knot; but as there is no better remedy for one thoroughly infected, down it comes,
                                and a healthy tree fills the vacancy, with an assurance that hereafter the disease will
                                be attended to as soon as it appears. Does not this teach us the lesson, that to be
                                thrifty in spiritual fruits, every moral disease must be eradicated; for if, "Angels
                                wait on Providence And mark the sundered places To graft with gentlest instrument^ The
                                heavenly graces." Should we not work with them? Sti'awberries have yielded well for a
                                second year's growth. Fifteen bushels have been taken from the vines, and berries four
                                and a half inches in circumference were numerous, while a few measured five and even
                                five and a half inches. The vegetable garden under the care of Elder Calvin, and the
                                root garden adjoining, are an honor to the workers therein, and a pleasure to the
                                beholders. Often observing our faithful Elder Joseph out as early as the birds, and late
                                in the evening, using every moment that can be spared from his spiritual duties, to
                                assist where the burdens lie heaviest, we are led back in thought through the century
                                wliich has witnessed the building up of our Communities and can readily see where the
                                success lay, which transformed a swampy wilderness to our now comparatively fertile
                                plateau. There is no measure of time for labor in any real home. Stated hours belong to
                                the hireling, whose employer's interest is not his. Still it is a positive duty to so
                                wisely garner our strength that we may not fail when most needed. 187 <pb n="188" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> 188 THE MANIFESTO. We were lately cheered by a few hours visit from Elder
                                George Wilcox and Eldress Sophia Copley, of Enfield, Conn., and if "short visits make
                                long friends" our friendship stands a chance to be very much j elongated in these days
                                of fast movements. Our Central Ministry leave us on the 11th inst. for another prolonged
                                absence, to be missed so much; for with all the spiritual strength extended, their hands
                                are ever active to lend temporal aid, proving that "I serve" is a kingly motto, and the
                                way royal to human hearts." Amelia J. Culver. North Family. July, 1894. On the evening
                                of June 26th, our family had the pleasure of the presence of our beloved Ministry
                                Sisters and Br. Alonzo Hollister during an informal and entertaining talk of an hour and
                                a half with our old and esteemed friend, Dr. Dewey of New York. The doctor remarked that
                                he understood and experienced the religious impulses, motives, and inspiration of the
                                higher or spiritual life, and desired most earnestly to impress upon us the importance
                                the life and principles we stand for to be to humanity at large, and to encourage us in
                                the high cause to which we are consecrating our lives. He would, in the presence of a
                                company so much more able to speak upon the experimental and practical side of religious
                                life, occupy the time he had in presenting ideas from the philosophical and intellectual
                                standpoint, whicl might stimulate thought and be interesting as leading up to and
                                supporting the same principles. It has been said "True religion and true philosophy must
                                ultimately arrive at the same conclusions." What better definition can religion give
                                than the philosopher Plato, who defines pure love as a "pure spiritual love, free from
                                carnal desires, having regard to the excellencies of the mind only." Dr. Dewey believes
                                in the law of evolution. In the rise, not in the fall of man. He believes that all
                                things have souls, or a spiritual prototype. We notice that recent scientific
                                investigators are inclining to the spiritual rather than the mechanical origin and
                                evolution of life. The late Prof. Tyndall writes, "Two courses, and only two, are
                                possible. Either let us open our doors freely to the conception cf creative acts, or
                                abandoning them let us radically change our notions of matter. If we look at matter as
                                defined for generations in our scientific text books, the absolute impossibility of any
                                form of life coming out of it would be sufficient to render any other hypothesis
                                preferable. But the definitions of matter given in our scientific text books were
                                intended to cover its purely physical and mechanical properties, and, taught as we have
                                been to regard these definitions as complete, we naturally and rightly reject the
                                monstrous notion that out of such matter any form of life could possibly arise. Dr.
                                Dewey's belief is that the planets were projected and all species of life evolved for
                                the sustenance and production of man as a medium and instrument for the expression of
                                the Divine Mind (God) which he believes to be pure spirit, impersonal, the projector,
                                energizer, life principle of all created things and inspirer of man. That the quickening
                                of the vital spark of the Divine Mind in man, the consciousness of spiritual unity and
                                responsibility, is awakened in souls in all conditions of environment, that it is not
                                conditional upon a degree of preparedness, (here the doctor was closely questioned) that
                                it immediately produces a change of heart, is a birth, but the full stature of man as a
                                spiritual being is not attained until he has risen out of all selfishness and carnal
                                desire and lives wholly in the moral and spiritual qualities of his being. The doctor
                                spoke of the five physical senses and also a sixth and seventh sense, the sixth
                                intuitional, the seventh the sense or consciousness of the through-flowing of the Holy
                                Spirit. He believes heaven to be a condition of union and harmony, that <pb n="189" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 189 man can not reach this condition of himself, but must
                                do so in union with his God and in fellowship with his brother. The idea of
                                re-incarnation is repulsive to the doctor's mind. He believes in the illimitable
                                possibiliti s of the progress of man under divine inspiration. ? God is and always has
                                been a moral idea. God is that moral power, n&gt;t ourselves which makes for righteousness.
                                Jesus gave the world an inspiring and consoling idea when he taught humanity to think of
                                and pray to God as our Father. Mother Ann completed the idea when she revealed the
                                Mother Spirit in Deity, giving us a still more loving, intimate, and sympathetic idea of
                                the love and wisdom of the Divine Mind. Visiting us at the same time were two lady
                                friends. One of them H. Rathburn, an earnest worker in the woman suffrage cause, read
                                the following evening a very interesting paper on Woman's Sphere. We give our blessing
                                and words of encouragement to all workers in a righteous cause. A company of four
                                Sisters and one Brother start for Enfield. Conn., to-morrow to enjoy a good gospel
                                privilege with our generous friends there. Wiiiitr S. Sheyhei'd. South Family. July,
                                1894. Beloved Elder Henky: We take this opportunity to announce that our worthy Sister,
                                Jane (Sutton) Brainard, passed away June 13th at the age of 88 yrs. and 6 mo. The
                                funeral services were, held in the afternoon of the 15th, and lasted about two hours.
                                The several families were well represented, over twenty members from the North family
                                being present. Many words of praise and regard were spoken in honor of our dear Sister.
                                Elder William remarked that he felt more in earnest to be upright and exemplary in all
                                things, as the departed Sister had been, and not be a hindrance to others in any good
                                work. One good Sister expressed deep affection for Sister Jane, an 1 for mxuy other aged
                                ones who have lei't the shores of time, as well as for tli.se who stiii remain with us.
                                Eider Ciintun Brainard remarked that those who do the will of our heavenly Father, are
                                his fathers, mothers, sisters and brothers. He also thanked the family for the kind care
                                extended to his aged parent. We ara glad to inform you that a new pointed, iron fence
                                will soon take the place of tiie old wooden one. This is a great necessity. We now hive
                                the two volumes of the "World's Parliament of Religions," and like then very much. Last
                                week we received Elder Henry's photograph, for which please receive our sincere thanks.
                                I have just received another that I prize very much, that of Edward Bok, editor of "The
                                Ladies' Home Journal." S-trah Collinx.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watervliet, New York" TEIform="index"/>Watervliet, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">North Family. Jnlv, 1814. Wtitle we enjoy communing wit'i our dear Brethren and Sisters
                                through tin medium of the "Home Notes," and lake great pleasure in the perusal of the
                                communications from the different Societies, we also want to remember the old adage
                                that, "short visits make Ion.'; friends," and not crowd those who aie more worthy. On
                                our National day, the Fourth, we enjoyed a season of social communion with our gospel
                                relation of the Society, who met in the Church grove and tasted of the good things in a
                                material sense that were pleasing to the palate, and with diversified forms of innocent
                                amusement, the hours passed pleasantly away until after the dinner hour, when the rain
                                compelled an adjournment to the North family, where the balance of the day was spent in
                                speaking pieces, reading, and in social intercourse. Such recreative seasons properly
                                conducted, are beneficial to tue <pb n="190" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> 190 THE MANIFESTO. partakers in
                                the cultivation of the social feelings. As it is in order to note the weather, we will
                                observe that July opened with a tropical climate. The thermometer registering at one
                                time, 102 degrees in the shade. At pi-esent writing, the 8th, it is like autumn; this
                                morning it stood at 55 degrees, quite cool for July. We are reaping the fruits of our
                                labors in vegetables from the garden. The farmers are busy securing the hay crop and in
                                plying the cultivators and hoes in the care of the farm. Hamilton DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Canaan, New York" TEIform="index"/>Canaan, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">July, 1894. It is truly said, "time waits for no man." It seems but a few weeks since
                                1894 was just dawning upon us, and now July, is reminding us that the harvest is near at
                                hand. On this stony hill-side with changeable climate, if one would gain an honest
                                livelihood he must be awake and alive to the pressing duties of each day. Our Brethren
                                have commenced haying, and this as every good farmer knows calls forth energy and
                                willingness on their part. Beloved Eldress Ellen from Harvard, formerly a resident of
                                this place, has lately spent a week with us, which was very enjoyable, and I trust she
                                returned home strengthened by the opportunity of social and spiritual interchange with
                                many of her gospel relation, as this tends to strengthen both soul and body. Dr. Dewey
                                from N. Y. has been spending a few days with us. His humanitarian labors will be better
                                appreciated, and more generally accepted as the great truths they involve become
                                demonstrated. He very kindly consented to give us several lectures, which were very
                                edifying. . His visit afforded us much pleasure. The meeting of the Floral circle
                                occurred on the fourth of July. It was adapted to the occasion. Several appropriate
                                articles containing excellent ideas, were read. The younger portion of the members
                                marched to spirited music each bearing a white flag to denote that they were followers
                                of the Prince of Peace. The room was brightened by nicely arranged bouquets, and the
                                evening was spent very pleasantly and profitably and afforded enjoyment to all the
                                family. Such simple social entertainments shared at home, serves to animate and cheer
                                every heart and thus truly give a zest to life. Angeline Brown.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>West Pittsfield.</head><p TEIform="p">July, 1894. The little band at Hancock send a kindly greeting to their good Editor, and
                                to the Brothers and Sisters in each Society. We hope there is no illness, and an
                                abundance of happiness in the several homes. What is more inspiriting than cheerfulness?
                                How much a bright "Good morning!" warms the heart of the recipient, and incites him to
                                make a happy response in like manner. The terrible "Western Railroad Strike" serves to
                                awaken gratitude for our quiet haven. The proprietors of Meat Markets in the adjacent
                                city of Pittsfield complain bitterly, but Br. Ira thinks we need not, as it has been the
                                means of effecting a very advantageous sale of his beeves. On the 30th ult. we received
                                a short, though pleasant call from Elder George Wilcox, and Eldress Sophia Copley, of
                                Shaker Station, Ct. We hope the old adage will prove true, "Short visits make long
                                friends." The hay harvest has been very good, thus far. It is thought that potatoes also
                                will yield fairly well. The usual lively occupants of the potato field were somewhat
                                late in taking possession, but have since made good all lost time. The pride of all is a
                                large and flourishing field of oats, which does indeed present a fine appearance. The
                                fence dividing the door-yard from the public road, looks much improved since being
                                freshly painted. Our school children are looking forward <pb n="191" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> Tl IE
                                MANIFES TO. 191 to the summer vacation, after the 13th. inst. On June 14th, our teacher
                                and the writer, visited (by invitation) one of the Pittsfield schools. It has an
                                attendance of one hundred and fifty pupils. In the afternoon they commemorated "Flag
                                Day" with appropriate exercises, which could hardly fail to fill the mind of "Young
                                America" with loyal and patriotic impulses. The burden of the remarks in our last Sunday
                                service "was the need of an awakening, and a baptism of fire that will search every
                                heart, and bind us in consecration to Zion's interest. Emoretta Belden.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station, Conn.</head><p TEIform="p">July, 1894. "Blessed are the meek." We are exhorted by precept and example, to have a
                                meek, submissive disposition, a resigned spirit. Meekness is one of the characteristics
                                of God's people. One of the fruits of the spirit is meekness, and we are encouraged to
                                walk in the heavenly pathway "with all lowliness and meekness" and to "put on mercy,
                                kindness, humbleness of mind, long-suffering" and to follow after righteousness,
                                godliness, faith, love and patience. We are told if these things abound in us, we shall
                                be dilligent, earnest workers in God's vineyard. There is no such thing as being too
                                humble and meek. Let us increase in every virtue that will fit us for that home where we
                                wish to go. "Say nothing that you would not like God to hear." "Do nothing that you
                                would not like God to see." "Write nothing that you would not like God to read." "Go to
                                no place where you would not like God to find you." "Never spend your time in such a
                                way, that you would not like God to say, 'What are you doing?' " There is but one
                                foundation for happiness, truth and purity. If the cross has been borne the crown will
                                be worn. "Time was, is past; thou canst not it recall. Time is, thou hast; employ the
                                portion small. Time future, is not, and may never be; Time present, is the only time for
                                thee." ******* "The processes which convert the heavy bar of pig iron into the finest
                                cambric needles, are too manifold to enumerate, though all are interesting, perhaps most
                                of all, the drilling of the eye. So delicate a task is this, that the skilled workman
                                can drill a hair and pierce it with its end. Auditorium building, Chicago, length 362
                                feet, width 187 feet, height twenty stories, or 266 feet. Cost of structure $3, 000
                                000." ****** * One of the greatest drawbacks to beginners in poultry growing, is to
                                attempt to keep one hundred hens in a house or lot none too large for fifty. Poultry
                                yards should be on sandy soil, if possible, in order to avoid mud on the ground, as roup
                                is liable to affect the flocks that are kept in wet locations. Barley should be fed
                                spairingly to laying hens, as its nature is too fattening. Daniel Orcutt. South. Family.
                                July, 1894. How delightful to gaze upon the beauties of nature at the present time, and
                                to listen to the music of the feathered songsters as they fill the air with peans of
                                delight. It does not fail to call forth inspirations of love to the Giver of all good
                                for the blessings that rest upon our lives. Whenever my heart receives such
                                ministrations, it uplifts, strengthens and brings a peaceful influence which elevates
                                the mind and I recognize that Power whose ways are wise; whose works are grand. As time
                                is swiftly passing I desire to become quickened and gain a new comprehension of life and
                                its duties. June was extremely dry and on the last day of the month a very hard shower
                                came which was much needed, but for the new and commodious facilities for watering the
                                    <pb n="192" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> 192 THE MANIFESTO. garden, tl;e effect of I lie drouth would
                                have been more conspicuous. The strawberries were much b( nefitted by it, and made good
                                returns with a bountiful supply of nice fruit. The peas also were made to yield a good
                                supply, by watering. All the early vegetables have come in their season, currants and
                                cherries quite plentiful. The corn, potatoes and tomatoes, are in good growing condition
                                but rather later for the drouth. Our haying has just commenced, so far the weather has
                                been propitious, so warm and dry. The prospect for apples is not favorable, although the
                                blossoms were extremely full and promising, but the fruit is falling off while very
                                small. Pears are looking finely. Thankfulness for the constant blessings enjoyed, should
                                fill our hearts, knowing a Father's love keeps watch, and rest content to know his way
                                is best. Maria Witharn.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Weather Record for June, 1894. Highest Temp, during the month, 87 Lowest " " " " 39 Mean
                                " " " " 06.1 Amount of rain in inches, 3.01 j\T. A. Briggs. July, 1894. On the morning
                                of the "Fourth," the quiet of our Village was unbroken, although the booming of cannon
                                in the distance could be distinctly heard. Later on, or at the school hour, agreeably to
                                the approval of our S. S. C, the timehonored Independence Day was observed by our
                                pupils, who treated their older friends to an appropriate entertainment of recitations,
                                dialogues and songs. The selections were well made and adapted to the youthful
                                understanding, as well as calculated to impress upon their minds, the importance of the
                                event which our nation commemorates. The school-room was decorated with flags
                                manufactured by the pupils, to represent the different nations, and also with original,
                                historic drawings on blackboards tt hand, prominent among which was the "Liberty Bel],"
                                while the star spangled banner, "Emblem of peace" floated gracefully over all. A
                                "picnic" in the grove followed the morning exercises, which was highly enjoyed by our
                                deserving little boys, as well as was the rural dinner by some of larger growth. The
                                "regulation'" shower which occurred at about 1 p. m. was not a novelty, and did not
                                dampen the children's ardor in the least, for to them it was a holiday full of pleasant
                                happenings. The silo, which was in process of construction at last writing, is
                                completed, apparently awaiting the growth of future ensilage. Our Brethren are now
                                actively engaged in the hay field, with but slight assistance from hired help. May God
                                bless every such worthy enterprise. The Sisters, meantime, are harvesting and canning
                                small fruits. Gooseberries and currants, especially, promise an abundant yield. Not less
                                than fifty bushels of the former are anticipated. Athletic goods and socks are net in
                                great demand at present. The wide-spread depression of business in our country, affects
                                our leading industries very seriously. Yet we have abundant evidence that "God helps
                                those who help themselves," and also, that if we are careful to "seek first the kingdom
                                of heaven and its righteousness" which we mean to do, all needful things will be added
                                thereunto. Let us covet the best of spiritual gifts, union, harmony, peace and purity,
                                for these will abide when earthly riches take to themselves wings. Elsie York.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">July, 1894. As our tribute for the coming Manifesto, we will give a brief account of what
                                we were privileged to witness, as a "Sunday School Offebing," on July 8th, designated as
                                "Children's Day." <pb n="193" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 193 In the eai-ly evening the
                                members of the Society gathered to our place of worship. Soon notes from an organ were
                                heard in the distance, as a signal for the school. Thirty-two in number entered the
                                room, dressed in white, marching and singing the piece, "Sheltered in the fold of
                                Christ, Blessed is thy portion." They formed ranks in front of the audience, giving at
                                the close of singing an appropriate Scripture response, with such an impressive opening
                                that we felt sure of a very profitable and enjoyable season. A dialogue having for its
                                theme "The Better Choice," was marked as giving practical lessons. The characters were
                                Life, Youth, Pleasure, Fame, and Religion. Life presented its many phases to youth,
                                while pleasure brought roses, fame a crown, and religion a cross of evergreen. The
                                points made by each character were so realistic, we all felt that we, too, could join in
                                the closing chorus: "Rejoice, rejoice, with heart and voice For thou hast made the
                                Better Choice." Another exercise, entitled The Tree of Spiritual Blessings was enjoyed
                                by all; a miniature evergreen bore cards upon its branches with names of the desired
                                gifts, so as each one expressed their grenttst need, whether it chanced to be Joy,
                                Longsuffering, Gentleness, Patience, or Purity, it was freely dispensed. It was
                                calculated to teach what every young Christian will do well to learn. Recitations by the
                                younger children were all nicely rendered and if a word of commendation has its proper
                                effect, t'.iey will strive still more to profit by their instructions, for they were
                                given by both beloved Elder Henry C. Blinn, and Eldress Eliza Stratton who graced the
                                occasion with their presence. Right here I will say that Sisters, Mary Ella Briggs and
                                Fannie Fallon, had the direct charge of these classes and proved themselves faithful and
                                efficient workers for the young of the flock. After singing a piece entitled "The Flower
                                Land" the service closed by the reciting of a prayer in unison. This will be a bright
                                spot on the memory of both actors and listeners and an incentive to every youthful mind,
                                to purer and nobler aims. Julia Russell. North. Family. July, 1804. The July Manifesto
                                with its radiant, illuminating light, citing thought to the goodness of the Infinite and
                                our work toward the finite, we regard of great worth. From any one of its testimonial
                                pages could be gathered substance enough tj flood society with lessons of holiness, if
                                we would only "take thought" about the wandering souls shunning the halo of moral
                                persuasion, mindful only of the glitter of personal pleasure and of accumulating private
                                property. True, "love is the power that must break every yoke" that retards moral
                                growth, that stimulates selfishness, preferring to sit in a chair of ease in the shade
                                of lukewarmness, than to labor in "the fields white with rije blossoms" that should be
                                garnered to add strength and goodness to our home. As the sun draws moisture to the
                                clouds and the clouds water the earth, so with us, love should be the power to cause us
                                not only to absorb the good about us, but prompt us to give generously of what we have
                                gained in the development of a Christ-like nobility. Our social visit with our
                                Gloucester, Me. kindred, Eldress Lizzie Noyes and Sister Sirena Douglass, was fruitful
                                of pleasantness, with the interchange of thought that cheers. "Giving hope to the
                                fainting, To the sorrowing joy." Preserving of early berries, with the general routine
                                of household work, engages the Sisters' time, while caring for farm duties, haying etc.,
                                occupies the Brethren. Thus the united help of all in things temporal, with as
                                concentrated a zeal in <pb n="194" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> 194 THE MANIFESTO. the moral welfare of
                                each other, become the strong arms of salvation that saves souls from the stream of
                                worldliness, whose polluting current seeks to draw the soul from the divine lovliness of
                                Christian service. George H. Baxter.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Union Village, Ohio" TEIform="index"/> Union Village, O.</head><p TEIform="p">July, 1894. Dear Elder Henry :This is a calm, clear, Saturday morning and the robins are
                                somewhat more sparing of their songs than earlier in the year. The cuckoo still gives
                                warning of rain occasionally. Grain harvest is over. That of herds grass and oats is now
                                in order. Our lawn is covered with red clover blooms and the music of the bumble-bees is
                                heard as they pursue their quiet labors among the flowers. I see I omitted in my July
                                article to state that the three young Brethren who came on bicycles to visit us in June,
                                came from White Water, a very pretty little Shaker Village thirty-two miles south and
                                west from Union Village. What a stupid oversight it was to leave this out! (We thought
                                just so and wondered. Ed.) I am persuaded that no person has ever left the shores of
                                time from Union Village, who has done more good and less harm, than our dear Sister,
                                Polly Hunt. She has been a member of our Society about ninety years, having been brought
                                here by her parents in 1805. For many long years she was our Deaconess and discharged
                                all her duties with perfect righteousness. She was particularly noted for seeking those
                                in trouble and sorrow and especially the young, and administering to their needs. We may
                                truly say, "The memory of such is like ointment and balm." When I think of these souls,
                                the inspired oracle of the ancient prophet comes to my mind. "Let me die the death of
                                the righteous and let my last end be like his." Num. xxiii, 10. At 12-20 m. Meeting is
                                over and was a pleasant season. Elder Napoleon, exhorted the young to honesty, courtesy
                                and purity. The singing was inspiring, and the consoling hymns were a sermon in
                                themselves. The Ministry journey to Pleasant Hill to-morrow, if the trains are not tied
                                up. It is an awful time at Cincinnati, Chicago and St. Louis What may be the outcome, no
                                human tongue can tell. We had, not quite a cyclone on June, 26, but it blew down many
                                trees and a large amount of fencing. I fear we are not the praying people we were once.
                                What wonderful things I have known to follow a general, united prayer of the Church. The
                                ridicule heaped upon devout and humble petitioners by a certain class of Infidels who
                                call it superstition is ten times more superstitious than the most credulous prayer that
                                can be uttered by the simple and sincere. It is just as natural for fruition to follow
                                prayer as for day to follow night. We try to live in union and Christian fellowship and
                                to live for others and not for self. Repairs of our barns at old South House completion
                                and pi'omise to itable improvement. are nearing make a credO. C. Hampton.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Chadwick, J. W." TEIform="persName"/>[From a Sermon of J. W. Chadwick.l</byline><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Well-kept heart" TEIform="index"/>THE WELL-KEPT HEART.</head><p TEIform="p">That is one of the dangers of our socialistic dreaming, often so far remote from any possible
                            improvement of society at the present time, that it disdains all individual effort to make
                            wrong things right. It is so much easier to write Utopian articles, or even to read them,
                            than it is, beginning just exactly where you are, to do something "to widen the skirts of
                            light," to make social sympathy a living power, though in the humblest way. Believe me,
                            there are men and women who write no utopian books or articles who are doing more for the
                            advancement of the good time coming than those who write the best of these, because in their
                            business, manufacturing or household care they are <pb n="195" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 195
                            maintaining a strictly honest, just and generous and human relation to those who are related
                            to them in the habitual order of their lives. The well-kept heartit is the heart that is kin
                            1, the heart that is pure, the heart tliat is courageous, the heart that is steadfast, firm,
                            immovable in its devotion to the good and true. How keep the heart in this desirable estate?
                            I do not know of any better way of doing it than that prescribed by the apostle, or whoever
                            wrote to the Philippians, "Finally, brethren, whatsoever things are true, whatsoever things
                            are honorable, whatsoever tilings are just, whatsoever things are pure, whatsoever things
                            are lovely, whatsoever things are of good report, it' there be any virtue and if there be
                            any pr use, think on these things.'1'' So far, so good; but what remains is better still,
                            "The good things which ye have learned and received and heard and seen, these things do."
                            Here is the whole counsel of wisdom relating to this matter. You know tho things that keep
                            the heart from weakness and from sin. You know the influences, the books, the men, that have
                            in them the power of blessing and of peace, and you know those as well that have in them the
                            power to smite and kill. With which will you ally yourselves? Will you submit yourselves to
                            those which you know, if you know anything, will aggravate your evil tendency, or to those
                            which will as certainly rally the good there is in you to struggle and to mastery? There are
                            influences, there are books, there are men and women, with which and whom we can not ally
                            ourselves without degeneration of those springs of action upon which the good of life
                            depends. Let us avoid them as we would that cavern's mouth which Dante saw with the
                            inscription, "All hope abandon, ye who enter here." There are influences, there are books,
                            there are men and women, to ally ourselves with which and whom can only make for
                            righteousness and peace and joy. Let us ally ourselves with these, and in no lukewarm
                            fashion. If they threaten to elude us, let us wrestle with them, like Jacob in the Hebrew
                            stv&gt;ry with the angel in the dark, until we have made their strength our own", until they
                            have given us their blessing. When I think of the good influences of which we might avail
                            ourselves, of the good men and women ready to give us of their love and strength, of the
                            good books, the poems, the essays, the histories, the biographies, that set forth the
                            fidelities and n-&gt;Lilities of t'ie human heart, it seems as if we were without excuse if our
                            hearts remain as an unweeded garden, where things rank and foul obstruct the growth of what
                            is fair and sweet. But to think on these things, however patiently and earnestly, is not
                            enough. The good things which you have received and learned and heard and seen, these things
                            do. There is no other way. All the delights of admiration will leave you sentimental, will
                            leave you hard and cold and ineffectual, if you do not address yourselves with steady
                            purpose and unconquerable will to reproduce in your own lives the fidelities and nobilities
                            to which you have been drawn in literature and in life.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>HEALTH.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bowers, Lucy S." TEIform="persName"/>By Lucy S. Bowers.</byline><p TEIform="p">A peakly brow that tells of holy thought; A ruiy cheek, and eye with sparkling light; Strong,
                            well knit nnns thitt love to do the right; A heart that times life's motion as it ought, And
                            crimson blood from healthful substance wrought. Free lungs that heave with pure air day anil
                            night, These make of mortal life a sweet delight. Health, priceless health, a boon from
                            heaven brought. In sacred writ, we learn that God made man In his unblemished image, strong
                            and whole But sin, usurping power, has marred the plan, Destroying many a beauty of tlifj
                            soul. But God has yet dominion, and we can Through righteousness, regain the perfect goal.
                            Mt. Lebanon., N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good deeds ring clear through the heaven like a bell" TEIform="index"/>
                            Good deeds ring clear through the heaven like a bell
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Good deeds ring clear through the heaven like a bell.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Richter" TEIform="persName"/>Richter.</byline></div2><pb n="196" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological Journal and Science of Health" TEIform="index"/>
                                The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Phrenological Journal and Science or Health for July, is especially attractive for
                                its numerous and varied character studies. Of these Gen. B. F. Tracy is the leading
                                subject. His portrait is the frontispiece, and the interesting phrenograph is by Prof.
                                Nelson Sizer from a personal examination. Dr. H. S. Drayton's outline of a manual for
                                moral education will greatly interest all ethical teachers. Mrs. Charlotte Fowler Wells
                                eloquently sketches a masterful defender of Phrenology, the Rev. John Peirpont. "The
                                Faculty of Language," part ii., is learnedly analyzed by Jno. W. Shull. Dr. Beal, the
                                editor, explains the art of 1 hrenographing photographs, and, as illustrations, gives
                                character sketches with fine portraits of three eminent politicians, Lieut.-Gov.
                                Sheehan, of New York; ex-Gov. J.C.Campbell, of Ohio, and the Hon. Wm. B. Allison, of
                                Iowa. Prof. Sizer's series, "How to Study Strangers," bristles with information about
                                people of prominence, such as Muncacisy, Elkens, Abbey, Thomas C. Platt, lngersoll, etc,
                                A dozen pages are devoted to Hygiene, Juvenile Training and editorial matter of value.
                                One dollar and a half per year. Fifteen cents a number. Address Fowler &amp; Wells
                                Co., 27 E. 21st St,N. Y.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Making a suburban home" TEIform="index"/>Making a Suburban Home
                            </head><p TEIform="p">FOOLING WITHOUT AN AECHITECT. The ideal suburbanite has no time
                                to fool with an architect; he supervises the construction of that house himself, writes
                                Robert J. Burdettein an exceedingly numerous article on "Making a Suburban Home" in the
                                July Ladies' Home Journal. A laudable and loving ambition, for is it not his home? The
                                workmen are pleased with this arrangement; it takes them about five minutes to ascertain
                                just how much less than nothing it is possible for a man to know about house building,
                                and yet be able to distinguish an augur hole from a mortise. When he speaks of "jice" as
                                "joists" they take his measure. And when he calls "studd'n" "scantling," he is up to his
                                knees in the consomme, and getting in deeper at every step. But blessed be the placid
                                bliss of perfect ignorance, he doesn't know it. He is serenely happy. He prowls about
                                that house getting into trouble at every turn. He falls through the first floor "jice"
                                and abrades his happy shins. He looks up to see what is the matter when the down-trodden
                                sons of toil on the second floor shout "Look out below !" and catches a hatchet-handle
                                in his eye. He walks under the scaffolding when the plasterers are at work, and gets
                                gouts of mortar on top of his new hat and down the back of his neckbut what of that? The
                                mocking laughter of the busy "mud-wasps" disturbs lim not; he joins in it, merriest of
                                them all. Is it not his own hat and his own neck? And oh, bliss of the blistered, is it
                                not his own mortar? </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Journal of Hygeio-Therapy" TEIform="index"/>The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy. Contents. July. Foundation
                                Principles; Diphtheria; Killed by Vaccine Lymph; The Outlook; The Pride of the Company,
                                etc. etc. Dr. T. V. Gifford &amp; Co. Kokomo, Ind.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cosmopolitan" TEIform="index"/>Cosmopolitan
                            </head><p TEIform="p">  WHAT IS BEAUTY! QUESTION OF A
                                BUND MAN!" Replied Aristotle. But Mrs. Sherwood says that it is "dynamite" in her
                                article which opens the interesting pages of the July Cosmopolitan. Beauty is always a
                                fascinating subject, and Mrs. Sherwfflod's discussion is an especially interesting one.
                                That the July Cosmopolitan is a midsummer number is shown in many directions. Three
                                short stories, including one of sport and adventure, two travel articles, and other
                                light matter, make up 128 pages of charming reading. The July Cosmopolitan marks the
                                close of the first year since the revolutionary announcement was made that the price of
                                that magazine, already low, had been cut to onehalf of three dollars a year. All sorts
                                of predictions have come to be unfulfilled during the yearit would be impossible to
                                maintain the ratethe quality would be loweredthe size would be decreased. But even
                                severe critics admit that with each succeeding number there has been a betterment in the
                                quality of articles and illustrations, and the size has remained unchanged, except the
                                always growing advertising pages. The magazine printed, for the six months embraced in
                                Volume xvi, one million four hundred and nineteen thousand copies, an entirely
                                unapproached record, and has doubled its already large plant of presses and binding
                                machinery. The walls of the magazine's new home are rapidly rising at
                                Irving-on-the-Hudson. Artistically designed by McKim. Mead &amp; White, the new
                                building, with its eight porticos, will be 279 feet long by 79 feet wide, and one of the
                                most perfectly lighted buildings in the world, having 160 large windows each nearly
                                double the size of the ordinary window opening.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Brainard, Jane S." TEIform="index"/>Jane S. Brainard
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Jane S. Brainard, at Mt. Lebanon,N. Y. May 13, 1894. Age 88 yrs. and 6 mo. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hunt, Polly" TEIform="index"/>Polly Hunt
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Polly Hunt, at
                                Union Village, O. June 26, 1894. Age 91 yrs. 9 mo. and 6 days. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Love, Susan" TEIform="index"/>Susan Love
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Susan Love, at Shakers,
                                N. Y. July 10, 1894. Age 80 yrs. She has resided in the Community for fifty years and
                                her life has been a life of usefulness. E. E. W.</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p26"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
CONTENTS.
History of South Union No. 10,
Beauty,            ....
Lett ii\F. W. tCvans,
"        Wm. Elam,
"        Stephen Ball,
E. E. X.
My Testimony,
Purity and Unity,
Music,Higher,
Notes About Home,
The Well-Kept Heart,      -      Health,.....
Deaths,.....
Books & Papers,
Page.
-    V.S
176
-    178
180
-    181
182
184
-    18(i
187
-    194
lflo
-. 196
E, C, MORRIS, SAFE CO,
Successors to E. C. Morris fe Co.
Capital, $250,000.
64 Sudbury St.,  Boston, Mass.
fire and Burglar-proof safes.
Bank Saies, Bank Vaults, Bank Vault
Doors, and Deposit Work of all kinds.
The Best Safe in the World. _ 160,000 in use.
Always preserve their contents.
150 sold in Lynn, Mass., since that great fire
where 50 of our safes were subject to intense
heat, preserving their contents.
Champion Record also in the Great Ghicupn Fire in 1871, in the Great Boston Fire in
1872, and in all the great fired since. Send
for c irculars.        Agents Wanted.
PLAIN TALKS
ON
Being    Candid   Ansivers   for Earnest
Inquirers.
By Geo. A. Lomas.
Price, 10 cts.
THE  ALTRUIST.
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is published by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all
their property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing
officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. 50 cents a year;
specimen copy free. Address A. Longley,
901 Olive St.,   St. Louis, Mo.
BRIEF EXPOSITION
OF  THE
Principles and Regulations
of the
SOCIETY   OF
Price, 10 cts.
WANTED. f*fc rn to
sell our choice and
hardy Nursery Stock, and Seed Potatoes, full and complete line.     Many varieties can  only be obtained through us.
Commission or salary paid weekly, and
promptly.    Exclusive and choice of territory given.     Don't delay,    write  at once
for terms.
ALLEN NURSERY CO.
Rochester, N. Y.
World's Parliament of Religions.
Dr. Barrow's Wonderful History of its proceedings at the World's Columbian Exposition. Published in two volumes on beautifully fine paper, and with large, clear, new type.
The work contains 230 illustrations executed
in the highest style of art. Each volume contains some 812 pages, and contains a full, authentic report of the most Notable Congress
of Modern Times.
Price per set of two volumes.
Cloth stamped in Gold      $5.00
Leather   "        "     "        $7.50
Full Morocco,                  $10.00
Arrangements have been made with the Bplievers at Mt. Lebanon to receive subscriptions for the above Book, and all orders can
be addressed either to Thankful H. Hale, 206
E. Capitol St., Washington, D. C, or to
Anna White,                                  
Mt. Lebanon, Col. Co.,.N_._Y,
BELIEVERS.
PRACTICAL RELIGION.
<pb n="" id="p27"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
Baking*
Powder
JIbsolaUly
Pure
A cream of. tartar baking powder.
Highest of all iu leavening strength.
Latest United States Government
Food Report.
Royal Baking Powder Co.,
106 Wall St., N. Y.
Much knowledge for a few pennies.
Sent Postage paid to any address in the
U. S. We have on hand a few copies of
"Rip Van Winkle and other Sketches."
240 pages, 4x6.                          10 cts.
"A treatise on The Horse," by Dr. B.
Kendall. 90 pages. 5x7j^. Profusely illustrated.                                  12 cts.
An old, brass eight day clock, in long
case, in excellent order.           $65.00
An eight day brass time piece made in
1810   by Dr.   Thomas Corbett.
Spelling Book by Abner Kneeland.    .25
Second vol. of Cassandra written originally in French by Sir, Charles Cotterell
Published 1725.                                  .25
Sacred Roll and Book written by Inspi
ration in 1843.    A wonderful Book.     2.00
Hamlet, Prince of Denmark.
From Shakespeare.
.10
Address  H. C. Blinn, E. Canterbury, N. H.
CAVbAI o, InMUt MARKS
COPYRIGHTS.
CAN I OBTAIN A PATENT? Fora
prompt answer and an honest opinion, write to
MUNN tfc CO., who have bad nearly fifty years'
experience in the patent business. Communicatlona strictly confidential. A Handbook of Information concerning Patents and bow to obtain them sent free. Also a catalogue of mechanical and scientific books sent iree.
Patents taken through Munn & Co. receive
special notice in the Scientific American, and
thus are brought widely before the public without cost to the inventor. This splendid paper,
issued weekly, elegantly illustrated, has by far the
largest circulation of any sciantiflc work in the
world.  S3 a year.   Sample copies sent free.
Building Edition, monthly, $2.50 a year. Single
copies, 25 cents. Every number contains beautiful plates, in colors, and photographs of new
houses, with plans, enabling builders to show the
latest designs and secure contracts.   Address
MUNN & CO., New YoiiK, 31 Bboadwat.
A   CONCISE   HISTOKY   OF   THE
SHAKERS.
Just published. The book is printed
with large type and on excellent paper.
It contains 130 pages and has illustkations of the Shakers and their
COMMUNAL HOMES.    .
The work gives  quite an extended account of the Several SOCIETIES, their
organization and general management.
Price  in cloth 75  cts;   in boards 50 cts.
Address.    H. C. Blinn,
East Canterbury, N. H.
(Established 1M31.)
IS Oldest, Largest. Bt\-t,
Cheapest and the Only
weekly Bf" -Paper in all
America.  32 pag-< s. $l.0Q
ix year.   Send for Free Sample,
$1.00 BEE-BOOK FREB
. W. YORK & CO., 199 Randolph St., Chicago, IU.
THE DIVINE AFFLATUS,
A
FORCE IN HISTORY.
Price, 10 cts.
American Bee Journal.
H
E
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>