<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2808" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">20</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">28</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">8</biblScope><date value="18980801" TEIform="date">August 1898</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">113-128</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="28" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="8" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
MANIFESTO
 1898.
A CONCISE HISTOEY OF THE
SHAKERS.
Just Published.     The book is printed
with large type and on excellent paper.
It contains 130 pages and has
ILLUSTRATIONS
of the Shakers and their
A SUMMARY VIEW
OF  THE
MILLENNIAL   CHURCH,
OB
"United   Society   of  Believers"
It treats of the Rise and Progress of the
Society, together with the general Principles of the Faith and Testimony.
Price, 50 cts.
The work gives quite an extended account of the Several SOCIETIES, their
organization and general management.
Price, 50 cts.
THE ALTRUIST.
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is publisht by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all their
property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. 50 cents a year;
specimen copy free. Address A. Longley, 1719 Franklin Ave, St. Louis, Mo.
BRIEF EXPOSITION
or tHE
Principles and Regulations
of tht
SOCIETY  OF  BELIEVERa
Pric; 10 c(.
AND
SHAKERISM.
A synopsis of Theology of the United   Society of  Believers  in   Christ's
Second Appearing.    Illustrated.
By Giles B. Avert.
Price, 15cts.
THE
AUGUST,
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
Inebriety, Its Source, Prevention and Cure,
by Chas. Follen Palmer, 12 mo. Cloth, Gilt Top.
Net, 50 cts.   This excellent little work comes
into our Library at the direction of Mrs. Palmer.   We heartily commend it as a treatise of
merit upon a world-wide evil.   Publisht by
Fleming H. Revell Co., 158 Fifth Ave., New
York.
Among the contributors to the July Magazine Number of The Outlook (which, by the
way, is a special Patriotic Number) are,
Colonel T. W. Higginson, who tells the story
of The First Black Regiment; Brigadier General F. D. Grant, whose subject is With Grant
at Vicksburg; Edward Everett Hale, who continues his delightful James Russell Lowell and
His Friends; and Lyman Abbot, who in this
and a preceding issue furnishes in full his recent address on The Supernatural, which has
aroused so much discussion; Christianity in
the Camps, is the title of an ai'ticle by Anna
N. Benjamin, written at Tampa, and illustrated with photographs by the author.   ($3 a
year.)   The Outlook Co., 287 Fourth Ave., N. Y.
The Journal of Hygeio-Thekapy is devoted to the principles of health in abroad sense.
Dr. Gifford presents in the June No. another
chapter on The Science of Life, and the usual
departments of Anti-Vaccination and Phrenology are well represented.   Dr. T. V. Gifford
& Co.. Kokomo, Ind.   Price 75 cents per
annum.
President McKinley is to be given the
unique distinction of having a number of a
woman's magazine named for him and prepared in his honor.   The July issue of The
Ladies' Home Journal is to be called "The President's Number."   It will show the President
on horseback on the cover, with the President's new "lighting flag" flying over him; a
new march by Victor Herbert is called "The
President's March;" the State Department
has allowed the magazine to make a direct
photograph of the original parchment of the
Declaration of Independence, while the President's own friends and intimates have combined to tell some twenty new and unpublished stories and anecdotes about him which
will show him in a manner not before done.
The cover will be printed in the National
colors.
A most valuable and interesting work,
neatly bound in two volumes, bearing the
title "The Black Monks of St. Benedict," has
just come to us from Longmans, Green & Co.,
of New York.   Historians, Protestant and
Catholic alike, have acknowledged the wonderful work done by the noble sons of St. Benedict in an age when the greater part of the
Old World was groping in the darkness of
Paganism.   The Benedictines evangalized
nation after nation.   The echoes of their
voices have awakened every shore.   Rev. E.
L. Taunton, the author of "The Black Monks
of St. Benedict" deals chiefly with the work
of the monks in England.   The great abbeys
still standing in various parts of England bear
eloquent testimony to the work of the monks.
Within these abbeys the arts and sciences
were taught and fostered, and much of the
classical writings which were the glory of
ancient Rome, were preserved.   Every chapter of the work is of especial interest.   The
one entitled "The Monk in the Monastery"
brings the reader into close touch with the
every-day life of the monks.   We can not say
too much in praise of the work.   No student
of ecclesiastical history can afford to pass it
over.   It is one of the works that is "born to
live."   The work will be no less interesting
and valuable to the members of religious
communities.   After the Savior and his apostles had disappeared from this earth, it was
the Benedictines who took up and continued
their life of communism, in fact, communism
reached its highest development among the
Benedictines.   It may oe of interest to note
here that these same monks founded as far
back as the fourth century have to-day a
flourishing college and monastery, in the
state of New Hampshire proudly situated on
one of its lovely hills, near the city of Manchester.   The building is a massive brick
structure, and a master-piece of architecture.
Within its walls the monks live the very same
life of religious communism which was lived
by their brethren centuries ago on the vineclad hills of Italy.
"THE LIGHT OF  THE WORLD
OR OUR SAVIOR IN ART"
Cost over $100,000 to publish. Contains nearly 200 full-page engravings of our Savior, by
the Great Mastei-s. It is not a life of Christ,
but an exhibit of all the great Masters' ideals
of the Christ. No other book like it ever published. Agents are taking from three to
twenty orders daily. The book is so beautiful that when people see it they want it. Published less than a year and already in its twenty-fifth edition, some editions consisting of
18,500 books. The presses are running day
and night to fill orders. (It has never been
sold in this territory.) A perusal of the pictures of this book is like taking a tour among
the great art galleries of Europe. The Hermitage, Prado, Uflizi, Pitti, Louvre, Vatican,
National of London, National of Berlin, Belvidere and other celebrated European art
galleries, have all placed their rarest and
greatest treasures at our disposal that they
might be reproduced for this superb work.
"FIRST GLANCE AT THE PICTURES
BROUGHT TEARS TO MY EYES," says one.
"Cleared $150 first week's work with the
book," says another. Many men and women
buying and paying for homes from their success with this great work. Also man or
woman, of good church standing, can secure
position of manager here to do office "work,
and corresponding with agents in this territory. Address for full particulars A. P. T?-.
Elder, Publisher, 189 Michigan Ave., Chicago,
111., First Floor.--><pb n="113" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our pilgrimage" TEIform="index"/>OUR PILGRIMAGE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>By Elder Henry C. Blinn.</byline><p TEIform="p">"Grain by giain the treasure is won, And step by step the race is run." THIS is so like our
                            pilgrimage through this life,so like the growth of the body and then so like the growth of
                            the soul. Altho there may be a religious revival and a sudden ascendency from wrong to
                            right, from low estates to a seeming exalted Christian character, yet the lesson that we are
                            constantly learning from nature's law, is that everything moves by the law of its being and
                            unfolds with unvarying precision. During the weary term of forty years, the children of
                            Israel were moving from the slavery of Egypt, over the mountains and through the wilderness
                            to enable them and their children to enter the land of Canaan as a free nation. They made a
                            bold attempt to free themselves from the land of servitude and so distanced their
                            task-masters that their exultant voices on the shores beyond the Red Sea, had already a
                            triumphant sound. Altho it was an assured victory, it was only the victory of one degree.
                            They had left the land of Egypt, but that was all. In their manners and customs, in all
                            their appetites and passions, and in their religious belief even to the worshiping of idols,
                            they were exactly as were the Egyptians from whom they had so recently parted. After their
                            exaltation with music and dancing they took up the line of march for that beautiful land of
                            Canaan, from which they had already reAUGUST, <pb n="114" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 114 THE MANIFESTO.
                            ceived some wonderful specimens of fruit, and which had been represented to them as "a good
                            land, a land of brooks of water, of fountains and depths that spring out of valleys and
                            hills; a land of wheat, and barley, and vines, and fig-trees, and pomegranates, a land of
                            oil-olive, and honey ; a land wherein thou shalt eat bread without scarceness, thou shalt
                            not lack anything in it." "A land that floweth with milk and honey." But so soon as this
                            nation of Hebrews and the heathen camp followers commenced their journey, the selfishness of
                            human nature began to assert itself, and this favored people, who had inspired teachers sent
                            of God, who had angels commissioned to watch over them, and who had the direct presence of
                            God as a special protection ; with all this care they had not manhood enough to deny
                            themselves of the idolatrous customs of the Egyptians or even to abstain from the food and
                            drink of those omnivorous eaters. They wanted the leeks and garlicks and cucumbers as were
                            provided by their task-masters. "Would to God we had died by the hand of the Lord in the
                            land of Egypt," said they, "when we sat by the flesh-pots, and when we did eat bread to the
                            full." But the journey to that land of promise, and the life they lived is a long story. The
                            trials and temptations, the struggles to keep in the right way and the enduring of
                            influences from in and out of the body demanded an obedience to the spirit of God, as the
                            only sure passport into the land of plenty. Habits and customs have a tenacity upon the mind
                            that it may take many years to overcome, even when it has been admitted that the habit was
                            wrong. A less sensitive mind may not only ignore a change, but may both by precept and
                            example, hold others from advancing. Jesus accepted this same thought when he spoke of the
                            Pharisees, and said, they would neither enter the kingdom of God themselves, nor suffer
                            those that are entering to go in. In all probability they concluded that the course they
                            pursued was as good as the more modern one, and as it proved agreeable to their idea of
                            right, possibly it was their best way, but it was not a way of personal Christian
                            discipline. It is generally conceded that what defiles one man, will defile all men if they
                            pursue the same course of life, and that which purifies one man will purify all men if they
                            walk in the light, and accept the cross of Christ. On this same line of thought are the
                            words of Mary Hayes Chynoweth; "There is something more than eating and drinking that a man
                            must overcome. Thinking and feeling wrong will produce poison in the blood and make people
                            believe there is no God. They will fret and get angry and find fault with circumstances."
                            "Keep your bodies clean to bear the messages of God. You can not do it by eating the things
                            that poison the blood and bring sickness and death. Think of this and see to it that nothing
                            foul or unclean shall be put into your <pb n="115" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 115 mouth, and
                            no thoughts that are unclean and immoral shall proceed from your brain." If the education of
                            children was continued along these lines of kindness, of honesty, of truthfulness and of
                            chastity, till the coming of more mature years, there would be a wonderful change for the
                            better, on the full development of the mind. ' It is the step by step. The gradual growth
                            from one degree of knowledge to another, and the maturing into that state where the
                            intelligent reason shall guide them into the best conditions that may be known. To those of
                            more mature mind it is the putting away of an education of unrighteousness in its every
                            phase and the accepting of an education in the fulness of righteousness, which is the
                            highest light that God has given to man. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="Section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To A. G. Hollister, Dear Friend in Christ..." TEIform="index"/>To A. G. Hollister, Dear Friend in Christ...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Japan, March 24, 1898" TEIform="index"/>Japan. March 24, 1898.</dateline><p TEIform="p">To A. G. Hollister, Dear Friend in Christ;Your very welcome message of Feb. 12, reacht me
                                a few days ago. It is so spiritual and broad in its declaration of truth, I have read it
                                over several times and have also read it to a few friends wTho were delighted to hear
                                it. It gives me great pleasure to become acquainted with a people who are evidently
                                striving after a life no less perfect than that which our dear Master and Way-shower
                                presented and taught us to follow. How evident it is that the mind of Christ is at work,
                                for individuals, tho having never met in person, are of one mind, seeing the same
                                spiritual mysteries by revelation from the Father. Thus we may know and understand each
                                other, tho oceans roll between. Our friendship, unlike that of the human mind, will
                                stand the test of time and eternity. Having risen above my fellow-beings here, I am no
                                longer as one of them, and naturally hunger for the communion of those who are spiritual
                                enough to see the same spiritual mysteries and understand me. You are one of such, and I
                                have a deep feeling of gratitude to have had the privilege of learning of the faith of
                                the body of people to which you belong. I can not understand how men professing to have
                                searched the teachings of the New Testament for centuries are blind to the truths which
                                are so plain to you and me and others. It can only be that they loved the way of the
                                flesh, and so could not develop spiritually. They were willing to give up a part, but
                                not "all." ' 'Except a man forsake all th&amp;t he hath, he can not be my disciple."
                                Blind preachers teaching a blind people, and "how great is that darkness!" I do not know
                                of any other body of people who strive to <pb n="116" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 116 THE MANIFE8 TO.
                                follow as closely after the teachings of Christ as the Shakers, and I am glad to learn
                                from one of your books the meaning of that name. At the time of my first distinct
                                revelation, I felt quite alonesince then others have written who understand at least in
                                part, and now I have the pleasure of knowing that you as a body of people have been
                                trying to practice this faith for many years. When I sent out my booklets, many wrote
                                condemning the work, others did not deny its truth, but said it would do harm instead of
                                good because it was premature. The thought came to me, Truth is always premature to
                                those who do not want it. When Christ came eighteen centuries ago, His teachings nailed
                                Him to the cross, but he was not premature. Truth can never be premature, for "He whose
                                right it is shall reign" and evil should never be. I am glad to learn what I have of
                                sister Ann Lee, and to know of her advanced spiritual life, and the example of her
                                practical life while here. But I do not understand why you call her Mother. Jesus said,
                                "Call no man father upon earth, for one is your Father which is in Heaven ;" is it not
                                as much principle to call no woman Mother? Since God is the Parent, both Father and
                                Mother, let us be called Brethren for we must become as little children or as virgins
                                who bear no parental title. Did sister Ann Lee work open miracles as did the early
                                followers of Christ? I read your letter to a Bible class of young men (Japanese) this
                                morning and again in the evening to a class of some eight or ten seamen. Our interests
                                are one in Christ, hence we need have no fear of each other. Purity of thought extends
                                the boundary of human friendships and seals them to all eternity. As the "bride" of
                                Christ, each must prepare his own "wedding garment," that when the Bridegroom comes to
                                claim his own, we may be found clothed in pure whitea character without spot or blemish.
                                Yours in that love which binds us together with bands not to be broken even by death,
                                which is to have no power over the righteous.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B.---, M." TEIform="persName"/>M. B.- - - - -</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Some kind friend has been sending us..." TEIform="index"/>Some kind friend has been sending us...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> SOME kind friend has been sending us The Manifesto in which I find many good things. The
                                current number is especially good, and its contents much in advance of the thought of
                                to-day, and expressing so much truth that will be recognized by all truth-searchers, in
                                which I am glad to enroll myself, tho marching under no especial banner, save the banner
                                of "Truth" Or "Good." There is a "Free Masonry" that is only felt and recognized by
                                those in the same ranks and it is the sesame that unlocks the treasures of the wealth
                                within and reveals it to the "whosoever will" may come. Here and there one and another,
                                are awaking to the fact that man has dominion over many things that have had dominion
                                over him^ Our blessed Master and Way-shower taught it and said, "These things can ye do
                                and <pb n="117" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 117 greater" and there is no other way to the
                                Father "but by me" or by my way "Follow me." It is not I, but the Father or Spirit "that
                                dwelleth in me, He doeth the works." That same spirit dwells in each and every one of us
                                and it is this that makes us great. I can but think that we have kept ourselves and our
                                brothers down, by only seeing the seeming evil and not looking deeper and thus
                                recognizing the divine and calling the latter into activity. How quickly a child
                                responds to the thought that it is good, or it is bad! Our best educators are
                                recognizing this, and are using the ideals and teaching that those ideals are in each
                                and can be brought into manifestation, that we do not pour knowledge in but we educe or
                                draw it out, and that we are all store-houses of inexhaustible knowledge, having God for
                                the source. When more recognize this, if it is a fact, we must make greater progress
                                Godward than we have done in the times past, when we have thought of ourselves as poor,
                                vile, weak worms of the dust, with no good in us. Emerson says, Lbelieve, "Evil is
                                unripe good," just as we might say of an unripe plum or peach on trying to eat it, "It
                                is not good," and one that had never seen the fruit in its ripe state or condition could
                                not be blamed for saying, I can see "no good in peaches and plumsbut one who knew the
                                deliciousness of those fruits when ripe, will wait with patience until that time comes.
                                So we only see the unripe conditions of humanity and judge accordingly; 'but God can see
                                the end from the beginning and knows that all is good. We have only the one ripened
                                specimen of our raceChrist, the Conqueror of death, hell and the gravebut this one is
                                sufficient to show us how glorious mankind is. I believe we are seeking the truth and we
                                can join in speeding the day when superstition and ignorance of every kind may be
                                "shaken" till the things that can not be shaken may take their place. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="T., S. F." TEIform="persName"/>S. F. T.</byline><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Washington, Tacoma" TEIform="index"/>Tacoma, Washington.</dateline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Evolution" TEIform="index"/>EVOLUTION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, Oliver C." TEIform="persName"/>By Oliver C. Hampton.</byline><p TEIform="p">' A ND the Spirit and the Bride say, Come." This voice of the Spirit _i_A_ and the Bride, is
                            that divine energy, which has been eternally urging the more and more perfect unfoldment of
                            all things, and which in our language goes under the name of Evolution. If we will listen
                            attentively we shall hear it in all the departments of Nature and Grace. It called Abraham
                            out of Chaldea ; it called David to the earthly throne of Israel and Jesus to the spiritual
                            throne of the Universe. 0 my soul, listen diligently to this sublime call, which has never
                            ceast to reverberate through all time and all eternity, and whose word is from everlasting
                            to everlasting, "come up higher." <pb n="118" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 118 THE MANIFESTO. The evolution of
                            man upon this earth, is an unspeakably sublime and wonderful phenomenon. There can be no
                            doubt but he was placed here under the circumstances we find him in, and the environment
                            which followed, for some good and glorious purpose, and altho he is not yet sufficiently
                            developt, to see and avoid the horrors of the mutual destruction of his fellow-man, and his
                            fellow-man of him, still he is rising to a higher altitude of spiritual light and
                            perfection, and ere many centuries, will rub off this barnacle of ancient barbarism. Atheism
                            and materialism are Likely to be utterly annihilated by mere science, leaving out the
                            sweeping, overwhelming evidences against it contained in spiritual inspiration and
                            intuition. For example, the materialist looks to the oft-quoted atom for a foundation
                            whereon to build his theory. If this fails him, what then? And now we hear it announced that
                            the atom is not what we call matter at all, but merely a vortex of energy. So then the
                            central plank of materialism falls away forever. But what if all visible phenomena can be
                            proven to be spiritual in nature? or at least had its origin as an effect, of Spirit as a
                            Cause ? And what is an effect but the end of a cause? So much the better, for now we have
                            only one long magnet to study into, and all the old impossible theories gotten up by the old
                            school of Theology, (as useful as it may have been in its day,) can now be dispenst with,
                            without the loss of any valuable material. The great law of Evolution relegates ignorance
                            and erroneous theories to the limbs of a silent and hopeless oblivion, and altho this is a
                            gradual process, it is none the less inevitable and inexorable. The process when brought ta
                            bear on man, is necessarily painful. How agreeable to the sensual man are the lower lusts
                            and excitements of the rudimental condition! But the edict of Divine Evolution is "Come up
                            higher" every time. Then comes the cross against lusts and affections, and in favor of
                            purity of life, love, wisdom, peace and glory. I am not the least surprised, that our holy
                            Savior exacted such extreme conditions of sacrifice of those who would follow him. After
                            every outward possession and animal pleasure, then "his own life also" must be given up.
                            Herewith, the very last cord of individual selfishness is snapt asunder. This consists in
                            surrendering himself entirely subservient to the will of the visible orderthe Institution
                            God has establisht for the evolution, protection, travail, and final salvation of man here
                            below. This was the plan of the Pentecostal Church and Jesus knew it would require just such
                            an institution, to set man on the highest round of evolution he could ever hope to reach.
                            The whole economy of the plan of-Jesus for the elevation of humanity to higher perfection,
                            peace and glory, hinges on this visible order and has its foundation (logically speaking) in
                            the great law Paul gave utterance to,"Without all contradiction, the less are blest of the
                            better."Heb. vii., 7. Did you ever notice what a beautiful and sublime reference the rapt
                            Proph- <pb n="119" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 119 et made to this Pentecostal arrangement of
                            the visible order? If you have not, I will quote it for your delectation. "And a man shall
                            be as an hidingplace from the wind, and a covert from the tempest; as rivers of water in a
                            dry place, as the shadow of a great rock in a weary land."Isaiah xxsii., 2. In this sublime
                            arrangement, salvation and peace are found; but none can know this only by trying it, and
                            none can try it faithfully and be disappoint ed. "The spirit and the bride say, Come." Union
                            Village, Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vision" TEIform="index"/>A VISION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>By Martha J. Anderson.</byline><p TEIform="p">In the seclusion of a lovely spot, Where bloomed the laurel and forget-me-not, Where the dark
                            cypressall in shadows plumed Waved in deep sadness o'er the earth entombed; I saw there,
                            carved in alabaster white A fountain, glistening in the morning light, Whose seeming spray
                            with silvery whiteness shone, Whose crystal basin was a gleaming zone, Encircled with a
                            wreath of ivy leaves, As perfect as the type of nature weaves, Design so delicate, so chaste
                            and fair, Wrought by the Sculptor's hand with skill and care ! I gazed upon that peerless
                            work of art, And pondered o'er its meaning in my heart. O living spring! upwelling pure and
                            free, True emblem of man's immortality, No death can dry the fountain of the soul; No change
                            can check the stream that on shall roll, No blight of time, or withering frost can sear, The
                            wreath that twines the soul's perpetual year. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Resurrected" TEIform="index"/>RESURRECTED.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo G." TEIform="persName"/>By Alonzo G. Hollister.</byline><p TEIform="p">Happy are those who truly keep The gospel in its purity; A bounteous harvest they will reap,
                            Their souls well satisfied will be: Who keep their understanding bright, Their mental
                            eye-sight strong and clear, Their spirits shall be clothed in white, With perfect love which
                            casts out fear. <pb n="120" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 120 THE MANIFESTO. TTTHAT can one desire beyond
                            perfect love ! Love is lifeperfect love V V is perfect life, and perfect joy of life, and is
                            attended with perfect conduct in all the relations of life. It obeys perfectly the law of
                            God, which is the law of life, and'has no other desire than to do the right in every time
                            and place. Consequently, it reaps a full blessing continually, and is clothed with the power
                            of the commandment which it obeys. Once I served God through fear. The Apostle says, "Work
                            out your salvation with fear and trembling." I had a fearful conflict in my youthful days
                            and early manhood, through the clash of opposite elements and influences drawing me away
                            from the truth and the cross of Christ. I feared I might miss the mark, and fail of
                            conquering the enemy of my soul,of all souls, and of all righteousness, fail of reaching the
                            goal of my aspiration. Fear hath torment; fear hath restraint, and restraint is torment to
                            the libertyloving. But perfect love casts out fear. I now serve God through love. The
                            contrary desires, the struggle and fear have vanishthave been outgrown, and I have risen to
                            a higher plane of thought and feeling,to a plane where life, much of the time, is ecstatic
                            joy. I had sometimes foretastes of this joy, earlier in life. But then, I had not been
                            sufficiently tried and primed, or purified to have it abiding. Perfect love casts out fear,
                            and the service of love, is free service, and no other service is free. I serve God now
                            through love and not through fear. And it is by obedience to the testimony of Mother Ann
                            Lee, that I am made able to do this,by bearing the cross of Christ against self-will and the
                            carnal life, till all is conquered by the cross. I give this testimony concerning the
                            results of my Christian experience to encourage the young. I saw but one way of happiness
                            for me. Either the angel which came down from above, and who with the aid of my teachers in
                            the gospel, taught me how to overcome the lower nature and compel it to serve, must be
                            obeyed, or the evil elements of this world, would drive out the angelmake it impossible foj
                            the love of God to dwell in my heart, and make it desolate of sympathy, and of all that
                            constitutes true freedom, or life, or enjoyment. There was no middle course for me. I did
                            not desire one for various reasons. One was,it could be only for a short space of time at
                            the longest. For what is man's life-time, or a hundred years, or even a thousand years
                            compared with Eternity? It is less than a needle's point to the whole round world. Another,
                            and the principal one was, it would only delay an issue which .must finally be met, before I
                            could be at peace, with all my debts cancelled. It would be a prolonging of the struggle,
                            and making it a tenfold greater torture, than if immediately taken up and carried to a
                            finish. Mother Ann said, Better ten souls be lost that never heard the gospel than one that
                            has,which signifies a ten fold greater loss to such, and Mother Ann had the gift of God to
                            know by what power she spoke. I wanted the best that was offered, and could not afford to
                            barter the riches of eternal life and <pb n="121" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 121 the glories
                            of heaven, for a brief season amid the shadows of time, or for pleasures that sting and
                            stain, and vanish like a morning cloud, or for any of the prizes which the world can bestow.
                            Never have I regretted my choice, nor the struggle it has cost to secure it. Their spirits
                            clothed in white, signifies purity, victory, gladness and rejoicing. White reflects the rays
                            of pure light, and the wearers have become transmitters of light. Is not this the true
                            resurrection, or rising from death to life? With those who follow in the steps of our divine
                            Teacher, this mortal is putting on immortality and this corruption is putting on
                            incorruption, so that when the garment of flesh falls off, because it has ceast to be of
                            further service, the creature is changed as it were in a moment, from its old and temporal,
                            to its new and eternal habitation. It is not the mortal and corruptible that is changed, but
                            the tenant, till then imprisoned therein. For flesh and blood can not inherit the kingdom of
                            God, neither doth corruption inherit incorruption. These are left to return to the elements
                            whence they were taken, while the freed spirit rises to life forevermore. Mt. Lebanon, N.
                        Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Trust" TEIform="index"/>TRUST.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stephens, Annie R." TEIform="persName"/>By Annie R. Stephens.</byline><p TEIform="p">It seems but yesterdaywhen winter's gloom Its somber robes of desolation spread, When
                            leafless trees swayed lonely bare and dead. And now, what glorious resurrection from the
                            tomb! The frozen bough is white and pink with bloom, The woodland violets faintest perfume
                            shed, O'er velvet slopes on cloth of gold we tread That sunlight weaves, dark places to
                            relume. And so we trust the hand that guides the year, Who, to the arid wastes new life can
                            bring; Serene we wait without a doubt or fear For Hope to bloom, for Joy to soar and sing ;
                            For out of life's dark reaches sad and drear, A touch divine shall bring immortal Spring.
                            Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Which is a part of the natural law..." TEIform="index"/>Which is a part of the natural law...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"Which is a part of the natural law, the ebb or the flow? Either, certainly. Likewise with
                            life's sufferings and life's joys.As you can not say the ebb is go-od, the flow is evil, so
                            you can not say of pain or joy (life's ebb and flow) this is good, that is evil. As long as
                            your spirit is not immutable, whether on the high-way strewn with palm leaves and joyful
                            cries of "Hosanna" around you, or on the road to the cross with the fiendish yell of
                            "Crucify him" piercing your ears, you have not yet entered the "holy of holies."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pick, Ernest" TEIform="persName"/>Ernest Pick.</byline></div2><pb n="122" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. AUGUST, 1898. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is publisht by the "United
                            Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued regularly by
                            the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the religious
                            views of the Okdek and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. Address all communications
                            to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. One copy one year, postage paid. .50 A
                            cross in the margin will show that your subscription has closed. Remittances for
                            subscription by Money Order should be on the Post Office at Concord, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">June. Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. Thermometer. Rain. 1897. 63.93 4 in. 1898. 68.33
                                5.625 " Highest Temp, during this mo. 90 above 0. Lowest " " " " 46 " " Number of rainy
                                days " " 10 " " clear " " " H " " cloudy " " " 9 July, 1898. Since 1898 was ushered in,
                                accepting the statement of Astronomers, we have taken a free journey on the earth's
                                stupendous railway, without having met with any accident by collision or otherwise,
                                195,392,000 miles, at the rate of 68,000 miles each day. The Lord's conveyance is far
                                safer than a Pullman sleeping car, and all without charge. We have ridden through six
                                signs of the zodiac, viz.; Aquarius, Pisces, Aries, Taurus, Gemini and Cancer, each
                                including 1800 geographical miles. Having gone so far safely, I shall patronize this
                                safe conveyance throughout the year. Having entered the constellation Leo, we find the
                                Lion's breath rather too hot for unalloyed comfort, but we will abide the heat. It is a
                                busy season of the year, and all hands are plying skill and strength in the line of
                                duty, in making needful repairs* cultivating crops, and gathering small fruits of which
                                we have a plenty for home comfort and some to sell. The wet weather has subsided since
                                July has taken the throne, yet Professor Hicks predicts electrical storms from the 4th
                                to the 15th inst. If the electric bolts strike terra firma, may they choose a place that
                                will do no harm. We have commenced haying in the fields of clover and if we are favored
                                with good weather we shall garner a supply of excellent hay. Potatoes are looking fine
                                and if they are not soakt to death by continuous wet weather, we shall have an ample
                                supply of this esculent vegetable. Crops generally are looking well, but it requires the
                                use of the cultivator and hoe, and also the particular use of the fingers to keep the
                                weeds subdued. The State Road on the mountain is having an additional section put in
                                traveling order. Hands are working the worst part of the road between Lebanon and
                                Pittsfield. New York State has made appropriations for improving the roads in this
                                state. Surveyors are selecting the best line through New Lebanon from the terminal point
                                of the state of Massachusetts. We opened Public Services to-day, July 3. A goodly number
                                of spectators attended and showed markt appreciation of the spirit of the gathering. The
                                speaking and singing were truly devotional, filling TERMS. <pb n="123" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                                MANIFESTO. 123 the entire service with heavenly, inspiring gifts. The health of the
                                family as a whole is excellent. There are none to my knowledge that are not able to take
                                daily rations, and to perform their daily share of manual labor. Thus in blessing we are
                                blest. Calvin G- lieed. North Family. July, 1898. Old Sol seems now in earnest to make
                                up for past delinquencies. Some of the crops may come forward, but peas are almost an
                                entire failure and other garden produce will be late and inferior. Cherries and currants
                                are abundant and are being daily sent to market. Our Sabbath services were opened to the
                                public the 3rd inst. Many better enjoy the seclusion of our home services, but we can
                                not look at it otherwise than selfish, to withhold from others a knowledge of that which
                                we so highly prize, and if we sow not how can we expect to reap? It is reported that
                                Columbia Hall at Lebanon Springs is to have many guests this season. Many letters are
                                still being received as the result of the article concerning our Society which appeared
                                in June number of "The Ladies' Home Journal." The greater number of these letters are
                                from those advanced in years or in unfortunate circumstances who think they would enjoy
                                a home among us, while others are from intelligent, high-minded people in whom a deep
                                interest has been awakened to visit and learn directly concerning the principles and
                                life practice of the people inhabiting "The Wonderful Little World." A few are from
                                those who seem to feel that a revelation has thus been given them of the means to attain
                                the life and the peace which the world can not give. May we have grace and wisdom to
                                impart to such the needed help. On the 21st. of June we received into our home for a
                                brief tarry our dear friends of long and loving acquaintance, Sisters, Hannah Wilson and
                                Eliza Brown from Enfield, Conn. Only those who have risen into the spiritual life
                                through sacrifice of the earthly, can know of the "richness and fullness of heavenly
                                love whose interchange makes such seasons of meeting a privilege and joy." We hope that
                                all of our friends who have seen the many gross misrepresentations concerning the action
                                taken by Alfred H. Love, President of the Universal Peace Union in his efforts for peace
                                between our country and Spain, will also read the facts of the case as stated by himself
                                in the June and July numbers of the "Peace-Maker" of which he is editor. His long years
                                of earnest and devoted labor in promoting the cause of peace entitles him to our fullest
                                sympathy and support. In behalf of the Brethren and Sisters of North family, Eldress
                                Anna White has written him a letter of appreciation and encouragement which can not fail
                                to be most welcome to one thus unjustly persecuted. Catherine Allen. South Family. July,
                                1898. June 10, we had the pleasure of meeting the Ministry from Maine. We deeply enjoyed
                                our visit with them; it was all too brief, but we shall long remember them and their
                                pleasant tarry. Tuesday afternoon of the 21st ult. we attended the funeral of Sister
                                Ximena Gates at Second family. As earth to earth was rendered the gates of heaven opened
                                and her soul entered, where the blind see, the lame walk, the deaf hear and the dumb
                                speak; where no darkness nor death can come, but all is life, light and liberty. On the
                                24th ult. we renewed our acquaintance with Sisters Hannah Wilson and Eliza Brown who
                                spent a portion of the day at our family. They were formerly of Canaan, now hail from
                                Enfield, Conn. Their tarry among us, like the visitation of ministering spirits will add
                                to the happy remembrance of the past. To all lovers of truth we call attention to the
                                article in the June number of the <pb n="124" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 124 THE MANIFESTO. "Ladies'
                                Home Journal" entitled "A Wonderful Little World of People" by Miss Madeline S. Bridges.
                                Slie has gathered many interesting facts during her recent visit at Mt. Lebanon and
                                knows whereof she speaks. The work is richly illustrated, containing photos of people
                                and places of our Ipeautiful hill-side home, arranged especially for the "Ladies' Home
                                Journal." Miss Bridges is an interesting writer and a friend of Sister Cecelia DeVere.
                                We hope our friends in the summer land of Florida, the land of orange blossoms and
                                crocodiles, will find much pleasure in their Southern venture, and continue raising cane
                                and all fruits of the sunny South. Kindest love and_ sympathy to our dear Editor. May
                                time and Providence restore him to health and activity again. Genevieve DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">July, 1898. During the month of June we were very pleasantly interrupted in our usual
                                vocations by a visit from our gospel friends from the state of Maine, Elder William
                                Dumont and Elder Henry Green. If friendship and the bond that holds us in spiritual
                                communion are strengthened by the application of the adage, "Short visits make long
                                friends," our alliance must be indissoluble. Yea we will "remember the Maine," but with
                                the spirit of peace that makes all those who love our blessed cause and are striving for
                                its prosperity one in spirit and purpose, instead of the revengeful interpretation which
                                at present is given to that saying. We also had a very pleasant visit from our Sisters
                                Emma Thayer and Celia Thorpe of West Pittsfield, Mass. We were glad to hear from them
                                that our good Brother Ira Lawson is imprpving in health. May the angel which cometh with
                                healing in his wings restore him to perfect health. As we write these Notes on this
                                pleasant Sabbath morning, July 3, our thoughts have been moving forward to the
                                contemplation of the probable results of tomorrow. How many realize the true import of
                                and the spirit that should prompt the celebration of our Independence? That it might be
                                a reality in our national life there were those who suffered and gave their lives for
                                their country, and the present generation if they are to hold as a sacred and
                                indissoluble inheritance what has been gained must be prepared to meet the living
                                questions of to-day with the same heroism and confidence in the ultimate triumph of the
                                truth that our forefathers had. Summer has put on her royal robes and the vegetation
                                that has been so backward is at present hurrying forward to complete the task assigned.
                                July 3, gives us the highest registration of the season to date, 98 degrees in the
                                shade. Hamilton DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>West Pittsfield, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">July, 1898. We come once more from the Berkshire Hills with a greeting of love for our
                                friends in other homes. We are enjoying the fulness of active, growing summer. It seems
                                to us that we can faintly hear the mysterious forces so busily at work, forming the
                                material for the growth of each tree and plant or flower. Every morning we realize the
                                progression constantly at work about us, and at evening can trace the result of sun or
                                shower by the growth toward maturity of fruit or grain. Potatoes promise an excellent
                                harvest, and the hay crop we think, will exceed that of last year in abundance. While
                                truly grateful for the many blessings which are ours and recognizing the benefit of so
                                peaceful a home, our hearts are filled/vvith sympathy for the brave ones, who beneath
                                the tropical suns of Cuba, are fighting so courageously for a poor and opprest people.
                                Never before in the history of any country has the spirit of unselfishness and courage
                                so actuated <pb n="125" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 125 the people, and while we desire
                                the advancement of peace, we pray for the coming of the day when man shall acknowledge
                                the universal brotherhood of man; when the cry of the slave and cruelty of the master
                                shall cease. There came to our family a few days since two Sisters from the
                                "Canaan-Enfield" family, Hannah Wilson and Eliza Brown. They are traveling toward the
                                west in life's journey and the radiance from a golden setting sun even now brightens
                                their faces, as they impart messages of courage and strength to those whom they meet.
                                They attended meeting with us benefiting all thereby. Sister Annie Case, of Watervliet,
                                also paid us a flying visit, but as the good things of life are best appreciated when
                                not too freely bestowed, we will look forward to a repetition ojf the hurried call.
                                Fidelia Estabrook.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">July, 1898. The firs|; f this month we had the honor of entertaining our friend,
                                Honorable E. H. Cheney, editor of "The Granite State Free Press," of Lebanon, N. H. and
                                ExConsul to Matanzas, Cuba. In the evening he gave us a very fine discourse, intersperst
                                with many of his experiences while stationed in that beautiful, war-blighted island. As
                                we think of the cruel power administered by the Spanish upon their subjects, can we do
                                otherwise than hope that the Cubans will soon realize their longdreamed-of state of
                                republicanism and personal freedom? Surely from out of the black war cloud now hovering
                                over Spain's colonial possessions and our own country, we can believe that there will
                                arise moral effects, enriching to each race, the consequence of a larger and better
                                light of civilization and righteousness prevailing. On the evening of July 4, we
                                gathered upon the lawn before our large Dwelling, which was well decorated with flags,
                                as were also the fruit trees about, and enjoyed an entertainment of music and
                                recitations, given by our little girls, after which, a collation of cake, ice-cream and
                                berries was indulged in. Thus closed the "glorious Fourth" of 1898, so eventful with
                                national rejoicing. July 5, we again welcome Elder Henry C. Blinn, who was prevented by
                                journeying "into the valley of the shadow" from making Jiis regular visits to our
                                Society, for a little while. We are also pleased to renew our relations with Elder
                                William Briggs, and greet him-as the associate in office with Elder Henry. Our first
                                service with them was fraught with gratitude for past blessings and petitions that added
                                strength and zeal may be had, enabling us to work as the heart of one. George II.
                                Baxter.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Narcoossee, Florida" TEIform="index"/> Narcoossee, Fla.</head><p TEIform="p">July, 1898. Our drought which has continued more or less for six months has finally given
                                way to the earnest feelings of the brainy toilers of the soil whose prayers and desires
                                have been from morning until night for a shower of rain. None came of much account until
                                June o, but within a short time we had two and one half inches, but far too late to save
                                the thousands of drooping crops except where there were facilities for irrigation. This
                                may look to some very discouraging, but not so to the Florida farmer whose pertinacity
                                of feeling to combat with such things is not checkt by defeat. As soon as the rain came
                                the ground was again ploughed, old stubble turned under and a new crop sown. Should we
                                take a consistent view of such conditions, it would soon show us the necessity of
                                something more to rely on for permanent crops than the elements. It is certain beyond a
                                doubt that farming can not be carried on successfully in Florida without some kind of
                                irrigation. The present season demonstrates this truth. Those who have irrigating plants
                                    <pb n="126" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 126 THE MANIFESTO. have in a measure saved their crops, while
                                those who have not were left to see their crops go down among the thousands who have
                                lost all. To those who are looking to Florida for a home I would say look well before
                                you take the step. The irregularity of the seasons has been the source of discouragement
                                to hundreds of honest people who have come] here under the recommendations of dishonest
                                speculators and put in their thousands to build up a comfortable home, and after years
                                of hard labor and toil were compelled to forsake their homes at half the cost and return
                                to their former homes. I would not say this has been the case with all but with a great
                                majority. In the advantages of the soil and climate of Florida it is only the equal of
                                the other states in proportion as one estimates the value of climate over soil, which is
                                to say that while the climate is just about as satisfactory as one would ask for; the
                                soil is not so in consideration of or relation to the world's present knowledge of
                                agriculture. There is some, a large amount in fact, of really good land in Florida, but
                                as a state its soil is poor, being sandy and non-productive. So in order to have a crop
                                the farmer must make his soil. That there will eventually be found something of value
                                that these lands are especially adapted to that will make them equal to other lands, is
                                the hope of many minds. But give me for farming the home of my childhood the hills and
                                valleys of old New England! Andrew Barrett.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="history" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Turnkey, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>THE TURNKEY No. 2</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/>By Elder H. C. Blinn.</byline><p TEIform="p">As the first human beings evidently cut down trees and then rolled the logs, we may possibly
                            touch the right point by going back to some of those first lumbermen. Jubal Cain according
                            to Biblical history, made organs and har^s, and was in all probability a wood-chopper and a
                            log-roller. These brothers, Jubal and Tubal, were skillful workmen and soon brought out a
                            nicely wrought Canthook. We may be assured that Jubal was pleased, even tho the Bible may be
                            silent on the point. The Canthook was a success in pulling logs out of a bad place, and it
                            was soon seen that a smaller instrument made after the same pattern, would be a nice thing
                            to pull an aching tooth from its socket. Assuming all of this to be correct, we have no
                            hesitancy in believing that Jubal Cain was the first dentist that ever used a Turnkey in the
                            extracting of teeth. Its form may have changed slightly since that early day, but not enough
                            to destroy its original design. Dr. Harris, who publisht his work on Dental Surgery in 1855,
                            would spoil this idea of giving the credit of invention of the key to Jubal Cain, as he
                            says:"For about fifty years the key of Garengeot was almost the only instrument used in the
                            extraction of teeth." But this does not say that Garengeot did not get his idea from some
                            one of an earlier date. One might easily so arrange his mind as to readily believe that the
                            very same person that invented the canthook also invented the Turnkey, as they are so much
                            alike; and if it could be proved that Jubal Cain owned a saw-mill, the whole matter would be
                            perfectly clear. Altho considerable ingenuity has been displayed in the manufacture of
                            dental forceps they were not made, as a general thing, with such nice adaptability till near
                            the beginning of the present century, and were not brought into general use till 1830. The
                            Turnkey was presented at first, on nearly every occasion, except in the extracting of teeth
                            for children, and for the upper and lower front teeth of adults. It was the custom of the
                            family physician to take with him a small box of dentist's tools, that he might be able to
                            extract a tooth if his services were demanded. As the Turnkey or Dentist's Key was made on
                            the same principle as the Canthook, when it was placed on a tooth, and the physician had
                            hold of the handle, <pb n="127" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 127 it was sure to bring the tooth
                            from its socket or break it off in the attempt. Should it so happen that the tooth broke and
                            the roots were left imbedded in the jaw, the key was laid aside and the forceps brought into
                            use, or possibly a hammer and chisel were used to separate the roots that they might be
                            drawn more readily. It was not a pleasant thing to fall into the hands of a heroic
                            physician, in those days, before any preparation of anaesthesia had been discovered. If the
                            forceps failed to extract the roots, other tools were used and they were lifted from their
                            socket, as the farmer lifts a bowlder from the ground. We might anticipate a patient who has
                            through a long day and a still longer night endured the severe pains of an aching tooth
                            welcoming almost anything that would promise to afford relief. A visit to the physician and
                            a brief story of aches and pains might possibly awaken his interest. Quite a lengthy and
                            wise examination must now be made in order to determine what should be done and to see what
                            tools would be necessary for the case. At this date but few persons owned a dentist's chair
                            and the common form not answering the purpose, the patient is ordered while standing to
                            designate the tooth that he wishes to have extracted. Yery few if any questions were askt by
                            the physician, why the tooth should be taken out, as it was enough to know that the patient
                            had askt to have it done. The dentist of to-day kindly proffers his advice, whether or not a
                            tooth should be extracted, and the patient is expected to be governed accordingly. But the
                            dentist with an office, and with an education that fitted him for this special branch of
                            surgery, had not come forward save in a few of the largest cities. In many places the
                            extracting of teeth was even trusted to men who gave evidence of a little mechanical genius,
                            and when it was not convenient to reach a physician, these self-appointed dentists performed
                            the operation. The forceps at this date were quite rude when compared with those now in use,
                            and as a general thing were only for the extraction of the front teeth. At a somewhat
                            earlier day, and especially in places a few miles distant from the city, it was not uncommon
                            for the shoemaker, or carpenter, or even the blacksmith to take upon himself the office of a
                            dentist and do some heroic work. Within the memory of the writer a ludicrous instance of
                            this kind occurred. It was a boy of some twelve years. An aching tooth had brought him to
                            the shop of the old shoemaker. A hurried examination was made and the boy was told to stand
                            near the bench of the cobbler. Taking the boy's head within the circle of one arm, the
                            lancing of the tooth was soon accomplisht. Under the most favorable circumstances a
                            shivering dread passes through the system so soon as a lance or a pair of forceps comes in
                            sight. In this case the forceps were a pair of shoemaker's pincers. They were large,
                            awkwardly made, and wholly unfit for any such purpose. So soon as the little fellow saw
                            those formidable things and learned that they were to be put into his mouth he began to cry
                            from mere dread. The shoemaker, however, retained his grip, but took time to deliver a
                            severe rebuke to his little patient, and then ordering him to stand still, was successful in
                            getting the great pincers into the boy's mouth, and attaching them to on# of the molar
                            teeth. Possibly it may hawe been the right one, but as none of \hem ached at this time, it
                            was difficult to determine. When everything was made right the would-be dentist attempted to
                            display his skill. So soon as he began to pull, the poor frightened boy gave a leap and the
                            pincers slipt from the tooth. The crying of the boy and the scolding of the shoemaker closed
                            the operation, and the little fellow was glad to escape any more torture. (To be
                        continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let the mud dry first" TEIform="index"/>"LET THE MUD DRY FIRST"</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Heke is a capital lesson that may well be imprest upon the memory of both young
                                    and old; Mr. Spurgeon in walking <pb n="128" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 128 THE MANIFESTO. a little
                                    way out of London to preach, chanced to get his pantaloons quite muddy. A good
                                    deacon met him at the door and desired to get a brush and take off some of the mud.
                                    'Oh no,' said Mr. Spurgeon, 'don't you see it is wet, and if you try to brash it
                                    now, you will rub the stain into the cloth? Let it dry, when it will come off easy
                                    enough and leave no mark.'' So, when men speak evil of us falselythrow mud at
                                    usdon't be in a hurry about brushing it off. Too great eagerness to rub it off, is
                                    apt to rub i$ in. Let it dry: by and by, if need be, a little effort will remove it.
                                    Don't foster scandal about yourself or others, or trouble in society, or in a
                                    church, by haste to do something. Let it alone; let it dry; it will be more easily
                                    eradicated than you think in the first heat of excitement. Time has a wonderful
                                    power in such matters. Very many things in this world will be easily got over by
                                    judiciously 'letting them dry.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Requiem from sister Ximena Gates" TEIform="index"/>A Requiem for Sister XIMENA GATES.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Shattuck, Alma J." TEIform="persName"/>By Alma J. Shattuck.</byline><p TEIform="p">Farewell, dear Sister, rest in peace, Thy journey here is run, And angels pure have welcomed
                            thee Tp thy eternal home. A faitMul servant thou hast been. Thy labors were well done, And
                            to the mansion thou hast made The angels bid thee come. No monument of honor, fame Will mark
                            thy absence here; Thy purity and sinless life Are virtues which appear. So patiently, our
                            Sister dear Hast waited for the call, That rest, at last, is sweet to thee Which comes to
                            one and all. We feel that joy and peace are thine: No earthly thing doth mar Thy spirit,
                            which has entered now Beyond the gates ajar. And when the summons from that land Shall come
                            to beckon me, Ah may I meet that happy band Which now doth welcome thee. I patiently will
                            watch and pray, Until the close of life Doth bring me nearer to that home Where ceases
                            worldly strife. Farewell, dear Sister, fare thee well Until we meet again, Thy spirit now
                            doth sing at last Sweet restis the refrain. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>OUR EXCHANGES.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Stories from nature" TEIform="index"/>Stories from Nature
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Stories from Nature. Devoted to the study of the Natural Sciences, and to the
                                dissemination of information regarding the wonders and beauties of nature. J. F. Alldis,
                                Editor, DeLand, Fla. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Progressive thought" TEIform="index"/>Progressive Thought
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Progressive Thought is publisht by the Progressive Thought Co. and
                                edited by E. Z. Ernst. It is an Official Organ of The Labor Exchange. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="American federationist" TEIform="index"/>American
                                Federationist
                            </head><p TEIform="p">American
                                Federationist is the Official Magazine of the American Federation of Labor. Edited by
                                Samuel Gompers. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Individual" TEIform="index"/>The Individual
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Individual is edited by Alex M. Darley and publisht in Pueblo,
                                Colorado.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gates, Ximena" TEIform="index"/>Ximena Gates
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Ximena Gates, at Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. June 20, 1898. Age 87 years 2 mo. and 28 days. Our
                                Sister has gone home to rest. Being resurrected in early life into the new and living
                                way, she will join living souls in the eternal spheres and rejoice in the home she has
                                built there by faithfulness and true consecration to gospel principles. J. E. S.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="McBride, James" TEIform="index"/>James
                                McBride
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> James
                                McBride, at Watervliet, Ohio. June 29, 1898. Age 71 years 8 mo. and 22 days. An honest
                                Believer for many years, our Brother has gone to reap the reward promist to the
                                faithful. J. O. T.</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p19"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
AGENTS!
This is  tlie   opportunity of your life.
Agents are making $50.00 to $150.00 a week.
Fitzhugli  Lee,  Maj. Gen. IT. S. V., and late
onsul General to Cuba, writes
A BOOK ON CUBA
SPANISH WAR.
V^e have on press for early issue, General
Lee's own story of Cuba and the Spanish War,
to be produced in a substantial book of over
500 pages, 7x9% inches in size and almost
ONE HUNDRED ILLUSTRATIONS.
This is the only authentic work published
on the one subject occupying the minds of the
entire civilized world.
OUTFITS READY.
Liberal commissions will be paid and credit
given.   Address for full paiticulars,
THE INTERNATIONAL SOCIETY,
91-93 FIFTH AVENUE, NEW YORK.
PUBLISHERS OP GENERAL LEE'S BOOK.
We have authorized distributors everywhere.
HUMAN NATURE
is an illustrated Monthly, now only 50 cts.
per    year,    devoted   to   PHKEN0L0GY.
PHYSIOGNOMY,  HEALTH,   MEDICAL
& SOCIAL EEF0EM.
Would you like a copy?
Send 5 cts. for Sample to Prof. Haddock,
Phrenologist, 1016 Market St.,
San Francisco, Cal.
WONDERFUL strange REVELAIffl,
SHAKER   THEOLOGY.
A Book of 320 pages.    It contains not
only the Shaker's Faith but explains
Scripture Metaphor.    By H. L. Eads.
Address H. C. Blistx, East Canterbury
N.  H.
DANIEL'S & STJOHN'S
PE.OPHEOIES.
48 page pamphlet.    Price 10 cts.
13 for $1.00.
Address,   H. B. Bear, Preston, Ohio.
WAITED
By Old Established
HouseHigh Grade
Man or Woman, of good Church standing
to act as Manager here and do office work
and correspondence at their home. Business already built up and established here.
Salary $900. Enclose self-addressed
stamped envelope for our terms to A. P.
T. Elder, General Manager, 189 Michigan
Avenue, Chicago, 111., First Floor.
AGENTS WANTED
in Every County to Supply
the Great Popular Demand for
AMERICA'S WAR FOR HUMANITY
Compiled and Written by
SENATOR   JOHN   J.
Of Kansas.
The most brilliantly written, most profusely and artistically illustrated, and
most intensely popular book on the subject of the war#with Spain.    Nearly
209 Superb Illustrations from Photographs
taken specially for this great work.
Agents are making 50 to $100 a week
selling it.    A veritable bonanza for live
canvassers.    Apply for description, terms
and territory at once to
N. D.Thompson Publishing Co.
ST. LOUIS, MO.,or NEW YORK CITY
AND   TH3
INGALLS
<pb n="" id="p20"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
Royal makes the food pure,
wholesome and delicious.
60  YEARS'
EXPERIENCE
Trade Marks
Designs
Copyrights Ac.
Anyone sending a sketch and description may
quickly ascertain our opinion free whether an
invention is probably patentable. Communications strictly confidential. Handbook on Patents
sent free. Oldest agency for securing patents.
Patents taken through Munn & Co. receive
tpecUti notice, without charge, in the
Scientific American.
A handsomely illustrated weekly. Largest circulation of any scientific journal. Terms, $3 a
year; four months, |t Sold by all newsdealers.
MUNN 4Co.361Bfoad^' New York
Branch Office. 625 F St., Washington, D. C.
HOW TO MAKE MONEY!
If you are out of employment and want
a position paying you from $50 to $100
monthly clear above expenses by working
regularly, or, if you want to increase your
present income from $200 to $500 yearly,
by working at odd times write the GLOBE
CO. 723 Chestnut St. Phila., Pa. stating
age, whether married or single, last or
present employment, and you can learn
how to make more money easier and
faster than you ever made before in your
life.
AUTHORISED   RULES
OF
THE   SHAKER   COMMUNITY,
The religious basis of the Oeder must
be a foundation resting on the principle of
righteousness, which principle is God.
This should rule the life of the individual for tfcte protection of his own soul, for
the peace of the family and as an evidence
of his upright standing before the world.
Price, 10 cte.
SHAKER HAMAMELIS
(WITCHHAZEL,)
.A. remedy for Cuts, Burns, Scalds,
Headache, Sore Throat and all
cases of external inflammation
Taken internally for Bowel
Complaint, B!eeding of the
Lungs or Bowels, and for
all aches and pains.
For use externally, bathe the parts and
lay on a cloth wet with the Extract,   Internally, take one half teaspoonful three
times a day.   Use hot or cold.
Ask your druggist for it or send your
order to Abthuk Bbuck.
East Canterbury, N. H.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure
ROYAL BAKING POWDER CO., NEW YORK.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>