<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2810" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">20</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">28</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">10</biblScope><date value="18981001" TEIform="date">October 1898</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">145-160</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="28" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="10" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
THE
MANIFESTO
 1898.
A CONCISE HISTORY OF THE
SHAKERS.
Just Published.     The book is printed
with large type and on excellent paper.
It contains 130 pages and has
ILLUSTRATIONS
of the Shakers and their
A SUMMARY VIEW
OF THE
MILLENNIAL,   CHURCH,
OR
"United   Society   of Believers"
It treats of the Rise and Progress of the
Society, together with the general Principles of the Faith and Testimony.
Price, 50 cts.
The work gives quite an extended account of the Several SOCIETIES, their
organization and general management.
Price, 50 cts.
THE ALTRUIST.
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is publisht by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all their
property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. 50 cents a year;
specimen copy free. Address A. Longley, 1719 Franklin Ave, St. Louis, Mo.
BRIEF EXPOSITION
or tee
Principles and Regulations
of the
SOCIETY   OF   BELIEVERS
Price, 10 cts.
AND
SUAKERISM.
A synopsis of Theology of the United   Society of   Believers  in   Christ's
Second Appearing.    Illustrated.
By Giles B. Avery.
Price, 15cts.
OCTOBER,
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
The Outlook continues to give its readers
a week-to-week history of the events of the
war.   In addition to the valuable letters of
Mr. George Kennan, which will still continue,
altho for the moment interrupted by an attack
of fever which compelled Mr. Kennan to return to this country from Cuba, The Outlook
has printed many extracts from private letters about the war, is publishing from time to
time extracts from A Trooper's Diary; (being
the diary of a young Ainherst student who is
now in Manila,) and, of course, gives in ad
dition a connected history of events as they
occur.   The September Magazine .Number
contains an illustrated article on Santiago.
After the Surrender; by Anna N. Benjamin,
an installment of A Trooper's Diary; an account of The Fight of the Rough Riders; as
told by a private in one of the treops, an editorial examination of Secretary Alger's Defense; and in other ways shows an active interest in the events preceding the declaration of peace.   ($3 a year.   The Outlook Co..
287 Fourth Avenue, N. Y.)
The widow of Richard Wagner some time
ago authorized her husband's life long friend,
Houston Stewart Chamberlain, to write, with
her assistance, two articles on The Personal
Side of Richard Wagner.   Mr. Chamberlain
undertook the work, and The Ladies' Home
Journal secured the material.   The articles
are singularly valuable in that they give a
complete picture of the man in his home and
daily life, and contain much new matter,
while many of the illustrations and portraits
have never been printed.   There will be two
articles, His Personal Side; and How He
Wrote His Operas; and the first one will appear in the October number of the magazine.
Who Made the New Testament?   By H. L.
Hastings.   It would, indeed, interest a large
number of persons to know for a certainty,
just who made the New Testament.   To set
the mind at rest, the author has endeavored
to answer this question, and to answer it
clearly and correctly.   A careful perusal of
the little book will no doubt shed much light
upon the subject, and the interested reader
will be amply compensated.   Send five cents
to No. 47 Cornhiil, Boston, and obtain a copy.
The hpoidsome external appearance of
Fkank Leslie's Popular Monthly for September is borne out by an exceptionally attractive table of contents.   The leading article, A Warship's Battery; by Henry Harrison
Lewis, tells how the great guns are placed
and workt, and is illustrated with some
splendid pictures of our victorious ships in
action at Manila and Santiago.   The famoua
Johnson Island Conspiracy; an episode of the
Civil War, recalled by the recent death of
Leonard B. Johnson, of Sandusky, Ohio, is interestingly recounted by Frederic Boyd Stevenson.   Another article of historical as well
as picturesque value is John P. Ritter's Story
of Wyoming the Beautiful.   The artistic rambles in Holland, of Bisbing, the celebrated
American cattle painter, are chronicled, with
some original sketches by his friend J. M. Erwin.   Canoe Cruising; by Commodore F. R.
Wood, is f ullof pleasant summer suggestions.
Katharine Tynan contributes some charming
notes upon The Irish People at Home; accompanying half a dozen characteristic pictures by Helmick.   The tenth and final paper
of the Religious Denominations series is The
Roman Catholics; by the Rev. A. P. Doyle.
The two serials, Marie Tremaine; and An
American Princess; are continued.   The complete short tales in this month's Frank Leslie's Popular Monthly include; Merely a
Passing Passion; Maude Conway's Brother;
Which Won Cuba? by Genevieve L. Brown,
and As a Last Resort; by J. Frederick Thorne.
A notable poem is Mr. H. N. Dodge's Spirit of
Freedom; illustrated by Frank Adams.   The
Soldier's Tent; by Carmen Sylva, the gifted
Queen of Roumania, will rank as one of the
most beautiful war lyrics of modern times.
A Visit to the
of EAST CANTERBURY,   N. H.
LLOYD II. CHANDLER.il. S. H
Liber-ally   Illustrated   with   half   tone
pictures of peiisosts and places.
The Village of EAST CANTERBURY
is situated in one of the loveliest spots of
NEW Hampshire, and is high enough to
overlook the surrounding country.
Price,  15 cts.
Address   H. C. Blinn,
East Canterbury, N. H.
Sketches of Shakers and Shakerism. A synopsis of the United Society of Believers in Christ's Second
Appearing. Illustrated. By Giles
B. Avery.    Price 15 cts.--><pb n="145" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ascending life" TEIform="index"/>ASCENDING LIFE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>By Martha J. Anderson,</byline><p TEIform="p">The fine and subtile laws of alchemy A secret power of transmutation hold, Touch with
                            refining sensibility, And bring to light each hidden grain of gold. Thus, from earth's basis
                            to ethereal spheres In pure atomic substance wisely planned, More sublimated each degree
                            appears That forms successive kingdoms, high and grand. Life's occult forces work with magic
                            skill To build anew, till earth and heaven blend, Eternal laws of progress to fulfill In
                            chain of being that shall never end. Mark the material forms that round us rise! They reach
                            their zenith, yield to blight and death, But spirit hath a growth that never dies. 'Tis life
                            of all that lives, and ceaseless breath. 'Tis spiritual force that guides the suns And
                            worlds that fill immensity of space, <pb n="146" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 146 THE MANIFESTO. Electric fluid
                            through each atom runs That evolution gives a form and place. Mancrowning point of the
                            created whole The impress of his Maker's image wears; This microcosmbody, spirit, soul,
                            Resemblance to creation fully bears. Each special phase of being here combined, The soul and
                            sentiment of every thing Is germinal within the immortal mind That yet shall blossom in
                            eternal spring. My wisdom placed within this rudimental sphere To give his noble powers
                            unfoldment free, His childhood state brings teachers, year by year, Who spreads for him the
                            chart of destiny; He reads and thinks, he learns and understands, Aspires still further with
                            a yearning hope, And lo! his God-like soul expands, And ever fruitful fields before him ope.
                            'Tis life progressive, ever on and on, A glorious resurrection day by day ; 'Tis step by
                            step, and starry summits won, That mark our ever upward, onward way. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes from our diary" TEIform="index"/>NOTES FROM OUR DIARY.</head><p TEIform="p">We left home on Monday Aug. 1st and only reacht the City of Concord, a distance of twelve
                            miles. Elder Wm. W. Briggs was one of the company so far as this place. Aug 2. Left Concord
                            at 10-15 a. in. for Boston. Several hours were occupied in canceling some obligations that
                            demanded attention. While walking along the street, the voice of singing was heard and a
                            little boy proffered this information "It is only two or three doors ahead of you, mister."
                            "What is it that's only two doors ahead?" "They are having a meeting, sir. It is right up
                            these stairs." Thanking the little man, we ascended the stairs and soon found that we were
                            among Salvationists. They were having a private meeting, and we soon learned that not many
                            strangers would be admitted as the Captain came and fastened the door, so that others could
                            not enter,but did not ask us to retire. We enjoyed the singing and speaking, and at the
                            close of the service converst very pleasantly with the Captain, who extended an invitation
                            for us to come again. Aug. 3. Took the cars at 8-30 a. m. at the Boston &amp; Albany
                            Station for Pittsfield, Mass., the ticket costing $3.60. On reaching Pittsfield at 1-15 p.
                            m. we found Brother Ira Lawson, with a carriage waiting to convey us to the Village, some
                            three <pb n="147" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 147 miles distant. A kind welcome greeted us on
                            arrival at the Trustees' Office and we soon found ourselves in Hancock among the best of
                            friends. In the p. m. two enquirers called, one being a young minister and the other a
                            physician. We are happy in the anticipation that they went from the Village, wiser and
                            better for the interview An enjoyable, social chat with Elder Louis Basting made a pleasant
                            close for the evening. Aug. 4. Took a stroll over the new, State road which has been built
                            through this Village and is being continued to the top of the mountain, on the road to the
                            Village of Mt. Lebanon. At most the grade is only about five feet in one hundred. If the New
                            York commissioners decide to build a new road on the west side of the mountain it will be of
                            immense value to the traveling public. Another enquirer called at the Office. He assured us
                            that the Lord sent him, altho we soon learned that he had a debt of $500.00. Persons should
                            cancel their debts before they attempt to enter a religious community. Aug. 5. The Iron Ore
                            Company that least a section of land belonging to the Community has suspended work. The
                            machinery has been sold and the buildings are being moved away. Two little girls came out
                            from the City of Pittsfield, yesterday, on their wheels, to visit the Shakers. They were the
                            daughters of wealthy citizens. A heavy thunder-storm past over the Village and they feared
                            to return. A message was sent to their parents, that the Shaker Sisters would care for them
                            until morning. Having an excellent water privilege in this place, we find a motor in the
                            dairy and a Davis churn. The milk is set in pans. Wood working machinery may be found in
                            another building and ample reservoirs supply water for this, and other places. The best of
                            drinking water comes from springs found on the mountain. Brother Ira, the Trustee of this
                            Society, has within a few years made important additions to the Trustees' Office, which is
                            now a beautiful building and has been furnisht with all the modern conveniences. In the
                            Office room are two sets of fans, revolving very rapidly, being propelled by a small water
                            motor. Aug. 6. The Society in this place has three families. The Church, Second and East.
                            The Mayor of the City of Pittsfield and the City engineer called at the Office. We had an
                            introduction and enjoyed a very pleasant and social conversation. The Mayor told of the
                            reception that was given to the 1st N. H. Regiment of Volunteers when they past through the
                            City. Col. Rolfe had retired for the night, but the Mayor had him get out of bed and witness
                            the demonstration made in honor of the soldiers. We made a short visit to the Second family
                            and had a very pleasant interview with Eldress Sophia Helfrich and the other members of the
                            family. In the p. m. accepted a ride with Brother Ira. He drove to the reservoir or lake in
                            the town of Richmond. This water is held for the Grist Mill and other mills, and covers
                            several hundred acres. From this place he drove over some very interesting roads till we
                            reacht the Village of Richmond, some five miles south of the Shaker Village. In this poor
                            little town, one mile of State road has been built and the people anticipate the building of
                            another mile. I hardly think we shall be able to find a road, a mile long, in N. H. that
                            will compare favorably with these roads in Mass. After reaching home we estimated our trip
                            to have been some fifteen miles or more. Sunday, Aug. 7. We had breakfast at 7 o'clock.
                            Elder Louis'called at the Office and extended an invitation for us to attend the morning
                            Service which commenced at 10 o'clock. Members from the several families attended. Elder
                            Louis made a few remarks at the opening of the Service. He then announced and read <pb n="148" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 148 THE MANIFESTO. the hymn. An organ accompaniment rendered valuable
                            service to the voices, and! the whole was very pleasant to the mind. The Service continued
                            about an hour,, and the time was well rilled with singing and speaking. In the p. m. several
                            of the Brethren and Sisters from the Society of Mt. Lebanon, called at the Office. The
                            interview was very pleasant, and the invitation to visit their home very much appreciated.
                            Aug. 8. We accepted the invitation to take a ride with Brother Ira to the City of
                            Pittsfield. We rode many miles around the country before we reacht the City, and entered
                            fully into the enchantment of the scenery of western Mass, where the mountains and valleys
                            and lakes remind us so forcibly of those in ISTew Hampshire. We called at the Berkshire
                            Atheneum which has a Public Library and a large collection of works of Art. It has also
                            several cases of geological specimens and a great variety of curiosities. On our return we
                            met Elder Joseph Holden who had just arrived from Watervliet. At 5 o'clock p. m. Mr. Robert
                            Brannen and lady, of Denver, Col., called. They had driven from Troy to see their Shaker
                            friends. Mr. Brannen is a wealthy banker in the City of Denver. His visit to the Community
                            was a very pleasant surprise. The cutting and drying of sweet corn is one of the industries
                            of this place, and they have the best of facilities for expediting the business. The
                            Circular barn is a, novelty, but, no doubt, it has many advantages which could not be
                            obtained by building in any other form. The cows are all stalled with their heads toward the
                            center. In the upper loft the teams drive in at one door with their loads of hayr and after
                            unloading can drive around on the inside of the barn and pass out at the same door that they
                            entered. The Family Dwelling is a large, commodious brick building. Liberal mindsplanned it,
                            and also arranged it for the convenience of the Community. Additional improvements have been
                            made within a few years and it now stands among the modern dwellings. The underpinning
                            stone, the door-steps and fence posts are mostly of marble found in this section of the
                            country, while the stone walks are generally of coarse limestone. A fine specimen of Granite
                            would be hard to find. Some beds of gravel are occasionally found, and this has been used
                            largely on the State Eoad. On our return from a morning walk, we past on to the Laundry and
                            received a kind invitation to enter. We found several Sisters and two or three little girls
                            busily engaged in washing the clothes. Two of the Sisters gave us special attention and
                            conducted us through the several departments. The boiling, rinsing and other holders a-re
                            supplied with hot water from a large boiler. The washing is still performed by hand, but an
                            excellent wringer reduces much of the hard work. The floor of the laundry is laid with
                            marble slabs, which at first might seem objectionable on account of coldness to the feet. It
                            was thought, however, to be preferable to wood. The room for ironing adjoins that of the
                            wash-room, and has an arch and a stove well arranged for the heating of the flat-irons. The
                            Sisters accompanied us to the Corn-drying establishment which will soon be in operation. Not
                            less than four corn-cutting machines will be used to keep the four kilns well supplied with
                            corn for drying. Aug. 10. We walkt to the Cemetery which is but a few rods distant from the
                            Office. The stones are of marble and contain the full name, with the age and date of death.
                            The place presents a very neat and orderly appearance. We found within the enclosure the
                            resting place of Anna Berdick, who was appointed to the Order of Ministry in Canterbury and
                            Enfield, Feb. 15, 1792. She returned to Hancock, in 1793. <pb n="149" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. 149 Brother Ira invited Elder Joseph and the writer to accompany him to Lenox. A
                            covered carriage offered sure protection against the threatening rain. Lenox is twelve miles
                            distant, and is largely built up by the wealthy residents of New York. We drove through the
                            Village and then directly home, reaching the Trustees' Office at 12 m. The rain had been a
                            little disturbing, but not enough to deprive us of the pleasure of sight seeing. Limestone
                            seems to be the predominant rock, and it is of beautifully variegated colors. When we reacht
                            Lenox we saw the homes of wealth. Thousands and thousands of dollars have their
                            representation in the beautiful residences, and in many places even the barns are as richly
                            furnisht as the family dwelling. Tens of thousands of flowers are to be seen in the
                            beautifully cultivated gardens and lawns. As God made the flowers they are all "very good"
                            and worthy to be admired in all their beauty. Our return trip was over the Berkshire Hills
                            where Brother Ira says the health air may be found. If going up and up and up would help us
                            to find health, then certainly it must have been found. All in all it was a delightful ride,
                            as the whole journey presented some of the most beautiful scenery. Aug. 11. At 1 o'clock we
                            took a ride with Brother Ira to the top of the mountain over the new road. On our return we
                            entered one of the fields, and were shown a section of land where a company of Indians lived
                            when the Shakers settled in this place. We were shown the.old foundation, where the house of
                            Nathan Goodrich formerly stood, in which Mother Ann and the Elders held religious Services.
                            It was in this place that Mother Ann said to the mob that came to the house,"Draw Tjack, or
                            I will smite the horse and his rider." The horses immediately ran to the road, some ten rods
                            distant, and the riders had no power to govern them. We made a visit to the East family and
                            had a very pleasant interview with Eldress Catherine Pepper and others. They have a small
                            store in the Office where they exhibit some fancy articles for sale, Sunday, Aug. 14. The
                            day was spent as noted at an earlier date. At 6 p. m. we attended a religious gathering at
                            the Family Dwelling. A company of young Sisters, with the little girls were present. A
                            director or superintendent was chosen from among the company present, and the exercises
                            moved along quite pleasantly. Bible reading, singing, and the reading of original or
                            selected articles occupied the time. This can not otherwise than be a profitable,
                            educational school. Aug. 15. We again walked to the Station and found the Railroad Officials
                            very gentlemanly and affable. By the road side we stopt to examine a wild flower, and soon
                            discovered the plants so familiar in New Hampshire, Blue Vervain, Toad Flax Wood Sorrel,
                            Nettles, Scabish and several other varieties. On reaching the Second family, Eldress Sophia
                            Helfrich invited us to call and see the cloaks that they were making for sale. Visitors to
                            the Village call at this place t,o see the goods and make purchases. A great many people
                            pass through the Village on bicycles, but very few stop for dinner. The gardener at the
                            Second family says that the worms are destroying his cabbages and he has been advised to
                            sprinkle them with Paris green. Eldress Caroline Helfrich has in safe keeping a collection
                            of antique curiosities which we were invited to see. Several patterns of bonnets, the oldest
                            being made without a cape. The frame was of pasteboard and covered with silk. The length
                            some thirteen inches. A cap made of thick cotton cloth, but with a muslin border. A great
                            variety of kerchiefs, aprons, dresses, etc, etc. Aug. 11. At 1-15 p. m. Brother Ira with a
                            span of horses and a covered carriage, took the writer to the Trustees' Office at Mt.
                            Lebanon. Two Sisters accompanied <pb n="150" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 150 THE MANIFESTO. us. A ride over
                            the new State Koad took us to the top of the mountain. Everybody speaks in its praise. Of
                            the road on the west side of the mountain but little need be said. We may, however,
                            anticipate an improved highway when the Commissioners ofiNew York decide to locate it. On
                            reaching the Church family at Mt. Lebanon, we were soon among friends, and proffered a very
                            cordial welcome. Our visit to the several families was somewhat limited, yet it was
                            pleasantly appreciated. We had the pleasure of meeting the Elders of every family and many
                            of the Brethren and Sisters. We saw some little girls playing a game of Enchantment, and
                            others equally as happy seated in a lawn swing. Mt. Lebanon'is a beautiful place. Every
                            thing about it is neatly arranged, while the care of the lawns and flowers in front of the
                            Family Dwelling are really attractive. The large, brick Dwelling at the First family, and
                            the Family Dwelling at the Novitiate Order are especially handsome buildings. The Church or
                            House of Worship attracts the attention of all visitors. The rooms formerly occupied by the
                            Order of Ministry have been vacated since the building of the new residence. A public
                            Service has been held during the season. Sister Amelia Calver in connection with many other
                            duties has the charge of several colonies of honey bees. That she appreciates the pleasure
                            of the employment,, there can be no doubt, as all the care given to the "little busy bee,"
                            meets with a ready and sweet response. Not even man's best friends, the dog or the horse is.
                            more appreciative of care and kindness than is the -'Queen and her family." As our time was
                            limited we made only a brief visit to the several families. In these visits we thankfully
                            shared many acts of care and kindness. This is the central home of all our gospel relation,
                            who have accepted the cross of Christ, and become sons and daughters of our God. Aug. 21.
                            Public Service was held at 10 a. m. Elder Calvin Keed conducts the Service one Sabbath,
                            Elder Timothy Rayson the second Sabbath, and Elder CharlesGreaves the third. Quite a large
                            company of spectators were present, and we learned that the speaking and singing were
                            excellent and appropriate for the occasion. The dear friends at the Trustees' Office, were
                            all that friends could be, and our every need was amply supplied. Three little girls and
                            their Caretaker made us a visit at the Office. Other Brethren and Sisters were also present,
                            and all were pleasantly entertained by the children, who sung several pieces and played
                            their own accompaniments on an organ. This was followed by some very pretty recitations and
                            formed a fitting close for the day. Aug. 22. At 9-45 we said "Good-bye" to Mt. Lebanon, and
                            Brother Ferdinand Gainebin with two Sisters were at the door with a covered carriage and a
                            span of horses. We were now on our way to Hancock, which we reacht via. Canaan Lower family,
                            Queechy Lake, and Richmond Lake, at 12-15. Aug. 23. Left Hancock for Albany, N. Y. at 7-35
                            a. m. Ticket, $1.08. Reacht. Albany at 9-10 a. m. and found Elder Joseph Holden present with
                            a carriage. We drove through a beautiful City Park, and then through West Albany, and reacht
                            the Shaker Village at 11-15. As the Ministry of Mt. Lebanon were at this place, we visited
                            them at their residence. This Order was establisht as the leading authority in all the
                            spiritual interests of the Community at large, and through this, their care becomes
                            universal. This little interview was very pleasant. As the time was quite limited for the
                            visit to this Society, only a very short time could be spent in any one place. Our home was
                            in the Trustees' Office, which is under the management of Brother J. Philip Smith and two
                            Sisters. Every care and <pb n="151" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 151 kindness was extended to
                            make the time pass pleasantly. We visited each family and enjoyed the privilege of meeting
                            with the Elders, and with many of the Brethren and Sisters. It was a busy season of the
                            year, and three of the families were engaged in the canning of beans, peas, tomatoes, etc.
                            Aug. 24. Last night we were visited by a thunder-storm that gave us a continuous flashing of
                            lightning, and an incessant roar of thunder for three hours. It was a fearful exhibition of
                            the powers of the air, and it was a great relief to the mind when the outburst was over. The
                            downpour of rain was as in the days of Noah when the windows of heaven were opened. While it
                            did no damage to the Community, it destroyed many buildings and trees in its line of march.
                            The several families in this Society are quite distant from each other, and entirely hidden
                            from the view of either one. The Cemetery at this place presented a very neat appearance.
                            The stones were of white marble, and placed in the best of order. Of this little enclosure
                            no one need be ashamed. It manifested a kind regard for the departed and a respect for the
                            living. The First family has a large two story brick building for a Trustees' Office. The
                            rooms and halls are of liberal size and high posted. Some of the rooms have recently been
                            papered on the sides and overhead, and present a very pretty appearance. The Family Dwelling
                            is a frame building, of two stories and well arranged for the comfort and convenience of the
                            family in every respect. Every family has ample accommodations in their dwellings, and all
                            of these buildings present an appearance that is highly commendable to our religious
                            Community. Aug. 26. We bade adieu to the good friends of Watervliet and were taken to West
                            Albany in a carriage, and were at the Station and ready to take the train for West
                            Pittsfield, where we arrived at 4-20 p. m. Brother Ira Lawson was in waiting and we were
                            soon riding on our way to the Church family. Aug. 27. Took a walk to the reservoir which
                            supplies water to the dwellings and to the mills. The water was as "clear as crystal" and
                            the supply we trust, never failing. Sept. 1. We made a visit to the vacated Society of
                            Tyringham. At 7 a. m. Brother Ira Lawson was at the door with a carriage and a span of
                            horses and with Eldress Sophia Helfrich and Emoretta Belden we were soon on our way. We past
                            through Eichmond, Stockbridge, South Lee and reacht Tyringham at noon. In the building
                            formerly used as the Trustees' Office, we found a family who were taking charge of the
                            property. Mr. Nash invited us into the house, and then very kindly offered to show us about
                            the premises. We past into the Office, and then through the Meeting House. These buildings
                            had been entirely remodeled on the inside to accommodate the summer boarders. We made a
                            hasty inspection of the other buildings, and everywhere was to be seen the substantial work
                            of consecrated hands. Force of circumstances, however, had obliged the Believers to sell the
                            property and take up their abode in other Societies. The Shakers of Tyringham selected a
                            remarkable place for the location of their Village. It is in a mountainous region, and while
                            the mountain rises several hundred feet above the buildings, the valley in which was to be
                            found their best land for tillage, was many hundred feet below them. Some of the houses that
                            were entered from the roadway and built for a two story dwelling, were in the rear a four
                            story building. A marble tablet in the Family Dwelling shows the date of the building to be
                            1823. Several other buildings were in a good state of preservation. A little building was
                            made in the side of the mountain, and about ten feet square, to be used for the setting of
                            milk and the storing of butter. A large limestone slab formed the roof, and assisted in
                            making this a simple cold storage. <pb n="152" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 152 THE MANIFESTO. The place is
                            now being fitted up for Summer boarders. It is six miles from a Eailroad Station and in a
                            section of the country with few inhabitants. The scenery, however, to those who love lofty
                            mountains and deep valleys, is enchanting. Bidding adieu to the once loved Community home, a
                            sad, unbidden thought flitted across the mind. We reacht Stockbridge at 1-45 p. m. and dined
                            at the Eed Lion's Inn. As the Believers are so well acquainted with the Proprietor and his
                            lady we felt very much at home. The house was filled with guests and many called only to be
                            refused for want of room. At this place we were shown a museum of curiosities, in furniture,
                            in crockery, etc. etc. A shelf extended around the large dining room and on this were
                            hundreds of plates, of all patterns, sizes and ages. Some were of historical value, while
                            others were prized for age and others illustrative of some special incident in life, while
                            others were of great value on account of being rare' specimens. The guide informed us that
                            some of these plates were valued at not less than $40.00. The Proprietor, Mr. C. H. Plumb,
                            very kindly took us to see his tall, brass clocks. He had three very nice specimens and one
                            in a mahogany case could not be purchased for $150.00. After dinner we continued our journey
                            toward home, and past through Lenox and on through the City of Pittsfield, reaching the
                            Village at 7 p. m. to the satisfaction of the whole company, after such an interesting
                            excursion. Sept. 2. At 9 a. m. in company with two Sisters we took the cars for Pittsfield.
                            After closing our business in the city we took an electric car for Lake Pontoosuc a few
                            miles distant. The little lake is one mile long and three quarters of a mile wide. A small
                            steamer took us around the lake for ten cents each. A man steers the boat but a woman
                            officiates as an engineer. We called on some friends of the Believers, and then returned to
                            the City for dinner. After attending to some more business calls we took the cars for West
                            Pittsfield. Sept. 5. At 9 a. m. in company with two Sisters we took the cars for Pittsfield.
                            Several Sisters also accompanied us from the East family. As this was "Labor Day," the
                            Catholic Temperance Societies had arranged for a parade. Delegations were present from
                            several cities in Mass, and not less than ten or twelve bands of music were in the
                            procession. It was estimated that 18000 persons were present, but the best of order
                            prevailed during the day. The Sisters from the East.family, soon after took a car for Lake
                            Pontoosuc where they spent the day, while we went to Dalton Village some five miles distant.
                            We dined at the Hotel and then returned to the City, and at 4-20 p. m. took the cars for
                            West Pittsfield in company with the other Sisters. All seemed of the opinion that they had
                            spent a very pleasant day, The cultivation of music is receiving increast attention in every
                            society. A piano or a Cabinet organ may be found in nearly every family. Not many, however
                            use them during the time of religious worship. Since the organization of the Community these
                            several changes have been taking place,in the architecture of the buildings, in the general
                            management of their business, as well as in articles of diet and in the manufacture of their
                            clothing. Medieval customs and habits were eminently proper in that age, but as the earth or
                            world moves, the people must move with it or be left in the rear. To stop this onward
                            progress would be like attempting to stop the wheels of time. It was only a few years since
                            and no Shaker would have worn a beard, or even accepted the gift of an artificial tooth. A
                            drab coat and a broad-brimmed hat designated the order to which he belonged, and the Sisters
                            were no less conspicuous in their lace caps and high heeled shoes; but as hats and coats are
                            quite destitute of religious vitality some families have felt at liberty to bring forward a
                            system more in accordance with the light of to-day. East Canterbury, N. H.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/>H. C. Blinn.</byline></div2><pb n="153" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In memory of our loved sister, Nancy Dow" TEIform="index"/>In Memory of our Loved Sister,
                            NANCY DOW.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sears, Elizabeth" TEIform="persName"/>By Elizabeth Sears.</byline><p TEIform="p">A loved one has left us and past through the portals That lead to an endless fruition of joy.
                            Perfected through suffering she joins the immortals The purified number in heavenly employ
                            Through scenes of adversity, conflict and trial Our Sister has past with an unshaken trust
                            Through noble endeavors and true self-denial Secured the reward of the upright and just. In
                            life's early morn when temptations surrounded She chose the straight path which our Savior
                            e'er trod, With faith in his teachings her spirit abounded Devoting her all to the service
                            of God. While many turned backward in search of vain pleasure Companions and friends who
                            were dearer than life Our Sister chose rather the heavenly treasure Contentment and freedom
                            from turmoil and strife. Her talents and strength with unswerving devotion Were most freely
                            given, Zion's cause to sustain She made no reserve but with full consecration Gave all she
                            possest for its honor and gain. In acts of benevolence freely she tendered That love which
                            pervadeth her spirit each day. To the stranger and friendless sweet services rendered To aid
                            and encourage them in this pure way. How deep was her interest and strong her endeavor To
                            lighten the burdens of each weary one. With kindness and love for each sister and brother
                            She faithfully toiled till each duty was done. Dear sister and friend, may thy shining
                            example Be ever a light to illumine our way. And while here we journey through sunshine and
                            shadow Permit us to share in thy blessings, we pray. Narcoossee, Fla.</p></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our olive branch" TEIform="index"/>OUR OLIVE BRANCH.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">IN Eunnymede township, one mile from Ashton station on the Sugar Belt Railway,
                                    lies the splendid domain of the Shaker colony known as Olive Branch. To call it a
                                    farm would belittle the place in a section where farms are so small as here, for it
                                    contains nearly seven thousand acres, of which <pb n="154" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 154 THE
                                    MANIFESTO. sixteen hundred are enclosed with a substantial fence, and arrangements
                                    are about completed for fencing as much more. If all the "doubting Thomases" in
                                    Florida would visit Olive Branch, their opinions as to the capacity of soil for
                                    producing stock, cereals, fruits, vegetables and cane would change materially, or at
                                    least be modified, as their land is but a fair sample of what may be found in any
                                    portion of Osceola county. The writer recently inspected the place through an
                                    invitation from the business manager, Mr. Benjamin Gates, and came away convinced it
                                    only needed the patient, intelligent industry manifested here to make farm life not
                                    only a delightful, but a remunerative occupation. In the grounds connected with the
                                    house and business office are orange, peach, apricot and persimmon trees with a
                                    large number of flowering plants. It seems to be the policy of this community to
                                    unite the beautiful with the practical; so you find here fruit trees, vines, shrubs,
                                    tropical foliage plants and flowering bulbs all in one group relieving the lawn from
                                    that stiffness noticed in public parks. An irrigating plant supplies the five acres
                                    immediately adjoining the house. For field crops they are this season growing Irish
                                    and sweet potatoes, cane, velvet beans, cow peas, beggar weed, rice and pumpkins.
                                    All of them look well, the cane being remarkably good. Living largely, but not
                                    exclusively on vegetable food, the garden is always a feature in a Shaker community.
                                    I noticed remarkably fine tomatoes,, okra, beets, spinach and turnips. Most
                                    interesting of all to visitors is the pinery, which is now buddings blossoming and
                                    fruiting. The plants are uniform in size and fruiting well. While not as large a
                                    pinery as some others in the state we have visited, for health of plants and general
                                    neatness of the grounds it has no superior. The design of the community has always
                                    been to make cattle growing the great industry, and for this the place is admirably
                                    fitted. It has numerous lakeswith abundant water for every pasture. Stockmen who
                                    have had cattle on this range claim it is one of the best in Florida. At present
                                    there are about nine hundred head of cattle in the portion enclosed. With the
                                    additional pastures to be enclosed this fall they can carry 2,000 head. It is a fact
                                    that the revenues of the place now make all the improvements, and that it is not
                                    done, as many claim, with assistance from kindred associations north. Under the able
                                    management of Mr. Benjamin Gates, and his aids, Andrew Barrett and Brother Egbert,
                                    Olive Branch will soon become a landmark in Florida, an experimental station without
                                    state aid. There are no secrets here. Success is obtained and made possible by
                                    brains and muscle. A pleasant and profitable day it was we spent at Olive Branch,
                                    and to Sis ters and Brothers we tender our sincere thanks.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>�Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prayer prevails against temptation..." TEIform="index"/>Prayer prevails against temptation...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Prayek prevails against temptation and brings the tried soul peace.</p></div2><pb n="155" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. OCTOBEB, 1898. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is publisht by the "United
                            Societt of Believees" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued regularly by
                            the Shakes Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the religious
                            views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. Address all communications
                            to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., K. H. One copy one year, postage paid. .50 A
                            cross in the margin will show that your subscription has closed. [Remittances for
                            subscription by Money Order should be on the Post Office at Concord, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">August. Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. Thermometer. Eain. 1897. 67.52 4.5 in. 1898.
                                72.84 10.75 " Highest Temp, during this mo. 92 above 0. Lowest " " " " 50 " " Number of
                                rainy days " " 14 " " clear " " " 8 " " cloudy" " " 9 Sept. 1898. Here we are standing
                                on the front steps of the portico of autumn, taking a survey of the exodus of summer
                                which is floating away upon the boundless sea of eternity. We shall never again see the
                                summer of 1898, The flight of time brings forcibly to mind the reveries of thepoet
                                Whittier: "O welcome calm of heart and mind ! As falls yon fir tree's loosened rind, To
                                leave a tenderer growth behind, So fall the weary years away; A child again my head I
                                lay Upon the lap of this sweet day." Prof. Hicks, the great weather prognosticator, said
                                that from the 4th to the 15th. of July we should have electric storms, but July was very
                                quiet, not being affected especially with this element; August abounded in electric
                                storms, some of them terrific. Of late we have had a superabundance of rain, which cut
                                deep gutters in the face of Mother Earth. Nevertheless between storms we have got our
                                hay crop safely garnered. We have commenced digging potatoes. The wet weather is causing
                                the rot to affect the crop some. Elder Henry C. Blinn has been spending a season at the
                                Church family, Hancock, to recuperate his health. From August 18th to the 22nd, he
                                called at the Mount, and we spent a very pleasant time with him for he is skilled with
                                tact and ability to make time pass pleasantly while in his. company. He makes the
                                impress, 'Tis joy to meet with kindred minds And spend the social hour Replete with
                                pleasure pure, refined Distilled from heaven's bower. Sympathy is a heavenly gift that
                                causes us to joy with those who joy: to weep with those who weep; to share in .one
                                another's grief and loss; to impart consolation to the sorrowing; to show a divine
                                inspiring radiance to light the pathway of the mourner. Our spirits mingle with yours,
                                dear gospel relation, in your late bereavement in the passport of your dear Eldress
                                Dorothy. With some this will beyour day of trial, but keep the Faith that will make you
                                worthy to receive the crown, of life, that will weave for you and adorn you with the
                                robe of angelic purity and the diadem of unsullied beauty, and the blessing and
                                inspiring influence of Eldvess Dorothy will be an enduring light TERMS. <pb n="156" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 156 THE MANIFESTO. to guide you safely in the pathway of righteousness
                                and abiding peace. Calvin Cf. Reed. North Family. Sept. 1898. It certainly is delightful
                                to draw a breath of pure restfulness at last without scorching reminiscences of our new
                                tropical possessions or of that other place which Ridpath politely designates the bottom
                                of the old theologies. This summer has been one of many visitors from the numerous
                                resorts among the Berkshires. The world is surely fast growing better, more thoughtful,
                                more sensible, more aspiring, or we are honored by calls from the best of its people,
                                for our visitors this summer have been of an exceptionally high type, people of culture
                                in the broadest sense of that word, wide awake to the necessities of the times and eager
                                and earnest in their inquiries for any and everything by which these necessities of
                                body, brain and soul might be supplied. Dear Sister Catherine has talkt from morn till
                                dewy eve explaining and expounding, and then frequently supplements this talking by
                                means of letters in answer to would-be questions forgotten at the time. Among all the
                                pleasant memolies of our visitors none are more satisfactory than those connected with
                                Elder Henry Blinn. And yet this pleasure is tinged with a thought of sadness. Have we,
                                perhaps in our mistaken kindness, retarded instead of hastened the health we so
                                earnestly desire him to possess? Our full sympathy, best wishes and highest hopes attend
                                his goings forth and his home comings! Sisters Lydia Staples and May Kullhausen are in
                                Chatham presiding over the Shaker exhibit there. This exhibit has called forth warm
                                words of commendation in the columns of the local paper. Our family have about forty
                                entries of articles for competition in the Ladies' Industrial Department. The course of
                                events at home is as usual. We believe with our poet; "God is in His Heaven All is right
                                with the world" or will be when the coming kingdom comes. G. Ada Brown. South Family.
                                Sept. 1898. The closing summer month was made delightfully memorable by a visit from our
                                sainted father and Mend Elder Henry C. Blinn. We had long lookt for his coming and as
                                each year waned we said, he will surely come the next, it must be we shall meet him
                                again in this life. But oh, we so much regretted his brief tarry with us, while we are
                                not disposed to envy our neighbors over the way we congratulate them on their good
                                fortune of entertaining an angel and we wish such had been our pleasing mission too, But
                                we'll hope in the future As we've hoped in the past That again he will come While yet
                                life shall last. So good-bye we'll not say But a welcome extend For the coming again Of
                                our father and friend. Mr. and Mrs. Brannen of Denver, Col. made a pleasant call at our
                                home sometime ago. They are interested in all religious and spiritual improvements of
                                the age and are workers in the cause of humanity. They are personal friends of the late
                                Eldress Alvira Conklin of the Watervliet Society. Work on the farm and in the house
                                progresses grandly, hay and grain are of the very best; apples we fear will be a ghost
                                of the past, they are few and inferior, but we shall live and give thanks for the
                                numerous blessings which are ours to enjoy. Fine weather prevails. September is glorious
                                for the harvesting of fall produce. Health and prosperity rules our family. Genevieve
                                DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Sept. 1898. We have had another proof of the truth of the ancient proverb thaf'allgood
                                comes <pb n="157" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 157 to those who wait." We have anticipated
                                and hoped that the Editor of our Manifesto would find time to give us a call, and we
                                almost concluded that we were hoping against hope, when his benign presence appeared in
                                our midst. We were thankful for the short period of social communion that we enjoyed
                                with him and will hope that sometime in the not distant future it may be repeated. The
                                quickening of the moral and spiritual sensibilities of the nations as manifested in the
                                proposal of the Autocrat of Russia to call an International Conference to consider the
                                question of the disarmament of the nations, is evidence that the brutal system which has
                                literally made bondslaves of all races has seen the hand writing on the wall, and is
                                realizing the fact that its days are numbered. We will pray and will work to hasten the
                                consummation of that time "When the war drum throbs no longer And the battle flags are
                                furled, In the parliament of man The federation of the world." September has heralded
                                its advent with a tropical climate. Up to the present date of writing, the 5th inst.,
                                the thermometer has daily registered in the nineties. But we enjoy the antumnal season
                                when the result of the anxiety and toil in producing fruits and vegetables is realized.
                                Hamilton JDeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Sept. 1898. The past month has been an especially busy one for the sisterhood, in caring
                                for numerous companies of visitors. One day seventy-eight individuals called, of which
                                number fifty-eight partook of dinner. While consecrated strength has been given to care
                                for temporal affairs, the educational, spiritual and social duties have not been
                                slighted, and we are pleased to record the kindness of friends who have added their
                                gifts with ours to help brighten and edify the lives of our own kindred. Our towns-lady,
                                Inez Packard, a late graduate of the Boston School of Oratory, kindly entertained us for
                                an hour, with various selections of prose and poetry. On another occasion, Mrs. Ida
                                Harrington, of Worcester, Mass, entertained us with music and songs of a high order. As
                                occasional intermissions, some of the youngSisters sang and rendered recitations. We
                                also entertained for a short period, the Kev. M. W. Borthwick, of Manchester, N. H.
                                While with us, he delivered an impressive lecture on Temperance. Among many fine remarks
                                he said, what we would not tolerate in our individual lives we ought not to tolerate in
                                our society. As a people, believing that God takes more notice of our deeds than of our
                                sentiments, we can endorse the above counsel, knowing,He that knoweth what is right and
                                doeth it not committeth sin. Companies of Sisters attended the camp meetings held at
                                Lake Sunnapee and Wilmot, N. H. also the Vermont State Fair. Those who sold fancy
                                articles, report good results. We drew first premium on braided and knit mats, bread,
                                onions and beets. George II. Baxter.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Sept. 1898. This season has past into history with full record of thunder-storms and
                                sudden showers. Winds and rains have done their best to test the standing strength of
                                the luxuriant growth of corn now at hand, but it succumbed at last. Twenty acres of fine
                                ensilage corn bowed to the ground and had to be cut by hand, while the Corn Binder was
                                for once useless. Cutting for the silos commenced on the 13th inst., at the rate of
                                seven or eight tons an hour. About 1400 squashes of unusually fine quality must have, at
                                least, honorable mention. 350 bushels of oats have been thrasht. Now the nuts are
                                claiming attention and the butternut trees offer employment for many hands. The
                                squirrels are nimble and avaricious, but we shall apply for our rightful share of all
                                varieties. One of the perpetrators asks to have recorded that 40 woodchucks met a
                                violent <pb n="158" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 158 THE MANIFESTO. -death this season. Partridges have
                                been protected by law in this state from Jan. 1 to Sept. 15, under penalty of a 10.
                                fine, but sportsmen are now taking advantage of their freedom. The register at the dairy
                                records 93 gallons of milk one day last week. Sisters have canned over 1000 quarts of
                                fruit during the month. The peach harvest is estimated at about 150 bushels, all
                                varieties included. School opened for fall term on the 13th, with fifteen pupils
                                andtwenty classes (?) Thanksgiving Day has dawned to an eternity with us, for we see
                                God's goodness written upon every gift, we feel his unerring wisdom directing every
                                dispensation of discipline; and even when the keenest blow falls we can but say, "Thy
                                will, not mine, be done." Jessie Evans.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Narcoossee, Florida" TEIform="index"/> Narcoossee, Fla.</head><p TEIform="p">Sept. 1898. The love that labors and waits is the rewarded love. Our prayers are borne to
                                God on the wings of our deeds, and this fruitage of the spirit can not be realized save
                                through labor and sacrifice. Consistently speaking we have no faith in that love that is
                                not a working or doing love. Go to work is the word and accomplish something for the
                                good of humanity. God, if he blesses us with the fruits of the Spirit, expects us to
                                make our profession good by acts. Are we fulfilling our obligations to our divine Father
                                or have we concluded to sit down with folded arms and wait for him to do our work? The
                                smallest deed done in a great spirit becomes significant. The most obscure life lookt
                                upon by the invisible and the eternal becomes rich and full at last. Is there, then, any
                                reason why our ranks should not be filled with true and noble souls if we do our whole
                                duty? The extent and responsibility of our living does not wholly depend on beautiful
                                surroundings of the material conditions. If it did then some of us might say we have
                                done our work, and we will trust to the accomplishment of the rest. "Variety is the
                                spice of life." Change sometimes gives food for thought. Orange trees are growing
                                beautifully. All the late corn has made a good yield;Peas are blooming and bearing. The
                                largest sweet potato crops ever known are planted in this section and are growing to
                                beat the band, and take it altogether we might be a great deal worse off than we are. We
                                should be and are thankful for small favors until larger ones can be received. Andrew
                                Barrett.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watervliet, Ohio" TEIform="index"/>Watervliet, Ohio.</head><p TEIform="p">Sept. 1898. We are having fine weather for fall seeding. Crops are fine, but prices low.
                                This is not encouraging, when we think of our heavy taxes. J. O. Tyler.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our loved ones" TEIform="index"/>OUR LOVED ONES.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">[Contributed by Genevieve DeGraw.] 
                                    What are our loved ones doing to-day? Those who have crost o'er the chilling
                                    tide, And landed safe on the other side, Those who have left in the shrouding's fold
                                    Beautiful clay for the grave to hold, What are those dear ones doing to-day? I who
                                    must deal with sorrow and care, I who am hoping the crown to wear, I with a heaven
                                    to lose or win, I who am tempted and tried within, Long to step over the bounds of
                                    time, And see what is done in that glorious clime. Waters of life untroubled are
                                    there, Life's fair tree hath its fruits to bear, Songs far sweeter than poets dream,
                                    Angels sing by the flowing stream, Folding their snowy wings they glide Over the
                                    sands by the river's side, Welcoming those who pure and white Enter the beautiful
                                    gates to-night. Oh, to be with them! Oh, to be there! Oh, to be free from this
                                    cumbering care! <pb n="159" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 159 Oh, to be safe in the
                                    heavenly fold, Out of the gathering storms and cold Only to know my sorrows all past
                                    Jesus has loved me and crowned me at last. Soul be content, thou must labor and
                                    wait, Toiling and trusting both early and late, Jesus knows when to call thee up
                                    higher More than his will dost thou ask or desire? Called in the morning or called
                                    in the night Called from earth's darkness or called from its light, Patiently wait
                                    thou and all will be right.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>�Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Perfect people" TEIform="index"/>PERFECT PEOPLE.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Perhaps no one of our friends is exactly as we would like to have him. He has his
                                    good qualities and strong points which attract and win us: at the same time he has
                                    defects of character to which we can not be blind. We have gone far, however, in
                                    cultivating the art of friendship when we take our friends as they are, and
                                    recognize that what we deem their faults are often closely connected with their
                                    excellencies. You can readily imagine a man more attractive to you in some elements
                                    of character than Jones, but if Jones were exactly the kind of man you would like to
                                    have him, he would not be Jones at all. A friend of ours was in search of a horse
                                    that was an excellent roadster, full of spirit, and yet safe for his little girl to
                                    drive. He soon discovered that while there are many excellent roadsters and also
                                    many horses that children can drive, yet there are not many horses that have spirit
                                    and at the same time are perfectly safe in the hands of a child. This combination of
                                    qualities is pretty hard to get in horses. And there are combinations of qualities
                                    that it is pretty hard to find in men. We say that we love and respect Jones; that,
                                    in truth, he is one of our best friends but we wish that he were different in this
                                    or that respect. Ah, yes, but the qualities that he has you do not often find in men
                                    who have the qualities that he lacks. A man with push and energy if endowed with the
                                    gentler qualities which make up the character of his neighbor, would not be himself,
                                    with outstanding characteristics which give him an identity, but simply a mediocre,a
                                    faint resemblance to himself and a shadowy likeness of his neighbor. If we could
                                    make over Jones to please our idea of what he should be, he might not be as good a
                                    specimen of the race as he now is, and yet we can very clearly point out the
                                    improvement he might make in his character. Let us remember that we, too, have our
                                    deficiencies and excesses and be charitable to our friends and trust that time, and
                                    intercourse with noble and intelligent minds will yet add to their character the
                                    sterner traits which they lack, mayhap, or adorn them with those graces, which will
                                    mark them as followers of the meek and lowly Nazarene. Perfect men are not very
                                    common, and furthermore, the kind of man that we should deem perfect, because of his
                                    relation to our own qualities might not be perfect by any means. What most of us
                                    mean by a perfect parson, is one whose qualities harmonize with or supplement our
                                    own.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>�Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Charity" TEIform="index"/>CHARITY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>By Sinter Mary Whitcher.</byline><p TEIform="p">My soul hath a secret I'll keep it secure. That if coolly treated The same I'll endure. And
                            never repeat it In one mortal ear, With God rather leave it Who only should hear. No malice
                            I'll harbor In view of the same, No sadness shall cover My brow with its claim. But onward
                            in duty My steps shall proceed, Beholding but beauty And working for need. East Canterbury,
                            N. H.</p></div2><pb n="160" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary.</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Don't talk of your ills" TEIform="index"/> DONT TALK OF YOUR ILLS.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">"Eveky one of us has his and her own ailments," writes Edward W. Bok in the
                                        December Ladies' Home Journal, decrying the unpleasant habit many people have of
                                        discussing their bodily ills. "It is enough for us all to keep well ourselves :
                                        to be compelled to listen to the ailments of others does not make that task any
                                        easier. Besides all this, these unnecessary narratives of personal ailments are
                                        positively injurious to ourselves. Physicians all agree that many of the slight
                                        illnesses, of which some people make so much, could be cured if they would but
                                        take their minds from themselves. Too many people work themselves into
                                        illnesses, or prevent themselves from getting well, by talking about a petty
                                        ailment, which, if forgotten, would right itself. It seems that one of the most
                                        important lessons we can all learn is to refrain from inflicting upon others
                                        what is purely personal to ourselves. Let us cease this tiresome, this
                                        inconsiderate, this unnecessary talk about our ailments. Cold and hard as it may
                                        seem, the fact is nevertheless true, and will ever remain so, that the vast
                                        majority of people are interested in what is pleasant in our lives, but not in
                                        what is unpleasant. l^ains and sorrows are elements in our lives which are
                                        sacred and interesting only to ourselves."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>�Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Unconscious influence" TEIform="index"/> UNCONSCIOUS INFLUENCE.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">It is daily life that tests usthe manner of men we are. It is not our prayer,
                                        it is not our profession; but it is the tone of daily intercourse and conduct
                                        that decides how we stand. The little, homely graces; the cheerful, every-day
                                        amenities; the Christ spirit uttering itself not so much in conscious act as in
                                        unconscious influence ; not so much in deeds as in that subtle aroma which,
                                        without name, exudes from the saintly soul to equals and inferiors; to agreeable
                                        and disagreeable; to rich, poor, ignorant; to young, to old; bearing burdens,
                                        accepting crosses, seeking no great thing to do, content to put self by, and be
                                        a servant of the lowest these are fruits of only one rootfruits that none may
                                        counterfeit.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>�Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>OUR EXCHANGES.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Altruist" TEIform="index"/>The Altruist
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Altruist is devoted to equal rights, mutual assistance, united labor and common
                                property. Alexander Longley, Editor. Its office is in St. Louis, Mo. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Islamic world" TEIform="index"/>The Islamic World
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Islamic World
                                is publisht in Liverpool, Eng. by "The Cresent Printing Company." </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Modern philosopher" TEIform="index"/>The Modern
                                Philosopher
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Modern
                                Philosopher, includes Philosophical Comments, Eeviews of Books that help Progress,
                                Miscellaneous Reading, Original and Selected. Albert Chavannes, Editor and Publisher,
                                Knoxville, Tenn.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Happy is the man..." TEIform="index"/>Happy is the man...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Happy is the man who early learns the wide chasm that lies between his wishes and his
                        powers.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dunning, Daniel" TEIform="index"/>Daniel Dunning
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Daniel Dunning, at Watervliet, Ohio. Aug. 29, 1898. Age 81 years. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dow, Nancy" TEIform="index"/>Nancy Dow
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Nancy Dow, at
                                Narcoossee, Fla. Sept. 1, 1898 Age 69 years, 6 months and 25 days. The battle is fought
                                and the victory is won. Sister Nancy was one of the pioneers who over three years ago
                                left their homes on the hillside to pledge their all in forming a home in the sunny
                                South. She has died as she lived, a noble, worthy Sister, true to her convictions of
                                right, and like the true patriot fell while sustaining the gospel banner of purity and
                                love. Sister Nancy entered the Society of Shakers in 1833. A. B.</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p19"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
AGENTS!
This is  the   opportunity of your life
Agents are making $50.00 to $150.00 a week.
ritzhugh Lee, Maj. Gen. U. S. V., and late
Consul General to Cuba, writes
A BOOK ON CUBA
AND   THE
SPANISH WAR.
We have on press for early issue, General
Lee's own story of Cuba and the Spanish War,
to be produced in a substantial book of over
500 pages, 7x9% inches in size and almost
ONE HUNDRED ILLUSTRATIONS.
This is the only authentic work published
on the one subject occupying the minds of the
entii-e civilized world.
OUTFITS READY.
Liberal commissions will be paid and credit
given.   Address for full paiticulars,
THE INTERNATIONAL SOCIETY,
91-93 FIFTH AVENUE, NEW YORK.
PUBLISHERS OP GENERAL LEE'S BOOK.
We have authorized distributors everywhere
is an illustrated Monthly, now only 50 cts.
per year, devoted to PHRENOLOGY.
PHYSIOGNOMY,  HEALTH,   MEDIOAL
& SOCIAL REF0SM.
Would you like a copy?
Send 5 cts. for Sample to Prof. Haddock,
Phrenologist, 1016 Market St.,
San Francisco, Cal.
SHAKES   THEOLOGY.
A Book of 320 pages.    It contains not
only the Shaker's Faith but explains
Scripture Metaphor.    By H. L. Eads.
Address H. C. Blinn, East Canterbury
N.  H.
WONDERFUL strange REVELATIONS.
DANIEL'S & STJOHN'S
PROPHECIES.
48 page pamphlet.    Price 10 cts.
13 for $1.00.
Address,   H. B. Beak, Preston, Ohio.
WITHOUT   DOUBT
THE BEST FAMILY PAPER PUBLISHED
IS   THE
NEW   YORK   WEEKLY   WITNESS.
16 Pages.   Only   $1 a year.
Has a very wide scope, comprising as it
does the following departments:
Editorials,
Spirit of" the Press,
Scientific and Instructive,
Kite Odd and Uncommon,
Our Country's Hope,
Foreign News,
A Talk With the Doctor,
Around tilts Hearth,
Xiittle Men and Women,
Weekly Articles ly <*eoi'g-e St. Scott
Vatmag-e's Sermon,
Money and Business,
World-Wide Field,
Our Family Story,
Farm and Garden,
Market Reports,
SABBATH READING.
16 Pages.   Only 5O cents a Year.
An Inter-denominational Weekly Paper.
Sabbath Beading is solely religious.
No news; no politics. A grand paper
for the truth-seeker.    It contains:
Editorial.
Christian Endeavor Topic,
Ejswortli Iieag'ue Topic,
8atI>atn-8chool Iiesaon,
Choice JPoetry,
ftood Stories,
Reports of Missions,
Mothers' abt>ath Afternoon
With the  Children,
And a mass of matter  carefully  selected.
Send for free sample copies of Witness
and Sabbath Beading. And send for
free sample pages of our Bagster's Bible.
Address
JOHN BOUaALL h CO., 150 Nassau Street, New York.
HUMAN NATURE
<pb n="" id="p20"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
Royal makes the food pure,
wholesome and delicious.
60  YEARS'
EXPERIENCE
Trade Marks
Designs
Copyrights &c.
Anyone sending a sketch and description may
quickly ascertain our opinion free whether an
invention is probably patentable. Communications strictly confidential. Handbook on Patents
sent free. Oldest agency for securing patents.
Patents taken through Munn & Co. receive
tpecial notice, without charge, in the
Scientific jnnericatu
A handsomely illustrated weekly. Largest circulation of any scientific Journal. Terms, $3 a
year; four months, $L Sold by all newsdealers.
MUNN &Co.36tB'oadwa'' New York
Branch Office, 625 F St., Washington, D. C.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure
HOW TO MAKE MONEY!
If you are out of employment and want
a position paying you from $50 to $100
monthly clear above expenses by working
regularly, or, if you want to increase your
present income from $200 to $500 yearly,
by working at odd times write the GLOBE
CO. 723 Chestnut St. Phila., Pa. stating
age, whether married or single, last or
present employment, and you can learn
how to make more money easier and
faster than you ever made before in your
life.
AUTHORISED   RULES
OF
THE   SHAKER   0OMMUNITY.
The religious basis of the Okdee must
be a foundation resting on the principle of
righteousness, which principle is God.
This should rule the life of the individual for the protection of his own soul, for
the peace of the family and as an evidence
of his upright standing before the world.
Price, 10 cts.
SHAKER HAMAMELIS
(WITCHHAZEL,)
.A. remedy for Cuts, Burns, Scalds,
Headache, Sore Throat and all
cases of external inflammation
Taken internally for Bowel
Complaint, Bleeding of the
Lungs or Bowels, and for
all aches and pains.
For use externally, bathe the parts and
lay on a cloth wet with the Extract,    Internally, take one half teaspoonful three
times a day.   Use hot or cold.
Ask your druggist for it or send your
order to Abthur Bruce.
East Canterbury, N. H.
ROYAL BAKING POWDER CO., NEW YORK.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>