<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm0905" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title><editor role="editor" TEIform="editor"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/></editor></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">9</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">5</biblScope><date value="18790501" TEIform="date">May 1879</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">97-120</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="9" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="5" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                <pb id="p1"/>
                        <p> MAT, 1879. The Shaker MANIFESTO. (OFFICIAL MONTHLY.) G. A. LOMAS, Editoe. Published by the United Societies. OUR
                        HOME AT HARVARD, MASS. "And they shall turn to you for a testimony:" ''Go preach the Kingdom of God!" ADDRESS ALL
                        COMMUNICATIONS TO " The Shaker Manifesto, Shakers, N.D." G. B. AVERY, PUBLISHER. 1879. vol. ix.; No. 5. j i 60 Cents
                        I Per Annum,</p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
--><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><pb n="97" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Philanthropist" TEIform="index"/>PHILANTHROPIST</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Devyr, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/>Cecelia Devyr</byline><p TEIform="p"> 0 straggling heart, be strong, be strong ! And angel hosts will comfort thee ; Each jmlse
                            that throbs against the wrong, Shall yet beat high in victory. Were not the prophets ever
                            stoned? Were not the messengers reviled ? And yet the earth in error groaned, And writhed in
                            anguish wild ! The martyr's spirit is not killed — Though cruel racks his flesh have torn,—
                            His mission still must be fulfilled, His mantle must be onward borne. God knows the earth's
                            great sins and needs; Through human hearts His aid must flow ; He marks the true, unselfish
                            deeds, He bids the noble impulse glow ! To speed His holy work is thine ; To sow the seed,
                            'mid storm and rain ; E're long the harvest fields will shine, To bless thee for thy toil
                            and pain. 0 ! Prophet heart, be strong in love, That swells from fountains bright clear ;
                            The angel bands from heaven above, Unite with angel spirits here. All dark, and drear, thy
                            path may be, Yet thou art light to the oppressed ; And for thy labors given free, Thy soul
                            shall find eternal rest. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prophet and Jesus" TEIform="index"/>THE PROPHET AND JESUS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/>Antoinette Doolittle</byline><p TEIform="p"> It is difficult for the natural mind to grasp and comprehend spiritual things except by
                            comparison, illustration or inspiration. Hence, the ancient prophets used metaphors and
                            symbolic utterances. Because of the unspiritual condition of the unbelieving, unbaptized
                            people of their time, Jesus and his disciples spake many parables to those who had not been
                            quickened by the spirit — as the apostles of Jesus had been — to discern truth from error,
                            and to divide the natural and exterior from the spiritual interior, which is the soul of all
                            things. And Jesus was under the necessity of rebuking his disciples even, for a deficit of
                            faith, want of understanding, and dullness of hearing. Jesus said, " The words that / speak
                            are spirit and life." They were replete with divine essence, redolent with truth that could
                            reach the soul senses, and vivify the germs of immortal life that are in every human heart,
                            and cause them to grow and expand and be ingrafted into the living vine, and receive of its
                            sap, and become fruitbearing branches. The Prophet Isaiah, when under the beautiful spirit
                            of divine inspiration, foretold the advent of the Messiah — " the Rod that would come forth
                            from the stem of Jesse, and the Branch that would grow out of his roots;" and that the
                            spirit of the Lord, of wisdom and counsel would attend the Messianic reign : for in that day
                            a willing people would arise and joyfully accept the Rod as the ruling spirit in the male
                                <pb n="98" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 98 THE SHAKEK MANIFESTO. order in Christ's kingdom; and, " when in
                            the fullness of time He set his hand again to gather and restore the remnant left," the
                            Branch bearing the olive leaf, as the symbolic delineator of the female, or love element,
                            would have a lot and place. Then the dual likeness of Father and Mother in Deity would be
                            truly represented. From the Rod, and the Branch, in simile, we have the " olive trees/'
                            representing the "two anointed ones"— male and female—the " golden pipes," through which "
                            oil"—living inspiration—flows from the Church in the invisible world, into the "golden
                            bowl"—the visible Church of God upon earth—the repository of divine truth. That this "
                            golden bowl" may never be broken, become fragmentary, and be severed, from those "pipes," so
                            beautifully illustrated by the Prophet, should be our great concern. We may see, by the
                            light reflected upon the pages of past history, how great is the danger of apostacy ! how
                            subtle and wily have been the influences which have crept over and found their way into the
                            temples of the past, that were reared in the name of God, and professedly dedicated to His
                            service, to be purely preserved as receptacles of divine and spiritual truth ; and where
                            oblations could be acceptably offered, and vows performed. When Antichrist gained the
                            ascendency, the power of the holy people was scattered ; and instead of those temples being
                            filled with living souls, who through tribulation and self-sacrifice had washed and whitened
                            their robes, and were by those means fitted and prepared to praise God, day and night,
                            bearing palms of victory, and triumphing over the powers of death, they were filled with
                            idol worshippers; justly compared to unclean birds, whose false plumage, and fascinating
                            musical strains — as siren songs are wont to do — allured multitudes to seek pleasure in
                            unrighteousness, to forget God and profane his sanctuaries, which were designed to be
                            sacredly kept for praise and prayer. Let us reap instruction from the past, and avoid the
                            pitfalls of those who have set out in the highway of progression, and failed; then we shall
                            not swell the ranks of those who are " ever learning, but never able to attain the knowledge
                            that will enable them to understand the truth and reduce it to practice." </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life and its purpose" TEIform="index"/>LIFE AND ITS PURPOSE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, G. B." TEIform="persName"/>G. B. Avery</byline><p TEIform="p"> " We believe the Supreme Being created intelligent beings for some benevolent and glorious
                            purpose." — Webster. The ambition of the worldly man is generally directed to one, or more,
                            of the following purposes: the acquisition of wealth, power, or fame, for distinction. The
                            worldly, unambitious, purpose simply pleasure, enjoyment, creature comforts. To every young
                            man or woman starting out on the journey of life, the question is a very serious and
                            important one : To what purpose shall I give my life ? The lowest and meanest of all
                            purposes is entire selfishness. To plan, toil, and, if possible, obtain a degree of wealth,
                            and spend the entire sum of life's earnings for individual, selfish ends, the satisfaction
                            of the passions ; social and sexual pleas- <pb n="99" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 99
                            ures; travel, sight-seeing or voluptuousness, gormandizing in meats and drinks, or feeding
                            the mental maw, without appropriating its treasured lore for the benefit of humanity. A step
                            higher in the scale of life's appropriations is to live for self and family on the
                            generative plane ; and with these to share the products of toil, material wealth, mental
                            wealth, and the love and affections of a normal, natural life. A life strictly in accordance
                            with nature's unadulterated laws is an honor and blessing to the worldly man and woman, and
                            to the interests of its common society; the difficulty of thus living lies in the fact that
                            the passional nature of man is so corrupted at the fountain, that, in this relation, men and
                            women do not find strength to keep nature's law of continence. But, a still higher, nobler,
                            happier life, is one devoted and consecrated to the family of Christ—the Christian
                            community, where, instead of simply one man, or one woman, upon whom to bestow
                            care,benefits, love and affection, there are multitudes, all dwelling together in a pure,
                            virgin relation, in the capacity of Fathers, Mothers, Brothers and Sisters of one household
                            of faith, and harmoniously toiling in one labor of love, that is, the support and comfort
                            immediately, of the family of Christ, mediately for the benefit of all mankind, as far as
                            influences may extend, and opportunity offers to do good. In this order of life there is,
                            comparatively, little suffering ; the domestic cares and burdens are borne by many; and if
                            one sister or one brother is sick, or unable to attend to the duties of life, the companions
                            are not left to ply the laboring oar alone ; there are others ready to lencl assistance ;
                            therefore, no occasion of sufferings from neglect of care. In the social sphere of this
                            relation, the privileges of reciprocal comfort and blessing are enlarged more than an
                            hundred fold, because, while one companion, as a brother or sister, is suffering from
                            physical disease or pain, or is worn down with cares and sorrows, there are, in this family
                            relation, still others, at all times accessible, to cheer, comfort, and help bear up. In its
                            spiritual communion, the privileges and opportunities of enjoyment, comfort and strength,
                            are infinitely increased among the truly consecrated and faithful, for the sources of bliss
                            are three fold. 1st, A consciousness of having lived to be and do good, not only to one's
                            self but to the household of faith, and the whole family of man; 2d, the blessings and love
                            which are bestowed by others for benefits received; 3d, the blessings and benedictions of
                            Grod. In the relations of this Christ family the opportunities of reciprocal benefits are
                            extensively multiplied ; since, with those true to its order, there is a gushing fountain of
                            personal and social peace flowing like the ceaseless rolling river ; and union and blessing,
                            which are infinitely expanding and interchanging, nursing the plants of grace, refreshing
                            the flowers of cheerfulness, and swelling to perfection and luscious ripeness the fruits of
                            Heaven —those soul-lit inspirations which gladden every participant, bringing heaven to
                            earth, and converting earth, within the arena of this pure relation, into an Eden, when
                            compared with <pb n="100" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 100 THE SHAKES MANIFESTO. the abodes and conditions of
                            those in a carnal life, who war, and contend for supremacy and power, and who, as the
                            subjects of sensuality, feed on sorrows, bitterness and disappointments. Go to the squallid
                            habitations of the poor and destitute, where hunger gnaws, and tatters and sickness from
                            exposures tell the tale of woe, or where sin corrodes the heart 'mid luxury's palaces of
                            glittering plate on sideboards laden with silver and gold; where, not the wants that pinch
                            the poor are known, but the want of peace and contentment; where the brain is fevered with
                            cares of hoarded wealth, and the spirit weighed in sadness from convictions of ill-gotten
                            gains and injured innocence. Take thy stand where the gay and grand, the full-fed and giddy
                            throng are rushing into pleasure's fields and fashion's gauzy palace; here, in these
                            retreats, ask, Are these life's noble purposes? Alas, how miserable, then, such life. Visit
                            the fields of this worldly life's closing drama ; pause 'mid the works of art sacred to the
                            memory of these dead ; see here the harvests of toil, che burdens of misspent genius and
                            wealth, piled in gorgeous, massive blocks, — monuments of pride, vanity and
                            foolishness—cold, heartless and cheerless as the death-clod upon which they are piled. Here
                            pause again, and ask yourself, Is this the end of life's noblest purpose? If so, 'tis not a
                            prize ! Ah, nay ; a lottery blank; a vestment, color faded, and stripped of warp and woof;
                            thin as the fleeting mist, and evanescent as the scent of flowers. But, God be praised ;
                            life hath a l nobler gift, a higher purpose, when consecrated to the upbuilding of Heaven's
                            Kingdom upon earth, and devoted to virgin purity ; it rises above earth and its corroding
                            cares, treasures, toils, turmoils and strife; above that Heaven of which the selfish and
                            worldly only sing and dream, but always place in the regions " over there." It holds, while
                            here, sweet converse with the comforting angels of the brighter spheres, and rests securely
                            in the possession of peace, quietness and heavenly communion with the loved, honored and
                            blessed who are reaping sheaves of gladness from the ripened harvests of the heavenly
                            shores. Shakers, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ways of the wanderer: a personal experience" TEIform="index"/>THE WAYS OF THE WANDERER: A
                            Personal Experience</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Andrews, Watson" TEIform="persName"/>Watson Andrews</byline><p TEIform="p">I went from the liome of my fathers When youth and its Eden were mine , When parent restraint
                            was a fetter, And nature and pleasure divine ; When light was a joy to the vision, And sound
                            found an echo within; When taste was unsated with pleasure, And feeling unpoisoned by sin ;
                            When odors were loaded with nectar, And health coursed in every vein ; When, the woi"ld
                            before me, a wand'rer, I roamed over ocean and plain. I saw the wide West in its beauty, Ere
                            civilization had trod The innocent bosom of nature, Effacing the image of God, On the verge
                            of the evening horizon, Where prairies were mantled in green, I have gazed in the glow of
                            the sunset— Entranced with the heavenly scene. On the shores of the Father of Waters— On a
                            crag overarching his wave— I have pondered the past with the millions Who have found on his
                            margin a grave. And under a falling Niagara, On the brink of the feathery foam, I have
                            heard, in the roaring of waters, And seen, sublimity at home. I have seen, far away in the
                            forest, The gleam of the " council fires " blaze, And heard the monotonous tum-tum Of the
                            drum of the Blackhawk brave. I have marked the dread path of the panther <pb n="101" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. 101 And traversed the trail of the deer ; I have gazed on the swoop
                            of the eagle, And met the wild wolf in his lair. In his birchen canoe, with the savage, I
                            have flown o'er the crest of the wave ; Where the missiles of death made their music, I have
                            stood in the ranks of the brave. I have heard from the deck the rude thunder Reverberate
                            over the main ; And blanched at the blaze of the lightning, As it swept over cordage and
                            chain. I have been where the sweep of the tempest Had riven the cordage and mast, When, a
                            wreck on the billowy waters, We were driven before the rude blast: And when night, with her
                            shadowy pinions Had shrouded the billows in gloom, And despair, with her skeleton ringer,
                            Had shown us a watery tomb ; On the crest of a wave, like an arrow, We swept o'er the foam
                            of the reef, And high on the sands were stranded, And found the rude wreckers' relief. I've
                            shared in the homes of the wealthy The solace of pleasure and ease; Have sought, in the
                            marts of the city, And tasted whatever could please. In books, in the lore of the ages, I
                            have passed many years in review ; Have traced in the life of the nations Esteem for the
                            pure and the true. But, alas ! for the poison of passion ; Alas ! for the virus of wrong ;
                            It lurks in the shade of the forest, It stalks in the camps of the strong ; It hides in the
                            halls of the mighty, It festers in dungeons of crime ; It poisons the life of the million,
                            Its reign is coeval with time. We forge, in the fires of passion— In our habits of pleasure
                            — a chain Which must, link by link as we forge it, Be worn out in a furnace of pain. We may
                            soar with the flight of the eagle, Or sweep with the wind o'er the wave ; Seek repose in the
                            shades of the forest, Or renown in the ranks of the brave ; May delve in the lore of the
                            scholars, Or mingle with men in the mart: But happiness — earnest of heaven — Dwells alone
                            with the pure in heart. North Union, 0.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Active faith" TEIform="index"/>ACTIVE FAITH</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ervin, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>ANNA ERVIN</byline><p TEIform="p"> The Apostle James tells us that faith without works is dead; but by works is faith made
                            perfect. Jesus taught a system of salvation from all sins. This was his mission; he had no
                            other; and the question that arises now in my mind is this: Are his teachings as important
                            at the present time as when he first expressed them ? I think they are; and though aware
                            that this subject might be treated elaborately, I think the few remarks which I shall offer
                            will be sufficient to show that activity of the faith of Christ is requisite to our final
                            salvation. " For what doth it profit though we say we have faith and have not works"
                            correspondingly ? That faith which saves, prompts us to holy action; and through the
                            activity of the Christian faith only, is our salvation wrought. The Apostles taught the
                            necessity of an individual activity of faith ; not a simple reliance on the love and
                            goodness of another, without entering into the spirit thereof, and practically imitating
                            such goodness. Faith is not the wind which makes the wave ; it is the swelling, moving,
                            onrolling undulation itself—a heavenly force prompting the soul to a righteous activity.
                            This germ is planted in the soul by a divine hand and having been fostered by understanding,
                            fed by experience, nourished by knowledge, out- of this germ comes faith, strong, succulent,
                            constantly filled with the sap of divine revelation. And out of faith like true children
                            from holy parentage is born, Love, Peace, Joy, and Trust.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spring" TEIform="index"/>SPRING</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, Catharine" TEIform="persName"/>CATHARINE ALLEN</byline><p TEIform="p"> We read of ancient nations that held annual celebrations at their spring season; who went
                            forth in grand, and solemn procession to greet the fresh glories of earth. At this glad
                            season, we also go forth in one communion to walk in pleasant places. Is it in recognition,
                            or imitation of their rites, and customs ? or simply in response to our own love of the
                            beautiful, to hail the power of the risen sun, and hearken to the mingled voices of new
                            forms of life, which springtide, glowing in magnetic light, hath brought forth from the
                            bosom of hoary winter ? The woodland hills outstretched in ever varying beauty, and babbling
                            springs that course onward, winding like silver threads through the green valleys below ;
                            the tender grasses <pb n="102" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 102 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. and perfumed flower,
                            answering sweetly to the smile of sunny skies, and robing the turf in beauty, the opening
                            blossoms, waving boughs in promise of future harvest, are all objects of rejoicing, and
                            worthy of our gratitude. But are we not prompted by deeper motives, and is not our tribute
                            of praise for higher objects ? These withering beauties—the tangible effects of evolution's
                            hidden forces—are not only shadows of realities, more perfect, but they are emblems of our
                            own resurrection ; and while we consider the wonderful transformations of matter, under the
                            action of the material sun, it seems appropriate for us to review the changes wrought by the
                            sun of the Spiritual universe. Peering through the long dim vista of time, we note the
                            period when its dawn barely lighted the horizon, and commenced its developing work upon the
                            crude elements of mind then existing. Its course has been onward and upward. Organizations,
                            nations,and empires have been brought forth, and, like the successive seasons, have had
                            their births, bloom, fruitage and decay; each time enriching the soil of humanity for
                            superior growth. Not only do we perceive that nations and empires, politically and socially
                            considered, have passed through these changes, but from the light which gleams upon us from
                            antiquity, we are shown that above and encircling all, are great cycles of spiritual
                            progress, marked by the onward course of the soul of all illumination, the Christ orb, whose
                            energizing radiance has ever operated on the mind of many to develop and define. Upon its
                            orbit of supernal brightness, as on that of the material sun, are marked the degrees of its
                            cycles, corresponding to the seasons of earth. The divine influx, pouring like a flood upon
                            humanity, ere long will reveal that knowledge of principles, in which the entire past will
                            become luminously visible, and the future appear as present. Then shall the years of
                            spiritual progress be numbered, as Astronomers and Geologists count the years of time. Even
                            now the signs are being read by leading minds of all classes. Great agitations and upheavals
                            of earth, storms, famine and pestilence, are known to have connection with comets, eclipses,
                            and other unusual occurrences in the planetary systems. A similar relation exists between
                            spiritual forces, and the revolutions of kingdoms, and upheavals of mind, from which
                            continual change is wrought. Previous to the divine influx, in which every religious revival
                            the world has ever known, has had its origin, and been maintained—till new organizations
                            spring forth —has been a wintry season of infidelity and spiritual dearth, in which thinking
                            classes have reasoned themselves out of reason into cold intellectual philosophies,
                            containing scarcely a gleam of spiritual faith; and the masses clung to old forms, and
                            lifeless effigies which had once represented a living worship. That this chill season of
                            spiritual inertia has long spread its gloom over earth, is sadly felt by many; but there is
                            much to cheer and encourage. It has been a natural and needed rest to the soil of humanity,
                            in which vital forces have been concentrating, which will soon burst forth in a beauty and
                            grandeur, never before equaled. Already we feel their throbbings, and are fanned by mellow
                            breezes. The air is rife with inspiration, and the voice of prophecy tells of a glad future.
                            New fountains of life will be unsealed, and the tree of Immortality put forth its " leaves
                            for the healing of the nations." A deeper, broader religious revival than has ever before
                            visited the children of earth, comprehending the very soul of science and philosophy, shall
                            descend in sunshine and shower, from the spiritual spheres, bringing many needed reforms in
                            Civil Governments and in physiological habits. Then shall the nations rejoice in the
                            youthful beauty of New Heavens, and New Earth, and worship God in a well-ordered life. Mt.
                            Lebanon N. Y..</p></div2><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ann Lee: her work, her people and their critics, twelfth paper" TEIform="index"/>ANN LEE. HER
                            WORK, HER PEOPLE AND THEIR CRITICS.Twelfth Paper.</head><p TEIform="p"> John Hocknell was, financially, the staff upon which Mother Ann's little society <pb n="103" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 103 leaned for temporal support during their emigration
                            to, and colonization in, America, as he was the principal in the founding of the Shaker
                            institution in this country. John Hocknell was a native of Cheshire, in England ; a very
                            respectable character, and possessed of considerable property. Religiously speakiug, he
                            first became a member of the Methodist society ; but, on witnessing the superior gifts and
                            power of the spirit manifested in the society of James and Jane Warldley, he became a
                            convert to their faith, and was baptized into the spirit of their dispensation of light and
                            power, which was the ripening fruit of the French-prophet manifestation of the work of God.
                            As Ann Lee became a leading spirit in that society, John readily embraced the increasing
                            light manifested through her, who subsequently became the acknowledged leader and Mother of
                            the little society. In deportment he was very meek ; and was greatly gifted in visions and
                            prophecies concerning the future of the work of God among this little band of spiritual New
                            Lights and their converts. Among other precious gifts which John possessed in a remarkable
                            manner was the gift of healing for the physical body. He sailed for America with Mother Ann
                            Lee, and the little band with her, defraying the expenses of the journey. On their arrival
                            in New York, August 6th, 1774, John Hocknell, accompanied by William Lee (who soon after was
                            entitled Father by his adoring followers), went from New York up the Hudson river to select
                            a location for the founding of a society ; this was fixed a few miles south-west of the
                            confluence of the Mohawk and Hudson rivers, in a place called by the Indian name of "
                            Niskayuna," meaning " good maize, or corn land." He purchased here a small tract of
                            wilderness land, located in Albany county, New York State, and about seven miles north-west
                            of Albany city. Soon after this John returned to New York and embarked for England, to bring
                            to America his family, and make further arrangements for the settlement of Ann Lee's little
                            society in this country. On the 25th of December, 1775, John Hocknell, with his family,
                            arrived in Philadelphia, accompanied by John Partington. From Philadelphia they proceeded to
                            New York, where they found Mother Ann Lee. They continued in that city until the following
                            February, then went up to Albany by land. After the opening of the river in the spring, they
                            went down the river to New York to bring up their chattels. On their return to Albany,
                            Mother Ann joined them. Soon after their arrival in Albany, John Hocknell and some others of
                            the society proceeded to " Niskayuna," where they commenced clearing the land John had
                            purchased, and preparing for a settlement by erecting suitable buildings and making other
                            necessary provisions. This was accomplished in the course of the summers and winter of 1775
                            and 1776, insomuch that the members of Mother Ann's small society who still stood faithful
                            in obedience to the principles of the new light they had embraced, in the month of
                            September, 1776, found a residence together, in the wilderness of the town now called
                            Watervliet near Niskayuna. The financial burden of this enterprise was borne by the devoted,
                            sainted Brother John Hocknell, to whom the little infantile society thus far owed its
                            fortunes. He remained steadfast in the faith and principles of the Gospel of Christ's Second
                            Appearing, and faithful to its behests unto the end of his earthly pilgrimage, which took
                            place on the 27th of February, 1779, aged 76 years. It was really a gigantic task for a man
                            73 years of age, and still burdened with family cares, to leave his native land, and
                            emigrate to a new world, 3,000 miles distant, and make a new home in the wilderness,
                            comparatively distant from human society, waiting and working in faith for the development
                            of principles which should introduce upon earth an order of the Kingdom of Heaven, but the
                            growth of which, on earth, he did not survive to witness. In this man's life we have a
                            sample of consecration to God of life, time and treasure greatly to be admired and honored,
                            but equaled by few. His heroism and godliness merit an imperishable record in the memory of
                            all the followers of Mother Ann Lee, till time shall end. Some souls imagine they make great
                            sac- <pb n="104" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 104 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. rifices for the Kingdom of Heaven's
                            sake, who never leave their country, home, treasure, nor friends, but simply yield their
                            time and services to the genuine Christian Cause; let such bestow honor where it is due,
                            and, by the example of their peers, learn to be humble and unassuming; this is true loyalty
                            and dignity.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cometh a blessing down" TEIform="index"/>COMETH A BLESSING DOWN</head><p TEIform="p"> Not to the man of dollars, Not to the man of deeds, Not to the man of cunning, Not to the
                            man of creeds, Not, to the man whose passion Is for the world's renown, Not in form of
                            fashion Cometh a blessing down. Not unto land's expansion, Not to the miser's chest, Not to
                            the princely mansion, Not to the blazoned crest, Not to the sordid Avorldling, Not to the
                            knavish clown, Not to the haughty tyrant, Cometh a blessing down. Not to the folly blinded,
                            Not to the steeped in shame, Not to the carnal minded, Not to unholy fame, Not to neglect of
                            duty, Not to the monarch's crown, Not to the smile of beauty Cometh a blessing down. But to
                            one whose spirit Yearns for the great and good ; Unto the one whose storehouse Yields the
                            hungry food; Unto the one who labors Fearless of foe or frown ; Unto the kindly hearted
                            Cometh a blessing down.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wealth" TEIform="index"/>WEALTH</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="White, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>ANNA WHITE</byline><p TEIform="p"> How prone is the human heart to trust in uncertain riches. When we see men of influence and
                            wealth, who, by regal authority, extend their possessions over broad acres, and " go down to
                            the sea in ships," heavily laden with commerce, to do business on a large scale "in-deep
                            waters," men are apt to think, and say, surely money is power, and is it not the key to
                            happi?iess ? Let us trace the Rothchilds, the Stewarts, the Astors and Vanderbilts through
                            their trade and traffic — by which they have accumulated their vast wealth—and watch their
                            restless spirits during the midnight hours. When the honest tiller of the soil is quietly
                            resting in the arms of Morpheus, what care and deep concern drive sleep from their eyes and
                            slumber from their eyelids! Scheming speculators—who are planning to get the greatest amount
                            of labor and profit from their dependents, with the least return—are they happy ? They eat,
                            drink, display their expensive equipage and apparel, and have' their merry pastimes ; but
                            the conscience, their accuser, speaks in accents strong and clear, " God is thy Judge ! He
                            sees and knows the secret intent of the heart; at His tribunal the account must be settled !
                            " Still they accumulate more and more, till the sun of life to them sets, never more to
                            rise. What have they to take with them to the land of souls ? Where is their treasure ? They
                            must go just as they are, leaving their earthly possessions behind them, without a spiritual
                            inheritance there ; being destitute, blind and naked, they are vagrants in that land ; else
                            they must cling to their ill-gotten possessions here, and see them waste away in the hands
                            of others, while they are powerless to act; and that will be their torment — create for them
                            a hell. How unwise to "trust in uncertain riches, that will surely take to themselves wings
                            and fly away ? " Goodness of heart is preferable to material wealth or worldly popularity.
                            Virtue is immortal—it never dies ! It forms a robe for the soul that will not wax old; but
                            increases in lustre, and grows whiter with age. A virtuous, unspotted life is the only sure
                            passport to heaven and happiness, here and hereafter. If all should heed the injunction of
                            the Apostle, " Let no man seek his own, but every man another's wealth," poverty, suffering
                            and selfishness would flee the land. Righteous laws would be enacted and established by wise
                            and just rulers. No rich landlords to be feared; no poor tenants to be turned penniless into
                            the street; no disputes and wranglings over contested wills ; no <pb n="105" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            SHAKEK MANIFESTO. 105 crafty speculators ; no magnificent temples of worship that would
                            debar the least of God's children from entering, and no hired priest to speak smooth things
                            to the people. 0, for a return of the pentecostal spirit, which would create equality and
                            true wealth ! a stupendous monument of wealth ! Not of polished stone, nor costly marble of
                            artistic beauty and wealth — these soon crumble into dust — but that wealth which comes of
                            right doing, of truth, of purity, of honesty and integrity, and all those noble excellent
                            and beautiful attributes that constitute the life of a Christian. Slowly, but surely,
                            through faith and selfdenial, so journeying home-bound pilgrims wend their way up the rugged
                            hills of progression, each day earning a little more than they spend, which is borne by
                            kindly, angel hands, and placed to their account in the spiritual treasury, where it is
                            secure from moth, rust and thieves. What rejoicing of spirit with spirit, when the journey
                            is ended — the conflict ceased, and welcome voices are heard : " Enter into rest—thou hast
                            well done ! " Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers on usury" TEIform="index"/>THE SHAKERS ON USURY</head><p TEIform="p"/><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="John A. Lant: Esteemed friend.— Four postal card was received by to-day's mail..." TEIform="index"/>John A. Lant: Esteemed friend.— Four postal card was received by to-day's mail...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Ohio, Lebanon, April 7,1879" TEIform="index"/>Lebanon, Ohio, April 7,1879</dateline><p TEIform="p">[From the Liberator.] <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">John A. Lant: Esteemed friend.— Four postal card was received by to-day's
                                        mail. I return my thanks for the same. You write : I would be pleased to have
                                        your explanation in the matter of Interest. Your coupon was the first I ever
                                        held, and I felt condemned. In regard to your condemnation for holding an
                                        interest coupon, I would suggest that you would counsel with your wife and get
                                        her judgment. Men sometimes become alarmingly squeamish on such subjects, and
                                        can be greatly benefited by opening their feelings to a sensible woman, and the
                                        man is generally safe in following the course given. In regard to interest, I
                                        have no defense of it to offer. It is like land monopoly and kindred evils,
                                        which, as we progress in goodness and justice, we will gradually out grow. Some
                                        extremists, like yourself, may work themselves into a feeling of condemnation
                                        for holding a paltry one-dollar coupon, just as some of the Abolitionists would
                                        not use cotton cloth or sugar, because it was the product of slave labor. I
                                        always respect such men, but doubt the wisdom of their sentiments. The evil of
                                        monopolies is that they are used selfishly. If you set up a monopoly where the
                                        poor and the rich are alike benefited by it, then its objectionable features
                                        disappear. I belong to a community where the poor and the rich are alike
                                        benefited by the coupons that might accrue on a thousand or ten thousand a year,
                                        or any other amount of thousands of dollars. Some years since, during the
                                        crusade against whisky shops in this State, our people became interested in it.
                                        One good Elder would not sell his barley to the buyers (and he had a large
                                        quantity), and the consequence was. his family came to want. His taxes were to
                                        pay, and no money to meet the payments. If that man had been allowed to go on in
                                        that way, disaster would have ensued, not to himself alone, but to 45 or 50
                                        others. Others took a more practical view of the situation, and declared we were
                                        in a period of the world's history that, to exist, we had to own land, work for
                                        a living on it, and even raise enough from it to pay taxes on it; and this we
                                        could not do in any other way than by selling part of the crop to do it. Nay,
                                        friend John, I don't believe the efforts of a single, obscure, individual will
                                        amount to a feather's weight to cure the interest evil, any more than the
                                        efforts made by the poor Abolitionist to destroy slavery, when he refused to
                                        wear a cotton shirt, because the slave picked the cotton away down in Alabama.
                                        But when judgments got ripe and the war was inaugurated, that was the kind of
                                        reasoning that slave owners could respect ; and so it will be in regard to
                                        interest on money.* There is no greater curse resting on civilized nations at
                                        the present time than the CURSE OF USURY —and all kinds of interest is usury.
                                        Every interest at the pres* <pb n="106" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> ent time is feeling1 the
                                        effects of this evil, as every person of common sense will understand. And the
                                        remedy may come slowly, but it is sure to come ; and those who have the most of
                                        the filthy lucre will be the deepest in their wail, because their treasures do
                                        not any longer bring them in the desired dividends. You may think by what I have
                                        written that we are wealthy, and have bonds by the quantity. Such is not the
                                        case, however. We, as a Society, it might be said, are neither too rich nor too
                                        poor. We have lands and houses, and if we don't get to be too lazy, we need not
                                        come to want, for we can always get a good living from the land, if they don't
                                        raise the taxes too high to pay the interest on the State and other debts. Now,
                                        friend John, I have written three times as much as I intended to when I began,
                                        but am not well versed in the art of condensing my ideas, although I have that
                                        continually in mind when writing, especially to a man of your profession.
                                        Wishing you a long life, plenty to do, and the reward of a good conscience, and
                                        a comfortable home, I am ever your friend, Wm. Reynolds.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Liberator" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit></p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Reynolds, William" TEIform="persName">Wm. Reynolds.</persName></byline></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">This is a personal opinion, and is not acceptable to the ministry for which, refer.—
                            Ed.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker spiritualism" TEIform="index"/>SHAKER SPIRITUALISM</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p">SHAKERISM. What is it ? It is the God government of to-day. There has always been a God
                            government and a God people, in each day of human history. Cotemporary with such government
                            and closely associated ? therewith, there has always been a Christ Order—a Prophetic Order.
                            While the God people conserved the good of the preceding revelation, the Christ people led
                            on toward the promised land bf ultimate abstract goodness and truth. These are the
                            conservative and progressive ^forces of humanity, ever present, always operative and
                            evoluting, as seasons in the physical elements, succeeding each other to make up the year
                            —spring, summer, autumn, winter—each coming to a final end, as it were. So is it •with
                            cycles in the spiritual elements of human progression. What could be more like the end of
                            all things than our present winter ? The thermometer at zero, the store of food, wheat and
                            potatoes, being rapidly consumed. We have on hand so much store, and no more. It lessens
                            every day. What shall we do ? Nothing can be raised, not a cabbage, an onion nor a kernel of
                            corn. We are saved by our faith, knowledge, hope and assurance, derived from former
                            experience in the earth elements. SPIRITUALISM. Is it not by Spiritualism that we come in
                            rapport with the denizens of the inner spheres, who have, by their extreme age and long
                            experience in the Spirit world, attained the same knowledge of cycles that we possess of the
                            seasons ? By faith, we may possess ourselves of their knowledge, derived from their
                            existence in the Spirit world, and confirmed to us by our knowledge of the histories of the
                            earth, that give us the experience of past generations added to our own. This is the basis
                            of our hope and confidence in the future, and hence we have a well-grounded expectation that
                            another earthly year, with its successive seasons, will open to us in the spring. There are
                            a Heavenly Father and Mother, interior to all existencies, elementary and personal, a
                            fountain and source of spiritual knowledge and affection to rational beings. " He, that made
                            the understanding, shall he not know? the ear, shall he not hear? the eye, shall he not see
                            ? " She, that is Love, shall she not love all souls of which she is the primal mother ? The
                            origin and history of the Jews may stand as a fair specimen of how the God people, in each
                            race of men, originated, and also of the Christ, or Pophetic Order. Out of the millions of
                            earth, the God Jehovah was appointed, by the God above, to choose Abram as a seed of a new
                            people—a God people. That people possessed the germs of all the lusts of the flesh and of
                            the mind of the Gentile world ; and they had all the virtues, gifts and graces of the Christ
                            sphere, to learn and acquire. <pb n="107" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 107 In a dream,
                            God spake to Abram — " Get thee out from thy kindred and country and thy father's house,
                            into a land that I will show thee." Thus giving him a new location, to make it easy to break
                            off old associations. " I will make of thee a great nation, and I will bless him that
                            blesseth thee, and curse him that curseth thee, and in thee shall all the families of the
                            earth be blessed." How? The Redemption Order is a medium of spiritual influence to all
                            mankind. Through it, the Spiritual resurrection Sun snines upon them. Where is the
                            philosopher who can estimate the value of one day of sunshine upon our earth, or the loss
                            that the deprivation of its rays, for twenty-four hours, would be to the race? So, when
                            there is no vision — no heavenly sunshine — the people perish. Thus waa a communication
                            between jthe two spheres established, Now the dream is good and the vision very pleasant,
                            like the spiritual manifestations of our own day and time, but what was the practical result
                            ? Abram did depart as the Lord had spoken. He went down into Egypt and lied about Sarah,
                            unto Pharaoh, who reproved him.— Gen. 12. He went to war, and after his slaughter of the
                            kings — Gen. 14, 15 — was met by the Christ Prophet, Melchesidek, who became this
                            instructor. And now we have the two orders, the God man, and the Christ Prophet, who
                            received from Abram, tithes of all he possessed. Abram was blessed by the Prophet. The less
                            is of the better blessed. Abram's generative line culminated in Jesus, the son of man, and
                            Melchesidek's line of Christ Prophets culminated in John the Baptist, who also made Jesus a
                            priest after the order of Melchesidek. Abram's spiritual education began with a dream, the
                            lowest form of spiritual communication. It ended with materialization, the last and highest
                            form of communication to Israel.— Gen. 18. As he sat in his tent door, three men stood
                            beside him. He ran to meet them, bowed according to eastern custom, and invited them to
                            partake ofjhis hospitality. He washed their feet, baked some cakes upon the hearth—'wheaten
                            Johnny cakes — caught and killed, and dressed and cooked a calf. His war spirit and flesh
                            eating went together, from which the Prophets only would redeem him. At the Lord's Supper,
                            there was no calf, no selfish table, no war, no generation. Jesus had become a Prince of
                            Peace and a celibate communist. It had taken two thousand years to accomplish that process,
                            and then only by a dispensation, as new to the Jews, and affected by as new a spiritual
                            manifestation and revelation as was that of Abram to the people of his day. And just where
                            we are to-day, is at the opening of the Second Cycle in a new Dispensation. But, .to
                            continue our narrative, when Abram and Sarah had dressed the calf, baked the cakes and set
                            butter and milk before them, Abram stood by them under a tree, and they did eat, just Jike
                            non-materialized, born men eat, and it helped their materialization. Then they promised to
                            Abram and Sarah a child — a son — under the same law of materialization. And the Lord said,
                            "Abram shall become a great and mighty nation, and all the nations of the earth shall be
                            blessed in him." How shall they be blessed, if not in changing from what they are, to what
                            they should be — from the natural to the spiritual ? What are these changes 1 Two more
                            materialized men appeared unto Lot in the gate of Sodom, and the men and boys of Sodom saw
                            them and called upon Lot to bring them out. Then the angels rained upon Sodom and Gomorrah
                            brimstone and fire. The Jews were to be saved, by their God, from evils that other nations
                            were not saved from. Their righteousness, of the stomach, of the reproductive powers, of the
                            affections and of property, was to exceed that of all other people upon the earth. Dietetic
                            lusts were first noticed. Five kinds of animal food — kine, sheep, goats, pigeons and doves
                            — was the limit to begin with, and no animal food at all was to be the end of the spiritual
                            training and travail, then commenced with Abram. Generative lusts were taken in hand and
                            circumcision instituted. The true signification of the rite has not been understood by
                            Gentile Christians. The God man Jew was to be cut off from the lusts of generation and to
                            use marriage <pb n="108" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 108 THE SHAKES MANIFESTO. for procreation only — while
                            the Christ man Jew or Prophet, was to be cut off entirely from generation itself—as were
                            Melchesidek and John Baptist — thus making two orders of people, in the Mosaic, as well as
                            in all other Dispensations, like Jacob and Esau. Wars and fightings have no place in the
                            Christ order. They originate in the slaughter of animals and in the eating of their bodies.
                            In the Jewish order property lusts were curtailed by the land being owned by their God and
                            not by the people. Slavery could not exist beyond seven years, and debtors had faith in the
                            Sabbath-day — the seventh year. Thus, while in the natural order, there would have been
                            neither sickness nor poverty, in the ^spiritual community of goods, is ended all the trouble
                            growing out of capital and labor. But what has all this to do with Shakerism? Its beginning,
                            history and apparent decline 1 It has much to^do with it, for it is the New Dispensation,
                            wherein, under the law of evolution, inherent in humanity, the two orders — natural and
                            spiritual— are rising higher and higher, like two parallel spiral shafts, each cycle
                            accomplished in an upward as well as a circular movement. The Shaker order, formed by
                            converts from orthodox Christians, and the United States Government, formed by converts from
                            the orthodox infidels or skeptics, are the- New Heaven and New Earth in the first cycle of
                            their evolution. Each of them has six more cycles to pass through before they shall reach
                            the state where there shall be no more curse in either order, and all shall be peace — an
                            endless peace. In the New Earth, the laws of food, generation and property will be obeyed by
                            women and men as one. Co-operation will prove the love of neighbor to be godlike, whereas,
                            in the New Heavens, community will prove that its adherents love one another, and that each
                            one seeks another's wealth, not their own. The error, in both orders, has been the same. The
                            common people generally supposed that what was only the beginning of the New Earth— The
                            American Republic— and the New Heavens — the first cycle of the Shaker order — were, in both
                            cases, the ultimate. The sovereign American people were all men, and they not only held land
                            as property, but monopolized it like Joseph in Egypt, and owning the land, they owned the
                            people, including the women. The believers believed the first cycle, with its testimony
                            against generation and private property, was the whole gospel and the whole testimony of
                            Christ's second appearing— just as the child believes that its toys and joys and trials are
                            a perpetual inheritance. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Risen with Christ" TEIform="index"/>RISEN WITH CHRIST</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName"/>WM. H. BUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p">There is an apparent contradiction in some of the teachings of the Apostle Paul, which to the
                            casual reader seem like utter confusion. To the same Christian church he writes, "You hath
                            He made alive together with Christ," and again, "Ye are dead, and your life is hid with
                            Christ in Grod." To those who are "in Christ," however, there is, in fact, no confusion,
                            whatever may be said of the language used to express actual conditions. The novice in
                            masonry should understand the language and ceremonies of the degree into which he has beea
                            initiated ; the master mason should be familiar with all its degrees. "Art thou a master of
                            Grael and knowest not these things ? " conveyed reproof, because the "master" should have
                            understood himself what he professed to teach. "We speak wisdom to those who are perfect,"
                            that is, who have been thoroughly instructed. The various states in the individual life are
                            paralleled in external or physical nature and in all human history. <pb n="109" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/>
                            THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 109 Says the poet, Wordsworth, " The child is the father of the man."
                            Says Paul, "When I became a man I put away childish things." There is here no contradiction
                            in fact. From the child comes the man and the perfect angel. Forms and conditions change,
                            the individual remains. Once was chaos, then came order ; first the savage, then the
                            civilized state ; the animal, then the intellectual ; the sensuous, then the spiritual.
                            Perfection appertains to the Creator, necessarily; imperfection to the created. When it
                            becomes possible for the creature to love as God loves, then the creature becomes perfect.
                            This Jesus enjoins upon His disciples "Be ye perfect as your Father in heaven is perfect."
                            But this is a state not to be gained at once, by progressive steps alone it is attained. "I
                            press toward the mark." "That I may attain to the resurrection from the dead." Thus did
                            Paul, pursuing the course that Jesus pursued before him. Thus he arose "with Christ." Jesus
                            arose, not from the tomb hewn out of the rocks, merely, but from all those human conditions
                            in which he was "made like unto His brethren," from which all must rise ere they can be
                            partakers of the divine life. He arose from the death of prejudice. The wall intervening
                            between himself as a Jew and the Gentiles he broke down utterly. "Love your enemies" was
                            enjoined upon all His disciples. The great prophet of olden times called down fire from
                            heaven to consume his enemies. This later and greater prophet declared that His mission was
                            to save men's lives and not to destroy them. Thus Jesus died to all prejudices, whether
                            individual or national, and thus He arose and entered into the glory of His Father, the
                            glory of universal and everlasting love. So must all His disciples die with Him, and so must
                            they rise. They must die to all vices and rise to all virtues. They must ultimately die to
                            every form of disease, whether bodily or mental, and live in the enjoyment of perfect
                            health. They must die to every kind of ignorance that hinders the perfect action of the
                            reasoning powers, whether pertaining to human or divine matters, and be able finally to see
                            all truth as God sees it. Thus alone will they live the life of God. This is the
                            resurrection and the life of Christ. If any one has a religion, a philosophy or a science
                            superior to this, the Christian can afford to let him enjoy it.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spiritual chemistry" TEIform="index"/>SPIRITUAL CHEMISTRY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Devyr, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/>CECELIA DEVYR</byline><p TEIform="p">It is said that of " the earth God created man ;" and certainly there are many of its
                            elements to be found in his anatomy at this day (microcosm that he is), and we might well
                            think that the breath which made him a living soul was a combination of the spiritual
                            conditions of every thing that existed in the heavens above, and on the earth below, and in
                            the waters of the earth. A person who deals with things as well as theories, will tell us
                            that two substances, or conditions, that are opposite to each other, may be united by the
                            introduction of another element, which will not make them like itself, but will so transform
                            and be transformed as to leave no trace of what any of the three were originally. There are
                            two great opposing forces which oper- <pb n="110" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 110 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. ate
                            on the soul. The natural, which is of the flesh, and destroys the life of the soul, and the
                            spiritual, which is of the heavens, and destroys the life of the flesh. Whenever I meditate
                            on their workings, I think I am studying spiritual chemistry. And why am I not ? If natural
                            fire can resolve material substances back to their first principles, and make new
                            combinations, cannot the gospel fire also analyze the soul — destroy whatever is worthless
                            or pernicious in its composition, and in course of time re-create it ? The gospel is, to us,
                            at least, the regulating and developing power of God. If we come fully under its influence,
                            it will so soften and blend our feelings in ourselves, and with each other, that we shall be
                            like the instrument of a master-hand, which the musician never fails to discover, because of
                            harmonies. The ancient mythologists recognized every passion and feeling as a separate
                            spirit, and represented them as gods and demons. Poets, philosophers and all other inspired
                            persons have likened the soul to every thing, from the boundless universe, yea, from God
                            Himself, down to the ear of corn or the blade of grass. The similarity between the earth and
                            the soul is very clear. Both, in a natural state, are either sterile or yield good and bad
                            plants together. And they mostly bear leaves. Fruits are the reward of culture. The soul is
                            a curious gift — self-contemplative, sensitive, affectionate, having as one of its
                            attributes an assurance of immortality, and yet affected by and attracted to earthly things,
                            ever ready to shrink from its own mercies, and forget that " The high suffering which we
                            dread, A higher joy discloses. Men saw the thorns on Jesus' head, But angels saw the roses."
                            Truly the gospel comes like a living spirit to help us to govern and cultivate our souls. If
                            we are faithful, rich will be the harvest of our lives. But if we do no worse than neglect
                            our privileges, and idle our time, the summer will pass, the harvest will end, and we, like
                            the barren fig tree, shall have " nothing but leaves." Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>EDITORIAL NOTES</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Key-note of our religion" TEIform="index"/>THE KEY-NOTE OF OUR RELIGION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We purpose, by the preaching of Shakerism, to keep in view of the world two prominent
                                testimonials, and to proclaim these in language so simple, plain and unmistakable that
                                "he who runs may read " just what we mean. First, our testimony against sin; in this, we
                                have the sympathy and aid of the whole theological world. This testimony objects to the
                                breakage of any of God's laws, regardless of the class to which they may be classified.
                                There is but little controversy among all the churches as to what sin is, in its general
                                signification. But we find the great stumbling-block, in the way of Shakerism being
                                acceptable to the majority of professedly Christian people, to be its renunciation of
                                the good, as well as the bad of the world. Herein is the key note of Shakerism found;
                                and herein is thought to be found sufficient cause to call us fanatical and unreasonably
                                provoking in our testimony. The rule of a Christian life should be, to live separate,
                                not only from the bad, but of the good of those living unlike Christ Jesus. To follow
                                Cheist, then, is the rule ; and who does so is a Christian. " To follow me/' said the
                                great Apostle, "as (far as) I follow Christ; " and the following of any other pattern is
                                unchristian, Peter, Paul or Apostles to the contrary, notwithstanding. We plead our
                                cause, for the resurrection of the life of humanity now ; for the copying of a life
                                superior to the good and best worldly lives ; and Christ's life being that life,
                                    aitoxint<pb n="111" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. Ill our model, the key-note to
                                Shaker ism is found in the denial and renunciation of every thing not in accordance with
                                that life as a pattern. </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="As ye would" TEIform="index"/>As ye would</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">NOTES. —President Hayes is worthy the thanks of all heavens for the just and merciful
                                position he acts from, when dealing with the Chinese. While so many intriguers with
                                policy are seeking selfish ends at the government's capital, it is an assurance that
                                America is not God-forsaken, nor likely to be, while R. B. Hayes stands at its official
                                head. And what a shame it is, that the names of so many brilliant political lights of
                                both parties (and particularly shameful for the Republicans), were recorded in favor
                                that "the heathen Chinee must go ! " May the President and his counselors give us as
                                practical illustra tions of the golden rule while dealing with the Indian question.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Living issue" TEIform="index"/>The Living Issue</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">It is clearly apparent to every thinking individual that secta rian bigotry and the lines
                                of theological separation are being dissolved by that better religious element — Common
                                Sense,— and men are looking above the mists of mere denominationalisms to see who is
                                living the best, most Godly life. The living issue is to take precedence of mere
                                profession; while his theology is right, whatever it is termed, whose life is righteous
                                ? If Christ's life is the standard, the theology which teaches and demands a similar
                                life of us is the correct one; and before it, let empty theological professions
                            vanish.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home mission work" TEIform="index"/>Home Mission Work</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">While The Manifesto is the intended medium of evangelizing the world, according to
                                Shakerism, and to be a missionary athwart our United Societies, we would kindly inform
                                these that recent communications to this office, from genuinely sin-sick souls, are
                                burdened with the inquiries pertinent to " the broth erly love and bonds of faith" among
                                us. Unless we can present the most convincing proofs that we have something better to
                                live for than can be found anywhere else among the churches ; and give positive
                                assurances that we are " raised from death unto life, because of our love to the
                                brethren" it were better we ceased the circulation of The Manifesto until home missions
                                were in the most sucessful operation. Brethren, we are being watched ; and let the
                                result of the watching result in the conviction that we have the love of God manifested
                                in our love for each other.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker life" TEIform="index"/>A Shaker Life</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">demands self-denial; more — self-renunciation and Christly substitution. All that we
                                have, which can harmonize with Christ's life, is saved; thus Christ saves us. This
                                self-denialj and renunciation of self are not to be indiscriminately applied, but most
                                consistently applied, for the correction of our selfish loves and lives, and
                                resurrection of the human life up to the divine pattern. Thus, the passionate loves and
                                lusts of the generative, worldly man and woman are lost in a new creation or habitude of
                                life, wherein these selfish considerations are become dead, or, at least, dying in the
                                soul, and upon whose dying ashes there rises the saintly character of unworldly,
                                unselfish Christians—followers of Christ. No lusts ; no selfish ends to accomplish ; no
                                love of the flesh nor of money ; no appetites for the normal nor abnormal habits of the
                                worldling — bat a Shaker, so nearly representing the Christ to the world that the
                                relationship and identity will be easily and generally remarked upon.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bread on the waters" TEIform="index"/>Bread on the Waters</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We are still receiving letters highly commending the contents of our March number of The
                                Manifesto. The beautiful communication of Elder Henry Cummings comes in for the " lion's
                                share " of praise. Since issuing that number we have had more calls for it as a sample,
                                from parties not subscribers, than any other number for months. It is with <pb n="112" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 112 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. laudable pride that we refer our subscribers to
                                the tenth answer in the article, " What shall 1 do to be a Shaker f " in March number of
                                Manifesto, and to be able to assure our friends that the answer to the tenth question
                                has excited large attention and universal admiration, as far as heard from any.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notice: summer boarders" TEIform="index"/>Notice: Summer Boarders</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> In the limits of Harvard Society, situated one mile from Ayer, Mass., is Rural Home,
                                which, considering its contiguity to the Society of Shakers proper, is not only the best
                                opportunity to study the customs of our people, but is, withal, a quiet retreat and
                                delightful resort for rest, or rural pleasures, at very reasonable rates. The people at
                                Harvard and Shirley are models of Shaker polity and high principles. We know from
                                experience, and we recommend Rural Home, for many good reasons, to summer boarders. The
                                editor inserted a short advertisement in April number, which some have misconstrued as
                                intended to imply that the Societies were to become the resort for boarders. We only
                                intended the adv. to raise an honest dollar or two for The Manifesto, and we make this
                                explanation ; and while paying Harvard and Shirley a part of the tribute of which they
                                are worthy, also to say, toe forgive those sensation-loving parties who have so
                                disturbed our valued publisher, if they will make their peace with him. The Societies
                                proper are too commonly overburdened with transient visitors, and we mean all of this,
                                to think of making application for either Summer Boarders or Winter Shakers.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Message of Gov. Talbot" TEIform="index"/>The Message of Gov. Talbot</head><p TEIform="p">of Massachusetts, to the Legislature, has been sent us, and we find it to be a very able
                                State paper, brimful of political wisdom and human kindness. Its many suggestions,
                                offered as amendments to previous customs and laws, are so cogent and desirable as to be
                                a valued document for the Legislatures of other States to ponder over, and could only
                                improve the wisdom of our national legislators.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>TRANSITIONS</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Seaton, Anna" TEIform="index"/>Anna Seaton</head><p TEIform="p">At Enfield, Conn., March 5, 1879, , aged 73 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bowen, Elizabeth F." TEIform="index"/>Elizabeth F. Bowen</head><p TEIform="p">At Shirley, Mass., March 13, 1879, , aged 63 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Jacobs, Lydia" TEIform="index"/>Lydia Jacobs</head><p TEIform="p">At Poland Hill, Sept. 26, 1878, , aged 76 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bangs, Susannah" TEIform="index"/>Susannah Bangs</head><p TEIform="p">Also, on March 21, 1879, , aged 88 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gillett, Maria" TEIform="index"/>Maria Gillett</head><p TEIform="p">At Shakers, N. Y., April 5, 1879, , aged 80, grand-niece of Gen. Ethan Allen, and a
                                    staunch Shaker for fifty years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wallace, Samuel" TEIform="index"/>Samuel Wallace
                                </head><p TEIform="p">At Union Village, 0., April 6, 1879, Samuel Wallace, aged 66 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sharp, Sally" TEIform="index"/>Sally Sharp</head><p TEIform="p">Also, Eldress , aged 80 years, so long known as the leading authority of feminine
                                    government in western Societies, being one of the bishops for many years, was
                                    translated from earth April 7, 1879.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Blake, Francilla" TEIform="index"/>Francilla Blake</head><p TEIform="p">At Alfred, Me., , aged 35 years. " An irreparable loss."</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prentiss, Shubael" TEIform="index"/>Shubael Prentiss</head><p TEIform="p">At Shakers, N. Y., April 14, 1879, , aged 75 years.</p></div4></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Received" TEIform="index"/>RECEIVED</head><p TEIform="p"> From N. A. Briggs, $6.00. From E. Myrick, $11.00. From Otis Sawyer, $12.00. From Wm.
                                Wetherbee, $20.00. From Chas. Clapp, $24.80. From S. W. Ball, $5.00.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>The Children's Grotto</head><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Son of the wishtonwish" TEIform="index"/>SONG OF THE WISHTONWISH</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sproat, Granville T." TEIform="persName"/>GRANVILLE T. SPROAT</byline><p TEIform="p"> The Indians1 believe that, after death, the spirits of their friends often assume the
                                appearance of beautiful birds, and visit their former abodes, to comfort and cheer with
                                their songs, the loved ones left behind them. The whip-poor-will (wishtonwish), is the
                                bird whose form they often take, as it loves to sing in the still hours of night, when
                                the spirit is calm and undisturbed by the cares of the day, and can best appreciate its
                                loving and friendly mission. I come, I come from the Land of Souls— The beautiful spirit
                                land ; Where the friends you love, in their white canoes, <pb n="113" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                                SHAKER MANIFESTO. 113 Glide over the silvery strand. Where the forest with singing birds
                                resounds And the skies are bright and clear ; And the summer breeze to the sun god
                                sings, Through all the festal year. I come from the friends you have loved so well— The
                                noble, just, and true ; All day they sit on the shore and wait— They sit and wait for
                                you. They sit beside the billowy sea, And gaze across the main ; They long to clasp you
                                in their arms, And. feel your hearts again. Last night I sat by their wigwam fires, And
                                heard the children sing;2 Their merry laugh and shout arose From all that joyous ring.
                                Oskinawa, the young, was there, And Ahkawainze, old ; And strong and brave were the
                                songs they sung; And many a tale was told— How Manche Manito, the strong— The spirit
                                that fought with good, Once swept the red men all away, By the waters of a flood. How
                                the adventurous beaver plunged Into the depths below ; And from the ruins of the old,
                                Caused a new world to grow. 3 How the Great Golden Eagle bore The dying maid away; And
                                from them sprung a better race, And made of purer clay. 4 'Twas thus they sang in the
                                land of Souls, And I heard their songs afar — Now chanting the deeds of the Mighty One—
                                Now singing the songs of war. I joined in the great Metawa dance,5 With spirits noble
                                and true ; How many were the prayers they said, And often they thought of you. They
                                worshiped Keche Manito, The mighty and the strong. The warriors worshiped before him
                                there, With dance, and shout, and song. I went with the fishers, as they sailed Out on
                                the summer sea, Where Wahbishkego dwells below—6 The sportive and the free. Old Keche
                                Nodin did not dare Disturb the billow's crest, 7 Or ruffle even the softest down That
                                decks the sea-bird's breast. I went with the hunter, o'er the hills, And where the
                                prairies lay ; Where the moose, and elk, and wild deer rove, Through all the sunny day.
                                His bow was bent, his arm was strong— How swift his arrows fly ! 'Tis the Good Spirit
                                marks their course, And guides them with his eye.8 There lives great Meno Manito— The
                                wise, the good, the high ; His windows open to the south, To hear his children cry. 9
                                His heart is warm, and longs to take His wandering children in ; 'Tis like the sun, that
                                shines on all, Though worn, and sick with sin. I come, I come from the Land of Souls—
                                The beautiful spirit land ; From forests resounding with singing birds; From prairies
                                open and grand. I come from the friends you love so well— The good, the pure, the true ;
                                And this is the song I sing, and this The message I bear to you. 1 The Indians of the
                                North-west, with whom writer resided from 1834 to 1846. 2 The Kehegoamahgade —
                                story-tellers of the tribe, gathered the children around them during the long winter
                                evenings, and by the light of their wigwam fires relate to them the famous exploits and
                                brave deeds of their ancestors. They use for illustration pictures, or hieroglyphical
                                writing, preserved on rolls of birch bark. Many of them are very ancient. The children
                                learn to sing the songs, and repeat the famous deeds of their ancestors with great
                                delight. 3 The Indians believe that Manche Manito, the Great Evil Spirit, destroyed the
                                world with a flood. The Good Spirit, Meno Manito, in the form of a beaver, plunged down
                                to the bottom of the waters, and brought up stones and earth, from which he made a new
                                world. 4 When the waters had covered the highest mountains, the Great Spirit flew over
                                in the form of an eagle. There was only one person left alive, and that was a maiden
                                just expiring. The Great Spirit bore her away on his wings to the new world he had just
                                made, and from them two, sprung the race of red men. 5 The Metana, or sacred dance of
                                the Indians, is performed in a wigwam open at the top; for they say that the Great
                                Spirit wants to look right down into the hearts of his children, without any covering.
                                It is built by the women, with fir boughs ranged along the sides, and an entrance at
                                each end. It is long and narrow, and large enough to accommodate 50 or 60 worshipers. On
                                the day appointed, the tribes assemble and seat themselves within—the men on one side,
                                and the women on the other side of the place of worship. The singers and musicians stand
                                at either end. They keep time in the dance to the sound of the drum and rattle, while
                                the singers chant the praises of Meno Manito, the Good,and Keche Manito, the Great
                                Spirit. They give him thanks for all his mercies. It is he who gives them success in
                                hunting and fishing, and gathering the harvest of corn and wild rice i nto their
                                wigwams. He gives them strength to worship before him. He gives them power to dance. And
                                this they do with great earnestness—dancing, and leaping and whirling with their hands
                                extended—the palms downward, and their feet close together, keeping time to the sound of
                                the drum and rattle. Toward the close, the aged priestess of the tribe comes, and,
                                laying her hands on the heads of the worshipers, as they kneel, blesses them for their
                                zeal in the dance. Although it has continued for many hours, they often show no signs of
                                fatigue; the Great Spirit, they say, breathes upon <pb n="114" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 114 THE SHAKEE
                                MANIFESTO. them from his window in the south, and strengthens them. They close with a
                                feast of thanksgiving—the food being brought in kettles, and presented to each one In
                                order, in bowls of wood or bark, as they sit ranged along the walls of the wigwam. 6
                                Wdhbishkego—the beautiful white fish—the favorite food of the Indians of the great
                                lakes. Its flesh is white and delicate, and it lives only in the clearest waters. 7
                                Keche Nodin—the Spirit of the Wind. He is a very strong spirit; but subject to Keche
                                Manito, the greatest and strongest of the spirits. 8 The Indian believes that the Great
                                Spirit points out to him in a dream, the tree from which he is to select his bows and
                                arrows for hunting. This is just as he is arriving at manhood. He is sitting in the
                                wigwam with his father alone. His father orders him to throw all his childish toys and
                                playthings into the fire of the wigwam, and follow him into the forest. He builds for
                                him there a wigwam, paints his face black, places him on a mat in the center of the
                                wigwam, with his face downward, puts a cup of water by his side and then leaves him. He
                                is to fast before the Great Spirit for many days. The cup of water is to be his only
                                refreshment. After many days of fasting the Great Spirit shows him in a dream the tree
                                from which he is to select his bow and arrows for hunting, also the animal he is to be
                                most successful in taking, and which is to be his totame, or family name through life.
                                Thus, and thus only, can he become a mighty hunter. The Great Spirit will go with him,
                                nerve his arm to bend.the bow, and,direct the arrows where to fly. He does all in the
                                strength, and by the direction of the Great Spirit. 9 The Great and Good Spirit dwells
                                in a great house away in the southern heavens, and his windows are open, night and day,
                                that his ear may hear the cries of his children. Canaan, N. Y.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>Home Topics</head><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lime water" TEIform="index"/>Lime water</head><p TEIform="p"> A handy thing to have in the house is a jar or bottle of lime-water. Pour water over
                                unslacked lime (the quantity; is not important, as only a certain amount will be
                                slacked), and cork up for use. A spoonful of the clear liquid stirred into milk, cream
                                or bread sponge in danger of souring, will prevent that catastrophe. It also cleanses
                                bottles, etc., that have an unpleasant odor. A person who needs milk, but whose
                                digestion is so weak as not to manage it, will find no inconvenience if into a glass of
                                the lacteal fluid is stirred a wineglass of lime-water. The difference in taste is not
                                perceptible.</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Molded crushed wheat" TEIform="index"/>Molded Crushed Wheat</head><p TEIform="p">While the boiled or steam crushed wheat is still warm, pour it into molds slightly wet,
                                and let it stand several hours, or until quite cold and loose at the edges ; then turn
                                it out on a dish of corresponding shape, an oval mold on a platter, a round mold on a
                                plate or saucer; if to be dished on the table, use a large mold ; if to be brought on
                                already dished, tea-cup molds, served in saucers with trimmings, look nicely. After
                                cooked wheat is once cold, it cannot be warmed and mashed up with hot water and then
                                molded; long steaming only can restore any of its fluidity, but even then it will not be
                                so good nor mold so readily as when first cooked.</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Floating island" TEIform="index"/>Floating Island</head><p TEIform="p">Heat a quart of milk to the boiling point; stir in the yolks of five eggs, well beaten,
                                and let them cook, while you stir them often, three minutes. Cool and add a little lemon
                                or vanilla. Beat the whites to a stiff froth, and dip by the spoonful into a kettle of
                                boiling water ; and when stiffened lay them over your custard.</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mealy potatoes" TEIform="index"/>Mealy potatoes
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Mealy Potatoes. — Select the potatoes so that they will be nearly of a size ; do not put
                                them into the pot until the water boils. When done, pour off the water and remove the
                                cover until the steam is gone. Then scatter in half a teaspoonful of salt, and cover the
                                pot with a towel. Watery potatoes will thus come out mealy.</p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="One who writes on 'Food for the famishing,' urges the poor to..." TEIform="index"/>One who writes on 'Food for the famishing,' urges the poor to...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">One who writes on " Food for the Famishing," urges the poor to emancipate their minds
                                from the superstition that beef and beer are indispensable. He informs them that a
                                pound£of lentils, peas or beans has as much slaying 'power as two pounds of beef,
                                costing ten times as much.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Meat barrels" TEIform="index"/>Meat Barrels</head><p TEIform="p">We have found a new and good use for kerosene oil barrels. To make a cheap meat barrel,
                                buy a coal oil barrel; knock one head in; take a bunch of old hay, set fire to it, and
                                throw it in the barrel; let it burn until the staves begin to burn; put it out by
                                turning the barrel upside down; scrape the coal off, and you have a|good, sweet
                            barrel.</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Graham bread" TEIform="index"/>Graham Bread</head><p TEIform="p">Three pints of Graham flour; one pint of wheat flour; one cup yeast; half cup molasses
                                and a teaspoonful of salt. Mix with lukewarm water as stiff as you can stir with a
                                spoon. Let it rise over night, and bake in a moderately hot oven. </p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Superb Graham Gems..." TEIform="index"/>Superb Graham Gems...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Superb Graham Gems are made from the following recipe: Take half a pint of Graham flour;
                                half a pint of wheat flour; two fresh eggs; one pint of rich milk ; a tablespoonf ul of
                                salt. Heat and butter the pans first, and then bake in a quick oven.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><pb n="115" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>THOUGHTS FOR TO-DAY</head><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Different lives" TEIform="index"/>Different Lives</head><p TEIform="p">In a letter of a correspondent of the Christian, , London, Eng., writing from Cannes,
                                said: "A skeptical young German said, ' Plead for your Christianity as eloquently as you
                                like, but till I see your professing Christians live different lives frona other men, I
                                cannot believe in Christianity.'" It is indeed the test by which every religion must
                                rise, or fall.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Blessed am de dead" TEIform="index"/>Blessed am de dead</head><p TEIform="p">"I hab hearn," said a colored preacher, while enforcing the duty of liberality on his
                                congregation, " ob many a church what hab died bekase it gib away too little for de
                                Lord, but I neber hearn ob any what died bekase it gib away too much. Ef any ob you know
                                ob any church ob dis kind, what died from liberality, jes tell me where it is, and I
                                will make a pilgrimage to it, and by de soft light ob de pale moon I will crawl upon its
                                mosscovered roof, and write upon its topmost shingle : ' Blessed am de dead what die in
                                the Lord.'"</p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A man who is tricky..." TEIform="index"/>A man who is tricky...
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Clark, Alexander" TEIform="persName"/>Dr. Alexander Clark</byline><p TEIform="p">Dr. Alexander Clark is not mistaken in saying: "A man who is tricky soon becomes a
                                treacherous man, and then no man at all—only the ghost of a dead conscience."</p></div3><div3 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A movement in New York is contemplated to..." TEIform="index"/>A movement in New York is contemplated to...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A movement in New York is contemplated to make all Episcopal churches freeseated, alike
                                for the poor and rich.</p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rest" TEIform="index"/>Rest</head><p TEIform="p">"Doctor, you must really prescribe something for me." " My dear lady, you need no
                                medicine—only a little rest, and then you'll be as well as ever." •' But, doctor, surely
                                I ought to be given some medicine of some sort or other. You've only felt my pulse ;
                                examine my tongue." (He does so.) "Precisely, madam, your tongue needs rest too."</p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Like swans?" TEIform="index"/>Like Swans?</head><p TEIform="p">A Scotch minister thus discoursed on the carelessness of his flock : " Brethren, when you
                                leave the church just look down on the duke's swans. They are very bonny swans, an'
                                they'll be sooming about an' aye dooking doon their heads and laving theirsels wi' the
                                clear water till the're a drookit. Then you'll see them sooming to the shore, an'
                                they'll gie their wings a bit flap an' they're dry again. Now, my friends, you come here
                                every Sabbath, an' I lay you a' ower wi' the gospel till ye're fairly drookit wi' it.
                                But you just gang awa' hame, an' sit doon by your fireside, gie your wings a bit o'
                                flap, an' ye're aa dry as ever again."</p></div3><div3 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Arbitration vs. War" TEIform="index"/>Arbitration vs. War</head><p TEIform="p">The cost of the armies and navies of all the nations which call themselves civilized,
                                amounts to a thousand million dollars each year, in times of peace. In order that these
                                nations may assume a defensive attitude and be ready to protect their rights, or assault
                                the rights of some other nation on slight provocation, five million able-bodied men are
                                taken from the active producing portion of the people, and a burden of twelve dollars
                                per year is laid upon those who remain at work, for the support of standing armies and
                                navies. When wars occur the expense is, of course, greatly increased, and burdens of
                                debt contracted which require years to wipe out.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Colds, so-called" TEIform="index"/>Colds, so-called</head><p TEIform="p">It is rare indeed that a person catches cold if decent regard be paid to dress. So
                                marvelously is Nature prepared to guard against even violent changes of temperature when
                                the individual is " in condition." A celebrated physician relates a fact in his
                                experience of a certain family — nearly every member invariably had a cold in the head
                                after dining on roast goose, a dish of which they were especially fond. Dining there one
                                day he observed how they caught their colds. He was the only one at the table that was
                                not helped twice, and, strangely enough, the only one that escaped a cold. Many
                                scrupulously careful people, about dress, are continuallv suffering with the complaint
                                in question, when, if they were as considerate as to what they put in the body as to
                                what they put on they would be exempt from this, as well as many other troubles. When
                                the stomach is disordered, bowels closed, the system completely clogged, and headache,
                                running at the nose, fever, lameness, weakness and lassitude, give warning of a fearful
                                reckoning near at hand, the poor, self-abused victim wonders how he caught such a cold,
                                or <pb n="116" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 116 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. very likely fancies he can remember
                                just when he caught it—like the old lady, when fairly at a loss for an exciting cause,
                                attributed her last cold to taking gruel out of a damp basin. I cured one of the worst
                                cases, where all of the above alarming symptoms were well marked. The cure was complete
                                in twenty-four hours, and without one drop of medicine. A sponge bath was ordered at
                                bed-time, another in the morning ; no breakfast was allowed, in spite of the gnawing at
                                the stomach, which was appeased by small draughts of cold water, one-fourth the usual
                                dinner, and a single slice of bread and butter with a cup of weak tea for supper, pure
                                air throughout the day, sponge bath at bed-time. Simple enough, certainly. The result
                                was a good night's rest, and an awakening in perfect condition. It is safe to assert
                                that 90 in the 100 of these colds might be as speedily cured, instead of having their
                                usual run, while this treatment would prove the most effectual in every case, and if due
                                care be taken they may be still more easily prevented.— From Page's Good Health.</p></div3><div3 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let chinee stay" TEIform="index"/>Let Chinee Stay</head><p TEIform="p"> The Chicago Tribune reports a conversation with an intelligent Chinaman named Chan Pak
                                Kwai, on the subject of anti-Chinese legislation. He denied many of Senator Blaine's
                                assertions, and said : " There are hundreds and thousands of families in Cliina where
                                the family ties are as sacredly kept as among the whites ; and, under the influence of
                                the mission schools and Christianity, they are increasing every year. The charge that
                                the Chinese do not assimilate with Americans or adopt their manners and customs is also
                                false. They are slow to accept the policy of brickbats and cobblestones, it is true. You
                                must remember that they are completely ostracized. If a Chinaman marries a white, woman,
                                the first thing is to kill him. Still they have married white women, and established
                                good homes. They are not allowed to attend the public schools, nor to have public
                                schools in their own quarters. What education they get of American ideas, manners and
                                customs they must get by observation or in mission schools. If you will give the
                                Chinaman the privilege of stuffing ballot-boxes, he will probably put on American
                                toggery and cut off his queue. The Chinaman's queue is his badge of nationality. With
                                it, he is a subject of the Chinese government, and under its protection. If he cuts off
                                his queue, puts on pantaloons, and adopts American manners and customs, he is
                                denationalized., and ceases to be a Chinese. But the American government will not admit
                                him to citizenship, and he therefore becomes a waif without a nationality. He,
                                therefore, prefers to wear a queue, and be the subject of some government. I once cut
                                off my queue, put on American dress, adopted your manners so far as I was able, and,
                                after fifteen years' residence, applied to the government for citizenship, and was
                                denied. I then put on my queue and Chinese costume, so that I might belong to some
                                nation. If the American government would admit to citizenship a Chinaman when he had
                                acquired the English language, adopted the customs of your people, and established a
                                character for honesty and integrity, thousands are now ready to cut off their queues and
                                become American citizens."</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>Agricultural</head><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Carding cattle" TEIform="index"/>Carding Cattle</head><p TEIform="p"> " Whilst horses are carefully groomed and brushed," says the London Agricultural
                                Gazette, " cattle are entirely neglected; and in such a state they cannot thrive or do
                                as well as they would in a state of cleanliness. Look at a lot of cattle when released
                                from their bonds, and they find a rubbing post, or, when they approach each other, and
                                in bucolic language say: " Lick me and I'll lick you. The offer is seldom declined. When
                                they are bound their efforts to get something to rub against and allay the itching are
                                something pitiable to see. I remember the case of a bull which, for some time, would not
                                permit me to approach him in his stall. Beginning with a rub and a scratch on the rump,
                                I at each visit extended the scratching, and now if I omit the operation he shows
                                unmistakably his disapprobation. Nothing pleases him better than the application of a
                                hard <pb n="117" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. 117 brush, and he exhibits in a
                                variety of ways his pleasure. I have tried him with food of various kinds, by having
                                them put before him, but he will not touch any of them until the rubbing down is
                                finished."</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Keep them clean" TEIform="index"/>Keep Them Clean</head><p TEIform="p">The Maryland Farmer (Baltimore) reminds farmers that " a good rubbing, brushing and
                                cleaning of the hair of cattle, horses and even hogs is equal to or better than a hearty
                                meal. Keep all stock free from dirt and filth. Rub or wash off all mud from horses' legs
                                before going into the stable for the night. Keep the cattle dry and free from the mire
                                and muck of the barnyard. To do this the yard should be well littered, and thereby the
                                manure-pile will accumulate."</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cure of dry teat" TEIform="index"/>Cure of Dry Teat</head><p TEIform="p"> A correspondent of the American Jersey Bulletin (Judge Beer, of Bucyrus, 0.), writes to
                                that journal: « * * "when she calved last year she lost one of her hind teats, and gave
                                no milk from it during the year. * * I had noticed in the Country Gentleman (March 7,
                                1878, p. 155), that Dr. Home prescribed fluid extract of scoke root (Phytolacca
                                decandra). I gave it internally and applied it externally, beginning ten days before
                                calving. It had a marked effect from the first. The cow had commenced ' making bag'
                                before the medicine was used, in the three sound quarters only. Immediately after its
                                use the other quarter began to develop, and at the time of calving (December 2) was
                                nearly as large as the others, and continued growing until it became so, and yielded as
                                much milk as the rest. The cure is perfect." [Dr. Home's directions are: Ten days or a
                                week before calving, give one drachm of the extract in one ounce of rain-water,
                                increasing to two drachms, and rub on a little of the same a day or two before and after
                                calving—rub in hard. On no account allow the cow to become plethoric. — Ed.
                            Manifesto.</p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Care of the orchard" TEIform="index"/>Care of the Orchard</head><p TEIform="p">"Young orchards should be cultivated and manured for the first ten years, when they will
                                bear good crops if properly handled," wrote M. C. Baldwin, of Chemung, N. Y., in a
                                letter to the Elmira (N. Y.) Farmers' Club, on the management of orchards. For twenty
                                years he left the wormy fruit that dropped from his trees on the ground, when the apples
                                became so wormy and small that he was obliged to change this practice. For the past
                                three years he has turned in sheep and hogs; they have eaten the drops, and, he thinks,
                                destroyed the worms. For trees that need cultivation he throws manure or coarse mulch
                                around them, and the hogs root it up and turn it over and over again until it is
                                thoroughly mixed. He stacked his stalks and coarse fodder, and fed all in the orchard,
                                and also draws coarse manure there, such as tobacco stalks, straw or mulch. Leached
                                ashes is considered first rate, and a little lime is pronounced beneficial. The result
                                is, that his fruit is clean, free from worms, smooth and handsome, and the trees bear
                                great crops. President Hoffman said that many of the orchards of Western New York are
                                treated as Mr. Baldwin treats his. Mr. Barry thinks that the ravages of the coddling
                                moth are materially lessened when pigs and sheep have been allowed free run. Joseph
                                Harris, he believed, also approved of this practice. Some farmers leave their orchards
                                without cultivation, but keep the surface of the ground well scarified by using sharp
                                drags freely. If the land is set with grass, President Hoffman had no doubt but that
                                good results would follow such treatment.</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Most of the diseases of cattle are caused by wrong treatment..." TEIform="index"/>Most of the diseases of cattle are caused by wrong treatment...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Most of the diseases of cattle are caused by wrong treatment — too much feed at one time,
                                too little at another; too rich at one time, too poor at another, etc. If all the cattle
                                and horses were fed and watered and used properly, there would be little disease.</p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To clear cistern water, add two ounces of..." TEIform="index"/>To clear cistern water, add two ounces of...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">To clear cistern water, add two ounces of powdered alum and two ounces of borax to a
                                twenty barrel cistern of rain water that is blackened or oily, and in a few hours the
                                sediment will settle and the water be clarified and fit for washing, and even for
                                cooking purposes.</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The liquid yieldings of animals..." TEIform="index"/>The liquid yieldings of animals...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The liquid yieldings of animals are worth more—good authorities say one-sixth more —pound
                                for pound, than the solid excrements, and are saved with greater care by the best
                                European farmers and gardeners. All the leaks in the stable are not in the roof; those
                                often in the floor are quite as objectionable, and are the cause of a great deal of
                                waste.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><pb n="118" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Only a little while" TEIform="index"/>ONLY A LITTLE WHILE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="White, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>Anna White</byline><p TEIform="p">Mount Lebanon, N. Y. 1. Only a little while tarry I here, Work lies before me as 2. Pleasant
                            the journey, tho'constant the strife, Rich the reward of a 3. Hasten, O hasten, while time
                            doth abide! Sow ye at day break year follows year. Up and be doing lest the night close
                            around, And virtuous life. God will repay with a bountiful hand, His and fair even-tide. Sow
                            by all waters, till the truth shall increase, And darkness prevail where light should
                            abound. Only a little while goodness extends o'er ocean and land, many embrace the gospel of
                                peace.<pb n="119" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 119 Repeat Softly. I have to stay,
                            then with the angels I'll away, away.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Book Table</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life of Benj. F. Butler" TEIform="index"/>Life of Benj. F. BUTLER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bland, T. A." TEIform="persName"/>T. A. Bland</byline><p TEIform="p">by Lee and Shepard, Publishers, Boston, Mass. Worthy to be read by every lover of his
                                country. " Speak of me as I am; nothing extenuate, nor set down ought in malice." We are
                                not politicians ; but when Congress, the President, and all leading officials of
                                Government, tender thanks and grateful acknowledgments to an individual for very
                                important and valuable services rendered our nation, it is wise for individuals to read,
                                become informed, and reflect, before passing censorious criticism. We know B. F. Butler
                                much better for the reading of this little work; and he has our much larger respect for
                                the knowledge.</p></div3><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New testament" TEIform="index"/>The New Testament</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Rotherham, Joseph B." TEIform="persName"/>Joseph B. Rotherham</byline><p TEIform="p"> translated and critically emphasized, by , is among the invaluable publications of the
                                day. We feel sure that the author has exercised much care and intense critical judgment
                                in preparing, in its correctness, this literal version from the original Greek, for the
                                benefit of all English readers. We are also made aware that it has been the
                                conscientious motive of the author to assist in particular manner that class of people
                                who would reach Apostolic Writings with as little conventionalism as possible; and to
                                this class, of which we are sure there are many, we are pleased to recommend this work,
                                feeling sure it will prove an unparalleled assistance to the study of The New Testament.
                                Indeed, we think there could be no more valuable addenda made to the library of every
                                theological student; and we believe it not extreme to say, that this work should be in
                                the hands of every Bible Scliolar. Its merits are beyond exaggeration. The second
                                edition is certainly an improvement upon the first, its modes of expression having been
                                cautiously softened without loss of exactness ; while a superior neatness graces its
                                pages. We feel an exceedingly warm pleasure in introducing this very valuable work to
                                our readers, and direct them to correspond with John Wiley and Sons, Publishers, 15
                                Astor Place, New York.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mullein as a cure for consumption" TEIform="index"/>Mullein as a Cure for Consumption</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A correspondent writes as follows about the flower of a well-known plant: "I have
                                    discovered a remedy for consumption. It has cured a number of cases after bleeding
                                    at the lungs had commenced and the hectic flush was already on the cheek. After
                                    trying this remedy to my own satisfaction, I have thought that philanthropy required
                                    that I should let it be known to the world. It is common mullein steeped strongly
                                    and sweetened with coffee sugar and drank freely. Young or old plants are good dried
                                    in the shade and kept in clean bags. The medicine must be continued from three to
                                    six months, according to the nature of the disease. It is very good for the
                                    blood-vessels also. It strengthens and builds up the system instead of taking away
                                    the strength ; it makes good blood and takes inflammation away from the lungs. It is
                                    the wish of the writer that every periodical in the United States, Canada, and
                                    Europe should publish this recipe for the benefit of the human family. Lay this by
                                    and keep in the house ready for use."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Lexington press" TEIform="index"/>Lexington Press.</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="120" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Important functions of the skin" TEIform="index"/>IMPORTANT FUNCTIONS OF THE SKIN</head><p TEIform="p">Looking at the complicated mechanism of our bodies from a popular standpoint, we should say,
                            perhaps, that the brain is the most important part of us ; but that would be a mistake; not
                            only the brain, but the stomach and kidneys are less necessary to life than our skin.
                            Reflect upon the matter for a moment ; you can go without food for several days and not
                            suffer serious injury; your liver may cease to act for a week, and you can attend to your
                            business as usual; the brain may be paralyzed for months, and life goes on ; but if the
                            functions of the skin are suspended for two hours, death follows. Take a dog or cat, and dip
                            the animal into melted parafflne or tallow, so that the skin excretions and secretions are
                            suspended,and the animal will die almost as quickly as if ten grains of strychnine had been
                            administered. The skin is a most important auxiliary to the lungs in the process of aeration
                            of the blood, and so intimate the connection, or so similar and important are its functions,
                            that when death ensues from skin obstructions, all the conditions resemble those occasioned
                            by cutting off air from the lungs. More deaths from consumption are caused primarily by skin
                            obstructions than from any original weakness or disease in the lungs. The lungs are the
                            first of the important organs to be influenced by derangements of the skin, and they often
                            become congested or disorganized through secondary causes.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The burning of Michael Servetus" TEIform="index"/>THE BURNING OF MICHAEL SERVETUS</head><p TEIform="p">" When he came in sight of the fatal pile, the wretched Servetus prostrated himself on the
                            ground, and for a while was absorbed in prayer. Rising and advancing a few steps, he found
                            himself in the hands of the executioner, by whom he was made to Bit on a block, his feet
                            just reaching the ground. His body was then bound to the stake behind him by several turns
                            of an iron chain, while his neck was secured in like manner by coils of a hempen rope. His
                            two books—the one in manuscript sent to Calvin in confidence six or eight years before his
                            strictures, and a copy of the one lately printed at Vienna were fastened to his waist, and
                            his head was encircled in mockery with a chaplet of straw and green twigs bestrewed with
                            brimstone. The deadly torch was then applied to the fagots flashed in his face, and the
                            brimstone catching, and the flames rising, wrung from the victim such a cry of anguish as
                            struck terror into the surrounding crowd. After this he was bravely silent, but the wood
                            being purposely green, a long half hour elapsed before he ceased to show signs of life and
                            suffering. Immediately before giving up the ghost, with a last expiring effort he cried
                            aloud, ' Jesus, Thou Son of the Eternal God, have compassion upon me !' All was then hushed
                            save the crackling of the green wood ; and by and by there remained no more of what had been
                            Michael Servetus but a charred and blackened trunk and a handful of ashes." Thus perished a
                            noble man of whom liis age was not worthy—the victim of murderous, religious bigotry. But
                            the crime that had been committed shocked the humanity of Geneva, even in the dark period,
                            and before the year was out Calvin was driven to self-defense, and displayed the remorseless
                            traits of his character by libeling the man whom he had slain. It is said that in this
                            persecution unto*death he only manifested the spirit of the age, and must be judged by that
                            standard. While this may be true, it is also happily true that in the lapse of centuries
                            better standards have arisen, by which the character of Calvin will be given to execration,
                            while that of Servetus will be increasingly honored as that of an heroic Christian martyr.—
                            Popular Science Monthly,</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Do we act thus" TEIform="index"/>DO WE ACT THUS</head><p TEIform="p">It is certainly wrong to talk of a member's faults behind his back, with a view of injuring
                            him. If you have any thing to say about his faults, go to him like a Christian, and tell him
                            all about it, and if he is the person he ought to be, it will do him good. It does no good
                            to talk of a man's faults behind his back, nor is it right. Such things ought not to be
                            allowed in any congregation that wishes to retain peace and harmony, nor should any,
                            professing the name of Jesus, permit himself, or herself, to drift into such a sinful
                            practice. </p></div2><!--
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <pb id="p29"/>
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] </p>
                    </div2>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>