<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0608" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shakers, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">6</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">8</biblScope><date value="18760801" TEIform="date">August 1876</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">57-64</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="6" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="57" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="8" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">THE SHAKER Official Monthly.—Published by the United Societies. WHAT IS TRUTH ? "THE ETERNAL
                        RKIL,I&gt;rQTTISIIM:EN-T OF ERROR." Vol. VI. G. A. LOMAS, EDITOR. SHAKERS, I L AUGUST, 1876. N. A. BRIGGS,
                        PUBLISHER. No. 8.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Estimation of character" TEIform="index"/>ESTIMATION OF CHARACTER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Butler, Matilda A." TEIform="persName"/>MATILDA A. BUTLER</byline><p TEIform="p">It is quite too common for us to pass judgment, with a freedom unbecoming, on our confiding brother, sister or
                            friend, we not seeing the living springs of their hearts, nor hearing the reasonings of their minds' inner
                            depths. "In olden times, justice was meted out by the sword, the spear avenged the wrong, and the lot decided
                            the right." The condemning waters still roll, and we wait not to see what the end will be, but determine the
                            right or the wrong, by the issue of failure or success. " Count no one more evil because he is unfortunate;" for
                            the blessing of a better heart does not always lie in the sunshine of prosperity. Chastisement, not less than
                            reward, proves the good Father's love to his children. In looking at our fellow beings, we say, who can pass
                            righteous judgment? such an one is holy and accepted, and such an one is reprobate and doomed ; there is so much
                            of good among the worst, and so much of evil in the best, that looking a little deeper than the surface, it is
                            hard to pronounce one a saint, and condemn another as a sinner. Our character is the complex of all that we
                            love, and we never love any truth or make it our own to live by, until our aifections are first fastened upon
                            it. The love that is so strong, can be no superficial sentiment, but an inward element of the heart. Admitting
                            love to be an intense and all-pervading power, the very life of our souls, the importance of training ourselves
                            to love only that which is pure and true, at once becomes manifest. And so long as we are at liberty to take
                            care of our own character, and grow it to the highest principles of truth and virtue, we are not dependent on
                            reputation, which is a kind of earth robe, and like the leaves of the tree, worn only in suitable seasons. "
                            Character, not death, is the end of life." We die not, all our deeds remain, to crown with honor or to mar with
                            shame. Our character is just what we make it; our reputation is made by others for us, and is always liable to
                            discount, if not entirely counterfeit. True it is, accidents may modify, circumstances may control, externals
                            may change it, but still it is the same; the map of the face and picture of the eye are traced by the pen of
                            passion. A knowledge of ourselves gives us power ; in the exercise of this we consider our failings, search out
                            our latent virtues, cultivate the good and crush out the evil. Ignorance of self is the symbol of idolatry,
                            while a love for the upright and noble will cause us to stand up and battle valiantly for the truth, fearless of
                            ridicule, for this is a weak weapon when leveled at a strong mind. It takes years of untiring zeal to grow into
                            the genuine characteristics of the higher life. " Science may be learned by rote." Wisdom can only be learned by
                            experience," and it is sad to reflect that " experience " is only an elegant term for suffering ! In the great
                            battle of life its triumphs rarely compensate for the wounds they inflict, still it is a battle that must be
                            fought, and the winning is worth the sacrifice. No one ever attained the heights of virtue without a bold,
                            daring spirit of love for self ; far no one ever did a noble deed that did not truly love self. We cannot truly
                            love humanity unless we love ourselves enough to find out in what elements the fruits of good will grow most
                            prolific; itnd here is the field inviting our superior love of self. Character grows, or is formed of all our
                            little deeds ; every act of our lives has a meaning, as every word in the dictionary has a definition. Then let
                            us walk together as friends, giving the hand of fellowship, acknowledging the heart of sympathy, and let not
                            charity be a stranger at the board that is spread for our brother or sister. Let us rise to nobler themes, for
                            the soul hath an heritage of glory, in the majestic character of God. Union Village, 0,</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Centennial smoke" TEIform="index"/>CENTENNIAL SMOKE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fletcher, Richard" TEIform="persName"/>RICHARD FLETCHER</byline><p TEIform="p">The exhibition at Philadelphia affords opportunity for useful moralizing. Since editors have become constant
                            preachers, church attendance is falling off; people read daily sermons and do not go to sleep over them so much,
                            because they call them "editorials." A wide range of illustrations for " texts," is open in the accounts of the
                            present World's Fair. Near Memorial Hall is a beautiful work of art in bronze. It represents a large mortar,
                            used in national, wholesale murders. By the side of the mortar is " an old tar," body bent forward, pointing
                            with full stretched arm to the far distance. On the other side stands an officer in full uniform, telescope in
                            one hand, while the other rests on the rim of the mortar, also watching the effects of the deadly missile,
                            evidently just fired. The group is completed by the figure of a lad, in naval uniform, who has sprung upon the
                            mortar feet hanging across its mouth, shading his eyes with one hand as from the powder smoke. The writer adds
                            that the smoke, although it could not be pictured in bronze, can easily be imagined hanging around, so life-like
                            is the whole expression. Ah ! there is indeed much smoke about such an object, and about many popular customs
                            and systems of society — smoke that hides truth, and needs clearing away. Look at the text again : however
                            skillfully that bronze work has been done, it is a icrong use of art, nothing beautiful or interesting about it
                            to right thinking persons. The artist has worked out sickly ideas of scenes, shocking to common kindness, which
                            all men shrink from taking part in until goaded to a species of madness, simply because false education makes a
                            market among the people for his work. The real actors in such a scene, hidden by smoke, deafened by the thunder
                            of human hatred, sickened by cruel sights, take little relish in telling over details of their worst deeds, much
                            less in bronzing memory's worst pictures and their consciences at the same time, by " works of art" that hide
                            what little love of God there is left in human hearts. If this nation shall live to see its second Centennial,
                            such relics as the exhibits of fire-arms with all the machinery for making murderous weapons, will be looked
                            upon as we look upon an old flint-lock musket of 1776, or upon a hand spinning wheel. And now, if the metal were
                            only the right kind, that casting would look much better in form of plough-shares ; although if it is much like
                            the delicate artist, the material is too poor to honestly turn a furrow. Why is it a wrong use of art ? Because
                            its only result is to harrow up natural sympathy into ragged sorrows, useless, as well as cruel— and about a
                            black, sulphurous smoky business which nations have all to repent of and forget — the sooner, the easier and
                            cheaper. " I will break the bow and the sword, and the battle out of the earth" (Hosea, 2 : 18). Would it not be
                            more truthful, in describing the naval group, to say the sailor has a savage scowl, the officer puts on a
                            terrible squint, the youth looks distressed for want of fresh air, and from the entire expression, all their
                            eager, interested, " artistic " manner would be changed to cursing, if that shot should fail in its deadly
                            errand ? Those metal figures mean nothing if they do not mean interest in destruction, and of what? of property
                            not only, but of human life ! Such interesting feelings can only come from worse than metal hearts, and iron
                            grip of deadly passion. Now, the very fact that such ideas as the above find crowds of admirers, that sad fact
                            is the moral of this article. Pulpit religion befogs large crowds, who pay preachers to expose soul-truths as
                            much as is consistent with popular tastes, and no more. May " The Shaker " keep on clearing away the smoke of
                            human lusts. Of course, those who live in a city do not realize the heavy vapors which outsiders can see
                            settling down like a cloud, hiding the sunlight more or less at all times. So those who breathe the clear
                            wholesome air of sexual purity, do not think but know that false views of our society are held by the citizens
                            of the " old earth " on the plane of the first Adam all in the smoke of their own lusts. SHAKER VILLAGE, III.
                                <pb n="58" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 58 THE Indistinct murmurs arise from their murky valley of delusion about the higher
                            plane. Shall it draw us lower, or shall we not rather strive to shed a brighter light from the highest hill-tops
                            ? However much, nations, sects, families differ, they all agree in the worship of one, likened to a '¦ beast"'
                            in prophecy. Nothing muddles preachers, politicians, collegians, workers and idlers, quicker than flattery of
                            the most corrupt part of our common human nature. iV matter how, whether by costly painting, brilliant writings,
                            almanac wit, coarse slang, or polished pulpit smut, the god of this world brings all classes to one level,
                            groveling in the mud of their earthly natures. They seem to cry, " Great is the universal object of our desires
                            !" Let people murder one another by wholesale, and call it glorious war, let foolish fashions blind our common
                            sense, but let not one single soul refuse to crawl to the lowest level! Strange that they cannot see the beauty
                            of living equal, as with consecrated property and equality of sexes ! Perhaps, from the level of the " old
                            Adam1' plane, Christians (so-called) cannot grasp the idea of a truly spiritual life, nor realize the wholesome
                            love among brothers and sisters in Christ, although they often hear from their pulpits: " In the resurrection
                            they neither marry nor are given in marriage, but are as the angels in heaven." What smoky glasses people look
                            through to see beauty in fashionable dress! Plainly dressed people look so much more healthy and honest by very
                            contrast, that the " stylish " ones, especially the women, look as though they were trying to hide the twisted,
                            distorted souls within ; and they bid fair, before many years, to sin humanity out of its last traces of
                            physical beauty. Sonyea, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="No" TEIform="index"/>NO</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leggett, E. T." TEIform="persName"/>E. T. LEGGETT</byline><p TEIform="p">How many a hell or a Heaven below, Is made by that wonderful arbiter No! Weird child of the doom is that magical
                            word ; Fate bows in submission wherever 'tis heard: How many a soul going lost to the grave, A heart-uttered No
                            would inspirit and save ! How many of desolate hearth-stones there are, This champion word of our language would
                            spare! How little this word, yet a monarch in might! Just born of a breath and a child of the light; How Godlike
                            in meaning! how trenchant and brave! How potent to shield and how mighty to save \ The wealth of the Indies in
                            diamonds and gold, The fame that encircles the brows of the bold, How powerless they to protect us below,
                            Compared to that mighty magician, a No ! How many a hero of field or the flood, With 'scutcheon red-written in
                            letters of blood. That, dauntless, would charge all the furies below, Yet hesitates, falters, recoils from a No
                            ! Thus Eve was beguiled in lost Eden and fell. When Satan wove round her his mystical spell; Her lips faltered
                            yes, while her heart beating low. In vain sought for courage to utter a No. What folly in hoarding the
                            world-worshipped ore, Or delving in darkness for mystical lore; Or seeking high up in the temple of fame, With
                            heroes and martyrs to blazen our name, While lacking that jewel, more precious and rare, Our spirit's sheet
                            anchor, the courage to dare To utter, when sin is enticing below, No half-hearted yes, but a ichole-hearted
                        No!</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If God does not accept our earnestness..." TEIform="index"/>If God does not accept our earnestness...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">If God does not accept our earnestness, wanting as it oftentimes does the necessary liberality, let us learn the
                            lesson. Let us use special care that, in consequence, we do not become luke warm and indifferent to eternal
                            interests of our own, and others' souls.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas" TEIform="persName"/>Lomas</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Flowers" TEIform="index"/>FLOWERS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, G. B." TEIform="persName"/>G. B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p">That Creative Providence made flowers beautiful, and made the eye with capacity to drink in their beauty to
                            contribute to the happiness of his creatures, there is no room to doubt. The poet has truly said, " A thing of
                            beauty, is a joy forever." And, in a true life, the useful and the beautiful are combined. The beautiful is
                            useful, yet in what sense, and to what extent ? A true, Christian, godly life, is devoted to the most important
                            uses. Were the entire time of human society devoted to the culture of flowers only, where were the fruits of the
                            earth to sustain life ? Were the pioneer settlers in a new country to give much time to the culture of flowers,
                            they would perish with hunger, cold and nakedness, nor could they spend much time or strength to construct the
                            merely ornamental in dress or architecture. The most important uses must necessarily engage their attention,
                            time and strength. In this age, the burdens and duties of the Christ life may justly be compared to those of the
                            pioneer settlers in the wilderness; and, to cut down the gigantic forests of human errors, and clear the soil of
                            human society for the planting and culture of those goodly trees bearing the precious flowers and succeeding
                            fruits essential to the strength and sustenance of a godly life, is primarily the duty and burden of the
                            Christian; little is the opportunity to such of cultivating those earthly flowers which contribute their share
                            of bliss to life, only in feeding the desires for earth's beauties. Jesus — the firstJChristian — enunciated the
                            great truthful principle, " The life is more than meat, and the body more than raiment." Yet, without meat and
                            raiment, what would become of the body ? But, all necessary duties should be attended to in the order of their
                            importance ; and those persons called to the highest duties of life,— to such numerous and onerous burdens as to
                            engage all their strength, needing, besides, the strength of myriads more, cannot be justified in spending much
                            of their precious life to mere pleasure ; they must be largely utilitarian. , To them, Jesus' injunction was, "
                            labor not for the meat that perisheth." And, " in those early days" (of Christianity even) when the number of
                            the disciples was multiplied, there was a murmuring of the Grecians against the Hebrews because their widows
                            were neglected in the daily ministration. Then the twelve called the multitude of the disciples unto them and
                            said : " It is not reason that we should leave the word of God and serve tables." * * " But we will give
                            ourselves continually to prayer, and to the ministry of the word," The duty of all the members of the true
                            Christian Church, in this age of the world, is analogous to those of that chosen twelve ; they are called to be
                            kings and priests unto God. We would repeat, all necessary duties should be attended to in the order of their
                            importance. We have known some persons so absorbed in the culture of flowers, they neglected to clean and mend
                            the clothing, and properly prepare the food needed for the family, and to keep clean the house. Flowers, except
                            those precedent to the fruits needful for human support, are secondary in importance, and those persons called
                            to the highest order of life,— the Christian, to be " Kings and Priests unto God " must toil most largely in the
                            field of fruits, both physically, morally and spiritually considered. Such was the field of toil for Jesus;
                            and,in this day, when his true followers — the ministers of light, life and salvation — are so few, such must
                            largely be the toiling field of his true followers ; they must be mostly utilitarian in its boldest and most
                            important sense, rather than in its florid phase.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Two slates—a vision" TEIform="index"/>THE TWO SLATES-A VISION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Child, Henry T." TEIform="persName"/>HENRY T. CHILD, M. D.</byline><p TEIform="p">My eyes were opened to see men and women spiritually, as they moved about on earth ; each one seemed to have two
                            slates, some dark, some light and transparent. One directly in front of them, the other behind. On the front
                            side of the first, in open view, was written the professions which men make, sometimes of religion, sometimes of
                            worldly things, of ambition, etc. I could see that some had many things attached to this, shelves of books,
                            various mottoes, the bible, the creed of their church, so that the world might see all these. The back of this
                            slate was directly in front of their faces, on this they wrote their real conditions, their secret thoughts,
                            generally very different from those on the front slate. They were concealed from the view of others ; instead of
                            their professions, their real lives were written upon this side, and it was within the reach, so that they could
                            change or wipe out what they had written. The other slate was just opposite this, and behind them, arid so
                            arranged that whatever was written on the front slate was reflected upon this, and though it was not seen by
                            all, my spiritual vision was opened and I was permitted to see these duplicate records. There was a purpose in
                            my seeing these, for it was shown me that while they could put out their hands and wipe oft the front slate,
                            they could not reach this. Then I saw a person who was really desirous to have both slates cleansed ; he went
                            down into the valley of repentance and taking up the waters therefrom he washed off the front slate clean ; then
                            he was obliged to go to some one who was qualified to receive his open confession, and show them just what had
                            been written on his slates, not only this, but he was to have an inward and spiritual baptism of repentance, and
                            then the individual to whom the confession was made could dip a sponge into these baptismal waters of true
                            repentance, and wash off all the slates. I saw that when an individual attempted to rub oft the marks on the
                            front slate and was not willing to confess, the marks on the back slate seemed to come out more distinct. I saw
                            how necessary it was for those to whom the confessions were made, to have clean hands, else they might soil the
                            slate with that which was upon them. These slates were representations of the conditions of individuals, and
                            when all the slates were clean and transparent I could read them from every side. I could see that such
                            individuals walked along life's road free, and the angels walked beside them in love. Their lives were an open
                            book to be read by all who had a spiritual vision : and in reading these there was always a blessing, for pure
                            lives are the highest and holiest testimonies ; they bring God and heaven to man, and earth and earthly things
                            are swallowed up in heavenly and divine things. Philadelphia, Pa.</p></div2><pb n="59" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Establishment of harmony" TEIform="index"/>ESTABLISHMENT OF HARMONY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Paine, Thomas" TEIform="persName"/>THOMAS PAINE</byline><p TEIform="p">The height of development is harmony— a diffusion of ideas, without being met by the spirit of opposition,
                            saying, you can go no farther, for the spirit that stirs up thought is accounted the devil's platform of labor.
                            When harmony is established, a just judgment of all the elements that afflict and bless man is arrived at; evil
                            takes the negative platform, and goodness is the predominating result of a term of schooling, in all the
                            branches of godly forethought and purpose, to make man a self-reliant and responsible agent, sent out, after
                            repeated changes, to do the work of world redeeming, becoming like unto Gods, knowing the exact path of duty,
                            and the full and complete law of love. " One by one fall ancient errors, Reared by might and propped by wrong,
                            And earth wonders, when they perish, That they stood the test so long."</p></div2><div2 type="article'" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harmony" TEIform="index"/>HARMONY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName"/>WM. H. BUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p">The term implies a combination of various • parts so as to produce the highest and best possible effects in the
                            whole, — as the strings or the keys of a musical instrument, which, together, may be touched so as to produce
                            melody far sweeter than even a Paganini can call forth from a single one; or the orderly inter-volutions of
                            worlds with worlds, and systems with systems, in the universe, where originate the myriads of beings destined to
                            glory and immortality. Our highest idea of harmony is gained by the contemplation of the Divine Mind ; and, as a
                            matter of course, we regard the state producing the greatest harmony among human beings and in the individual
                            soul, to be that of the completest union with the Divine Mind. The fact is evident enough that, at present,
                            there is inharmony everywhere among mankind, and notwithstanding what has been said or sung of paradises and
                            go4den ages in the past, yet unpoetic history shows us discord throughout its entire length. But we cannot,
                            because of that, impeach the divine wisdom. Its purposes and plans are perfection itself though man is conscious
                            of imperfection in himself and his surroundings. This very consciousness, however, is proof of harmony somewhere
                            existing ; and acts as an impelling power toward its final attainment. All legitimate wants are prophetic of the
                            day of abundance. Harmony in the individual and in communities, is the result of growth, not merely during the
                            period of a single earthly life, but for ages. This is effected by the inspiration of divine life in the soul,
                            gradually unfolding and perfecting all its powers, and the action of the individual upon the community. Divine
                            love is ever active, though not always in the same manner. Often we fail to recognize it, and call it any thing
                            but what it really is. The temperance movement, the anti-slavery movement, the peace movement, are all styled
                            the works of fanatics until the results of years have shown that God's messengers have actually been in them
                            all, and that a grand advance has been made toward the day of harmony. It is utterly vain for us to ignore the
                            divine methods of action, yet how frequently is the attempt made. " I verily thought within myself I ought to do
                            many things contrary to the name of Jesus of Nazareth," said Paul: "I believed the salvation of the nation
                            depended upon my shooting that tyrant," said the murderer of Lincoln. But the beautiful lessons that Jesus
                            taught are still operative, and are likely to affect the hearts of men in all coming ages. The blow struck at
                            the individual life is of but transient effect, that aimed at wrong produces effects eternal in duration. Such
                            is the present condition of mankind, it is impossible there should be entire concert of action in any movement
                            having the general welfare as its object. But no matter. For a time, Jesus stood alone. The disciples were but a
                            " little flock," at first. It is not a cause of reproach that some spend the most of their efforts in behalf of
                            the public upon one object, if that be a good one. Sumner was a man of large culture in many respects, yet he
                            was classed by most persons with the men of one idea. This to him was a matter af no concern, nor to many who
                            listened to his powerful utterances, whether before the senate or the assembled people, all tending to one
                            object — the destruction of the slave power. Though error often has numerous adherents, yet truth never has
                            lacked a sufficient number to advance its interests in the world. That is seed which never perishes, however
                            deeply it may be buried in the earth. It will all finally come to the light and the air. There are some who
                            assert that the efforts of professing Christians are rendered more effective by their division into numerous
                            bodies than if they formed but one. That depends upon what their efforts are tending to. It never yet has been
                            proved that error benefits the world. If all were actually inculcating the same truth there could be no
                            hostilities. A difference in mere organic form might be favorable for different localities and not disturb the
                            essential unity of the spirit. The union resulting from the operation of divine love in thejieart, never yet has
                            been fully exhibited by the various sects toward each other, yet it must be admitted by those who have traced
                            their history, that there is a tendency to ultimate harmony, visible at the present time which has not been seen
                            in the past. Less stress is laid upon peculiar dogmas and more upon the active principles which edify. All minds
                            that clearly see the same truths must agree with respect to them, and all hearts governed by divine love must
                            accord. Through the smoke and dust arising from the contentions of political parties light is visible, greater
                            than heretofore has been seen; individual crimes and national vices may seem to some more numerous than ever,
                            but it is only because the light shines more powerfully, revealing such as once lay hidden in darkness. The
                            tendencies toward national amity may not seem remarkably strong, yet no age has equaled the present in that
                            respect. The earth will yet be glad with greatest joy for the glory of universal peace ; but the day of perfect
                            harmony lies beyond that, when all the powers of the individual shall be attuned to melody and celestial
                            society, though formed in myriad groups, shall possess nothing that will disturb its endless quiet. Sonyea, N.
                            Y.</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Not from political reasons..." TEIform="index"/>Not from political reasons...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Not from political reasons, but from more reasonable grounds, do we think Gov. S. J. Tilden might be the better
                            president: Being unmarried, he has none but the Lord and the people to serve unselfishly — if he could only
                            really do so.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Centennial year" TEIform="index"/>CENTENNIAL YEAR</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webster, Elizabeth" TEIform="persName"/>ELIZABETH H. WEBSTER</byline><p TEIform="p">For what shall this year, the centennial, be known, For what be emblazoned on high ? In the archives of history
                            what laurels be shown, That never can wither nor die? What victory gained o'er oppression and wrong, And all
                            that truth's river dams? What power to enable each heart to be strong, What triumph o'er shoddy and shams? For
                            what shall this year, the centennial, be known, What record of progress be made? Wxhat noble deeds done like
                            sweet flowers strewn, To mark this our greatest decade? Not honor nor riches, not science nor art, Though
                            shining effulgently bright, Can make her page white if she still bears a part In any injustice or slight. Oh,
                            deed the most worthy, if she could but give To all of her daughters so brave, The freedom her sons have, to be
                            and to live, All true to the life which God gave; The treasure of freedom our forefathers won, With a goodly and
                            blessed increase; A freedom for all, beneath its broad sun, Each sex and each nation in peace. Harvard.</p></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Record of a remarkable family" TEIform="index"/>RECORD OF A REMARKABLE FAMILY</head><p TEIform="p">References have been made in The Shaker to the remarkable data connected with the Wells' family, and so many
                            quotations have been made from our paper concerning the same, that we would now correctly put on record the
                            birth and death of each member. Eleven of the fourteen died in this Society — Shakers, N. Y.— leaving only the
                            father, and an infant,* as exceptions to this rule. " He liveth long who liveth well;" but it is a fact, whether
                            commune life is commended better or not than the more contracted spheres, that it tends greatly to longevity.
                            Thomas Wells, born April 27, 1739. Died May 2, 1819. Abigail Youngs, born Feb. 14.1741. Died Feb. 28, 1826.
                            Married April, 27,1766. Seth Y. Wells, born August 19th, 1767. Died Oct. 30,1847. Thomas Wells, born Dec. 6,
                            1768. Died Sept. 33, 1843. Benjamin Wells, born July 1,1770. Died Sept. 30, 1851. Calvin Wells, born Feb. 33,
                            1773. Died March 31, 1853. Luther Wells, born Sept. 3, 1773. Died Feb. 6, 1863. Stephen Wells, born April 18,
                            1775. Died Feb. 33, 1864. Hannah Wells, born July 31, 1776. Died Sept. 1, 1863. Jesse Wells, born March 37,
                            1778. Died March 4, 1876. Abigail Wells, born Dec. 4, 1780. Died Feb. 7, 1830. Anna Wells, born Sept. 34, 1782.
                            Died Dec. 14, 1783. Fregift Wells, born May 30, 3785. Died April 15, 1871. ft * This infant would, Undoubtedly,
                            have lived as long as any of the family, but for an accident of scalding, from the effects of which it died.
                        Ed.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Inevitable discipline" TEIform="index"/>THE INEVITABLE DISCIPLINE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Arthur, T. S." TEIform="persName"/>T. S. ARTHUR</byline><p TEIform="p">" But, painful though the process be, it is the only one through which the soul can ascend to the high and noble
                            estate for which it was born ; and sooner or later, in the infinite goodness that overshadows all, there will
                            come to the life of every man and woman a discipline of sorrow, misfortune or suffering, intended to break the
                            lower, selfish life, so that the soul may turn away from the husks upon which it has been starving, and suffer
                            itself to be led into green pastures and by still waters." ' ¦ Alas for the many that will not so be led ! For
                            the many who sit down in anger or despair amid the ruin of their hopes, crying after their lost delights 1"</p></div2><pb n="60" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="As a spiritualist, I believe" TEIform="index"/>"AS A SPIRITUALIST, I BELIEVE."</head><p TEIform="p">Among the favorable signs of to-day, indicating liberality in extenso, and the acceptance of spiritual truths, is
                            the fact that the secular press have so freely and fairly devoted space to the recent discourses of our dear
                            friend J. M. Peebles, lately lecturing in the Southern States. The Chattanooga (Tenn.) Commercial is before us,
                            and from it we copy the following beauties, only sorry that we cannot present the address entire. Let us read,
                            and inwardly digest the brave words of a courageous soul: As a Spiritualist I believe, In one living and true
                            God — the Infinite Presence of the universe — Wisdom and Love. I believe in Jesus Christ as teacher, mediator,
                            Saviour, accepting Peter's definition (Acts ii, 22), '"Jesus of Nazareth, a man approved of God among you by
                            miracles, wonders and signs that God did by Him." I believe in the Holy Spirit — that it fell upon the apostles
                            — was poured out upon the Gentiles, and is a constantly descending afflatus from the Christ Heavens. I believe
                            in inspiration, a spiritual inflowing from the Divine Fountain. Prophets and apostles, martyrs and poets have
                            been inspired in all ages. I believe in the beauty of faith, the necessity of repentance, and a just and
                            adequate punishment for all sins in violation of law. I believe in heaven and hell, as conditions rather than
                            locations. Depraved, selfish spirits suffer the keenest remorse in the lower spheres. " The Kingdom of God is
                            within you," said Jesus. I believe in spiritual gifts, prophecies, dreams, clairvoyance, visions, trances, and
                            spirit materializations as demonstrating a future conscious existence. In fact this is not belief, but positive
                            knowledge, and thus conditioned, I have obeyed the apostolic injunction, "Add to your faith knowledge." I
                            believe in a natural and spiritual body, and when death transpires, each individual commences the hereafter life
                            precisely as he left this, mentally and spiritually ; but all, there as here, are the subjects of progression. I
                            believe in trying "the spirits," accepting only such teachings as are pure, holy, spiritual and Christlike. I
                            believe in salvation through Divine obedience — through Christ, just as I believe in buds and flowers and
                            harvests through the quickening sunshine. I believe in the church of God, the church of humanity, the holy
                            apostolic church within whose pale may be found purity and peace, spiritual gifts and " all things in common "
                            as upon the Day of Pentecost. This is the living church of Christ enfolding Believers. Touching the moral
                            influence of these doctrines the speaker said that if a demonstration of the soul's immortality, the certainty
                            of punishment, the happiness derived from purity, goodness and holiness, the harmony between religion and
                            science, the conscious presence of ministering spirits, and a continuous baptism from the Christ Heavens, would
                            not tend to better the world he could not conceive what would. Add to this, he said, the fact that none have
                            secrets — God, angels, spirits, know them all. Our souls are as the leaflets of open books, and self-denial and
                            purity of life the only passports to heaven.</p></div2><div2 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Chemical forces of plants and animals, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>THE CHEMICAL FORCES OF PLANTS AND ANIMALS. NO. 2</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL FRASER</byline><p TEIform="p">Bkan is a wonderful article in its power to maintain right conditions for the play of vital chemical affinities.
                            Neither vital nor inorganic affinities can operate except the conditions are right. They are like the spiritual
                            mediums — the conditions must be right, which all who have had spiritual experiences know to be true. Bran has a
                            chemical constitution of its own —has an affinity for, and is retentive of moisture ; it protects the grain from
                            being parched in the soil, and when in the intestines, true to its character, is retentive of moisture there.
                            And from its demulcent nature, facilitates transmission,and from its bulk distends, keeps open the absorbents
                            and lacteals, and normally excites the muscularity of the intestines. Food lubricated with saliva descends into
                            the stomach, and remains there for hours enveloped in moisture, in a temperature above ninety degrees, highly
                            favorable to inorganic decomposition. Why is it that fermentation does not take place ? The answer is, vital
                            chemical affinities take hold and triumph over decomposing forces, and determine the phosphate of lime and the
                            compounds that support combustion to their respective quarters. Such is the power that " triumphs over the
                            causes that induce death." There is a limit to this power, and it varies in the same person. If the barometer is
                            high, we inhale more oxygen, our digestion is better ; hence, the necessity of forming habits of adaptation, not
                            only to the state of our health, but also of the atmosphere. We are somewhat like steam-engines; one is fifty
                            horse power, others only ten. If we exact from the ten what the fifty can barely do, the ten will break down. So
                            with us, if "We take more food than our vital forces can control, then we will have an acid stomach, and if
                            saleratus or soda is taken as a corrective two difficulties immediately appear; the alkaline matter weakens the
                            stomach, and chemically prevents the blood from absorbing the grand digester, oxygen. The true way is, never eat
                            so as to create acidity ; never take, nor put saleratus or soda in any food ; even salt should be sparingly
                            used; food should never taste salty. There is another difficulty about eating too much ; the digestive force
                            with some is greater than the assimilating power; there is a greater now of nutriment to the circulation than
                            can be taken care of. This is a bad state of things. Add to this the foul air of close rooms, and we have the
                            true seed-bed of colds, scrofula and consumption. Never take cold. If you do, give up over eating, lessen the
                            quantity greatly; throw aside all cakes, pies, butter and fats; rub and wash your body vigorously, and so
                            increase the power of assimilation. Open the windows, let in the oxygen, and keep letting it in forever. I see a
                            light in the distance. I read, " There is no need of being sick." We live in the inside of a self-renewing and
                            self repairing house, and all the furniture is self-repairing, even to the shingles which cover it. In young
                            persons the bones, etc., are not only renewed, but increase in size. The old bones are carried off by the
                            excretory organs. All this refuse matter should be saved and applied to the land, and we may have the happiness
                            to eat ourselves over again once or twice. An apple tree was planted near the grave of Roger Williams ; one of
                            its roots invaded the resting-place of the illustrious dead, and the question was raised, " Who ate Roger
                            Williams 1" The tree did, and others ate the apples. In this matter of renewal have we any duty to do? By our
                            food and drink can we faciliitate or hinder the process '? We can ; tea and coffee hinders the renewal; so,
                            also, does superfine flour, and this is a great Avaste of precious wheat — about one-seventh — enough thrown
                            away every week as would supply us with bread for one day. Human progress is slow; let charity abound; bless
                            good exam pies ; be and do the truth. Shirley, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="music" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Music, no. 8" TEIform="index"/>MUSIC, NO. 8</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, J. G." TEIform="persName"/>J. G. RUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p">Time. In treating upon this peculiar division of the science of music, the writer is forcibly reminded of the
                            impression made upon his mind, while taking his first lesson from one of the good old music books of Dr. Lowell
                            Mason (Boston Academy's Collection of Church Music), which instruction ran as follows: — " During the
                            performance of a piece of music, time passes away," etc. So, also, it does, while working or sleeping, was as
                            deep as the musical conceptions seem to run at the time, and hardly as much attention given to the subject as
                            the hungry farmer boy would give, while counting the minutes of the last hour, preceding his summons to dinner.
                            But upon more mature reflection and reasoning, the subject was revealed in clearer light, and the estimation of
                            its importance has in no wise subsided from that time to the present. Now, in the minds of many, who are in
                            search of musical truths, the question often arises, " WThat is the utility of such practical recognition of
                            time in singing?" — to which the answer, in its broadest and general sense, would be to produce harmony of
                            action, without which but little would be accomplished in the way of praise-rendering, through the medium of
                            song. As the praises of the sanctuary are generally through this channel, and that, too — many times—in
                            congregational choruses, it follows, as a matter of course, that unless harmony of action be properly secured,
                            chaotic discordancy is the inevitable result. To enhance, then, the indispensable means, requisite to success in
                            this department of the science, the subject must be considered in all its bearings, with a thorough practical
                            application of the same. The more popular and musical term for time is rhythm, which — in borrowed language —
                            "is the periodical recurrence of accent, the measured beat, which marks the character and live expression of the
                            movement." (Moore's Encyclopedia of Music.) The first prominent feature, discoverable in rhythm, is the variety
                            of length of tone, which variety numbers no less than eight — all of which should be thoroughly understood, and,
                            in general cases, practically regarded in musical performances. Again, it is asserted that tones have no
                            positive length, but are measured, or determined, by a relative system,— a fact which many singers fail to
                            recognize, and, therefore, encounter difficulties not easily removed. For instance, the familiar melody of
                            Hamburg may be written in two different forms, rhythmically (see illustrations No. 1 and No. 2), and yet be the
                            same tune, with no perceptible change in the time, — a thing which could not be done, if the length of tones was
                            positive. It follows, then, that the important point to be gained is to determine accurately the various
                            relative length of tones. The means, thus employed to this end will here be considered by the more popular term,
                            method. As there are various methods for reaching desired results in the science of mathematics, so, likewise,
                            there are various methods for attaining desired results in musical rhythm. But whatever method may be adopted
                            for securing proper rhythm, the fact is conclusively evident that the great superintending agency is <pb n="61" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. 61 the mind ; and if this fails, in its responsible office, the singer is left, as it
                            were, " like a ship without a rudder."— subject, at any time, to be thrown from the proper rhythm, unless guided
                            by a power superior to its own. This is often done by the method, termed " beating time." As far as the superior
                            exercises influence over the inferior, beneficial results may follow this method of time-keeping ; but how much
                            proficiency the musical scholar is acquiring by this course of culture, will clearly be manifest, as soon as
                            left to rely upon his own resource. ' WTithout exaggeration it might be asserted that — in a majority of cases —
                            one-third of the number of singers, composing an ordinary choir, practically fail of preserving proper rhythm,
                            if left without a leader ! But if the mind—. under proper development — performs the task assigned it, of what
                            practical utility would be its subordinate servants, the hand, or the foot, even, in making demonstrations of
                            what the mind, alone, is capable of performing ? As the remaining portion of this topic is better befitting a
                            future number, suffice it, now, to say that if visible motions, whatever, are made by the singer, expressive of
                            sustaining rhythm, they should be most carefully superintended by the mind. ILLUSTRATIONS. FIRST TWO LINES OF
                            HAMBUfSQ. No. 1.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Remarkable fragment" TEIform="index"/>A REMARKABLE FRAGMENT</head><p TEIform="p">The following lines are handed to us by Mr. Frederick E Partington, a student at Brown University. They were
                            given to him at a book-stall in the little, sooty town of Llsuielly, Wales, four years since. The writer of
                            them, a strange looking, shy, retiring girl of eighteen or nineteen years, was pointed out to him by the
                            book-seller as " a dreamer,"' and the village folks called her crazy. The verses were written In 1868, when she
                            could not have been more than sixteen years of age. Considering the place, the time, and the author, we think
                            the lines remarkable. We believe they have never before been published in this country : They cry : "He come? —
                            The signs are sure — all lands are armed for war— The mystic number is fulfilled — He comes ! " We answer: O
                            that he would come! We want The Christ! We want a God to burn the truth Afresh upon the forehead of the world !
                            We want a Man to walk once more among The wrangling Pharisees, to drive the beasts And moueymongers from the
                            temple courts; To bring the Gospel back again, and prove How all unlike the Churches are to Christ! We want that
                            Christ again to tell the "saints " Their sins : that they were sent to bless the poor, And they have sold
                            themselves unto the rich , That they were sent to preach the works of peace, And they have filled the world with
                            war of words; That they were sent the messengers of love, And they have driven love out of their creeds That
                            they were sent to teach men not to lie. Nor tremble when their duty led to death — O for the Christ again ! He
                            —He would dare To tell the Churches how they lie and cant. Ahd talk of serving God — and serve themselves ; And
                            talk of saving souls — to save their " cause ; " And pare and narrow God's divinest truth Until a man can hardly
                            be a man And member of a Church. ******* Already Christ is coming. Hear ye not The footfalls of the Lord? He
                            tramples down The cruel hedges men have built about The gate that leads to heaven. He rends the creeds And gives
                            their tatters to the merry winds. He does not come as bigots prophesy To choose a handful and to damn the rest,
                            To found a Jewish-Gentile kingdom here And roll the world into the past again. He comes the Spirit of a riper
                            Age When all that is not good or true shall die — When all that's bad in custom, false in creed, And all that
                            makes the boor and mars the man, Shall pass away for ever. Yes, He comes To give the world a passion for the
                            truth, To inspire us with a holy human love, To make us sure that, ere a man can be A saint, he first must be a
                            man.</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE SHAKEE. Monthly — 60 cents per annum. A DUAL ADVOCATE OF CHRIST PRINCIPLES.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Unreason of shaker opponents" TEIform="index"/>UNREASON OF SHAKER OPPONENTS</head><p TEIform="p">There was a time when Shakerism endured the sobriquet of disguised impurity cast by persecuting masses. Now, that
                            it is privileged to enjoy the celebrity of unchallenged purity it is sad that a certain respectable Monthly
                            should feel that " the Shakers must be very weak, to be so very good !" It does not surprise us, when people say
                            that the life standard of our principles is an unnatural one — that Shakerism generally adopted, would
                            depopulate the world — these are held to be truths by many honest investigators, who are worthy of, and have our
                            respect. That the Creator made no mistakes in the institutes of nature, we are free to admit; nor feel that this
                            admission encourages only the highest uses of these institutes. The Shakers have a strong, their strongest
                            testimony against the lusts of the flesh ; yet no reasonable Shaker has ever decried marriage or reproduction as
                            unrighteous, per se. That these are misused for most lustful purposes, we do make declaration ; and let none
                            flutter who do not feel hit. Marriage and reproduction are good. And we would, that those having no knowledge of
                            the better uses of the institutes of nature, might comply with the law of right only, and produce only " sound
                            minds in healthy bodies ; " that these institutes might not disgrace the God of nature by bringing forth unsound
                            and disgraceful fruit. So perverted do we know humanity to be, in the engagements of fleshly lusts, that
                            honorable, undefiled marriage is either nowhere to be found, or is a jewel of rarest earthliness. We do not say
                            this, because conscience teaches us '' to find (and live) that better way ;" but would prefer, aye, rejoice to
                            say, that marriage was without fault in the eyes of God or man — an honor to him who instituted it, and to all
                            engaged in it. Even then we should live just as we do, perhaps more self-exacting in that which the world
                            complains most of us. It is not because marriage is not good that ice refrain from its practice ; but because
                            Celibacy is better and best ; and will not this assertion be accepted as the only cause of our extreme life
                            practice? Nor do we feel, because we live thus strictly celibate, that all, nor even a majority of present
                            humanity should attempt the practice — only those who " can receive the saying — none save those to whom it is
                            given." And had marriage been for ages past what it should have been, there would now be many thousands fold
                            more celibates than there are ; for the rule has been the honoring of the devil rather than of God, through the
                            abuse of the institutes of reproduction, and consequently but little fruit is ripe for an exceedingly godly
                            life. 'Tis a question worthy of most serious reflection by the married, or by those intending it: How much of
                            the higher, heavenly life is there in it ? And when this is correctly, truthfully answered, will any blame the
                            Shakers for saying that, however good marriage may be, it is an insult to the Angels to call it a Christian
                            institution, from whom Christianity derived an origin ? Now, the unreason of our opponents appears most plainly,
                            when, condemning us for certain rules of life, they applaud Jesus most, for the same practices ! We deny
                            ourselves as Shakers of no more, nor of any thing, which the great head of Christianity denied not himself. If
                            we are despicable or condemnable for self-denials, why not pass the same judgment upon him who was and is our
                            living pattern ? Why admire and adore Jesus for doing and being just what we, the Shakers, are upbraided by the
                            multitudes for doing and being ? If our opponents, who claim so much respect for Jesus, would but mentally
                            reinstate him on our earth to-day, listen to his teachings, accept his literal rule of life as their dutiful
                            pattern, how much more or longer would they respect him than they do the Shakers'! Would not millions " turn
                            away," and only " the few " be left to answer: " To whom shall we go, for thou hast the words of eternal life 1"
                            The same reasoning will equally apply to our testimony of peace as opposed to wars of nations, contentions in
                            households, and all church and state combinations. Also to community principles as opposed to selfish relations
                            and property. Wherein do we differ from Jesus ? Him, or those whom we love best, we will strive to be like. If
                            the love of Shaker opponents for Jesus, is measured by the nearness of their lives to his life, is there any
                            love lost ? If any will live more like Jesus than we do, we will not despise them, but will try to be like them.
                            It is not a question with us, but an establishment, that we will only approach Jesus, by association, love and
                            obedience to those living more in accord with his life than we do. True, we dance in worship ; but who complains
                            of this, equally with the denunciation of our life testimony ? We could easily abandon any external form like
                            it, if that would induce men and women to forsake their worldly associations. But no sooner would they honestly
                            forsake these, than they would dance from pure joy, and want us to dance with them. Let us all, " who wear the
                            name of Christ, depart from all iniquity" — live just like him, and one of two things will ensue — our
                            unreasonable opposition to Shakerism will cease, or we will " also turn away " and condemn Jesus as well. "
                            Consistency, thou art a jewel!" Are the multitudes of Shaker opponents and professedly Christian people
                            consistent V And echo answers—; and are we then " so very weak, because we are so very good ? " </p></div2><pb n="62" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our unity" TEIform="index"/>OUR UNITY</head><p TEIform="p">The majority of the people called Shakers, had an earlier education without the domains of Shakerism. While bone
                            and marrow were composing, physically, ideas were making, apparently, eternal impressions. There is nothing
                            strange in the fact, that upon theological niceties we are not agreed. And moreover, let none hope nor imagine
                            that this can be so in this life. All mere theological discussion for argument's sake, is next to wasted breath
                            — whether " Paul," and else — but know all people, that we are a unit in belief, in a pure, virgin life, with
                            all it can signify ; in a brotherhood of common property; in that peace which comes from all denials to selfish
                            lusts, whether of the flesh, or personal superiority ; and in a freedom from worldly associations that would in
                            any manner impede a spiritual advancement. Accept, all people, the true theory of our religious liberality, as
                            expressed by our best living, theological exponent — Elder F. W. Evans:—"Believe, just what you please,
                            theologically, but Live the life of Christ." Now, let every Shaker permit this kind of a life to regulate his
                            theology ; and keep all old, anti-christian theology out of the discussion of those who would be saints, and we
                            are a unit and will have peace. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cruelty to animals, birds, etc." TEIform="index"/>CRUELTY TO ANIMALS, BIRDS, ETC.</head><p TEIform="p">We are proud of humanity, at every recollection or mention of the " Societies for the Prevention of Cruelty to
                            Animals, etc." May heaven bless, and we believe it will, every one who raises a voice or hand to aid the noble
                            cause. Every youth of our land should learn Cowper's beautiful lines upon " Cruelty," beginning: " I would not
                            enter on my list of friends, Though graced with polished manners and fine sense, The man, who needlessly sets
                            foot upon a worm." We have received from one Dr. Sterling, of Cleveland, (X, a kind but severe criticism upon
                            recipe second, for protection from the crow, in " Spirit of Farm " for June. The gist of the complaint is, that
                            having recommended recipe one as efficacious, the second was one of extreme cruelty. The doctor claims that a
                            thorough knowledge of the crow, and other birds, would convict us of the ill necessity of their extermination.
                            We realize the crow as a scavenger, and, plying his vocation, we believe in respecting his rights as such. Just
                            so with flies, mosquitoes, and many creeping things ; but out of their sphere, as intruders, " into scenes
                            sacred to neatness and repose " — into fields, gardens, etc., sacred to better purposes — we believe it right to
                            add sufficient extermination to prevent much recurrence. Says Cowper : "The sum is this: If man's convenience,
                            health, Or safety interfere, his rights and claims Are paramount, and must extinguish theirs." This is the
                            correct view of the matter. A sickly sentimentalism might open the window to remove a mosquito ; and should it
                            rain, put him in the next room until clear ! Respect for the rights of all things would prevent our entrance
                            upon territory devoted to the economy of beasts, birds, fishes or insects, for the simple purpose of
                            destruction. Again, wishing the extensive growth of such humane Societies as care for the brutes and birds, we
                            cannot acknowledge the point of the Dj*. in the case of the crow, as well taken, as " A necessary act incurs no
                            blame ; " and the protection of our crops is a prime, physical necessity. </p></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Errata" TEIform="index"/>ERRATA</head><p TEIform="p">In July No. of Shakkr, in article "That Dream," occurred mistakes : The " We " who left Liverpool was intended to
                            mean the ship's crew, and not the writer's family, as he had no family at that time. "Mary Ann," referred to in
                            parenthesis, was not then his wife, but became so some months afterward. The responsibility of mistakes is
                            assumed by us ; copying for the press, and intending only to make matters clearer, we made matters worse for
                            some, and enacted some panlo post futuro incidents, for which we claim no credit as a prophet.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/>Ed.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gospel armor" TEIform="index"/>GOSPEL ARMOR</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL ORCUTT</byline><p TEIform="p">According to ancient history, spears and lances were used as weapons of war, and men wore armor to protect their
                            bodies from them. It was often formed of brass plates laid over each other like the scales of a fish, and
                            jointed together, so as to allow a free motion of the body. We are informed that Goliath's armor weighed nearly
                            two hundred pounds! The Gospel armor, provided by Christ, the good Commander, for volunteers in the spiritual
                            warfare, is a sure defense against the wiles of Satan, the great adversary of souls. " Take unto you the whole
                            armor of God," says Paul to the soldier of the cross. " Stand, therefore,"— resist every attack; "having your
                            loins girt about with truth." An iron belt bound the ancient armor to keep it in place ; so truth, encircling
                            the soul, keeps it always guarded, ready for action. "And having on the breastplate of righteousness," —
                            integrity, holiness, purity of life. The breastplate defended the vital parts, and if one of mail was necessary
                            to protect the heart from the weapons of the enemy, no less so is the breastplate of integrity necessary to
                            preserve the soul from the assaults of Satan. It was Job's incorruptible integrity that gave Satan no advantage
                            over him. "Above all, taking the shield of faith, wherewith ye will be able to quench all the fiery darts of the
                            wicked." Fiery darts! such as sudden temptations, wicked impressions, the naming of sinful passions, etc. "xViid
                            take the helmet of salvation, and the sword of the Spirit, which is the word of God." No soldier was fully armed
                            and equipped without a sword. It was short, sharp and two-edged. The sword of the Spirit is a death-dealing
                            weapon of the truest, to remove error, destroy sin and .foil temptation. If Eve, in the garden, had used her
                            sword, " the word of God," Satan would not have overpowered her. It was this weapon with which Christ foiled him
                            in the wilder ness so that he fled. Stand fast by the " sword." Wield it daily. " Praying always with all
                            prayer." No matter how complete is our armor, or how skillful and courageous we may be, without watchfulness and
                            prayer we shall be beaten. God alone giveth the victory ; and when the Christian soldier goes forth fully
                            prepared to war the good warfare and to " fight the good fight," he is sure to overcome in every encounter ; and
                            " he that overcometh shall inherit all things." Enfield, Ct.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Freedom of conscience" TEIform="index"/>FREEDOM OF CONSCIENCE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Castelar, Emilio" TEIform="persName"/>EMILIO CASTELAR</byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Yesterday the walls of the Lower House of the Spanish Cortes listened to the time honored pleas in
                                    favor of religious intolerance, marshaled by Senor Moyano, the Moderado orator. He urged that Spain's
                                    greatness was achieved under the strict rule of the Papacy, that the will of the Pontiff ought to be law
                                    to her still. To-day a fresher air swept through the thronged House. The lady of fashion, the statesmen
                                    of every shade of political feeling, the whole diplomatic bodies, the passing stranger, listened for two
                                    hours and a half enthralled by the eloquence, and hanging upon every word, of the great orator, Emilio
                                    Castelar. He said, speaking from his own place: "From the day when the elements of human matter rose up
                                    from the confusion of the chaos, uprose with them spirit and heart and conscience ; that spirit you
                                    cannot curb, that conscience you cannot bind by any human law of coercion. Try it, it has been tried ;
                                    it has ever failed ; it ever will fail. And why? Because it is against the will of the great Creator of
                                    the, Universe. The State has ever—in the pages of the Divine or human history go and seek it — sought to
                                    bind down the conscience of men ; Pharaoh, who represented the State, sought to force hit, own form of
                                    worship upon Moses and the Jews ; Pilate, the State representative, through seeking to do this, wetted
                                    his hands in the blood of the Spotless One ; Nero, the Cossack of the Don, King Henry VIII. and his
                                    harlot Parliament, Charles IV.—-all these, powers of the State, committed a like fatal error; and how do
                                    their names sound to our ears? No, brother Deputies, you cannot do it. Sirs, I charge no one with
                                    desiring to bring back the cursed age of torments, the horrors of the Inquisition, the street and altar
                                    smeared with innocent blood, nay, but, sirs, I charge you with trying to coerce men to be hypocrites and
                                    liars from fear — fear lest their children should be illegitimate, fear lest their rights of citizenship
                                    be taken from them, fear lest when dead, their bones should rot on some dunghill, or in the Campo. You
                                    say, 'the State undertakes to support the Roman Catholic religion and its ministers.' Well, I give that
                                    creed its due honor; I own its beauty, and its force, and its antiquity. And you say, ' This is the true
                                    religion.' Sirs, are you so gross as to say, 'This is the true,' because it is imposed by human law and
                                    force of arms? Nay, sirs, you will surely say, ' This is true because, and only because it recommends
                                    itself to your heart and conscience as the true one ;' and if so, why do you want a human law to force
                                    you to follow that which your conscience tells you is true? Are you afraid of a rival? Sirs, you do an
                                    honor to Protestantism if you think it so true as to be able, in a fair race, to outrun Roman
                                    Catholicism. But if it be not true, this religion of the State —if it be not true, brother Deputies,
                                    what then? Magna eat veritas et praevalcbit. If the Roman Catholic creed be true, it will prevail by
                                    force of truth ; if Protestantism be true, it will prevail, and you cannot crush it. If this liberty of
                                    conscience be of God, you cannot, if of man you need not, crush it. Protestantism and Catholicism have
                                    both tried to coerce. Look at their failure in the fall of Felipe II., in the history of England under
                                    the Tudors and James II. * * * Sirs, I have appealed to history; I have appealed to your conscience ;
                                    now I make my appeal to your patriotism. Do you believe because you are triumphant in the North over the
                                    bodies, that you have won ascendancy over the souls also, of the Basque peasantry? Religious
                                    exaggerations have wrought more ill than democratic exaggerations; but in three months, sirs, our
                                    advanced Republic put an end to the riots in Carthagena, Seville, Cadiz ; but, sirs, four years and 300
                                    000 men have been necessary to put down a religious war ! The women of Jerusalem went to the sepulchre,
                                    as at this season, and found it empty, and said the body of their Master was stolen; but it was no human
                                    voice that answered, 'He is not here: He is risen.' Blind women of Jerusalem. Sirs, foolish women. But
                                    more foolish, more blind still are those retrograde and reactionary parties: they are seeking for Christ
                                    where He is not, they are seeking Him in His sepulchre of stone —in the feudal castle of Middle Age
                                    story, in flame and torment, on the floor of the Inquisition, in history —and lo! He has risen. Yes,
                                    sirs, Deputies, He has risen : He SHAKER, <pb n="63" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE S H .A. K E R . 63 is not there. He
                                    has risen in Keason ; He has risen in Liberty, In Equality, in Fraternity, in the punishment of John
                                    Brown, in the martyrdom of Lincoln. Lo! the chain they break, and they find and fulfill truth and
                                    eternal justice. Brother Deputies, go to your libraries, to your publishers, and search those books
                                    which breathe this spirit of perfect freedom of thought and conscience ; persuade, and seek not to
                                    coerce; conciliate, and leave off to persecute; break the chains and fetters that man, and not God, has
                                    forged and is forging. I have spoken." The whole speech was delivered without hesitation; bursts of
                                    suppressed applause followed at the conclusion of each separate division of the subject, and the House
                                    was enthralled. Castelar sat down fairly exhausted with his tremendous effort.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New York times" TEIform="index"/>New York Times.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Materialization among the indians" TEIform="index"/>MATERIALIZATION AMONG THE INDIANS</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Editor of the Shaker: The most remarkable case of materialization among the Indians that came to my notice
                            during my twelve years of residence among them was during the summer of 1836, of which I noted down the
                            particulars at the time, and of which the following is the history: Ke-che Be-zhe-kee, or Big Buffalo, as he was
                            called by the Americans, was at that time chief of that band of Ojibway Indians who dwelt on the southwest
                            shores of Lake Superior, and were best known by the name of the " Lake Indians." He was wise and sagacious in
                            council, a great orator, and was much reverenced by the Indians for his supposed intercourse with the
                            Man-i-toes, or Spirits, from whom they believed he derived much of his eloquence and wisdom in governing the
                            affairs of the tribe. In the summer of 1836, his only son, a young man of rare promise, suddenly sickened and
                            died. The old chief was almost inconsolable for his loss, and, as a token of his affection for his son, had him
                            dressed and laid in the grave in the same military coat, together with the sword and epaulets, which he had
                            received a few months before as a present from the Great Father at Washington. He also had placed beside him his
                            favorite dog, to be his companion on his journey to the land of souls. One morning, a few months after his
                            death, the old chief came to my wigwam, his step light and elastic like a chill, his form erect and his face
                            lighted up as if he had just received some new and joyful intelligence. "I have seen him," he said, "I have seen
                            him whom we mourned as dead! I have seen him, and he is still alive!" "Seen him! when?" I asked. " Yesterday, in
                            the Me-ta-wa (sacred dance). We were all assembled together in the great dancing lodge of the chiefs, to worship
                            before the Great Spirit, and On-wi came there and joined us." "What! in your dance before the Great Spirit? Did
                            you speak to him?" " We did, and he spoke to us." "What did he say?" " He said it was weakness for us to mourn
                            for him. He had gone to the happy hunting grounds, far better than these, on the cold shores of the lake. He
                            mentioned some of those whom he had seen, particularly Man-i-bo-zho and Ah-ke-wain-ze, who had welcomed him
                            there.'' " Did he join with you in the dance?" " He did. We all danced before the Great Spirit. On-wi danced
                            with us. His step was light as a fawn. His face was bright as the sky overhead. I wish you could have seen him.
                            It made our hearts glad and joyful as the birds in spring. After the dance we all sat down and smoked the pipe
                            of peace together." •'But how do you know it was On-wi whom you saw? May it not have been some one of the tribe
                            who counterfeited him, with his face painted with the sacred emblems which you wear in the dance?" '¦ Did I not
                            mark his form, his features, his every look? Was he* not dressed in the very coat I gave him, a present from the
                            Great Father at Washington ? Who else in all the tribe has a coat like that? How, then, could I be deceived ? "
                            " And you — every one of you — saw him ? " "Every one of us. Ask the aged men, and they will tell you. The
                            wisest men of the tribe were there. Could they, too, be deceived? Have they got eyes and do not see straight
                            forward ? Have they got ears and do not hear what is spoken to them ? Ask them, and they will tell you the
                            truth. Their tongues are not hung in the middle, speaking lies at both ends, like the pale faces. The toes of
                            their feet do not turn outward, so that they walk two ways at once, like them. They keep straight forward in the
                            path. Ask them, and they will tell you the truth." I did ask them, and heard from them the same report brought
                            to me by the old chief concerning his son. For many days it was the theme of conversation in every wigwam of the
                            camp. The old men spoke of it in an undertone, with their heads bowed as if in reverence; and one day, while
                            walking through the camp, I saw Wah-chus-co, the great seer of the tribe, standing amidst a group of earnest
                            listeners, and, with a great burst of eloquence, telling them how Ke-che Man-i-to made the two worlds round,
                            like the sun, for so the Spirits had taught him; and taking a piece of birch bark and drawing on it two spheres
                            touching each other, he pictured to them whole bands of joyous spirits passing from one to the other, thus
                            bringing together the inhabitants of the seen and unseen worlds. Yours,</p><byline TEIform="byline">Canaan, N. Y. <persName reg="Sproat, Granville T." TEIform="persName"/>Granville T. Sproat</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christianity of the future" TEIform="index"/>CHRISTIANITY OF THE FUTURE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Swing, David" TEIform="persName"/>DAVID SWING</byline><p TEIform="p">The last body has been racked, the last heart broken for religious belief. The State demands only peaceable
                            citizens, the guilt of too much belief or too little, it leaves to be determined at the bar of God. To what
                            shape of Christianity have we come ? Not fully to any form has our age come, but with slow and sure footsteps it
                            is drawing near a religion of character. The pageantry'of the barbaric ages, the curious questions of the
                            schoolmen, the mysteries of the old creeds rivaling the mysteries of Eleusis, the bloody struggles for temporal
                            power, have all been turned aside or hurled into oblivion, that the human heart might see itself in the great
                            mirror of Jesus Christ. At last, the world draws near the truth that Christianity is not an external
                            architecture, or art, or scarlet robe, is not a speculation; is not a military conquest; but it is a washing
                            white of self in the fountain opened in the being of Christ. The words, "Blessed are they who do his
                            commandments, that they may have right to the tree of life, and may enter in through the gates of the city," are
                            words that betray the genius of the coming religion. If our hearts are not too sanguine, we^are standing upon
                            the borders of an age that will hold a religion of principle, not of form, not of curious or complex dogma, but
                            of those deep principles that make the better man. It is daily becoming more and more evident, that what God
                            demanded all through the Old and New Testaments, was an obedience of his law, the purity of human life; evident
                            in all the reflections of reason, (hat religion must lie in the inner life; and now, it has become evident by
                            the condition of society, that what is demanded is a religion of virtue. Chicago, El._____________</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Love and order" TEIform="index"/>LOVE AND ORDER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Broadway, Emeline" TEIform="persName"/>EMELINE BROADWAY</byline><p TEIform="p">Love and order are requisite to promote happiness and to sustain a pure life. Love, unlike passion, produces the
                            fruits of peace, and causes individuals to make large sacrifice of selfish enjoyments, to increase the happiness
                            and comfort of others. The higher spirits in admonishing their charge, gave this precaution—"while cultivating
                            love and good will for each other, beware that you do not foster that which is worse than hate." If we live and
                            love so as to affect each other for good, then are we Christians in truth. Passion has often been permitted to
                            usurp the name of love, but has ever failed to represent the true character of this godly element. True love is
                            known by its heavenly characteristics, of kindness and constancy, while order unlocks the entrance to the
                            superior harmonies of the Angel life. The necessity of order and regularity to both temporal prosperity and
                            spiritual advancement, is an eternal, unchanging truth. We might as well expect to catch showers from the sky,
                            with vessels bottom upward, as to receive the blessings of divine inspiration from the spirit world, in
                            disorderly and inharmonious conditions. There is no salvation outside the first law of heaven ; the law which
                            sustains and pervades the universe, preserves the individuality of all its parts, and their proper relation to
                            each other. Let us keep our vessels clean, and right side up, that we may receive of the waters of life, and as
                            we receive, freely give. Union Village, O.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Who can it be?" TEIform="index"/>WHO CAN IT BE?</head><p TEIform="p">A recent visitor at Canterbury writes a most glowing description of one of their spiritual meetings, and of the
                            effective simplicity and sincerity of the people there during the hour of worship. Howells' recent account was
                            thoroughly indorsed; and the opinion fully expressed that " mere doctrines, however good, will not hold people
                            together for a century: it requires an afflatus; meetings of the members very frequently, which the Shakers do
                            nearly every evening of the week, etc." But we are in search of a new contributor to The Shaker, and it is the
                            one whom the above writer alludes to, beginning with Frederica Bremer's words, concerning her: " She is of
                            singular beauty, and a more fascinating, inspired glance than hers, I never beheld," continues, " Hers is an
                            inspirational nature; through her are given many of the songs which enter so largely into the worship and daily
                            life of the Shakers. Here is one: " Ever changing, ever aiming Toward a higher, better life; Ever learning, ever
                            earning, Is the good believer's strife. Light unfolding, spirit moulding, Is the law of endless growth; Feeding
                            thought and word and action From the wells of boundless truth." Then the writer gives us an epitome of "the most
                            effective discourse of the day," from her lips ; "the burden of her utterance was the genuineness of one's
                            religious character, etc." Now, Who can tliis be? and why does she not, and will she not, become an immediate
                            contributor to The Shaker? Nor her alone, but let all those choice spirits in form, " send holy inspirations
                            down," and " aid the goodly work along. Does not the life of The Shaker form part and parcel of the perpetuity
                            of our institutions ? vV</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ollapodrida?" TEIform="index"/>OLLAPODRIDA?</head><p TEIform="p">There are few afflictions, not affecting the health, that are more embarrassing to both speaker and hearer, than
                            stammering. Here what a man, who has entirely cured himself, advises: "Go into some room alone, with any book
                            you choose to read. Close the jaws, so that the teeth will shut tightly. Read aloud for two hours ! Your jaws
                            will ache, but immediately thereafter you will talk better, and the practice, persisted in, will insure a cure."
                            We have had sent us a quarto pamphlet from John Wanamaker, Phila., Pa., containing the very best arrangement of
                            scripture questions for Sunday Schools. As an aid for both Teachers and Scholars, it is an invaluable work. We
                            add our thanks to those of»many others, which must reach the publisher. ^ Two new socialistic papers were
                            launched in July — " The Eclectic and Peacemaker," and " The Christian Socialist.'''' The former represents a
                            new undertaking in the associative line, upon a large tract of land in Virginia. There never was an hour in the
                            past, that gave more evidence, that we live in a day of transition. From our own observation, we are assured
                            that creedal forms and churchal bondage stand less as barriers to the acceptance and progress of the truth, than
                            at any time of the past. The time has come, the people are more than ready; and the shackles that have so
                            erroneously bound consciences, are silently, but surely, falling on every side. Instead of our feeling, that
                            never was irreligion more prevalent, let us observe that only the practical truths of Christ are accepted as
                            religion, by the noble and thoughtful of to-day. Lomas. " Spirit Voices "—music in July No., is receiving an
                            unusual share of encomiums. Ere long, "Shaker Music Books " will be in active demand. A few more left.
                            Post-paid, 50 cents. Bekcher.— If Christ should come to New York this morning, He would not find any more
                            followers than he did 1800 years ago. If Jesus Christ should come from Heaven and stand in New York to-day and
                            oppose us, as he opposed all the legends and traditions in the synagogue of that olden city — if he opposed us
                            in the same way, he would have a small following.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>EVERGREEN SHORES</head><p TEIform="p">Unwilling to spare any of our saints for the "evergreen shores," we are happy in having none to record under this
                            heading for this issue. The saints live on earth none too long.</p></div2><pb n="64" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Power of faith" TEIform="index"/>POWER OF FAITH</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>MARTHA J. ANDERSON</byline><p TEIform="p">Mount Lebanon, N. Y. __Feelingly. Thou who hast walked upon the wave, And calmed the storm on Galilee, Come forth
                            again with power to save, And bid the faithless come to thee. For tempest tossed like those of old, Are hearts
                            depressed with doubt and fear, May such, through faith, enjoy, behold, A blessed Saviour ever near. 2. The same
                            rebuke, Oh, may we bear, Which was to thy disciples given, Oh, ye of little faith beware Lest ye may slight the
                            gifts of heaven; Oh, that our souls might feel the glow Of faith that filled thy soul with light, And shed its
                            radiance here below, To beam with lasting glory bright. 3. How beautiful that holy trust, Which made thy life a
                            work sublime, Whose noble deeds undimmed by rust, Have lived through all the years of time. The earthly miud
                            still seeks a sign. As did the ancient Pharisee, But, give us, Lord, that faith divine, Which blest thy heavenly
                            ministry. The faith that works by truth and love, To search and puriiy the heart, Which turns the mind to joys
                            above, From sin and worldliness apart. As oft we ask in silent prayer From out the soul's Gethsemane, Our
                            spirits, trusting, own thy care, And look for strength and help from thee.</p></div2><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pray ope' the gates" TEIform="index"/>PRAY OPE' THE GATES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Briggs, Mary Ella" TEIform="persName"/>MARY ELLA BRIGGS</byline><p TEIform="p">Enfield, N. H. Pray ope' the gates that stand ajar, Ye ministers of life, Pour out a flood of fire and truth, To
                            invigorate us for the strife. For the resurrection power of God, Alone can satisfy The soul that's wrestling for
                            the truth, Oh, give it lest we die.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Amen!" TEIform="index"/>AMEN!</head><p TEIform="p">Enfield, N. H., July 3, '76. Elder F. W. Evans — Dear Friend: I feel strongly impressed to write you, though
                            briefly. For nearly thirteen years I have been head miller for the Church Family of Shakers, peaceable and
                            friendly with the Society ; have been, and am a subscriber to The Shaker. To my mind, it grows better and
                            better. It feasts my heart and soul with spiritual truths, new and old. The present No. (July) contains truths,
                            by your pen, for which 1 am so thankful as to cause this ex pression. I sincerely hope it may be the means of
                            turning the tide of humanity from Priestcraft and Sectarianism, to true and genuine Christianity. Yours for the
                            truth,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dennison, William G." TEIform="persName"/>Wm. G. Dennison</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Impressive thought" TEIform="index"/>AN IMPRESSIVE THOUGHT</head><p TEIform="p">We think of the earth as the only solid, substantial and abiding thing; all else is changing, when, in fact, it
                            is only an egg-shell with a yolk of liquid fire seething within. What if there were to be a great rift in the
                            crust, and the ocean let in upon the fiery mass? The generation of steam and gases would blow this great
                            terrestrial bomb-shell into millions of fragments in a twinkling, filling the surrounding space with new
                            asteroids, just as we have reason to think we see now the seventy or eighty fragments of an exploded world
                            moving in their orbits around the sun!</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Daily duty" TEIform="index"/>DAILY DUTY</head><p TEIform="p">Each day its duty brings. The undone task Of yesterday cannot be now fulfilled Without some current work's
                            displacement. "Time And tide will wait for none." Then let us act So that they need not wait, and keep abreast
                            With them by the discharge of each day's claim; For each new dawn, like a prolific tree, Blossoms with blessings
                            and with duties, which So interwoven grow that he who shirks The latter fails the first. Ye cannot pick The
                            dainty and refuse the task. To win The smile of him who did his Father's will In the great work assigned him,
                            while 'twas day, With love self sacrificing, his high course We must with prayerful footsteps imitate; And,
                            knowing not what one day may bring forth, Live so that Death, come when he may, shall find Us not defaulters in
                            arrears with Time — Mourning, like Titus, " I have lost a day! "—• But busily engaged on something which Shall
                            cast a blessing on the world; rebound With one to our own breast, and tend to give To man some benefit, to God
                            some praise.</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>