<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2606" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">20</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">East Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">26</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">6</biblScope><date value="18960601" TEIform="date">June 1896</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">89-104</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="26" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="6" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
THE
MANIFESTO
A Visit to the
A CONCISE HISTORY OF THE
Just Published.     The book is printed                              SHAKERS
with large type  and  on  excellent  paper,  of EAST CANTERBURY,   N.   H.
It contains  130 pages and has
ILLUSTRATION8
of the Shakers and their
by    
LLOYD II. CHANDLER. U. S. N
The work gives  quite an extended account of the  Several SOCIETIES, their
organization and general management.
Price,  50 cts.
Address   H. C. Blinn,
East Canterbury, N. H.
A SUMMARY VIEW
OF  THE
 CHURCH,
OR
"United   Society    of    Believers"
It treats of the Rise and Progress of the
Society, together with the general Principles of the Faith and Testimony.
Price 50 cts.
Liberally Illustrated with half tone
pictures of persons and places.
The Village of EAST CANTERBURY
is situated in one of the lovliest spots of
New Hampshire, and is high enough to
overlook the surrounding country.
Price,  15 cts.
AUTHORIZED RULES
OF
THE   SHAKER   COMMUNITY.
The religious basis of the ORDER must
be a foundation resting on the principle of
righteousness, which principle is God.
This should rule the life of the  individ
ual for the protection of his own soul, for
the peace of the family and as an evidence
of his upright standing before the world.
Price, 10 cts.
JUNE,   1896.
MILLENNIAL
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
Word and Works for May opens with an
interesting story of the Heavens and has in
addition to the usual illustrations of the planetary system, a beautiful and enlarged, representation of the planet Saturn. The curious
rings that encircle that \Nonderful globe, and
also the eight attendant moons will be studied
with great pleasure. It is no wonder that so
many people love to believe that heaven is located on this planet. After closing all busi.
ness relations on the earth, it would be just
nice to sail around Saturn on her beautiful
rings, for some few thousands of years. And
after we have expatiated so freely on the
beauties of our one moon, and then to be
transported to a world when we can have no
less than eight, well, to say the least it must
be just lovely. The good Dr. says we must
look out for the first fifteen days of May; there
may be violent storms on the sea and on the
land, but even with these predictions we will
not be frightened, but quietly turn to the Query Corner and see what the readers are asking
Questions about this month.
Word and Works Pub. Co., 2201 Locust St.
St Louis, Mo.
Israel's Messiah by H. L. Hastings, 47 Cornhill, Boston, Mass.
A fund of information can be obtained from
these books that are published in the interest
of the Christian church. Although they are
called anti-Infidel, yet any Infidel and no less
the majority of Christians will be much better
informed in regard to ancient and modern history, by a careful perusal of these pages. The
theological feature of the work is not of so
much consequence to the general reader, but
to be assured that so good a man as Jesus of
Nazareth once walked upon this earth and
taught lessons of righteousness to rich and
poor alike, makes this little book a valuable
treasure.
Human Nature for May presents a very interesting, illustrated article on the change
that was made in the character of a young
man through his knowledge of Phrenology.
This article is well worth a careful perusal
for those who wish to improve the health of
body and mind. The whole paper can be
studied to profit. A sample copy can be obtained for five cents. Prof. A. Haddock, San
Francisco, Cal.
ARBUTUS.
Under the snow, under the snow,
The leaves of the trailing arbutus grow;
Toiling the earth that loves them nigh,
But hoping to some day see the sky.
Under the snow, under the snow,
The flowers of the trailing arbutus glow;
E'en in the dark their duty done,
But hoping to some day kiss the sun.
Will Carleton in Every Where for May.
What is Spiritualism? You can best learn
if you are an investigator, by reading a Reliable Spiritualist paper, one that is free from
bigotry and does not condone fraud in any
guise. Such a journal is The Medium, a bright
and interesting 8-page weekly, published at
Los Angeles, Cal. The only Spiritual paper
on this coast. Only 50 cents a year, Sent two
months on trial for 10 cts silver. Address
The Medium, 202 N. Main St., Los Angeles, Cal.
The Journal ok Hvgeio-Therapv. The
April Journal has reached number four of the
Science of Life by T. V. Gifford, M. D. Those
interested in a life of health in this world,
would be better informed on this subject
if they should read these articles.
"What we know and what we don't know
about Vaccination," gives very extended information on the subject; and the story of
the wicked city in England that will not accept vaccination, will please many readers.
The Journal has also many interesting articles on subjects belonging to the health and
happiness of the home and of the individual.
Dr. T. V. Gifford & Co., Kokomo, Ind.
The Pulpit for April presents a series of
six sermons preached by Rev. J. E. Lanceley
of Brampton, Canada.
The Sermons are Why? When? Who? How?
What? and Whither? As no special denomination is mentioned, the Preacher of course
belongs to the People and his message is to
the people. The good words of J. E. Lanceley can now be read by the members of all the
churches and be known as a friend of humanity .
"How Sundaj is spent, and how to spend it"
is a sermon by Rev. Wallace Nutting. His
story of the Sabbath is wonderfully strange.
He illustrates a city of 40,000 inhabitants.
From the large number he estimates that
10,000 may be in the churches, 15,000 may be
drinking at home or on a visit to the saloons,
and 15,000 spending the Sunday in reading or
visiting or as their inclinations suggest.
Published by G. Holzapfel, Fredericksburg,
Pa.
The Phrenological Journal for May has
an illustrated article of the great Bankei, Mr.
Henry (lews. It is said to be from a personal
examination by Edgar C. Beall, M. D. A
presentation like this must prove very pleasant to Mr. Clews and to his many friends as
Dr. Beall has marked for him nearly all that
is good in the head of a man. Even a Puritanic church member would be in honor to accompany so good a man to the Celestial City .
In an article by C T. Parks we are informed
that there is Character in the eyes. Six illustrations with six recognized types will readily inform us to which we may belong. As the
position of the eyes will be hard to change we
must accept the judgment of public opinion.
The Principles of Phrenology by Prof. N. L.
Fowler is a Historical Paper and will be read
with interest.
Child Culture by Prof. Nelson Sizer is beau
tifully illustrated with the little folks, and so--><pb n="89" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Autobiography of Chas. D. Hampton of Union Village, Ohio, no. 5" TEIform="index"/>AUTOBIOGRAPHY OF CHAS. D. HAMPTON OF UNION VILLAGE, O. NO. 5.</head><p TEIform="p">IIN our estimation, it is indeed marvelous and in truth passing strange that minds
                            enlightened by the illumination of science, by the experience of age, and all the immense
                            mass of information to be obtained from books in the middle of the nineteenth century should
                            not see the signs of the times, when it seems as if everything on earth and in heaven
                            proclaims the fact that light is bursting from the Spirit world in almost a perpetual blaze.
                            We insist upon it that intelligent men of the age examine and judge for themselves. If they
                            look over the state of the world since the middle of the last century, they will find in
                            this examination a wonderful and astonishing era in the world's calendar. A movement
                            revolutionizing the whole social, moral and religious world, upheaved in the aggregate and
                            staggering under combined effects of the moving phalanx stih1 going on. Now to what cause is
                            this universal movement to be ascribed? Notice the stir almost simultaneous through the
                            moral and religious world in regard to intemperance, the testimony against it springing up
                            in Europe and America, spreading far and wide through all orders, sects and denominations.
                            Observe the exertions of manly and liberal minds on the subject of slavery; with what a
                            noble and dignified front they have breasted the appalling wrath of almost half a nation
                            battling against them. The combined darkness of ignorance, interest and obstinacy arrayed
                            against the majesty of human rights and human liberty in all the slave-holding states, and
                            in thousands of the free states whose narrow and sordid spirJUNE, <pb n="90" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 90
                            THE MANIFESTO. its are interested in perpetuating the evil. See the influence of a few quiet
                            unassuming men on the important subject of war. Half of the civilized world are now
                            convinced of its impropriety and converted to the sentiment of peace, and many who are still
                            under the influence of ancient prejudices in its favor are standing up boldly in defense of
                            peace principles. See also the humane influence exerted in many states, and in some of them
                            almost in every county, to benefit the condition of the helpless, poor and aged, instead of
                            selling them every year to be kept and maintained by the lowest bidder. They are now
                            provided for at the expense of the government, and generally are treated as human beings,
                            worthy of commiseration. The invention of the steam engine and its application to the
                            various purposes of life; carrying commerce almost to the farthest verge of the green earth
                            ; spinning our cotton; drawing water for mechanical purposes ; printing thousands and
                            thousands of books, papers and pamphlets ; reaping grain ; mowing and raking hay, etc., etc.
                            Lastly, time and space almost annihilated by the telegraphic wires. But how is it that
                            within the short space of eighty or ninety years the minds of men should so universally
                            revolt at the idea of the civil and ecclesiastical tyranny to which they used so quietly and
                            tamely to submit. Whence has been derived the astonishing acuteness and intellectual
                            sagacity by which these surprising inventions have been produced and from what source has
                            been derived the almost universally received feeling which now exists among men of learning
                            in regard to the propriety of a social compact of human interests as may be seen in the many
                            attempts to institute communities and connected associations. I can not doubt that all this
                            mighty revolution in mind, all these salutary and glorious improvements in the civil, moral
                            and intellectual world have been produced by the infusion of light from the Spirit world
                            into the minds of men fitted and prepared, by the hand of Providence, for the reception and
                            elucidation of these revelations for the good of the human family. From the hour in which
                            the unwearied mind of Columbus found no rest, until it was wafted by the winds to America,
                            and brought to view a new world, a spiritual influence from the upper world was constantly
                            urging him on and on until the end was answered and the grand object in view was fully
                            attained. And all along down through the annals of time, while the master spirits of the
                            intellectual powers of mind were exhibited in that constellation of great men who flourished
                            in the seventeenth and eighteenth centuries. It was from the foundation thus laid by these
                            pioneers in human progress, as the human mind was just emerging out of the long, dark night
                            of apostacy, that the germ of civil liberty had its rise, and finally terminated in
                            establishing permanent principles under the constitution of the United States. (To be
                            continued.)</p></div2><pb n="91" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tribute" TEIform="index"/>TRIBUTE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Brainard, D. C." TEIform="persName"/>By D. C. Brainard.</byline><p TEIform="p">"And I heard a voice from heaven saying unto me write, Blessed are the dead which die in the
                            Lord, from henceforth; Yea saith the spirit, that they may rest from their labors, and their
                            works do follow them." ''For as in Adam all die, even so in Christ shall all be made alive."
                            OUR Sister Johanna Freeborn whose earthly existence terminated March 31, was sixty-two years
                            of age, and has been with our people about ten years. She has always manifested a quiet,
                            amiable disposition, ready and willing at all times to do whatever duty required. She has
                            gained the affection of her companions, the respect of all, and can say with the Psalmist,
                            "The Lord is my Shepherd I shall not want yea, though I walk through the valley of the
                            shadow of death, 1 will fear no evil, for thou art with me, thy rod and thy staff they
                            comfort me." We have every reason to believe it is well with her. Prentice says, "O! could I
                            snatch the eagle's plumes And soar to that bright world above Which God's own holy light
                            illumes With glories of eternal love, How gladly every lingering tie That binds me down to
                            earth I' d sever . And leave for that blest home on high This hollow-hearted world forever."
                            The living can always be benefited by every such occasion as this to-day. To renew our vows
                            to be more faithful in our duties, more consecrated to the cause committed to our care, to
                            keep constantly before us, the solemn truth that life is short at best and our abode here is
                            but temporary to discipline and fit us for our final and eternal home. "Our lives are
                            rivers, gliding free To that unfathomed boundless sea, The silent grave. Thither all earthly
                            pomp and boast, Roll, to be swallowed up and lost In one dark wave." And shall we not meet
                            our friends and fellow pilgrims in that home beyond the grave? I believe we will, when we
                            have exchanged mortality, for immortality. The devoted Greek in "Ion" when about to yield up
                            his life was asked, Shall we meet again? replied,"I have asked the question of the hills
                            that look eternal, of the clear streams that flow forever, of the stars, among whose field
                            of azure my raised spirit has walked in glory; all are dumb. But as I gaze on the living
                            face. I feel there is something in the love that mantles through its beauty that can not
                            perish,We shall meet again." Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><pb n="92" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Zion" TEIform="index"/>ZION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Andrews, Watson" TEIform="persName"/>By Watson Andrews.</byline><p TEIform="p">[A revised copy of a poem which appeared in the July No. of The
                            Manifesto for 1894. By the original author.] Lo! in wrapped silence, 'mid bright, rural scenes, Fair Zion sits, the virgin Queen of
                            queens. Lo! from "the Mount" her living waters flow; A thousand hearts, their healing
                            virtues know; A thousand souls, drink and are satisfied, And know, and love the risen Groom
                            and Bride; And know and love each other in the Lord, A dual Priesthood ;Such the gift of
                            God. This holy union, male and female joined In gospel order, as of yore designed, And
                            symbolized in Israel,chosen name, As seen by Moses, on the mount of flame, The Cherubim and
                            Mercy-seat of gold, And fine twined linen fabrics, fold on fold; A Tabernacle, type of that
                            to come, When Christ should bring again his Zion Home; When types and shadows should be done
                            away, And the reality declare the day; When in the mighty power and gift of God, The Mother
                            spirit, with the living Word, Should mark and mortify the seat of sin, And with a holy zeal,
                            should usher in The Second Advent; Woman's virgin reign ; For which, the ancient church in
                            vain Essayed to stand, but failing fell away; The faithful waiting for the Latter Day. This
                            latter day of glory now begun, When not the Father only, and the Son; But Mother too, and
                            Daughter, four as One, Should be revealed, a family Divine, To such high lineage we trace
                            our line, Whose 'image and whose likeness' since we bear, Their 'image and their likeness'
                            we declare. 'The things invisible, of Him,Paul said, Are seen and understood, by what is
                            made.' The world of nature, being Grod manifest. Thus proven this question should forever
                            rest. Nor still exclude, in sheer absurdity, The female attributes from the Diety. <pb n="93" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 93 Making the Source of universal life Inferior, by
                            half, to that same life. But such the darkening power of priestly art; And such the nature
                            of the woman heart; She's slow to think the world is all astray, On this, and kindred
                            questions of the day. What she desired offended nature gave, And with that gift, the doom to
                            be a slave, Until the light of gospel truth should shine Into her servile heart, with power
                            Divine; Until, in all the strength of Jachin, she Should rise and slay her deadly enemy;
                            Should crucify original desire, Baptizing "with the holy Ghost and fire." The Cross of
                            Christ; the risen Savior's life ; The 'sacrifice of husband, children, wife;' 'Of lands and
                            chattels, selfish will and way;' Such the baptism of the woman's day. Away with cant; away
                            with priestly guile ; Away with subtle reasoning's specious wile, The gaud of vanity and
                            lukewarm ease, The damp of death o'er Zion, comes of these. Be not deceived, we reap
                            whate'er we sow Whate'er we cultivate, we surely grow. If light and life ; a knowledge of
                            the way ; A faith unshaken in the Mother's day; A faith unshaken in her precious word; In
                            Zion's Order as the gift of God, We cultivate; we've nothing then to fear; Such conecration,
                            brings the kingdom near; But if instead, we lend a willing ear To the seductive cry, Lo here
                            ! Lo there I We're liable to drift, we know not where. Union Village, O.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To the memory of our gospel father, elder John B. Vance" TEIform="index"/>To the Memory of
                            our Gospel Father, Elder JOHN B. VANCE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Casey, Fannie" TEIform="persName"/>By Fannie Casey.</byline><p TEIform="p">At the close of the day in the quiet of evening, Our father was called to his rest; In death
                            as in life he calmly surrendered, As the voice of the spirit thought best. <pb n="94" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 94 THE MANIFESTO. We watched by his side and prayed, "'0 our Father, Wilt thou
                            this sad cup pass by ;" But he whispered not one word of complaint, As the messenger, Death,
                            drew nigh. He knew that the body, alone, could be buried, While his spirit so happy and
                            free, Would soar to the mansions of heavenly glory, Where joy and rejoicing would be. He has
                            met with the loved ones who've gone on before, Their welcome, methinks I can hear, "O come
                            dearest brother, we've longed for thy presence, Thy home and thy treasure are here." "A
                            crown of bright glory awaits thy sure coming, And robes of pure white will adorn Thy spirit
                            made pure through deep tribulation, As thou hast the burden and crosses well borne." Our
                            father, so loving, so kind and so gentle, Has past from our sight here below; But he will
                            not leave us, his presence will cheer us, And guide us wherever we go. So firm and so loyal,
                            unyielding in duty, No matter though foes oft opprest; He took for his guidance the will of
                            "Our Father," And silently past into rest. The aged well know of his justice and mercy, The
                            young, ah ! how much they will miss Their father and friend, their earthly protector, Who
                            shared in their sorrows or bliss. Thy life, precious Elder, will be as a pilot To guide us
                            along the lone way, Thy example of purity, virtue and truth, Will be a sure guide from this
                            day. Though storms may arise and foes oft oppress us, And sad seems the journey below ;
                            We'll think of thy zeal and patiently bear it, As on to thy home we may go. Our Elder's not
                            dead but only arisen, He's gone to a far brighter sphere, Where he will await the day of our
                            coming, For that day, to many, is near. Our holy pledge we now give, dearest Elder, <pb n="95" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 95 To be true we ever will be; And in that precious home
                            of glory so bright, We'll share of God's blessing with thee. Alfred, Me.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christ ideal in shakerism, no. 1" TEIform="index"/>THE CHRIST IDEAL IN SHAKERISM. No. 1.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Tyner, Paul" TEIform="persName"/>By Paul Tyner.</byline><p TEIform="p">[Published in the Humanitarian of
                            January 1896, and re-published by permission. Ed.] Affection shall solve every one of the problems of freedom. Those who love each other shall
                            be invincible. ******* The dependence of Liberty shall be lovers. The continuance of
                            Equality shall be comrades. Walt Whitman. IN the history of men and nations, every great
                            step forward and upward is marked by an awakening of the human consciousness to higher and
                            larger realization of truth and its demands on character and conduct. Involution of the
                            Divine Spirit from above ever accompanies the evolution of material forms and conditions
                            from beneath. We are drawn as well as pushed onward, and every advance brings us not only
                            supremacy over the lower, but also strength and stimulus for fresh effort and still further
                            endeavor. To the awakened and advancing soul, there are always more worlds to conquer. First
                            in a single individual, thence rapidly spreading to hundreds and thousands, a new light
                            shines forth, revealing at once the beauty of the higher, further ground, and the
                            comparative depth and darkness of the lower path by which we have climbed. The Shakers
                            believe that there has always been, is now, and will continue unto the end (if end there
                            shall be,) a divine force intelligently working in humanity to accomplish divine ends. Some
                            special manifestation of this ever flowing God-force has marked the beginning of every great
                            advance in human history. Abraham, Moses and Jesus, mark three distinct progressive cycles
                            of revelation, each summing up the Law and the Prophets of all preceding dispensations and
                            calling for the fulfillment of "every jot and tittle" of the old law in spirit and in truth,
                            while at the same time revealing, in the new light of the latter day, new and higher
                            standards of right, which all who could perceive were summoned to strive towards, if they
                            would truly live. Shakerism, in each of these cycles of the working of the divine afflatus,
                            sees steadily enlarging preparation for the advent among men of human society organically
                            divine. "The Christ Spirit," to the Shakers, means the Spirit of Truth, and while its
                            openings into, and operations upon and through, <pb n="96" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 96 THE MANIFESTO.
                            Abraham, Moses and Jesus are believed to be especially connected and to have near and direct
                            bearing on the evolution of humanity in the Western world, it is as fully recognized that
                            the inspiration of such leaders in the East as Buddah, Krishna and Confucius, were similarly
                            appearances of the Christ Spirit, having special reference to the special needs created by
                            Oriental conditions and lines of development. That at bottom Truth is one, in all times and
                            among all nations, is an axiom of universal acceptance among the Brethren and Sisters of the
                            United Society of Believers in Christ, commonly called "Shakers." A fourth cycle of divine
                            illumination, it is held, was opened in the person of Ann Lee. In a very large and very true
                            sense, Ann Lee, the founder of Shakerism, may be considered the pioneer New Woman. Nearly a
                            century before our women pioneers lifted up their voices for woman's political emancipation,
                            this Manchester blacksmith's daughterthis woman of the people began a valiant battle for
                            woman's moral emancipation. As the revolt of Luther sowed the seeds of American independence
                            aud the French Revolution, so the revolt of this simple and fearless daughter of God, this
                            AngloSaxon Joan of Arc, against woman's moral slavery sowed the seed which the closing years
                            of this century sees ripening into a recognition of woman's true place beside her brother in
                            every field of human effort and advance. When Ann Lee proclaimed the gospel of purity, she
                            inaugurated the first really great woman movement. Her conception of the woman movement,
                            however, was much larger than that of some of its later apostles. With the clearness of
                            vision of a great mother soul, Ann Lee from the first perceived that the true woman movement
                            must not be a sex but a race movement. She instinctively recognized the truth Walt Whitman
                            sings : "Unfolded out of the folds of the woman, man comes unfolded, as is always to come
                            unfolded." So the truth she proclaimed and preached is the truth that shall make men freemen
                            male and female, without regard to sex, race, color, creed or existing condition of
                            servitude. The millennium which Shakerism has in large degree realized, and to the fuller
                            realization of which its history and its teachings point the way, is a social organism in
                            which love shall be the supreme law, and the greatest good of every individual sought and
                            found, as it can only be found, in the greatest good of the social organism, to be attained
                            through absolutely unselfish unity of purpose and interest finding expression in highly
                            organized, intelligent and harmonious unity of action. It is only a truism to say that every
                            human advance has been marked by a breaking of old bonds and the attaining of greater and
                            greater freedom. In Tennyson's dedication To the Queen, he pointed out the chief distinction
                            of Victoria's reign when he wrote : <pb n="97" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 97 "And statesmen
                            at her council met Who knew the seasons when to take Occasion by the hand and make The
                            bounds of freedom wider yet." The successive steps in our growth and progress in art,
                            science, religion, philosophy and government, may as a rule, be traced to movements often
                            small in their beginnings, but gathering force and momentum as they grow, and finally moving
                            on over all obstacles and opposition by the irresistible force of truth. (To be
                        continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="Section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Friend;--'Life is real..." TEIform="index"/>Dear Friend;--'Life is real...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mt. Lebanon, March 1896" TEIform="index"/>[Letter from a young Believer
                                to an outside friend. "Out of the mouths of babes and sucklings thou hast perfected
                                praise."] Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. March, 1896.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Friend ; "Life is real, life is earnest, And the gra\e is not its goal, * Dust thou
                                art to dust returnest Was not spoken of the soul." These words, from Longfellow's Psalm
                                of Life, come to mind at this time, and I am impressed to write them. It seems to me
                                that a good, firm, strong faith in the immortality of the sonl is essential to the
                                happiness of our present lives. Never have I felt the land of spirits so near, never
                                have I felt so close a joining to those wrho have gone on before us, as at the present
                                time. The Shaker life is in a great measure calculated to develop the spiritual and
                                prepare souls for the work of higher spheres. This is indeed a holy and a pure gospel,
                                evidencing by its fruits that it is of the Christ Spirit. In your last letter you
                                express much the same feeling which I entertained for some time before coming here. You
                                say you "would be glad to find your place in the world of usefulness, and that you feel
                                like a stranger in a strange land." I remember how I longed to find some people with
                                whom I could share the joys and burdens of life; above all I longed to find some cause
                                worthy of my best effort's. Eureka ! (I have found it.) Indeed everyday that I pass here
                                only increases my desire and determination to make this cause mine, to make myself
                                worthy of so good and true a companionship. Life is now full of good things, not without
                                its rough places to be sure, but so different from the lives of those who have no hope.
                                I feel quite an interest in your travel of soul, for so I must consider your present
                                condition, and would be glad to extend a helping hand or do what is <pb n="98" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 98 THE MANIFESTO. best toward bringing you to a state of rest and peace. Do you not
                                think it would be well for you to investigate our life ? There is room among us for
                                every one who will come with a sincere desire for truth. Our gospel is no respector of
                                persons, all are on a common footing, equality is one of our cardinal principles. This
                                means quite a good deal, and I do not believe that any people can successfully establish
                                a community home except on a religious basis. The spiritual gift must be uppermost, or
                                the people perish. In our life there is a cross to be borne against the carnal nature
                                which we all have inherited, but once the separation from the world is made, and a real
                                gift for the work is obtained, life becomes indeed a blessing. Our life also is
                                necessarily a busy one as we have the material to maintain by hon est industry, but all
                                things are made easy to those who have understanding faith. The real beauty in our home
                                is that we are continually surrounded by those, who like ourselves are earnestly
                                striving for the higher life, ever ready to sustain us in every good and noble effort.
                                The only way for one to know the worth of this faith is to stop theorizing and come and
                                live it. The world is full of theory concerning the Christian life with but few who are
                                earnestly striving to put its principles into practice. I believe that nothing short of
                                the genuine practical life, as taught and lived by the lowly Nazarene, will bring
                                contentment to any in this sphere and everlasting joy to the soul in future states of
                                existence. You say you are troubled with the "blues." That is on account of your
                                solitary life perhaps, and I know the companionship of those who have much faith and
                                hope is a sure cure for that disease. Think the matter over and if you come to any
                                decision, let me know. I have no knowledge of the Colorado Co-operative Colony, but am
                                convinced that all such enterprises have in the past proved futile when established on a
                                purely material basis. Our people know from experience how hard it is to overcome the
                                selfishness of human nature so far as to admit of a successful co-operative or
                                communistic effort. As before stated, nothing but the true spirit of love and
                                forbearance founded upon a life of absolute purity will hold together any Community.
                                With kind regards I remain sincerely yours,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stewart, Ezra J." TEIform="persName"/>Ezra J. Stewart.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Self-culture is intellectual..." TEIform="index"/>Self-culture is intellectual...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Self-culture is intellectual, but never exalt the intellect above the moral principle. The
                            first grand principle of intellectual progress, is to receive the truth no matter how it
                            bears on myself. I must follow it no matter where it leads,, what interests it opposes, to
                            what persecution or loss it lays me open, from what party it severs me, or to what party it
                            allies me.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Channing" TEIform="persName"/>Dr. Channing.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Use, with religious awe..." TEIform="index"/>Use, with religious awe...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Use, with religious awe and reverence, God's holy name.</p></div2><pb n="99" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. JUNE, 1896. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is published by the "United
                            Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued regularly by
                            the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the religious
                            views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. Address all communications
                            to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. April. Thermometer. Ruin. Snow. 1895. 44.44 5 in. 0
                                in. 1896. 48. 1 " 4 " Highest Temp, during this mo. 84 above 0 Lowest " " " " 18 " '
                                Number of rainy days " " 4 " " snowy " " " 2 " clear " " " 1:5 " " cloudy" *' " 11 C. G.
                                Reed. South Family. May, 1896. As this is a fine spring morning with a bright sky,
                                bracing air and music of birds to be heard everywhere, we are induced to make you a
                                brief call just to tell you about home. Eldress Sophia Copley of Enfield, Conn, and
                                Sister Martha Johnson of Hancock, Mass., favored us with a flying visit one day. The
                                home here is being improved by the removal of some old fences and the building of new
                                ones; the orchards are being renovated, busy hands are trimming and grafting fruit
                                trees; when you come this way, which we hope will be before long, you shall dine on the
                                very best of fruits. Poultry culture is an important and profitable item in the domestic
                                economy. The industrious chicks deposited over two hundred and fifty doz. eggs the past
                                mo. These hens are not April fools. The dairy record for the last year records 3814 lbs.
                                of the finest quality of butter in market. Br. Wm, Thrasher passed his one hundredth
                                anniversary April 11. He enjoyed hearing some articles that were written for the
                                occasion. He is well and happy. Genevieve DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">North Family. May, 1893. The unfolding of leaf and blossom and the reclothing of the
                                destitute forms in the vegetable world with fresh and unsoiled garments, while beautiful
                                to view and inspiring to contemplate, reminds us that now is the acceptable time in
                                which the good seed should be sown and cared for if a harvest of those fruits which
                                bring joy to the reaper is to be expected. Action is at present the watchword on farm
                                and garden, and the toilers are up early preparing the soil for the reception of the
                                seed. The prospect for fruit in this section is very poor; many peach trees are frozen.
                                April, while giving us a week of tropical weather, was devoid of those "April showers
                                which bring May flowers" and at present writing we are greatly in need of rain. We
                                peruse with pleasure the Home Notes and have in mind some that we should be glad to see
                                occasional communications from in that department. The Manifesto is our interest, and
                                prayer is sent forth that it may prosper, and may the spirit of the Comforter be with
                                those who are directing its ministrations. Hamilton DeGraw.</p></div3><pb n="100" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">May, 1896. The theologies of all ages have had a powerful influence in shaping the lives
                                of humanity and advancing civilization. Today we know that all things that tend toward
                                the bettering of self-hood, or the advancement of society, are of God; and numberless
                                are the influences that work for our general good. Good literature, exhortations and
                                prayers, are three great forces effectual in the degree that they inspire to moral
                                activity and good works. Shingle sawing and gardening, combined with the usual invasion
                                of housecleaning are now in full operation, demanding consecrated hand service from
                                willing laborers. As willing hands make light work, so genuine heart goodr/ess is
                                productive of results that bespeak a living christliness, by which human life is brought
                                into rapport with the attributes of God. God, the beauty, wisdom and power, That governs
                                this world of ours; Evolves the crude ore into the flue; Makes life sparkle of the
                                divine. God, centered in spirits not of earth; Known in service of moral worth That
                                tells for justice, wisdom and love Blending mankind with Christ above. George H.
                            Baxter.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>West Pittsfield, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">May, 1896. As we look around us we are led to think of the wonderous changes two short
                                months can make. Fields that when we last called at the "Home Corner," were but white,
                                frozen plains, are now teeming with verdure. The trees have exchanged their white
                                garments for graceful and attractive suits of many colors. The birds have once more
                                joined usT and the twittering of the sparrows, the chirping of the friendly robin, the
                                piping of the bluebird and sweet melodies of the oriole, are heard from trees and
                                hedges. It is indeed a pleasant change. As the season for obtaining maple sap arrived, a
                                season which has generally failed to receive a celebration in our locality, our young
                                brother, Kudolph Kirsten became anxious to obtain some of the sweets, and in spite of
                                many prophecies of failure, tapped fifty trees, and for two weeks obtained from them a
                                good supply of excellently flavored sap, which after being duly subjected to the
                                necessary boi ing and purifying, gave as a result about twenty gallons of syrup. Elder
                                Louis, who has been spending a month at Florida, we were glad to welcome in our home
                                once more, and we listened with interest to his description of the "Flowery Land," which
                                has ever held forth so many inducements to the stranger, since the days when the search
                                for the "Spring of Immortal Youth,'" was instigated. Housecleaning is nearly completed.
                                For several weeks the fever raged, each day finding some new place for an attack, and so
                                continued until all places to locate itself were nearly exhausted when it moderated, and
                                is now in a quiet state of convalescence. Brother Ira, who though constantly employed
                                with many duties still is ever ready to do an act of kindness, has furnished us a long
                                hose which will easily carry water to every flower garden on the lawn, thus making the
                                task of keeping the soil moist much pleasanter. Fidelia Estdbrook.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harvard, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Harvard, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">May, 1896. Nature is now at her best. Fruit trees all in bloom, giving promise of an
                                abundant harvest, if no cruel frosts nor blight disappoint us. Meadows and gardens are
                                now suffering for much needed rain, as there has not enough fallen in four weeks to
                                moisten the earth and the mercury for the week past has ranged from 70 to 90 deg.
                                Planting and gardening are actively progressing, if we well improve the seed-time we may
                                hope for an abundant harvest. We have repaired and re-roofed some of our out-buildings,
                                which has improved <pb n="101" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE Mi INIFES TO. 101 their looks very much.
                                All our window sash are receiving a coat of paint. Our orchards have been under the
                                hands of the pruners and cultivators. With the life and activity of springtime may we
                                not be unmindful to keep alive the true spirit of Christ's kingdom of peace. Aftiraia M
                                liwllard.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Narcoossa, Florida" TEIform="index"/>Narcoossa, Florida</head><p TEIform="p">May 3, 1896. Ouk Friend The Manifesto;Sixty days without rain. Yesterday 1% in. of rain
                                with hail. Eleven pines are in blossom. Trees by watering are in prime condition. The
                                garden has taken on its summer rest. Cabbages, potatoes and beans remain to furnish our
                                table. We have dug two wells into the quicksands about 9 ft. deep from surface, with
                                cui'b ample to collect water. Br. Charles, who has been sick for the past week, is very
                                much better. For two days and two nights he received heroic care and attention. Elder
                                Louis Basting visited and worked with us in the garden and on the hammock for one week,
                                visiting the Big Dredge south of us and other places of interest and improvement. If it
                                were possible for him to stay with us we should have been thrice happy. His mission
                                could be felt if not spoken to the ear. May those penetrating x-rays of every good
                                testimony find the shutter over a broken heart ever open, that they may permeate and
                                mold anew our thoughts and affections, and may we carefully close our heart to every
                                selfish feeling and cruel thought lest the impression taken be too deep to erase.
                                Florida.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station, Ct.</head><p TEIform="p">May, 1896. Jesus said, "Come unto me all ye that labor and are heavy laden, and I will
                                give you rest." Why may we not have more of that rest, more of that joy? Why may we not
                                even here breathe the pure air of heaven and be strengthened by the sweet songs of peace
                                the angels sing? Let us never be discouraged by trials. If we firmly resolve to subdue
                                wrong we can do it. We should not be disheartened at slow progress, little by little
                                great things are accomplished; "with truth for our standard" success will be be certain.
                                Avoid all that leads to sin, is a commind of no small import. Nothing is more beautiful
                                than purity, it was this that made our Savior's character divine. It is one of our
                                golden opportunities to be watchful and prayerful. Patient continuance in well-doing
                                will be crowned with success. The way of success is according to the commandment of God.
                                ****** * "The largest library is in Paris, the Xational, containing 2,200,000 volumes."
                                "The great bell in Japan is 24 ft. high and 16 ft. in diameter across the rim." "Pekin,
                                China, has the oldest paper, its age is one thousand years." "The largest lemon was sent
                                to market from Florida in 1888, it weighed 2 lbs. and 2 oz." Daniel Orcutt.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Union Village, Ohio" TEIform="index"/> Union Village, O.</head><p TEIform="p">May, 1896. We are being favored with some nice showers these times which is a blessing we
                                have had to do without, for quite a long time. But Ohio can safely take the blame to
                                herself for her scarcity of showers of rain during the last several years, for the good
                                Lord and Father of us all, had provided a grand and sublime system of irrigation for his
                                Ohio children, and it remained in active and successful operation for a great many
                                years. At last the worship of Mammon, became the all absorbing interest of the
                                inhabitants of our beautiful state. The Father had previously erected thousands and
                                thousands of pumps of the most elegant structure <pb n="102" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 102 THE
                                MANIFESTO. capable of supplying the whole state with an all sufficiency of water. These
                                consisted of beautiful trees scattered all over the land, from end to end of our
                                beautiful state, ome of these irrigating machines were so efficient, that 1000 of them
                                would carry into the atmosphere in one year, 7,000,000 tons of water. All this beautiful
                                machinery of the Lord's planting, has been ruthlessly torn away, so we are now, and have
                                been for several years, suffering for our lust and greed of the Almighty dollar, and we
                                are so blindly infatuated by this sordid Moloch of selfishness, that we are making no
                                provision for anything better by passing forestry laws for the piotection of what few
                                forests yet remain to us and the possible restoration once more, of our beautiful State,
                                to her original moisture and fertility. History assures us, that millions of acres of
                                land in Persia and China, once fertile as the garden of Eden, are now weird wastes of
                                sand, on which not one spear of grass can be found and all from the ruthless destruction
                                of the forests with which they were formerly clothed. Well! I suppose we must learn by
                                what we suffer. Egypt and Algiers are rainless regions, but since the French have
                                occupied the latter, they have sunk Artesian wells, and set out hundreds and thousands
                                of trees, now they have several fine showers in a season and expect to entirely restore
                                the country to a rich standard of fertility in process of time. Well! we are all well
                                and things are going at about their usual rate and the times are rather barren of
                                incident. During the last winter a good deal of repairing has been done also painting
                                and whitewashing. We have a grand prospect of fruit, if the frost will only let it
                                alone. We most earnestly wish The Manifesto all possible success and the worthy Society
                                and operators who print and conduct the same. Oliver V. Hampton.</p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Uniformity of thought..." TEIform="index"/>Uniformity of thought...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Uniformity of thought makes an orderly intellect; uniformity of purpose a well regulated
                                life.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="V., C. C." TEIform="persName"/>C. C. V.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To the Dear Brethren and Sisters..." TEIform="index"/>To the Dear Brethren and Sisters...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">[ We have received the parting blessing of a Brother in the faith who lived in the city
                                of Philadelphia. He passed away on the 9th\of last March, at the age of 57 years. Ed ]
                                To the Dear Brethren and Sisters: We are remembering with great pleasure the visit of
                                Eldress Alvira to our family, and also the birthday of our blessed Mother Ann Lee,
                                February 29. To the beloved Editor of The Manifesto we send hearty greetings and love
                                for the many kind favors we have received. By this note I show my thankfulness, and not
                                only for myself, but also our little family in the city of brotherly love, who have
                                through your liberality been blest with copies, each month, of The Manifesto. I also
                                remember with pleasure, and in all kindness, my privilege to visit the dear friends at
                                Mt. Lebanon, at Watervliet, and at West Pittsfield, in 1882. Affectionately,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Meltzer, August" TEIform="persName"/>August Meltzer.</byline></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">[The above was received in a letter written by Sr. Rebecca Jackson. In her letter she
                                says that she shall visit the Community at Watervliet, N. Y., in company with another
                                Sister on the 18th of May, and in all probability make it their home for the future.
                                Ed.]</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">North Family. May, 1896. There is so much to write that is lovely and fair, That I
                                scarcely know where to begin it, nor where It is best to conclude, but will keep to the
                                rule That stands on the square of four fifties, nor let My words 'yond the Editor's
                                limit to roam' Lest in future he begs me to keep them at home. Earth and air, sea and
                                sky are in grand competition, Each seeks to be first in their beautiful mission, God
                                might have created a handsomer sphere, But he surely did not, perfect beauty is here.
                                The spring work advances, and over the land The bountiful sower outstretches his hand,
                                Already the sowing counts up by the score, For the Brethren have sowed forty acres or
                                more. The Sisters are sewing a different way, With success that <pb n="103" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/>
                                THE MANIFESTO. 103 is sometimes as varied as May, For the nonce I'd suggest (as all
                                house-keepers can) That our genius all follows tlie housecleaning plan. So, in loving
                                and blessing and helping each other, We find the true friendship cf sister and brother,
                                And over our home like an archway of gold The love of our Parents above we behold, This
                                light and this love lengthening out like a chain Encircles us all from Kentucky to
                                Maine. Cora C. Vinneo.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tribute to the memory of elder John B. Vance" TEIform="index"/>A Tribute to the Memory of
                            Elder JOHN B. VANCE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cummings, Ada S." TEIform="persName"/>By Ada S. Cummings.</byline><p TEIform="p">The golden sunset's splendor, With its rays so calmly sweet; Settles down on all so tender,
                            When the day's work is complete. And its radiant cloudlets, gleaming As a beautiful,
                            brilliant light; Unfold the twilight's beaming, Betokening the night. Away in the glimmering
                            brightness, When its power enchants the soul, We may see our father's likeness, Where the
                            rays of light control. And there, through the golden beauty, With the radiant spirit band,
                            We know he entered safely The beautiful "Summer Land." Ere the last, bright sunbeam fadeth
                            Shutting out the golden light, We may catch a gleam of rapture From our father's home,
                            to-night. We may peer beyond the cloudlets, When the sun sinks in the west, But the mystery
                            we can not fathom Of Eternity's sweet rest. But we love to think of our dear one Beyond the
                            sunset land, Arrayed in spotless garments, With the purified angel band. Beside the crystal
                            streamlet, Where the purest waters flow, 0 there, at my life's sunset! 1 too, would like to
                            go. And when the twilight deepens, And Time's dark shadows fall, May we all, like him, be
                            ready To obey the Keaper's call. He responded to the summons When his work below was o'er;
                            When he saw the golden beauty That was gilding hill and shore. He knew that angels waited To
                            bear his soul away, Into the Holy City, Into the realms of day. Now when the evening
                            twilight Comes flooding o'er the lea, We'll think of thee, our father, Immortalized and
                            free. Sahbathday Lake, Me.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In memory of our brother, David Ray" TEIform="index"/>In Memory of our Brother, DAVID RAY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Agnew, Hannah R." TEIform="persName"/>Jiy Hannah It. Agnew.</byline><p TEIform="p">Dear Brother, go and take your rest On the immortal shore, By all the faithful you are blest
                            Time's toilsome march is o'er. Those worthy souls you love so well, The guardians of your
                            youth, Who led you, we are pleased to tell, In ways of light and truth, Will greet you in
                            that land of love And make you welcome there To join the angel host above The joys of heaven
                            to share. We, in the varied walks of life, Will miss our brother here; His words and acts
                            with kindness rife, Did often please and cheer. He lent a helping hand to all Who ever
                            sought his aid, No matter whether great or small If plans were rightly laid. Here in the
                            vineyard of the Lord, Was faithful in his day; His patient toil brings rich reward
                            Sufficient to repay. Farewell, dear brother, till we meet Again in heaven above; Long in our
                            memory we shall keep Your kindly acts of love. <pb n="104" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 104 THE MANIFESTO. As
                            one by one, friends drop away, Are we prepared to go? The call will come to us some day, But
                            when, we can not know. Again one more has gone before, And left us, toiling on; The moments
                            fly, and passing by, Say we shall soon be gone. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary.</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Drugs and kidney diseases" TEIform="index"/> DRUGS AND KIDNEY DISEASES.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> Pbohably the majority of people are not aware of the fact that the poisonous
                                        medicines taken into the stomach must be eliminated through the excretory
                                        organs, and chiefly through the kidneys. Many drastic drugs which are not at all
                                        unpalatable, and which can be swallowed easily in considerable doses and without
                                        disturbing the stomach, are extremely irritating to the kidneys, and much
                                        mischief is done to these important organs when they are required to eliminate,
                                        day after day, the doses of poisons swallowed with the supposition that they
                                        will somehow cure a chronic cough, a disordered digestion or a torpid liver. The
                                        continued use of arsenic for a skin disease, iodide of potash or mercury for
                                        some constitutional malady, or of simple chlorate of potash for a throat or
                                        bronchial affection, may be the means of setting up an incurable kidney disease.
                                        The last named drug is perhaps particularly dangerous, because commonly regarded
                                        as harmless. It is extremely irritating to the kidneys as well as depressing to
                                        the heart, and many persons have doubtless been greatly injured by its frequent
                                        and long continued use.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The New York Papers..." TEIform="index"/>The New York Papers...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> The New York Papers tell us of a man who had become so hoglike that he ate
                                        seven pickled pig's feet at a single meal. In twenty-four hours he was dead from
                                        acute indigestion. !S"o doubt the hogs rejoiced at such an act of justice.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Temple of Health" TEIform="index"/>Temple of Health.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Many people, after almost gorging themselves..." TEIform="index"/>Many people, after almost gorging themselves...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> Many people, after almost gorging themselves with unwholesome food, will eat
                                        some luscious, healthful fruit right on top of it, and then because they are
                                        ill, will declare that fruit does not agree with them.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Universal Republic" TEIform="index"/>Universal Republic.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Publication" TEIform="index"/>KIND WORDS.</head><div3 type="shaker-press" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Manifesto is published monthly..." TEIform="index"/>The Manifesto is published monthly...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> "The Manifesto is published monthly by the Shakers at East Canterbury, N. H.
                                        It is one of the best and cleanest monthlies published."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Temple of Health" TEIform="index"/>Temple of Health.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="shaker-press" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Manifesto, a bright, fresh magazine..." TEIform="index"/>The Manifesto, a bright, fresh magazine...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> "The Manifesto, a bright, fresh magazine published monthly by the Shaker
                                        Community at East Canterbury, N. H. For close and practical observations of
                                        nature's lawsfor industry, sobriety and righteousnessfor keen sagacity in
                                        detecting shams and fraudsfor kindly brotherhood, fairness in criticism and
                                        withal, healthy, harmless and genial humorcommend us to the honest, thrifty
                                        Shakers."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Word and Works" TEIform="index"/>Word and Works.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ten persons were recently burned to death..." TEIform="index"/>Ten persons were recently burned to death...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Ten persons were recently burned to death in Pachuca, Mex. They were condemned as heretics.
                            The judge said he was acting according to the will of God, manifested to him in a
                        vision.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Newton, Ezra" TEIform="index"/>Ezra Newton
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Ezra Newton, at Harvard, Mass. April 23, 1896. Age 101 yrs. 1 mo. and 27 days. The
                                obsequies were more in the nature of a memorial meeting than anything else, where all
                                the Brothers and Sisters gathered together in the common meeting place and paid their
                                last tribute of love and respect to one who had beefl associated with the Shaker
                                settlement for nearly half a century. A very interesting and extended account of the
                                funeral services was published in the Worcester Telegram of April 27, 1896.</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p19"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
written as to be very interesting and very instructive for all ages. Many other articles
may be found in the Journal that will prove
valuable to the Reader. Fowlek & Wells
Co., 27 East 21st St. New York City.
"Humanity" is a pamphlet of nearly 100
pages. It is said to be for the people now on
the  earth,  and No. 2. of Vol. I., is true to  that
statement. The subjects treated are of interest to the general Reader and a copy is worth
your perusing Published at Kansas City, Mo1215 Oak St.   Price 5 cents.
How to Disinfect is a Guide to Practical
Disinfection by C. T. Kingzett, F. I. C. It is a
book of 96 pages and shoul.l be studied to
know its real value. Price 10 cts. Published
by The American and Continental Sanitas Co.
636 West 55th St., New York City.
Alaska needs no instruction as to the position of the New woman. "The woman in Alaska is the superior being, The child belongs
to the mother's totem or clan, and if tribal war
occurs, he fights on his mother's side." Thus
writes Mary C. De Vore in an illustrated
sketch of "Child Life in Alaska," in the Sun
day School Times of April 11, 1896. Mrs. De
Vore, who was for some years in active mission work in Alaska, treats her subject in a
vivacious and entertaining way, and manages
incidentally, to supply her reader with a dea.
of information on all phases of Alaskan life.
Louisa M. Alcott is said to reveal herself in
a most interesting way in a number of letters
(written to five little girls) which are to appear in the April Ladies'1 Home Journal. These
letters were written during the busiest period
of Miss Alcott's life, anil present a pen picture of the author drawn by her own master
hand. In these she talks with singular frankness of herself, her work, her aims, her home,
her spiritual belief, and of the influence that
directed her to literature. She never saw any
of her five correspondents, but their youthful
frankness, intense interest in all her writings,
and their love for the author and for the char
acters of her creations, impelled her to turn
aside from her work and cares to find diversion in chats with sujh eagerly enthusiastic,
admiring and sympathetic friends. Miss Alcott's first letter is dated 1872, and the others
were written at intervals up to within a short
time of her death.
"Scientific Demonstration of Theology,
Prophecy and Revelation." by H. B. Bear.
This work, just from the press, is a pamphlet
of 44 pages. Elder Henry says the book is
designed for a text book and is a quick method to arrive at a scientific knowledge of the
subjects.
Published by H. B. Bear, Preston, Ohio.
Colonel John J. Garnett, of the Confederate
States Artillery> lias contributed to the "Lee
of Virginia" series now running in Frank
Leslie's Popular Monthly, a paper on "The
Seven Days' Campaign near Richmond." It
appears in the June number, and describes
the second battle of Manassas, the first invasion of Maryland, and the battle of Antietam.
The article is handsomely illustrated with
battle scenes and portraits of General Lee,
Stonewall Jackson, General Johnston and
others. In the same number of the Popular
Monthly is an interesting article about
Sarah Bornhardt, "the Genius of Tragedy," by
W. de Wagstaffe, with a number of portraits
of the great actress in her various characters.
Then there is a description of "The Ladies of
the Harem1," telling of their life, amusements,
etc., and beautifully pictured. Other features
are: An account of a visit to Dalmatia, by
Robert Howard Russell; "In the Grand Canon
of the Colorado," by Edith Sessions Tupper;
"In the Land of St. Francis," Marie D. Walsh;
an entertaining article on pistols and their
early history and use, by John Paul Bocock;
laid the first installment of a new department
for young people, containing a serial story by
Horatio Alger, Jr, and a short bicycle story
by Henry E. Haydock. Besides all this there
are some excellent stories and poems.
the mm covenant.
This work sets forth the form of appointment, the qualifications and powers of the
several
ORDERS    OF   OFFICERS
in the Community : of the
PRIVILEGES  and OBLIGATIONS
of all the Members, and of the
DEDICATION     AND     CONSECRATION
of persons and property.
The book will afford interest to all, and at
he same time, afford instruction to all  inquiring  minds.    Price 5  cts. each,  postage
paid, or 36 cts. per doz.
<pb n="" id="p20"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure.
For information and free Handbook write to
MUNN & CO., 361 Broadway, New York.
Oldest bureau for securing patents in America.
Every patent taken out by us is brouirht before
the public by a notice given free of charge in the
Largest circulation of any scientific paper in th
world. Splendidly illustrated. No intcUi^r.t
man should be without it. Weekly, <srj fca
year; $l.r.O six months. Address, MUNN'& GO,,
Publishkrs, 361 Broadway, New York City,
A cream  of  tartar  baking   powder.
Highest of fill in leavening strength.
Latest   United   States   Government
Food report.
Eoyal Baking Powder Go.
106 Wall St., N. Y.
AND
SH AKERISM.
A synopsis of Theology of the United   Society   of   Believers   in   Christ's
Second Appearing.    Illustrated.
By Giles B. Avery.
Price,  15cts.
BRIEF EXPOSITION
OF   THE
Principles and Regulations
of the
SOCIETY   OF   BELIEVERS.
Price, 10 cts.
WANTED
Good reliable men, to sell
our Choice and Hardy
Nursery Stock such as Fruit
Trees, Roses Shrubs and Ornamentals. Toadies make this business a success. Easy work, pleasant, light and profitable. Outfit Free. Apply at once, with references, and secure choice of territory.
F. N. may COMPANY,
Nurserymen and Seedsmen, Rochester, IT. Y.
POUR
By Pressing the Lid.
"INTERPRETING PROPHECY"
AND   THE
"Appearing of Christ,"
is  the  title  of  a  neat little pamphlet of
some forty pages, just sent out by A. G.
HOLLISTER Of MT. LEBANON, N. Y.
The many at the present time who are
interested in the fulfillment of prophecy
and in its mathematical calculation, will
find themselves by the side of the good
old prophet Daniel, and with him illustrating the Coming of Christ so clearl
that no occasion can arise for the least
doubt.                             Price, 10 cts.
Tea and Coffee Pots that pour by the lid without lifting or tipping.     Simple beyond belief.
Practical and artistic.   Send for pamphlet.
THE ASBURY-PAINE MFG. CO., Phila,, Pa.
This ia a good thingEd.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>