<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ss0308" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">Shaker and Shakeress</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Society</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Mount Lebanon, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">3</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">8</biblScope><date value="18730801" TEIform="date">August 1873</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">57-64</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="3" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="57" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="8" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!-- <p>Vol. III. No. 8. PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETY. F. W. EVANS, , r T , ^ , _ ^x ^ . on/o Fifty Cents Editor.
                        Mt. Lebanon, Col. Co. N. Y. August, 1873. PER ANKUM</p>
                    --><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Literature" TEIform="index"/>LITERATURE</head><p TEIform="p">Every spiritual — religious — Dispensation creates its own Literature. The first call of the Spirit, whenever a
                            new Divine influx flows to humanity, is, to repent, i. e., forsake; for that is repentance. When the
                            dispensation was external, like that of the Jewish, the forsaking was external. The Jews heard the voice of the
                            Spirit: "Israel shall dwell alone, and shall not be numbered — mixed — with the nations." " Get thee out from
                            thy kindred and country, unto a land that I will shew thee of," was the imperative command to Abram, the "father
                            of the faithful" to the Spirit's call. When his posterity had multiplied into a tribe, they went down into
                            Egypt; and, when these had become twelve tribes, and had in- creased into a nation, the Spirit repeated the same
                            command: "Go up out of Egypt into the land I promised Abram that I would give to his descendants." When they
                            obeyed this call, it was by forsaking all that they had acquired in Egypt. And the whole nation emigrated from
                            Egypt, the garden of the world, as literally as Abram emigrated from Mesopotamia, the garden of Asia. In thus
                            moving from Egypt, in a body, it is evident that they left its literature as truly as their ancestors forsook
                            the literature of the East; and, in both instances, the very highest art, the deepest science — the most
                            profound literature of the then known world — was what the Spirit of Truth— God—required them to abjure, andto
                            utterly destroy and leave behind them. It may also be observed, that, in both instances, the justifying reason —
                            the causes — were similar; that is, the literature had been created by the Dispensation — was the product and
                            expression of the real mental, physical, and spiritual condition of the people — was imperfect and wicked —
                            idolatrous — the "old heavens," that must "pass away." Hence, to break the images, throw down the sacred altars
                            on which their religious sacrifices had been offered, cut down the groves, kill the priests who officiated, and
                            trample under foot the mementoes of the whole Order, were common occurrences under the law of progress. Abram
                            did it; Moses did it; and Gideon did it. Indeed it was the universal practice of Avators. Consequently, the
                            charge of ignorance, from learned worldlings, was invariably preferred against them — woe to Alexandrian
                            libraries. Was not the charge well-founded? The Jews cut themselves off from the sources of knowledge known to
                            the Egyptians, plunged into a wilderness where there were no schools, and where even agriculture could not be
                            practised. The Spirit who led them supplied their every need of food and clothing. RESULT. The result was as
                            unlooked-for as it was extraordinary and world-wide wonderful. For, behold, the traditional journal kept by
                            those twelve tribes of wandering, vagabond slaves, who were self-emancipated, is, to-day, the foundation of the
                            literature of Christendom. What a comment this is upon the wisdom of man, in competition with the " wisdom that
                            comes from above" — by revelation — the learning, arts, science, and literature of the passing-away cycle. Nor
                            is this marvelous; it is not a solitary or isolated instance; but a law looms up in our spiritual horizon, that
                            is as universal in its application as it is in its effects: each Dispensation of God to man, and each cycle in a
                            Dispensation, create their own literature. In the cases of Moses, we have a man who was "learned in all the
                            learning of the Egyptians." Not so the general rule. Of Jesus it was asked, with astonishment, " Whence hath
                            this man this wisdom, seeing that he knoweth not letters ? " He was ignorant of the learning of the Dispensation
                            and cycle to which he had belonged. " Except a man forsakes all that he hath, he cannot be my disciple,"
                            included the literature of the past and passing-away Dispensation. The twelve Apostles are known to history as
                            ignorant fishermen. The early Christians were charged, by Celsus, with preferring the unlearned and low to the
                            more cultivated and refined classes, as converts to, and members of, their system. " Not many wise, not many
                            noble, not many strong, are called." Hath not God called the opposite to them ? the ignorant to confound the
                            wise; the weak to oppose the strong; and the off-scouring of the earth to compete with the learning of the
                            polished Greeks, and Roman philosophers, until it converted them ? What again was the result ? As before, these
                            simple Christians, who, in passing through the Hermit Age, spent a generation in the deserts of Egypt, in caves
                            or holes of the earth, without books or human society, as Israel spent a generation in the wilderness, separated
                            from the civilized world; and, like them, left a posterity — monks and nuns, who founded and formed the Monastic
                            Orders of Christendom. For, truly, more have been the children of those "eunuchs for the kingdom of heaven's
                            sake," than of the married Israelites in the wilderness; albeit they confined physical commerce to the use that
                            Nature designed. And those celibates have produced a literature that, to-day, is the literature of Christendom.
                            And as, " by reason of use," the Law becomes more possible to the race, we now have, in twenty-five years time,
                            a new literature, of mesmerism, phrenology, biology, psychology, electricity, rappings, table-tippings, dreams,
                            visions, prophecies and revelations, created by the Spiritualists; not so distinct from the old as in the
                            preceding instances already cited, for the simple reason that they have not been so much a new spiritual —
                            religious— people, but rather a scientific people, an outgrowth from the order of Christ's first appearing-—-a
                            John the Baptist epoch—-to bring the old and new, the First and Second Christian Churches, together. Query ?
                            Will not this Second Christian, or Shaker, Church — this Gospel of Christ — create its own literature? I tell
                            you Tea, and that right speedily!!!</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Revelation vs. experience" TEIform="index"/>REVELATION v. EXPERIENCE</head><p TEIform="p">Kevelation is the unfoldment of truth from the infinite to the finite mind — a means by which the ignorance of
                            the finite is supplemented by the knowledge of the infinite. The experience of human beings upon earth should
                            agree with and confirm the revelation of God through the heavens. The scope of revelation is comprehensive —
                            vast — connecting time and eternity. Individual experience is limited — incomplete ; but the experience of the
                            race collectively is full of confirmations of divine revelation. A pure crystal stream gushes forth high up some
                            mountain side, free from adulterous mixtures, as it flows over the clear rock-bed, until it reaches the rich
                            alluvial soil of the lower lands, when it becomes surcharged with particles of earthy matter, and enters the sea
                            as a dark and turbid river; the limpid fountain, changed to the conglomerate waters that go to make the sea,
                            shows the nature of the passage through intervening channels between the fountain and the ocean. Is it not thus
                            with the spiritual fountain — Revelation — as compared with the records termed Bibles? Sacred and profane
                            history interblended; the inspiration of the Prophets, and the divine mission of the priesthood, interwoven with
                            the history of kings and despots, and the chronicles of the bloody wars attending the rise and fall of nations,
                            that darken and almost obliterate the beautiful primal <pb n="58" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 58 SHAKER AND truths sought to be
                            conveyed to humanity by means of divine revelation. Yet, notwithstanding the blindness of the mental, and the
                            confusion of the physical condition and surroundings of the earthly re- cipients of revelation, its pure
                            abstract truths will stand through all coming time as being applicable to the final improvement of humanity ;
                            and future human experience will demon- strate that they underlie the basic foundations of the civil and
                            religious governments of a perfected God-governed race. If the vail, or rites and ceremonies connected with the
                            Mosaic Dispensation, be drawn aside, we shall discover principles involved in that system — an aggregation of
                            truths — adapted to the amelioration of present social conditions, and to the removal of society ills, not
                            elsewhere to be found. Although revealed thousands of years ago, they are the germs of all the reformatory
                            agitations and projected modern improve- ments in physiology, the equalization of property (by co-operation and
                            communism), land reforms — republicanism in general; the equal rights of the sexes, of labor; the distribution
                            of accumulated wealth, by bankrupt and homestead laws, and freedom of the public lands. These all had their
                            actualized antetypes in those long-ago revelations and human experiences which constitute the backbone of Bible
                            history. Men search the foundations of the earth for the testimonies of the rocks. They analyze all known
                            substances in their pursuit of physical truth. The starry heavens are pierced for hidden knowledge. The works of
                            Nature declare the truths of Nature's God, as do not the perverted passions and distorted affections of purblind
                            humans. So it is with true revelation in spiritual things. The founders of our infidel civil government turned
                            back to the Mosaic epoch for the model of human rights which they introduced in the Declaration of Independence.
                            Each advancing revolution in society centers around some one or more of these revealed principles of the past.
                            As well attempt to erect a building without foundations, as to build up society, in natural or spiritual things,
                            upon any other basis than the truths of the past.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Smith, Thomas" TEIform="persName"/>Thomas Smith, Canaan, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Word of God and the bible" TEIform="index"/>THE WORD OF GOD AND THE BIBLE</head><p TEIform="p">A vekt common, if not the almost universal understanding of professed Christians, is that the Bible and Word of
                            God are not only synonymous terms, but synonymous facts. But the revelations of God's truth, whether made cycles
                            of ages past, or in the days of Jesus Christ on earth, or in the present time, do not thus declare it. The "
                            Word of God" is a power that has stirred the pulse, warmed the heart, exalted the humble, humbled the exalted,
                            inspired the faithful, bound up the broken-hearted, comforted the afflicted, invigorated the feeble in spirit,
                            and " given to the righteous beauty for ashes, the garment of praise for the spirit of heaviness." The great
                            Hindoo reformer, Babboo Keshub Chunder Sen, who visited England in the year 1871, to determine whether it would
                            be advisable to introduce Christianity among the Hindoos, as he was about to return home, made this significant
                            remark: " There is a striving everywhere to find God externally, in forms, ceremonies, dogmas; that the mind
                            wants spiritual food is very little thought of." So there is a striving to find the " Word of God " in books ;
                            and the Spirit — God — in incarnations; apparently not awakened to realize that the " Word of God " is revealing
                            a God-character infinitely superior to the Jehovah of the Jews; a living Spirit Christ, illimitably transcending
                            the crucified and worshiped human form of Jesus; and an ever-evolving testimony of living truth; making more of
                            the " Word of God" than is contained in all the Bibles of the nations combined. The " Word of God," as defined
                            by the English Bible, is a testimony, " sharp, powerful, piercing, to the dividing asunder of soul and spirit,
                            the joints and the marrow, and is a discerner of the thoughts and intents of the heart." But who ever conceived
                            the Bible to possess this power ? The " Word of God " is light, life, and the power of salvation. It is a
                            revelation of God's will and purpose concerning the evolving destiny of man. It is a baptism of divine power in
                            such manner and measure as to magnetize and vivify the whole man — body, soul and spirit — with an intense
                            interest in, ]ove for, and devotion to, the salvation, development, and glorification of the human race. It is a
                            ministration of love so endearing and soul-thrilling as to cause its recipient to sacri- fice life for the
                            salvation of the object of the soul's affections and beatitude. But all the Bibles in the universe never
                            produced — never can produce — these effects. The Bible of the so-called Christians, as well as the bibles —
                            sacred books — of all nations and religious beliefs, when spoken of in their best estate, are nothing more than
                            records; and more or less sacred, as they more or less record God's Word unadulterated by the policy, ambition,
                            cupidity, or wickedness of man. Though this statement may grate harshly on the sensibilities of those Bible
                            adorers who consider that " every word embraced between the lids of the Bible is the ' Word of God,'" an
                            inspired utterance, and necessary for the salvation and redemption of man, yet darkened humanity needs the
                            utterance of truth. It is not our purpose, however, to rob the Bible of its meed and coronal among books ; nor
                            to detract from it that sacred regard which it justly claims in the estimation of those who have, through the
                            perusal of its records of the " Word of God," been ushered into the gush- ing baptisms of its power; far from
                            it; our purpose is precisely the reverse of this. We would woo souls to the perusal of its sacred pages, in
                            search of the utterances of truth, the power of which might become the " Word of God " for their salvation. The
                            " Word of God" is being spoken by spirits who are under the baptisms of the fire of truth, and whose utterances
                            are coals from off its burning altars. Under these baptismal inspirations, minds are being enlightened to see
                            the Bible in its real character as a book, stripped of the delusions of a false theology, which has been
                            spreading saintly robes over the records of base, sinful deeds, for centuries, and calling those records the "
                            Word of God." The character of the Bible, spoken of as a whole, is as multiform as is that of the authors who
                            wrought in its production; and, to speak of it wisely, one needs continually to heed the admonitory proverb, "
                            Speak of me as I am; nothing extenuate, nor set down aught in malice." Nothing is gained to the glorious cause
                            of salvation and redemption of the human race, to which the Bible is religiously consecrated, in the vain effort
                            to harmonize the multitudinous contradictory texts thereof; or in the attempt to reconcile its allegorical
                            Genesis with the more substantial and undeniable geological records, penned by the finger of God in the
                            everlasting rocks innumerable ages before the writers of Genesis had a being. Our race is not benefited by the
                            miserable effort of theological (not ritual) Christianity to canonize as sacred history those secular records of
                            the Bible which possess no more claims to inspiration than do the writings of Flavius Josephus, and which, with
                            reference to modesty and purity, when judged by biblical injunction, as a " tree known by its fruits," need
                            expurgation. It does not contribute to the cause of truth, to stamp as " sacred" and the " Word of God," those
                            biographical biblical records which portray the life-characters of men and deeds so base that all the vails of
                            theological Christian charity could never cover sufficiently to withhold the blush of shame from the cheek of
                            modesty while perusing them ; and the effects of such records, though compiled with sacred Bible, has, no doubt,
                            immensely contributed to the production of immorality, vice and crime, inasmuch as the actors in this drama of
                            shame have been held as sacred exemplars for pattern; but, without doubt, it would have been better for humanity
                            had the biblical records of such characters been consigned to oblivion by the flames, rather than canonized as "
                            The Word of God." It has been very truly said, " There is not only no statement in the Scriptures that the whole
                            Bible is the ' Word of God,' but there is no one of the writers thereof who claims that his particular book, or
                            books, is or are such ; " and we would show that not one, even of its most precious and ever-to-be-hallowed
                            records of inspired truth, is the " Word of God" but is simply the record of that" Word." Paul, indeed,
                            declared, " All Scripture * is given by inspiration of God, and is profitable for doctrine, for reproof, for
                            correction," etc. But, if we are to try Paul by his doctrines, this remark, and this " all" must be understood
                            in a very limited sense — in much the same sense as where it is said, " all the region round about Jordan went
                            to be baptized of John, in Jordan; " for Paul says : " Sin, taking occasion by the commandment, wrought in me
                            all manner of concupiscence." This certainly was not very "profitable." Again : " For what the law could not do,
                            in that it was weak, through the flesh, God, sending his own Son, condemned sin in the flesh." But, when Paul
                            thus spake of the Scriptures, the New Testament was not written ; and it was not possible for him to refer to
                            the hundreds of translations of the Old as well as the New Testament which have since been made; in the English
                            translation of which, the American Bible Society's Committee of Examination and Comparison with the original
                            manuscripts found " twentyfour thousand errors!" and of which the British and Foreign Bible Society, after
                            having * This should be rendered, All Scripture that is given by inspiration of God. And Adam Clarke says: "
                            This sentence is not well translated. The original should be rendered, Every writing that is given by
                            inspiration of God." Ed. <pb n="59" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> circulated millions of copies thereof, has declared that" a
                            faithful examination of it, gives rise to serious doubts whether it can be called the Word of God." * And,
                            taking Paul's testimony for the plenary inspiration of the Scriptures, and trying his testimony by himself, we
                            have no reason for supposing that he referred to every word of those thousand translations of the Scriptures
                            into all languages, whether concerning secular, historical, or religious matters ; or that he considered them
                            all plenarily inspired, and equally Divine truth, whether those words set forth the contradictory statement,
                            that King David was a " man after God's own heart" at the time he was reveling in the contemplation of the
                            murder of Uriah, and when he was committing adultery with Bathsheba; or whether they were recording the Divine
                            behests of the Law of Moses, or (which had not then been recorded) Christ's Sermon on the Mount; thus claiming a
                            full and continuous baptism of Divine light, illuminating every scholar in every language who ever assisted in
                            the translation of the Scriptures, whether they were contending with each other about Greek, Hebrew, and Latin
                            verbs, or combining to introduce an interpolation of a paragraph (as all prominent scholars admit the seventh
                            verse of chap. v. of John's First Epistle to be, and which cannot be found in more than three of the three
                            hundred ancient manuscripts, and only one of these deemed at all reliable, besides numerous others), or even
                            interpolations of whole chapters which can as easily be proved. As much as Paul had to learn and unlearn in the
                            school of Christ, he is not justly chargeable when inspirationally understood, with being the head of that band
                            of theological religionists who would throw together, into one common sink, secular and sacred history — the
                            records of the criminal prostitutions of some of the ancients, with those of ancient Prophets and holy men, and
                            their Divine revelations — calling them all the infallible " Word of God." The effect of biblical theology,
                            unaccompanied by the rays of the sun of revelation, has been, to establish a belief, that, while continuous
                            manifestations of greater truth in natural philosophy, science, and art, are vouchsafed to man, in religion, the
                            revelations of truth were sealed up with the final book of the Eevelation of St. John ; and that an utter end of
                            progress in revelation has been Divinely ordained. On the other hand, the effect of modern spiritualistic
                            revelation, added to the scholastic and scientific researches of " free religion" of these latter days, upon the
                            juvenile, the unsectarian, the unreligious, and the novitiate Christian portions of society, is to throw to the
                            winds the entire Bible as a worthless book; to ridicule it, and its devotees as worshipers of " they know not
                            what." This antipodal swing of the pendulum was ages ago, anticipated by the Spirit: " He that killeth you, will
                            think that he is doing God service," has been fulfilled to the letter, by both Greek, Catholic, and Protestant
                            churches. The devilish Inquisition, the Duke of Alva's wars, and the St. Bartholomew's massacre produced
                            reactionary powers— "horns" — which brought forth the French Revolution the utter abrogation of the
                            falsely-called * See address of Dr. T. S. Bell, before the Bible Revision Association, 1858. Christian religion
                            — its priesthood, sabbath, and Bible; the enthronement of the goddess of Liberty, Reason, and Fraternity, which
                            finally culminated in the founding of a State without a Church, giving to every individual an absolute right to
                            assume the entire responsibility of choosing or forming his own theology ; but utterly estopping even the most
                            pious and godly from "killing" each other to do their fighting gods good (or bad) service. Hence the American
                            Government is not a Christian Government; its powers being solely derived from the people, and do not extend
                            beyond civil matters. And its Constitution expressly disclaims any authority in matters of theology or religion.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>Elder Giles B. Avery, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers" TEIform="index"/>"THE SHAKERS."</head><p TEIform="p">From " The Church Bells," an English Paper. The denomination commonly known by this nickname prefers to be called
                            " The United Society of Believers, or Millennial Church." The nickname was given them in consequence of their
                            violently agitating their bodies while engaged in religious exercises, under the impression that the body ought
                            to take an active part in all true worship, and should express outwardly the inward emotions of the spirit; an
                            impression undoubtedly true, and only mistakenly applied in the mode of its manifesta- tion. In the worship of
                            God, the whole man, body, soul, and spirit, should be engaged; but true spiritual worship is ever subdued and
                            solemnized by a feeling of reverence, and does not consist in wild excitement of feeling; and the attitude of
                            the body should be such as to express outwardly and assist the inward reverence of the soul. The Shakers have
                            got hold of a true principle, which is too commonly lost sight of by Protestant denominations, who, in their
                            pseudo-spirituality, would have men worship " God," who " is a Spirit," as if men were also merely spirits,
                            ignoring the body's share in worship. The injunction to worship God "in spirit and in truth" certainly does not
                            exclude the body from its proper share in worship, but simply implies that worship must be sincere, not
                            hypocritical, and with the spirit lifted up to God, not merely mechanically performed, drawing nigh to Him with
                            our lips, while our heart is far from Him. This is not a sect of yesterday. The Shakers trace their origin to
                            the Camisards of the seventeenth century. These Camisards, or French Prophets, originated in a certain " School
                            of Prophets " in Dauphiny, conducted by Du Serre, a Calvinist. These prophets, professing, like the Irvingites
                            of our own day, to be inspired by the Holy Ghost, began to appear in Dauphiny and Vivarias, France, in 1688. The
                            " utterances " were not confined to the male sex, but the prophets were both male and female; and from being on
                            their first appearance numbered by hundreds, they soon amounted to thousands. When they received what seemed to
                            them, and what, no doubt, they honestly believed to be, " the spirit of prophecy," their bodies were greatly
                            agitated ; they quivered in every limb, staggered like drunken men, fell down, and lay as if they were dead.
                            After a while they recovered, twitching, shaking, and crying for mercy. It is impossible to account for such
                            manifestations ; they attracted then, as kindred manifestations and high pretentions do now, a number of persons
                            of credulous disposition whose restless minds, dissatisfied with the existing condition of the Church of Christ
                            are ever craving for a restoration of Pente costal privileges and gifts, and yearning for the realization of
                            their ideal of a Christian Church visibly guided by the Holy Spirit, anc free from all human fallibility and
                            imperfec tion. About seventeen years after their first ap pearance in France, three of their leading men left
                            France and migrated to England. With such success did they " prophesy," that they soon inspired others with a
                            like enthusiasm and before the end of the year (1705) there were two or three hundred of these "prophets" n and
                            about London, of both sexes and of all ages. The great subject of their prediction was the near approach of the
                            kingdom of God, ;he restored spiritual powers and privileges of ;he Church, and the advent of the Millennium.
                            About the year 1747, a society was formed, without any established creed or particular denned ritual, professing
                            perfect resignment to be led and governed from time to time as the Spirit of God might dictate. Their leading
                            members were James Wardley and his wife Jane, John Townley and his wife, both of Manchester, and John Kattis, a
                            distinguished scholar. This Latter gentleman, however, seems to have had tiis eyes opened after a time to the
                            extravagance of their pretentions, and retired from the society; as Mr. Baxter left the Irvingites of our time.
                            Wardley and his wife Jane con- ducted their meetings. Jane, having the principal lead in meeting, was called
                            "Mother." Some years after the formation of this society, a personage of no ordinary importance in the history
                            of the United Believers connected herself with them, and became known as Mother Ann. Her full name was Ann Lee.
                            She was born in 1736, and when arrived at a marriageable age she married one Abraham Stanley. She joined the
                            society in 1758. In consequence of receiving a special revelation in 1770, Ann was received and acknowledged by
                            all the faithful members of the society as their spiritual mother in Christ, and the true leader whom God had
                            appointed for the society. A few years after receiving this extraordinary revelation, Mother Ann received a
                            revelation that it was the will of God that she should go to America, where, as she prophesied, there would be a
                            great increase and permanent establishment of the " Church." Accordingly, as many as firmly believed her
                            testimony, and could settle their temporal concerns, and furnish necessaries for the voyage, agreed to follow
                            her. They procured a passage at Liverpool, and arrived at New York in 1774. In 1776 they settled in the town of
                            Watervliet, seven miles from Albany. Here they remained in retirement till the spring of 1780. In the beginning
                            of this year the society consisted in all (in America) of but about ten or twelve persons, all of whom came from
                            England. There was a gradual increase of numbers until the year 1787, when " those who had received faith" began
                            to collect at New Lebanon. This still remains as the " Mother Church." In a regular meeting, where nothing
                            extraordinary appears, they exercise in a regular dance while formed in straight lines, and sometimes in a
                            regular march around the room, in harmony with regular songs sung on the occasion." Yet, " shouting and clapping
                            of hands, and many other operations, are fre- quently given, all of which have a tendency to keep the assembly
                            alive, with their hearts and all their senses and feelings devoted to the service of God." They defend these
                            practices by quoting Holy Scripture. Is there any form of Protestant ¦ error which does not appeal to the
                            Scriptures, or, rather, to some isolated texts, in support of their delusions ? The texts which they allege are
                            Exod. xv., 20; Jer. xxxi., 4, 7,13; 2 Sam. vi., 14; St. Luke, xv., 25. For all their extravagances, the moral
                            life of the Shakers must be most exemplary, if it is at all in accordance with the following oode of " Faith and
                            Principles of the Society at New Lebanon:" 1. Abstinence from all carnal and sensual passions, and a strict life
                            of virgin purity, agreeable to the example of the Lord Jesus and the recommendation and example of the Apostle
                            Paul. 2. Abstinence from all the party contentions and politics of the world. " My kingdom is not of this
                            world," said Jesus. 3. Abstinence from wars and bloodshed. " Follow peace with all men," is a Divine precept ;
                            and hence also the necessity of abstaining from all acts of violence toward our fellow-men, and from all the
                            pursuits of pride and worldly ambition. 4. Perfect justice and honesty in all our dealings with our
                            fellow-creatures. 5. A faithful discharge of all just debts, and all legal and equitable claims of every
                            SHAKEREBS. 59 <pb n="60" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 6O SHAKER J±NT&gt; nature, as soon and effectually as possible; thus
                            fulfilling the Apostle's precept, " Owe no man any thing but love and good-will." 6. Do good to all men, as far
                            as opportunity and ability may serve, by administering acts of charity and kindness, and promoting light and
                            truth among mankind. " Whatsoever ye would that men should do to you, do ye even so to them." 7. Agreeably to
                            the example of the first Christian Church, let the object of our labors be directed to support and maintain a
                            united and consecrated interest, as far and as soon as preparatory circumstances will admit. But this is to be
                            done by the free will and voluntary choice of every member, as a sacred privilege, and not by any constraint or
                            undue persuasion. Of course, all that is true and excellent in this code is to be found in the summary of our
                            duty to our neighbor in the Catechism of the Church of England. The Shakers seem to lay almost exclusive stress
                            upon that part of man's duty which respects his neighbor; but they have no creeds or sacraments. They are far
                            more numerous in America than in this country, and are deserving of notice on account of their origin and
                            remarkable per- formance at their meetings for " Divine worship." Pretty fair for an organ of the Established
                            Church of England, the eldest daughter of the Great Mother of Sects — the Catholic Church. There is no Shaker
                            organization outside the United States. And, should the rising God-in-the-Constitution party succeed in their
                            wicked designs, the first demonstration of their power will be to strangle religious liberty. And religious
                            persons, being persecuted in one nation, will flee to another, as heretofore has been their wont. The Shakers
                            would go back to the mother country, where they originated. For, about that time, England will have completed
                            her " disestablishment," having then effectually separated Church and State; and her past history will eternally
                            bar a reunion. Thereafter, while- grass grows, and water runs to see it, the civil and theological institutions
                            of the British Isles will be after the pattern of the present free, liberal, and independent Government of the
                            United States of North America.—Ed.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Portland, Maine, May 21, 1873" TEIform="index"/>Portland, Me., May 21,1873</head><p TEIform="p">Elder John B. Vance. Friend and Brother : Through the brotherly love of some one, whom I suppose to be
                                yourself, I have, for several months, received the " Shaker and 8hakeress." It is a welcome visitor, in
                                several respects. The articles by the Brethren and Sisters are beautifully expressed, and abound in good
                                common sense and true sentiments. It has helped me to appreciate and better understand the basis of your
                                organic system of community. Your doctrine of celibacy in a regenerate plane, I consider favorable to
                                spiritual growth. But this is a great subject. I only intended to say, I thank you for sending me the little
                                pure-minded monthly, and herewith forward 50 cts. to pay for it. I am not afraid to allow my sons and
                                daughters to read it. It is good. Truly your friend,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pingree, L. F." TEIform="persName"/>L. F. Pingree</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New York, June 13, 1873" TEIform="index"/>New York, June 13,1873</head><p TEIform="p">Friend F. W. Evans : I have received (per mail) your monthly for June. I see no falling off in its articles.
                                It is a New Testament of Gospel Christianity to Christism, and bears the same relation to modern
                                Christianity that the four Gospels bore to Judaism nearly two thousand years ago. The " Shaker and
                                Shakeress" bears a civil and religious testimony to the truth as taught by Jesus of Nazareth, who, while
                                upon earth, was the Exemplar of Shakerism, which is a resurrection of his life and teachings. "What has been
                                the civil and religious history of Christendom, for all its centuries, but war, bloodshed, cruelty, and all
                                conceivable kinds of criminality and barbarism? Hell has ex- isted more in Christendom than in all the world
                                besides. Is there not more antagonism between the jarring sects of Christianity than can be found outside of
                                its blood-stained precincts ? " By their fruits ye shall know them." Exhortations for peace and good-will
                                among men, in Europe, are vain, whilst wars and slaughter, robbery and devastation, are the works of its
                                people. Your " Shaker and Sliakeress" for June is very good, indeed. The articles, "Mother's Bay" " Follow
                                Me," " Convention" are excellent, and " Our Shaker Some" cannot be surpassed. The other articles make an
                                interesting variety. Eldress Antoinette is not idle as an editress. Indeed, the " Shakeress" for June is
                                rich and entertaining. I see, also, that the daughter of my friend Devyr is a poetess, and contributes some
                                choice pieces of poetry. In short, the monthly is to the Shaker world what the New Testament is to outside
                                Christianity. It is the modern Scriptures — a Godspell to the religious world; and its editor and editress
                                are Christian Apostles. P. S. — Love to my daughter. Her father often thinks of her, and is thankful to
                                Divine Providence that she is among godly people, and living in quietude. # # #</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To the shaker and shakeress:" TEIform="index"/>To the Shaker and Shakeress :</head><p TEIform="p">My feelings are warmly enlisted in the cause you are bringing before mankind. I am em- boldened to write of
                                my feelings of sympathy with you from the consideration that the union of every earnest soul, however
                                humble, will at least not retard the cause. As my soul emerges from the petrifying influence of sin, and
                                begins to appreciate the glorious liberty of the Gospel, so does your divine mission become dear to me. The
                                literature of the world, which formerly delighted me, has now lost its savor, and such pages as yours can
                                alone supply the food my soul craves. You are primarily endeavoring to make plain to humanity the
                                distinction between flesh and spirit. You are pointing out the discordant results that spring from the
                                former, the peace and good will of the latter. You are doing this in an effectual, but by no means bigoted,
                                way. Your words carry the weight of experience more or less extensive. As Jesus told his great truths in
                                serious and loving language, to the truthseekers of his time, so do you to those of yours. Intertwined, as
                                outward signs to the principle of a problem, as the body to the soul, are spiritual and physiological truth.
                                I gratefully unite with your testimony in this respect. I have derived, during the past few years, physical
                                and spiritual benefit, by adopting a vegetable diet, and from the discontinuance of the use of tea and
                                coffee. Surely there is a significance in the fact that the food of the prophets of God has always been
                                simple. As to tobacco, I cannot conceive how rational beings can consume such nauseous poison. I can but
                                conclude that its use was instigated by the wily powers of evil as a torment to their unconscious devotees.
                                Many who use it understand its injurious effect. I have eagerly looked at agricultural pieces, for comments
                                on the cultivation of tobacco by Believers. The Jewish law required frequent bathings of the whole body.
                                Mother Ann said that, unless the body were kept clean, the gifts of God would not flow. Other points of your
                                testimony on the relation of physical health to spiritual life, such as punctual manual labor, I fully unite
                                with. Desiring to be a humble follower in every progressive movement, which originates in the true gift, it
                                is my aim to live out each successive development of truth.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stroud, Thomas J." TEIform="persName"/>Thomas J. Stroud, Enfield, Conn.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Self-consecration is not a single act..." TEIform="index"/>Self-consecration is not a single act...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Self-consecration is not a single act, or fact in the past — a definite thing to be referred back to ; it is not
                            an act, an impulse, an emotion, a sentiment; but a principle brought and laid upon the altar of service, to be
                            constantly replaced, re-sanctifted, as the shew-bread of the table before the altar.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tobacco" TEIform="index"/>TOBACCO</head><p TEIform="p">As nigh as I can remember, in the year 1825, there was a religious movement, or reforma- tion, on the Darby
                            Plains, in Ohio. It did not originate with any of the sectarians, but was, in some measure, led by a man who
                            seemed much inspired to do good, and denounce Ortho- doxy, being quite independent of the sectarian clergy. The
                            subjects of this work met together, sang and prayed, exhorted, told their experiences, and, what was a peculiar
                            feature, confessed their private sins in public. Among others, there was a quiet little man of the name of
                            Joseph Atsett who was drawn into the whirlpool of the revival. The writer was among them as a missionary at the
                            time. In a lively prayer meeting Joseph came forward to tell his experience. He informed the meeting that he
                            went among the hazel bushes for the purpose of secret prayer, and when he kneeled down the Spirit said to him "
                            Open your mouth and I will fill it." " And," said he, " I gaped open my mouth like a young robin, and the Spirit
                            said ' What is that in your mouth ?' " Said he " I had a great cud of tobacco in my mouth ! And I made haste to
                            spit it out, and again opened my mouth. But the spirit said, ' What is that in your pocket ? ' And I had almost
                            a whole plug in my pocket. I took it out and throwed it as far as I could send it among the hazel bushes. Then
                            both my mouth and my soul was filled with the Spirit, and I experienced a joy and peace I had never felt before.
                            I have never touched tobacco since, and I never will use it again." Twenty-five years after that, the writer
                            lived in the Society at Watervliet, O.,five miles from the city of Dayton. And in those days a revival, or
                            religious awakening, took place in that city. It began with the lower class, both in point of wealth and morals,
                            and operated more especially among the inebriate class. The sectarian clergy, Methodists, Baptists,
                            Presbyterians, etc., pitched in ; and each tried to gather the dear lambs into his own fold. These lambs were
                            found to be uncommonly refractory and independent. The writer had the following account from the mouth of one of
                            those converts from the ranks of the inebriate class. " I was," said he," a hard drinker, and had degraded
                            myself nearly to lying in the gutter. This spirit of reformation got hold of me, and I could not shake it off. I
                            finally closed in with it, and resolved never to use any thing that would intoxicate. But I could not stop at
                            that. I was led by the same Spirit to Bee the pernicious effect of using tobacco, and was required to quit its
                            use; and I did so. I felt the more like a man for it, and seemed to myself somewhat cleaned up. When this
                            movement began to die away a little, the clergy of the several sects began fishing, each with his own net,
                            trying to get the most. The Presbyterian called on me, and invited me to join his church. I told him I would
                            attend his meeting the next Sabbath, after which I would be prepared to give him an answer. Sabbath came, and I
                            attended the service ; a day or two afterward, the clergyman called to know how I liked the meeting, and how I
                            had made up my mind. I said to him : Sir, I attended your worship and discovered that many of your congregation
                            chew tobacco, and cannot afford to refrain even during the hour of worship. They squirt out the filthy juice,
                            and the floor was so unclean that I could not find a place to kneel before God. And, sir, you use the poisonous
                            weed yourself, and you have got a cud in your mouth now! Spit it out and quit its use, and get your congregation
                            to quit it. I will never join a church which indulges in a practice that the Spirit of God requires me to
                            abstain from. The same spirit that required me to abstain from whisky, urged me to quit tobacco ; and if I
                            should join a church that used it, I should be in constant danger of being dragged down to the same level,
                            which, by the grace of God, I never will be." This man informed me that the clergyman never called upon him
                            again. In conclusion, I will observe : At the time I received this narrative, I lived at Watervliet, O., and
                            there was not then a single member of that society that used tobacco in any of ita forms, which was to me a
                            great consolation.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pelham, R. W." TEIform="persName"/>R. W. Pelham, Union Village, O.</byline></div2><pb n="61" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakeress: wealth" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERESS: WEALTH</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">Wealth, as denned by Webster, is "large possessions of money, goods, or land." "All souls are mine, saith the
                            Lord." The earth, with its fullness, belong to Him. If God is just and without partiality, has not every human
                            being an inherent right to as much land as he needs, from which to derive 'his daily sustenance? Have not all an
                            equal right to God's sunshine, to the pure breezes which come from, the mountains, and to the cooling streamlets
                            that meander through the vales and woodlands? Would it not be just as much the prerogative of the few to shut
                            out the sun's rays, and to bottle up the winds, and dam up the streams of water (had they the power) as for them
                            to monopolize the land ? Whence came the right for one man or woman to possess a " large amount of land, goods,
                            or money," by which means they op- press and hold in vassalage other of God's creatures? If the answer is: "We
                            have wrought diligently with our hands — have toiled honestly and earnestly — while others have been indifferent
                            and idle; and we have only received the just reward of our works ;" then is God's justice vindicated, and man's
                            ways justified. " It shall be well with the righteous ;" they who do right in temporal as really as in spiritual
                            things ; and they will eat the fruit of their own toil; while the sluggard, who will not work, must suffer
                            hunger, for "the reward of his hands will be given him;" those who " sow sparingly " will reap accordingly.
                            Wealth that comes through honest industry, is God's gift and blessing to man, and is his lawful inheritance ;
                            but, if he so remembers his riches that he gathers them into his heart, and carries them in "his best
                            affections, until they are formed into idols, to be worshiped, then is God robbed and dishonored, and man
                            becomes a degenerate being, by abusing prof- fered blessings, instead of using them as a means to uplift the
                            erring; that the strong and more perfect might in that way be instrumental in aiding the weak and less perfect.
                            The corporeal body being composed of the elements of the earth, must of necessity derive its sustenance
                            therefrom, while in a physical state of existence. But, is it not a marvel (when intellect and conscience awake
                            from lethargy) that sentient beings, who believe in an endless existence in a life beyond the present, and who
                            know that time will soon carry them where earthly riches, honors, and pleasures will be beyond their reach,
                            should turn all their energies of mind and body to grasp and hold those uncertain riches, which in one short
                            hour may come to naught ? If the angel who rides the pale horse should delay his coming for a few short years,
                            yet the earthquake, which opens its mouth and swallows up cities and hamlets, and buries thousands in one living
                            tomb, may occur in an unexpected hour; or the mighty flood tide may sweep, as it has often done, over thickly
                            inhabited portions of the land, destroying life and property; and fire, that fierce devouring element, may lay
                            waste great and populous cities, like Chicago and Boston, in a brief period of time, then the people stood
                            aghast, and " cried with a loud voice: Alas ! alas 1" these great cities containing so much riches, are laid in
                            ashes, and ruined ! Tongue would fail to utter, or pen to paint, the fears, the weeping and wailing of the
                            people in that momentous hour, as they saw their costly edifices, one after another devoured by the merciless
                            flames ; while men, women and children fled for their lives, without daring, as it were, even to cast one
                            lingering look after the household gods — their ornaments of gold and silver, and precious stones — which they
                            had left behind them. What lesson has been learned from such visitations ? Have we learned humility and
                            dependence, and gained a knowledge that pride and haughtiness are precursors of the destructive elements? We may
                            remember that the proverb is just as true to day as when it was first uttered; that " He that hasteth to be rich
                            hath an evil eye;" and, we add, an evil intention also. The love of power, and a desire to live in luxury and
                            ease, cause men and women to be unjust, and to bind heavy burdens upon the poor, and to monopolize the elements
                            of subsistence, until their riches is oftentimes their greatest source of vexation, anxiety, and fear. " The
                            abundance of the rich will not suffer him to rest, but the sleep of the (honest) laborer is sweet." Many of the
                            ancient philosophers so feared the snares of sin, through the deceitf ulness of earthly riches, that their
                            strong love of virtue, and desire to consecrate themselves to a life of chastity, induced them to resort to
                            extreme asceticism, and, in solitude, on some lone mountain, or in a desert-place, remote from the haunts of
                            vice, from earthly friends, and every temporal comfort, they performed their vows far from mortal ken. As
                            Gregory said of himself, " he endured the rays of the sultry sun until his skin was parched, and dark as the
                            skin of the Ethiopean, and his limbs were made rough by the friction of coarse hair-cloth." When the power of
                            the holy people was scattered, and there was no organized body of true Christians on the earth, the prophetic
                            spirit rested with those faithful servants of God, who were clad in sackcloth and mourning ; for the true spirit
                            of prophecy has never left the earth, but continued with suffering witnesses through the long night of spiritual
                            darkness. They were God's stars. But, in the fullness of time, according to prophecy, the gathering of the
                            latter-day saints commenced, and the kingdom began to be established, in which the " will of God is done on
                            earth as it is done in heaven." We rejoice that the time has come when the power of salvation is given to those
                            who desire it, and strength to commence the heavenly life. And that brethren and sisters can dwell together in
                            unity, bearing aloft the banner of virgin purity, and can mingle together in a pure social relation, and in all
                            the duties of life, and preserve their continence without resorting to deserts and mountains, or to monasteries.
                            By the power of truth we are made free! We have engaged in the Christian warfare, and the God of battles is with
                            us, and teaches us how to use those spiritual weapons which are powerful in destroying the strong holds of sin
                            in the human heart. And those who are true in this strife, are not disposed to use carnal weapons to wound or
                            kill their brother man. We have peace and plenty. We plant vineyards and eat the fruit of them, and receive the
                            reward of unselfish toil. " We ask for neither riches nor poverty." If, by diligently putting our hands to work,
                            and applying our hearts unto wisdom, we gain more than we need for our own support, we cheerfully dedicate it to
                            the upbuilding of the Church of Christ on earth; while our greatest concern shall be to lay up treasures in the
                            heavens — the future home of the souls of those who love and walk in the truth. The riches of Christ's kingdom
                            are the riches which we covet.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian's rest" TEIform="index"/>THE CHRISTIAN'S REST</head><p TEIform="p">" Come unto me, all ye that labor and are heavy laden, and I will give you rest." These words, uttered by the
                            Divine Master centuries ago, are still new, and possess great power. He also said, " Take my yoke upon you, and
                            learn of me; for I am meek and lowly in heart; and ye shall find rest unto your souls. For my yoke is easy, and
                            my burden is light." What excellence and pathetic sympathy we find in that beautiful and loving invitation! From
                            those few sentences might be written volumes, well filled with instruction that would enlighten the
                            understanding of those who are seeking eternal life — the heavenly rest. Sometimes those teachings are spread
                            out before us like a map, or chart; and again we view them as a broad field of labor; not for the mind only, but
                            also for hands that are willing to work early and late in the Lord's vineyard. The voice of paternal tenderness
                            and love that is heard through those words, " Come unto me, all ye that labor and are heavy laden, and I will
                            give you rest," touches the tender chords of sympathy and soul affection in the heart of the weary pilgrim, and
                            causes them to vibrate anew. We are not sent to roam in distant lands, as strangers, alone and uncared for, in
                            search of the desired rest; but he stands with open arms ready to infold those who will hear his voice. His
                            language is full of inspiration and soul-stirring eloquence ; and, to the earnest seeker after truth, it feels
                            like the breath of heaven. It may be asked," How is it that he calls upon us to work in his vineyard, and yet
                            promises a rest ? We answer: It is rest from the turmoils of a worldly life — from its fashions and follies —
                            its sorrows and vain pleasures; for, how true it is, that, in our earth life, roses and thorns grow together;
                            and we tire of earth-born pleasures; and most assuredly does the soul who is seeking for heavenly joys, grow
                            weary of a life in sin, and loathe its vain pleasures. And they who strive for earthly gain, and for those
                            things which are selfpleasing, will continue to love the world, with its friendships and pleasures, and all its
                            alluring charms. Instead of being crucified to the world, as was Jesus, they are alive to its baneful
                            influences; and their sinful natures are constantly crying, " Give us more and more;" for a sinful appetite
                            cannot be satisfied. It is only to the sin-sick soul that those beautiful words," Take my yoke upon you and
                            learn of me," &amp;c, are acceptable. Do we feel that putting on and wearing the yoke of Christ is a hard
                            and grievous task ? if so, then are we unworthy of the sacred and hallowed rest that is promised. <pb n="62" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> " Learn of me," said the Savior. How shall we learn, except we deny ourselves of all ungodliness
                            and every worldly lust; take up the cross, and put off the old garments of self-love, pride, and ambition; and
                            by confession and repentance, wash our robes and make them white, and walk with our Father and Mother in Christ
                            whithersoever they lead? Then, even though it should be through the soultrying furnace of affliction that we may
                            be called to go, we shall be preserved ; or if we pass through deep waters, we shall not be overwhelmed ; nor
                            will death, the great king of terrors, have any power over us. Come then, dear Gospel-friends, let all who have
                            heard the heavenly call, " Come unto me/' and who have seen the light descend from the Eesurrection heavens, and
                            have " tasted of the good word of God, and of the powers of the world to come," be living souls ! Let us enlarge
                            the chambers of our hearts, and live not for self alone, but for the good that we may do to our brethren and
                            sisters in our home circle, and throughout the Zion of God. Then shall our light shine abroad, and the Holy
                            Spirit will clothe our souls with Divine love, that will refine all the senses, and perfect us in the " image of
                            the heavenly," and will fill us with purified joy and peace. Then shall we sing the song of Redemption full and
                            free. And the one prayer of Zion's children will be, " Lord, thy kingdom come, thy will be done throughout the
                            whole earth, as it is done in heaven !" — the glorious kingdom of Righteousness and Peace.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Gillespie, Mary A." TEIform="persName"/>Eldress Mary A. Gillespie, West Gloucester, Me.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beloved Eldress Antoinette:" TEIform="index"/>Beloved Eldress Antoinette :</head><p TEIform="p">Your kind appeal to the " Sisterhood," in the January No. of the Shaker and Bhakeress, seems to be looking us
                            steadily in the face this morning, and still demanding a reply. As we sit thinking of its claims upon us, and of
                            our obligations to the cause which we hope to honor, we mentally pledge loyalty to both, and would give proof
                            thereof by many simple tokens. We have been an interested reader of the Shaker ever since its advent, and
                            heartily thank all contributors for the favors which they have conferred on so large a class of readers in this
                            section, as we have been not only edified but instructed; so much so, that we sometimes think, after perusing
                            the pithy articles penned for its columns, that the whole story of our peculiar belief has already been
                            admirably told; that nothing new can be written on this subject. Again. When taking into consideration the
                            boundlessness of the theme to which we have pledged our lives, it would seem that an army of writers of the
                            Esdras type could not exhaust it. And, further, when contrasting the size of our little sheet with the
                            voluminous publications of the scientific and religious world, it is, comparatively speaking, but a mote in
                            magnitude to what it would be, were it possible to put into language the manifold excellencies which emanate
                            from the virgin life which we aim to interpret. But, anon, we are reminded of the youthful hero of bible
                            history, who accepted the challenge of Philistia's champion, and who also, refusing to wear Saul's armor
                            (preferring rather to trust in God), successfully vanquished the mighty foe with one smooth stone from out the
                            brook. Hence, may we not predict that similar results will follow the missiles of truth brought to view in the
                            Shaker and Shakeress, if aimed at the champion of our modern Philistia, alias " social evil 1" And if God is our
                            support too, we certainly have no need to wear the brazen armour of popular theology to meet this foe, nor to
                            convict the world that there is a God in Israel, through our present humble medium, even the Shaker and
                            Shakeress. We find that, with all that has been written concerning our religious belief, many questions are
                            still being proposed by strangers and friends not of our persuasion, with regard to the practical workings of
                            our community system, its advantages, its benefits, and the like. This is not strange, though we know that the
                            principles upon which it is founded are eternal, and that several societies embodying these have survived the
                            ravages of time for nearly a century, and resisted alike the waves of opposition, and the insinuations of false
                            doctrines, without any signs of decay; that they have stood while scores of man-made institutions have risen and
                            declined. Still, the world wonders and prophesies failure, while questions similar to what we here insert often
                            meet us. Some of these we do not remember to have seen very elaborately treated in our late publications ; we
                            therefore solicit the aid of experienced writers of our Order for more satisfactory replies to the same, in
                            future numbers of the paper, than we are able to give.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Can children, adopted by your communities..." TEIform="index"/>Can children, adopted by your communities...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">1st. Can children, adopted by your communities, and subjected to your peculiar modes of discipline, ever become
                            symmetrically developed in an intellectual point of view? In brief, Did this system ever produce a well balanced
                            mind? 2d. Is the quiet routine of duties daily imposed, calculated to develop energy of character, or give
                            breadth and soundness to judgment? 3d. Are individuals thus reared, self-reliant and able to cope with
                            difficulties of a complicated nature? 4th. Is it possible that minds thus apparently fettered by surroundings,
                            and controlled by one system of influences, ever rejoice in that expansion of ideas, and that independence of
                            thought which constitutes them free agents ? These are a few of the many queries which seem to puzzle the
                            multitudes who stand as spectators, apparently waiting to see how successfully the singular problem of a virgin
                            life is to be solved by human beings. We do not propose to answer these questions analytically, but will give a
                            general opinion. Would say, with regard to question first, that most children adopted by us, in these days,
                            belong to that class of individuals whom Christ came to save; hence wholesome discipline and quiet occupation,
                            are the grand counter-influences to which we must resort, to check the growth of inherent propensities which are
                            so glaringly apparent. If they yield to these means, we have some hope of balancing the future mind, morally, at
                            least. Our strife is, however, to create a taste for such healthful, intellectual and moral pursuits, as will
                            raise them above their former gross appetites. We find that Satan has already taken them " up into an exceeding
                            high mountain," and they have discovered the glories of the whole earth; and, shall we say it ? only the wisdom
                            of a God is equal to the task of reforming and elevating them from their low estates. We further claim, that the
                            principles of the Christ-life, when fully accepted, will not only elevate men and women, but will, in a certain
                            sense, reconstruct the minds of those who are wedded to the cause of spiritual progress. In other words, " They
                            who put Christ fully on," become gradually and radically changed in many respects, for " God helps those who
                            help themselves." Still further, with regard to the moral growth of children adopted by our communities, we
                            think that they have many advantages over their companions abroad, if the "one system of influences " mentioned,
                            is pure ; for, remarks an able writer, in one of our Educational Journals: '' The soul addressed constantly by
                            the highest possible influences, will have pure and lofty purposes, will aim at highest ends." Again: " It is
                            safe to say, that the moral character of the mature man will depend more upon the education which the conscience
                            shall have received in early days, than upon any other agency." But what of intellectual growth ? Simply this :
                            that the young Shaker and Shakeress are not only permitted, but urged to educate themselves in those branches of
                            science which will aid them in becoming useful members of society. Nor are they (as stated in " Science of
                            Life," February No.) obliged to suspend mental growth as a result of marriage, as is the fact of young women
                            abroad. With us we can see no reason why the mind should not continue to expand and increase its powers, as long
                            as it exists in the form ; and who can limit its capabilities when freed from an earthly tabernacle ? That there
                            have been well-ordered minds, and noble specimens of men and women developed within the confines of a Shaker
                            home, we truthfully aver. And why not ? since destroying the animal proclivities does not fetter the more
                            exalted attributes of the soul. History informs us, that John Bunyan, one of the most celebrated of English
                            writers, was imprisoned for twelve years ; and while thus incarcerated wrote his popular " Pilgrim's Progress."
                            Did this exalted mental effort prove that being secluded from the world for a time, the mind ceased to act or to
                            expand ? It is clear to us, that " the mind grows from what it feeds upon ;" and that that mind, absorbed in the
                            desire to do the will of God, becomes God-like in its capabilities, loves, and interests. The facts are, that
                            those who feel themselves called to this work of self-denial, recognize God in the whole plan ; and, while
                            professing to leave the worldly order, the plane upon which perfect natural men and women are developed, choose
                            rather to be perfected in the angel life, aspiring most to develop the angel character, which is to exist when
                            earthly attainments have passed away.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stickney, Asenath C." TEIform="persName"/>Asenath C. Stickney, Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="When men are called into the Christian life..." TEIform="index"/>When men are called into the Christian life...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">When men are called into the Christian life, they do not come in as experts and veterans ; they come in as
                            recruits, to be drilled. And all their campaign lies before them. The vic- tory of our faith is gained step by
                            step ; and the great personal epochs in our history are those in which the good principle, after severe
                            conflict, gains the ascendency over the evil that is in us. Communications from J. M. Peebles and A. B. Bradford
                            in September number.</p></div2><pb n="63" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Forbearance" TEIform="index"/>FORBEARANCE</head><p TEIform="p">The spirit of persecution is often keenly felt in many petty ways through life, sufficient to fully test the
                            fidelity of the striving Christian. Those only who meekly bear unmerited cen- sure, or injustice in its many
                            forms, still maintaining a calm, forgiving spirit, and con- tinuing to do good to their enemies are, indeed and
                            truly, Christian. Genuine forbearance is a virtue, beautiful, noble, and Christ-like. How many professing
                            Christians can meet the insults of scoffers, or hear slanderous reports of themselves or their friends, without
                            a retaliatory answer in their hearts, and who (if practicable) would not turn the weight of the offense upon the
                            offender ? May we never forget the lovely example of our Pattern, who bore so meekly the malice of the vile;
                            when scourged, spit upon, stoned, scoffed and jeered, his lofty spirit could not stoop to pour out a revenge.
                            How noble the breathings of his soul, " Father forgive them; for they know not what they do." Let each follower
                            of our Savior ask himself this question, — In how great a degree do I practise this Christian principle?</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Martin, Elizabeth" TEIform="persName"/>Elizabeth Martin, Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prayer" TEIform="index"/>PRAYER</head><p TEIform="p">The readers of the " Shaker and Shakeress," who believe that the Bible is the Word of God, and that the Apostles
                            of Jesus Christ were under the immediate inspiration of the Holy Spirit in all they said and wrote, from the
                            time he called them to leave their fishing nets on the banks of the sea of Galilee, and follow him, will pardon
                            us for dwelling upon the subject of Prayer, when they remember that one of the best injunctions the Apostles
                            ever gave was, to "Pray without ceasing."—Ed. Prayer is sometimes called the " sheetanchor of the soul, when
                            tossed upon the tempestuous sea of life ;" and " Prayer is the soul's sincere desire, unuttered or expressed."
                            Formal, wordy prayers, that do not proceed from the heart, are only "lip service." But how much to be desired is
                            a dependent, childlike spirit, which will lead souls, in times of need, to apply for help, and draw life from
                            the Fountain that is never dry. Mortals are so short-sighted, that they frequently ask for those things they
                            want (or desire), instead of seeking to have their real needs supplied ; and, in that condition of mind, may
                            sometimes think they receive a " stone for bread," or, " for an egg, a scorpion," and be led to exclaim (as did
                            Jacob of old), " All these things are against me." But, if such will patiently wait on God, they will eventually
                            see his wisdom in withholding as well as in giving. When (as Believers in Christ's second appearing) we pray for
                            the spread of the Gospel testimony, and that souls may be gathered to our Zion, would it not be well for us to
                            consider, and. ask ourselves, How much individual sacrifice are we willing to make for the good of others ? and,
                            Are we willing to share with them our temporal and spiritual substance ? We know how hard, or difficult, it is
                            for those who have spent their time and energies of body and mind in acquiring wealth, to consecrate it to the
                            good of others, and unselfishly share it with them. And, indeed, those who have no possessions in houses, or
                            land, or riches of any kind, find it exceedingly crossing to their selfish natures, to sacrifice, or give up, or
                            " forsake " their fathers and mothers, their brothers and sisters, and the pleasures of a carnal life; yet all
                            this must be done before they can realize the truth of the promise of a " hundred-fold more in this life, and in
                            the world to come life everlasting." Our faith and confidence is in God, who hears and answers prayer. Our faith
                            may be tried; but we will continue to watch and wait, to pray, and not faint; for his work will go on, and no
                            power on earth can stay his hand. A few years ago, thousands of souls, who saw and felt the great evil of
                            slavery in the United States, devoutly prayed that the slave power might be broken, and the oppressed made free.
                            The number who prayed and worked in the cause of freedom were few in comparison with those who upheld the slave
                            power; yet they knew they were on the side of justice and right, and were firm in their faith that the right
                            would prevail. The truth in respect to slavery worked (for a time) like leaven in the community, until the
                            people were sufficiently imbued with a sense of justice to rise and strike the blow that severed the captives'
                            chains.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webster, R." TEIform="persName"/>R. Webster, Union V., O.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The prayer taught by Jesus..." TEIform="index"/>The prayer taught by Jesus...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The Prayer taught by Jesus, inculcates all the duties pertaining to the Christian life. He taught us to say, "
                            Our Father, who art in heaven." This implies a Divine Parentage ; for, if we have " a Father in heaven," we must
                            also have a Mother there, through whose pure Spirit we become purified, and made fit subjects for that blissful
                            state that enables us dependent children to say — our Father and Mother ; and their sacred name can be honored
                            by those only who have " washed their robes, and made them white." In this simple, child-like spirit, we say, "
                            Give us this day our daily bread; not the stale bread of our forefathers," who ate their manna, and are dead,"
                            nor the spiritual food that was distributed to the primitive Christians ; for they also have passed away; nor
                            even that of yesterday; but the new and living bread of to-day; those glorious truths which, day by day, unfold
                            to our understandings, the will of our " Father and Mother in heaven," and fill our souls with that beautiful
                            spirit of " forgiveness" that we can in confidence ask to be " forgiven." Then we shall not be left in the hour
                            of " temptation ;" but our souls will be " delivered from evil;" and, in this purified state, we can humbly and
                            devoutly ascribe all the glory, honor, and power to our Father and Mother — God. " The fervent and effectual
                            prayer of the righteous," is not the bending of the knee to a set form of words; it is not the empty pharisaic
                            prattle, to be " heard of men;" but the Christian's prayer is the Christian life. Simple desires are good; but
                            they avail us nothing, unless we work with them. Then let us live under the heavenly influence of Divine love,
                            that we may devote our whole life to the beautiful work of prayer — that of ministering the healing balm of
                            comfort to the afflicted, and pouring the " oil of gladness" into the wounded heart; thus lifting huma- nity
                            from the dismal pit of a sinful life, into the glorious sunshine of our Parents' love.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bullard, Marcia M." TEIform="persName"/>Marcia M. Bullard, Canaan, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>HOME</head><p TEIform="p">" 'Mid pleasures and palaces, wherever I roam, Be it ever so humble, there's no place like home!" These lines
                            were written by one who, a stranger and alone, was wandering through the streets of a gay and populous city,
                            and, feeling homeless and sad, composed a poem that touched a chord so deeply implanted in the human heart, that
                            it has been copied and sung in every civilized country throughout the world. The love of home is coeval with the
                            race; from the monarch to the peasant, from the sage to the savage, all are (more or less) imbued with this
                            instinct, according to their degree of development. It is also seen in the animal creation: " The ox knoweth his
                            owner, and the ass his master's crib, were the words of an inspired Prophet long ago; none so stupid, that they
                            do not know the source whence their needs are supplied. Our Savior recognized this principle, when He said: "
                            The foxes have holes, and the birds of the air have nests; but the Son of man hath not where to lay his head;"
                            and, perhaps, this may have been one of the causes that combined to make him a " man of sorrows and acquainted
                            with grief." Being called to separate himself from friends and kindred, he was not even permitted to have a
                            home, where he might, when weary and op- pressed in spirit, seek an interval of rest, and find a momentary
                            relaxation from the great work to which he was consecrated. And what is home f Does it consist merely in the
                            supply of the natural and physical wants of our being, without any reference to the moral culture, the spiritual
                            growth, and that sympathy of feeling which bind heart to heart ? Where these are wanting, there may be opulence,
                            grandeur, and an outward semblance of happiness ; but it is not home, and cannot fill the yearnings of an
                            immortal spirit. A Shaker home is quite a different thing. Many admire the neatness, order, and air of repose
                            that mark our outward surroundings ; but they do not discover the hidden springs that produce this outgrowth,
                            and make it, of all others, the most attractive. For, while they pity our self-imposed seclusion from worldly
                            society, with all its selfishness, pride, and love of distinction, together with what they call our religious
                            fanaticism, they might indeed envy the peace, love, and harmony, that pervade our humble home, and form a
                            paradise on earth. Here self-love is not the ruling influence; but each one labors physically and spiritually
                            for the good of all; and the perverted passions of human nature do not bear the sway over the intellectual and
                            spiritual faculties of the soul; but are brought into subj ection to a higher law, which controls the body, even
                            the law of Christ. This makes the " golden rule " a possibility; and it becomes comparatively easy to prefer one
                            another in love, rather than to indulge in the opposite spirit, that would lead the strong to usurp authority
                            over the weak, and to allow the love of greed to be the only incentive to action. As the principles that
                            constitute this blessed home are eternal, we believe that it is emphatically the home of the soul, where all its
                            higher aspirations must center ; therefore we will cleave to it; for we know that purity, genuine friendship,
                            and hallowed love, possess the hearts, and form the characters, of the inmates of this our Zion home.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Rhoda R." TEIform="persName"/>Rhoda R. Hollister, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Scandal" TEIform="index"/>SCANDAL</head><p TEIform="p">If all be true that Beecher, Tilton &amp; Co. are charged with, by some meddlesome women, who is there,
                            amongst the magnates of Babylon, that can rightfully cast the first stone ? Are they not all under the influence
                            of perverted generation, or suffering from it ante- natally ? Wisdom would seem to dictate that the accused and
                            accusers come to terms, shake hands, and, like Pilate and Herod, be friends; lest the Shakers come forth from
                            their seclusion and inaugurate the Day of Judgment.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Unanimity of action is the order..." TEIform="index"/>Unanimity of action is the order of Heaven...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Unanimity of action is the order of Heaven. All of God's creation expresses perfection in unity and co-operation.
                            The worship of Believers is symbolical of the ultimate attainment of the soul, when the whole being shall be in
                            harmony with the Creator — God — and with associate intelligences living and moving in the element of pure love.
                            This is the doctrine that the Christ taught, and that Jesus accepted; and this was the Spirit that prompted him
                            to renounce his individuality and selfish life, with its prescribed interests, for the good of his brethren,
                            whom he served in love. He said, " The Son of man came not to be ministered unto, but to minister." And, in a
                            spirit of true consecration, he said, "Lo, I come to do thy will, O God! " And those who are baptized into the
                            same spirit, are lost to selfhood, and help to inaugurate the reign of " Peace on earth" and of love to God, "
                            and good-will to man."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Knight, J. D." TEIform="persName"/>J. D. Knight, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The secret of health: First, keep warm..." TEIform="index"/>The secret of health...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The secret of health: First, keep warm. Second, eat regularly and slowly. Third, maintain regular bodily habits.
                            Fourth, take early and very light suppers, or, better still, none at all. Fifth, keep a clean skin. Sixth, get
                            plenty of sleep at night. Seventh, keep cheerful and respectful company. Eighth, keep out of debt. Ninth, don't
                            set your mind on things you don't need. </p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Test" TEIform="index"/>The Test.</head><p TEIform="p">Whoever would put " God " into the Federal Constitution discovers a plentiful lack of that element in their own
                            constitution.</p></div2><pb n="64" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Twilight reflection" TEIform="index"/>TWILIGHT REFLECTION</head><p TEIform="p">1. When the soft shades of twilight drop over our way, Like curtains let down from on high, When life's busy
                            scenes that have crowded the day, 2. O, this is the season when calm, holy thought Like tidewaves our spirits
                            o'er-flow, While truest of pictures our life-deeds have wrought, 3. Then oft let us pause mid the con-flict and
                            strife, The counsel of wisdom to heed, To ask for a fore-taste of heavenly life, Have pass'd with the light
                            from the sky; Tis then that the spirit should rise and take flight, From tumult of earth and its care, Reflection shall over us throw, Till clearly portrayed on the vision within, Each motive and action will be, To
                            satisfy immortal need; And when the deep shadows of time close around, When life's fairest day-beams are
                            past, And seek sweet repose on the shadow less height, Communion with angels to share. The glory of goodness, the darkness of sin, In joy or in sorrow we see. May light from beyond us our path way surround, For
                            ever and ever to last.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Swedish emigrant" TEIform="index"/>THE SWEDISH EMIGRANT</head><p TEIform="p">It may be news to many subscribers, that, in Kentucky, connected with the Pleasant Hill Society, there is a
                            Shaker Family composed of emigrants from Sweden. Its Elder, John Barnett, has sent the following Poetic Lines,
                            and says: " The correspondence with Sweden shows that the fire is not smothered. Numbers speak of faith, and
                            expect to come; others wish to come, but have not the means. " I have sometimes thought that the Eastern world
                            being (as termed by you) masculine, and the Western, feminine, the next cycle of progress of our Gospel will
                            open in England. But to me it seems impossible for Believers to travel successfully, while so fettered by
                            inexorable 'fashion' in aliments and beverages, which belong exclusively to the dominion and kingdom made '
                            desolate.' " A blessed country, far away_ From tumult, war, and pain! 0 light the price that I must pay, Its
                            righteousness to gain. 1 leave my native land, and kin, And life, so dear to me ; All pride, and selfishness,
                            and sin, To there be pure and free. Its genial clime, and fruitful soil, Yield rich abundant food. There, honest
                            sacrifice and toil Return a lasting good. The precious olive, wheat, and vine, To cultivate with care, The law
                            of heaven shall make it mine, That I their wealth may share. The worldly-minded are not led Unto this blest
                            abode; The false and covetous but dread Its strait and narrow road. The vulture's eye hath never seen, Nor
                            ravenous beasts of prey, Nor trail of wily serpents, been Along this holy way. No fell disease, to interrupt The
                            flow of life and zeal; No moth or rust can there corrupt, Nor thieves break through and steal. No famine's death
                            hath there appear'd, But fruitful fields abound ; And Peace her temple bright has rear'd Upon this sacred
                            ground. Her simple laws, like Noah's ark, Will save all from the flood, Who will in honesty embark To find
                            eternal good. Lo, from the East and West they'll come, From North and South afar, All tongues and kindred find a
                            home Where many mansions are.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Barnett, John" TEIform="persName"/>John Barnett, Pleasant Hill, Ky.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our parentage" TEIform="index"/>OUR PARENTAGE</head><p TEIform="p">Lord, kindle thy burnings, and quench not the flame That consumes the nature of sin; Light up the dark places
                            with Truth's piercing beams, 'Till all becomes glorious within. Thy heritage, Father, we'll ever adorn With
                            emblems of beauty and peace; O chasten and cleanse us, till we become pure, And grow with eternal increase. And
                            then to thy honor we temples can build, Wherein thy pure Spirit can reign — A clean habitation with holiness
                            flll'd — All enmity there being slain. And sweet songs of praise through these temples shall ring, As we in thy
                            knowledge expand. And learn that thy gifts are all righteous and good, Dealt out with a bounteous hand. We'll
                            worship Thee, Father, on Zion's high hills, Where beameth the Sun's golden rays ; Our Heavenly Mother, so gentle
                            and dear, Down in her low valleys we'll praise. 'Tis there her sweet voice, from the angelic spheres, In love's
                            soften'd tones we can hear; Like music it floats on each heaven-born breeze, And bringeth the sound of good
                            cheer. The female Messiah in glory hath come, And now we have Saviors indeed, A Parentage perfect to guide us
                            along, A blessed and heavenly Lead. We'll follow in meekness, through Time's shady vale, To regions of beauty
                            and light, There, praising these Saviors through Heaven's high spheres, Shall be our eternal delight. Through
                            their holy unction, our souls have been raised From Nature's dark, unhallow'd plane ; We'll worship these
                            powers, and bow at no shrine But that of the heavenly twain. Our Father and Mother are Wisdom and Love, They're
                            seated on Heaven's "white throne;" And down on the earth, so benighted and drear, Their wisdom and glory have
                            shone. They've lighten'd and cheer'd it with radiant smiles Of kindness, affection, and love ; And open'd the
                            way of salvation and peace, Which leadeth to glories above. Blest land! fraught with bliss and with blessings
                            divine, We're hast'ning to thy pure abode, And, as we advance, we will loudly proclaim, Our Father and Mother
                            are GOD! !</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Smith, Jane Emily" TEIform="persName"/>Jane Emily Smith, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Subscriptions" TEIform="index"/>SUBSCRIPTIONS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Will, begin January, 1873. When bound the paper makes a beautiful volume.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Runyon, Matilda" TEIform="index"/>Matilda Runyon
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Pleasant Hill, Ky., May 14, 1873, <persName reg="Runyon, Matilda" TEIform="persName">Matilda Runyon</persName> passed to her
                                home in the spirit spheres to hear the sound well done; enter into rest!</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="League, Nancy" TEIform="index"/>Nancy League
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Also,<persName reg="League, Nancy" TEIform="persName">Nancy League</persName>, the 22d of same month, at the same place.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ring, Eliza" TEIform="index"/>Eliza Ring
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Ring, Eliza" TEIform="persName">Eliza Ring</persName>, October, 1872, aged 93, at Alfred, Me.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wakefield, Harriet" TEIform="index"/>Harriet Wakefield
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Wakefield, Harriet" TEIform="persName">Harriet Wakefield</persName>, March, 1872, aged 71, at Alfred, Me.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bean, Lucy" TEIform="index"/>Lucy Bean
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Bean, Lucy" TEIform="persName">Lucy Bean</persName>, June 24, 1873, aged 54, at Alfred, Me.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rice, Sally" TEIform="index"/>Sally Rice
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Rice, Sally" TEIform="persName">Sally Rice</persName>, June 14, 1873, aged 65, at Pleasant Hill, Ky.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Clark, Emeline" TEIform="index"/>Emeline Clark
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Clark, Emeline" TEIform="persName">Emeline Clark</persName>, March 20, 1873, aged 79, at Watervliet; also,</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Earle, Patience" TEIform="index"/>Patience Earle
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Earle, Patience" TEIform="persName">Patience Earle</persName>, June 17, 1873, aged 97.</p></div3></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>