<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2409" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">28</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">East Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">24</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">09</biblScope><date value="18940901" TEIform="date">September 1894</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">197-220</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="24" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="09" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
SEPTEMBER.
THE
MANIFESTO
PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES.
VOL. XXIV.
" Cast thy bread upon the waters ; for thou shalt find it after many days."
Eccl. XI: i.
East Canterbury, N. H.
1894.
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
CONTENTS.
History of South Union No. 11,
The Gift of Our Mission Meeting,
For Thought,        -       ...
Going Wrong,.....
Letter;W. N. Bassett,
Childhood,         .....
My Prayer,.....
Try Again,......
Scripture Text,      The True Millennium,    The Last Days,      ....
Music,Beign of Peace,
Notes About Home,
An Elopement,.....
True Greatness,    ....
The Mouse's Promise,    Acrostic,......
Pluck and Prayer,   Books & Papers,
197
200
201
202
203
204
205
206
208
210
211
217
218
219
220
A   CONCISE   HISTOKY   OF   THE
SHAKERS.
Just published. The book is printed
with large type and on excellent paper.
It contains 130 pages and has illustrations of the Shakers and their
COMMUNAL HOMES.
The  work gives  quite an extended account of the Several SOCIETIES, their
organization and general management.
Price  in cloth 75  cts;   in boards 50 cts.
Address.    H. C. Blinn,
East Canterbury, N. H.
THE  ALTRUIST.
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
qual rights to all. It is published by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all
their property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing
officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. 50 cents a year;
specimen copy free. Address A. Longley,
901 Olive St.,  St. Louis, Mo.
hardy Nursery Stock, and Seed Potatoes, full and complete line. Many varieties can only be obtained through us.
Commission or salary paid weekly, and
promptly. Exclusive and choice of territory given. Don't delay, write at once
for terms.
ALLEN NURSERY CO.
Rochester, N. Y.
PLAIN TALKS
PRACTICAL RELIGION,
Being    Candid   Ansivers   for Earnest
Inquirers.
By Geo. A.  Lomas.
Price, 10 cts.
THE SHAKER COVENANT.
This work sets forth the form of appointment, the qualifications and powers of the
several
ORDERS   OF   OFFICERS
in the Community : of the
PRIVILEGES  and OBLIGATIONS
of all the Members, and of the
DEDICATION     AND     CONSECRATION
of persons and property.
The book will afford interest to all, and at
the same  time, afford instruction to all   inquiring  minds.    Price 5  cts   each,   postage
paid, or 36 cts. per doz.
SKETCHES
or
SHAKERS & SHAKERISM.
A synopsis of Theology of the
United Society of Believers in
Christ's Second Appearing.
By G. B. Avery.
Price, 15 cts.
Reliable   men   to
sell our choice and
WANTED.--><pb n="197" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="History of South Union, Kentucky, no. 11" TEIform="index"/>HISTORY OF SOUTH UNION, KY. No.
                            11.</head><p TEIform="p">JAN. 4. Col. Nixon left this morning with his soldiers, for Russellville, having received
                            orders from head-quarters, last night. Col. Scott charged the pay-master to do better by us
                            than he did by Dr. R. We received $25.00 for corn; $100.00 for oats; $98.50 for beef ;
                            $48.00 for board bill of Officers, and $15.00 for milk, biscuits, etc. This amount was
                            passed to us in Confederate scrip, but we received no compensation for the wood that was cut
                            and hauled for them nor for anything that was taken, without orders, by the soldiers. During
                            the time of this encampment we lost several sheep skins that were tanned with the wool on,
                            also some horse collars and bridles. We try to be patient under all these trials. Through
                            the prayers of Believers we have been enabled to work patiently and this has influenced us
                            to be kind to the soldiers, and thus far we have marvelously escaped from all harm. For this
                            we have great cause to be thankful. After the soldiers were all gone from the Village, we
                            had time to reflect, and it pained us to think of the awful work, in which they were
                            engaged. Fathers and brothers in bitter conflict with each other, and doing all they could
                            to destroy life and property. We are praying for war to cease, and that a more substantial
                            government may be established on the earth, while the spirit of the Lord may find a place in
                            the hearts of the people. Col. Nixon was a careful reader of our publications, and Elder
                            John Rankin presented him with a "Millennial Church," and remarked,"I hope you may be able
                            to exchange the sword for a pruning-hook." A sick soldier expressed many words of gratitude
                            for the kindness that had been shown to him, while he was at our Village. SEPTEMBER <pb n="198" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 198 THE MANIFESTO. At one time while Elder Solomon was in company with
                            the soldiers, he was interrogated by them about our religion. Elder Solomon quoted some
                            passages of Scripture and then remarked,The Savior says, "Whosoever shall smite thee on thy
                            right cheek, turn to him the other also." These words were no sooner spoken than one large,
                            rough-looking man, struck Elder Solomon quite a hard blow on the cheek. The good man turned
                            around and the soldier struck him on the other cheek. This was a lesson in practical
                            Christianity and caused much amusement to those who were looking on. Jan. 29. Br. Urban
                            Johns goes to Bowling Green to ciiange some Confederate bonds into gold, which he does for
                            seventy-five ce.its on a dollar. Soldiers are passing on their way to Russellville, leading
                            horses which belonged to Scott's cavalry. About one hundred soldiers were killed, : nd these
                            horses escaped the sad fate of their masters. Br. Urban returns with an order from Gen.
                            Hardee, that no more forage should be taken from the Shakers for the use of the army. As the
                            country is under military law, we are now under the Confederate army. Jan. 30. Brs.
                            Jefferson Shannon and Cyrus Blakely, went to Russellville, to present two guns to the
                            Confederate Officer at that place, as the law now reads, "Every man with five hundred
                            dollars, shall either furnish a gun or pay twenty dollars." When it was learned that we had
                            only two guns for so many people, they told the Brethren to take one home. Jefferson and
                            Cyrus called on Capt. Williams, who was at the Village several days. He told them that most
                            of his men were sick with the measles. Feb. 4. Two doctors, Evans and Patterson, belonging
                            to Gen. Buckner's army, at Bowling Green, calls upon us to furnish hospital for their sick
                            soldiers, who were dying at the rate of ten each day. They wish us to accept from one
                            hundred to five hundred. The Brethren inform them of our crowded condition, since the
                            burning of the large building at our West family, but we would accept about twelve at a
                            time, and could take no more. The Physicians said they did not want their patients so
                            separated from each other, and they had asked this by the General's request, not by his
                            order, but the next time we may enforce it. Feb. 5. Br. Urban goes to Bowling Green, to
                            exchange some Confederate notes for gold. As our good Br. was on his way home, he was
                            accosted by some Texas Rangers, who had passed through our Village yesterday and called for
                            dinner, but the Brethren urged them to go to the Hotel, about one mile distant. This refusal
                            created a dislike toward us, and they stopped Br. Urban's horses. He asked them to explain
                            the object of their conduct. They replied,"You would not give us any dinner yesterday." At
                            this time, an officer, hearing the disturbance, halted to see what was being done. <pb n="199" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 199 The Rangers, fearing the officer, cursed Br. Urban
                            and then striking his horse, dashed off toward Bawling Green. Br. Urban was very glad that
                            he escaped with no more harm. To-day, we hear very distinctly, heavy cannonading in the
                            direction of Fort Henry. We count one hundred and three reports. Feb. 6. Soldiers are
                            passing through the Village, all day, in companies of two, four or six. They are moving
                            toward Bowling Green. Feb. 7. Fifty-two Cavalry pass through the Village, on their way to
                            the east. Army wagons are hauling corn for the soldiers. Elder Solomon met a Confederate
                            officer and asked him if the rumor was correct, that the Federals had taken Fort Henry. He
                            seemed very indifferent, but reckoned it was not correct. Sabbath, Feb. 9. A large company
                            of Cavalry and several army wagons, pass through the Village toward Bowling Green.
                            Thirty-two men with sixty-three horses, also go toward the same place. Then follow fourteen
                            wagons loaded with corn for the army. As the Cavalry halted in front of our dwellings, for
                            some little time, one of the Officers was heard to say,"Yes, yes, all these fine buildings
                            belong to them as a religious body. Every thing is held in common, as it was in the church
                            of the apostles. Do you not wish every body was like them ?" To this the answer came, ' 'If
                            we were like these Shakers, we would not be fighting the Yankees." Feb. 11. Two horses were
                            stolen from the West family last night, but no trace of them could be found. At about 2 p.
                            m., thirty horsemen halted in front of our dwelling. Elder John Rankin went to see what was
                            wanted. The Captain, McLemore, wished to know if the company could obtain a dinner. He was
                            informed that the Sisters would have dinner ready in fifteen minutes. We placed some tables
                            under the cedar trees, near the Trustees' office and the table was well furnished. When all
                            was ready, the Captain spoke in a low voice,"These are a religious and orderly people, and
                            we must be very quiet and orderly while at their home." After taking care of their horses,
                            they walked to the table in good order. They spoke in high terms of their dinner, as being
                            the best they had seen for a month. The charge was twenty cents each, which the Captain said
                            was cheap. (To be continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Neither circumstances nor surroundings..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Neither circumstances nor surroundings...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Neither circumstances nor surroundings however amplified or beautiful, hold attraction for
                            the soul that dwells in the innermostin the holy of holies of its beingwhere God is the ever
                            present joy and grace of life.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. A.</byline></div2><pb n="200" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gift of our mission meeting" TEIform="index"/>THE GIFT OF OUR MISSION MEETING.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="DeVere, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/>By Cecelia DeVere.</byline><p TEIform="p">We felt upon our spirits, rest A burden of the Living Word, And zeal that fluttered in each
                            breast, Was like a captive message bird. Vibrations thrilled affection's chain, Back to the
                            source of life's great good, To hearts beloved that here remain In Father and in Motherhood.
                            Dear guardians of that Mercy Seat. Brought out from types remote and dim ; That throne of
                            Truth where souls retreat For freedom and its morning hymn. We knelt in prayer, a circling
                            calm That held a central strength from heaven, Warm waves of blessing, mingling balm As
                            unction to our souls, were given. Ah, then it was within the veil, Parental supplication
                            rose, As perfumes, incense sweet exhale, When snow white lily leaves unclose. Our Mother
                            kneeling when we knelt But symbolized united hearts, Where Zion's every pulse is felt, Where
                            Zion's tide of blessing starts. Our duty saw no halting fear, The banner of the Light was
                            ours; An eager multitude drew near, As if to reach the holy powers. Our vision had extended
                            scope Through all that life's fruition mars, While reasons for each Gospel hope Were bright
                            as midnight's crown of stars. Plant faith, 0 God, the earth hath need, Of other harvest than
                            she bears; Glad rain, fair sunshine, and good seed Are folded in abiding prayers. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><pb n="201" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="For thought" TEIform="index"/>FOR THOUGHT.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo G." TEIform="persName"/>By Alonzo G. Hollister.</byline><p TEIform="p">IT is clear to me how souls may progress in the spirit world, without reincarnation. I have
                            no sympathy with that doctrine. It seems like a childish speculation of intellectual minds,
                            who must have something to fill the void made by the absence of knowledge. Some people feed
                            on fiction till it seems more real to them than truth itself; then they begin to doubt
                            truth, because it does not fadge with their imbibed fictitious measure. True intelligence
                            will teach them better things. A true knowledge of spiritual states will eventually so
                            commend itself to reason as to cast out the fantastic and unreal. If the true is not
                            immediately grasped by the understanding, the latter will leave as it becomes accustomed to
                            its growth and reality. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Going wrong" TEIform="index"/>GOING WRONG.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Mason, Moore S." TEIform="persName"/>By Moore S. Mason.</byline><p TEIform="p">IN reviewing the life of Samson in connection with the above subject, I was impressed with
                            the language reputed as his, "I will go out as at other times before and shake myself," and
                            find few parallel cases wherein sin sinks a man farther away from God'. Kad the degradation
                            which he brought himself to, been pointed out to him at an early period of his career, would
                            he not have said with one of old, "Is thy servant a dog, that he should do this thing?" yet
                            the position man attains and the character he makes for himself are no mere matters of
                            accident. Experience however, clearly shows us that falling away from integrity, is not
                            attributable to chance, but to deliberate choice; the rebellious will, the unstable
                            character: at first there is no intention of going far astrayjustI shall have a merry life
                            for a year or so and then settle down, but like a stone rolling down hill, we forget the
                            power evil habits have over us, and though we may have been instructed and warned, yet so
                            few will learn by any other experience than their own. Scarcely a week passes that we do not
                            read of young men going wrong; doubtless they supposed they had only to resolvenow I will
                            stop this folly and do right. It may have been, alas, the first temptation, and boasting in
                            the strength of young manhood they thought,I shall not yield again. How bold they are, but
                            lo, the next trying moment finds them again conquered and conscious of guilty shame; still
                            this class often overcome in the end. Each honest effort does them good. It is to the
                            indifferent person, having no desire than to be steeped in sin, that fearful apostacy from
                            God, that our best efforts should be made to save. The experience of the Shaker Church is
                            not unlike that of other religious bodies, the useful and hopeful members are and have been
                            those who learned <pb n="202" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 202 THE MANIFESTO. in youth to bear the cross, to
                            make the full surrender demanded by Christ. They soon found that all the difficulties
                            encountered in trying to live the Christ life, result from trying to serve two masters, God
                            and the world. How few of the friends of early years can we now trace; one by one they have
                            passed from sight, many, doubtless, lost on the turbulent sea of life, unknown, and without
                            restraint sunk by sinful indulgence, exclaiming like Samson ere they passed away,"I will go
                            out as at other times before and shake myself. And he wist not that the Lord was departed
                            from him." Union Village, O.</p></div2><div2 type="Section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Mother and Brother John..." TEIform="index"/>Dear Mother and Brother John...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mt. Lebanon, July 1, 1894" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. July 1,
                                1894.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Mother and Brother John;Your letter was received in clue time and I feel that I must
                                answer it especially on your account mother, for I know you feel interested to hear how
                                we are getting along. We are all well and enjoying ourselves far better than we could if
                                we were back living in the old way. I tell you John there is rest here for the sinsick,
                                weary soul in our peaceful, swreet Shaker home and I hope you will be wise enough to
                                live a pure, celebate, virgin life the remainderof your days. As for myself I would not
                                change back again for all the money, land and houses you could offer me. You told me we
                                could not bear the restraint that we would be compelled to live under here among the
                                Shakers, but I can assure you after five or six months' experience that I never enjoyed
                                so much real true liberty as I have since I came among Believers. Here in this family,
                                we have people of all ages, from little Gladys up to Sisters 82 years old, and we are
                                living far happier than we ever could if we were scattered around in little private
                                families. We are banded together not for the purpose of merely getting a temporal
                                living, but we declare our religious principles before the world, thereby making
                                ourselves an object lesson for the world to look at and learn from. We are now holding
                                our religious meetings in the large meeting-house, all of the six families attend, and
                                the doors are open to the public. The Brethren and Sisters are all at liberty to express
                                their honest convictions. Here we are a free people, we shake off our old earthly sinful
                                conditions, and rise into a higher and more spiritual state of mind. I tell you the
                                freedom of the spirit is the highest kind of freedom. Now perhaps you will say that you
                                can enjoy this liberty in the outside, worldly life without joining the Shakers; you are
                                welcome to your choice, but for my part I prefer to come out boldly and declare my faith
                                and let the world know just how I stand. <pb n="203" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 203 I wish
                                to be known as one who has arisen above the animal or generative plane of life, and that
                                I have put the lust of the flesh under my feet. According to my belief there are two
                                orders of life there is the generative order and the spiritual order. By the generative
                                order I mean all those who wish to multiply and replenish the earth, strictly in
                                accordance with nature's lower law, having no fellowship with the unfruitful works of
                                darkness, that is prostitution and abortion, or in any other way shirking the
                                responsibility of nature's requirements. This order is right for the Adamic man, and
                                there will always be plenty of people to carry on this work as long as the earth is
                                capable of sustaining material forms. The spiritual order is composed of those persons
                                who have risen above the desire for propagation. The more spiritually minded a person
                                becomes the less desire he has to beget or bring into life a natural offspring. The
                                powers and forces of the being flow in a higher channel, we have aspirations toward that
                                which is higher and better, we are living on the resurrection plane, that is in the
                                regenerative work. This is my experience, the more spirituality I have the less animal
                                desires rule and govern ; I think you will find it so. In your last letter you spoke of
                                married men being better than bachelors, now in a certain sense this may be true, for
                                they may be dissipated and live single only to escape responsibility, and to selfishly
                                spend their money on rum, tobacco and bad women. I claim that such men are not as
                                honorable as those who live in the married state; they have nothing to do with Shakerism
                                whose requirements are strict continence and self-denial. I know what the fruits of the
                                flesh are by my own bitter experience; but thank God I have risen up out of these low
                                groveling conditions which still cling to me, and then I will be free to progress onward
                                forever through the endless ages of eternity. With much love to you dear mother and
                                brother. I remain your loving son and brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bassett, W. N." TEIform="persName"/>W. N. Bassett.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Childhood" TEIform="index"/>CHILDHOOD.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>By Martha J. Anderson.</byline><p TEIform="p">Blest childhood ! happy, innocent and free, Rose-lipped and blushing as the dawning day With
                            eyes as brilliant, and heart as gay As the gazelle who loveth liberty. Though glad the life
                            and full of mirthful glee. Yet all the questioning through toil and play Show how unfolding
                            thought and reason sway And mould the face that speaks sincerity. Oh, joyful hours of early
                            spring-tide dreams! <pb n="204" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 204 THE MANIFESTO. Which lead by rippling stream
                            and flowery glade, When all the imagery of lii'e but seems Like some fair picture on a
                            canvas laid, ' Whose beauteous shades are like the sunset gleams, That from the expanding
                            vision quickly fade. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My prayer" TEIform="index"/>MY PRAYER.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Calver, Amelia J." TEIform="persName"/>By Amelia J. Calver.</byline><p TEIform="p">Father I pray. I do not know my needs, I only know I have a void within which Thou canst
                            fill. And whatso'er the cup Thou givest me, I'll press unto my lips, and let it work
                            Salvation in my soul. I do not know the way Which leadeth to the hights my soul would climb
                            But trusting Thee as I have trusted e'er, Since first I cast my lot and took the staff The
                            pilgrim's staffI'll follow on o'er hill And vale, where'er I hear thy still small voice,
                            Until I reach another hight attained Unto by perfect trust, which overlooks The wayward
                            windings of the past and gives Me sight to see still other hights beyond Which I must reach.
                            Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Try again" TEIform="index"/> "TRY AGAIN."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName"/>By Abraham Perkins.</byline><p TEIform="p">SUBJECT as poor humanity is to temptation and trial, the good old motto,"Try again,"
                            unfortunately is often unheeded. Because of failures in enterprises and engagements in the
                            affairs of life, courage oft goes down with disappointment. Prospects externally bright give
                            faith and hope ; yet, with the exercise of our best judgment and the application of our best
                            powers, human wisdom often proves inadequate to the accomplishment of the attainments and
                            objects sought. In human experience, this fact is verified:the battles of life are to be
                            met; they must and will come, bringing the invasion at our door. As it exists in the
                            temporal, so we find it in the spiritual. Many a traveler in pursuit of the treasures of the
                            spirit stumbles at the cross and fails <pb n="205" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 205 to obtain
                            the crown, because of the straitness of the gate and the narrowness of the way ; because
                            there are hills to climb and the paths oft rough and thorny; because of foes to encounter
                            and burdens to be borne, which imposes a sacrifice greater than he is willing to endure. But
                            vain is the effort to secure this endowment, without paying its full value by a total
                            surrender of all that is selfish, carnal and worldly. Eternal life is found only as we yield
                            the selfish. The yoke must be taken, and it is made easy by being continually and cheerfully
                            borne. Jordan must be reached and repeatedly entered for the baptism that gives complete
                            remission and the necessary washing. Failures in life, ignorant or willful, may be many; and
                            though they number seventy times seven, fail not to continue the strife; wrestle until the
                            break of day, as did the patriarch Jacob, and suffer not the angel to depart until the
                            blessing is reached. Oh, earth, earth! listen and hear the word of the Lord. Although it
                            bring heavy sacrifices, a satisfactory reward is sure to follow, commensurate with the
                            offering. As is the work, so will be the reward. No good effort will be unrewarded, and no
                            evil design or act will go unpunished. Therefore keep in view the wise motto,"Try again,"
                            and fail not to make it practical. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Scripture text" TEIform="index"/>SCRIPTURE TEXT.</head><p TEIform="p">Sent to us by Simon Emery, of Bangor, Me. ' 'And fear not them which kill the body, but are
                            not able to kill the soul, but rather fear him which is able to destroy both soul and body
                            in hell." Matt, x., 28. AS it was the mission of Jesus the Christ to lead mankind from the
                            paths of unrighteousness into those of righteousness and peace, he must adapt himself to all
                            the variations of life in which these people might be found. He was a Teacher of the rich
                            and poor, the educated and ignorant, and no less of the old and young. At this time Jesus
                            was giving instruction to his disciples as he appointed them to the mission of teaching
                            others as they had already been taught. They were to put on the whole armor of God, and go
                            into the world fearlessly in the accomplishing of their duty, as sheep in the midst of
                            wolves. (Matt, x., 16.) Several of these disciples had already learned by experience what it
                            was to battle with the world, and to enlist in the Lord's army without fear. Others may have
                            embraced the gospel testimony, having this invitation at heart, "Wisdom's ways are ways of
                            pleasantness, and all her paths are peace." To inspire the several classes with unflinching
                            love for God was the divine work of the Teacher. <pb n="206" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 206 THE MANIFESTO.
                            While the disciples were to "beware of men," lest they should become ensnared through
                            flattery or threats, they were expected to do their duty and trust in the protective spirit
                            of God which had called them into ihe gospel work. Jesus had forewarned them of the dangers
                            through which they must pass. The Jews, said he, will deliver you up to the councils ; they
                            will scourge you in their synagogues. It was no child's piny to be an evangelist, and the
                            timid might well shrink at the thought of being imprisoned or of being scourged with thirty
                            blows upon the naked back with brutal fore-1, and each blow cutting deep into the flesh. The
                            disciples were also made a gazing stock both by reproaches and afflictions, and hated of all
                            men. One might wonder at the determined zeal which could inspire the twelve to go into the
                            cities of Israel and deliver the gospel messages which were so well calculated to destroy
                            all the sensual pleasures of a selfish relation. After this wonderful preparation for
                            entering the gospel field, Jesus then adds another encouraging word by saying, "Fear not
                            them which kill the body but are not able to kill the soul." The duty to God was made the
                            essential feature. Through this came the fulfillment of the promise of increased blessing on
                            the earth, and in the world to come, eternal life. The same spirit that whispered the above
                            word" also said to them, "Be thou faithful unto death, and I will give the * a crown of
                            life." God's will and work must come first, and the love or fear of God must conquer every
                            other form of fear. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., H. C." TEIform="persName"/>H. C. B.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True millennium" TEIform="index"/>THE TRUE MILLENNIUM.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Burger, Sarah J." TEIform="persName"/>By Sarah J. Burger.</byline><p TEIform="p">ALL through the ages, prophets, priests and people have looked forward to the time when the
                            dawn of the great Millennium would break upon the earth, and the saying "like priest, like
                            people," instead of Indicating the ignorant and sinful condition of both, would apply to a
                            united brotherhood, a universal Church whose members would be joined together in the spirit
                            of holiness and love. But what of the present? war, crime, slavery to ambition and lust are
                            rife in the land: evil is not confined to the innermost thoughts and feelings, but it is
                            bold in coming to the front through the pages of the daily press, whereby even little
                            children often become tainted with its pernicious influence. We exclaim like one of old,
                            "How long, 0 Lord, how long before wickedness and sin will be swept from the land, and
                            righteousness and truth reign instead," Poets have written and bards have sung of the good
                            time coming, the glorious Millennium, the glad reign of peace; but when will it come ? When
                            the evils of the human heart shall give place to the virtues of the Divine life, and man
                            learns through the subjection of his lower passions to develop his superior faculties which
                            lead to a higher life and <pb n="207" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 207 plane of existence, when
                            the spiritual, or God life in the soul, shall permeate the very atmosphere as a sanctifying
                            presence. To attain unto this as a universal condition, will require a pentecostal revival
                            that shall awaken the nations and touch the hearts of all people ; then will the glorious
                            Millennium be realized, each seeking the good of his neighbor through the spirit of true
                            Christianity made manifest in their daily lives. If wrong conditions in man have their
                            effect upon the anthopostic world, producing conflict in the elements destructive to his
                            peace and well-being, should not the unfolding and development of a spiritual power bring
                            forth corresponding results, causing the "wilderness and solitary places to be glad, and the
                            desert to rejoice and blossom as the rose?" Most assuredly. Then may it be said of a truth
                            "ye shall go out with joy, and be led forth with peace; the mountains and the hills shall
                            break forth before you into singing, and all the trees of the field shall clap their hands.
                            Instead of the thorn shall come up the fir tree, and instead of the brier shall come up the
                            myrtle tree; and it shall be to the Lord for a name, for an everlasting sign that shall not
                            be cut off." In that time when the great Millennium shall come, righteousness and peace
                            shall kiss the earth, and the angel of joy brighten the hearts of all people, and the
                            nations shall be linked together in the bonds of universal brotherhooda harmonious
                            relationship springing forth from the love which is expressed in, "Each for all, and all for
                            each." As the flower is in the seed and only needs the careful hand of the husbandman to
                            nurture it till it expands into the bud, then on to the beautiful blossom, so with the
                            spirit of truth, though often concealed beneath the creeds and superstitions of a false
                            theology, yet it remains in its embryotic state, till the germ is touched with the sun of
                            inspiration and it bursts forth as a new revelation of the Holy Spirit, developing the God
                            life in man, creating a holy communion between the internal and external world, forming a
                            heaven upon earth, a paradise of God, the true Millennium. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Blessed is the man who lives..." TEIform="index"/>Blessed is the man who lives...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Blessed is the man who lives in accordance with the law of God written in his own heart; he
                            shall have wisdom and understanding, a strong brain, a vitalized spirit and vigorous body.
                            There shall be depth of music in his voice, firmness and elasticity in his step, and bravery
                            of heart to do right. To him will men look as one made in the image of God, who has not by
                            indiscretion marred or blighted his perfect likeness.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. A.</byline></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p"> NOTICE. Those wishing to communicate with the "Believers" at Shaker Station by wire, will
                            direct George Wilcox (or any other person) Shaker Station, Conn. If before 2 o'clock, p. m.
                            direct by mail to Springfield, Mass., but if after 2 o'clock at Scitico, Conn. George
                            Wilcox.</p></div2><pb n="208" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Last days" TEIform="index"/>THE LAST DAYS. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">WHATEVER may have transpired among men at an earlier date, and induced the apostles to write
                            of the perilous last days, we may now feel justified without reserve in calling these the
                            special last days of which the good man made reference to his son Timothy. We are having all
                            the signs placed so prominently before us that we have no occasion for any guess work. Paul
                            very properly calls them perilous times as they are so objectionable to the mind of a
                            Christian, and he evidences this by saying that the people would be lovers of themselves,
                            covetous, boasters, proud, blasphemers, disobedient to parents, unthankful and unholy. The
                            apostle extends the list of sad deviations from right still farther, as the unfortunate
                            result of a life of unrighteousness. It must, indeed, be perilous times to any individual,
                            or family or society when it enters into one or more of those selfish relations which would
                            so soon dc moralize the mind. If this was to be the state of those who had not experienced a
                            call in to the gospel testimony of Jesus the Christ, it would be a fair representation of
                            what might be expected, more or less, to enter into his church as probationary or more
                            permarent members. Those who are "lovers of themselves," would without doulit be covetous,
                            and even this fractional portion of the list would be enough to bring "perilous times" upon
                            any large or small community. The spirit of selfishness and the spirit of Christ could not
                            under any circumstances be brought into fellowship. Covetousness in the church of Christ
                            would soon reduce it to the level of the world, unless there was sufficient vitality in the
                            religious body to expel it. The fierce war which is now going on between capital and labor
                            is the result of that state which was so clearly presented to the apostle. The rich and the
                            poor are alike covetous, and either class would willingly allow the other to suffer, if the
                            suffering would increase their advantages to accumulate wealth, or increase their dominant
                            privileges over the souls and bodies of men. From the day that Cain made himself the
                            possessor of the property of Abel, an incessant war has been raging among men. Cain
                            evidently wanted to increase his wealth, and to obtain this he put Abel out of the way,
                            which gave him an undisputed right. This same spirit of covetousness which finds a home in
                            the hearts of the "strikers" and no less in the hearts of those who are struck, engenders
                            outrage and murder in order that their own selfish plans may be consummated. Jesus was espe-
                                <pb n="209" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 209 cially a friend to the poor and gave his life
                            that he might raise them from their low estate. Although poor, he would have them become
                            peacemakers, and then become the children of God. The essential lesson to be learned by
                            those who accept the divine Teacher as their heavenly guide is, first, to be pure then
                            peaceable, and this, at once, would exclude the piofarve person, and those who are
                            unthankful. It was the admonition of the first Elders of our own church, that those who were
                            unthankful for the blessings which God gave to his people from day to day, be they few or
                            many, they were equally unholy. The lesson of thankfulness must necessarily be accepted by
                            those who would become the children of our heavenly Father, if they expected to gather souls
                            and be able to protect them from the sins of the world. There may, indeed, be "perilous
                            times" when children become disobedient to their parents, and under the Mosaic dispensation
                            a severe penalty was inflicted upon either the son or daughter that presumed to disregard
                            the advice of a parent. This was the discipline of the natural order when the faithful
                            father and mother stood as mediators between their children and their God. The apostle may
                            have had this in mind as he saw other conditions moving forward and with prophetic vision
                            determined the time when even the children would deviate so far from propriety as to be
                            disobedient to their parents. Entering upon the spiritual plane where a higher and purer
                            relation is manifested to both parents and children, he anticipates greater things for the
                            church of Christ and urges the immature minds with the care of a faithful
                            guardian,"Children, obey your parents in the Lord." This was a step in advance. The church
                            had accepted the children and these spiritual parents now asked that due obedience might be
                            rendered to them as it had been rendered to their parents in the order of nature. In our
                            Community home it is imperative that children should be obedient to their parents in the
                            Lord, as without the acceptance of this, there can be no foundation upon which to build an
                            honest and an honorable character. And as we say of children, we would as clearly say the
                            same of every adult who accepts the cross of Christ. Study the character of Jesus, who in
                            his ministration of the gospel work said to his disciples, "Learn of me for 1 am meek and
                            lowly in heart." And in addition to this bear the good apostle in mind who says, "First pure
                            then peaceable, easy to be entreated." In the acceptance of these Christian lessons, we may
                            escape those "perilous times" which are sure to overtake the careless transgressor.</p></div2><pb n="210" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reign of peace" TEIform="index"/>REIGN OF PEACE.</head><p TEIform="p">''Peace I leave with you, my peace I give unto you."St. John, xvi., 27. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. 1.
                            Pure as the fadeless noonday light. Calm as the gentle hush of night, 2. Read we of days
                            when sword and spear,Darkened the earth with death and fear, 3. Many hosannas joyously,
                            Sounded in Bethlehem glad and free, 4. For we have seen love's guiding ray, Followed its
                            course till perfect day, Sweet as the breeze from the mountain's hight, Is peace, pure
                            heavenly peace. Love chorded not in the strains of cheer, Nor peace, pure heavenly peace.
                            And on the plains of fair Galilee, For the Prince of heavenly peace. Grateful to God who has
                            filled the way, With peace, pure heavenly peace. Come to our hearts with thy loveliness,
                            Soften our lives, control and bless, Bud to the world in its gloom and blight, Now has
                            appeared the Christ of light, We too can join in a heartfelt song, Glad that the right is
                            conquering wrong, Sound we again many praises sweet,Sung to the tread of angels' feet, Mold
                            us and ever our souls possess, Sweet peace, holy peace, Substance of truth and the pow'r of
                            right, Of peace, holy peace, Making our spirits in virtue strong, In peace, holy peace, For
                            they are coming all souls to meet, In peace, eternal peace.</p></div2><pb n="211" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. SEPTEMBER, 1894. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is published by the
                            "United Society of Believeks" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued
                            regularly by the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the
                            religious views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. All
                            communications should be addressed to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. TIE
                            JR.MIS. One copy per year, postage paid .75 " " six months, " " .40</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. July. . Thermometer. Rain. 1893. 55.52 5^in. 1894.
                                72.13 1.4" Highest Temp, during this mo. 94. above 0. Lowest " " " " 47. " " Number of
                                rainy days " " 10. " clear " " cloudy " 14. 7. C. G. Heed. Aug. 1894. Such sultry
                                weather is not conducive to either written or vocalized thought; consequently Notes will
                                be brief, leaving room for something better. We are deeply interested in the war history
                                of our Southern Believers, and won der where the strength and courage lay for so much
                                "arduous and continuous" toil, with no hope for remuneration only in the consoling
                                thought, that kindness was being done to many poor soldiers, whose hearts lay not in the
                                work before them. The society must have been under Divine protection to survive
                                financially and physically after such a tax on time, strength, and material wealth. The
                                most interesting feature of our home at present, is the increased gathering at our
                                public Sabbath service, of a quiet, attentive audience. Speaking and singing are so
                                appropriately alternate, that nearly two hours pass before we are aware; and there would
                                be a still greater variety of gifts ifwell perhaps it is better to speak too long, than
                                to keep the good thought hidden. But monopoly in these days seems to be unpopular. We
                                see nor feel no deterioration, in our gospel testimony. Our confidence in its worth
                                inci'eases, and it is only left for us to add works to faith, patience and unselfishness
                                to works, and as Elder Daniel Offord says, "let the light shine through all our works,
                                financially, as well as morally and spiritually," and our spiritual strength would
                                gather and hold many who are sick of sin, and are willing to cast their all into the
                                Lord's treasury for the compound interest which they will receive. Health of family as
                                good as such hot weather will permit. Haying nearly done and harvesting of grain in
                                order. Our abundant supply c f raspberries are gathered, blackberries and dewberries
                                nearly gone, but tomatoes are fast ripening to fill the place. Surely with such abundant
                                blessings, gratitude should be the characteristic of our lives. Our Sunday School class,
                                studying the life of Jesus from the four gospels during this quarter, are much
                                interested in selected readings from "Ben Hur" on that subject, which, with its
                                beautiful description of life in the Orient, clothed in such rich language, makes the
                                lesson very impressive. In reading a book we can always <pb n="212" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 212 THE
                                MANIFESTO. determine its character by the impression it leaves with us. 1 thought I
                                should be brief, but I see I have filled the entire space allotted me. Amelia J. Calrer.
                                North Family. Aug. 1894. Just a few hastily written notes, which I fear are too late for
                                acceptance by the tolerant editor and prompt compositors of our Manifesto. The good
                                Brethren have been rushing through the haying and harvesting; not only overseeing the
                                necessary hired help, but doing their full share of the laborious work. The weather has
                                been all that could be desired for gathering the crops: the last load of oats was
                                secured on the eleventh, a fair yield of hay and cereals, excepting wheat, which was
                                light. The Sisters have been kept quite busy harvesting; a nicely cultivated blackberry
                                patch in our north orchard has yielded twenty bushels of berries, two thirds of which
                                have been sold in the Pittsfield market, with other produce. Were it not for the dry
                                weather, we would have a fair yield of apples, as the orchards are in excellent
                                condition, all the trees having been trimmed in proper season. Those that have been
                                gathered are small; perhaps the winter fiuit will be larger. Tomatoes and sweet corn,
                                with other fresh vegetables are abundant; and our gardens show the diligent care of
                                those who handle the cultivator and hoe. Our public meetings have been largely attended
                                for three Sabbaths past; it was estimated that five hundred people were present
                                yesterday morning, and a more respectful, attentive audience could not have been
                                gathered in any house of worship. We find a growing interest in our own town to know and
                                understand more of our life and doctrines; which interest has been awakened by an
                                intelligent young friend of ours who is in business relation with Tilden &amp; Co.
                                She has been a constant attendant at our meetings, and says that many young men come to
                                our services who never step inside of any other church. We have discontinued exercises,
                                so it is not the external that draws them. We hope that many will be benefited by the
                                simple and sincere utterance of truth, and the offerings of praise and prayer rendered
                                to God, by those whose lives are consecrated to good, and who seek to draw all men and
                                women to the knowledge of right and the practice of every virtue. With universal love,
                                blessing and appreciation of every good word and work, I desire to strive with gospel
                                kindred for the unity of the Spirit of Christ. Martha J. Anderson. Center Family. Aug.
                                1894. Beloved Elder Henry;We have finished our cherry harvest which was very good and
                                the largest crop ever grown at Center family. Pears are beginning to ripen and to be an
                                average yield as do plums also. The material things of time engage most of our attention
                                as to how we shall get an ,jionest living, seeing that most of our industries have been
                                dropped for some reason or other. It is conceded by people generally, that eastern
                                people can not compete with the west in the raising of grain and cattle, hence we must
                                of necessity turn our attention to the growing of small fruits; this we can do to pretty
                                good advantage and the more pains we take in the selection and culture of it, the more
                                it will prove a means of livelihood. Timothy D. Rayson.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">North Family. Aug. 1894. We have had a special privilege the past month, in being favored
                                with a visit from our beloved Brother, Alonzo G. Hol- <pb n="213" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/>lister, of Mt.
                                Lebanon, N. Y. How true it is that we consciously or unconsciously mister to others,
                                just what we have in possession; and in the visit of our dear Brother, We realized more
                                fully than ever the truth of that assertion. His ministration was to strengthen and
                                encourage those who love the cause and to uphold the standard of virgin purity, that it may
                                be seen and read of all tribes and nations, that the truth alone maketh free,  We are
                                encouraged to press forward and to give all that we have to the support of the cause,
                                knowing that the testimony is going forth, bringing mankind to judgment a witness
                                thereof is given in the desion of the Catholic Church in regard to the liquor traffic.
                                It is to be hoped that they will have the courage of their convictions and stand firm in
                                the position bey have taken; if theydo, a blessing ill attend them. Every such move mong
                                mankind, is the trumpet sound of he angel of judgment, cleansing the outer temple,
                                preparing it for the repeption of e resurrection testimony; for how oould soul whose
                                body is filled with liquor and 'Qbaooo, understand the truths' of the higher life?
                                Impossible. Our grain harvest is about finished. At resent writing, we are having a
                                refreshing rain. Fruit prospeot fail' for apples nd pears. The cold weather in May
                                rerded tender vegetables, but if we can have a late autumn, they will develop a good
                                crop. Our beloved Ministry are with us and all the faithful ones are ministering he
                                testimony. May we receive it with humble spirits. </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station, Conn.</head><p TEIform="p">Aug, 1894. "VIRTUE alone is happiness," and happiness is heaven. Virtue is a bright [ew,
                                1 richer than gold or precious gems. To Main it, our hearts, which are the seat 1
                                prinoiples, must be purified by the ross. By the cross we are united to, the ea.venly
                                throng. Constant, self-denying efforts will insure Ull a safe passport to heavenly
                                mansions, What a flood of happiness fills our souls when we have striven earnestly for
                                overcoming power, and feel that we are made better for those strivings. Let us so live
                                that we can feel the treasures of heaven are ours. The first point is to staut right,
                                and keep in the heavenly pathway-it is plain. It is safe to walk uprightly. Success in
                                the Christian warfare is the result of the right improvement of time, the application of
                                energy and soul-struggles. Let us adorn our souls with 'the beautiful jewels of purity
                                and truth. How often are to-day's opportunltles, to-day's privileges neglected, and time
                                lost in anticipation of some good we are to gain in the future. Greater opportunities
                                will not come to-morrow unless we are faithful to improve those that God has given us
                                to-day. Let us do whatever conscience enjoins and shun all that it condemns. What ought
                                not to be done we should not think of doing. Among the pitfalls in our way, let us be
                                wary, watch and pray'. JUly 10th we were favored with a visit from Br. Walter Shepherd
                                and four Sisters of Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., and they seemed like an angelic band. We think
                                such visits should be more frequent. "The largest statue is Bartholdi's 'Liberty,' its
                                weight is 440,000 Its. the height of the figure is 152}~ ft. the pedestal 91 ft. the
                                fountain 52, one finger is 8 ft., the nose 3Yz." "Thunder-storms are more frequent in
                                Java than in any region in the world." "In Bussla there are 750,000 ac~es planted to
                                sun-flowers, one variety has small seeds for the production of oil; the other has larger
                                seeds, and is used for consumption, like our peanuts. 'I'he average yield is 1350 lbs
                                per .acre, and the seeds sell at lYz cts, per pound.ithe farmer's income being $20.25
                                per acre." * * * * * * * The key-note of poultry growing is profit <pb n="214" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/>it, and the quicker an unprofltable flock is disposed of, the better. For growing
                                chickens, meat and bone furnishes all the elements of growth if fed in moderate
                                quantttles, Bones furnish Iime for the formation of the egg shells, and the meat
                                furnishes a supply of albumen, of which the whites of eggs is largely composed.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">East Canterbury, N. H. Weather Record .for July, 1894. Highest Temp. during the month,
                                94 Lowest " ' " " " 51 Mean " ,,' " " 3.68 Amount of rain in inches, - 71.8 , N,. A.
                                Briggs, Aug, 6, 1894. As a historical note we are interested to have it understood that
                                on the 6th of August 1774, Mother Ann Lee and her little band of faithful followers,
                                after a perilous voyage of several months across the ocean, all landed safely in the
                                harbor of New York. i Holding this event in pleasant remembrance a social service was
                                held on the above date. .A very interesting . programme of recitations and songs had
                                been prepared by a company of young Sisters, rest1ng upon the historical incidents that
                                transpired in the lives and in the Gospel work of Mother Ann and the Elders. To us this
                                eventIs One of, deep interest. Through it comes the blessing of our earthly home, the
                                religious element ofour Community and the anticipated hope ofa never ending work of
                                righteousness and  peace. From New York City they went to Albany, and then purchased a
                                tract of land in the town of Watervliet. -For several years the little family toiled
                                earnestly. in their new home, and were faithful witnesses of the gospel of our Divine
                                Teacher, Jesus Christ. Under the-blessing of God they were able to establish other
                                community homes where the Believers had dedicated themselves to the Lord. With the
                                coming of an early spring and its never failing seed time, we pleasantly antioipated a
                                re,munerative harvest of all,. earth's blessings, but in this case as in I many others
                                we were unable to see the end from the beginning. From some cause the early potatoes did
                                not grow very large, which has prevented us from dig. gingmany of them up to the present
                                date. The, hay crop has been good and IUOst ;of it secured in excellent order, Some 200
                                tons have been cut and secured in this Society, , On the 9th lnst, eleven persons from
                                our ,Society,' by invitation, visited the village of Pittsfield, a ,distance of ten
                                miles and gave a public entertainment. The programme consisted of the singing of sacred
                                ' and secular pieces" and ,a varied order of recitations. The service of two hours gave
                                pleasure to 'an appreciative audience .of some two hundred persons. '.' Large companies
                                of visitors from the cities are with us nearly every day. Some of them dine in the
                                Trustees' Office, while others who bring their lunch find a place under the branches of
                                the maples. All want to walk about the premises' and see what the Shakers have in their
                                home, and if they are just like 'all other people. I wonder why the guides who accompany
                                these visitors do not keep a note book of the curiosities of literature, which could be
                                so easily gathered. A thousand and one questions are asked, and as many answers must be
                                formulated to make the pleasure reciprocal. , H. C. Blinn. </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Aug. 1894. HAYING on our ahome farm finished July 30th about an average crop, and good
                                weather to cure it. Every day two of our Sisters leave home early in the morning fOr the
                                Canaan farm to take care of the I house where the men lodge who are haying <pb n="215" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 215 on the meadows. Harvesting has commenced in the oat
                                fields, a good crop though a little rusty. On the 5th ult. a company of Brethren and
                                Sisters from the Church and North families held a meeting, by request, in the chapel at
                                East Lebanon, we had a very attentive audience from the villages round about us; many of
                                whom did not know in what we believed, so little do we let our light shine. We are happy
                                to record a short visit from Elder Nicholas Briggs of Canterbury. G. H. Kirkley. Aug.
                                1894. North Family. The periodicals which come to our home daily, contain an abundance
                                of useful knowledge and much matter that saddens; yet all, stores the reflecting mind
                                with valuable lessons; even the most horrifying news has its moral picture, informing us
                                that virtue pays and "the way of the transgressor is hard." I am led to muse, should not
                                literature, like the churcheswhich have a stronger hold upon the minds of menbe, not
                                only the strongest, but as true and pure sounding organs, caroling life's ennobling
                                lessons, through its steel lips, unsparingly denounce the evils in high and low life,
                                that peace and plenty, love and equality may triumph over sin and woe. May our
                                Manifesto, with its unalloyed pages, ever stand as a fit publication of what home
                                literature should be and spread abroad the glad tidings of God's love to mankind and of
                                Christ's redeeming virtues to those who "Awake the powers of mind, of soul attuned, To
                                all the grand sublimities of life." We have harvested seventy-five tons of hay and
                                twenty tons of oats and barley. Having had a few lowery days, the plough made furrows
                                through some of the worn out land near our home, which means a fuller and more
                                productive hay crop in the future: and the question is, would not the cultivation of the
                                land near us be a good idea, while that afar off be sold? The general health of our
                                family is good, and as health strengthens virtue, the most valuable gem mankind can
                                possess. We are still cheered with bright hope that leads away from sorrow and
                                strengthened by pure love that points toward the hights of a better self-hood. George H.
                                Baxter.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Alfred, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Alfred., Maine.</head><p TEIform="p">Aug. 1894. Since writing Home Notes two moons have waxed and waned. July with its extreme
                                heat so hard for humanity but so good for the corn, and now comes August with the New
                                England weather extreme. The night of the 10th brought frost on the low ground. , The
                                Brethren have finished the hajing and report 15 per cent less than last year, from the
                                last year's drouth on the grass roots. We had corn on the table the ICtli which is early
                                for this section. The Bivt'iren tried spraying the potatoes with the Bordeaux Mixture to
                                protect them from rust, and up to date our potato tops are green, while our neighbors'
                                are rusting badly. We look at things differently. Ii I should ask our children wliat was
                                the most important thing that happened in the last month, they would say their excursion
                                to Portland and the Islands. Some twenty-five of the younger portion of our Society with
                                a few older ones, went to Portland the morning of the 9th and had a sail on Casco Bay.
                                We landed at Peaks Island, where we spent a few hours, and then returned to Portland
                                where the purchases made were too numerous to be recorded in the Manifesto. Then came
                                our ride home in the evening on the P. and E. road, all glad to reach our quiet Shaker
                                Home. Fannie Casey.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harvard, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Harvard, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">Aug. 1894. Again Nature has favored us with a beautiful day and we improve it by going
                                    <pb n="216" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 216 THE MANIFESTO. to Shirley to meet with our gospel kindred
                                in prayer and praise. We met Elder Hiram Baker of Enfield, N. H. and were happy to see
                                him. We are pleased to learn through the Manifesto that we were in union with some of
                                our sister Societies in noticing our Nation's holiday. On the lawn tibles were spread
                                with dainties for material enjoyment, and we enjoyed a picnic here till the regular
                                Fourth of July shower drove us to shelter. But our pleasure was not spoiled, for we had
                                a good intellectual feast of singing, recitations and dialogues. Haying is finished, and
                                good judges say there are a hundred tons of good hay snugly packed away in the barns.
                                Our labor is now turned to herbs, of which we have a generous supply considering the
                                long drought. We have a bountiful supply of blueberries and whortleberries, which keep
                                our young people busy. They are quite near and a half dozen pickers go into the field
                                after dinner, and return at night with a bushel or a bushel and a half of nice berries.
                                They are a good substitute for the loss of our small fruits. We recently received a
                                visit from Bishop Chatschumain, an Armenian who is lecturing through the States in the
                                interest of his down-trodden countrymen in Armenia. In the evening he spoke to the
                                family upon the productions of the soil of that country, the social relations, habits
                                and religion of the people. They claim to be the oldest Christian nation in existence,
                                say their church was established in the days of the apostles. They use no pork and
                                seldom taste animal food. A good Christian example. Marcia M. Bullard.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watervliet, Ohio" TEIform="index"/>Watervliet, O.</head><p TEIform="p">Aug. 1894. We have had very dry weather making the crops very backward, but we can not
                                complain, as we have been blest with many gifts from God. We number thirty individuals
                                in our Society at the present time. It seems to be a hard m atter to gather souls to our
                                flock who are willing to become thoroughly baptized with the Christ spirit, and who are
                                willing to give up the world and its so-called pleasures, but we intend to keep right on
                                in the good work and do the best we can, for God will not let his children suffer. Our
                                crops are turning out pretty fair. Wheat has yielded about 25 bushels and oats about 50
                                bushels to the acre, but the price does not yield very much. Wheat is 45 cts. and oats
                                31 cts. per bush. We have put up about 50 tons of Timothy hay and about the same amount
                                of clover. We have recently been blessed with the company of our gospel Br. Charles
                                Sturr, of White Water. Henry W. Fredrick.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Union Village, Ohio" TEIform="index"/> Union Village, O.</head><p TEIform="p">Aug. 1894. As I passed down the road to the ferry from Pleasant Hill to High Bridge over
                                Kentucky River. I noticed the trees and plants which cropped out from the crevices of
                                the romantic cliffs, perpendicular walls, hundreds of feet high, which rise on each side
                                of this wonderful stream. This scene of cliff, tree, plant and flower, was one of
                                profound silence. Yet here was an invisible energy at work, sufficient to raise a
                                million tons of water into the upper air. From every crevice between the layers of rock,
                                sprang a tree or lesser plant, some so tiny as to be scarcely visible. Perfect peace and
                                concord reigned. No pushing, jostling or contention were here. Contentment and peace
                                pervaded the tiniest plant, the most inconspicuous shrub and the tallest tree. The
                                admirable and inspiring effect of this scene, was not produced by any one object, but by
                                the natural, spiritual combination of the sublime whole. All organizations, from the
                                tiniest plant to the tallest tree, from the smallest insect to the elephant, seem to
                                move in harmonious contentment with themselves and their environment. How beautiful, how
                                inspiring <pb n="217" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 217 this vital energy which calmly goes
                                on, "yesterday, to-day and forever," in the soundless silence of the fields and woods,
                                the rocks and valleys. Why are peace and contentment to be found everywhere but in
                                restless, roving man? There are good and all-sufficient reasons, which in due time shall
                                be satisfactorily explained to every rational being in existence. When Archimides
                                discovered the law of displacement, he exclaim ed,"Eureka! I have found it." This is the
                                point I profess to hail from in my experience : not as boasting by any means, but for
                                the comfort and encouragement of others who are dismayed at the pertinence of the above
                                question. We are contending with the present prevailing drouth, in more ways than one.
                                Our dry-house and laundry wood-shed was burned on the 18th of July, ult. The laundryj
                                itself had a close call, but was saved by our tank and hydrant system. We have had two
                                field fires since, but neither was very disastrous. There is no clew to our first fire.
                                We have had no fire in the dry-house for three years. As each of the fires came far
                                short of what they might have been quite a pleasant margin is left for thankfulness and
                                for saying as our beloved Brother Peter Boyd used to say, '-'It is well it is no worse."
                                We are watering trees, plants and flowers daily and have been for weeks. Notwithstanding
                                we meet unpropitious circumstances occasionally, we manage to keep a good degree of
                                cheerfulness and good nature through it all. Our harvest is abundant. Hay extra good.
                                Barley and oats good. Wheat averages 23 to 25 bushels to the acre. One field of oats,
                                (16 acres) yielded about seventy bushels per acre. I have seldom indeed read any thing
                                more edifying or spiritually uplifting than the Editorial in the August No. entitled
                                "Purity and Unity." May the Manifesto, which is replete with good things, long
                                wave"Clear as the sun, fair as the moon and terrible as an army with banners." 0. C.
                                Hampton.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Elopement" TEIform="index"/>AN ELOPEMENT.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Tuttle, Emma Rood" TEIform="persName"/>By Emma Rood Tuttle.</byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Two little bugs in a basket Lived very cosy and snug. With a mass of wool beneath
                                    them, And o'er them a pretty rug. Until one day in the winter, When the world seemed
                                    frozen up, A bug of the world came buzzing by, And stopped to dine and sup. When lo!
                                    these bugs in the basket Began to quarrel and fight, And the bug of the world kept
                                    piping up, "The little bug is right!" And the big bug said, "You may buzz and chime
                                    And coax my bug, if you will, But the wool, and the rug, and the basket This bug
                                    will stick to still!" The bug of the world walked to and fro Over the soft white
                                    wool, And said that he knew that the little bug Would not be the big bug's fool! As
                                    long as the big bug crowded him And stole his food away, He guessed the big bug had
                                    best move out And he and the little bug stay. But the big bug could not see the
                                    point And said in a saucy way, The bug of the world and the little bug Could never
                                    drive him-away! So the bug of the world, he flew away, And the little bug flew off,
                                    too, But the big bug lives in the basket yet, And now my story's through.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Delightful menu" TEIform="index"/>A Delightful Menu.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Guest.What have you got? Waiter.I've got liver, calves' brains, pigs' feet, and
                                    Guest.Hold up there! I don't want a description of your physical peculiarities. What
                                    have you got to eat is what I want to know.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Globe" TEIform="index"/>Globe.</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="218" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True greatness" TEIform="index"/>TRUE GREATNESS,</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Rullhausen, Belle" TEIform="persName"/>By Belle Rullhausen.</byline><p TEIform="p">"He that rulvth his own spirit, is greater than he that taketh a city." The annals of time
                            bear many records of those who have fought victorious battles, who have slain their
                            brother-man, and have conquered nations without mercy, but few in comparison are the truly
                            great and virtuous acts of self-sacrifice and heroism which have have been universally
                            acknowledged. Society has too long honored the power of the sword rather than puiity of
                            heart and integrity of purpose. He who has not moral courage enough to defend the right and
                            battle with inward foes, is in truth a coward; though he win the plaudits of men. How very
                            pathetic, yet inspiring are the many accounts of the great philosopher Socrates, who
                            willingly met death, rather than yield his convictions. With what calm resignation did he
                            endure false accusations, and when comdemned to die, his chief accuser sent a private
                            message wherein was stated, that if he would desist censuring his conduct, he should be
                            delivered from death; but from deep religious motives, Socrates spurned such a degrading
                            act, and replied, "While I live I will never disguise the truth, nor speak otherwise than as
                            duty requires." Only the divine, the God-like spirit could have prompted this noble
                            utterance. Greatness depends not upon external power and affluence, but upon the conquest
                            gained over the lower elements of our being. When virtue stands forth preeminent in the
                            life, and all the energies of the body, mind and soul are devoted to the elevation of
                            humanity, then do we find our God and then do realize our heaven. When we have attained full
                            victory over self, then shall we realize the dignity of that true greatness with which all
                            that is denominated as such by the worldlyminded, will seem as fleeting shadows. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mouse's promise" TEIform="index"/>THE MOUSE'S PROMISE.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A mouse fell into a beer vat, poor thing, and a cat passing by saw the struggling
                                    little creature. The mouse said to the cat: "Help me out of my difficulty." "If I
                                    do, I shall eat you," said the cat. "Very well," replied the mouse; "I would rather
                                    be eaten by a decent cat than drowned in such a horrible mess of stuff as this." It
                                    was a sensible cat and said, "I certainly shall eat you, and you must promise me on
                                    your word of honor that I may do so." "Very well, I will give \ou the promise." So
                                    the cat fished the mouse out, and trusting to the promise she dropped it for an
                                    instant. The mouse darted away and crept into a hole in the corner, where the cat
                                    could not get him. "But didn't you promise me I might eat you?" said puss. "Yes, I
                                    did," replied the mouse, "but didn't you know that when I made that promise I was in
                                    liquor?^ And how many promises made in liquor have been broken!</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Acrostic" TEIform="index"/>ACROSTIC.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Belden, Lizzie" TEIform="persName"/>By Lizzie Belden.</byline><p TEIform="p">A soft answer turneth away wrath. Prov. 15., 1. So shalt thou find favor in the sight of God
                            and man. Prov. 3., 4. Open rebuke is better than secret love. Prov. 27., 5. Fear the Lord
                            and depart from evil. Prov. 3., 7. The words of the pure are pleasant words. Prov. 15., 26.
                            A word spoken in due season, how good is it! Prov. 15., 23. Now therefore hearken unto me O
                            ye children. Prov. 8., 32. <pb n="219" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> TEE MANIFESTO. 219 Say not thou I will
                            recompense evil. Prov. 20,, 22. Wait on the Lord and he shall save thee. Prov. 20., 22.
                            Every purpose is established by counsel. Prov. 20., 18. Righteousness keepeth him that is
                            upright in the way. Prov. 13., 6. The heart of the wise teacheth his mouth. Prov. 16., 23.
                            Understanding is a well-spring of life. Prov. 16., 22. Righteousness exalteth a nation.
                            Prov. 14., 34. Nevertheless the counsel of the Lord it shall stand. Prov. 19., 21. Even a
                            child is known by his doings. Prov. 20., 21. The tongue of the wise nseth knowledge aright.
                            Prov. 15., 2. He that is slow to anger is better than the mighty. Prov. 16., 32. And he that
                            ruleth his spirit, than he that taketh a city. Prov. 16., 32. When thou goest thy steps
                            shall not be straightened. Prov. 4., 12. A man of understanding walketh uprightly. Prov.
                            15., 21. Yea, my reins shall rejoice, when thy lips speak right things. Prov. 23., 16. Whoso
                            keepeth his tongue, keepeth his soul from trouble. Prov. 21., 23. Reproofs of instruction
                            are the way of life. Prov. 6., 23. A good name is rather to be chosen than great riches.
                            Prov. 22., 1. The Lord is far from the wicked. Prov. 15., 29. He heareth the prayer of the
                            righteous. Prov. 15., 29. West Pittsjield, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pluck and prayer" TEIform="index"/>PLUCK AND PRAYER.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pollard, Josephine" TEIform="persName"/>By Josephine Pollard.</byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Thebe wan't any use o' fretting, And I told Obadiah so, For ef we couldn't hold
                                    on to things, We'd jest got to let 'em go. There were lots of folks that'd suffer
                                    Along with the rest of us, An' it didn't seem to be wuth our while To make such a
                                    dreffle fuss. To be sure, the barn was 'most empty, An' corn an' pertaters scarce,
                                    An' not much of anything plenty an' cheap But wateran' apple-sass. But then,as I
                                    told Obadiah It wan't any use to groan, For flesh and blood couldn't stan' it; and
                                    He was notliin' but skin an' bone. But, laws! ef you'd only heerd him, At any hour
                                    of the night, A prayin' out in that closet there, 'Twould have set you crazy quite.
                                    I patched the knees of those trousers With cloth that was noways thin, But it seemed
                                    as if the pieces wore out As fast as I set 'em in. To me he said mighty little Of
                                    the thorny way we trod, But at least a dozen times a day He talked it over with God.
                                    Down on his knees in that closet The most of his time was passed; For Obadiah knew
                                    how to pray Much better than how to fast. But I am that way contrary Than ef tilings
                                    don't go jest right, I feel like rollin' my sleeves up high An' gettin' ready to
                                    fight. An' the giants I slew that winter I a'n't going to talk about; An' I didn't
                                    even complain to God, Though I think that He found it out. With the point of a
                                    cambric needle I druv the wolf from the door, For I knew that we needn't starve to
                                    death Or be lazy because we were poor, An' Obadiah he wondered, An' kept me patchin'
                                    his knees, [out, An' thought it strange how the meal held An' stranger we didn't
                                    freeze. But I said to myself in whispers "God knows where his gifts descends; An'
                                    'tisn't always that faith gets down As far as the finger ends." An' I would not have
                                    no one reckon My Obadiah a shirk; For some, you know, have the gift to pray And
                                    others the gift to work.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="220" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological Journal and Science of Health" TEIform="index"/>
                                The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health for August is exceptionally strong and
                                bright. Mary Shaw, the well-known actress, is [ the subject of the frontispiece and an
                                artistic phrenograph by Dr. Btall. John W. Shull gives a masterly analysis of Ideality,
                                with four handsome portraits showing great contrasts of development. Prof. Sizer
                                continues his series, How to Study Strangers, with character delineations of Prof.
                                Charles E. West and Hon. Edwards Pierrepont. Mks. Charlotte Fowler Wells reviews the
                                life and character of Prof. Benj. Silliman. An article entitled Ethics for Lovers, by
                                Grace Pierson, is a brilliant and vigorous arraignment of Mr. Bok, the editor of The
                                Ladies' Home Journal, for some of his views on courting. The contributions on hygiene by
                                Dr. Dray, ton and. others are especially interesting. The other departments present more
                                than the usual variety. Dr. Beall's editorials cover half a dozen pages of breezy
                                replies to contemporaneous critics, also an illustrated physiognomical study of the eyes
                                of Col. Breckenridge as compared with those of Annie Bessant. This will attract especial
                                attention among young bachelors aud maidens. Price, 15 cents, $1. 50 a year. Address the
                                Fowler &amp; Wells Co., 25 East 21st St., New York. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Journal of Hygeio-Therapy" TEIform="index"/>The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy.
                                Aug. Contents. Four marked Characters; Foundation Principles; The Treatment of Forces;
                                The Science of Phrenology; Vaccination and Sanitation; The School that is to be; Notes
                                of the Home; The Pride of the Company; The Great Physician. Dr. T. V. Gifford, &amp;
                                Co., Kokomo, Ind. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mistakes of moses" TEIform="index"/>The Mistakes of Moses
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Mistakes of Moses ! by H. L. Hastings, Boston, Mass. This little
                                Book is an answer to that class who have written against the wonderful work that was
                                accomplished by Moses in liberating the children of Israel. It is now a revised and
                                enlarged edition and has reached no less than "three hundred thousand." Such an extended
                                circulation is positive evidence that the book has been appreciated by interested
                                readers and certainly it can not fail to afford a fund of information, and at the same
                                time interest every one who appreciates the study of biblical history. Published by H.
                                L. Hastings, 47 Cornhill, Boston, Mass. Edward Bok says that of 5000 poems which come
                                into his editorial office during a year, not fifty, if printed, would be read with any
                                degree of patience by the public.Ladies' Home Journal.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="shaker-press" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In 'The Altruist' for July..." TEIform="index"/>In 'The Altruist' for July...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">In "The Altruist" for July is a letter purporting to come from a Shaker correspondent who
                            writes;"I have been in this place for some time and have learned that it is not the place
                            for me. They are too narrow in their religious belief and they think it a great sin to marry
                            or have a wife, but I do not." We hope Br. Loiigley will write at once and have this fellow,
                            who is in distress for a wife, "hurry up" and reach the community at Mo. as soon as he can.
                            He certainly is too narrow for the Shakers and too ignorant to understand their religious
                            belief. The Shakers say no such thing, that it is a great sin to marry. Sin is a
                            transgression of the law, and the law almost enforced the men and women to marry. This man
                            who is ashamed to write his present address is evidently in the wrong place and is looking
                            for an easy job.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., H. C." TEIform="persName"/>H. C. B.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="That a woman can answer back..." TEIform="index"/>That a woman can answer back...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">That a woman can answer back effectively was shown recently at the ordination of
                                    Mrs. Amelia A. Frost, of Littleton, Mass. One of the council asked, "Does the Bible
                                    point to womens' preaching?" "Apparently so, in my case," was the reply. "But," said
                                    the questioner, "I had hoped you would answer by some quotation from the Bible."
                                    Instantly Mrs. Frost replied, "Your sons and your daughters shall prophesy." This
                                    answer was greeted with tremendous applause, and the examination was ended.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our lives should be, like the day..." TEIform="index"/>Our lives should be, like the day...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Our lives should be, like the day, mere beautiful in the evening; or like the spring aglow
                            with promise, and like the autumn, rich with golden sheaves, where good works and deeds have
                            ripened in the field.</p></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p27"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
MOTHER ANN LEE.
A brief account  of
HER LIFE
While   in   England,   and   subsequently
in the
UNITED   STATES!
also  her Exuerience as   a   Mt stunger
of the
WORD of  GOD.
P.ice 10 ds
A SUMMARY VIEW
OF  THE
 CHURCH,
OR
"United   Society    of    Believers"
It treats of the Rise and Progress of the
Society, together loith the general Principles of the Faith and Testimony.
Price iiO cts.
SHAKER'S   ANSWER
To THE OFT REPEATED QUESTION,
"What   will   become   of   the
World, if all become Shakers?"
Price, 10 cts.
THE
TESTIMONY
OF
CHRIST'S  SECOND  APPEASING.
 hy the Principles and Practices of the I ue CIIU1WII of CHRIST
A History of the progres.vive work of God,
extending from the Creation o'' man to
the "HARVEST,"1 cuiiiprixitm the Four
Dispensations note consummating in t.'/e
MILLENNIA L CHURCH.
Price,  *]..*)<>
A   THOUSAND   TUNES
can be played on the Symplioni< n nnr1 t'-e
Polyphon by merely insert in  t^e ] roper
disc. A concert given your friends in your
own home, the programme changes each
evening".
No Y~ars of rpactico. No raise Not~s.
Ho Exertion.
Only listen and y-n In ar any entrfneing'
waltz, beautiful symphony or fi.ntial nwrrii,
played in the sweetest tone with perfect
time.
Our large display of MUSICAL
NOVELTIES is well worth your pe. sonal inspection.
Illustrated Catalogue Free.
SANDER    MUSICAL    INSTRUMENT    CO.,
212 BOYLSTON STREET, BOSTON, MASS.
A
Exemplified
MILLENNIAL
K.
<pb n="" id="p28"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure.
A cream of  tartar   baking   powder.
Highest of  all in   leavening strength.
Latest   United   States    Government
Focd Report.
Royal Baxixg Powder Co.,
106  Wall St.,  N.  Y.
cMATSJRADE Marks
COPYRIGHTS.
CAN I OBTAIN A PATENT? Fora
prompt answer and an honest opinion, write to
MlINN cte CO., who have had nearly fifty years'
experience in the patent business. Communications strictly confidential. A Handbook of Information concerning Patents and how to obtain them sent free. Also a catalogue Of mechanical and scientific books sent tree.
Patents taken through Munn & Co. receire
special notice in the Scientific American, and
thus are brought widely before the public without cost to the inventor. This splendid paper,
issued weekly, elegantly illustrated, has by far the
largest circulation of any scientific work in the
world.   S3 a year.   Sample copies sent free.
Building Edition, monthly, $2.50 a year. Single
copies, 25 cents. Every number contains beautiful plates, in colors, and photographs of new
houses, with plans, enabling builders to show the
latest designs and secure contracts.   Address
MUNN & CO., New York, 361 BroadwatHOW I CAME
TO  BE
Price 5 cts.
Much knowledge for a few pennies.
Sent Postage paid to any address in the
U. S. We have on hand a few copies of
"Rip Van Winkle and other Sketches."
240 pages, 4x6.                          10 cts.
"A treatise on The Horse," by Dr. B.
Kendall. 90 pages. 5x7). Profusely illustrated.                                  12 cts.
An old, brass eight day clock, in long
case, in excellent order.           $65.00
An eight day brass time piece made in
1810   by Dr.   Thomas Corbett.    $20.00
Second vol. of Cassandra written originally in French by Sir, Charles Cotterell.
Published 1725.                                  .25
Sacred Eoll and Book written by Inspiration in 1843.    A wonderful Book.     2.00
Hamlet, Prince of Denmark.
From Shakespeare.
.10
Address   H. C. Blinn, E. Canterbury, N. H.
(Established 1861.)
IS Oldest, Largest, Best,
Cheapest and the Only
weekly Bee-Paper in all
America.  32 pag-es. $1.00
a year.   Send for Free Sample.
$1.00 BEE-BOOK FREE
H. W. YORK & CO., 199 Randolph St., Chicago, 111,
BRIEF EXPOSITION
OF   THE
Principles and. Regulations
of the
SOCIETY   OF   BESIxEETVERS.
Price, 10 cts.
THE DIVIHE AFFLATUS,
A
FORCE IN HISTORY.
Price, 10 cts.
A  SHAKER
American Bee Journal,
H
E
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>