<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1204" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">12</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">4</biblScope><date value="18820401" TEIform="date">April 1882</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">73- 96</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="12" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="4" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--                     <pb id="p1"/>
                    <p>VOL. XII. APRIL. NO. 4 MANIFESTO PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES. ,N. H. "Blessed are they that hear the word of
                        God and keep it.n Shaker Village, N. H 1882. </p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                        <pb id="p3"/>
                        <pb id="p4"/>
                    </div2>
--><pb n="73" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pursuit of life" TEIform="index"/>PURSUIT OF LIFE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>GILES B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p"> This should be to search after, find, and apply, practically, to the habits and conditions
                            of life, those levers that shall elevate the human character to the dignity designed by God.
                            Knowledge, talent, genius, position, these alone, cannot do it! But, a patriotic spirit,
                            desirous to be like the sunbeam, growing brighter from its early morning rise, and shining
                            to bless all mankind. A sacrifice of those belittling, debasing, selfish loves and pleasures
                            that degrade man to a brutish level; those selfish graspings for earthly gains, harvested,
                            often times, at the impoverishing and sufferings of the neighbor, those piles of sordid
                            wealth that bury the soul in things that perish in the using. This patriotism, these
                            sacrifices ; th&amp; seeking of that Wisdom that cometh from above, and the consecration
                            of one's life to live as God lives, and labor as God labors, to bless the whole race of man,
                            and help to elevate him to his proper niche in God's temple. This is living worthy of
                            existence. All else is sham ; life buried in death while threading the pathway of time. The
                            pursuit of knowledge, may be good, it ought to be ; but, knowledge merely, is an
                            acquaintance with facts, or a perception and comprehension of principles and powers. It may
                            be piled up in heterogeneous masses in the mind like miscellaneous books in a library; or
                            better, it may be systematically treasured in the memory, but, without wisdom, it simply
                            plays around the head, or like the babbling streamlet, tumbles over the obstructions in its
                            pathway, noisily and uselessly, dashing along to the ocean of forge tfulness. Wisdom peers
                            its way into causes and consequences, adapting its powers to the accomplishment of necessary
                            and blissful ends, feeling out, with its electric like fingers, the long lines of
                            intelligence, and charging their connecting wires so speedily as to be ready to meet any
                            exigency of occasion, or dignity of impor- <pb n="74" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 74 SHAKER MANIFESTO. tance
                            of condition; banishing animal dullness and stupidity of perception and comprehension, and
                            appropriately adjusting itself to all needs and purposes. Wisdom teaches, first, the
                            necessity of running in the journey of life. Secondly, the prizes for which to run. The true
                            benefactors of our race have been a class of earnest, honest, toiling and self-sacrificing
                            souls, in all the history of earth's unnumbered ages ! The devotees to the pursuits of
                            selfish gains and pleasures, at the expense of a neighbor's, a brother's or sister's need or
                            comfort, have never, in all their races of life, yet reached the goal of bliss. It has ever,
                            like the cup of Tantalus, been distant from their lips, and though, like Numidia's horsemen,
                            it has been swiftest in the race for earthly gains, like them, too, it has been faithless
                            and unscrupulous relative to the rights of fellow man; hence, its spoils have not been the
                            dispensers of happiness, but the treasuries of envy, hatred, and remorse. But, shall gold,
                            silver, jewels, piles of earthly pelf, or palaces and monuments of earthly glory engulf the
                            soul of humanity and harness man down to earth forever ? Shall saint like professions of
                            godliness, hollow as the apples on the lake of Sodom, though painted with their inviting
                            mellow orange hues, deceive the soul forever? Shall religion, like a clerical cloak, be only
                            worn on the exterior of human life, and be as destitute of life as the shorn wool the cloak
                            is made of ? Must still unnumbered ages roll and their history record the race of man
                            plodding only in the mire and dross of earth. Shall soul resurrection lie couchant as a
                            slain lion and man essay to find its bliss by the display of an empty skinny form? O let
                            earth roll up her musty scroll of self, of pelf, of sinful pleasure, and burn it in the fire
                            of God's truth and Love. Let man burst his snail shell of sensuality and animalism, and,
                            like an uncaged bird, fly to the freedom and redemption spread forth on the plains of God's
                            great salvation, perch on the trees of life that grow on either side of that river of love
                            that makes glad the city of God, and daily feed on their twelve manner of fruits. Thus
                            living make earth an Eden, and Heaven a sure inheritance by bringing it to earth ! Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y..</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lines for Brother Ezra Sherman" TEIform="index"/>LINES FOR BROTHER EZRA SHERMAN</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="McGuire, R. S." TEIform="persName"/>R. S. MCGUIRE</byline><p TEIform="p"> Our kind loving father Has gone to his rest, Wisely finished his labors below; Having
                            wrought in that righteousness Angels can bltss And Heaven approval bestow. Thus passed our
                            good brother, True, faithful and just, Like a sheaf of ripe grain, gathered home Where
                            treasures lay garnered, Untarnished by rust, The fruit of life's duties well done. How happy
                            the song Of the justified soul, When called earthly cares to lay down : "I have fought the
                            good fight, Over sin found control, Which gives me my kingdom and crown." And tho' the thin
                            veil Which now drops between, May hide our dear friend for a time, In spirit we mingle,
                            And^dimly discern His home in that beautiful clime. White Water, Ohio.</p></div2><pb n="75" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Job bishop" TEIform="index"/>JOB BISHOP</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>HENRY C. BLINN</byline><p TEIform="p">BY (Continued from last number.) So very peculiar was the impression that rested upon those
                            present that a solemn stillness prevailed for several minutes. Father Job afterwards
                            conversed freely and encouraged all to keep their union and to build upon the foundation of
                            truth. "The time will come," said he, "when 'one Avill chase a thousand and two will put ten
                            thousand to flight.' Not by words of steel, 'not by might, nor by power, but by my spirit,
                            saith the Lord.' Those who bear the cross of Christ, who come forth with a testimony that
                            the world cannot gainsay, will be the victorious children of God." Father Job Bishop was
                            among the itinerant ministers who visited New Hampshire several times between the years 1782
                            and 1792. It had been anticipated that Elder Henry Clough would be commissioned to organize
                            these churches, but in 1788 he was called to the church at New Lebanon, as an assistant to
                            Father Joseph Meacham. At this time Father Job was chosen to succeed Elder Henry as a
                            minister over the people of Canterbury and Enfield. In personal appearance Father Job Bishop
                            was erect and well proportioned, being about five feet and ten inches in hight. His hair was
                            dark chestnut and very strait ,his nose of the Roman type and h's eyes a brilliant black.
                            His voice in speaking was keyed higher than is usual for men and yet those who listened to
                            the power and spirit of his exhortations soon learned that he was a living servant of God.
                            He was remarkably gifted and endowed with the prophetic spirit in an eminent degree. In 1795
                            the title of Father was conferred upon him by the Ministry of New Lebanon and from that date
                            he has been known only as a wise, honorable and loving parent. In his ministrations Father
                            Job always spoke in the spirit of loving kindness. He manifested at all times a great degree
                            of patience, and was constant in his exhortations for every one to accept the beautiful
                            cross of Christ. Even the little children shared largely m his parental care and looked upon
                            him with reverence and respect. They sensibly felt through him an inspiration of holiness,
                            to which in more mature years they affectionaly bore witness. Father Job always manifested a
                            deep reverential regard for those who occupied an order before him and conformed implicitly
                            to the rules and regulations that were established by the mother church. He insisted that
                            the trustees should have a care over the articles that were manufactured for sale, and
                            unless free from blemish, they should be retained at home. The apostolic injunction, had to
                            its fullest extent enforced itself upon the first elders of the society. "Owe no man any
                            thing, but to love one another." To be in debt to the children of this world, was indeed
                            reprehensible, and Father Job would not suffer an infringement of the rule, even in the
                            least degree. A case in point was that of a brother who had, in closing a trade, found
                            himself in debt to the value of a few cents. Not having the necessary change he gave his
                            promise to send the balance early on the following Monday. The brother on being reported to
                                <pb n="76" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 76 SHAKER MANIFESTO. Father Job, was admonished to return, a
                            distance of four miles, on Saturday P. M. and cancel the debt. Although Father Job was among
                            the elders first gathered as ministers at New Lebanon, yet it was thought best by Father
                            Joseph, for him to enter the family as a common member that he might find his union and
                            order in the church of God. For several months he devoted himself, faithfully, to the
                            temporal and spiritual interests, but in the spring of 1790 he was again called to officiate
                            in the order of the ministry and in company with several others visited every place where
                            the churches were being gathered into order. In 1791 he visited the people of Canterbury. At
                            this time he was not as successful in his labors of union as he had wished and in
                            consequence was much depressed in spirit. On his return to New Lebanon he immediately
                            informed Father Joseph who very pleasantly remarked. Well, Elder Henry may go with yow, and
                            you may confer with each other in regard to your Christian work. In a few days the two
                            brethren were journeying on horse-back, side by side, on their way to New Hampshire. After
                            traveling several miles, a deep anxiety to ascertain the cause of the failure began to
                            pervade the mind of Father Job. Becoming deeply absorbed in these anxious thoughts, he
                            finally fell far in the rear of his companion. In this revery he received the impression
                            that gave him some new light on the subject and putting spurs to his horse soon overtook
                            Elder Henry and said to him,—Henry, you are my gospel elder ! Elder Henry reined up his
                            horse and replied :—Go, Job, you will have a gilt in your ministration. I will return.
                            Father Job entreated Elder Henry to continue the journey but he answered decidedly. Nay, it
                            will be of no use, you have the gift, and immediately returned to his home in New Lebanon.
                            Father Job now continued the journey alone and visited the Brethren and Sisters at
                            Canterbury and Enfield wTho kindly accepted him as their leader. It was not, however, till
                            the following year that he was permanently established as the Elder of the two Societies in
                            New Hampshire. At this time he was accompanied by Elder Henry Clough, through whose agency,
                            he received the cordial union of the people. Active preparations were then made to establish
                            the order of society, agreeably to the form of the first Church. The following incident
                            relating to President Madison's tour through N. H. in 1817 was found in a work Published in
                            Hartford, Ct. 1819. "Amid the regulated forms and the fashionable style of modern etiquette,
                            the President was received by one of the Shakers at Enfield, N. H. in a style of plain
                            hospitality which comes directly home to "men's business and bosoms." The Elder in all the
                            majesty of conscious integrity approached the President and said, 'I Job Bishop welcome
                            James Monroe to our habitation.' This must have been the language of the heart which can
                            neither be ornamented by the flourishes of rhetoric nor degraded by the sneers of
                            formality." (To BE CONTINUED.)</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is good discretion not to make too much of any man at first, because one cannot hold out that proportion" TEIform="index"/>
                            It is good discretion not to make too much of any man at first, because one cannot hold out that proportion
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bacon" TEIform="persName"/>Bacon</byline><p TEIform="p">It is good discretion not to make too much of any man at first, because one cannot hold out
                            that proportion.—</p></div2><pb n="77" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakerism" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERISM</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Eades, H. L." TEIform="persName"/>H. L. EADES</byline><p TEIform="p"> Being a reply to an Article in the Boston Investigator, by an "Ex-Shaker." Friend Editor:—In
                            replying to ExShaker's Article on the Confessional, which appeared in your paper of the 4th
                            Inst.—I would say, first, that I take the pen more to enlighten the public, than to
                            controvert his mis-statements ; but will notice the more essential before closing. All who
                            believe in, and look to the Scriptures for guidance, well know that there is no Christian
                            precept more clearly and positively enjoined than that of Confession, beginning with Adam
                            and ending with Ananias and Sapphira, who, for their dishonesty, were struck dead to the
                            spirit life of the Church and were, Adam like, ejected "from the- garden," "struck dead" and
                            buried in the world, and Ex-Shaker seems to have shared the same fate. Joshua, in his advice
                            to Achan, gives the most clear instruction on the subject, thus : "Achan my son, give, I
                            pray thee, glory to the Lord God of Israel ai:d make confession unto Him and tell me what
                            thou hast done, hide it not from me." Joshua vii, 19. On and on through the typical law, it
                            was enjoined, up to Jesus who confessed to God in the hearing of John the Baptist ; when the
                            new gospel dispensation commenced, and Jesus himself became the Confessor, and appointed his
                            successors, saying ; "Whosoever sins ye remit they are remitted unto them and whosoever sins
                            ye retain, they are retained. Jno. xx, 23. The Apostle Paul makes it clear, by saying; "Some
                            men's sins are open before hand, going before to judgment, and some they follow after." I.
                            Tim. v, 24. And further, "The saints shall judge the world." i Cor. vi, 2. Whenever a soul
                            is convicted of sin, and is led to the house of God, "where His name is placed for
                            Salvation," his "hour of judgment is come," thence-forward to worship Him that made the
                            heaven and earth and sea," Rev. xiv, 7, instead of doing as infidels, giving their worship
                            to the things that are made, instead of their Maker. ( !) But, I need not quote scripture
                            further ; besides the spiritual and scriptural injunction, there is a reasonable necessity
                            that the Elders should know the weak points of each applicant in order to be able to throw
                            around them the proper safe-guards and succor them. Besides, it is incumbent on the Elders,
                            and a duty they owe to the Church, to know what kind of material is admitted into the body.
                            The writer of this has been a confessor for near half a century, and quite willing to
                            anticipate Ex-Shaker's exposure of the Confessional. There are but two motives which should
                            induce any persons to seek entrance into the Shaker Church, viz: First, to get rid of all
                            the sins of a past life, by letting them go before into judgment, and 2nd, To place
                            themselves in a condition where they can live a better, higher, purer, more useful and a
                            more sinless life than is possible to any one, while remaining in the world. "For, without,
                            (in every part of the world,) are dogs, and sorcerers, whoremongers, murderers, idolaters
                            and adulterers and they that love and make a lie." Rev. xxii, 15. Every city, town and
                            village on the earth's surface, comes directly under this category, except Christ's Church
                            and followers, who are in the resurrec- <pb n="78" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 78 SHAKER MANIFESTO. tion, and
                            neither marry nor are given in marriage. Matt, xxii, 30.—Who, then, would not desire such
                            pure heaven-born company? But many come from selfish consideration, to obtain a living
                            without rendering an equivalent. Such ones usually fight shy of the Confessional, and come
                            forward, not to confess, but to conceal their sins and weaknesses from the light of God's
                            order, and sometimes need enlightening to help them, hoping they may receive a conviction
                            which has not yet reached them. I am led to believe that Ex-Shaker was one of this class. My
                            uniform course with applicants has been to inform them, that the first step to be taken, is
                            the confession of every transaction of life, within one's immediate remembrance, which the
                            confessor knew, or now thinks, was wrong and sinful. The earnest, honest applicant, then
                            begins and goes straight forward and gives a satisfactory account of himself, puts his name
                            to the Novitiate Covenant, and comes into full fellowship with the body of Christ.—So, God,
                            in His Order, and God in the penitent, remits the sins and lifts their burden from the soul.
                            A mountain is removed, and "Saith God, their sins and iniquities will I remember no more."
                            Heb. x, 7. The honest soul then feels a releasement, which it never felt before, and which
                            cannot be obtained in any other way. The burden gone ! and harmony restored between the soul
                            and its Creator ! Some, foolishly choose to put off the mortifying ordeal until they shuffle
                            off the mortal, expecting then to appear before some big imaginary Deity, seated on a large
                            white Throne, perhaps inside the rings of Saturn, or somewhere else among the stars ! But,
                            the scriptures, properly understood, justify no such belief. In this, such souls will find
                            themselves mistaken, for God has His Order, composed of finite agents, in both worlds, to
                            which all must bow, whether angels or men. 1. As to confessing all the acts of a married
                            life I w,ill say :—It is only necessary to confess what the enlightened mind now sees to be
                            wrong. 2. We know nothing about "the recording angel blotting out sins by our
                            intercessions." I have shown how sins are forgiven, by God, in the saint, and God within the
                            sinner. The latter with repentance and honesty, the former with love and charity. But it is
                            all labor lost with one sin willfully covered, God, in the sinner, will not bless and lift
                            the burden from the soul, and God in the saints cannot. 3. The Shakers have no masonic
                            secrets ; they wish to be investigated and probed to the bottom. They have nothing to
                            conceal or cover from the eyes of God or man. The Pearl obtained by their life, is the
                            "Pearl of great price." Its value is only known by the possessor. The more it is exposed the
                            more beautiful it appears ; the more it is rubbed the brighter it shines. 'Tis a pearl that
                            worlds cannot buy. 4. It is sometimes charged that the Shakers require confessing every week
                            ! Just so, if one sins every week, not otherwise ! 5. As to books and papers, no family is
                            without them ; but it would be better to have none, than not to have them well selected. 6.
                            Of furnishing children brought among the Shakers and expect them to <pb n="79" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/>
                            SHAKER MANIFESTO. 79 abstain from generation, would be just as sensible as to give them a
                            spoonful of brandy every day, and expect them not to be drunkards! 7. Shakers are not
                            required to subdue every natural instinct, as ex-shaker testifies. Our desire is to change
                            the carnal for the pure and spiritual! Is this objectionable? 8. Ex-shaker complains that
                            letters are to be read by the Elders. This is a good rule. If members cannot trust their
                            Elders, How can they expect to be trusted ? South Union, Ky.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Day dawn" TEIform="index"/>DAY DAWN</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="De Vere, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/>CECELIA DE VERE</byline><p TEIform="p"> In the still hour of the morning, E're the light began to shine, When the blush-rose of the
                            dawning Fluttered to the silvery line; When the silvery line expanded, Changing to a fan of
                            gold, And the rising mists were stranded As the glory upward rolled. Woke I then from
                            peaceful slumber To review a darkened earth, With its burdens that encumber, With its
                            ignorance and dearth ; Custom, creed and superstition Form a veil of every land,
                            Usurpation's Inquisition Works below to starve and brand; There the countless toiling masses
                            Never see with normal sight, Life, the night-mare, as it passes, Brings them only pain and
                            blight. To support the torturing errors That their hearts are forced to know, War, with all
                            its blackening terrors Fill them with appalling woe. There are noble souls contending With
                            the monsters of the world, Scaling high, and low descending, Wheresoe'er the serpent's
                            curled. But, I said, O vain devotion! What will all the effort do? Will the reeds beside the
                            ocean Change its rolling or its hue? 'Twas a thought of earthly reason Unillumined by the
                            light; 'Twas a doubt, and doubt is treason To the sacred cause of right. Quick reproof my
                            heart was taking, When a vision o'er it came, Faith, that like the day when breaking Flushed
                            it with a holy flame. And I saw, not trembling grasses, But the angel world of thought,
                            Bending down to reach the masses Through the minds that it had taught. They will tear the
                            veil asunder, They will rend it thread by thread, Show the tangled warp of blunder On which
                            scenes of blood are spread. They, commissioned, strong, indignant, That false covering will
                            destroy, And declare the God benignant, Made this irorld for peace and joy. God's estate, in
                            fair division To his children doth belong, Might has cancelled His decision Brutal might
                            that fights for wrong. But an angel might is coming Like the billows of the sea, Hark! the
                            waves are softly humming Snatches of a symphony; When the broken strains are blended, And
                            the music is complete, War and darkness shall be ended. Light and harmony shall meet. When
                            the lands of every nation To the people are secure, Earth shall know a new salvation, And
                            her peace will then be sure. To this end, 0 let us labor! Every one can take a part, Love to
                            God and to our neighbor Forms the bond of every heart. O, a mighty day is breaking! We must
                            hail its light, and grow, Earth and heaven alike are shaking, Only truth can safety know,
                            Light alone the truth will cherish, And expand its latent bloom, But the rankling wrong
                            shall perish, Day-dawn ushers in its doom. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><pb n="80" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Point worthy of consideration" TEIform="index"/>A Point Worthy Of Consideration</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lanebridge, William C." TEIform="persName"/>WILLIAM C. LANEBRIDGE</byline><p TEIform="p"> In reviewing the assassination of President Garfield, and all of the various circumstances
                            pertaining thereto, I perceive many inconsistencies not the least 'oi which I will mention.
                            Guiteau says that it was an act of the Deities, and that he was simply an instrument called
                            to perform that act. Of course all pious people express horror at such "shocking blasphemy."
                            Yet President Arthur in his Thanksgiving Proclamation, and again in his message to Congress,
                            says, "Whereas in His inscrutable wisdom it has pleased God to remove our beloved Chief
                            Magistrate, the late James A. Garfield," or words to that effect. Nearly every Governor and
                            clergyman in the United States has used similar phraseology, and I might add every pious
                            layman. Now I readily give President Arthur and every other one who has thus expressed
                            himself the credit of having good motives. But when a grave public document is issued by the
                            President of the United States, it should at least be in accordance with known facts, which
                            President Arthur's declaration was not, as by it he reaffirms what Guiteau so stoutly
                            asserts, viz: "That it was the will of God that President Garfield should die as he did,"
                            and by this assertion he practically admits that Guiteau was but an agent in the hands of
                            Providence, and is therefore an innocent man. The President was doubtless prompted by the
                            best of motives and by a tender regard for the memory of his illustrious predecessor, but
                            allowed himself to be betrayed into the usual conventional form of expression. Nothing can
                            be worse blasphemy to my mind than the present fashion of charging God with fathering every
                            crime committed. And I believe the time is not far distant when the majority of thinking,
                            intelligent people will regard with unqualified disapprobation and contempt this irrational
                            method of accounting for the sins and transgressions of mankind, and instead rest the blame
                            where it belongs—upon society. To say the part Guiteau took in the tragedy was the result of
                            "devilish depravity," and then in the next breath assert that it was the will of God, is a
                            species of reasoning the "national mind" fails to comprehend ; and which appears to me like
                            what logicians would term reasoning in a "vicious circle." This "inspiration" business is
                            becoming far too dangerously common, and Guiteau should be made such an example of as shall
                            cause other would-be murderers to pause before committing an act that must surely end in
                            ruin to themselves. They should be made to understand that the plea of Divine revelation
                            will not shield them from the penalties of the law. It is not even necessary to deny these
                            pretended revelations. Thus it may be said to Guiteau: "Possibly God did command you to
                            shoot the President; but in doing so he must certainly have intended you to be hanged, as
                            hanging is the punishment inflicted for murder." Personally I do not favor hanging Guiteau,
                            but if by so doing it shall teach a salutary lesson to others of his kind, the sacrifice
                            will not have been in vain. The best way to put an and to this pretense of Divine revelation
                            is for all sensible persons to take the view Mrs. Garfield does, when she says that she
                            fails to discover any Providence in <pb n="81" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 81 an act that
                            at once deprives her of a husband, the staff of her life, and her children of a father. Mi.
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Teach me to trust" TEIform="index"/>TEACH ME TO TRUST</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stephens, Annie" TEIform="persName"/>ANNIE STEPHENS</byline><p TEIform="p"> Time's golden sands are flowing One by one, Our life its course below Will soon have run.
                            Then whither wilt thou" go O soul divine? Where are the realms of day In which thou'lt
                            shine? What subtle power controls Thy destiny? Why wrap thy future life In mystery? Enough
                            to know is given, A voice replies, Prepare thy soul for heaven The spirit cries! Then
                            trusting, I will wait, And hopeful be, For I know the angel's love Rests over me. And though
                            my path may lead Up mountains steep, The hand that guards all life, Will guide my feet. And
                            I shall learn through faith, That hand is just; O blessed light of heaven, Teach me to
                            trust! Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We must beware of admitting into our souls the belief that..." TEIform="index"/>
                            We must beware of admitting into our souls the belief that...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Socrates" TEIform="persName"/>Socrates</byline><p TEIform="p">We must beware of admitting into our souls the belief that there is no soundness at all in
                            arguments. Let us rather believe that it is we ourselves who are not sound; but let us act
                            like men, and bestir ourselves that we may become so.—</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fragmentary thoughts" TEIform="index"/>FRAGMENTARY THOUGHTS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName"/>ABRAHAM PERKINS</byline><p TEIform="p"> Much is said and written in regard to the present moral condition of man compared with the
                            past. The verdict is largely, that conditions of society, as a whole, are improving and the
                            world is growing better. In a certain sense, as I perceive and realize it, this judgment is
                            true ; in another sense, it is not true. Taking the view that there never was an age when
                            man was more enlightened, when greater knowledge of truth never before existed and when
                            truth was never more cheerfully acknowledged and accepted as truth, the judgment is correct.
                            But in the sense that today man is truer to conviction than in any preceding age, it is
                            false. Although divine truths are in a good degree understood and accepted as the higher
                            revelations of God, yet there exists a species of belief that man may be justified in a life
                            less perfect than what he knows to be most perfect; that :t is not expected he will accept
                            fully the teachings of our Lord as his guide and example. In fact, that he deems the cross
                            too heavy to carry, that human nature demands ease and relaxation, that man is mortal and
                            should not presume on making the Savior strictly his example : therefore he yields to the
                            impulses of a depraved, selfish heart and is condoned on the ground that all men assume this
                            position and he is as good as his neighbor. We would ask, why then did our Master
                            say,—'"Follow me?" Did he require more than man is able to perform? And because of his
                            ^.weakness <pb n="82" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 82 SHAKER MANIFESTO. and short comings which he cannot
                            prevent, is he to be deprived of an heirship with Christ, a relation to his body and a place
                            in his kingdom, which admits of nothing that worketh iniquity, that defileth or maketh a lie
                            ? Again the injunction was,—"Be ye perfect, even as your Father who is in heaven is
                            perfect." What can we learn from this? As I understand the words, we are to become perfect
                            children in Christ; perfectly obedient to his instruction, truly subject to the dictates of
                            conscience, living watchfully, prayerfully and carefully in the spirit and life of Christ. I
                            acknowledge that manifold are the truths abounding today. They are ours to enjoy ; a blessed
                            gift from the Father and Mother of mercies. And however much "the earth is filled with the
                            knowledge of the Lord, even as the waters cover the sea," yet sin abounds in equal ratio. It
                            has probably never been known in the earth, when the catalogue of crimes, murders, suicides,
                            robberies, incendiarism and evils of every name was greater than today. The servants of
                            Satan are legions, all busy in his service, opposing every movement of reform, obstructing
                            every avenue of light and sowing tares which are yielding a harvest that is manifestly
                            impeding and checking progress and darkening many a soul; thus robbing the earth of the
                            genuine fruits of peace and leaving man to groan under suffering and pain, with little
                            prospect or encouragement of deliverance. I have favorable auguries, by which my confidence
                            is strengthened of a ' 'good time coming ;" and from the effects of the operation of an
                            apparent inner work of the spirit, we have the best of evidence that a brighter day is
                            dawning. "As fast as people learn to think, they demand liberty," and greater light is
                            sought and resources resorted to to obtain it; which, in the providence of God, in His own
                            time, is dispensed, giving liberty in a corresponding degree with the acceptation of light.
                            It comes not without sacrifice ; and the greater the sacrifice required and conscientiously
                            made, the greater the progress, purification and freedom of the soul. Yea, and the more
                            careful will be the obedience rendered to the principles of truth, the freer the
                            relinquishment of self to the consuming fire of the gospel, which cleanses the soul from all
                            impurities of the flesh, and of a depraved animal nature, bringing it into that baptism and
                            resurrection of the spirit which constitutes man the true image of God and makes him an
                            angel. Enfield, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Second eve" TEIform="index"/>THE SECOND EVE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webster, Ruth" TEIform="persName"/>RUTH WEBSTER</byline><p TEIform="p"> According to the allegorical account, men and women were created having equal rights ; but
                            in consequence of the woman taking the lead in the transgressing the law given them, she was
                            told that her "desire should be to her husband and he should rule over her," thus making her
                            condition little superior to that of a slave, and in fact, when united to an immoral man,
                            she has experienced the worst kind of slavery. But in all this she was not left without
                            hope, for the promise was given that the seed of the woman should bruise the serpents' head
                            ; thus give a death blow to that <pb n="83" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 83 propensity which
                            was the cause of all our woe. Finally, the Messiah was promised, and the people who kept the
                            knowledge of God, looked to that event as one that was to benefit them as a nation ; for
                            they expected Him to come as a temporal prince, notwithstanding, the promise had been given
                            that in Him all nations should be blest. In process of time Jesus came, and it was said of
                            Him, that he should "save his people from their sins." He was called the "second Adam." Now,
                            if there was a second Adam, should there not be a second Eve ? Jesus was called the "son of
                            man ;"—after the spirit descended upon him he was called "Christ," the "son of God." He was
                            said to be "God manifest in the flesh." As he said ; "the words that I speak unto you, they
                            are spirit and they are life ; the flesh profiteth nothing." God is also known by his works,
                            "evenhis eternalpowerand Godhead." All things that are made are male and female, hence, the
                            same principle exists in Deity. If the second Adam was the representative of the Eternal
                            Father, there should be a second Eve to represent the Eternal Mother. As Christ became the
                            author of eternal salvation in his first appearing, to all those that obeyed him, so was he
                            in his second advent "the author and finisher'' of eternal life to all who were obedient to
                            his testimony. In Christ's first appearing, woman was not redeemed from the curse, but was
                            required to be silent in the church and to obey her husband. The reason given, she was first
                            in the transgression. In Christ's first appearing there were some indulgences permitted,
                            short of bearing a full cross ; but it was said that his second coming should be "without
                            sin unto salvation." Purity of life, purity of heart and an entire consecration to God is
                            the aim of every true Christian believer. Indeed, "holiness to the Lord" is our motto, and
                            all that will not bear this inscription should be rejected. There was seen in vision an
                            angel flying in the midst of heaven having the everlasting gospel to preach, saying ; "Fear
                            God and work righteousness, for the hour of his judgment has come." There are many earnest
                            men and women who are zealously engaged in the different reforms, and as God works by human
                            agency, as well as spirit influences, much good will be the result. When the cry is
                            heard,—"Babylon is fallen ;" and the call is heeded, "Come out of her my people that ye be
                            not partakers of her plagues," many will gather to the spiritual order to live the Christ
                            principle of regeneration. Those who are not ready to be harvested from the earth will
                            observe times and seasons and beget their offspring according to law. These will constitute
                            the natural order or new earth. When their children shall be called into the spiritual
                            order, they will not be like those who are begotten in drunkenness and lust, so that it will
                            take ages to redeem them. We have been under the curse, and have been a partaker of its
                            sorrows, but thanks to God for the revelation of this cleansing work. I am now a free woman
                            ! O that mankind were as ready to follow the second Eve out of sin, as they have been to
                            follow the first into sin. Union Village, Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="All habits grow by unseen degrees" TEIform="index"/>All habits grow by unseen degrees
                        </head><p TEIform="p">All habits grow by unseen degrees.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dryden" TEIform="persName"/> Dryden</byline></div2><pb n="84" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Memorial letter" TEIform="index"/>MEMORIAL LETTER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>Henry C. Blinn</byline><p TEIform="p">Enfield, N. H. Jan., 1882. My Beloved Young Friends ;—As the time approaches for the Brethren
                            and Sisters to attend the funeral and bid a long and loving farewell to H., a life member of
                            our order, I find that my spirit goes out to be with you in your affliction. For many years
                            I have taken part with you in bidding adieu to those honored souls who have lived out the
                            full measure of their days in this life, and who have gone to reap the reward of 'well done,
                            good and faithful servant.'' Beautiful Brethren and Sisters who have so nobly fought the
                            good fight of faith, and earned for themselves a crown of immortal glory. I have, also, with
                            you seen those who were taken from ,us in the morning of life. Children, of tender years,
                            whose lives so prematurely cut off, must if they ever become heirs of the Kingdom of heaven,
                            earn it by a faithful adherence to the principles of godliness in the land of souls. And
                            there have been youthful minds from whom we have so regretted to part. Those who were
                            active, intelligent, interested, and so far as time and gospel privileges afforded, had
                            earned for themselves a home in the hearts of their beloved fathers and mothers in Christ.
                            Among this latter class we find our loved and loving sister H. A child of the church,—and
                            how much more consoling it is to be able to commit her to the care of the good angels, with
                            a recommendation of which we need not be ashamed, than to record that which so often carries
                            sorrow through this life, and must follow even beyond time. Although the youngest have no
                            more assurance of continued health than those more advanced in years, yet this summons has
                            been, to me, very sudden, and indeed, very reluctantly accepted. So recently one among the
                            most active, bidding so fair to pass on from year to year as a comfort and blessing to the
                            guardians of her yoxith, that we had not matured any thought in our mind for this hasty
                            transition. We had fondly anticipated a recovery to health, and that on our return to you,
                            she would have been advanced many degrees in strength and in the hope of a long and useful
                            life. But we were destined to be suddenly and sadly disappointed. Beloved young Friends ;
                            while we are bidding farewell to one of your class, you must bear in mind that her departure
                            takes from your ranks another of your loved companions, and leaves upon those who remain, a
                            greater responsibility to be honest and steadfast believers. Although lost to our natural
                            sight, H. has by no means left us. By appointment she has only moved into another sphere of
                            action. Reserve for her a place in your memories, that shall award to her an honorable
                            position in your class for all time to come. I trust that she may still be with you in every
                            good work, growing more and more faithful unto the perfect day. I trust also that you will
                            all add to your present faithfulness and be able to leave I clean record of your journey
                            through this life. As it is a Divine decree that all who are born into this world must
                            inevitably, at some subsequent period, again pass out from among us, into the better (?)
                            world, it becomes us as rational beings to accept the ultimate with all due consideration.
                            84 <pb n="85" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 85 In this age of inherited physical sins, of
                            deformities of mind and body, so fearfully transmitted from generation to generation, as
                            well as a legion of morbid appetites, we can only hope and pray for an inspiration of God to
                            enable us to so walk that life may be a blessing, and an honorable old age our deserved
                            inheritance in this world. No one should defer till tomorrow that which may be performed
                            today. To hesitate may often be the first fatal step to ruin. Every age urges its demand.
                            The honesty and truthfulness and chastity of a child foreshadows a virtuous youth, and this
                            cannot fail to develope into an honorable and spiritual manhood or womanhood. It should be
                            thoroughly impressed upon the mind of every young person that no transgression, however
                            trivial, can possibly fade away. A penalty is as sure to follow, as we are to exist. We are
                            creatures of law, andl,God's laws are imperative. Hence the very great and persistent care
                            that should be exercised over children that not only an actual wrong may be prevented but
                            also that the predisposition to wrong may be anticipated and doubly guarded. All this is an
                            Angel's work, and consequently it is a preparatory work for the Kingdom of God. We are all
                            engaged in it, but it sometimes seems so necessary, and especially for those who are yet on
                            the ascending grade of life's journey, that we cannot forbear adding a kind word of
                            monition. We would have the whole world good, and then we should be so happy. Farewell,</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="He who does a base thing in zeal for his friend burns the golden thread that ties their hearts together" TEIform="index"/>
                            He who does a base thing in zeal for his friend burns the golden thread that ties their hearts together
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> He who does a base thing in zeal for his friend burns the golden thread that ties their
                            hearts together.</p></div2><div2 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kellogg, H. S." TEIform="index"/>H. S. KELLOGG</head><p TEIform="p">An ancient maxim says, "Speak nothing but good of the dead;" but it surely would be more
                            consistent for the true Christian to speak nothing but truth of any, whether in the body or
                            out. Those with hopes and aspirations centered on this life, whose thoughts are engrossed by
                            the narrow affections of earthly relationships, or perhaps lost in the elements of the
                            world, will find nothing but terror in the thought of death. But they, who, by the love of
                            God, the baptism of fire and the Holy Spirit, have fought the good fight, who have mounted
                            up like eagles in spiritual aspiration,—such have also tasted of those divine powers which
                            will yield a more abundant harvest. The aspiration of the Christian, under such heavenly
                            influences will be to work out a character in true practical life which may bear the test of
                            Christ. We will briefly review the life of the deceased. At the age of nineteen years he
                            received faith in the testimony of Christ's Second Appearing as manifested among Believers,
                            and as soon as circumstances permitted moved into the Society at Enfield, Conn. He was then
                            twenty one years of age. It was through much tribulation that he gained a permanent planting
                            in the faith. He has been for forty five years a true and consistent Believer in Christ. For
                            many years he officiated as a Trustee and for a few years as an Elder. Though of a feeble
                            constitution, he possessed the spirit of determination which enabled him to triumph over
                            every burden. His life has been a protest against the evils of the world. He has always had
                            a testimony against sin, and kept that spirit power which is the life of the soul. He was a
                            ministration of strength to those whowere young; many have leaned on his strength and loved
                            him for his tenderness of heart. Though bearing a heavy burden in society he preserved his
                            faith unchanged, and gained the love and esteem of all who knew him. It is over such, that
                            death hath no power; the soul has within itself the consciousness that this is only an angel
                            call to "Come up higher;" to enter new fields of self-discipline and spiritual culture.
                            Enfield, Conn,</p></div2><pb n="86" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker manifesto" TEIform="index"/>SHAKER MANIFESTO</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">APRIL, 1BS2. Change of Office of Publication. The "Shaker Manifesto" for the present will be
                            published at Shaker Village, N. H. All business matters connected with the financial
                            department of the paper will be directed to the,— Publisher of Manifesto, Shaker Village,
                            Mer. Co., N. H. All other communications may be addressed, Editor of Manifesto, Shaker
                            Village, Mer. Co., N. H. One Copy per. year, Postage paid, " " six months, " " .60 .35
                            Enclose a two cent stamp for a specimen copy. To avoid mistakes, those who send money,
                            should write the name of their Post Office, County and State. to One inch, one insertion " "
                            three " " " six " " " twelve " " column ----- ---- ,f 1.00 each .75 " .G5 " .50 6.00 Larger
                            spaces, rates in same proportion.</p></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes" TEIform="index"/>NOTES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">A pastor in one of our liberal churches recently had for the subject of his Sabbath
                            discourse;—"Is the Gospel, Good News ?" By this it would seem that he was fractionally, in
                            doubt, and had raised the question, preliminary to an investigation. From his subsequent
                            remarks he seemed to prove, conclusively, that what was commonly called the "gospel,"
                            instead of being good news was quite the reverse. If to be a Christian one must
                            unhesitatingly believe in the theology of the church, a fall from original purity, the
                            incarnation of a savior and the vicarious atonement, then, we would rather be excused from
                            accepting the so-called "good news." The pastor then goes on to illustrate how the churchal
                            order has taught the inherent depravity of the race and the utter condemnation of all who
                            died in infancy, unless they had been so fortunate as to receive a baptism. That those who
                            pass away at a more mature age, unconverted, are denied one ray of hope or one moment of
                            consolation through endless ages. We are not surprised that the good pastor asked this
                            question, as the same interesting inquiry must necessarily occupy the minds of a large class
                            who entertain even a faint ray of hope in the immortality of their souls. There may be
                            reasons for believing all this and a great deal more of the same order, but there is an old
                            work, first published some two thousand years ago which teaches, emphatically, that the
                            "Gospel is Good News." In that day it was so fully believed that even the poor people are
                            said to have heard it with pleasure. The pastor of the former age, in his illustrations of
                            the gospel of good news, gave full instructions how to become a peace-maker, that they might
                            be called the children of God. How to become pure in heart, that they might see God. In
                            fact, how to establish an order of universal brotherhood that would afford to erery member
                            the peaceable fruits of righteousness. It may be that this ancient story of God's love for
                            man, can even at this <pb n="87" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 87 date, be found in some of
                            the old fashioned homes of New England. A writer in a recent number of "The Truth Seeker"
                            takes exceptions to the term, "Gospel Temperance," and remarks. "As if there were more than
                            one kind of temperance, a gospel temperance and an anti-gospel temperance." If the gospel is
                            good news and glad tidings, then the term Gospel Temperance is correct, and no other should
                            be used. We have thought that some of the Conventions would be more appropriately
                            styled,—"Political Temperance," and others "Vindictive Temperance." To do good we must be
                            consistent. Show to the beer and cider drinker and to the tobacco smoker, that we mean what
                            we say, that we are wishing to lead them from error to that which is right. It is rather
                            paradoxical, however, when a church al member calls to the people to abstain from wine, and
                            cider, and alcohol because they are injurious to the health, while at the same time he
                            indulges largely in the chewing and smoking of tobacco. For the present we shall conclude
                            that there are two or more kinds of temperance in the land, one the herald of "glad tidings"
                            and the others faithless and truthless representations. The subject of cremation is slowly
                            but surely gaining a hold on the minds of the people. Already it is reported that societies
                            have been formed in several of the United States, while in Italy, Germany and England,
                            Crematories are in successful operation. The subject is not popular, however, as it is a
                            strange innovation, hailing as it does from the land of the heathen and revived among as by
                            Free Thinkers or Radicals who are not expected to have much of a chance in the resurrection.
                            It is quite fortunate, in this case that these cremationists propose to burn the dead
                            instead of the living, and as they say, "to preserve from corruption the air we breathe and
                            the water we drink."</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="From the Letter of a Friend, in Pawtucket, E. I." TEIform="index"/>From the Letter of a
                                Friend, in Pawtucket, E. I.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="J." TEIform="persName"/>J.</byline><p TEIform="p"> [From the Letter of a Friend, in Pawtucket, E. I.] Elder Nicholas A. Briggs ;—I have
                                perused the documents you gave me, on my leaving the Village, and am pleased to
                                say,—That I see no inconsistency in your teachings, more tthan this ;—I am fully
                                persuaded that yours must be a very enjoyable life and expands into peace and happiness,
                                such as few or none atain in their natural living, for the vanities and pleasures of
                                this world. That you emulate the life of Christ is of tself a sufficient guaranty of the
                                nobleness of your aim and commends your life of purity and chastity. I know that he has
                                said, If we would be his disciples, we must deny ourselves and follow him. I here had a
                                train of thought about these matters since reading your circular. I don't know that I am
                                prepared to grasp your theories in their entirety, at once, but they are very feasible
                                if a man would live holily in this world. I feel with the Church, there is too much
                                form, while the power of religion is denied by the life." Your life and work in the
                                world is not in any degree understood by the masses of the people and only few could be
                                persuaded to accept it did they know of it, because of the lusts of the flesh and the
                                pleasures of life, which in themselves, are only emptiness and leave a sting behind. I
                                am in strong sympathy with you and wish that I was more pure, as He, Jesus, was pure.
                                Accept my thanks for all kindness. Ever yours. </p></div3><pb n="88" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="S. Mabee, Dear Sir;" TEIform="index"/>S. Mabee, Dear Sir;</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Barlow, Thomas" TEIform="persName"/>Thomas Barlow</byline><p TEIform="p">S. Mabee, Dear Sir;—A few days since I received the Jan. No. of the Shaker Manifesto :
                                from whom it came I knew not. I tried to satisfy myself, but in vain after a studied
                                effort. But subsequently I learned it was from you desiring to hear from me. You are an
                                entire stranger and why, or what you wished to hear from me I could not imagine, unless
                                it be my opinion of the pamphlets you sent me, and I cheerfully give it. It was enough
                                for me to know it was a Shaker production to satisfy me that it was well worthy of my
                                attention, and I read it through with pleasure and instruction. I hare considered the
                                two families or denom. inations of Quakers and Shakers as Christian brothers standing
                                upon the substantial, practical, happifying principles and truths of Christianity,
                                unmarred and undisturbed by the doctrines and dogmas of popular orthodoxy. They have at
                                an earlier day realized the slanders and persecutions of the orthodox churches, but by
                                patient lives and a more progressive civilization survived and come to the enjoyment of
                                a toleration secured, however to them more by the free, independent thought outside of
                                the churches than by the spirit governing within its pale. The world is moving on
                                despite of ecclesiastical influences, rather than with their aid. You have more of the
                                Christian heart and spiritual liberty in your religion than there are in the orthodox
                                schools of theology : and you are on a foundation as firm as practical wisdom and love
                                can lay, the teachings and life of christ being the corner stone. You (i. e. an article
                                in the Manifesto) truly say, speaking of our institutions of learning, they "are not for
                                the learning of the simple religion of Jesus" but for peculiar theories that "teach the
                                full cross of Christ unnecessary and a great deal of the worldly life not only
                                admissible in the church of Christ, but so harmonious as to become sacraments therein."
                                The time has come when the world is turning away from the church as the school of
                                truthful, practical instruction in religious matters, and demanding the more reasonable,
                                philosophical, and God honoring theology. The idea that a religion a little child can
                                understand and enjoy should be remodeled, hampered, confused and made ridiculous by the
                                bewildering cunning, and crafty selfishness of men in the dark ages long gone by, when
                                addressed to minds like yours as well as of infancy, is a sad commentary upon the
                                appliances and methods brought to bear to win or rather force into the church. But I
                                cannot dwell. Let/us seek and hope to be more enlightened on the great questions of the
                                life we should live, and of the life to come. Thanking you for the little book you sent
                                me I subscribe myself, Yours, with high respect for the Shakers, Canastata N. Y..[sic?]</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kellogg, H. S." TEIform="index"/>H. S. Kellogg</head><p TEIform="p">, at Enfield; Conn, Mar. 7. Age, 65 yrs. and 10 mo (See page 85.)</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gill, Harriet" TEIform="index"/>Harriet Gill</head><p TEIform="p">, at South Union, Ky., Feb. 28. Age 78 yrs. and 7 mo.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bolton, Edward Bennett" TEIform="index"/>Edward Bennett Bolton</head><p TEIform="p"> , at Shirley, Mass. Mar. 10. Age 79 years.</p></div4><div4 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="And thus our aged friends are passing..." TEIform="index"/>And thus our aged friends are passing...
                                </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whiteley, John" TEIform="persName"/>John Whiteley</byline><p TEIform="p">And thus our aged friends are passing away.—But they leave the blessed gospel to
                                    comfort us, and the same way of God, they have so faithfully traveled, and for which
                                    they have given up all to support—Let us not be discouraged! But in the same spirit
                                    of thankfulness they have manifested, let us toil on, that we may not be
                                    unprofitable servants of our God, but by patient endurance inherit the^promises,
                                    and, finally partake with them in the joys of the redeemed, beyond the reach of
                                    earth sorrows. In kindest love to all our dear relation Yours very truly,</p></div4></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>Juvenile</head><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Two coats" TEIform="index"/>TWO COATS</head><p TEIform="p">"My little girl must pay attention to what is read," said May's father one morning, as
                                they sat down to family worship ; and May, who was usually too restless to listen to
                                all, for once was quiet as a mouse, and scarcely took her eyes from her father's face.
                                88 r&gt;£i\.Tixs. <pb n="89" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 89 "Papa, I did pay
                                attention," she said eagerly, as they arose from their knees. '^'1 hearc you read about
                                the man that had two coats, and that he was to impart to him that had none." Then she
                                asked mamma the meaning of "impart." That day an old man came to the door with
                                shoe-laces to sell. May's shoes all buttoned ; but from her own little store of
                                spendingmoney she bought a pair of laces, just because the poor peddler looked so
                                forlorn; and as she gave him the change she saw that he wore no overcoat although it was
                                midwinter, and his old blue army jacket had not a button to hold it together. "Dear,
                                dear!" sighed May to herself, "what would I do if my papa had to go like that? and I
                                expect, as like as not, he's somebody's papa." And then she wondered if he did have any
                                little girls why they didn't sew some buttons on his coat. The old man read her sympathy
                                in her eyes, and as he dropped the pennies into his p cket said sadly; "I had a little
                                girl once like you, but she went away one day and never came back.'' The peddler drew
                                his sleeve across his eyes. "The preacher said she'd gone to sing with the angels ;" and
                                then he picked up his pack and turned away. May watched him with a pitying face. "I'm
                                'most sorry I didn't ask him to come in and let me sew some buttons on his coat," she
                                said, as she saw how the wind blew back his ragged coat; and then she remembered the
                                passage about coats that her father had read that morning. "Papa has three coats," she
                                said to herself, "and I'll ask him if he can't give this poor man one." "Isn't that
                                rather a literal rendering of the text, my dear !" asked papa, a little startled at
                                May's proposal. May knew nothing of "literal renderings,'' but she was very anxious to
                                have the coat. "I really don't know how to spare one," said her father to mamma. "But we
                                ought to mind the Bible," said May, quickly, "oughtn't we, papa?" Papa looked down into
                                the pleading eyes. "So we ought, my darling," he answered, wrapping the coat about her,
                                and kissing her eager face. "Now we will go and find your old man, and tell him that
                                this is what comes of a little girl being attentive at prayer-time. The shoe-string
                                peddler was just fastening the gate across the way, and when May's father beckoned him
                                over and made him put on the large, warm coat, it was hard to tell who was the
                                happier—the old man or the little girl. "I mean to pay attention every day/' said May,
                                as she skipped into the house. And papa felt that he would have to "pay attention"
                                too.—Angel of Peace.</p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Story writing" TEIform="index"/>STORY WRITING</head><p TEIform="p">Composition is the bugbear of the children, not without cause. When J. is told to write
                                upon the subject, "A Conversation among Themistocles, Aristides and Pericles, on the
                                Proposed Appropriation of the Funds of the Confederacy of Delos, for the Ornamentation
                                of Athens," no wonder she groans in spirit, wishes the schools were at the bottom of the
                                ¦sea, or at least, that she had the management of school affairs for a short time. With
                                what a glorious feeling she would abolish from the curriculum all composition! And woe
                                to the luckless wight who would dare to suggest its re-installment! Alas, poor J. ! thou
                                hast not the power to do this thing; but we hope that wiser teachers of an advanced and
                                wiser age will pursue a course which will make composition pleasant. A teacher of
                                experience says, "Let us call it story-writing, for story-writing is a word which every
                                child understands, and composition is not. I would have my reading-lesson first, and
                                have every member of the class read a paragraph; then order all book? to be put away,
                                slates to be distributed, and the subject of the lesson made the subject of the story to
                                be written by the children." Sc. Jour.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Letter Box</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Village, N. H." TEIform="index"/>Shaker Village, N. H.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="L." TEIform="persName"/>L.</byline><p TEIform="p">Shaker Village, N. H. Dear Sister Mary;—I thought some of the other girls had written to
                                you, so I thought it would be nice for me to write and tell you low much I loved you,
                                and what a good sis;er I think you are. I wish I could grow up and be as good as <pb n="90" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 90 SHAKER MANIFESTO. you are, then I should be happy, and all the
                                little girls would love me too. I thank you very kindly for that pretty card you gave
                                me. I think it was very pretty. All of the children send their love to you. Yesterday it
                                snowed. I am glad it is winter. I love winter because it snows. I am trying to be a good
                                girl. Don't you love to have some one to write you? I love to have some one write to me.
                                Last summer I had two gardens to pick flowers from. I love flowers. Good by, from your
                                child, [Age, nine years.]</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our Dear L ;" TEIform="index"/>Our Dear L ;</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>Mary Whitcher</byline><p TEIform="p">Our Dear L ;—Your nice letter was very acceptable, and you may be quite sure that I do
                                love to have somebody write to me, and especially the little folks, that I may see how
                                well they write, and Jearn what they love and what they are going to be. It seems you
                                love flowers, and love the snow, and love to be good. All these things are very pretty
                                and pure ; and now I judge you are to make a good woman. If you are good you will be
                                pretty and always happy. My love and thanks to you, and my love to all your little
                                mates. Affectionately,</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bertie's voyage across the Atlantic" TEIform="index"/>BERTIE'S VOYAGE ACROSS THE ATLANTIC</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bertie" TEIform="persName"/>Bertie</byline><p TEIform="p">My Father came to America from England, about six years ago and got acquainted with
                                Believers, and he returned to England to bring us, [a boy and two girls] to live with
                                Believers ; so we would grow up and become good brothers and sisters. It was six years
                                before he made his return to Believers. He said he would be much happier here, than he
                                would in England. Now I will tell you about our voyage across the Atlantic Ocean. It was
                                very stormy coming over here, for I was very sea sick, and at night I could hardly sleep
                                a bit. All day we were coming in sight of land, there was a man on the look out to see
                                how far distant we were from land; and when he could tell how far we were from land he
                                would shout to the man at the helm, and he would steer the ship in the right district.
                                Now I will tell you about the man who stands at the compass, who tells the man at the
                                helm where to steer too. He has a whistle which he blows so many times to tell the man
                                where to steer. When we got to land we rode to the station and met a brother who was
                                looking for us. We had our dinner and got into the train to go to C— when we got to C—
                                we rode with S—to the Village. [Age twelve years.]</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Village, N. H." TEIform="index"/>Shaker Village, N. H.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Everett" TEIform="persName"/>Everett</byline><p TEIform="p">Shaker Village, N. H. I went to the Camp with the Brethren and gathered sap. AVhen noon
                                time comes the brethren blow a horn for the boys to come to dinner. We boys went out to
                                play and swing on the trees. Two of us little boys had some sugar in a bucket. We had a
                                little red, white and blue ball. It squeaked like a mouse, and then we had some dinner.
                                Little Isaac was at home, but Albertis brought him some candy. [Age six years.]</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>House-hold</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Air we breathe" TEIform="index"/>The air we breathe</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lewis, Dio" TEIform="persName"/>Dio Lewis</byline><p TEIform="p">.—Our first, constant and imperative need is pure air. If we lack this, we have nothing.
                                Upon this vital point intelligent people are sadly and willfully stupid. A large
                                majority of the cars, theatres, halls, parlors and churches are dens of poisons. It must
                                be a strong attraction which can draw me to a public hall. In lectures before lyceums I
                                quarrel with the managers about the atmosphere of the hall. I return from church
                                sincerely doubting whether I have not committed sin in exposing myself in a poisonous
                                atmosphere. The eminent Baudeloque declared it as his conviction that the lack of proper
                                ventilation in our dwellings is the principle cause of scrofula. He believed if there be
                                pure air, bad food, improper clothing and want of cleanliness will not produce scrofula.
                                Sir James Clarke expressed the opinion that the bad air of our nurseries, sitting rooms
                                and bed rooms produce an immense amount of scrofulous disease. As a medical man I have
                                visited thousands of the sick, but have never found one hundred of them in a pure
                                atmosphere. Among the well, not one in a hundred sleep in a well ven <pb n="91" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 91 tilated room. The air of our close furnace heated houses
                                produces fits in our cats and dogs, and would kill our horses or cows in a few months.
                                God has provided this immense atmospheric ocean, a hundred miles deep, with its winds
                                and hurricanes, an exhaustless fountain of life and health! What a shame to our
                                civilization that we should expend thousands of dollars in erecting jplendid houses, and
                                so contrive them as to compel ourselves to breathe, instead of the pure air of Heaven, a
                                vile mixture of the poisonous execrations from our own bodies, and the poisonons gases
                                emanating from our gas-burners and fires.— Dr. in Golden Rule</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Moth preventitive" TEIform="index"/>Moth Preventive</head><p TEIform="p"> .—A correspondent of the Furniture Gazette commends the following remedy for
                                exterminating moths in carpets and furniture. After some years of experience with the
                                troublesome pests, says the writer, I found a sure preventive of moths in pitch paper,
                                the same as roofers use. The moth will live and grow on cayenne pepper and tobacco,
                                while I could never see that the use of these articles kept the moth miller out The plan
                                for the furniture dealer or housewife is to cut the paper in slips and place about the
                                room, under and behind sofas, chairs etc. This should be done as early as the middle of
                                April, and in warm climates earli. er. If the dealer wishes to make parlor suits moth
                                proof he should place on the inside of backs of chairs and seats small strips of the
                                pitch paper, and rest assured that the miller will not select these places to deposit
                                eggs. It is the miller that is the foundation of all the mischief.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ivy poisoning" TEIform="index"/>Ivy Poisoning</head><p TEIform="p">.—For dog-wood, or ivy poi soning the following is said to be an infallible remedy: Boil
                                wood ashes enough to make a strong lye ; wash the poisoned parts in this ; let it remain
                                a few minutes and wash off in soft luke-warm water ; when dry anoint with grease. Repeat
                                this process as the poison develops itself, and one or two applications wilj cure the
                                most obstinate cases. It acts like magic.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>Farm and Garden</head><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Principles governing the production of milk" TEIform="index"/>Principles Governing the
                                Production of Milk</head><p TEIform="p">.—From an article on this subject in the Scientific Farmer, we condense the following
                                items : "I understand very well, as probably every man does who handles milk, that there
                                is a wide difference in the composition of pure milk, especially in the matter of the
                                percentage of butter. All milk is richer in September than in June, and it varies in
                                this respect in different seasons in the same herd or cow. The cow that is fleshy gives
                                milk richer in butter than the cow that is thin and poor. One that has reached her full
                                maturity givesbetter milk than she did before she reached that age. A cow that is
                                gaining flesh day by day gives a richer milk than a cow that is losing it gradually.
                                Experience has taught me that a cow's milk very deficient in butter often fattens a
                                finer calf than that of a first class butter cow. When a man tells me what a splendid
                                fat calf his cow always rears, I do not wish to perchase her for a butter cow. A man
                                cannot procure milk profitably for any purpose without feeding his cows liberally with
                                good, sound, healthy nutritious food. It requires a certain amount of food to supply the
                                demands of nature. All above that amount which she will take and assimilate will be
                                converted into milk and flesh. The herd should be kept warm in winter and fed and
                                watered with regularity. This diet should be varied as much as convenience will
                            allow."</p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Striped bug" TEIform="index"/>The Striped Bug</head><p TEIform="p">.—Every gardener knows that this is a most destructive insect among melon, cucumber and
                                other young vines, sometimes damaging the crop seriously. Many remedies have been
                                suggested, some of them no donbt good in their way but troublesome. Now we have tried,
                                for several years, another which has-proved a complete success. Instead of aiming to
                                drive away the insect by soot, ashes, &amp;, we pet it, or rather furnish it with
                                food better than the young melon and cucumber plants. We sow around each planting a few
                                radish seeds, and coming up about the same time, the tops supply pasture for the bug
                                which it much pre- <pb n="92" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 92 SHAKER MANIFESTO. fers to the vines. Lettuce
                                will also answer, but the radish is rather liked the best. While our vines are untouched
                                by making this little provision for it, the young radish tops are completely perforated.
                                Should this fail, which is seldom the case and has never been with us, sprinkle the
                                vines with a solution of whale-oil, soap and water. No other insect but the curculio can
                                stand this. When this preparation is not attainable, a week solution of carbolic
                                disinfectant soap will answer as well. — Gfer. Tel.</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Silo meeting in Pittsfield" TEIform="index"/>THE SILO MEETING IN PITTSFIELD</head><p TEIform="p">A Letter concerning it by Elder Evans. Editor of the Sun:—There was a goodly gathering in
                                the town hall, Pittsfield, on the 10th inst., a company of substantial, noble looking
                                men. Instinctively I enquired, Where are the young men? Those present were uniformly
                                past middle age. Have Massachusetts farmers no posterity, or have their sons become
                                clerks, merchants, doctors, lawyers, priests, agents, soldiers, tramps? "Ill fares the
                                land to thickening wrongs a prey, where idlers nourish and true men decay." Is there not
                                something radically wrong in the system of national education when it thus results in
                                making labor on the soil uninviting, if not discreditable, to the rising generation of
                                young men? Suppose the clergy of New England revise its theology—form a new plan of
                                salvation—beginning with "the world that now is," allowing none to join the churches,
                                unless, as evidence of good character, they prove ownership of at least a part of an
                                acre of land, and also excluding all who own more land than they faithfully and
                                honorably cultivate. "Woe to those who add acre to acre and house to house, until there
                                be no place left for some of the people," and "blessed are the meek, for they shall
                                inherit the earth"—own a piece of land. Soon the school teachers would instill into the
                                minds of boys the idea that landless men are villians, i. e., holders of houses and
                                lands "by base servile tenure," and that the speculative land holder is also a villian,
                                i. e., "a vile, wicked man," a creator of criminals, poverty in land and riches in land
                                being the primary cause of human crimes. England is in great turmoil with her Irish
                                soil-workers—millions. Eussia is just now legislating to relieve the extreme poverty of
                                19,000,000 farmers who were emancipated from villiany or serfdom 20 years ago. Educate
                                and legislate the young men, with the best brains, unto the land. F. W. Evans. Mt.
                                Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenology" TEIform="index"/>Phrenology</head><p TEIform="p">. The time has come when people do not question the utility of Phrenology, and men in all
                                departments of life are now applying its principles, both in self-culture, and in their
                                dealings with others. The Phrenological Journal of New York is the only periodical
                                devoted to the subject, and it includes with this all that relates to Human Nature, and
                                the improvement of men physically, mentally, and morally. In the prospectus for 1882,
                                the publishers make liberal propositions to subscribers. The price has been reduced to
                                two dollars a year, and to each subscriber is offered a new Phrenological Bust. This
                                Bust is a model head, made nearly life size, of plaster of Paris, and so lettered as to
                                show the exact location of all the Phrenological Organs. It is a handsome ornament, well
                                adapted to the centre-table, mantel-piece, library, or office. With the aid of this, and
                                the illustrated key which accompanies it, together with the articles published in the
                                Phrenological Journal on Practical Phrenology, each person may become quite familiar
                                -with the location of the different Phrenological Organs, and a good judge of Human
                                Nature. The Bust is sent by express, carefully packed, to every subscriber who sends in
                                addition to the subscription price ($2.00), 25 cents extra for the boxing and packing;
                                or, No- 2, a smaller size, will be sent by mail, post-paid, on the same terms, to those
                                who have the Bust, or prefer the new Book Premium, will be sent "The Phrenological
                                Miscellany," worth $1.50. Our readers cannot do better than to subscribe at once for the
                                Phrenological Journal ; it will bn found the best possible investment for the money.
                                Those who desire a more explicit description, together with prospectus of the Journal,
                                should send their address on postal card, or accept the publishers' offer, and send 10
                                cents in stamps for sample copy of the Journal to Fowler &amp; Wells, 755 Broadway,
                                New York.</p></div3><pb n="93" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="World's cyclopedia of history" TEIform="index"/>The World's Cyclopedia of History</head><p TEIform="p"> The first volume of this great cyclopedia is announced to be ready in a few days. If it
                                reaches the standard indicated by its prospectus it will be altogether unrivaled in its
                                magnitude, comprehensiveness, and scholarship, and at the same time will be placed
                                easily within the reach even of any industrious laborer. Instead of being made up of
                                brief sketches by unknown authors, as are commonly the historical portions of
                                encyclopedias it will contain, unabridged, the great standard works of such authors as
                                Green, Macaulay, Grote, Carlyle, Gibbon, Guizot, Mommsen, and others. A very
                                comprehensive alphabetical topical index, covering all the works embodied in the
                                cyclopedia, will make ready consultation upon any subject convenient, and will group
                                together such wealth of knowledge and interest as will surprise the ordinary reader and
                                delight the profound student. Specimen pages received at this office show handsome
                                typography, good paper and good press work. Each volume will contain about 1000 large,
                                double-column, octavo pages, and will be sold at the amazingly low prices of $1.25 for
                                the cloth binding, and $1.40 for the same bound in half Russia, sprinkled edges. The
                                amount of matter contained in each volume, and for so low a price, seems almost
                                startling; Volume I containing, unabridged, Green's Larger History of the English
                                People; Carlyle's History of the French lie volution; Schiller's History of The Thirty
                                Years' War; and Creasy's Fifteen Decisive Battles of the world,—all for $1.25. No
                                payment is asked in advance by the publishers, but books will be sent to any part of the
                                United States by express, with the privilege of examination before payment is required.
                                It will be wise for those who want to purchase, to write to the publisher immediately,
                                as at these prices, the edition will be limited by the number of orders received before
                                publication. Specimen pages and full particulars sent free upon application to the
                                publishers, The Useful Knowledge Publishing Company, 162 William St., New York City. All
                                who wish for a "fair, fearless and Independent" exposition of the multiplied phases of
                                spiritualism, according to the general acceptation of that term, should become readers
                                of the RELIGIO-PHILOSOPHICAL JOURNAL. It comes to us now in an entire new dress, neat
                                and clean, and will no doubt be a pleasure to its readers. The paper will be sent for
                                twelve weeks, on trial, to new subscribers for 30 cents; for one year Address, John C.
                                Bundy, Chicago, 111.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>Select</head><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Queer bread materials" TEIform="index"/>QUEER BREAD MATERIALS</head><p TEIform="p">Earth bread is made from a white earth in Upper Lusatia, formerly a part of Germany, but
                                now under the rule of Prussia, and the poor of that region use this bread in times of
                                scarcity. The earth is dug from a hill where saltpetre was once manufactured. When laid
                                in the sun until heated it cracks, and globules like meal exude from it. It is supposed
                                that the saltpeter or soda in this earth gives it lightness. Something similar to it is
                                f'ouud in Catalonia and is also used for bread. It is affirmed that in cases of extreme
                                need many have lived on this bread for weeks without experiencing any injury. Soft
                                stones were ground and made into bread in the late famine in India, to prolong, if
                                possible, the lives of that striken people. Fish bread is still used in Iceland,
                                Lapland, CrimTartary, and other places far North. The fish is first dried, then beaten
                                to a fine powder; and sometimes the inner bark of some of the trees of that region is
                                mixed with it, and then wet and made into bread and cakes. Moss-bread is manufactured in
                                Iceland from the reindeer moss, which toward the month of September, becomes soft,
                                tender and damp, with a taste like wheat bran. This moss contains a large quantity of
                                starch, and the Icelanders gather it in the latter part of the summer season, thoroughly
                                dry it, then grind it into meal; and bread, gruels and pottages are made with it. The
                                want of better grain frequently compels the poor Icelanders to bake a kind of bread from
                                the seeds of the sand-reed, which, on their shores, are merely eaten by the birds of
                                passage.—Food and Health.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cause and effect" TEIform="index"/>CAUSE AND EFFECT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Kephart, L. L." TEIform="persName"/>L. L. Kephart</byline><p TEIform="p">[From the "Literary Microcosm."] <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A. M. God governs the Universe by mutual laws. These laws permeate all
                                        creation. In obedience to their mandates vapors rise, and rain falls; winds blow
                                        and frosts congeal; <pb n="94" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/> 94 SHAKER MANIFESTO. atoms cohere and
                                        planets whirl; and behind it all stands the Omnipotent Omniscient One, whose
                                        behests thess laws execute, evolving from this vast, intricate machinery, the
                                        greatest possible good, to the greatest possible number. In the happening of all
                                        events, careful observers have noticed the workings of the invariable law of
                                        Cause and Effect. Each effect always has its corresponding cause ; and each
                                        Cause, must, invariably produce Its corresponding effect. The Infinite God is so
                                        unchangable, so reliable, that whenever we see a cause set in motion and clearly
                                        comprehend it, we know, at once, what the effect will be. The Creator has
                                        endowed man with the ability to comprehend causes. He has also given him the
                                        power to set causes in motion, and the privilege of choosing, as to the kind ot
                                        causes he will set in motion. Herein consists man's supremacy. In this
                                        particular being, endowed with this prerogative, supreme, consists the fact that
                                        he is made in the image of his Creator. But, right here, man's supremacy ends.
                                        Having once set a cause in motion, it immediately passes beyond his
                                        jurisdiction, into the jurisdiction ot God. Man may choose which of two or more
                                        causes he will set in motion; but, having made his choice, that cause is so
                                        immediately linked with its proper effect, that man cannot, and God will not
                                        pre. vent the proper effect from following. Hence, Esau found no place for
                                        repentance though he sought it carefully, with tears. The great mistake of
                                        mankind is carelessness as to the causes they set in motion. Then, when
                                        overtaken by disastrous effects, they expend their tears and energies in
                                        bewailing their misfortunes, or "bad luck" and in imploring Divine Providence to
                                        interpose a miracle and save them from the effects of the causes they have
                                        willfully or carelessly started. This is supreme folly. A farmer carelessly sows
                                        bad seed. When the stalks begin to shoot, he discovers that it is cheat, instead
                                        of wheat. No matter how reverent and pious his life may have been, it is now too
                                        late for him to pray, so far as the result is concerned. The seed has been sown,
                                        the cause has been set in motion, and the effects will follow, the result is a
                                        crop of cheat, instead of wheat. A father and mother are careless in the
                                        training of a darling boy. They keep wine in the cellar, place it on the table
                                        at the evening meal, pass it around at the social gathering, drink it, and place
                                        it to the lips of the darling boy, on whom they dote with all the pride and
                                        fondness of which parents are capable. They are setting in motion a potent cause
                                        for evil, they are sowing seed, the fruit of which they little apprehend. Time
                                        rolls on, and when, in after years, they see their son wallowing in the gutter,
                                        and frenzied with rum, drive his wife and aged parents into the streets, they
                                        implore the Almighty to interfere and save the idol of their hearts from a
                                        drunkard's grave and a drunkard's hell. But, in reply to their importunities
                                        there comes back that wise and inexorable fiat; "Be not deceived, God is not
                                        mocked, for whatsoever a man soweth, that shall he also reap." And the
                                        thoughtful sympathetic observer, much as he may pity them in their anguish, is
                                        compelled to remark; "They have sown to the wind, they shall reap the
                                        whirlwind." One of the great lessons to be taught and learned today is that men
                                        should pray for wisdom to set right causes in motion, rather than for God to
                                        interpose and miraculously save them from the disastrous effects of malignant
                                        causes, after they have been set in motion. Let it be distinctly understood,
                                        that, wholly in temporal, and, in a large extent, in spiritual affairs, it is
                                        too late to pray, after a cause is set in motion, unless there may be some way
                                        in which our prayers may set in motion a new cause that will change or
                                        annihilate the previous one. The seed sown must produce its fruits. This is an
                                        inexorable law, hence the importance of exercising care, as to the seed we sow.
                                        This law holds good witli nations, as well as with indivduals. For many years,
                                        the great republic, sowed with the seeds of liberty, the tares of human slavery.
                                        Gradually the tares grew stronger and stronger, until the truth burst open in a
                                        terrible civil war, that filled the whole country withtleath and mourning,
                                        burdened it with debt, and, but for the mercy of God, and the abolition of
                                        Slavery, the annihilating of the cause, our <pb n="95" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER
                                        MANIFESTO. 95 whole national fabric, and with it human liberty would have
                                        perished from the earth. Fifty years ago, the spoils system, in our politics,
                                        was set in motion as a cause. As such it has gradually, but surely gone on,
                                        producing its concomitant effects, corrupting our social life, and creating an
                                        unholy greed for office, until throughout our municipal governments, up through
                                        our county and state organizations, to the very head o* our nation there runs
                                        this controling besot. ting influence,-—a desire to get at the spoils This
                                        principle has become so arrogant and dictatorial that it assumes to control all
                                        the energies of the nation, in the interest of rings, cliques, and monopolies.
                                        And, when the great, noble, God fearing Garfield, placed at the head of the
                                        nation offered a mild, bu&gt;firm resistance to its demands, this unright"
                                        eous principle, this unholy effect of an unholy cause, by the hand of a
                                        villainous assassin struck its blow, and the chief magistrate of the nation
                                        fell. This system is the cause, Garfield's death, and the whole nation bereaved
                                        and mourning, is the effect. Would we avoid similar calamities in the future?
                                        Then it is for us to see that the causes which produce such effects, are
                                        speedily annihilated. When the civil war was upon us, when the assassin had
                                        fired the shot, then it was too late to pray that we might be saved from the
                                        effects of the causes that were producing them. God's answer was, As with
                                        individuals, so with nations, they must reap what they sow. And this will ever
                                        be His answer. Hence the propriety of praying for wisdom to set in motion none
                                        but right causes.</quote></cit><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Literary microcosm" TEIform="index"/></bibl></p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A sad-looking man went into a drugstore..." TEIform="index"/>A sad-looking man went into a drugstore...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A sad-looking man went into a drug-store. " Can you give me, " said he, " something that
                                will drive from my mind the thoughts of sorrow and bitter recollections?" And the
                                druggist nodded,and put him up a little dose of quinine and wormwood, and rhubarb and
                                Epsom salts, and a dash of castor-oil, and gave it to him, and for six months the man
                                couldn't think of any thing in the world except new schemes for getting the taste out of
                                his mouth.</p></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True every time" TEIform="index"/>True Every Time</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">If an editor omits anything he is lazy. If he speaks of things as they are
                                        people get angry. If he glosses over or smooths down the rough points, he is
                                        bribed. If he calls things by their proper names he is unfit for the position of
                                        an editor. If he does not furnish his readers with jokes he is an idiot. If he
                                        does he is a rattle-head, lacking stability. If he condemns the wrong he is a
                                        good fellow, but lacks discretion. If he lets wrong and injuries go unmentioned,
                                        he is a coward. If he exposes a public man he does it to gratify spite, is the
                                        tool of a clique, or belongs to the "outs." If he indulges in personalities he
                                        is a blackguard. If he does not his paper is dull and insipid.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Boston post" TEIform="index"/>Boston Post</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A newly-varnished carriage..." TEIform="index"/>A newly-varnished carriage...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A Newly-varnished carriage is liable to spot. To prevent this some wash the carriage two
                                or three times in clean cold water applied with a sponge instead of using a hose ; this
                                will help harden the surface, and prevent it to some extent from being injured by the
                                mud or water getting splashed on the job. Never let mud dry on the surface, and then
                                wash off expecting to see no spots on the varnish. You will certainly be disappointed,
                                and the only way to remedy the evil will be to have it revarnished. Soft water is better
                                than hard water for the washing of carriages, as the lime which is in the hard water is
                                very liable to injure the varnish.</p></div3><div3 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Misdeeds and mishaps" TEIform="index"/>MISDEEDS AND MISHAPS</head><p TEIform="p">Tlie Eaw.Ham Poisoning CasesSix HVTore Deatlis Expected. Death will probably result in
                                the cases at Mineola, Minn., of Dr. Sanderson, the local physician, who was poisoned by
                                eating diseased ham; William Cushman; Peter Pickles, son of the butcher who raised and
                                killed the hogs ; Antonio Winter. Mr. Seidlistz, and a German living near the village.
                                It is not known and it is not probable that the disease exists outside the swine of this
                                one lot, but general fear prevails and the pork market is dead.</p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If censured, reply in a mild tone of voice, a high key forbodes trouble" TEIform="index"/>
                                If censured, reply in a mild tone of voice, a high key forbodes trouble
                            </head><p TEIform="p">If censured, reply in a mild tone of voice, a high key forbodes trouble.</p></div3></div2><pb n="96" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reapers' call" TEIform="index"/>THE REAPERS' CALL</head><p TEIform="p">"Thrust in thy sickle and reap, for the time is come for thee to reap, for the harvest of the
                            earth is ripe:"—Rev. 14,15. Alfred, Mb. Allegro. Sing, sing O Virgin of Israel, Tune your
                            harps with the chorus of angels The bright dawn of day is approaching, The armies of heaven
                            in glory descend. See the fields already ripening And the angel Reapers calling; Come bear
                            your sheaves with joy and gladness Home to the garners of our God.</p></div2><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="So much need have I to thank thee..." TEIform="index"/>So much need have I to thank thee...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Canterbury, N. H. So much need have I to thank Thee For thy mercy, care and love, That I have
                            no heart to murmur, And no lips but to approve. Teach me how I best may serve Thee, Every
                            conscious hour control; Then but little have I given For the wealth that greets my soul.</p></div2><pb id="p29" TEIform="pb"/><!--                     <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>