<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1206" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">12</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">6</biblScope><date value="18820601" TEIform="date">June 1882</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">121- 144</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="12" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="6" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--                     <pb id="p1"/>
                    <p> VOL. XII. JUNE. NO. 6. MANIFESTO PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES. OUR HOME AT SHAKERS, N. Y. " Blessed are they
                        that hear the word of God and keep it. Shaker Village, N. H. 1882. SHAKER</p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
--><pb n="121" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prayer" TEIform="index"/>PRAYER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bretzner, Emil" TEIform="persName"/>EMIL BRETZNER</byline><p TEIform="p"> In a diary, that I used to keep some time after my arrival :..t Mount Lebanon, there
                            appeared for a certain day the following statement: ';A fine, wintry day; I was working
                            alone and was led to do something strange." What could it have been, you ask ; I must tell
                            you. It was some nine or ten years ago ; I tried to pray, but I found it was hard work. When
                            I was a little boy in the parental home, under other skies, I was taught to pray, which
                            meant to repeat certain prayers every morning and evening, and at meals. What long prayers
                            they were, and such a lot of them ! I did not understand what they meant; I did not know
                            what it all was for, but I had to put up with it. I suppose I would not have lived long
                            under such strict, orthodox treatment, had it not been for the hope of future deliverance ;
                            for I had vowed in my wicked little heart, if that was all there was of prayer, then T would
                            certainly never pray, when I got big enough to determine the matter myself; and I never did.
                            I was told that I had a Father in heaven, and that my prayers were directed to him, and that
                            he would answer them. I could not see into it. How queer this is, I used to think. I know I
                            have a father and a mother, here on earth, but, when I want something of them, I do not go
                            and learn a long story out of a book, by heart, and then repeat it to them over and over
                            again. I would not get much that way, except, a friendly invitation to quit my noise, and
                            learn good manners. But I ask them simply and respectfully for what I want and, if I really
                            need it, then they will grant it, if it is in their power. That was my early experience in
                            praying, not a very good one either. No wonder that the latter effort appeared to me like a
                            strange proceeding. Yet it proved to be more fruitful of <pb n="122" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 122 SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. good, more blessed in its results, because it was truer, with less of dead form
                            and more of living spirit about it. The spoken words, the folded hands, the bended knees are
                            of no value in themselves, unless they are true expressions of the sincerity, the devotion,
                            the humility of the soul. Our faith gives us the assurance of both a Heavenly Father and a
                            Heavenly Mother, and of good guardian spirits and ministerinn angels. They have a tender
                            care for our welfare and an earnest desire to do us good ; and they are always ready to help
                            us. Prayer is simply the expression of that willingness on our part. In praying to them from
                            our hearts, whatever it may be, we tell them something like this. Here we are ; Ave want to
                            be good, much better than we are ; we need this, that or the other thing in order to become
                            so ; we know that you can help us ; give us of your gifts, and we will make a righteous use
                            of them ; clothe us with your power, and we will be strong ; tarry with us, and your
                            presence shall be our joy. We need be in no particular place to do this, neither in any
                            particular position. We need use no particular words to express it; the thoughts and the
                            feelings are sufficient, if they are true and sincere. Hence the beautiful, solemn habit of
                            our people to kneel down in silent prayer as often as we do, both publicly and privately ;
                            may it never be a mere soulless form with any of us ! Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beauty is power..." TEIform="index"/>Beauty is power...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W.</byline><p TEIform="p">Beauty is power, Though fragile quite, This being born of earth; Goodness is power Of other
                            mold And everlasting worth.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If all would" TEIform="index"/>IF ALL WOULD</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo G." TEIform="persName"/>ALONZO G. HOLLISTER</byline><p TEIform="p"> If all mankind were as careful at all times to speak the truth, every one to his neighbor,
                            as they are to accurately adjust their chronometers, the world would grow wiser, and lawyers
                            be dismissed to productive employment?. If everybody would treat injuries received with the
                            same neglect that they do those which they give, wars would soon cease, and death dealing
                            weapons might be converted into implements of useful industry. If all were as careful to do
                            unto others, whatever in like circumstances they would wish to have others do unto them, as
                            they are not to be shaved out of a half penny in change, all clannish and party distinctions
                            would disappear in a reign of universal brotherhood. If all were as careful not to add fuel
                            to anger, nor to entertain slander, as they are not to go too near a hot fire, many a
                            cockatrice egg would be crushed before it broke out into a viper, and many a slanderous
                            tongue be hushed for want of listeners. If all were as particular to keep their minds clean
                            from lascivious thoughts, and their hearts from lecherous desires, as they are to have their
                            dishes clean when they begin to partake of food, the kingdom of heaven would be immediately
                            revealed, and Christ would appear on earth in millennial glory. If all mankind were as
                            strict to obey the commandments of God, given for man's spiritual rule, and the regulation
                            of his moral conduct, as is the inventor to proceed according to the well known laws of
                            mechanical construction ; or as is the investigator of science, to proceed <pb n="123" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> SFIAKER MANIFESTO. 123 according to the obvious laws of nature in his pursuit
                            of definite results, the peace, love and blessing of God would flow upon them like great and
                            mighty rivers of life and happiness ; and justice, equity, and righteousness, would flow in
                            our streets like tidal waves from the Ocean of Omnipotence ; all blight and curse would
                            disappear, and human spirits bloom and expand on earth, with fruit surpassing in loveliness
                            the pictured glories of primitive Eden. The uniform operations of the laws of nature, and
                            our dependence upon the unvarying certainty of their results, should teach us the necessity
                            of adamantine integrity of purpose, and of unswerving obedience to the principles of virtue
                            written upou the heart, and engraved upon the mind, (of which the outward law is but a
                            transcript,) if we would cultivate the richest gifts of immortal life. That interior law
                            which preserves the understanding soul in its proper sphere, in harmonious relations with,
                            the universal mind, is expressed in the two commandments not found in the decalogue, but
                            testified to by the Savior, as the first and greatest commands of God, as follows : "'Thou
                            shall love the Lord thy God with thy whole heart, with thy whole soul, and with thy whole
                            mind— and thou shalt love thy neighbor as thyself." On these two, said the Son of God, "hang
                            the whole law and the prophets." These were doubtless given to man with the first dawn of
                            reasoning intelligence ; the law of primary attraction to its source, and the secondary law
                            of attraction to its kind, being essential to proper understanding. The inspired Psalmist
                            testified, "Man that is in honor and understandeth not, is like the beasts that perish,"
                            thus making immortality depend upon the cultivation of understanding. The Apostle tells us
                            that the law (ritual, and decalogue included,) was added because of transgression. That the
                            whole law is fulfilled in one word, that is love. Also that the end, or perfection of the
                            commandment is love out of a clean heart and good conscience, and faith unfeigned. Thus
                            man's duty, deepest interest, and highest pleasure, all begin, and are perfected in Love.
                            "Lo ! I come. I delight to do thy will, O my God." To these, our Savior added, "A new
                            commandment I give unto you, that you love one another. By this shall all men know that ye
                            are my disciples." This is a fundamental law of the kingdom of heaven. That the passion
                            which leads people to marry and produce a natural offspring is no part of Christian love, is
                            evident from several considerations. In the first place, it is a practice of which the
                            founders of Christianity never set the example in their Christian character. In the second
                            place, the married were required to hate and forsake that relation, as an indispensible
                            condition of discipleship. Luke. xiv. 20, 26, and other places. And to receive the kingdom
                            of God as a little child, (in whom said passion has no- place,) or in nowise enter therein.
                            In the third place, if that animal propensity, with or without the glamour which
                            intellectual refinement and a cultured fancy have woven around it, could be covered by the
                            sacred name of Christian love, the latter would not be a criterion of discipleship, because
                            it would apply as well to those <pb n="124" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 124 SHAKEE MANIFESTO. who never heard
                            the name of Christ, as to those who forsake all to follow his example. Finally, the two are
                            as distinct in their nature and operation on the soul, as miry clay and pure water, and so
                            utterly incompatible, that they cannot abide together in the same vessel. Hence, we find
                            that the law of virgin chastity, is a corrolary of the primary law of Love. If we obey these
                            laws and their sequences in all the duties and relations of life, as punctually as suns and
                            planets obey the laws of attraction and repulsion implanted in them, the fruits of such
                            obedience will be certain to satisfy all the rational desires of every soul that will keep
                            them. It is but a truism, that obedience must precede the ripening of the soul, and the
                            ripening of the soul must precede a permanent state of unalloyed happiness. Mt. Lebanon, N.
                            Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Coming cycles" TEIform="index"/>THE COMING CYCLES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wicks, Annie" TEIform="persName"/>ANNIE WICKS</byline><p TEIform="p"> 0, the gifts of God are dropping Like the flakes of snow that fall! Down from heaven, filled
                            with glory, They are resting over all. They are floating like bright seraphs, From the
                            beautious golden strand; Fill'd with love, with truth and wisdom, Wafted by an unseen hand.
                            Let us grasp these blessed treasures, While the angels bend to earth ; Let us learn the
                            loving lessons, Of their sweet immortal birth. They have come with gifts of shaking, Tongues
                            of love, and tongues of fire; Gifts of healing for the people, That will lift to life that's
                            higher. See ye not the light that's beaming O'er the hills of truth and peace? 'Tis the
                            grand prophetic cycle, When all war and strife shall cease! When the nations—blended truly—
                            Stand as brothers, hand in hand; Woman in her sphere be reigning, Strong for good in every
                            land. They shall both in honor mingle, Both be upright, just and true ; Each engaged, with
                            noble purpose Will the path of right pursue. Then will angels dwell with mortals, See each
                            other eye to eye, Working for the soul's redemption, Filled with power from on high. And the
                            coming generations, •Shall be ruled by Christian grace, For there will be true progression
                            In a nobler better race. Then through hearts by good inspired, Angels from the worlds above,
                            Will descend to teach earth's children Truths that form a heaven of love. They will lift the
                            darkened spirit With their words of hope and cheer, That they may attain salvatfon E're they
                            reach another sphere. Welcome then the angel bearers, Of God's power and truth sublime ;
                            They will lighten all our burdens Through the vale of transient time. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What is the matter?" TEIform="index"/>WHAT IS THE MATTER?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>GILES B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p"> (Continued from last number.) It then follows that this same creed teaches that man is not
                            justified by good works, that his good works are as filthy rags ! but, that he is saved in
                            sin, by believing that Jesus Christ, the Son God, performed good works for him, and by his
                            sufferings,—physical, and the shedding of his animal blood, he ransomed man from the
                            consequent sufferings of sin, while living in it! Yet Jesus Christ's mission was to save his
                            people from, not in their sins. Another hard <pb n="125" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 125
                            knot of Orthodox creedism is eternal, or infinite punishment for the sin of a finite being.
                            How everlasting torments of hell visited upon a sinner can be harmonious with the attribute
                            of a God of love and mercy, it is difficult for a. reasonable person to understand. A noted
                            modern religious scholar avers "There is no half way place for religionists between Rome and
                            reason." That is to say, a man cannot be a reasonable religious being.. And while the
                            legitimate conclusion of the vicarious atonement doctrine is, that, orthodoxically
                            considered, since Jesus, by his death upon the Jewish cross, has paid the debt of sufferings
                            for the sins of all sinners who believe on him, still, if you tell one of these believers
                            that this manner of faith is equivalent to telling their children, that, if they only
                            believe in Jesus they may sin as much as they please without injury or suffering to
                            themselves, and they look upon you with horror ! But this is its legitimate result. In the
                            face of so much inconsistency, which the light of Divine Truth, has. for the last half
                            century, been discovering to mankind, Is it strange that Creedal faith and professed
                            Christianity is dying out? Is it not rather strange that so many still cling to its shoddy
                            coat of righteousness. The great mass of the so called Infidels of the present day are not
                            infidel to God, to truth, to genuine Christianity—goodness, true religion, when properly
                            presented to them. Now is there not a heavenly Hope, a Dispensation of pure Religion and
                            full salvation for humanity ? We feel and know there is, and that it is to be found in the
                            Harvest of man from the worldly life. A new order, of both Earth and Heaven. A pure, chaste
                            union and communion of the sexes in a social capacity, of the individuals composing society
                            ; in a consecration of life, body and soul, to the work of human salvation from sin, and
                            redemption from the nature which tempts to sin. To some it has been revealed that the
                            religion of Christianity is a religion of reason ; its precepts shorn of mystery, are,
                            indeed, very simple. 1. That God is both a Heavenly Father and Heavenly Mother. 2. That
                            Jesus, apart from his baptism, was not God, nor the Christ. 8. That by his baptism of the
                            spirit, he became the Christ,—"the Son of God"—the "first born of many brethren, who, when
                            baptized with the same Christ Spirit, also became Sons of God, antl the Brethren of Jesus
                            Christ. 4. That the true and only Christian Resurrection, is a resurrection of souls dead in
                            sin, to a life in righteousness, and not of the physical body. That, of this resurrection,
                            Jesus "became the first fruits." Of no other resurrection was he the "first fruits." 5. That
                            the first appearing of Christ was through the male sex of humanity—this constituted the
                            Heavenly Bridegroom—"He that hath the Bride." The souls, however few or many, who were
                            obedient to Christ, manifested through the male line, constituted the Bridegroom, Church of
                            Christ, "He that bath the Bride, is the Bridegroom." John, iii. 29. This is not man, not the
                            man Jesus, abstractly, but Christ. 6. A bridegroom, must, necessarily, have a bride. The
                            heavenly Christ Bride is the manifestation of Christ, the "Second Time, in his Glory"—that
                            is, the female sex of humanity. And, those souls, however few or many, who are obedient to
                            the same <pb n="126" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 126 SHAKER MANIFESTO. Christ Spirit, manifested in, aod
                            through the female line, constitute the Bride Church of Christ—Jerusalem which is
                            above,—which is the Mother of us all." Gal. iv. 20, that is, all true heaven born souls. 7.
                            That Christ's mission is to minister the testimony and power of salvation from sin ; to call
                            mankind to judgment for sin by the confession of sin to God, in an Order of Saints, living
                            witnesses for souls before God, who, in like manner, have confessed all their sins. Its
                            culmination is, to bring the Kingdom of Heaven to Earth. tf. The testimony and work of
                            Christ's Kingdom is aggressive upon, even an end of the world; therefore, by the world,
                            hated. 9. The effort of professing Christians, in a wide sense, practically, though not
                            professionally so, is to harmonize the Church and the world, and is not this one great thing
                            that is the matter, that which has worked to destroy confidence .in the so called Christian
                            Church ? 10. Marriage, of the flesh, however purely regulated in its orc'er, Generation,
                            Private property, selfishness, sinful pleasure, all belongs to, and is of the worldly Order.
                            But, the Order of Christ's Kingdom is the "harvest of the world." It is virgin purity ;
                            salvation from all sin; community of goods among Believers, and universal Love. Mt. Lebanon,
                            N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prophetic conference" TEIform="index"/>THE PR0PHETIC CONFERENCE</head><p TEIform="p">In October 1878 there met at the city of New York a large number of ministers of all the
                            Protestant denominations, for the purpose of discussing the question of Christ's second
                            coming. During the three days session of what has been styled "the Prophetic Conference,"
                            some twenty elaborate essays were read, all relating exclusively to that interesting theme.
                            . Yet the striking fact became apparent at the outset that the convention was not called to
                            elicit the views any one might hold, but it was explicitly stated that the orthodoxy of
                            those who had gathered was unquestioned, that all agreed that the coming of Christ was to be
                            pre-millennial, and that it must be the visible appearance of the person of Jesus. In thus
                            confining the range of thought to such narrow limits the proceedings lost much of value and
                            interest, securing however that harmony which is so rarely a feature of theological
                            discussions. Notwithstanding this exclusiveness there were facts presented, sentiments
                            uttered and admissions made, that are of a peculiar significance to those to whom Christ's
                            second appearing is no longer a question, or a matter of speculation, or expectation. It was
                            stated that Scripture does not undoubtedly determine the question, although the New
                            Testament speaks no less than three hundred times of "the coming of the Lord." One speaker
                            argued that although the doctrine was surrounded by difficulties, so was every doctrine held
                            as vital to salvation; that it was not the divine intention that anything definite should be
                            known about it; that its purpose was to keep the church in a state of expectancy, thereby
                            inducing it to be prepared at all times to meet the Lord. The men of the first Christian
                            generation, including the Apostles and writers of the New Testament, lived in the almost
                            daily expectatiou of that coming, and of the end of the world. The historian Gibbon was
                            quoted as saying, that it was this belief in the impending coming of Christ which caused
                            them to regard their existence with contempt, and to suffer any martyrdom rather than
                            relinquish a hope, which, though not justified by experience, was one of the agencies of the
                            marvelcus spread of Christianity. The decadence of the belief in the coming millennium, or,
                            rather, the decline of primitive Christianity, is described in these words : The period
                            succeeding the politicoreligious triumph of Constantine, the period of the temporal
                            supremacy of Christianity in <pb n="127" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 127 the Roman Empire,
                            had come. The martyrage had passed away. No more councils like that of Mice, in which
                            martyrs fresh from the Maximian persecution, answered to their names. No more Paphnutius,
                            any more, venerable with silver hairs, one eye gouged out by the tools of the Pagan
                            torturer, its frightful socket seared with red-hot iron, standing by the side of young
                            Athanasius. A new generation has appeared, intoxicated with the Christian conquest of
                            Paganism and the splendor, of a Church and State establishment. When Christianity became a
                            worldly power, Roman Papal Catholicism advanced and took to itself, as a robberry, that
                            glory which is an object of hope and can only be reached by obedience and humility of the
                            cross. The new theory was invented that the millennium is a present fact, the ecclesiastical
                            state establishment in the visible Christocracy, the kingdom come! The visions of Daniel and
                            of. John, are now referred to the first advent, not the second The cross, once a symbol of
                            ignominy, is now everywhere in honor, on the Roman standard, the soldier's shield, the
                            Pontiffs' robes, the churches altar, the temple of victory, an object of perpetual
                            adoration. By union of church and state and perversion of victory, the foundation was laid
                            for a carnal and Satanic carricature of the millennial kingdom of Christ on earth, sunk in
                            the gross materialism and idolatry of political and military Christianity, and vanished the
                            last remnant of a suffering, but pure, apostolic church. In contradiction of those who hold
                            Christ's kingdom established already, the following extract is given : It cannot be ! There
                            is to be—it has not yet come—breaking with a rod of iron, shivering to pieces as a potter's
                            vessel is shivered. The clang of the stone striking the feet of the huge image has not yet
                            been heard, the crumbling of dynasties and the sweeping away of their debris as with the
                            breath of a tempest has not yet been seen. But it approacheth ! He who witnesses the
                            downward sweep of that stone cut out of the mountain, will hear the last cry of human woe
                            under human oppression before its shivering shock takes place, and see every shackle that
                            human greed has forged shattered forever under the earthquake convulsions of that
                            approaching hour. Thereafter, under the sway of the Son of God, will the gates of commerce
                            be forced by the enginery of war to thrust into a resisting nation's throat, a drug that
                            dwarfs and poisons the body and degrades the soul? Will liquor-leagues control legislators
                            and bribe judges, after a mightier bolt than Vulcan ever forged shall have been hurled?
                            Reason answers no ; and prophecy from the shores of Euphrates, thunders down along the
                            centuries, an authoritative no. Christ's kingdom established, iniquity cannot triumph. The
                            same speaker advanced the argument that the advent must occur before the millennium, because
                            the church is powerless to effect the conversion of the world. Of the 300 millions of
                            nominal Christians, not 30 millions are actual Christians, and more than eighteen centuries
                            have been spent in reaching this. England, he exclaims, is a Christian nation, yet of the
                            workingmen of London not three per cent, attend church on the rfbrd's day. Another speaker
                            in support of the same argument, uses the following language: Where are the churches planted
                            by apostolic hands and watered by martyr's blood? They have long since perished. Where are
                            the countries over which the diciples of Jesus swept as an army with banners? Under the
                            black pall of spiriUial death. Where is the city or town or village in the most highly
                            favored part of Christendom, all of whose inhabitants even profess to believe in the Son of
                            God? Of the earth's population li)5,000,000 are Roman Catholics, 160,000,000 Mohammedans,
                            340,000,000 Buddhists, 460,000,000 Pagans, 97,000,000 Protestant in name, and of these last,
                            so few comparatively really follow the Good Shepherd. (To be continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Have courage enough to review your own conduct..." TEIform="index"/>Have courage enough to review your own conduct...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Have courage enough to review your own conduct, to condemn it where you detect faults, to
                            amend them to the best of your ability, to make good resolves for your future guidance, and
                            to keep them.</p></div2><pb n="128" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Exaltation" TEIform="index"/>EXALTATION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>MARY WHITCHER</byline><p TEIform="p"> First learn our possession, Then, need of progression, And ply ourselves ear:y and late ; In
                            childhood if told it, And youth should unfold it, Through manhood no labor abate. All those
                            who love beauty Should also love duty, Keep diligent march with the sun,— At morn in its
                            brightness, At noon in uprightness, Till evening, when labor is done. Each day thus resuming
                            And all sloth consuming, Most godlike the being will grow ; A (id earth will inherit 'j.
                            iiat manhood and spirit Which constitute heaven below. What joy in pains taking ! What
                            sadness in making A havoc of talents and time; Why should we turn traitor To God our
                            Creator, And place ourselves lower than swine? Arise to the hearing, The love and God
                            fearing Which rational man should embrace ; While heaven is holy And wisdom is lowly We'll
                            gain and retain our true place. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dream" TEIform="index"/>A DREAM</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>MARTHA J. ANDERSON</byline><p TEIform="p"> gr. I dreamed that a beautiful summer Sprang from the winter drear ; The air was soft and
                            balmy, And the sky serene and clear. The grass was as smooth as velvet, And out of the rich
                            dark earth : Came plants of rarest beauty, And gems of floral birth. The birds were blithe
                            in the sunshine, And sang mid the foliage green; While trees with blossoming fragrance Waved
                            in the sunny sheen. Sweet vines o'er the fence were climbing; And shrubs by the wayside
                            grew, All laden with snow-white flower*, And gleaming with pearly dew. A mellow haze was
                            circling The distant wooded hills, And a sound of joyful music Came from a thousand rills.
                            The kine on the slopes were feeding; Sheep, necked the meadows gay, Where with the gold-eyed
                            daisies, Were dallying winds at play. A sense of rapturous beauty Over my spirit fell; And
                            the glory of that fair season, Seemed an enchanting spell. But, there cometh a meaning Out
                            of that vision bright, Clear as the morning shineth All in its golden light. A season of
                            full fruition Of all our prayer and hope, Will, like a beautiful summer, In heavenly glory
                            ope. And the good seed sown by angels Will come to a perfect birth ; For the sun of truth is
                            melting— The frigid locks of earth. Methinks I feel the breezes, Warm as the south-land
                            breath, The glow of inspiration That calls new life from death. And the types of gifts
                            supernal, Pictured in earth's ideal, Will in the good time coming, Prove to our spirits
                            real. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Work" TEIform="index"/>WORK</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Barrett, Andrew" TEIform="persName"/>ANDREW BARRETT</byline><p TEIform="p"> Our proposition is, that to do the greatest amount of good, we must not overtask our
                            strength; zeal in conjunction with wisdom should be maintained. We are building up a
                            community of interest, and it will readily be granted that to do this, every individual
                            talent <pb n="129" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. • 129 should be employed to the best
                            advantage ; but zeal without wisdom often terminates in a life injury. A zealous person
                            labors in such a way as to accomplish a third more in a given time, one day or week-, as the
                            case may be, and the result of such labor is sickness, lasting a day cr week. What is the
                            gain on his part? Would it not be well to apply the lesson of the tortoise and the hare ?
                            Had the spirit of moderation guided his movements would it not have been better ? "Hands at
                            work and hearts to God" is the watch-word of our community. We practice readily that in
                            which wre take pleasure. Too many view labor in the light of being degrading. While many
                            profess, and really manifest their willingness to do whatever may be required of them, they
                            are nevertheless unreconciled to the duty itself. This we would claim as wrong. If we do not
                            like the discipline of labor, we should be industrious because we conscientiously deem it
                            our dnty. We consider eating and sleeping as a necessary part of our existence. In the same
                            light we should view the importance of labor. We do not wish to be understood that we refer
                            wholly to manual toil; this would be as disastrous to society as though all were engaged in
                            purely intellectual pursuits. In whatever sphere of action we may be placed, let us not
                            allow any excuse to seduce us from our duty. As we love the interest of our community, let
                            us exercise that self-denial requisite to the consecration of every talsnt needed for its
                            growth and prosperity. Perhaps no one is really idle, but there is much done fruitlessly,
                            much that accomplishes no good. "Rest is not quitting this busy career, Rest is the fitting
                            of self to one's sphere ; 'Tis the brook's motion, clear without strife, Fleeing to ocean
                            after its life. 'Tis loving and serving, the highest and best 'Tis onward unswerving and
                            this is true rest." Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dialogue" TEIform="index"/>A DIALOGUE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescott, James S." TEIform="persName"/>James S. Prescott</byline><p TEIform="p">Between a Shaker and a Clergyman. S. Good morning, I have come to imform you, that T have
                            changed my religious sentiments, and embraced the testimony of Christ's Second Appearing. C.
                            Is it possible? I am surprised! I am sorry for you! How could you, after being a member of
                            our church so long, go and throw yourself away among that deluded people, whose religion is
                            so universally spoken against? S. I did not throw myself away, I only "saved myself from
                            this untoward generation." If it is a delusion, it is a happy one, and as happiness is what
                            all men desire, it is but reasonable to expect them to close in with it, when, and wherever
                            they find it. C The Shakers are well known to us. Their sentiments and practice made their
                            appearance early after the church began to apostatize from the truth of God, revealed in his
                            holy word. Shakerism is the monkery of the catholic church, the "Mother of harlots." S. The
                            sentiments and practice of the Shakers made their appearance on the day of Pentecost—See
                            Acts, ii. 44, 45, and iv. 34, 35, and 37, and was consummated in the Church at Jerusalem;
                            and while it stood in its purity, was a real Shaker Church, representing what the Shakers
                            have been doing in America, ever since 1792. Let me explain further. Did not the primitive
                            Christians live lives of celibacy? Peter, one of the Elders of the church said, lo ! we have
                            left all to follow Christ, and the wife was included. So do the Shakers. Did not the
                            primitive church, hold their property in common? So do the Shakers. Did not the early
                            Christians abstain from war and blood- <pb n="130" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 130 SHAKER MANIFESTO. shed? So
                            do the Shakers. It was the sentiments and practice of the churches, both catholic and
                            protestant, that made their appearance, early after the apostasy took place, and not the
                            Shakers. C. It is no new sentiment for men to deny as your teachers do, the doctrine of the
                            imputed righteousness of Christ, and claim that they will climb up some other way than by
                            Jesus Christ, the way, the truth and the life. Many being ignorant of God's righteousness,
                            have gone about to establish a righteousness of their own, having never submitted to the
                            righteousness of Christ, but such the scriptures assure us will receive this at God's hand,
                            to "lie down in sorrow." S. On this point I found by critical examination, that the Shaker's
                            theology was the most rational and consistent of any now extant. It commended itself to my
                            reason and understanding. I was always at a loss to know, how God could punish the innocent
                            and let the guilty go free, without violating his attribute of justice, while "justice and
                            judgment, were the habitation of his throne." I think there was some priest-craft about this
                            doctrine. C. Forbidding to marry was one of the prominent features of the apostate church.
                            See I. Timothy iv. 1, 2, 3. "Now the spirit speaketh expressly, that in the latter times,
                            some shall depart from the faith, giving heed to seducing spirits and doctrines of devils,
                            speaking lies in hypocrisy, having their conscience seared, with a hot iron ;—Forbidding to
                            marry, and commanding to abstain from meats which God hath created to be received with
                            thanksgiving." S. On investigation of the Shaker doctrines I found that marriage was a civil
                            rite and not a Christian institution, and belonged exclusively to the children of this
                            world, and not to Christ's kingdom, as it is written. "The children of this world marry, and
                            are given in marriage : But they which shall be accounted worthy to obtain that world, and
                            the resurrection from the dead, neither marry, nor are given in marriage :" See Luke, xx.
                            34, 35. Who are accounted worthy? Why, all true Shakers of course—they do not forbid
                            marriage and never did. But they abstain from it, as Christ and the Apostles did. They have
                            the highest Christian auth ^rity for living lives of virgin celibacy. Christ lived that
                            life, and he was our example. Paul lived that life. Peter, and all the Apostles, and the
                            primitive church lived that life, before the apostasy. (TO BE CONTINUED.)</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Duty" TEIform="index"/>DUTY</head><p TEIform="p">In all the despatches of the Duke of Wellington, the word Glory so commonly used by Napoleon
                            never occurs. Duty was with this great General, his watch-word, and his guiding star, and
                            the greatest victories he achieved were but the discharge of the duties he owed to the
                            British nation. So should it be with every battler in life, and more especially so with
                            every soldier of the cross. To overcome evil, and to subdue the propensities of their
                            natures is a duty they owe to themselves, and to exercise the beneficent influence of such a
                            regulated nature is a duty they owe to others. The consciousness of having done our duty in
                            the various relationships of life, will inspire youth, sustain old age, and smooth our
                            passage to the tomb ; nor will it be asked in what particular garb or circumstances this
                            duty has been performed. To all his faithful servants, the great Father of the human race
                            will at last say ''well done." j'What is our duty here? To tend From good to better, thence
                            to best; Grateful to drink lifes' cup then bend, Unmurmuring to the bed of rest; Gathering
                            the flowers that round us grow Scattering their fragrance as we go :" "And so to live, that
                            when the sun Of our existence fades in night; Memorials sweet of mercies done, <pb n="131" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 131 May shroud our names in memories bright; And the blest
                            seeds we scattered bloom A hundred fold in years to come." Amigo,Shirley Village, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nobility" TEIform="index"/>NOBILITY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Gary, Alice" TEIform="persName"/>Alice Gary</byline><p TEIform="p">True worth is in being,—not seeming; In doing each day that goes by Some little good,—not in
                            the dreaming Of great things to do by and by. For whatever men say in blindness, And spite
                            of the fancies of youth, There's nothing so kingly as kindness, And nothing so royal as
                            truth. We get back our mete as we measure,— We cannot do wrong and feel right: Nor can we
                            give pain and gain pleasure, For justice avenges each slight. The air for the wing of the
                            sparrow, The bush for the robin and wren, But always the path that is narrow And straight
                            for the children of men. We cannot make bargains for blisses, Nor catch them like fishes in
                            nets ; And sometimes the things our life misses Helps more than the thing which it gets. For
                            good lieth not in pursuing Nor gaining of great nor of small; But just in the doing, and
                            doing As we would be done by, is all. Thro' envy, thro' malice, thro' hating, • Against the
                            world, early and late, No jot of our courage abating,— Our part is to work and to wait. And
                            slight is the sting of his trouble Whose winnings are less than his worth : For he who is
                            honest is noble, Whatever his fortunes or birth. .</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Teachers and workers" TEIform="index"/>TEACHERS AND WORKERS
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Give the workman water pure, Give the workman light and
                                    air; If his life is insecure Health and mind cannot endure, And his home becomes a
                                    snare. Build the workman's dwelling sound, Not an earth-house or a cave; Scan and
                                    drain well underground, Heed and pave well all around, Or you'll make his living
                                    grave. Educate the workman's child, In your lesson aye impress That the fountain
                                    undented Lies in truth so oft exiled— Mind and body cleanliness. Teachers of the
                                    present age, Teachers of the coming time, If you'd live in history's page, Let these
                                    truths your mind engage ; They will lead to work sublime.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Builder" TEIform="index"/>The Builder.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Highly esteemed Sister :" TEIform="index"/>Highly esteemed Sister :</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Halloway, Cephas" TEIform="persName"/>Cephas Halloway</byline><p TEIform="p">[Elder of Uaion Village, Ohio, who is now 81 years of age, recently wrote to Sister Mary W.
                            from which we take the following.] Highly esteemed Sister :—We received your letter of the
                            4th ult. and read aud re-read it with much interest. Allow us to thank you again for that
                            beautiful book.—"Elements of Character." Since that time we have made a free distribution of
                            some twelve copies. We remember quite well your school and the interested teacher, and the
                            interesting pupils; their recitations, their varied exercises, and particularly their little
                            lessons of declamation. Indeed, we were highly pleased with Shaker Village, and with all its
                            inmates. Many of that number who were young at that date are now, as you inform us,
                            occupying useful positions in Society. We now remember them as beautiful children and are
                            interested to learn of their better and more advanced lives. With the little children we
                            always eujoyed a pleasant chitchat, and took pleasure in their amusements. I will now write
                            you a little more ful- <pb n="132" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 132 SHAKER MANIFESTO. ly concerning myself as
                            you requested. I was born on the 29th of December, A. D. 1800, in the State of Ohio, which
                            was then only a Territory. My parents at that early date lived in a rude, log cabin, which
                            was situated in the dense forest. We had no roads, bridges, school house nor even a meeting
                            .house. Years passed on and our first school house was built of unhewn logs and covered with
                            split boards, called clap boards. It had one room, only, as it was innocent of even a hallor
                            closet. Our place for study was well lighted, having several windows about eight inches long
                            and less in width. Instead of glass these placed wore covered with paper that had been
                            dipped in oil. From some of the logs of which the house was built, the sprouts grew during
                            the first summer, full two feet. It presented a very singular appearance as these long
                            sprouts were growing on all sides of the house. At this date 1 was six years old, and with
                            this privilege learned to spell and read quite well. For books we had Dilworth's prim3r,
                            Noah Webster's speller and the New Testament. Our teacher had no burden about arithmetic as
                            it was not taught, not even the multiplication table. As our school house was built in the
                            green woods, in a green country and having a green teacher and greener pupils, it need be no
                            wonder that the writer of this article should be one of the western evergreens. At the early
                            date of which I am writing, even small children could be spared but a short time each
                            season, to attend school. They were needed at home and often made quite useful in picking up
                            brush and chips preparatory for the plough and the hoe. My parents, Jacob and Hannah
                            Halloway became the owners of 170 acres of excellent land, in the Miamie valley, on which
                            they built a comfortable house and barn. They kept three spans of horses and fifteen head of
                            cattle. On account of the depredations committed by the bears and wolves, they were able to
                            keep only a few sheep or a few swine. I was but five years of age when my parents became
                            acquainted with the Shakers, and my initiation into the faith of the order, must date, I
                            suppose, about that time. Allow me also to make this remark, that I have not been confined
                            to the house one day, by sickness, since I was a very small child. I have not taken any
                            medicine to the amount of one dollar. I have never ate nor smoked tobacco, and do not think
                            I have used a gill of spirit for more than fifty five years. [Notwithstanding all these
                            early disadvantages, our beloved Elder Cephas has been one of the most active workers in the
                            Society ot Union Village, and has been appointed to many of its offices of trust and
                            responsibility. At the present time he is the Elder in the church family. Even at this
                            advanced age the good man is an excellent penman, and his whole letter would be a severe
                            rebuke to the many, who having every advantage for an education, allow themselves to write
                            so badly and to spell even worse.]</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Quench not the spirit" TEIform="index"/>QUENCH NOT THE SPIRIT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hillsgrove, Elmira" TEIform="persName"/>ELMIRA HILLSGROVE</byline><p TEIform="p"> As we are so engrossed in the cares and interests of this life we do not always recognize
                            the strivings of the good spirit in its varied forms. The voice may come in the whisperings
                            of conscience, gently chiding us for what we are now doing, or intending to do at some
                            convenient opportunity. It <pb n="133" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 133 may be, in the
                            warning of a friend, to prevent some harmful result; or in rebuke, which shall slay our
                            cherished idols, and seemingly take from our grasp, while it gives to another whom we deem
                            not as worthy as ourselves. How nature rebels as the spirit of Truth thus disarms us of
                            selfish advantages ; for the worldly mind dlscerneth not the things of God aright; we often
                            construe his mercies into judgments, his truths into hard sayings; and fail to reap the
                            blessings intended for us. Do we not create many battles for ourselves, and find the
                            victories in such contests, only convictions of our folly? If a lesson is learned, our eyes
                            opened to the truth in any degree, so much good is attained thereby ; yet had we yielded in
                            humility and perfect trust to the molding of the Potter, we might have found a joy which
                            surpasseth all knowledge, and been led in the green pastures of heavenly light and love,
                            instead of exploring the barren hills of self pleasure and sin. O, let us not trifle with
                            monitions of the e;ood spirit; neither as concerns our own interests, nor those of another
                            soul ; but tenderly cherish the good, which we have not the power to replace when it is
                            lost. While it is possible that we may through right influences and virtuous examples, aid
                            the development of a spiritual character, it is quite as possible that we may retard the
                            maturity of goot seed sown in the soul, by cultivating adverse principles or opinions. Let
                            us magnify right, over error, anc if we cannot see with another, k'eye to eye," we shall
                            always be blest in re specting sincerity of purpose. Canterbury, N. H. Accept no unmerited
                            praise, lest it tend to vanity.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Take care of your thoughts" TEIform="index"/>TAKE CARE OF YOUR THOUGHTS</head><p TEIform="p">Sin begins in the heart. If you can keep 7our thoughts pure, your life will be blameess. The
                            indulgence of sinful thoughts and desires produce sinful actions. When lust lath conceived,
                            it bringeth forth sin. The )leasureable contemplation of a sinful deed s usually followed by
                            its commission. Never allow yourself to pause and consider the pleasure or profit you might
                            derive from this )r that sin. Close your mind against the suggestion at once, as you would
                            lock and bolt your doors against a robber. If Eve lad not stood parleying with the devil and
                            admiring the beautiful fruit, the earth might lave yet been a paradise. No one becomes a
                            thief, a fornicator, or a murderer at once. The mind must be first corrupted. The wicked
                            suggestion must be indulged and revolved in the thoughts, until it loses its heinous
                            deformity, and the anticipated gain or pleasure comes to outweigh the evils of the
                            transgression. Your imagination is apt to paint forbidden pleasure in gay and dazzling
                            colors. It is the serpent's charm. Gaze not upon the picture. Suffer not the intruder to get
                            a lodgment. Meet the enemy at the threshold and drive it from your heart. As a rule, the
                            more familiar you become with sin the less hateful it appears; so that the more completely
                            you preserve your mind from unholy and wicked thoughts, the better. Avoid the society where
                            obscenity or blasphemy is heard. Cultivate the society of the virtuous. Read nothing
                            unchaste or immoral. Make a covenant with your eyes. Familiarize not your mind with the
                            loathsome disease of crime. Never harbor malicious or envious thoughts. Direct your thoughts
                            toward pure and holy subjects. Contemplate the character of the spotless and perfect Son of
                            God. Keep your spirit untainted, your thoughts uncontaminated. So shall your life be
                            virtuous. As a man thinketh, so is he. Take care of the thoughts, and the actions will take
                            care of themselves. Exchange.</p></div2><pb n="134" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker manifesto" TEIform="index"/>SHAKER MANIFESTO
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">SHAKER MANIFESTO. JTJTVE, 1H82. Office of Publication, The "Shaker Manifesto" is published at
                            Shaker Village, Mer. Co., N. H. All business matters connected with the financial
                            department of the paper will be directed to the Publisher of Manifesto, Shaker Village, N.
                            H. All other communications may be addressed, Editor of Manifesto, Shaker Village, N. H.
                            One Copy per. year, Postage paid, .60 six months, " " . .35 Enclose a two cent stamp for a
                            specimen copy. To avoid mistakes, those who send money, should write the name of their Post
                            Office, County and State. to i\.r&gt;vx:ii.aissxt.s. One inch, one insertion $ 1.00 each
                            .75 " ;' six " " .65 " " twelve " ',' .50 " column 6.00 Larger spaces, rates in same
                            proportion.</p></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes" TEIform="index"/>NOTES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Anthony Comstock recently lectured on the "Corruption of our Youth." He stated that in ten
                            years the Society for the Suppression of Vice had suppressed one hundred and sixty obscene
                            publications, and that an aggregate of twenty four tons of obscene matter had been seized,
                            and the arrests numbered six hundred.—Eeligio-Philosopical Journal. What a fearful avalanche
                            of immorality the above note represents ! Twenty-four tons of uncleanness to deal out to a
                            class, upon whose minds the impression may be indelibly stamped, and through this may come
                            the consummation of their ruin. Those who make and sell books and papers of this debasing
                            class are doing an immense amount of injury. They place their unhallowed goods into the
                            hands of those of immature mind which cannot otherwise than awaken a train of thought among
                            the precocious and often lead directly to sinful practices. It is certainly one of the
                            redeeming features of our day, that there is a wholesome regard for the law of chastity,
                            among the fathers and mothers who are now acting as honorable guardians over the minds of
                            the young. Our order cannot do otherwise than anxiously hope for success in the effort to
                            protect the rising generation from every phase of immorality. The practice, which is too
                            prevalent among school teachers of boxing the ears of children is not only barbarous, but a
                            dangerous custom. There has probably many more injuries resulted from it than are ever heard
                            of or suspected. A blow on the head may not only occasion deafness but may produce fatal
                            injuries. Southern World. It has been said that a word to the wise is sufficient, and yet it
                            can do no harm to act upon the principle as set forth by the good prophet, and, give line
                            upon line, here a little and there a little, and save if possible the infliction of injuries
                            upon those who are too young to defend themselves. It is very questionable if any good,
                            moral quality was ever forced into a child by bodily punishment. A fear from a superior
                            force might under certain circumstances prevent the repetition of an error, but the fear has
                            not prepared the mind to do good from a loving and peaceful heart. Too many,persons are
                            inclined to inflict their punishment upon others, while <pb n="135" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. 135 their own minds are under the excitement of passion. Better leave the
                            correction till after you have eaten your dinner or till you have read the story of Jack and
                            his bean stalk. More especially should this refer to those who accept children by adoption.
                            The time has been when a sad stigma rested upon our order for real or imaginary punishment
                            toward those of immature years. We have learned this one fact, that an undisciplined or
                            ignorant mind often does in the name of religion what a little common sense would, at once
                            forbid. The story of the old farmer who laid his "judgment to the line and his righteousness
                            to the plummet" should not be lost to the "children of light.'' Whenever anything occured to
                            arouse his temper, instead of beating his animals or whipping his children, he would sing
                            "Old Hundred." The effect was no doubt, charming. Try it, and if your passion does not end
                            the same moment the tune does, then try again, and sing a little louder. CANTERBURY, 2NT. H.
                            The Town Report for the year ending March 1, 1882 makes reference to the Shaker school as
                            follows ; Summer term taught by L. Jeannette Forest, assisted by Asenath C. Stickney. Number
                            of weeks, 16 ; number of pupils, 25: average attendance, 23 ; wages per month, $24. We are
                            pleased to report a good school, a faithful devotion on the teacher's part, and a ready
                            response by the pupils. Winter term taught by Ednah E. Fitts, assisted by Agnes E. Newton.
                            This school has also been successful, and a steady improvement is manifest. The pupils are
                            young, but show results of earnest efforts and careful teaching. Number of weeks. 15 ;
                            number of pupils, 25 ; average attendance, 24 ; wages per month, $26. N. A. Briggs, S. S. C.
                            ENEMEr/D, N. H. District UNTo. 13. Teacher of Summer Term, Mary E. Elk ins. This school
                            was one of superior excellence. The teacher's remarkable administrative talent the previous
                            conformity of the school to her methods, and her thoroughness in teaching, all conspired to
                            make the school one of real worth. Every study was made a specialty. The class in anatomy
                            excelled all others in town. Winter session, Arthur Theobald, teacher. Too much cannot be
                            said in praise of this school. For one to appreciate its real worth it must be seen. The
                            order was perfect the recitations without a fault. The fact there was not a case of absence
                            or tardiness, is much to the credit of the teacher and scholars. The teacher's success would
                            have done honor to one of many years experience. Penmanship as in the Summer Term, was
                            faithfully attended to. The interest the Shakers take in education is very commendable. If
                            all did, as much for schools as here, we should have far better ones in town. DISTRICT NO.
                            18. Annie M. Ellis teacher for the year. The teacher loves her work, studies to make her
                            labors profitable to her pupils, and a credit to herself. The scholars were very ready in
                            their answers showing they had not been idle. If all teachers were as ambitious as this one
                            we <pb n="136" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 136 SHAKER MANIFESTO. should have fewer poor schools. You have
                            made a good beginning now press on. I rank this teacher among otir hard workers. The
                            guardians in this district do much for the education of their children. Geo. F. Pettengill,
                            S. S. C. &gt;f the town of Enfield, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Gloucester, Me. Feb. 1882" TEIform="index"/>West Gloucester, Me. Feb. 1882</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sawyer, Otis" TEIform="persName"/>Otis Sawyer</byline><p TEIform="p">Beloved Editor :—The following communication was handed me by the author, who is a
                                gentleman of respectibility, and an earnest advocate of all needed reforms in society,
                                and appreciates good wherever and in whoever he may find it. In fraternal love,</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="There is no mystery but ignorance" TEIform="index"/>THERE IS NO MYSTERY BUT IGNORANCE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Todd, John M." TEIform="persName"/>John M. TODD</byline><p TEIform="p"> To the Editor of the Manifesto ;— I have been impressed for a long time to write an
                                article for the Shaker Manifesto, thinking that a few lines from one who is not a Shaker
                                might be of interest to its readers. I am upwards of sixty years of age. I am a husband,
                                father, and grandparent, and for fifty years an earnest seeker after the truth. I have
                                been an interested reader of the Shaker paper, from the publication of its first number.
                                In my youth I lived near the Shaker family of New Gloucester, Maine, and the first
                                impression of the order, I received from a minister at my Father's house. He gave me an
                                account of the Shakers, and also gave as a reason why they settled near a lake. It was
                                handy for them to drown the unwelcome babes born in their Society For years the
                                impression prejudiced me bitterly again si the Shakers. Some years after this I hearc
                                that the Legislature of New Hampshire hac ordered a lake to be dragged, to prove the
                                shaker's guilt. As a reward for their labor they had founc some bones which they
                                declared to be those of little children, but which on investigation proved to be the
                                bones of a sheep. This, to me made the finders appear rather sheepish, and suggested to
                                my mind that possibly, the other stories which I had heard told against this people,
                                might be equally as false. Knowing that there is no mystery but ignorance, and that he
                                who has, never changed an opinion, has forsaken none of his errors, I thought I would
                                inform myself upon the great subject of immortal life, as presented by the Shakers. This
                                much I have learned; that the true life is the eternal life, because truth is eternal;
                                and happy, indeed, is he who walks therein. I also wished to inform myself more fully
                                concerning tills strange sect, who were everywhere, spoken against. I now found that I
                                had much to unlearn, and at the same time much to learn. One thing I have ascertained,
                                and that is they are not murderers of, but are dear lovers of children, both natural,
                                and spiritual. That they do believe in marriage, in its proper order, hence, the oft
                                repeated proposition urged against them, that if the doctrines should prevail, the race
                                would become extinct, is not true. They believe that there will be enough of the human
                                family, occupying the Adamic plain, to perpetuate the race. The charge against them that
                                they do not believe the Bible, is not strictly true, for I find that their belief,-
                                interpretation and practice of its teachings, are far in advance of their accusers. It
                                is said that the Shakers do not believe Jesus is the Savior of mankind, yes, they do,
                                and that there are more than one, with less power, who are also saviors of the race.
                                But, more horrible still, it is said that they believe '-Mother Ann" was also a savior.
                                Well, what if they do? Has she not saved many from the error of their ways? Is there a
                                true man who does not wish and pray that she may save many more? The Shakers believe
                                that both Jesus and Ann will save all who accept and practice the doctrine which they
                                taught. Those who will accept the virgin life of Jesus, and forsake houses, lands,
                                father, mother, brothers, sisters, wife and children for this, and the gospels' sake,
                                shall be saved hereafter, and I <pb n="137" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 137 was about
                                to say, better still, saved now, here in the present time, having been resurrected from
                                the dead works of the flesh. Such have laid the ax at the root of the tree, and put
                                aside the old man, Adam, who was of the earth earthy, and have put on the new man, the
                                second Adam, who is the Lord from heaven. Yea! they have become the new man having put
                                off the old man and his deeds, and marry not, neither are they given in marriage, but
                                are like the angels in heaven, being children of the resurrection. These have accepted
                                Jesus, as the Chri«t, or the anointed, and with him, have entered within the vail into
                                the innermost temple, the heaven within, set up upon earth. And while conceding to Jesus
                                and Ann to be the greatest Saviors the world ever had, but not the only ones, I have
                                seen many a sneer, and heard vulgar jokes and derisive laughter given in lieu of
                                argument, against the Shakers and their doctrine ; but seldom, if ever, have I met a
                                person who was well informed, that would allow himself to treat the subject with levity.
                                As Burns once said "An athiest's laugh is a poor exchange for Deity offended." So do I
                                consider the scoffs, the jeers, the ridicule and the refuge of lies resorted to, and
                                heaped upon the order, a very poor exchange for such logic as Eldress Doolittle, Elders
                                Evans and Vance, gave in Portland a few years since, which I had the pleasure to hear
                                and more recently have read in the Manifesto. Hoping there may be more than the hundred
                                and forty and four thousand, who will learn the song of deliverance spoken of in Rev.
                                xiv. 1, 2, 3, 4. 1 shall continue interested with you for the right, the truth, and for
                                the fair treatment of all opponents. Portland, Me.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is the providential arrangement, that some men shall sow the seed, and other men shall reap the harvests..." TEIform="index"/>
                                It is the providential arrangement, that some men shall sow the seed, and other men shall reap the harvests...
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Woodbury, Augustus" TEIform="persName"/>Augustus Woodbury</byline><p TEIform="p">It is the providential arrangement, that some men shall sow the seed, and other men shall
                                reap the harvests ; that some shall fight the battle, and others enjoy the fruits of
                                victory. It is the sign of human weakness, and perhaps of human ingratitude, that those
                                who reap and enjoy should forget those who sowed and fought.—Rev. , at the funeral of
                                George G. Fogg.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Van Valen, John" TEIform="index"/>John Van Valen</head><p TEIform="p">, at West Pittsfield, Mass., Apr. 27. Age, 74 yrs.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wells, Eliza" TEIform="index"/>Eliza Wells</head><p TEIform="p">, at Watervliet, N. Y. May 1. Age, 84 years, 9 mo. and 14 days. She was the daughter
                                    of Calvin and Betsy Wells, and is the last of the noted family of Wells, that were
                                    members of our Society. Her long life of strict adherence to the principles of
                                    Christianity, has been marked for its charity, humility and enduring fortitude.
                                    Patient under trials and always ready to assist others. She was a dearly beloved and
                                    praise worthy sister, and has now passed on to receive the reward of well doing.</p></div4></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is quite probable that..." TEIform="index"/>It is quite probable that...
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sawyer, Otis" TEIform="persName"/>Otis Sawyer</byline><p TEIform="p">It is quite probable that the following item may interest some of the rea.lers of the
                                Manifesto. In looking over the Record of Deaths in this Society, I was surprised at the
                                great age to which so many of our departed friends had attained. The demise of Richard
                                Donovan on the third of November 1881, completed a list of two hundred, dating back to
                                1790. One hundred of them were over seventy years old when they died. Thirty, seven were
                                from eighty to ninety, and thirteen were from ninety to ninety seven years old at the
                                time of their death. The average age of the two hundred is 62 years, 9 months, 6 days
                                and 2 hours. If there is any other Society of Believers, or a Community in the land that
                                can present a death rate like that during its existence, I would be pleased to see it
                                reported in the Manifesto. Alfred, Me. ") Apr. 6, 1882. / </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>Juvenile</head><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Motherless turkeys" TEIform="index"/>THE MOTHERLESS TURKEYS
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The white turkey was dead! The white turkey was dead!
                                        How the news through the barn-yard went flying! <pb n="138" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 138
                                        SHAKER MANIFESTO. Of a mother bereft, four small turkeys were left, And their
                                        case for assistance was crying. E'en the peacock respectfully folded his tail,
                                        As a suitable symbol of sorrow, And his plainer mate said, "now the old bird is
                                        dead, Who will tend the poor chicks on the morrow? And when evening around them
                                        comes dreary and chill Who above them will watchfully hover?" "Two each night I
                                        will tuck 'neath my wings,'1 said the duck, "Though I've eight of my own I must
                                        cover !" "I have so much to do! For the bugs and the worms, In the garden, 'tis
                                        tiresome pickin'; I've nothingto spare—for my own I must care," Said the hen
                                        with one chicken.j "How I wish," said the goose, "I could be of some use For my
                                        heart is with love over-brimming!'' The next morning that's fine, they shall go
                                        with my nine Little yellow-backed goslings, out swimming!" "I will do what 1
                                        can," the old dorking put in, "And for help they may call upon me too, Though
                                        I've ten of my own that are' only half grown, And a great deal of trouble to see
                                        to; But these poor little things, they are all head and wings, And their bones
                                        through their feathers are stickin'!" "Very hard it may be, but, oh, don't come
                                        to me!" Said the hen with one chicken. "Half my care I suppose, there is nobody
                                        knows, I'm the most overburdened of mothers! They must learn, little elves ! how
                                        to scratch for themselves, And not seek to depend upon others," She went by with
                                        a cluck, and the Goose to the duck Exclaimed with surprise, "Well, I never!"
                                        Said the Duck, "I declare, those who have the least care, You will rind are
                                        complaining forever ! And when all things appear to look threatening and drear
                                        And when troubles your pathway are thick in, For some aid in your woe, O, beware
                                        how you go To a hen witli one chicken,"</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Exchange" TEIform="index"/>Exchange.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Some Sunday-school children were taken for a picnic to the sea-side..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Some Sunday-school children were taken for a picnic to the sea-side...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Some Sunday-school children were taken for a picnic to the sea-side. One of the teachers
                                ask?d her scholars how they liked the sea. "Very much, miss," replied a child; "but
                                where are the tinnamies?" "The tinnamies, my child! What do you mean ?" "Why, you know,"
                                the child replied again, "the tinnamies that go with the sea. You know the Commandment
                                says, 'the sea and all the tinnamies.' " This was the way the child had been repeating
                                "the sea and all that in them is."</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Letter Box</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Village, N. H." TEIform="index"/>Shaker Village, N. H.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A." TEIform="persName"/>A.</byline><p TEIform="p">Shaker Village, N. H. My Dear Sister J. ;—It is a real privilege to write to you because
                                1 love you and I know that you take great pains to teach me and my companions nice
                                lessons about the Bible and as I expect to live so good and happy in my pretty Shaker
                                home, I want to learn all the good I can from the Bible and other good books. I want to
                                promise you that I will be very industrious and try as hard to learn, and be prompt with
                                my lessons as you are in teaching me. I am trying to be useful in other ways. Sister M.
                                is teaching me to be helpful; since I have lived with her I have learned to darn
                                stockings very nicely. Perhaps you will smile to hear a little girl praise herself but
                                last week I showed my work to Sister L. and she said it was neatly done, and she would
                                be willing to have it on her stocking; now if she said it was well, I guess you will
                                believe it. 1 want to promise you, dear Sister J. that I will try real hard to be a good
                                girl, and live kindly with all my little mates, so that you can love me and ever claim
                                me as your little sister. Lovingly. </p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Village, N. H. Mar. 1882" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Village, N. H. Mar. 1882</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Forest" TEIform="persName"/>Forest</byline><p TEIform="p">Shaker Village, N. H. Mar. 1882 Dear Sister Mary;—As I was going to write to you I
                                thought I would tell you that I am <pb n="139" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 139 trying
                                to be a good boy, so that I can become a good man and be like Br. William. I have
                                learned my text from the Bible .to repeat this evening, I hope you will come and see us
                                sometime in our Sabbath school. I have been to the sugar camp this week. It is two miles
                                from home. We have tapped all the trees and have been chopping wood. We have two yoke of
                                oxen. You must come to the Camp sometime. We had a good time playing hide and seek. I
                                drove a yoke of oxen and they hauled a log to the Camp; the oxen had hard work to pull
                                the log through the snow. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>House-hold</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Air" TEIform="index"/>AIR</head><p TEIform="p">or the atmosphere we breathe, is, in its purity, composed of twenty three parts of oxygen
                                and seventy seven parts of nitrogen, but it contains particles which do not naturally
                                belong to it. In a damp day the air is full of water or fog, and a pint of it may not
                                contain more than three-fourths of a pint of air ; and as the atmosphere is the thing
                                which acts directly on the blood in the lungs, to withdraw from it all the impurities
                                which it contains, the purer the air is the more capable is it of absorbing the
                                impurities of the blood, and the purer the blood the better the health enjoyed in all
                                climes and countries. The purest air is out of doors. There is no pure air within any
                                four walls of a house. You may go into any room, even if it is entirely empty, and a
                                musty or close smell will be immediately observed, much more will there be impurities in
                                the air of our dwellings in proportion to the decaying or odorous things in it—as slops
                                ; food, fruits, flowers and the like. That air is best for the health which has no
                                perceptible "smell" about it. The fragrance of the rose and the pink are delicious; but
                                if a person were to sleep in a close room in which there were a great many pinks and
                                roses he would be nearly dead next morning, because the nature of the flowers is such
                                that they are throwing off' a multitude of odorous particles every instant, and they
                                being more material, more solid than the air, displace it, so that in every breath there
                                is less air taken into the lungs and more of the substance of the flowers.— Dr. HalVs
                                Health at home.</p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pickles" TEIform="index"/>Pickles</head><p TEIform="p"> —"An excellent way to make pickles which will keep a year or more is^ drop them into
                                boiling hot water, but not to boil them; let them stay ten minutes, wipe them dry, then
                                drop them into cold spiced vinegar. They will not need to be put into salt and
                            water."</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A strong, good-sized table..." TEIform="index"/>A strong, good-sized table...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A strong, good-sized table is almost a necessity in the cellar. Jars that are too heavy
                                to be lifted on and off shelves may be set on the table. Many cellars are sometimes
                                infested with ants and other bugs. One way to keep them from crawling over the jars is
                                to take the tin-cans in which peaches or tomatoes come, set the legs of the table in the
                                cans, and fill them half full of water.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Receptacle for soiled linen" TEIform="index"/>Receptacle For Soiled Linen</head><p TEIform="p"> .—Take an ordinary flour barrel, line it with paper muslin, and on the outside cover it
                                with cretonne laid in dox plaits. Around the top finish with a lambrequin made of turkey
                                red, with cretonne flowers transferred on the center of each point. Cover the lid with
                                cretonne inside and out, and put a full plaiting of the same around the edge. For the
                                handle on top use an iron trunk-handle. By leaving the handle off the top, and having
                                the lid made large enough to fit over instead of the ordinary way, the barrel can stand
                                in a rooir, and be used for a table.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A little soap lather mixed with..." TEIform="index"/>A little soap lather mixed with...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A little soap lather mixed with starch will prevent the flat-irons from sticking on the
                                linen and gives the gloss so conspicuously absent from the ordinary home-laundried
                                article. It is easily tried.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A piece of cork, about the size of a jugcork is recommended as..." TEIform="index"/>
                                A piece of cork, about the size of a jugcork is recommended as...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A piece of cork, about the size of a jugcork is recommended as perhaps the best thing for
                                scouring knives with. It is both stiff* and flexible, and the knives are polished with
                                very little exertion.</p></div3></div2><pb n="140" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>Farm and Garden</head><div3 type="equipment" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home-made roller" TEIform="index"/>A HOME-MADE ROLLER</head><p TEIform="p">The Agriculturist gives the following description of a simple roller : Cut a log into
                                sections, two feet long, that it may be more readily turned round. The log should be at
                                least two feet in diameter, of heavy wood, such as oak or hard maple, and the sections
                                should be sawed v ry true, so that the ends will work freely and not bind against each
                                other. The sections are bored through the center with an auger an inch and
                                three-quarters in diameter, and the holes should be bored from each end to the middle,
                                where they should meet; they can be made more true in this way than by boring through
                                from one end. The axle is an iron rod of one and a half inch diameter. Washers, half an
                                inch thick, should be placed between the sections. The frame should be made of heavy
                                stuff, at least four inches square, so as to gain weight and a driver's seat may be on.
                                When built, the sections should be raised from the ground, and planed smooth and
                            true.</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cows" TEIform="index"/>The Cows</head><p TEIform="p">.—Treat them generously and kindly, but do not keep them fat unless they are to be turned
                                off for beef. A cow is a machine, a laboratory for converting raw materials into milk.
                                If little be given, little will be received. All animals should have exercise,
                                especially those kept for breeding. Some of them are naturally lazy, but they will be
                                the better for stirring about in the open air.</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Charcoal for fowls" TEIform="index"/>CHARCOAL FOR FOWLS</head><p TEIform="p">There is one thing which nature does not supply, and which civilization renders quite
                                necessary to fowls. It is charcoal. Charcoal of wood does not answer the purpose. But if
                                any one will put an ear of ripe corn into the fire until the-grains are well charred,
                                and then shell off the corn and throw it to the flock, he will see an eagerness
                                developed and a healthy constitution brought about which will make a decided
                                improvement, and the average yield of eggs greatly increased.</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kindness in horse training" TEIform="index"/>Kindness in horse training</head><p TEIform="p">.—Nothing contributes so much in modifying high temper in animals, or in the enhancement
                                oi their physical beauty and powers of productiveness—as the case may be—than good
                                treatment and patient kindness. Prof Wagner, speaking of its effect in the training of
                                young horses, says : Many think they are doing finely, and are proud of their success in
                                horse training, by means of severe whipping, or otherwise arousing and stimulating the
                                passions, and then crushing the will through which the resistance is prompted. No
                                mistake can be greater than this, and there is nothing that so fully exhibits the
                                ability, judgment and skill of the real horseman, as the care displayed in winning
                                instead of repelling the action of the mind.—Exchange.</p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Preserving harness" TEIform="index"/>PRESERVING HARNESS</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The first point to be observed is to keep the leather soft and pliable. This
                                        can be done only by keeping it well charged with oil and grease. Water is a
                                        destroyer of each of these ; but mud and saline moisture from the animal are
                                        even more destructive. Mud, in drying, absorbs the grease and opens the pores of
                                        the Lleather, making it a ready prey to water; while the salty character of the
                                        perspiration from the animal injures the leather, stitching and mounting. It,
                                        therefore, follows that, to preserve a harness, the straps should be washed and
                                        oiled at intervals as required. To do this effectually, the straps should all be
                                        unbuckled and detached, and washed with warm,-soft water and crown soap, and
                                        hung by a slow fire or in the sun until nearly dry, then, coated with a mixture
                                        of neatsfoot oil and tallow and allowed to remain in a warm room for several
                                        hours, and when perfectly dry rub thoroughly with a woolen rag. The rubbing is
                                        important, as it in addition to removing the surplus oil and grease, tends to
                                        close the pores and give a finish to the leather. In hanging harness, care
                                        should be taken to allow all the straps to hang their full length. Light is
                                        essential to the care of leather, and when the harness closet is dark the door
                                        should be left open at least half the time during the day. All closets should be
                                        well ventilated and, when possible, be well lighted. To clean plated mountings,
                                        use a chamois with a little tripoli or rotten stone. But they should be scoured
                                        as little as possible.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Harness journal" TEIform="index"/>Harness Journal.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><pb n="141" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books and papers" TEIform="index"/>Books and papers</head><p TEIform="p">Phrenological Journal ; May; Pub. by Fowler &amp; Wells, 755 Broadway, N. Y.
                                Contents; Henry W. Longfellow.— With portrait.—-The Poet of America of whom it is said.
                                "His life was gentle ; and the elements so mixed in him that Nature might stand up and
                                say to all the world. 'This was a man!'" Phrenology &amp; Pestalorzianism. Our
                                Weather System. Illustrated. Flowers and seedless Plants, Illustrated. Knowledge of the
                                World. Touching matters Chirographical. A portrait Gallery of Confederate Celebrities.
                                Prophetic Dreams. Indigestion, Its causes and remedy. Cow pox,—What it is. Kitchen
                                leaflets. Poetry. Notes in Science and Agriculture. Editorial Items, etc. etc. See
                                Advertisement in an other column. Hall's Journal of Health; April; Pub. by E. H. Gibbs,
                                A. M., M. D. 141 Eighth St. N. Y. Contents. Health and Habit. Cold Catching. Ventilation
                                anrl fresh Air. Animal Combustion. A Clergyman's Congregation. What is Patent Flour?
                                Particles in the Eye. Consumption. Drinking at Meals. To bring up children. Health
                                Employments. Spitting Blood. Liquor Drinking. Cold Bathing. Pure Food. Exercise, etc.
                                etc. Terms, $2.00 a year. $1.00 for six months. Single copy, 20 cts. The St. Louis
                                Magazine for April is an especially good number. The fact that it has lived as a
                                Representative Western Publication for 13years is much in its favor and judging from the
                                April number it appears now as one of the prosperous magazines of the day. It is
                                handsomely illustrated, full of good original Stories, Poems and Timely reading and
                                contains besides an illustrated fashion article which is well worth the subscription
                                price. For 10 cents the publishers will send a beautiful set of picture cards and sample
                                copy of the Magazine to any address for inspection. Address St. Louis Magazine Company,
                                213 N", 8th St., St. Louis, Mo. Herald or Health : May; Pub. by M. L. IIolbrook, 13
                                &amp; 15Laight St.,N. Y. Contents; Food and Education; Reform for Criminal Girls;
                                Fasting in Rheumatism; Glucose; Cai bolic Acid in Diphtheria; Gymnastics in schools;
                                Consumption ; Salt and other Condiments; Fats; Health hints for May and June; Milk from
                                sick Cows; Woman's dress; Warts, etc. Terms, $1.00 per year. Single copy, 10 cts. The
                                following are among the contents of the May number of The Homiletio Monthly :— Sermonic
                                : The Spiritual Building, "A Dedication Service," by R. Kogel, D. D., translated by Rev.
                                Prof. J. C. Brodfuhrer; "The Mormon Question," by J. P. Newman, D. D.; "The Natural
                                Immortality of the Human Soul," by Canon II. P. Liddon, D. D.; "Christ's Salutation to
                                the Christian," A Communion Service, by James L. Ludlow, D. D.; "The Intercession of
                                Christ," by W. Ormiston, D. D.; "Is the Free-Pew System a Failure?" by Justin D. Fulton,
                                D.D.; "The Upward Look," by Joseph Parker, D. D. Among other very suggestive papers, are
                                the following : "Misquoted Scriptures," by Talbot W. Chambers, D. D.; "Light on
                                Important Texts," by Howard Crosby, D. D., LL. D.; "Nine Months' Vacation of City
                                Churches," by Rev. W. F. Crafts; "Lectures to my Students," by Charles H. Spurgeon. Then
                                there is a large quantity of matter under the heads, "Hints at the Meaning of Texts;"
                                "Sermonic Criticism;" "Preachers Exchanging Views," "Queries and Answers," etc. This
                                Monthly is of special value to Clergymen and Bible S.udents. Price, $2.50, per year;
                                single number, 25 cents. Funk &amp; Wagnalls, 10 &amp; 12 Dey Street, New York.
                                SOME CHOICE BOOKS OF WIT AND HUMOR. The book-buying public will certainly be delighted,
                                even if the, old-line publishers are disgusted, with the work The Useful Knowledge
                                Publishing Company, of New York, is doing. The}' are just issuing a number of works of
                                the choicest grade of wit and humor. One, "Studies in Stanzas, Tints for the Times,
                                Ballads, and Broadsides," is by Orpheus C. Kerr, than whom no American humorous writer
                                has won worthier fame. For keen wit, scathing satire, deep laid, mysterious plot, purity
                                and nobility of thought, and rollicking, healthy, hearty fun, he is quite without a
                                rival in his varied brilliant accomplishments. The millions of the American people who
                                have in times past laughed at his inimitable productions will give his new book most
                                hearty welcome. It is issued in a charming little volume at the usual marvelously low
                                prices of The IT. K. P. Co., Utility Binding, 20 cts., Extra cloth, 30 cts., Half
                                Russia, 40 cts. At the same time they publish, each in a large 12 mo. volume of nearly
                                800 pages, the complete works of the inimitable wit and essayist, Charles Lamb, the
                                Choice Works of the incomparable Irish Humorist, Tom Hood, and the Choice Works of Dean
                                Swift, whose quality of wit is. without its like in the world's literature. All these
                                are books which naturally belong in every man's library. Enterprising booksellers supply
                                them, and the publishers want club agents and canvassers in every county and town, to
                                whom very unusual terms and facilities are given.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bronchitis" TEIform="index"/>Bronchitis</head><p TEIform="p"> .—A simple recipe, which affords relief in ordinary cases of bronchitis, is to occasionally
                            suck a small piece of common saltpeter as you would candy, and swallow the juice. If the
                            case be severe, medical advice should be had without delay. The animosities are mortal, but
                            the humanities live forever.</p></div2><pb n="142" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>Select</head><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Duty and privilege" TEIform="index"/>DUTY AND PRIVILEGE</head><p TEIform="p">People seem to have very mixed ideas of duty and privilege. In the first place, they seem
                                to think there are more duties than privileges; in the second place, that it is harder
                                to discharge the former than to enjoy the latter ; and in the third place, that these
                                are quite opposite, if not contrary, things. Each of these propositions is false. There
                                are a hundred things to enjoy where there is one to do. It is difficult to enjoy our
                                privileges, because they are not always perceived to be privileges, and most of us have
                                accustomed ourselves to pull in the harness of duty. We have contracted the habit of
                                making ourselves do what we ought to do. We feel as if there was something glorious in
                                that. We praise ourselves and others, and expect ourselves to be praised, for doing
                                duty. We are all the while magnifying duty. All heroism seems to consist in doing duty.
                                And that is right. But we do not accustom ourselves to enjoy our privileges, and that is
                                wrong. AVe do not blame a man if he permit a proper enjoyment. We do not blame him if he
                                omit a manifest duty. More than all that, so far from being antagonistic, we cannot long
                                study either one or the other without coming to perceive that there is no duty incumbent
                                on man which it is really not a privilege to discharge, and there is no enjoyment
                                possible to man which it is not his duty in some sense to possess. We forget that all
                                existence is the gift of our heavenly Father. If we could only always remember that, how
                                it would change the color of our entire life; we should cease to drag ourselves to the
                                discharge of duty. We should cease to regard life as a hardship because it has its
                                duties.— The Watchman.</p></div3><div3 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Woman as an inventor" TEIform="index"/>Woman as an Inventor</head><p TEIform="p">.—It is mentioned, inter alia, that women obtain from the II. S. Government an average of
                                about sixty patents yearly; seventy is the number for the year ending July, 1880. As
                                might be expected, most of them relate to lightening women's work. Among them are a
                                jar-lifter, a bagholder, a pillow-sham holder, a dress protector, two dust-pans, a
                                washing machine, a fluting iron, a dress chart, a fish-boner, a sleeve adjuster, a
                                lap-table, a sewing-machine treadle, a wash-basin, an iron-heater, sad irons,
                                garnient-stiffener, a folding chair, a ward-robe bed, a window-cleaner, a napkin, a
                                clothes-pin, a weather-strip, a churn, an invalids bed, a strainer, a milk-cooler, a
                                sofabed, a dipper, a paper dish, and a plaiting device. In a recent patent law-suit, a
                                woman (Helen M. McDonald) conducted her own case and won it, establishing her right to
                                her skirt-protector, planting an injunction on a bold infringement, and utterly routing
                                one of the most distinguished of the patent-law barristers.—Exchange.</p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Make somebody glad" TEIform="index"/>MAKE SOMEBODY GLAD
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pierce, Rebecca R." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Rebecca R. Pierce. On life's rugged road, As we journey
                                        each day, Far, far more of sunshine Would brighten the way, If forgetful of self
                                        And our troubles we had The will, and would try To make other hearts glad.
                                        Though of the world's wealth, We've a little in store, And labor to keep Grim
                                        want from the door, With a hand that is kind, And a heart that is true, To make
                                        others glad There is much we may do. A. word kindly spoken, A smile or a tear,
                                        Though seeming but trifles, Full often may cheer. Each day to our lives Some
                                        pleasure t'would add, To be conscious that we Had made somebody glad. Those who
                                        sit in the darkness Of sorrow, so drear, Have need of a word Of solace and
                                        cheer. <pb n="143" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 143 There are homes that are
                                        desolate, Hearts that are sad— Do something for some one, Make somebody glad.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="West chronicle" TEIform="index"/>West Chronicle</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Truth" TEIform="index"/>Truth</head><p TEIform="p">.—Truth will never die; the stars will grow dim; the sun will pale his glory, but truth
                                will be forever young. Integrity, uprightness, honesty, love and goodness, these are all
                                imperishable. No grave can ever entomb these immortal principles. They have been
                                imprisoned, but they have been freer than before ; those who have enshrined them in
                                their hearts have been burned at the stake, but out of their ashes other witnesses have
                                arisen. No sea can drown, no storm can wreck, no abyss can swallow up the ever-living
                                truth of God. You cannot kill goodness and truth and integrity and faith and holiness ;
                                the way that is consistent with these must be a way everlasting.—Spurgeon.</p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What foods are most economical!" TEIform="index"/>WHAT FOODS ARE MOST ECONOMICAL!</head><p TEIform="p">With an advance of 20 to 100 per cent., and more, in the price of staple foods, the above
                                is now a most important question to over 40 millions of our people, and one of much
                                interest to seven or eight millions more. Probably there are not two millions who take
                                no thought or care as to the cost ;&gt;f their daily diet. Meats, flour, potatoes,
                                cornmeal and rcilk are the main articles of sustenance for the great masses. Fish, rice,
                                beans, and oat-meal (recently), with lesser amounts of some other articles, are
                                consumed; but these altogether do not, we judge, constitute one-tenth of the food of the
                                entire people, perhaps not more than five or six per cent. Dried or smoked beef, ham and
                                cheese rank high, but dried fish outranks all others. The nuitritive value of dried
                                codfish is remarkable, and it deserves special attention, 100 lbs. of it supplying as
                                much nuitriment as 341 lbs. of beef! It is cheap and abundant everywhere, because very
                                portable, and easily kept. It yields labor-sustaining aliment at from one-third down to
                                one-ninth of the cost of beef in different sections of the country. It is easily
                                digestible, and if properly freshened and cooked, it can be made palatable and
                                acceptable to a very large class needing to practise economy.—American
                            Agriculturist.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Grumblers" TEIform="index"/>Grumblers</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Chronic grumblers are pests from which the Church may well pray to be
                                        delivered, especially if they grumble with a serene confidence in their own
                                        superior sanctity, under shelter of their own groundless assumptions. As long as
                                        they sit in their bomb-proof of self-complacency, and seold at the Lord's
                                        workers through some convenient hole, it is useless to answer them with facts or
                                        arguments. They are too good to do anything themselves, and as nobody else does
                                        anything to suit them, they grumble for their own glory. Well, let them enjoy
                                        themselves !</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Evangelical messenger" TEIform="index"/>Evangelical Messenger</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Iron bar" TEIform="index"/>An Iron Bar</head><p TEIform="p">.—A bar of iron worth .$5.00 worked into horse shoes is worth .$10.50, made into knife
                                blades, is worth 832 85, made into balance springs for watches, is wortli $250,000, What
                                a drilling the poor iron bar must undergo to reach all that; but hammered and beaten,
                                pounded, rolled, rubbed and polished, how was its value increased! And so all the
                                drilling and training to vhieh you are subject, all the trials and hardships, thumps and
                                pains which often seem so hard to you, serve to draw out the finer qualities, and fit
                                you for greater and more responsible posts in the world.—N. H. Statesman.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Every man is a missionary" TEIform="index"/>Every man is a missionary
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Every man is a missionary now and forever, for good or for evil, whether he intern's or
                                designs it or not. He may be a blot, radiating his dark influence outward to the very
                                circumference of society; or he may be a blessing, spreading benedictions over the
                                length and.breadth of the world; but a blank he cannot be. There are no moral blanks;
                                there are no neutral characters. We are either the sower that sows and corrupts, or the
                                light that splendidly illuminates, and the salt that silently operates ; but being dead
                                or alive, every man speaks.-CM. Union.</p></div3></div2><pb n="144" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Recompense" TEIform="index"/>RECOMPENSE</head><p TEIform="p"> Canterbury, N. H. 1. The beautiful gifts of the spirit Are treasures I 2. I'm finding these
                            treasures iminortal. And sing in the 8. I on]y surrender the worldly, And joys of the I
                            covet as mine; I'll earnestly seek to inherit The wealth of the joy of my soul; Their glory
                            in creasing forever, New powers, new spirit abound; I only pray earnestly, humbly, And
                            angels are kingdom divine. This earth hath no textlire, no visions un fold. I banish a .
                            thought that is hovring around. I know that the channels are tinting, Which hastre or beauty
                            afford, Like that of the ovil, And purity reigns in my heart; Its sweetness is Open, From
                            earth to the heavenly land; For while the true spiritual graces We fashion in serving the
                            Lord, cheering and precious, I pray that it ne'er may depart, kingdom we're gaining,
                            Supplies amply meet the demand.</p></div2><pb id="p29" TEIform="pb"/><!--                     <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>