<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2512" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">28</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">East Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">25</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">12</biblScope><date value="18951201" TEIform="date">December 1895</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">267-290</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="25" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="12" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
DECEMBER.
THE
MANIFESTO
PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES.
VOL. XXV.
" Cast tht brkad upon the waters ; for thou shalt find it after many days."
Eccl. XI: i.
East Canterbury, N. H.
1895.
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
THE
This  is an American   Stem-winder,   up to date.    It represents  the  most important step taken in watch evolution in many years.    It describes a line beyond
which nothing radical will pass for years, not only in the matter of price, but quality
Two styles.   Grilt and niclcel,   Snap  back, Bevel crystal,
Stem 8efc   Fully timed and regulated.
For $2.00 we will  send the Watch   ar>d also a copy of The Manifesto for one
year, to any address in the U. S.          Address
The   Manifesto.
EAST    CANTERBURY,    N.    H.
AUTHORIZED RULES
THE   SHAKER   0OMMUNITY,
The religious Jbasis of the Order must
be a foundation resting on the principle of
righteousness, which principle is God.
This should rule the life of the individ
ual for the protection of his own sojul, for
the peace of the family and as an evidence
of his upright standing before the world.
Price, 10 cts.
BRIEF EXPOSITION
OF THE
Principles and Regulations
of the
SOCIETY   OW   BELIEVERS.
Price, 10 cts.
"INTERPRETING PROPHECY"
AND   THE
"Appearing of Christ,"
is the title of a neat little pamphlet of
some forty pages, just sent out by A. G.
Holi.ister of Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.
The many at the present time who are
interested in the fulfillment of prophecy
and in its mathematical calculation, will
find themselves by the side of the good
old prophet Daniel, and with him illus
trating the Coming of Christ so clearly
that no occasion can arise for the least
doubt.                             Price, 10 cts.
CLIMAX
OF--><pb n="267" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Passing away" TEIform="index"/>PASSING AWAY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, Catherine" TEIform="persName"/>By Catherine Allen.</byline><p TEIform="p">A NOTHER year is wrapping itself in burial garments and soon will have JT\_ gone to slumber
                            in "Time's ancient sepulchre;"that unknown and measureless period called the Past. Another
                            chapter in the history of the universe has been written, and, on the memory chambers of each
                            individual soul are indellibly impressed the griefs and joys, the struggles and conquests,
                            and those deep interior feelings, which like the subteranean stream, bear no outward tokens
                            of their coursings. But there is an Eye that pierceth unto the deepest caverns of the heart;
                            an Ear that hearest the faintest whispering of the soul; and there is a judgment seat
                            whereunto the inmost thoughts and motives shall be brought. But God's justice is tempered
                            with his mercy an d souls who know his love can feel no fear. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God's true witnesses" TEIform="index"/>GOD'S TRUE WITNESSES.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bowers, Lucy S." TEIform="persName"/>By Lucy S: Bowers.</byline><p TEIform="p">"Acquaint thyself with God if thou would'st taste His works. Admitted once to his embrace,
                            Thou shalt perceive that thou wast blind before, Thine eyes shall be instructed, and thine
                            heart Made pure, shall relish, with divine delight Till then unfelt, what hands divine have
                            wrought." GOD'S light and truth are eternal; from time immemorial they have ex isted, and
                            through a glorious future will continue to live; they have been felt and known in the hearts
                            of all races of mankind in different degrees from the beginning, increasing in fulness of
                            revelation according to the dispensation and spiritual capacity of the people. DECEMBER <pb n="268" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 268 THE MANIFESTO. In all ages there have been spiritual heroes, those
                            who have defended with their lives, the cause of right; having received a baptism that
                            revealed to them the presence of surrounding evils, the harm of false creeds, and the
                            necessity of an increase of moral development they had to contend against opposing
                            multitudes and stand and work alone, truly such are God's mediators. It has been with many
                            as it was with Jesus who said ;"If I be lifted up, I will draw all men unto me." Glory and
                            honor to those who can thus endure the test! "Out of suffering have ever emerged the
                            strongest souls; the most massive characters are seamed with scars : martyrs have put on
                            their coronation robes glittering with fire, and through tears have the sorrowful first seen
                            the gate of heaven." Behold the uplifted cross on which the courageous would not recant; the
                            dungeon cells in which God-loving hearts would not faint; think of the gardens of
                            Gethsemane, the holy Mounts and lonely wildernesses from which have arisen the prayers of
                            everlasting faith. "Not a truth has to art or to science been given, But brows have ached
                            for it, and souls toiled and striven." This is the testimony of all whose consciences have
                            led them on, who for truth's sake have submitted themselves a full consecration. Such may
                            have the satisfaction of knowing, as some writer has expressed it, that "what subsists
                            to-day by violence, continues to-morrow by acquiesence and is perpetuated by tradition, till
                            at last the hoary head of abuse shakes the gray hairs of antiquity at us and gives itself
                            out as the wisdom of the ages." Among these sterling characters who have received divine
                            revelation and become living witnesses for God, is the founder of our organization ; a woman
                            whom we do not worship but whose memory we cherish with de^p aud profound love, and of whom
                            we often speak. Having been shown the depth of human loss she determined to make restoration
                            of purity, and liberty from the thralldom of sin in her own soul and teach and lead others;
                            "He that overcometh has power in the nations." He that reigns within himself and rules
                            passions, desires and fears is more than a king. "Jesus took the human to exhale an
                            atmosphere of God that should fill and finally renew creation, bathing all climes and times
                            and ages with its ineradicable power." This same atmosphere through the spiritual powers of
                            Ann Lee has been re-exhaled and renewed, and is destined to bathe all climes and bring into
                            perfection the lives of all mankind. Prominent among the teachings of this inspired woman,
                            exceeding in beauty and outreaching all former comprehensions was the sublime idea of the
                            maternal spirit in Deity. "How much he knew of the human heart who first called God, Our
                            Father;" how much she knew of the human heart who first called God, Our Mother.
                            Intelligence, power, majesty, protectionlove, pity, tenderness, sympathy, these combined
                            reveal duality;Our Heavenly Parentage. Not, Father God and Mother Earth, for every circling
                            star is <pb n="269" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 269 controlled by dual forces and so is
                            everything mineral, vegetable or animal upon the earth. "Sweet is the image of the brooding
                            Dove! Holy as Heaven, a Mother's tender love!" Love is the crowning grace of humanity ; the
                            holiest right of the soul; the redeeming principle, and is prophetic of eternal good. When
                            this idea is fully received and practically demonstrated by the controlling minds in the
                            land, then will the governmental and ecclesiastical arrangements of society be rightly
                            proportioned and improved. Ann Lee taught and renewed the principle of oral confession of
                            sin, true repentance of, and conscientious abstinence therefrom. She taught virgin purity
                            which should elevate souls above the plane of generation into the sphere of angelic holiness
                            where they could mingle and commingle their gifts with the holy hosts of heaven and enjoy
                            while on earth salvation and peace. A modern exhorter has felt the divinity of this truth
                            and expressed it in these words; "In the power of the Spirit of God we realize the oneness
                            of the church both in heaven and in earth, and the spirits of just men and women made
                            perfect are in union with us. No gulf divides the militant from the triumphant; we are one
                            army of the living God. We sometimes speak of the holy dead, but there are none such; they
                            live unto God." Ann Lee had a few followers and friends, as did Jesus, his disciples; all of
                            whom were stigmatized as fanatics and suffered trials, persecution and imprisonment. When
                            they left their homes on the transatlantic they saw nothing before but a weary waste of
                            waters, and a new -country beyond, but were led on by the light of the promise of God on
                            which they firmly relied. Under the rule of a free government the way opened and in that
                            faith that is mighty to overcome they conquered all inward and outward foes and conditions
                            and founded indeed a new order. "The truth can not be burned, beheaded or crucified. A lie
                            on the throne is a lie still; and truth in a dungeon is truth still; and the lie on the
                            throne is on the way to defeat, and truth in the dungeon is on the way to victory." It is
                            good to follow in the well-beaten track of self-denial and moral heroism, not with blind
                            credulity, but with minds of understanding to carry on the work of righteousness wisely,
                            earnestly as others have done, and thus be able to bequeath to future generations an
                            increased heritage of glory. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="When we are lifted..." TEIform="index"/>When we are lifted...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">When we are lifted into the realm of spiritual thought and feeling, no duty is distasteful,
                            for we then feel that they are ah1 divinely appointed, each a stepping-stone on life's
                            journey. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, C." TEIform="persName"/>G. Allen.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Honesty is the square..." TEIform="index"/>Honesty is the square...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Honesty is the square, by the application of which, we may know the correct angles of life.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Staples, L." TEIform="persName"/>L. Staples.</byline></div2><pb n="270" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harmony of thought" TEIform="index"/>HARMONY OF THOUGHT.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="DeGraw, Hamilton" TEIform="persName"/>By Hamilton DeGraw.</byline><p TEIform="p">TT^HE world's "Congress of Religions" held in Chicago in 1893, was for JL the purpose of
                            bringing together the discordant views in religious matters and causing them to work
                            harmoniously in the endeavor to uplift mankind to a higher plane of thought than the one now
                            occupied. The one whom the Christian world looks to as their supreme example and pattern
                            gave a clear and definite statment of what constituted religion in its most comprehensive
                            meaning,"Pure religion and undefiled before God and the Father is this; to visit the
                            fatherless and widows in their affliction and keep himself unspotted from the world." Is it
                            possible to bring about a perfect spirit of concord in the religious thought of mankind? We
                            think it is, and may say that we know it is, judging from the advance that has already been
                            made; but not by an entire obliteration of the diversity of thought and independent line of
                            action that is needed to keep up the different degrees of growth from the apparently
                            discordant of now, into the more perfectly harmonious future. In civilized society are
                            needed numerous departments or offices to make the wheels run smoothly as it would be
                            impossible for one finite mind to grasp the whole universe. But there need be no discord,
                            for harmony can rule even this diversity. It is the goal of attainment that commands the
                            soul's energies ; that quickens the pulse, and causes us to struggle with the powers of
                            darkness that overshadow and enshroud the soul in its primitive, undeveloped state, although
                            the line of action pursued may be as varied as each individual entity, in matters of detail.
                            An anonymous writer has written a work entitled "The Gospel in Pagan Religions ;" It being a
                            review of the work done and views advanced by the delegates of the so-called Pagan religions
                            at the "Congress of Religions." We exclaim with Galileo, "The world moves." Fifty years ago
                            conceit and self-righteous assumption would have made it impossible for any one out of the
                            circle of orthodoxy to have had a hearing if advocating contrary views of the religious duty
                            of man, yet at the present time the fact is being conceded that there is not, and can not be
                            a monopoly of the truth. Here is what the author has to say. "There is back of all the great
                            ethnic religions the universal religion which infuses into them all a soul saving stream of
                            the waters of life." Our spiritual exampler has told us, "except your righteousness shall
                            exceed the righteousness of the Scribes and Pharisees ye shall in no wise enter into the
                            kingdom of heaven." And except the so-called Christian nations have something of more
                            practical value, that gives a higher tone of thought and makes that thought felt for the
                            betterment of human conditions, the claims <pb n="271" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 271 of
                            superiority are but a sham, and the professions are as but "sounding brass and a tinkling
                            symbol." The religious thought of the world is becoming more critical, demanding not merely
                            a blind faith in dogmas that in their very best estate were nothing but the shell of a
                            profession and at present the soul life has departed leaving them to become death masks
                            burdening and retarding the quickened spirit in its struggles after the living bread and
                            waters of life. In the construction of immense armaments of war, inventors steadily make
                            improvements that are rendering them more terrific and horrible in their deatli dealing, and
                            Christian (?) nations take the lead. We do not write with the spirit of the pessimist
                            believing that the tide of human progress is ebbing; not by any means. Slowly but surely,
                            through a mighty struggle against demoniac forces in man, the higher life,the promptings of
                            his better nature are calling him upward to leave the animal and sensuous as not worthy of
                            his companionship. In this struggle to attain unto the goal of human redemption from the
                            influences that draw us downward there is no sect or party, but "all who fear G-od and work
                            righteousness are accepted." Here is what the Divine Spirit through the medium of some of
                            the advanced Hindu teachers have given their people. "I am in every religion as the thread
                            through a string of pearls, and wherever thou seest extraordinary holiness and extraordinary
                            power, raising and purifying humanity know ye that I am there." When the holy spirit at the
                            time of the Pentecostal baptism descended upon the multitude and in tongues of fire
                            proclaimed the truth of the Brotherhood of man, it made those assembled with their different
                            nationalities and beliefs "of one accord," so that none could say they held in a selfish
                            sense the blessings granted to them, but only as stewards they used them for the good of the
                            whole world as occasion required. Would that the closing years of the nineteenth century
                            with its strikes, lockouts and enforced labor unions, compelled from necessity to combine
                            for protection against rapaciousness of the modern Shylocks, could receive a baptism of that
                            divine Spirit poured out in its fullness, making them realize the superiority of the divine
                            Brotherhood over the barbaric strife at present existing. But mankind must suffer until it
                            is weary of the senseless strife of factions and classes, and is ready to accept the truth.
                            We will work and wait for the blessed harvest. Shakers, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Faithfulness sits not with extended hands..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Faithfulness sits not with extended hands...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Faithfulness sits not with extended hands to receive jewels for its own crown, but patiently
                            gathers the diamond dust that falls from the workman's tools, until her whole garment
                            glitters in its brightness.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Staples, L." TEIform="persName"/>L. Staples.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sin obscures the light..." TEIform="index"/>Sin obscures the light...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Sin obscures the light of man's noblest faculties.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., M. J." TEIform="persName"/> M. J. A.</byline></div2><pb n="272" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Friendship" TEIform="index"/>FRIENDSHIP.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, Isabella" TEIform="persName"/>By Isabella Bussell.</byline><p TEIform="p">True Friendship ! what a sacred trust To hold unharmed, through time and change; Whatever
                            joys, or ills betide ; To keep within our vislon*s range. That star so beautiful and bright,
                            Which through all ages should endure, A solace kind, a beacon light To guide us on to paths
                            more pure. And yet, alas ! how oft this tie Is broken by an unkind word, And hearts that
                            once were pure and true Unto their deepest depths, are stirred With jealousy and cruel hate
                            Engendering deeds of vice and erime Befitting more, the beasts of prey Than man, the human,
                            the divine^ Who, then would willingly forego, The pleasure, which true friendship brings, Or
                            sacrifice life's higher joys, For lower, baser, meaner things ? *Tis love alone can conquer
                            hate, And light the darkness comprehend, While error vanishes from sight, As truth's
                            effulgent beams extend. Then let us strive while life remains To cultivate these graces
                            rare, To work and toil for other's good, And in their joys and sorrows share. To scatter
                            blessings by the v/ay, As on our upward march we go, Will make the journey seem less drear,
                            And help assuage another's woe, We may not always know the cause, That fills another's heart
                            with pain \. Far wiser, then indeed, for us From words of censure to refrain:. And who can
                            tell the grand results. Arising from our lives below ? Tf all our energies are bent, In
                            doing good where'er we go. Enfield, N. H,</p></div2><pb n="273" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Follow me" TEIform="index"/>FOLLOW ME</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="York, Elsie B." TEIform="persName"/>By Elsie B. York.</byline><p TEIform="p">T I THOUGH centuries have passed since our Savior uttered these words in _1_ person to a few
                            men in humble circumstances, who immediately responded to his call, they are heard no less
                            effectually to-day. Although we have not Jesus of Nazareth in our midst, his words and works
                            remain with ns. Many hear the call, not from a personal Savior, present with us, but in the
                            still small voice pleading with us that we may follow in the path that will lead to Christ's
                            kingdom. The question would naturally arise in the mind,follow where, how and for what
                            purpose? If Jesus Christ was the Resurrection and the Life, as he asserted that he was, in
                            following his example we may gain admittance into the kingdom of heaven. Shortly before his
                            death he said to his disciples, "I go to prepare a place for you, that where I am there ye
                            may be also." We infer from this, that even In the Spirit world he was called to lead the
                            way for others to follow. Having commenced a new order of life in this world, in a future
                            state there must also be a new place prepared for such as follow his life and example. Jesus
                            tells us that "The kingdom of God is within you," yet we believe there is a place reserved
                            for those who "love him and keep his commandments." "Order is heaven's first law." Admitting
                            this, it seems reasonable to believe that in the heavens, as on the earth, we shall each
                            find our home, in future life as we have prepared it by present faithfulness. East
                            Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Light--spiritual and natural" TEIform="index"/> LIGHT-SPIRITUAL AND NATURAL.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo G." TEIform="persName"/>By Alonzo G. Hollister.</byline><p TEIform="p">AN inspired apostle tells us "God is Light, and in Him is no darkness.' The light referred to
                            is spiritual light, which is communicated from mind to mind and from thought to thought,
                            without the intervention of material sight. Matter can not propagate it, obstruct, nor
                            obscure it; neither can it increase nor diminish it. But light which is visible to the
                            natural, is a figure or symbol of moral and spiritual light, which is the light of
                            intelligence, seen only with the eyes of the mind in which thought originates. Light is
                            propagated only in straight lines; it can not shine through a crooked hole. Only certain
                            forms of matter will transmit light and these are translucent or transparent, such as water,
                            air, glass and certain gems. We say of an honest, frank, generous, open hearted person, such
                            a one is transparent. Of a deceitful, selfish, designing person, we say in our hearts if not
                            audibly, such are dark, treacherous and need watching to avoid trouble with them. All
                            mankind have by nature a dark side and a light side. The appetites ME. <pb n="274" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 274 THE MANIFESTO. and passions of the being that belong to the dark
                            side of human nature, the side that seeks concealment, either from a sense of propriety or
                            of shame, or to gain undue advantage over others, have their seat in the lower half of the
                            body, and in the base and back part of the brain. They are self-active, and blind to
                            everything but their own gratification and the means to obtain it. Not that one part of the
                            body is morally better than another, nor that the passions and appetites are evil in
                            themselves, except they have been made so by excess or by perverted or unlawful use. They
                            are the force-giving faculties, which build and sustain the vital economy in its rela ions
                            to the world of matter. Primary reference is made to these in the command to replenish. When
                            they are perverted to a dishonorable use, those who do so seek to hide from the mental which
                            reproves and discloses the origin and vile character of their motives. If any one questions
                            the propriety of alluding to the inferior parts of the body in a religious talk, on the
                            ground of liability to fix the thoughts of some minds unfavorably constituted, on subjects
                            antagonistic to purity of heart and religious devotion, they thus prove their own assent to
                            the condemnation that virtue and godliness place upon certain motives and conduct which
                            gives inferior parts of the body undue prominence and allows them to dominate with tyranical
                            sway over the superior. This is an inversion or subversion of the true order of man's
                            creation and government, and the chief cause of man's perplexity, in not comprehending the
                            oracles and commands of God, given for his spiritual illumination and direction. It is our
                            duty to remove this excitability to wrong and perverte.l action, by bringing all our conduct
                            into that light which shines in appointed agents, and abstaining from impure thoughts and
                            from all actions which this light condemns, till all desire to do them is overcome and
                            destroyed. This can be done, for it has been done by many, and is being done. It is a most
                            glorious emancipation and conquest, leading to unbounded freedom of joyous exultation and
                            serviceable comradeship. The upper half of the body and the top and front of the brain
                            represent the light side of humanity. Are the seat of the faculties of reasoning
                            intelligence, virtuous and pure affections and of all that is noble, dignified, commendable
                            and commanding in the human character. It is formed to rule over and give law to the dark
                            side and never to sink into servile subjection. We do not seek to hide these, as something
                            that will procure us dishonor, unless they are engaged in dishonorable service to the dark
                            and baser part. We know that the more of the light side we can manifest, the better we feel
                            and the more we are loved and appreciated by our fellows, or by those whose love and esteem
                            is of greatest worth. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Contentment is a rare jewel..." TEIform="index"/>Contentment is a rare jewel...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Contentment is a rare jewel, let us set it in our crown of life.</p></div2><pb n="275" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mother Ann Lee's mission" TEIform="index"/>MOTHER ANN LEE'S MISSION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>By Martha J. Anderson.</byline><p TEIform="p">THE grandeur and importance of the life and mission of Mother Ann Lee. can only be
                            comprehended and appreciated by those whose spiritual experience has opened to them the
                            avenues of interior vision and revelation which brings them in rapport with the same Christ
                            heavens whence came her baptism and anointing. The carnal or natural man can not perceive
                            spiritual things. That the coming of a woman in whom should be manifest or reflected the
                            glory of the Son of man as prophesied in Scripture, no one can dispute; and no doubt there
                            have been interpolations that have made some passages not only obscure, but have entirely
                            obliterated the original meaning. The daughter and the bride are frequently spoken of, but,
                            in order to continue masculine supremacy, priests and commentators have construed them to
                            mean the church. In Mother Ann Lee's life and mission, we see much of the fulfillment of
                            prophecy, as we carefully read and judge. Many female messiahs have arisen who have laid
                            claim to the high titles of the "Woman clothed with the Sun," "the Bride of the Lamb," etc.
                            and no doubt their mediumistic qualities and a measure of the Spirit given through special
                            gifts have made them ministers to certain classes of people, but their works have ceased and
                            their converts scattered. The fruits of the system brought forth by Ann Lee and her noble
                            brother co-laborers, who embodied and exemplified the spirit and life of the divine
                            Fatherhood revealed through Jesus, the head and chief corner stone of the first Christian
                            Church, have been purity, love, peace, good-will and unselfish communism, Math the equality
                            of the sexes, and a holy spiritual relation in every domain of life. There may be a greater
                            than she yet to come, a still more glorious embodiment of the Divine Motherhood, or a
                            re-embodiment of her own progressed individuality in a more perfect development. There is
                            ever increasing truth to be made manifest among her children according to their growth and
                            desire for more light; she fixed no bounds for revelation or advancement. None have as yet
                            eclipsed her highly illumined soul-life, or the inspired testimony that rent the veil of the
                            covering that was upon all nations, ("the secrecy enshrouding the carnal life") and wrought
                            in all who received the new life a great salvation, even power over sin and sensuality that
                            dominates the natural man and woman and beclouds their spiritual natures. By her
                            faithfulness and obedience, by self-abnegation and devotion to others, (through the higher
                            law of loving service,) by the persecution, imprisonments and deprivation she steadfastly
                            endured for the promulgation of the truth, and the testimony of Christ against the hidden
                            works and abominations of fallen man, which have ever sowed the seeds of discord and strife
                            in the <pb n="276" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 276 THE MANIFESTO. earth. For her deep suffering and incessant
                            labors in striving for the regenerate life, she became a spiritually illumed, refined and
                            sanctified soul. "A chosen vessel unto tne Lord" to do his will and work "his strange work
                            and bring to pass his act, his strange act" that the word of tlrj Lord to Teremiah might be
                            fulfilled. "The Lord hath created a nsw thing in the earth, a woman shall compass a man."
                            The church of the first Christian Dispensation, founded by the immediate followers of Jesus,
                            was masculine in spirit and government, yet it was but the first fruit of the seed-sowing of
                            the God-man, imperfect and incomplete, but a degree forward on the dial toward the iipw age
                            of perfect fitness aud unfoldment. There was yet need for the exemplificatiQii of a more
                            perfect order of human society, spiritually, intellectually and socially ; forming a true
                            household of communistic relation where the mother should stand in her lot and place as the
                            dispenser of true love and saving grace, which flows through the Heavenly Maternal Spirit
                            uplifting souls to the new life. "The virgins her companions follow her" in the
                            regeneration, they are the children of the King, the Father and head of the church or
                            association forming the Melchisedec Order. "Hearken O Daughter and consider and incline
                            thine ear, forget also thine own people and thy Father's house, so shall the King greatly
                            desire thy beauty, He is thy Lord worship thou Him."Psa. xlv., 10. Did not Ann Lee forsake
                            her own people and country with its oppression, in obedience to the Heavenly vision and come
                            to a hind where a great nation was struggling to obtain freedom from the yoke of bondage?
                            Thus the Spirit of God widely directed them, that they might in due time enjoy freedom of
                            conscience and religious liberty. And again was fulfilled the prophecy "Behold I will allure
                            and bring her into the wilderness (a new country) and speak comfortably to her; and 1 will
                            give her vineyards from thence, and the valley of Achor for a door of hope (confession of
                            sin) and she shall sing there as in the days of her youth."Hos. ii., 14. Through her baptism
                            was renewed the ministration of the father spirit which was manifested in her noble
                            co-workers, they were indeed men to be wondered at. Rising superior to sinful passions and
                            selfish desires, they were imbued with the new life which comes through the conservation of
                            force ; and were empowered with strength to successfully lay the foundation of the Spiritual
                            Order. Almost superhuman physical labor, combined with spiritual and mental exercise wrought
                            wonders in a short time, buildings were erected by their own hands, virgin soil was cleared
                            and believers in Mother's testimony were comfortable in homes of the united inheritance. The
                            real mission of Ann Lee was to uplift and release woman from the tfiralldom of sin and set
                            her in her proper place as the helpmeet and equal co-worker with man in all the duties and
                            services of life. She struck the <pb n="277" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 277 key-note to
                            woman's emancipation, and it has sounded through the world ever since her message of truth
                            was given. The order and governmentm the church of her planting,was designed to be equal
                            with the sexes. Steps in advance need now be taken to perfect it. Woman should have a voice
                            in financial affairs, in order to maintain the equilibrium of forces, and to conserve the
                            spirit of our institution which fosters no speculation, incurs no debts, and practices
                            economy in all things, that there may be a substance secured for generations to come. All
                            hail the dawning of the age of conservation and of reconstruction. The Father and Mother
                            spirit brood over all, to the bringing forth of order, harmony and the perfect
                            exemplification of love, to be made manifest in every domain of active service in life. We
                            honor the past, glory in the present and look forward with hope to the future. Mt. Lebanon,
                            N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What is it to be a shaker?" TEIform="index"/>WHAT IS IT TO BE A SHAKER?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Estabrook, Fannie" TEIform="persName"/>By Fannie Estabrook.</byline><p TEIform="p">TO be a Shaker is simply to live a life of purity according to the example of our Savior. He
                            taught the gospel work while he was on the earth, and it was prophesied that there should be
                            a second appearing, which we believe came to mankind through the ministry of Ann Lee, a
                            woman who came from England to teach a good and godly life. One of the first principles she
                            taught was Love, for "By this shall all men know that ye are my disciples it ye have love
                            one for another." So to be a disciple of Christ we must love each other. Mother Ann taught,
                            as did our Savior, to love our enemies and think evil of no one. Peace is another principle
                            of the Christian life. There should be no war except the war with the elements of sin.
                            "Whatsoever ye would that men should do unto you, do ye even so to them," should be our
                            rule. If we do wrong we should confess it one to the other and thus restore the peace broken
                            by our transgression. Faith in the work of righteousness is necessary would we add good
                            works. We do not live in a community for the enjoyment of temporal blessings alone but
                            because these conditions are condusive to our spiritual growth. It is a beautiful life which
                            gives happiness in this world, and an eternal home hereafter. We who are yet young and have
                            chosen a Christian life should be zealous to remember our Creator in the days of our youth.
                            Our gospel parents have suffered for the cause and we are reaping the results of their
                            faithfulness. If we but obey the light with which we are blest we shall find saviors and
                            teachers who will ever point us the "the way, the truth and the life." Hancock, Mass.</p></div2><pb n="278" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Millennium" TEIform="index"/>THE MILLENNIUM.</head><p TEIform="p">ONE of the evidences of the millennial age will be, no doubt, "Peace on earth, good-will to
                            men." Wars, and rumors of wars will have passed away and whoever enters that order which
                            heralds the incoming of the spirit of Christ will be known as a peace worker among men. A
                            profession which savors more of words than of good works can have but little direct
                            influence in reclaiming that which has wandered from the light, or in redeeming the mind
                            from error. Our aim should be high above the earth. Nothing short of the testimony which
                            became the very spiritual life principle of Jesus the Christ should satisfy those who have
                            been called to walk in righteousness and peace. "There shall be nothing to harm nor hurt,"
                            says the prophet, "in all God's holy mountain." Swords will be made into ploughshares and
                            spears into pruning hooks. This is certainly a foreshadowing of a peaceful reign on earth,
                            and quite as clearly that the Lord's people will become an agricultural and a fruit growing
                            people. Everything that tends to elevate the race and to make the human family more deeply
                            and strongly, the active friends of humanity, will aid us in approaching that state which
                            has sometimes been termed the millennial age. Those who take pleasure in wandering among the
                            mazes of prophetical numbers have, seemingly, made themselves wise in ascertaining a correct
                            (?) solution of the prophetic mind and in becoming able to establish with but few shadows of
                            doubt the precise time for the introduction of a thousand years. The same time if spent in
                            active labors for the better education of the morally and spiritually ignorant would, no
                            doubt, have brought the millennium much nearer to our doors. One of the strongest evidences
                            that we can have of the honesty of a religions belief is the preparation that is made for
                            the great f.nd wonderful event. Those who anticipate the near approach of some national
                            holiday are not slow or careless in regard to the duties requisite to an honorable
                            reception, and a Christian who would do less in the preparation for the great day of the
                            Lord, would be a feeble specimen of that consecration which demands all that a man hath,
                            soul, body and spirit, and less worthy to share in the blessings of God. One of the good
                            preachers that came from the wilderness of Judea, has said :"Repent, for the kingdom of God
                            is at hand. Prepare the way and make his paths strait." Faithful souls who have heeded this
                            voice of warning have made strait paths by confession and repentance. <pb n="279" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/>
                            THE MANIFESTO. 279 God's kingdom came, and it came to dwell among men, and was in their
                            souls the new, the heavenly Jerusalem. The same voice of the spirit continues to seek for
                            repentant souls and to help them on toward God by frequent baptisms and by a faithful
                            continuance in well-doing. The same kingdom of God is near at hand and demands the same
                            earnest attention in the making of strait paths, and in the forming of pure hearts. This
                            divine manifestation makes for each individual that season of rest which has so long and so
                            earnestly been anticipated, and which has been called the glorious reign of a thousand
                            years. We need the millennium. We need to see the dawning of that new day that was foretold
                            by the prophet when "the Lord shall be unto thee an everlasting light and thy God thy
                            glory."Isiah, lx., 19. The stolid ignorance which is displayed concerning the advent of this
                            most beautiful period of time is certainly one of the great wonders of the By some classes
                            however, this work is supposed to be near at hand, "when the knowledge of the Lord shall
                            cover the earth as the waters cover the sea," when the wicked shall all be destroyed and the
                            righteous only shall inherit the earth. Others put this wonderful day afar off. A few only
                            manifest much anxiety about any special preparation for the event. Preaching and praying has
                            occupied a part of the time, but buying and selling, marrying and giving in marriage as they
                            did in the days of Noah, has occupied still more of the time, and the beauties and glories
                            of the great millennium have been left for some more future generation. This may be
                            accounted for in part, as we learn how brutal and warlike man has always been toward his
                            brother man. How, even under a religious discipline, his life has been one of sensuality and
                            of great cruelty. The greed for power and the spirit to dominate for selfish interest has
                            through all the history of man had a wonderful influence on the mind and as often resulted
                            in making this world a place of unnecessary afflictions and physical torment, instead of
                            making it as it should be, a paradise of God.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/>H. C. Blinn.</byline></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p"> Please write the articles that are intended for publication on sheets of NOTE SIZE; 5x8
                            inches; Write with ink on one side of the paper only, and much oblige the printers of The
                            Manifesto. age.</p></div2><pb n="280" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. DECEMBER, 1895. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is published by the
                            "United Society op Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued
                            regularly by the Siiakeb Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of
                            the religious views of the Okdee and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. All
                            communications should be addressed to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer, Co., N. H. .75
                            .40 One copy per year, postage paid " " six months, " "</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. October. Thermometer. Bain. 1894. 50.36 3.75 in. 1895.
                                44. 4 in. Highest Temp, during this mo. 64 above 0 Lowest " " " " 26 " " Number of rainy
                                days " " 5 ". " clear " " " 15 " " snowy " " " 1 " " cloudy " " " 10 C. O. Heed. Mt.
                                Lebanon, N. Y. North Family. Nov. 1895. Little has transpired in our peaceful mountain
                                home that would gratify the external mind, but much has been granted to us from the
                                Giver of all good, that would nourish and uplift mind and soul. The 4th ult. we received
                                a pleasant call from Elder George Wilcox and Elder Thomas Stroud, who enriched us with
                                the love of true hearts. For a short period we had to use a steam motor for shirt work,
                                but upon the 12th the long looked for rain refreshed the earth and enabled us to again
                                use water power. October 14th the District school opened. The school house had
                                previously undergone repairs and re-arrangements to better adapt it for the
                                accommodation of boys and girls in separate class rooms. Following carpenter and
                                painter, Sister Amelia Calver's deft fingers added many appreciated touches in
                                preparation for the new teachers, Ezra J. Stewart, Grace Ada Brown and Annie R.
                                Stephens. Sister Grace Ada Brown, recently from Long Island has had large experience as
                                principal in public schools and is well qualified to instruct advanced classes.
                                Courteous manners and sound morality are a part of the lessons daily inculcated. The
                                long expected volume of poems entitled "Mount Lebanon Cedar Boughs," has just come from
                                the press, it is a neat and handsomely bound book of three hundred and sixteen pages and
                                well represents the work of many gifted persons. We have already had many subscribers
                                and hope to have the patronage of many more. We are more than pleased to say that
                                although we are now entering upon the severe winter season, yet we feel we are in the
                                spring of our hopefulness. We believe that a new age is dawning wherein we shall see the
                                spirit of brotherly love rule the hearts of mankind, "Mercy and truth meet and
                                righteousness and peace kiss each other." Belle Rullhausen.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 1895. We have lately been much interested in the perusal of "Emerson's Essays." The
                                thoughts given and the style of expression prove him to be an illuminated soul, a true
                                prophet that had already caught a 280 TERMS. <pb n="281" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 28 L
                                glimpse of the dawning day. His essays would make interesting and instructive reading
                                for lyceums and self-improvement societies for the coming winter. The past season witli
                                all its drawbacks has been generally a prosperous one. The crop of apples was fair but
                                not as large as the previous season. Hay very light crop, but potatoes the best for
                                several years; corn good. So we can with grateful hearts render thanksgiving for the
                                blessing we are under and to remember the poor and needy. We have an occasional visit
                                from the "Little Sisters of the Poor," a charitable institution located in Albany; their
                                work is commendable as it is given free depending upon contributions for support. Of the
                                new varieties of sweet corn that we have tested the past season, we have not found one
                                that equaled' in quality the "Country Gentlemen," a variety introduced the past season.
                                It is a late variety and for a family garden can not be surpassed. The Burpee's Dwarf
                                Lima Bean still proves a valuable acquisition, being a true Lima, enormously productive
                                and of excellent flavor. We are at present enjoying beautiful autumn weather very
                                desirable for the completion of fall work, but are needing rain. At present date Nov.
                                3rd we have had but one slight flurry of snow. Hamilton DeGraio.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station, Ct.</head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 1895. The Apostle says, "Praying always with all prayer." Prayer and watchfulness is
                                the armor for the battle of life. It is well to pray but better still to watch and work
                                and remember that "God helps those who help themselves." Prayer and watching is a
                                safeguard each hour. When we pray to our heavenly Father, it is an acknowledgement of
                                our dependence upon Him. How blessed is the thought that we can pray while performing
                                our daily duties. Our supplication can ascend to God without moving our lips. Without
                                watchfulness we shall be overcome by the adversary of souls. Let us strive to attain to
                                this watchful spirit, and commit all our burdens and trials to One, who has promised to
                                protect those who trust in Him. We can never pray too often, "Leave us not in
                                temptation, but deliver us from evil." October 16th, a company of five Sisters from
                                Hancock, Mass, came to visit iis. We have been greatly blest by such peaceful
                                messengers, who have been numerous during the year; they come none too often however. At
                                this season of the year we have no time to lose; there are so many things to be done to
                                prepare for winter. Cayenne peppers when mixed with soft feed are an excellent stimulant
                                for hens. It is proper care and food that hastens early laying. Hens should have all the
                                milk they can drink; no kind of food is better adapted to egg production. Hens should be
                                supplied in winter with what they can pick up in summer. A hen at large supplies herself
                                with grit in the shape of sharp flinty substance. Dtmiel Orcult. South Family. Nov.
                                1895. The beautiful October is past, leaving its place to drear November with its cold,
                                bleak winds. Snow has already made its appearance; on the 5th inst. the ground was well
                                covered, but it soon entirely vanished under the rays of the warm sun. Preparations for
                                winter are neai'ly completed. Our garners are well filled; and with so many blessings we
                                have naught to fear. The prospect for our winter garden is encouraging; tomatoes and
                                cucumbers are growing finely at this date, and other vegetables will be ready for the
                                table in due season. Time will prove the success of any new enterprise; thus we say when
                                thinking of our Brethren and Sisters in Florida. Our sympathies are with them, and we
                                hope health and prosperity may attend them. <pb n="282" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 282 THE MANIFESTO.
                                The addition to our family of two Sisters from the Society at Canterbury is a great
                                biessing to us. One in faith and one in interest, seeking to do good wherever duty calls
                                us is the beauty of our order of life. The faithful Christian may truly expect a
                                blessing through this life as well as in the great hereafter. Maria Witham.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harvard, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Harvard, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 1895. The constant rotation of the seasons tell us that progress is the key-note to
                                all things, not only in the material but in the intellectual, scientific and spiritual
                                world. Who can compare the present times with those of half a century ago and not
                                exclaim with wonder upon the changes time has produced? What will the next fifty years
                                do for us? Lately the town of Ayer has been visited by burglars and they did not forget
                                to give us a call. They have broken into our barn three times and made an unsuccessful
                                attempt to enter the Office but the tooting of an old campaign horn informed them they
                                would not be welcome. This is Thanksgiving month and we have indeed cause to be
                                thankful. Our dear gospel friends of Enfield, Conn., whose works sustain their
                                reputation for generosity, sent to us some very fine apples. Never in the history of
                                this Society has it been so completely destitute of this desirable fruit as this year.
                                With hearts full of gratitude we obey the injunction of the apostle,In love remember one
                                another. Marda M. Bullard.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 1895. We are just now in a waiting mood. We want some ice for the use, first, of the
                                dairy as it is difficult to obtain cream without ice, and then we want the warm weather
                                to continue with us so long as it may, as it saves the fuel and is more agreeable to
                                northern minds. The leaves have all fallen from the trees, and the birds have gone to
                                more southern homes. The farmers, and the Lord has blest them, have secured abundant
                                crops and have husked more than fourteen hundred bushels of corn. Two silos of one
                                hundred tons each are full of the best of ensilage, and the cows look with pleasure upon
                                the liberal herdsman as he gives to them their daily allowance. The reconstructing of
                                the dairy has brought advantages to that department, and the blessing rests upon the
                                whole Community. Light and shade, with its sunshine and clouds move with us on our
                                journey tlirough this world. We have had great pleasure in seeing the wild and the
                                cultivated flowers as they have blossomed from early spring till late in the fall, but
                                they are all gone and may be to prepare more beauty for the new spring and summer that
                                is soon to be with us. The flower garden,is it still with us,after so many of its
                                beautiful plants have been plucked up by the roots, to spirit them away? And here comes
                                a pleasing contrast. Some of the children are already wishing for a "good big snow-storm
                                so that we can bring out our sleds," and the churches are looking forward to the winter
                                for a season of religious revivals. God is good! "Who soweth good seed shall surely
                                reap." "The year grows rich as it groweth old; And life's latest sands are its sands of
                                gold." H. C. Blinn.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 1895. What exalted thoughts entrance our mind as we view a glorious sunset. Surely
                                no picture of nature can be grander, unless it be the brilliant autumnal foliage. As the
                                component parts of nature aid in beautifying and enriching the world, one season
                                depending upon the other for its contributions; even so the varied qualities of the
                                human mind are necessary to complete the perfect whole; and godly <pb n="283" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/>
                                THE MANIFESTO. 283 patience is one of the essential powers to mature the strong,
                                immortal life of Cliristliness, that can withstand, unmoved and unrelenting as a rocky
                                ledge, the surging billows of ungodliness that heat against it. Under the ministration
                                of perfect patience we endeavor to "Strive well for every fair, adorning grace, For
                                healthful growth of body, soul and mind; For love, in which all beauty is combined. In
                                true self-culture, sin we may not trace, In lovely lives, it has no part nor place."
                                Human life is a pilgrimage, and it may be well to add to our zeal the leaven of
                                Christian ambition, ever remembering it was the cheerful, devoted giver, endowed with a
                                penetrating sight of the world's needs, of those minds who have caught the heavenly
                                message of full resurrection from the soil of iniquity and founded our homes with the
                                view of bettering humanity. May we work with as consecrated a purpose, and move with the
                                inspiration that "God helps those who help themselves." With the ending of the harvest
                                season, we realize a harvesting of good results, not only in the record of farm
                                products, but our religious and educational services have yielded blessed fruits of
                                strong faith and moral activity. Though the harvest season is past, there is still work
                                for busy hands, and souls who seek for the graces of a Christ-like spirit. Fall
                                ploughing, also the filling of our average contract of eight hundred corn planters is in
                                active operation. There has been prepared for the market one thousand lbs. of beet seed,
                                also fifteen hundred lbs. each of yellow dock and burdock root. Happy indeed are they
                                who combine with willing service of the hands, full consecration of the mind and soul.
                                George H. Baxter.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Sabbathday Lake, Me.</head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 8, 1895. November 2nd, we had from two to three inches of snow, but since then the
                                weather has been remarkably fine and spring-like. People say they never knew it to be so
                                warm at this time of year; yet before long we shall have to be gathering round the fire
                                for the storms of winter will surely come. Through the untiring efforts of Sr. Aurelia,
                                much needed improvements are being made in our Office. The young Brethren are completing
                                a larger hot-house 15x50 ft. In a portion of which the Sisters will grow tea roses and
                                carnation pinks this winter, while the rest of the house will be used for the
                                cultivation of early vegetables. We were glad to hear a word of encouragement from
                                Florida. Trust those faithful workers will be prospered in their consecrated efforts,
                                and that each plant and tree now started will yield an abundant increase. Four aged ones
                                are still with us each over fourscore. We are thankful for every day that they remain
                                with us although we see that they are gradually growing more feeble and must soon join
                                their companions in a far happier home than this. Ada S. Cummings.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Alfred, Maine" TEIform="index"/>-Alfred., Me.</head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 1895. This is the last opportunity we shall have to greet our gospel relation and
                                the readers of The Manifesto this year, and we can not let it pass although our offering
                                is but the Widow's mite. The President and the Governor of our State have set apart a
                                day in which to give thanks to the Giver of all good; but we feel like giving thanks
                                every day for the many blessings we enjoy. Our barns and cellars give evidence of
                                temporal blessings, and our hearts can count with greater thankfulness the beautiful
                                gifts of the spirit. The Apostle while telling of the future coming of Christ was not
                                quite sure as to the manner of his appearing, but felt sure that at the appearing they
                                should be like Him. He has appeared to us the second time without sin and the testimony
                                of <pb n="284" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 284 THE MANIFESTO. this second coming will make us like Him if
                                we are obedient to it. The November Manifesto was filled with good things. "Sheaves of
                                Experience" was most excellent. The Editorial "Double Dealing" was very good and
                                interesting. The quotation from Paul to Timothy 1 think is more sensible in the New
                                Version. We are well along in the eleventh month of '95 and death has kept far away from
                                us,for which we give thanks. At this writing we are enjoying the warm pleasant days of
                                Indian summer, but a week ago two inches of snow fell. October 23rd we enjoyed a short
                                call from two worthy Sisters of New Hampshire. Eldress Eliza Stratton, whom we have met
                                before and hope to again, and Sister Sadie Webber. Both were made welcome and will be
                                again if they come this way. The past three months we have been selling our milk instead
                                of the cream as formerly, which proves more profitable thus far. Fannie Casey.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary.</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Turkish porters" TEIform="index"/> TURKISH PORTERS.</head><p TEIform="p">Captain Eea assures me that he never witnessed such feats of strength as exhibited by the
                                porters of Smyrna. In unloading vessels with Havana sugar, each porter carries a box of
                                sugar upon his back from the vessel to the storehouse; and this is done all day without
                                complaint. The weight is over four hundred pounds. One porter was seen carrying a load
                                of boards so large that the individuals present had the curiosity to detain him and to
                                have it weighed. Capt. Eea saw it weighed and learned that it was nine hundred and five
                                pounds. The drink of these porters was nothing but water, and bread the staple article
                                of food.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A prominent physician..." TEIform="index"/>A prominent physician...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A prominent physician of New York recently declared that hot water is our
                                        best friend. It will cure dyspepsia, taken before breakfast and will ward off
                                        chills. It will stop a cold if taken early in the stage. It will relieve a
                                        nervous headache and give instant relief to tired and inflamed eyes. It is most
                                        efficacious for sprains and bruises and will frequently stop the flow of blood
                                        from a wound. It is a sovereign remedy for sleeplessness, and iu conclusion, the
                                        doctor asserts, "wrinkles flee from it, and blackheads vanish before its
                                        constant use."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Womankind" TEIform="index"/>Womankind.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>EXCHANGES.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="International association of machinists" TEIform="index"/>The International Association
                                of Machinists
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Mackintoshes and Kubber Clothing large commissions can be earned by retailing to users.
                                Sample free. Manufacturer, P. O. 1371 New York, EXCHANGES. The International Association
                                of Machinists is published in Chicago, 111. It is a beautiful Journal both without and
                                within as it is working in the interests of humanity. Better men and women on earth,
                                will make a better congregation in heaven. It is a monthly Journal of some 42 pages, and
                                Edited by I). Douglas Wilson. Terms $1.00 pr. year. 330 Monon Block, Chicago, 111.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Many years ago..." TEIform="index"/>Many years ago...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Many years ago an old gentleman told the writer that when he was a young man his uncle lived
                            in Salem, in a house located close on a line with the sidewalk. Next to his house a
                            neighbor's house set well back from the street, leaving an open green sward in front, over
                            which his uncle's family had a fine view down street toward the morning sun from their
                            sitting-room windows. One night the neighbor's house was destroyed by fire. He did not wish
                            to rebuild and sold the land to another neighbor who proposed to build a house on a line
                            with the uncle's house, which was the customary way, he said: "Uncle, you won't allow it to
                            be done, will you?" "I don't know as I can prevent it." "But the front of that lot was never
                                <pb n="285" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFES TO. 285 fenced in since the discovery of the country.
                            It has always been open to the public and they have no legal right to build on it." "But I
                            don't see how I can help myself." "Don't you think I had better go and consult Ben Merrill?"
                            (The best lawyer of his time iii Salem.) "You may, if you like." He called on the lawyer,
                            stated the case, and asked if they had a right to build as proposed. The lawyer replied: "No
                            they have not." "Then, if we pursue a certain course, [naming it] we can stop them." "No, I
                            did not say so. Young man, you see this ruler. I hold it upright by placing my finger on the
                            end. If I take my finger away, can you tell me which way it will fall?" "No." Neither can I;
                            but [letting it fall] now both you and I know. Well, the law is just as uncertain as that."
                            "I see. How much is to pay?" "Three dollars." The old gentleman said; "I don't think uncle
                            ever invested any three dollars better than that."</p></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kind words" TEIform="index"/>KIND WORDS </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Thebe is no reason why all the Shakers who read The Manifesto, and it is taken for granted
                            that all do read it, should not share in the good things that are said about our little
                            paper as well as the Editor. A little touch of approbation may not be out of place with
                            those who are trying to do good, even if they fall short of the mark. In "Human Nature," a
                            paper published in San Francisco, Cal., and edited by Prof. Haddock: "The Manifesto is
                            published by the United Society of Believers on the first of each month, and is the only
                            work issued regularly by the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple
                            statement of the religious views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness.
                            'The foundation stone upon which the structure of Shakerism rests, is virgin purity; or in
                            other words, a life of celibacy. The principle has been kept unsullied for over one hundred
                            years.' They are confronted with the cry, 'If all should become Shakers, the world would
                            become extinct.' But the Shakers answer that "they believe the great sin of the age is the
                            destructive force of sensualism, and it is "only by a return to the law of God through
                            chastity in the relationship of men and women that human beings can be delivered from the
                            curses of want and disease, and the great train of evils that so effect modern society."</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Who was the heathen?" TEIform="index"/>WHO WAS THE HEATHEN?</head><p TEIform="p">A family in St. Paul had never employed a Chinese servant, but thought they would like to try
                            one. Accordingly, one presented himself, of whom several questions were asked. Among them
                            were: "Do you drink?" "No, I Band of Hope boy." "Do you gamble?" "No, I Band of Hope boy."
                            "Do you smoke?" [rather indignantly,] "No, I Band of Hope boy." He was engaged and gave so
                            much satisfaction that a dinner party was given by his employers. Wine was on the table, and
                            the after dinner cards and cigars were enjoyed. Breakfast was prepared next morning. John
                            appeared, bundle in hand, saying, "I go." "Why do you go? We like you very much." "When I
                            come here you say: 'You smoke?' You smoke. You say, 'You drink?' You drink. You say, 'You
                            gamble?' You gamble. You heathen. I no stay." 'If some tall steeple totters from on high
                            Will gravitation cease while you go by?"</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Teachout, Almira" TEIform="index"/>Almira Teachout
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Almira Teachout, at Shakers, N. Y. Nov. 1895. Age 11 years, 2mo. and 5 days.</p></div3></div2><pb n="286" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">INDEX. All, Merry Christmas to A- - - - - - - . Acrostic, Arimathea, Joseph of Age, Address
                            to Old Acrostic, Page. 5 - 56 70 95 117 143 152 166 193 216 255 267 48 149 216 Age, Old .
                            ... Away, Passing Best, Whatever is, is Bronson, Hannah Building, We Are C Commemoration,
                            Bryant Centennial 9 Confession, 29 Cross, Glorious - - 47 Cleaning, Spring - - 116 Creed,
                            What Was His - - 117 Christianity, Aggressive - 158 Charity, - - - - 177 Culture, Self - - -
                            222 Compensation, ... 228 Done, Thy Will Be - - 100 Denunciation, - - - 119 Duty, Faithful
                            in - - 132 Day, The New - - - 173 Dietetics, - - - " Page. Deceived, Be Not - - - 182
                            Democracy, - - - 200 Dealing, Double - - - 252 Emery, SimonLetter - 80 Everywhere, God is -
                            - 123 Envy, 180 Editor, He was an - - - 217 Envy, - - - . 223 Experience, Sheaves of - - 243
                            F Faith, Christian 28 Family, North - - - 30 Faith, Household of - - 36 Florida, - - - , -
                            69 Fiction, Truth and . - 97 Foundation, Life's - - - 102 Faith, 131 Footprints, Angels - -
                            - 143 Friction, So Much of the - 146 Faith, - - - - - 205 " - - - - 232 Friendship, ... -
                            272 Gleams, - - - - 98 Gillette, E. B.Letter - 177 Ground, Gaining ... 192 H Home, Notes
                            About 17, 39, 63, 87, 111, 136, 161, 185, 211, 234, 257, 280 Harding, Bernard E.Letter - 55
                            Home, -.....70 Harvard, Reception 93 A. <pb n="287" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 287 Page.
                            Hampton, 0. C.Letter - 176* Heathen, Who Was the 285 I Improvement, Social - 123, 155
                            Inspiration, - 124 Ill-temper, - 178 Judgment, Come to . 53 June, - 122 Judging, - 204
                            Jealousy, 224 Knowledge, True - 59 Kitten, Spelling 146 Labor, Effective Soul - 57 Living,
                            Right - 108 Line, The Separating - 171 Lyon, Elder John - 198, 225, 247 Life, - 217 Life,
                            The Unfolding of - 219 Laughed, Boy Who 264 Light, Spiritual and Natural 273 Mind, The - - -
                            - 32 Me, Learn of - 60 Me, Father Take 70 Me, Speak Lord to - . 71 Ministered, They 102
                            Mission, Our ... 130 Memory, InP. Van Houten 166 Mount, Sermon on 172 Manners, Good 190
                            Make, If you Would - 191 Mother Ann, ... 192 Memories, Scenes and 197 Manhood, ... 203, 227
                            Mission, Life's - 216 Memory, InC. Downs 263, 265 Me, Follow - . 273 Mission, Mother Ann
                            Lee's liillennium, The 275 278 IV STeighbor, Do Not Judge your - 57 O Off ord, DanielLetter
                            - - 7 Orcutt, D.Letter - 47, 118, 241 Obedience, - 105 Pansy, The White - - 22 Preaching, -
                            - - - - 31 Providences, Special - - 121 Peace, - - - - - 202 Providence, Mysterious - - 206
                            Prayer, A Railroaders - 217 It Righteousness, - - - 84 Reaping, Sowing and - 104
                            Rosicrucians, Among the 125, 154 Reed, Calvin G.Letter - - 127 Rupe, Nancy L. " - - 153
                            Religion, Feeling in 168 Road, The Easy ... 192 Reliance,..... 199 South Union, History of
                            3, 25, 49, 73. Sincerity, - - - - - 23 Spirit, Public - - - - 32 Shadow, Sunshine and - - 35
                            Spiritualism, True ... 77 Self-control, - - - - - 100 Side, The Bright - - - 118 Shakerism,
                            The Mission of - - 147 Society, Social Improvement - 155 Self-denial, Practical - 165
                            Saying, What Are the Wild Waves 167 Snowdrops, - - - - - 168 Self-defence, Right of - - 169
                            Sanitary, - 189, 215, 239, 263, 284 Stronghold, Virtue our - - 195 Page. <pb n="288" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 288 THE MANIFESTO. Page. Page. Sacrifice, .... - 221 DEATHS. Shaker, What it
                            is to be a 277 Atkinson, John - 71 T Baner, Jacob - Turkeys, A Plea for the - 8 Thoughts,
                            New Year's 82 Battles, Albert J. - - 265 Tribute,S. Small - 93 Carpenter, Catherine 23
                            Thoughts, - 117 Childs, Simeon - 120 Tribute,M. Crooker - 142 To-day, Strength for - 191
                            Crooker, Martha ... 143 Thine, Mine and - 229 Cameron, John ... " Tribute,Mother Ann Lee -
                            245 Carpenter, Julia H. - 170 Tripp, F. SilsbyLetter - - 251 Clifford, Angeline B.- 218
                            Thought, Harmony of 270 U Davis, Eliza - - - - 194 Upward, Look - 59 Downs, Caroline - .265
                            " " 116 Elam, William ... 143 White, AnnaLetter 6 Ferris, Elizabeth - 23 War, A Shaker's
                            Testimony Against 53 Hennessey, Kate 71 Wilson, Sarah F.Letter 129 Hulet, Elvira Curtes -
                            218 Whiteley, John 202, 250 Words, Kind 232, 285 Koch, William 170 March, Harriet - 265
                            Year, The Incoming 14 Ye, Which Choose 107 Parsell, John H. 143 Potter, Eleanor - 71 Pack,
                            Bestey - 218 MUSIC Patterson, Clarissa 265 Abiding Hope - - - 209 Prouty, Abagail Best
                            Gifts, - 86 Small, Sarah - ... 71 Center of Light, - 16 Standish, Sarah A. - 96 Courage, -
                            110 Streeter, Bertha - 241 Heavenly Pathway, 135 Shannon, T. J. - I Look to Thee, 160
                            Teachout, Almira 285 Life's Infinity, 38 Soul Awakening, 256 Van Houten, Phebe - 170 Toil
                            and Win, 62 Wicks. Nancv - 241 True Riches, 233 White, Demolius -</p></div2><pb n="289" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Number in nature, an evidence of creative intelligence" TEIform="index"/>
                                Number in Nature, an Evidence of Creative Intelligence
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> "Number in Nature, an Evidence of Creative Intelligence," is a Lecture delivered by
                                Edward White, at New College, London, England. It is not strange that the Editor should
                                have selected this interesting address to help strengthen his position, in cumulative
                                evidence in favor of a Creative intelligence and in opposition to those who say, "There
                                is no God." When a man dwells on the right side he is quite sure to dwell safely and
                                feels the undoubted assurance in his own mind. The many illustrations drawn from
                                mechanism, from chemistry, from astronomy as well as from vegetation and from the
                                plumage of birds, are each and all wonderful steps of in. telligence that lead up to
                                God. Send for this little work at a price of only five cents and read this beautiful
                                lesson of Creative Intelligence. H. L. Hastings, 47 Cornhill, Boston, Mass. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Standard dictionary" TEIform="index"/>The Standard
                                Dictionary
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Standard
                                Dictionary "is illustrated with a number of colored (plates,a novel featureexecuted in
                                Prang and Co.'s best style. The plate of gems and precious stones is one of the most
                                beautiful specimens of the lithographer's art ever turned out. The two volumes of the
                                work contain altogether about 5000 illustrations, including a number of full page
                                pictures. Those at horse, dog, fowl, seals, sheep, and swine, and like words are
                                practical and valuable. An important feature for the scientific reader in this
                                connection is the exact definition of the six primary colors of the spectrum, containing
                                the analysis of several hundred shades and tints. Many thousand samples were considered
                                and carefully compared by Professors Hallock and Gordon of Columbia College, in
                                perfecting the color plate and in preparing the table of some 400 formulas which
                                accompany the spectrum plate. This beautiful and instructive color plate under Spectrum
                                was made by LiPrang and Co. of Boston, in more than 50 separate lithographic printings
                                and at a cost of several thousand dollars."</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mount Lebanon cedar boughs" TEIform="index"/>Mount Lebanon Cedar Boughs
                            </head><p TEIform="p">"Mount Lebanon Cedar Boughs." This beautiful
                                little volume is before us, having just been published by the Paul Book Co. of Buffalo,
                                N. Y. These original Poems were collected among the Believers of the North family at Mt.
                                Lebanon, N. Y. and are "Affectionately dedicated to our spiritual kindred of the
                                Household of Faith, and to yearning souls in the wide, wide world." Already the Book has
                                met with a favorable reception and having as it does a very attra ctive binding, it will
                                make a present for the Holidays. It contains over 300 pages. Price $1.50. Address all
                                orders to Anna White, Mt. Lebanon, Col. Co., N. Y. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Journal of Hygeio-Therapy" TEIform="index"/>The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy for
                                October lias interesting articles in reference to the "Invalids' Home," and to the "Last
                                Annual Reunion." The Journal is also beautifully illustrated in connection with these
                                anniversary exercises, which gives us a much more pleasant introduction to the people
                                and their place of abode. Not only are the good Physicians introduced to us but an
                                illustration of the "Invalids' Home" is presented and also an illustration that would
                                make glad the heart of the animals' friend, George T. Angell. With this we also wish
                                abundant peace and prosperity for all the dear friends who are working in the interest
                                of humanity.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health monthly" TEIform="index"/>Health Monthly
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Dr. Foote in the "Health Monthly" for November has a long article on the
                                "Diseases of the Kidneys." Information obtained from reliable medical Journals on this
                                and kindred subjects, gives that information which is so much needed by every person.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pleasant hours for boys and girls" TEIform="index"/>Pleasant Hours for Boys and Girls
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Young people will find much to interest and please them in the November number of Frank
                                Leslie's Pleasant Hours for Boys and Girls. There is a capital short story by Oliver
                                Optic; an article giving some excellent hints for boys on buying and using a gun, by
                                Wilt P. Pond; an interesting description of an incident of the war, by J.Frederick
                                Thorne; a valuable paper on "Children in Japan," by A. B.de Guerville; an illustrated
                                poem about an arithmetical puzzle, by Clifford Howard; a story for very little folks; a
                                description of a new and exciting game for boys; several illustrated jingles, and a
                                number of puzzles; while the two serial stories by Edward S. Ellis and Jeannette H.
                                Walworth continue with increasing interest. A unique feature of this magazine, which
                                starts in the November number, is the editor's talks about the new books for boys and
                                girls, in which he points out what is best in the late juvenile publications. The number
                                is splendidly illustrated. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cosmopolitan" TEIform="index"/>Cosmopolitan
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A complete and immediate revolution of the transportation
                                methods, involving a reduction of freight charges on grain from the West to New "York of
                                from 50 to 60 per cent, is what is predicted in theNovember Cosmopolitan. The plan
                                proposes using light and inexpensive corrugated iron cylinders, hung on a slight rail
                                supported on poles from a cross-arm the whole system involving an expense of not more
                                than fifteen hundred dollars a mile for construction. The rolling stock is equally
                                simple and comparatively inexpensive. Continuous lines of cylinders, moving with no
                                interval to speak of, would carry more grain in a day than a quadruple track railway.
                                This would constitute a sort of grain-pipe line. The Cosmopolitan also points out the
                                probable abolition of street-cars before the coming horseless carriage, which can be
                                operated by a boy on asphalt pavements at a total expense for labor, oil and interest,
                                of not more thai one dollar a day. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="This country of ours" TEIform="index"/>This Country of Ours
                            </head><p TEIform="p">  
                                It is announced that ex-President Benjamin Harrison
                                is engaged in writing a series cf <pb n="290" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/> 290 7 RE MANIFES TO. magazine
                                articles for The Ladies' Home. Journal in which periodical they will begin in the
                                December number. The series will be called, "This Country of Ours," and will consist of
                                ten articles and probably more. The papers are being written by General Harrison
                                especially for women, to meet a growing, widespread desire on their part to
                                intelligently understand the workings) of our Government and the great National
                                questions. It will be the aim of the articles to explain in the clear and concise style
                                for which the ex President is famous just what the United States Government means; the
                                origin and also the meaning of the Constitution; how laws are enacted and enforced; what
                                the powers of the President and other officials are; what the judiciary system means;
                                how our foreign relations are brought about and their meaning; how Congress and the
                                Senate legislate,in fact, a complete explanation of the Government told in a popular
                                way. General Harrison writes the articles from the standpoint of a citizen who
                                understands. They have no bearing on politics whatever. While directly intended for
                                women, the articles will naturally have a much broader scope and likewise interest men,
                                and especiallyyoung men.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Boston post" TEIform="index"/>The Boston Post
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Boston Post has just issued a new type book containing specimens of 332 different
                                styles of type, which it has assembled for the convenience of its advertisers. The type
                                book is a very artistic publication in colored covers and contains sixty-seven large
                                pages of specimen types, many of them very novel, artistic and effective. In fact, it
                                would seem as if the Post had at its disposal an entire foundry of display types. They
                                vary from the Diamond type, which almost requires a magnifying glass to read, to a type
                                over eight inches deep. In addition to the types, there is a bewildering collection of
                                eighty-one different kinds of borders, and a large variety of circles, ovals and other
                                typographical material. This type book is unquestionably the most elaborate and artistic
                                publication of its kind in the country. The Post's advertising de partment in its
                                composing room is said to be the best equipped in New England. The latest type books of
                                the Globe contain 225 types, the Herald 221 types and the Post 332 types. Such a
                                publication marks not only the persistent enterprise of the Boston Post, but also
                                indicates the great advance now being made in the way of artistic and effective
                                advertising. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological Journal and Science of Health" TEIform="index"/>
                                The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> In The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health for November, many
                                important elements of dramatic talent are illustrated in a phrenograph of Mme.
                                Janauschek, the famous actress, by Dr. Edgar C. Beall, who has made a personal
                                examination of the tragedienne. This should interest not only theatrical people, but all
                                lovers of the drama and of course all students of scientific character reading. Mr.
                                (jreorge C. Bartlett in his third European letter gives a most charming description of
                                Switzerland, including the ascent of Mont Blanc, and a walk through the vale of
                                Chamonix. "Temperament and the Teeth," by Allison It. Law she is a finely illustrated
                                article showing the characteristics of the teeth in the four principal temperaments. It
                                is a novel contribution to the literature of phrenology. Mrs. Commelin continues her
                                phrenological romance. Dr. Drayton learnedly discusses "Practical Psychology." Speeches
                                at the opening of the American Institute of Phrenology make an interesting feature.
                                Prol. Nelson Sizer writes in his happiest vein of the German Emperor's children. In the
                                hygienic department several physicians discuss the "Imx)ortance of Water," "Animal and
                                Vegetable Poods," "Intemperance and Suicide," "Cousin Marriages," etc. The editor
                                philosophizes on "Economics in Mentality,' announces a phrenological centennial, and
                                finds Tolstoi a disbeliever in immortality. New York: Fowler &amp; Wells Co., 27
                                East Twenty-first street. $150 per year. 15 cents per single copy.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="He who sits and looks..." TEIform="index"/>He who sits and looks...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">He who sits and looks on the palpitating world, and feels his heart swell in him large enough
                            to hold all men within it, is near his great Creator's standard, though he dwell outside the
                            pale of churches, and knows not a feast day from a fast . day, or a line of Scripture even.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wilcox, Ella Wheeler" TEIform="persName"/>Ella Wheeler Wilcox.</byline></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New Missionary: Can you tell me..." TEIform="index"/>New Missionary: Can you tell me...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">New Missionary: Can you tell me what has become of my predecessor? Cannibal Chief: He has
                            made a trip into the interior.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Refrain from that belittling censure..." TEIform="index"/>Refrain from that belittling censure...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Kefkain from that belittling censure, that springs forth from common lips, like weeds from
                            marshy soil. Genius spreads its wings and soars beyond itself, or selfish things. Talent has
                            need of stepping stones.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wilcox, Ella Wheeler" TEIform="persName"/>Ella Wheeler Wilcox.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cheerfulness is an excellent wearing quality..." TEIform="index"/>Cheerfulness is an excellent wearing quality...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Cheerfulness is an excellent wearing quality. It has been called the bright weather of the
                            heart.</p></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p27"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
WANTED SALESMEN
      t,wn fiOPlTl nVfRTNT in pnp.h rinniltv
We
w a n t
one or
two GOOD MEN in each County to take
orders for a Choice line of NURSERY
STOCK or SEED POTATOES- Stock and
See.il guaranteed. We can give you Steady
Employment with Regular Pay. It will
cost you nothing to give it a trial. State when
writing which yor prefer to sell.   Address
The Hawks Nursery Co.,
Rochester, N. Y.
CAN I OBTATN A PATENT? Fora
prompt answer and* tin honest opinion, write to
MUNN fe CO., who have had nearly fifty years'
experience in the patent business. Communications strictly confidential. A Handbook of Information concerning Patents and bow to obtain them sent free. Also a catalogue of mechanical and scientific books sent free.
Patents taken through Munn & Co. receive
Special notice in the Scientific American, and
thus are brought widely before the public without cost to the inventor. This splendid paper,
issued weekly, elegantly illustrated, has by far the
largest circulation of any scientific work in the
world.  $3 a year.   Sample copies sent free.
Building Edition, monthly, $2.50 a year. Single
copies, tia cents. Kvery number contains beautiful plates, in colors, and photographs of new
houses, with plans, enabling builders to show the
latest designs and secure contracts.   Address
MUNN & CO., New Youk, 361 Broadway.
THE SHAKER COVENANT.
This work sets forth the form of appointment, the qualifications and powers of the
several
ORDERS   OF   OFFICERS
in the Community :  of the
PRIVILEGES  and OBLIGATIONS
of all the Members, and of the
DEDICATION     AND     CONSECRATION
of persons and property.
The book will afford interest to all, and at
the same time, afford instruction to all inquiring  minds.    Price 5  cts. each,  postage
paid, or 36 cts. per doz.
WANTED
Good reliable men, to sell
our Choice and Hardy
Nursery Stock such as Fruit
Trees, Roses Shrubs and Ornamentals. Ladies make this business a success. Kasy work, pleasant, light and profitable. Outut Free. Apply at once, with references, and secure choice of territory.
W.  INT.  MA.Y   COMPANY,
Nurserymen   a,nil   Seedsmen,   Roches,
ter, N. Y.
THE  ALTRUIST.
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
-pelling, aud devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
qual rights to all. It is published by the
\ltruist Community, whose members all
live aud work together, and hold all
heir property in common, all the men and
.omen having equal rights in electing
officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. 50 rents a year;
specimen copy free. Address A. Lonklry.
Higbee,   .VI o.
is an illustrated Monthly, n<>u- niiiy 50 cts.
per     yenr.    devoted   to   PHRENOLOGY,
PHYSIOGNOMY,  HEALTH,   MEDIOAG
& SOOLiL ItEPOEM.
Would you like " copijl
Send ."> cts. for Sample  to Prof. Haddock,
Phrenologist, 1016 Market St.,
San Fn.ncisco. Cal.
Is a six-page
weekly   paper published by the ALTEURIA CO-OPERATIVE COLONY.    It   is   one  of the
ablest   reform   journals   now  published.
Price: One Year 50 cents; Six Months, 25
cents; Ten Weeks, 10 cents.    Sample copies, no charge.
Alti-ui-iii. California,
William II. O'Bryan, I3uitiiic-. Iffang-.
| Any of our subscribers who may be interested in learning' more about the "Altrurians,"
can obtain a copy of their interesting naper,
by addressing a postal card, to their Office in
Altruria, Cal.       Ed.]
HUMAN NATURE
THE ALTRURIAN
<pb n="" id="p28"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure.
A creim of  tartar  baking   powder.
Highest of all in leavening strength.
Latest   United   States   Government
Food report.
Eoyal Baking Powder Co.
106 Wall St., N. Y.
POUR
By Pressing the Lid.
Tea and Port (  Tc ts th it pour 1 \ the lid without liftnu or Tipnni        Simple he\ond belief.
Practical and artistic.   Send for pamphlet.
THE ASBURY-PAINE MFQ. CO., Phila., Ps,
This is a good thingEd.
(Established 1861.)
IS Oldest, Largest. Best,
Cheapest and the Only
weekly Bee-Paper in all
America.  32 pages. $1.00
a year.   Send for Free Sample.
$1.00 BEE-3OOK FREE
G. W. YORK & CO., 199 Randolph St., Chicago, 111,
A Visit to the
of EAST CANTERBURY,   N. H.
LLOYD II. CIIANDLER.IJ. 8 Hf
Liberally Illustrated with half tone
pictures of persons and places.
The Village of EAST CANTERBUEY
is situated in one of the lovliest spots of
New Hampshire, and is high enough to
overlook the surrounding country.
Price 15 cts.
A. SUMMAKY VIEW
OF  THE
 church:,
OB
"United   Society    of    Believers"
It treats of the Bise and Progress of the
Society, together with the   general
ciples of the Faith and Testimony.
Price 50 cts.
MILLENNIAL
American Bee Journal
H
E
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>