<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ss0501" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">Shaker and Shakeress</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Society</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Mount Lebanon, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">5</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">1</biblScope><date value="18750101" TEIform="date">January 1875</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">1-8</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="5" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="1" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="1" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">Vol. V. No. 1. PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETY, F. W. EVANS, Lebanon, Col. Co. N. Y.. January,
                        1875. Editor. Fifty Cents per annum.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="1875: 'Seven thunders uttered their voices" TEIform="index"/>1875. "Seven Thunders uttered
                            their voices."</head><p TEIform="p">G-lory to God in the highest — Peace on Earth. In place of war, Good will to all mankind,
                            especially the Household of Faith, who have kept the Gospel and obeyed its first Testimony.
                            Seven Thunders uttered their voices — Seven Testimonies. First Testimony — Against
                            Generation — perverted and per se. This was the beginning of a New Heaven — new Religious
                            System. Second Testimony — Against perverted physiology— habits of food, dress and occupa-
                            tion, which tend to create and stimulate fleshly lusts, or that ultimate in generation. Is
                            it advisable, for the children of the Resurrection, to leave the use of animal food, to the
                            children of the world, who marry and are given in marriage ? Would all. who eat flesh meat,
                            be willing to be butchers 1 Change of Life involves change of diet, as with the Egyptian
                            Israelites. Third Testimony — Against selfish agriculture— Robbing the Land — taking from
                            it, and not returning to it, the elements of food. The Land should enjoy its Sabbaths of
                            rest'—¦ should be cultivated and managed, not in the Heathenish, but in a Godly manner. The
                            accumulations of ages, of fertilizing economy, on the part of nature, should not be wasted,
                            nor squandered, for temporary ends and objects, without regard to the Laws of compensation
                            which exist between the soil and humanity, and between present and coming generations.
                            Fourth Testimony — Against perverted commerce — creating class distinctions — a general
                            desire to live without work — making labor dishonorable — Land greediness — a desire to own
                            more land than can be taken good care of, ending in speculation. By these means, the
                            inhabitants of a nation are withdrawn from the land and heaped up in villages, towns and
                            cities. The productive agencies of the country exist in the form of young men and women,
                            whose food is all raised for them, by a few overworked agriculturists. Their clothing, made
                            by operatives and machinery, in large factories, where disease-creating conditions are ever
                            present. These landless, homeless classes, in different nations, under the same system, are
                            often involved in strife and strikes with the capitalists, or in national wars of mutual
                            destruction. Fifth Testimony — Against perverted, debauched Literature—the mind-food of
                            millions— sustaining all the seven plagues of Babylon — Generative lusts, by obscene
                            Literature— Physiological lusts, by advertisements, which cause the sale of adulterated and
                            disease-creating food, and then of an endless amount of death-creating medicines,
                            administered by legal and illegal quacks, who live and thrive upon the sins of the
                            population, no better than themselves. It being like Doctor, like dupes. No National wars
                            could be long maintained without war literature and war Instrumental music. Sixth Testimony
                            — Against the prostitution of Spiritualism — Spiritualism, the mother of Science, has been
                            largely prostituted to selfish ends and purposes. "In her was found the blood of Saints and
                            Martyrs — of all that was shed upon earth." The holy wars and crusades, and the murder of
                            Spiritual Media, as witches, is common to man, and has abounded in all the Kingdoms of our
                            Christian Babylon, not excepting America. Millions of men and women, shabbily got up by
                            perverted generation — badly educated, by perverted physiology, agriculture and commerce,
                            who have passed to the lower Spirit World, return to Great Babylon — unclean spirits —
                            making its Church Organizations their cages and domiciles. Seventh Testimony — Against the
                            prostitution of Religion — Religion, instead of Love, to God and Humanity — to God in
                            Humanity, is so perverted, or inverted, as to become the synonym of Hate. Those, possessing
                            it in the largest measure, being distinguished, as murderers, above all others, either as
                            national warriors and manufacturers of war implements, so that the Heathens are constantly
                            learning the arts of war from the Christian nations — as witness China and Japan—or they are
                            pre-eminent as inquisitors — religious persecutors. Whole Peoples have, by them, been
                            exterminated from the earth, and doomed to an eternity of unbearable torment. Religion, in
                            its normal condition, is a Dove of Love and goodness. It immediately flits away from the
                            heart that admits the demon of hate. To contend about religion, is to lose the thing
                            contended for.</p></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Mikado is making almost as good a thing out of his reformation as Henry the Eighth..." TEIform="index"/>The Mikado is making almost as good a thing out of his reformation as Henry the Eighth...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The Mikado is making almost as good a thing out of his reformation as Henry the Eighth did of
                            his. One of the discarded gods of Japan is advertised for sale in a Japanese paper in the
                            following terms : " For sale, at Kama-Kura, a very fine idol with six arms. It is fifteen
                            feet high, and was cast in bronze, at Sheffield." Sheffield now shares with Birmingham the
                            doubtful honor of supplying, with impartial generosity, missionaries and bibles to the more
                            inquiring among the heathen, and idols to those who prefer to walk in the old ways.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reality of materialization in Philadelphia" TEIform="index"/>REALITY OF MATERIALIZATION IN
                            PHILADELPHIA</head><p TEIform="p">To the Editor of the Banner of Light: I am sorry to know that certain Spiritualists, who have
                            not attended a single one of the sittings for materialization by the Holmeses, in June and
                            July last, assume to decide, iti advance of personal observation, that these manifestations
                            are the result of imposture. I attended forty of the sittings then held. No one who saw "
                            Katie King " walk about, and heard her speak, and touched her, ever doubted, for a moment,
                            that she was a living, thinking being. Either, then, she was what she professed to be — a
                            spirit from another world — or else she was a confederate, secretly introduced by the
                            Holmeses for purposes of deception. But if human beings cannot pass and repass at pleasure
                            through the substance of a brick wall or of a stout walnut partition, then, under the con-
                            ditions we obtained, entrance to or exit from the cabinet except by the door into the parlor
                            where we sat, was a physical impossibility. It follows that, if human senses are good for
                            anything as evidence, the "Katie King" whom I and four or five hundred others saw and heard
                            last summer was a spirit not of this world. Of all this, and especially of the precise con-
                            ditions under which these materializations were obtained, the public will be better able to
                            judge by reference to an article, to appear in the January number of the Atlantic Monthly,
                            which I am preparing with the strictest care, containing a record of what passed during
                            these sittings. I stake whatever of reputation I may have acquired, after eighteen years'
                            study of Spiritualism, as a dispassionate observer, upon the genuine character of these
                            phenomena.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Owen, Robert Dale" TEIform="persName"/>Robert Dale Owen Philadelphia, November 2d,
                        1874.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Idol worship" TEIform="index"/>IDOL WORSHIP</head><p TEIform="p">If any presume that the day of idolatry is past, we would hasten to relieve them of the
                            hallucination, and raise a warning cry against the false gods of the day in which we live.
                            At no time, in all past human history, has idolatry been more prevalent than now — never has
                            the imperative proclamation, " Thou shalt have no gods but me," been more needed, nor more
                            opportune. And when we think of the gross blindness of the people in by-gone days, these
                            remarks become all the stronger. We are too apt to look with extreme pity or dis- gust, upon
                            those we have chosen to call heathen, because they paid much adoration to cu- riously carved
                            blocks of wood or stone, forgetting meanwhile that these are the most harm- less practices
                            of all idolatry. The homage paid to flesh and blood, to gold, to institutions of various
                            kinds, and to " idols dwelling in the heart," far surpasses, in extent and in de- pravity,
                            any former age since the history of the world began. To enumerate for denun- ciation, all
                            the idols that are holding carnival in unregenerate hearts, would fill volumes; and we
                            purpose no such undertaking. But against the whole army of figures, animate and inanimate,
                            that are occupying the place of <pb n="2" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKEK Christ in the heart, we would
                            bear testimony, while we endeavor to point out some few prominent gods, that are worse, and
                            more worshiped than any fixture of wood or brass ever erected by any heathen. That
                            selfishness is the great idol and sin of the world, there can be but small success at
                            denial. That nearly all things are made to bend to the worship of self, needs but little
                            evidence to render general proof. Inclination may lead us to set apart the Bible as an
                            object of adoration. The same may be said of the Sabbath. While we know that without the
                            spirit of truth, the letter or materiality killeth; and that " the Sabbath was made for man
                            " and not man to worship the Sabbath. Thus selfish inclinations would cause us to live to
                            uphold any and all institutions that would further the demands of self. Instead of making
                            institutions the means of self-control, abasement and consequent elevation, we too commonly
                            seek to make them the objects that shall ultimate in selfish redundancy. Making money,
                            position, fashion, dress, luxury, or any dominant desire we may have, is an idol before
                            which we are tempted to bow perpetually, consecrating thereto the first fruits of our
                            thoughts and affections. With us, as Believers, there is as much danger of idolatry as in
                            any class of people known. We may pride ourselves upon the peculi ar purity of ou r lives,
                            and at the same time be idolatrizing institutions of mammon in some of his protean forms.
                            Living apart from the world may become a matter of such lazy selfishness that we make it a
                            matter of studious gratification. We are liable to make the garments we wear, objects of
                            worship, and instead of their being representations of principles that are true, they take
                            the precedence of the principles themselves. Principle is the main thing. Let institutions,
                            young and old, subserve the purposes of godly principle ; and not principle humiliated to
                            sustain any institution. Self-abnegation, in some particular point or points, may be very
                            good; but this can never answer the purpose of an entire submission to principle. To eat or
                            drink that we may expend our strength in the gratification of other lusts, is a common
                            species of idolatry. The lusts for good (?) living will sometime appear to us as bad as any
                            other lusts. The seating of some human favorite in our hearts to rule or bias our conduct,
                            where only principle should sit, is still another common idolatrous shrine. The common god
                            of the age is gold ; and this god worships the goddess of fleshly lusts. And look where we
                            may, the world over, we find but few exceptions from the general rule that the worship of
                            women, land, and kindred monopolies, have been the idol-causes of all the wars and
                            inflictions that have ever cursed poor humanity. Let the object of our heart's worship be
                            God alone, and to love our neighbor as ourselves will be consequent fruits.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Loomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/>G. A. Loomas, Watervliet, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The importance of ventilating bedrooms is a fact in which..." TEIform="index"/>The importance of ventilating bedrooms is a fact in which...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The importance of ventilating bedrooms is a fact in which every one is vitally interested,
                            and which lew properly appreciate. If two men are to occupy a bedroom during the night, let
                            them step upon the weighing scales as they retire, and then again in the morning, and they
                            will find that their actual weight is at least a pound less in the morning. Frequently there
                            will be a loss of one or two pounds, and the average loss throughout the year will be more
                            than one pound; that is, during the night there is a loss of a pound of matter, which has
                            gone off from their bodies, from the lungs partly, and partly through the pores of the skin.
                            The escaped material is carbonic acid and decayed animal matter or poisonous
                        exhalations.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Second thunder" TEIform="index"/>SECOND THUNDER</head><p TEIform="p">Beloved Elder J. B. Vance, Alfred, Me.: The Lynn " Record," containing an account of your
                            successful meetings there, is received. I have just finished re-reading your able address —
                            wise in spirit, luminous and logical in matter. To see the rising class — the young men —
                            coming up to the help of the Lord, is a great comfort to my spirit. « Who shall go forth in
                            this fight ? The young men of the princes of the provinces." " Who shall order the battle ?
                            " Henceforth these must fight the battles of the Lord — Truth against Error — the New
                            against the Old: the second thunder sounding to raise the dead in Nature, and to awaken
                            those who are sleeping in the dust of the earth, in the present Gospel degree. Dust was to
                            be the serpent's meat, even in the Holy Mountain. In my day I have striven zealously to do
                            my work. I have fought the good fight, and kept the living faith of a Gospel-increase alive
                            in my own soul, and in the souls of many others. I glory in the cross I have borne against
                            physical lusts, other than those of generation. I am joyful in this day because I have "
                            suffered in the flesh," having ceased to eat flesh thirty-five years ago. The battle has
                            been a heavy one, for the pioneers, but victory lights upon our banner. The morning dawns;
                            the end draws near, when the waters of truth, like the Mill river flood, will burst the
                            barriers that have so long held them in check. Pretty soon the old theological dam will give
                            way all at once. It cannot much longer withstand the wear and tear of waves succeeding each
                            other, keeping up a continuous, everlasting pressure of new ideas, right from the inner
                            heavens. The primary fundamental principles of the Old Theology, laid down by the Council of
                            Nice, reformed by Luther, Calvin, Servetus, and their successors, Knox, Edwards, Bushnell,
                            Beecher, Cheever, Tyng; and reaffirmed and reissued by the Evangelical Alliance — these,
                            with Scott, Clark, Miller and Grant, and all the rest of them, are done for — the dam will
                            give way 1 My work has been to help start the lower tier of theological stones and timbers
                            in the old dilapidated structure. In the New York Tabernacle, a long time ago, I declared
                            that the Grod of Israel was a medium of powers still above him; that, even under Scripture
                            ruling, " He called them gods, unto whom the word of God, from higher powers — the
                            Christ-Heavens — came." It was strong meat for many; and when I affirmed that Jesus was not
                            the Christ, any more than Ann was the Christ; that as she was a woman, and a Gentile one at
                            that, so was Jesus a man, a Jew, who as truly confessed his sins as did Ann Lee, or as any
                            one of us has ever done,e verybody/e^ that that was just as the thing ought to be. But would
                            not the old dam of the first cycle go, if these positions were admitted and suffered to be-
                            come Orthodox ? Have we not all, in the world, been educated in the old theology of a God
                            above law, a mythical Jesus, or Christ, and of the holy Protestant Scriptures ? Did we not
                            practically believe and hold them as the word of Grod ? Was not the Protestant translation
                            the true one ? Were not the apostles — to say nothing of Jesus — unbounded in knowledge,
                            perfect in doctrine ? The fall of man from the holy, immaculate state in which God created
                            him, a full grown angelic being, by virtue of his existence, without any travail of soul —
                            our great loss by Adam's great sin, these must not he questioned ! As antichrist began to
                            work in the Primitive Church, has he not continued to work in this Church, in all physical
                            and physiological matters; for was not sickness, amongst us, a matter over which we had no
                            control ? Was it not a wise dispensation of the all-wise Creator, entirely beyond human
                            supervision? I take these positions: First, the Mosaic law is fundamental to the Gospel;
                            they belong together — complement each other. Second, there is a sharp distinction between
                            Jewish and Grentile Christianity, which must be removed. Third, all parties and processes,
                            connected with the generation of Jesus, are -wrachristian, and do not belong to the resur-
                            rection order. Fourth, no man or woman was ever born a Christian. Fifth, generation, whether
                            of Gods, Christs, Holy Ghosts, Angels, or Men and Women, is demonstration, strong as proof
                            from holy writ, that the parties concerned, from beginning to end, were in some one of the
                            earths — the most outward and external proceeding from the creative fountain of Deity, the
                            lowest of all normal spheres. The hells are abnormal. Jesus travailed into Christianity.
                            Like all Jews, he believed in a physical resurrection, and headed a general movement in the
                            spiritworld, to actualize it. He failed, but not without achieving a partial success, by
                            raising Lazarus, returning to his own body, and also raising the bodies of many other of the
                            saints who had died in the faith of a physical resurrection, and whom nothing but the fact
                            of reentering their former bodies, and then dying over again, could convince and confound.
                            They all belonged to the same race of our modern antichristians, of whom the Second
                            Adventists are the most logical type. As a Jew, Jesus believed in war; he practiced it in
                            the temple. When arrested, his company possessed, if indeed they had not sold garments to
                            provide swords. He expected spiritual assistance, and as a good Jew, properly so. He headed
                            a general insurrection against the powers that were, in the belief that he would be
                            sustained by supernatural phenomena, as were the Jews, against the inhabitants of the land
                            of Canaan. At his birth, he was so noticed. Why not in becoming " King of the Jews ? " The
                            apostles all believed in the physical resurrection, " Dunlavy" did not perceive that fact.
                            Spiritualism is a science, not a religion. Hitherto, we, as Shakers, have been but a Gentile
                            Pentecostal Church, comparatively ignorant of the physical truths of the Jewish order, which
                            the Jewish Pentecostal Church fully understood and indorsed eighteen hundred years ago.
                            J^NJD 2 <pb n="3" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKEEE88. The marriage of the Lamb has not yet occurred, except
                            so far as Ann Lee and her successors in office, power and trust, have been con- nected, by
                            magnetic and spiritual association, with Jesus and the Jews of the Pentecostal Church, in
                            the spiritual world. This Grentile Mother Church will hear the seven thunders, before she
                            will receive the whole counsel of Grod. Then will come the day that will be as the light of
                            iseven days. It is a novel idea, that good old Believers, who thought themselves perfected
                            Christians, far better than any Jews, will yet have to learn truth of them; that a perfect
                            union between the old saints of former dispensations and the new saints of this order, must
                            be effected, each party giving and receiving truths, one from the other, and becoming joined
                            like a ring. These and similar truths are now pressing upon Believers from the spirit-world.
                            We must fall at the feet of Jesus, like Paul before G-amaliel, and accept him, not as a
                            Catholic, a Protestant, nor a Greek Christian, but as a Jewish Christian. The old '¦' dam "
                            must give way, then the " flood " of truth will carry off a lot of rubbish. Old things will
                            pass away. When the ''dam" breaks, the waters will do the rest. Judgment begins at the house
                            of God; and it is a great work to convert into real Shakers, many Believers who have passed
                            out of the body. How could it be otherwise? When in the world, I was joined to a company of
                            materialists — radicals — unto whom the first principles of the new earth were being
                            revealed. We loved our fellow-man with a love that many Christians might do well to emulate.
                            But Gfod put it into our hearts to hate the Old Mill Dam — all the old theologies of
                            Christendom, of Babylonian confusion. With the subtle waters of natural truth we worked away
                            at the "old dam," like beavers, until we removed the lowest tier of foundation stones and
                            timbers, held together by rotten cement, under shoddy contracts . First, we claimed the
                            right to think, to reason; the right of conscience. Second, that belief was the result of
                            evidence, not of authority. Third, that woman was the equal of man, except in physical
                            strength, possessing the same right; that it was her province to regulate reproduction in
                            all respects, just as females of all other animals regulate it. In government, in property,
                            and in all duties of citizenship, there should be no invidious distinction nor disparaging
                            preferences. If war was improper for woman, that was proof that it was also improper for man
                            — was wrong per se. Fourth, that the land belonged, by inalienable right, to the race, not
                            to individuals; and that land monopoly preceded all the wars, and wars created chattel
                            slavery, wages, slavery and poverty — diseases coming in from secondary causes. We were as
                            truly inspired, though we knew it not, to reassert and bring forth these primary truths of a
                            new earthly order, as were Ann Lee and her compeers, to reassert and bring forth the first
                            principles of a New Heavenly Order. And that new spiritual order will never exist in its
                            glory, until it recognizes, in full, the truths pertaining to a millennium on the earth,
                            even as they are recognized by the first Pentecostal church in the spirit-world: A true,
                            godly, scientific agriculture, conjoined with a perfect physiology, that will remove the
                            causes of all diseases in the new earth and from the new heavens — a dietary as pure as was
                            the manna, and as natural. Because these truths are a two-edged sword, cutting both ways
                            upon physical and theological errors, in the natural and spiritual orders, is he who
                            iterates and reiterates them therefore an enemy? Is not truth our dearest friend, Guide and
                            guardian evermore? Will it not our plans subtend, Eeaching the immortal shore? Fraternally
                            yours,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., June 17th, 1874.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bible spiritualism" TEIform="index"/>BIBLE SPIRITUALISM</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Winder, D." TEIform="persName"/>D. WINDER</byline><p TEIform="p">TRANSFIGURATION AND MATERIALIZATION. Text : — " Jesus took Peter, James and John, and went up
                            into a high mountain to pray; and as He prayed, the fashion of His countenance was altered,
                            and His raiment was white and glittering; and behold there talked with Him two men, which
                            were Moses and Elias ; who appeared in glory, and spake of His decease which He should
                            accomplish at Jerusalem. — They (Peter, James and John) saw His glory, and the two men that
                            stood with Him."—Luke 9: 28-33. —o— The history of the physical sciences,— their dis-
                            covery, progress and development,— is being repeated in the new spiritual philosophy. A
                            little more than two centuries ago, Galileo was imprisoned for uttering the discovery that
                            our globe revolved on its axis. Previous to that time, and long after, eclipses of the sun
                            and moon, the appearance of comets, and the lurid glare of aurora borealis, were regarded as
                            supernatural phenomena, foreboding some dire calamity to the children of earth. We have an
                            example of transfiguration in the case of Stephen, the first martyr to the cause of Jesus
                            Christ. When he was brought before the Jewish Sanhedrim, and false and grievous charges
                            brought against him, we are told by the historian, Luke, that "all that sat in the council,
                            looking steadfastly on him, saw his face as it had been the face of an angel." He was not
                            only transfigured, but his spiritual vision was opened, and he cried out, "Behold, I see the
                            heavens opened, and the Son of Man standing on the right hand of God."— (Acts 6: 15, and 7:
                            55.) Advance has been made in all the physical sciences, as well as in astronomy. The
                            mysteries of the material world are rapidly unraveling, elevating the human race to a
                            physical plane far beyond either the comprehension or credence of even our grandfathers. A
                            corresponding advance is being made in the mental, moral and spiritual sciences. Not only
                            the crude ideas of the ancients in reference to natural phenomena, but the old theological
                            dogmas and creeds are being rapidly exploded, giving place to a more rational and con-
                            sistent system of moral ethics. The present is evidently a grand epoch in the history of our
                            world ; especially in its moral, religious, and spiritual phases. And it is a significant
                            fact, that the most startling religious and spiritual events of the present times, are
                            almost exact duplicates of those which characterized the period when Jesus of Nazareth
                            sojourned on earth. The history of the Nazarene and his followers is being repeated,
                            although this fact is fully recognized by comparatively few at the present time, owing to
                            the perversion and misapprehension of the events of both periods. In the imagination of the
                            masses, the events of the Nazarene period are exaggerated, while the events of the present
                            are disparaged and underrated. Unbelievers in modern spiritual phenomena delude themselves,
                            in assuming that if they could see such prodigies as are ascribed to Jesus and his
                            disciples, they would be convinced ; but the fact that thousands who witnessed the so-
                            called miracles of Jesus, rejected all his pretensions, fully demonstrates this delusion.
                            Influenced by pride and selfishness, when they could not deny the phenomena, they imputed
                            them to satanic power and influence, or deceptive magical arts. It is just so now. It seems
                            to me that even the most advanced Spiritualits are not aware of the grand stage of progress
                            already reached in this glorious development of heavenly experience and truth. As the
                            materialization of disembodied spirits, so as to render them visible, tangible and audible
                            to ordinary mortals, is now a demonstrated fact, by the most rigid scientific tests, I am
                            persuaded the way will soon be opened for the free intercourse of kindred spirits, in and
                            out of the flesh. We shall then realize the words of Paul: " Ye are come to an innumerable
                            company of angels, and to the spirits of just men made perfect." In our text, we have an
                            example of two phases of spiritual phenomena, transfiguration and materialization ; the
                            latter in the cases of Moses and Elias, who had long been inhabitants of the Spiritworld ;
                            the former in the case of Jesus of Nazareth, still in the flesh. This phase,— transfigura-
                            tion,— I regard as the highest to be obtained by earth's children in the flesh ; while
                            materialization, with all its consequent results, is the highest phase of development on the
                            part of disembodied spirits, in their relation to our mundane sphere. Jesus was then in his
                            material body, and Moses and Elias in their spiritual body. The transfiguration of his body,
                            and the materialization of theirs, had, no doubt, the effect to produce a uniformity in
                            their appearance. While on this subject, I wish to draw the attention of advanced Christian
                            Spiritualists to the peculiar physico-spiritual status of Jesus, during the forty days that
                            intervened between his resurrection and ascension. The solution of this appa- rent mystery
                            remains as one of the future achievements of Spiritual Philosophy. If we understood all now,
                            we should have no more to learn ; progress in spiritual knowledge would be at an end. The
                            further we advance in spiritual science, the more we understand of the historic records of
                            the New Testament; and the more firm and abiding our faith becomes in the truth of these
                            records. Old theologies have proved a total failure in explaining and harmonizing these
                            records. With them, the words " miracle " and " mystery" are satisfactory answers to all
                            inquiries they cannot answer. With us, our answer is, "ignorance of spiritual laws." In the
                            first place, it is certain the records testify that the physical body of Jesus was dead and
                            buried, and that his soul, or spirit, went to hades, the ordinary place of departed spirits,
                            called the intermediate state. It is also certain that his physical body was raised from the
                            dead, and reoccupied by his soul or spirit, until his ascension to heaven. These facts are
                            distinctly stated by the four Evangelists, and recognized as true by the Apostles in all
                            their speeches and writings. Peter, in his famous discourse on the day of Pentecost, says :
                            " His soul was not left in Hell (hades); neither did his flesh see corruption." Theologians
                            attach to the word "Hell" the idea of a lake of fire and brimstone. The detailed account of
                            the scene at the sepulchre of Jesus ; the testimony of angels who met the disciples there,
                            and invited them to " see the place where the Lord lay; " the meeting of Jesus in person by
                            the disciples, as they were hastening to inform their brethren ; His hailing them ; their
                            holding Him by the feet, etc., all show that His physical body was reanimated. Hence He was
                            called the " first fruits of them that slept." He was the first who was raised from the dead
                            to die no more. He appeared to His disciples on various ocasions after His resurrection; and
                            on one occasion, when they were alarmed at His sudden and unexpected appearance, and
                            supposed they "saw a spirit," He invited them to handle Him, saying: "A spirit hath not
                            flesh and bones, as you see Me have." He also asked them if they had any meat (victuals),
                            and He ate before them, to convince them that He was not a spirit, but the veritable Jesus
                            of Nazareth, in the same body He occupied before His crucifixion. Between His resurrection
                            and ascension, He had the power to ap- pear and disappear at pleasure: to enter into the
                            rooms where the disciples were assembled, with the doors bolted and locked for fear of the J
                            3 <pb n="4" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 8HAKBE Jews. He met the disciples on the road, and "their eyes were
                            held that they should not know Him," until He pleased to make Himself known. This phase of
                            Physio-Spiritual Philosophy, though remarkable and extraordinary in Jesus, was not peculiar
                            to Him. In the eighteenth chapter of the acts of the Apostles, we have an account of Philip,
                            the deacon, whom, so soon as he came out of the water, after baptizing the Eunuch, the
                            "spirit caught away, and the Eunuch saw him no more." This phase of Bible Spiritualism
                            remains yet to be developed in our new, or modern spiritual philosophy. As the angels are
                            revealing the chemical process by which spiritual bodies are materialized, when we reach the
                            phase of transfiguration, no doubt they will explain this also. Is it unreasonable to
                            conclude that the twelve men, whom Jesus educated as his scholars, understood what his views
                            about the resurrection of his body were, and that, as he believed so did they believe ? —
                            Ed.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker convention" TEIform="index"/>SHAKER CONVENTION</head><p TEIform="p">In Steinway Hall, New York, Nov. 23,1874. Delegation of sixteen Shakers. PKOGEAMME. Will
                            Shakerism depopulate the world ?—Primary ideas of God—The God of the Jews not the
                            Deity—Jesus not the Christ—Spiritualism a science, not a religion—It originated among the
                            Shakers eleven years previous to the Rochester Rappings—The Angel of Spiritual, ism—Rev.
                            chapter 18—Swedenborg cotemporary with Ann Lee—Father Evans' recent visit to the
                            Eddys—Spirits can materialize and are materialized. True religion based on physiology, and
                            secures salvation of both soul and body—supplying all spiritual and temporal wants. Two
                            Great Fundamental Orders—the earthly Order, based on correct Generation, with co- operation,
                            and the Heavenly Order, based on Christian Celibacy and Community—A new Heaven and a new
                            Earth. In the Millennium, the civil government will hold the land as common property, and
                            all labor will be performed by co-operation—a final solution of the capital and labor
                            question -—The Equality of Woman recognized—All Government offices held by intellectual
                            celibates. The Spiritual Government or Order based on Divine Revelation, through
                            Spiritualism, resulting in Christian Celibacy and Community. History—from the Jewish
                            Pentecostal to the Gentile Pentecostal Church, founded by Ann Lee. " The Reign of the
                            Beast"—" The Woman that fled into the wilderness," and the " Two Witnesses," were all in the
                            1260 years, ending in 1793, when the Shaker Order was established. The " Beast that came up
                            out of the sea," was Catholicism—" The Beast that came up out of the Earth, with ten horns,"
                            Protestantism—The " Ten Horns " were Skepticism, Infidelity, Scientism, Rationalism, etc.
                            Gentile Christianity is based on Generation and private property—Its product is blood, war,
                            prostitution and all phases of crime, through the union of Church and State which should be
                            separate. The " Doctrine of Devils "—" Seven Seals " " Seven Trumpets"—" Seven Vials "—"
                            Seven Plagues "—Perverted generation, Physiology, Agriculture, Commerce, Literature,
                            Spiritualism, and inverted Religion. Christ's Second Appearing took place in Ann Lee—In 1793
                            the foundation of the new earth was laid in the American government, which is yet to be
                            developed into a Millennial Order. Danger of putting the Jewish War God into the American
                            Constitution—Catholicism in Europe culminating in Infallibility—Protestantism in America has
                            culminated in the Beecher-Tilton lawsuits. A new Creation—Church and State are to be
                            separate—The People will live in one of the two Orders—Generative Co-operation, or Celibate
                            Communism—In both Orders will be Health of Body—All Disease, Pain and Death will be removed
                            from the people, who will enjoy life in health and happiness. Q. F. Train writes, " The
                            Shaker Convention was a grand success, and is still shaking Babylon through the press." The
                            Graphic gave a pictorial view of the Convention, quite good.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Elder Evans and the Executive Mansion" TEIform="index"/>ELDER EVANS AND THE EXECUTIVE MAN-
                            SION</head><p TEIform="p">What a text! Would you be understood there is any relation between Elder Evans and the
                            Executive Mansion ? I would be understood, may it please ye, no such thing. What would I be
                            understood ? I would be understood, that in pursuance of Elder Evans' prophecy of the
                            increase of God—the New Earth —¦ the New Generative Order, wherein shall dwell
                            Righteousness,—the next occupant of the White House may be a celibate. Why, bless your dear
                            souls, don't you see, the Empire State, true to her motto, has already taken the initiative
                            ? Sensible people comprehend that Official Station involves much drudgery. Fools don't see
                            it. Sensible people comprehend that Paternity and Maternity involve much drudgery. Fools
                            don't see that. In the New Earth aforesaid, the Righteousness aforesaid will vouchsafe to
                            the performers of the drudgery last aforesaid, immunity from the drudgery first aforesaid.
                            Those who prostitute Official Station to low ambition, or pelf, and those who prostitute the
                            Reproductive powers to gratification purposes, are fit subjects for Physiological Reformers.
                            Amen.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prentise, O." TEIform="persName"/>O. Prentise.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sympathy" TEIform="index"/>SYMPATHY</head><p TEIform="p"> " A soft answer turneth away wrath ; but grievous words stir up anger." How little we
                            appreciate the amount of good to be derived from kind words. The tides of men's lives are
                            turned by kind words, fitly spoken. A cheery " Merry Christmas," or a " Happy New Year,"
                            will draw one from a gloomy contemplation of self, and fill the heart with charity and love
                            for all mankind. Many, upon the verge of a foolish, wicked action, are, by a pleasant word,
                            or kindly recognition, drawn away, and made to look upon their trials and crosses in a light
                            modified by the sympathy so expressed ; and with renewed zeal gird their armor of good
                            resolves the closer, and spring forward in the battle they are waging against their own
                            terrible pride and passions. So let us not only sympathize with one another, but express our
                            sympathy; and in so doing enlarge our charity for the short comings, and our appreciation of
                            the struggles of others in the way of right. Then let us cultivate our powers of
                            sympathizing ; let us grow womanly in this respect, and learn to use tact and delicacy in
                            our sympathies. Let us cultivate our sensibilities, so that we may intuitively understand
                            the conditions of others, and be quick to sympathize and help. Let no lives be lost through
                            the lack of cheering words. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="E." TEIform="persName"/>E</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>BOOKS</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gardarene of spirits in prison" TEIform="index"/>Gardarene of spirits in prison</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Barrett, J. O." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">The " Gardarene or Spirits in Prison," by J. O. Barrett, and J. M. Peebles, Colbey
                                &amp; Rich, Boston. The names of these authors is a guarantee that the money of
                                purchasers will be well invested. " Eating for Strength," by Dr. Holbrook, No. 15 Laight
                                St., New York, filled with short articles and recipes, which those who cook or eat food
                                will find useful. " Primitive Christianity and Modern Spiritualism," by Eugene Crowell;
                                Vol. 1, G, W. Carlton &amp; Co., New York. A very interesting and instructive book —
                                an educator.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers" TEIform="index"/>Shakers
                        </head><p TEIform="p">[From the <cit TEIform="cit"><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New Haven daily press" TEIform="index"/>New Haven Daily Press.] </bibl><quote TEIform="quote">SHAKERS. From Elder Frederick, W. Evans, etc.: We learned that the Shakers, who
                                    are the followers of "Mother Ann" (Lee), are believers in the fulfillment of her
                                    prophecy, which was "the gathering of persons to the gospel of Christ's second
                                    appearing, of which she was the messenger." For this they hope, labor and watch.
                                    They also believe in " community of goods," and instead of attending solely to one's
                                    spiritual necessities, they care for and supply the temporal wants. The Shaker
                                    societies have never extended beyond the bounds of the United States, which is
                                    accounted for by them from the fact that their religion cannot exist and flourish
                                    except under such governments as secure freedom of speech and of the press, liberty
                                    of conscience and perfect separation between Church and State. About twenty-five
                                    years ago the use of swine as food was discontinued, and they use no alcoholic
                                    preparations except under medical advisement. Their objects in dress are modesty,
                                    health, and comfort, and unless these virtues can be promoted they never change
                                    their fashion. The other vir- tues which they claim are sexual purity, temperance in
                                    food, and all other things ; neatness, industry, peace, charity to the poor, and a
                                    prudent, saving economy in all temporal things. Each sex works in its own
                                    appropriate sphere of action, there being a proper subordination, deference and
                                    respect of the female to the male in his order, and of the male to the female in her
                                    order, so that in any of these communities the zealous ad- vocates of "woman's
                                    rights" may here find a practical realization of their ideal. We were not of course
                                    permitted to observe their peculiar form of private worship (there was no public
                                    meeting), but everyone knows that they serve God by singing and dancing, as they are
                                    " moved by the spirit." They quote the customs of the Jews, who made their Sabbaths
                                    joyous festivals, and rejoiced before the Lord with music and dancing as a
                                    justification of their mode of worship. We will not longer tire your readers with
                                    our visit to the Shakers except to say that order and neatness everywhere prevail,
                                    not only in their numerous buildings but also on their farms and in the streets. So
                                    far as we have consulted with residents in the vicinity there is but one opinion
                                    regarding the dealings of the Shakers, and that is that they are upright and
                                    honorable in all their transactions between man and man. "Our Local S."</quote></cit></p></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Chinese bankruptcy" TEIform="index"/>CHINESE BANKRUPTCY</head><p TEIform="p">They settle all money disputes among themselves, never appealing to the courts. They have a
                            novel bankruptcy practice. On the last day of the year, the Chinaman who is unable to meet
                            his obligations, pays the largest percentage he can, declaring his inability to do more. On
                            New Year's morning his creditors forgive him, embrace him, and declare him " free of the
                            books." Afterward, if able, he cancels the debt from pride, not obligation. In their cooking
                            neither butter nor milk are used.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Richardson, Albert D." TEIform="persName"/>Albert D. Richardson</byline></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We don't believe there is a calm thinking man in Wyoming who..." TEIform="index"/>We don't believe there is a calm thinking man in Wyoming who...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">We don't believe there is a calm thinking man in Wyoming who does not feel that woman's
                            presence at the ballot-box has worked for us, in the matter of elections alone, the greatest
                            reform of the age. Our elections used to be a general public row and riot, which would put
                            to shame aDonnybrookfair. Now they are as quiet, orderly and peaceable as any other
                            assemblage, no matter how heated and excited may be the campaign.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Laramie Sentinel" TEIform="index"/>Laramie Sentinel. </bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religion is the exclusive property of none..." TEIform="index"/>Religion is the exclusive property of none...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">ReIjIGION is the exclusive property of none. All religions are true in essence and aim; all
                            are sadly mixed with error and distorted by superstition. That religion will have a purer
                            and higher interpretation is one of the certainties of the future. To this the labors of all
                            good men converge and no doubt it comes as rapidly as it should.</p></div2><pb n="5" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakeress: renovated woman" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERESS. [Address at Steinway Hall.] RENOVATED
                            WOMAN</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">Friends : We appear before you as representatives of an Order of people, who have been
                            misapprehended ; and their mission has generally been misinterpreted. It is not our work,
                            nor purpose, to reprehend others for not believing, and seeing eye to eye with us, so much
                            as to reprove wrong in ourselves; and to practically raise the standard of moral virtue and
                            spiritual truth, so high, that others may thereby be led to glorify God, in word, in deed,
                            and in truth. Names, sects, parties and isms, are of little account. Every sect holds some
                            imperishable truth that belongs to God, its Fountain and Source. Truth will live. It is
                            strong, and will ultimately displace error. As far as Shakerism embodies Truth, it is potent
                            to shake what is false and untrue. But Shaherism, and its adherents, will be tested by
                            truth's unerring standard; and whatever is erroneous in their theory, or practice, will be
                            outgrown and left behind. The wheels of progression are moving and naught but truth will
                            stand, "when God in the glory of His majesty ariseth to shake terribly the earth." The work
                            of shaking is not a new thing. He shook the heavens and earth in the Jewish dispensation;
                            (their civil and religious institions.) And yet once more He has promised to shake all
                            things that can be shaken. Shaking and removing error, and establishing truth, will not be
                            accomplished by sudden revolutions and great upheavals in society, so much as by degrees,
                            and in ways that will meet the reason and conscience of intelligent immortal beings. The
                            times in which we live are propitious, fraught with actual and portentous events. Slavery,
                            in its grossest form, has been abolished. At what cost of physical life, material wealth,
                            and moral virtue, the captive's chains were broken, will be seen and felt when the present
                            generation shall sleep with their fathers. Such wounds are not soon healed. Now, Woman is
                            beginning to hear the trumpet's voice, which is sounding loud and clear, calling her to come
                            forth from the tomb wherein her .best powers and capabilities have been buried and lain
                            dormant so long. The time is fulfilled, and an Angel of the Lord has rolled away the great
                            stone from the door of the sepulcher, and is calling upon woman to leave her grave clothes
                            behind — to be resuscitated — to assert her libe-rty, and to arise in the dignity of woman-
                            hood, under the influence of regenerate life and love, and henceforth breathe the air of
                            freedom. She has a work to do — a sphere to fill — a standard to raise, and the demand for
                            labor is great. If woman would work successfully, she must keep within her own sphere. The
                            distinctive lines between the masculine and feminine are clearly denned. Love, refined from
                            sensuality, is woman's stronghold! There is great power in true love! As far as woman is
                            guided and influenced by that power, she represents the Motherhood in Deity. Man, by his
                            stern logical powers, his strength and wisdom, represents the Fatherhood in Deity. The sea
                            and land have their prescribed limits. So with man and woman. Bach should have full freedom
                            to act in their own spheres, according to the behests of conscience — moving in harmony —
                            being mutual aids, the one to the other; for without concert of action, little good can be
                            attained. As in the natural family circle it is difficult for man to fill the office of
                            father and mother both, so is it quite as difficult for a male priesthood to minister and
                            perform the duties and requisitions of both male and female. Male Saviors need the
                            co-operation of Female Saviors in the work of regeneration. The duality of Deity is a grand
                            truth, long kept within the veil; for the reason, that humanity had not progressed unto it.
                            As the veil is removed, and that truth is revealed, the mystery of godliness will pass away.
                            Who will not joyfully trim up their lamps, and go forth to meet the Bridegroom and Bride — a
                            perfect Parentage — to feel a Father's strength, and a Mother's love and care? 0, the
                            tenderness of a heavenly Mother's love! How barren the churches are without it! Many weary
                            and sin-sick children have pined and sorrowed for a spiritual Mother's love, and knew not
                            how, nor where, to find it! Now, the maternal spirit, from the highest heavens, is
                            descending through " many mansions," or spheres, using various instrumentalities, to vivify,
                            warm and bless the race. Many hearts are made glad; and a shout is heard — Welcome! thrice
                            welcome, every dove messenger, sent by our heavenly Mother, to the earth sphere. This
                            beautiful spirit is quickening the hearts of many daughters, and opening their eyes to the
                            necessity of energetic action. Already they are putting forth strong efforts in the
                            temperance cause — taking a noble and honorable part, and from our hearts we say " God bless
                            and prosper them." In the promotion of Peace principles, they are also working
                            energetically, and, we hope, successfully. If Peace prevail, War must cease. All can see
                            that two opposites — love and hate — cannot rule in the human heart at the same time. We
                            watch with profound interest every endeavor — whether by visible or invisible agencies — to
                            reform and elevate the race to which we belong. The sexual question which is now agitating
                            the public mind, and causing society to reel and totter to its very center, is of vital
                            importance. The fountain of physical life is corrupt— exceedingly foul and diseased! Can it
                            be purified and made healthy ? If so, by what means ? The marriage relation is per- verted,
                            and now chiefly used, as a cloak for licentiousness — legalized adultery. Where, and what
                            the remedy ? Will it be found in casting off all restraint? These questions remain to be
                            answered. But this truth we can fully comprehend, i. e. Man and woman, unaided by power from
                            on high, cannot roll back the flood of sensuality, which threatens to deluge the whole land.
                            Who can look upon the rising generation, and contemplate the destiny of unborn millions
                            (unless a radical change in society be effected), without having their feelings stirred, and
                            uttering deep cries of, "Lord help and save." We need a better, purer administration in
                            civil government. The vanguards of the nation should be constituted of the best minds. As
                            public opinion is one of the great kings, to whom the American people bow and do homage, the
                            creators of public opinion should be men and women of sterling integrity and principle; who
                            will raise a standard of morality and justice, in the councils of the nation. And they who,
                            through love of pelf and vain ambition, are governed by political intrigue should be counted
                            unworthy to bear rule. The religious progress of a nation greatly depends upon the status of
                            the civil government of that nation; for the civil power is the basis upon which the
                            religious must rest. How much the growth of virtue and true religion is retarded, by
                            FASHION, the goddess that rules and binds the female portion of the population of to-day;
                            unto whom they bow the knee, and give their time and strength. It is a great idol in the
                            land, that needs to be broken, just as much as the brazen images, and gods of wood and
                            stone, that Christian America sends her missionaries into foreign (so-called) heathen lands,
                            to demolish. There are some noble exceptions, who feel the need of true reform; they have
                            resolved to spend less time at the toilet, and give their strength and influence to stay the
                            fearful increase of crime, and help (if permitted) to form just laws in defense of equal
                            rights, for all lawabiding citizens, whether male or female. A stone of truth has been
                            "taken from the mountain without hands," or visible agency, and is rapidly growing at the
                            present time, i. e., Freedom for woman — her right to be and to act within the pale of God's
                            laws, without constraint from man. That stone will continue to grow and increase, no mortal
                            power can stay its course! Let woman arise and stand upon her feet, and shake herself from
                            the dust of centuries that has gathered over her by the usages of society and false
                            education, and come forth with new life, and engage in the conflict of truth against error,
                            and work for humanity. Let her efforts be directed to uplift her erring, fallen sisters.
                            Fervent prayer, dictated by pure love, will cause the heavens to bend! Angels will catch the
                            sound of deep, heart-felt intercessions, and will joyfully lend their aid. When woman
                            stretches forth her hand unto God, and earnestly pleads the cause of the poor and needy,
                            will He not hear and answer? Woman, in the hands of a higher power, is destined to become an
                            efficient worker in the cause of human progress. Let her be true and just — strong in virtue
                            —repelling every wrong. Then will the creators and upholders of the armies and navies feel
                            the loving, peaceful influence of woman, that will cause the war spirit to hide its hideous
                            head. Bv the purity of her life, and a testimonial sword proceeding from her mouth,
                            sensuality will be rebuked, intemperance will flee the <pb n="6" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 6 8HAKEE land;
                            and the white-winged dove of peace will find a resting place on this beautiful earth! May
                            Grod, through his working Angels, speed the day!</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Self-denial" TEIform="index"/>SELF-DENIAL</head><p TEIform="p">Self-Denial is a subject upon which much has been said and written, and yet it is not
                            exhausted. It is one of the grand old themes upon which we love to dwell; it opens a broad,
                            expansive field of thought and exercise of mind, and affords means for self-improvement.
                            Jesus said: " If any man will come after me, let him deny himself, take up his cross, and
                            follow me." Perhaps we have not a more perfect example of self-denial than is found in the
                            life of Jesus of Nazareth. His was the full cross against all sin. He resisted every evil
                            temptation and inclination. His whole life, as far as we have knowledge, was devoted to the
                            cause of truth to promulgate pure, undefiled religion, uncontaminated by false creeds and
                            theories. His mission was to establish a faith that would raise mankind from a state of
                            self-servitude, in which he found them, into a higher condition of spiritual freedom. To
                            accomplish that object, history informs us, he sacrificed all selfish considerations, and
                            went about doing good, teaching purity of life — of which his own was a practical illus-
                            tration. By a life of self-denial, he was lifted up into the resurrection state, and drew
                            others unto him ; and he became a Savior — Eedeemer — unto them. He was one of the greatest
                            Philanthropists the world has ever known ; and his name will be remembered and exalted
                            through all generations. While attentively reading the historical accounts of the life of
                            Jesus — how he endured the scoffs and jeers of his ignoble persecutors — the question
                            naturally arises, Why did he endure all this opposition ? Why his unremitting devotion to
                            principle — enduring the cross — despising all shame that his cruel oppressors sought to
                            heap upon him ? The answer is: " Because he loved righteousness and hated iniquity ;" and
                            was a chosen Instrument to perform a work for humanity, and to be their great Exemplar. His
                            mission was to prepare the way of holiness, that others might, with safety, walk therein.
                            And he became as a lamp to the feet, and a light to the path of all who choose to follow him
                            in the work of regeneration; aided by ministrations from on high, he raised a standard upon
                            which was inscribed Purity, Fidelity, and Self-sacrifice ! There were beauty and excellence
                            in his whole character. Every virtue found an abiding place in him. Benevolence, firmness,
                            and strength of purpose to sacrifice selfish pursuits, were manifest throughout his life. He
                            did not allow his powers to lie dormant and await some great revolution to arouse them to
                            action, but by persevering energy he '' overcame the world," and encouraged his followers to
                            do as he had done. He said : " Be of good cheer, I have overcome the world." What world was
                            it that he overcame ? He did not use carnal weapons to conquer nations ; far from it. He was
                            a man of peace ; and, if it were in his power to achieve military renown, his life was
                            devoted to a higher purpose. Jesus was a man of like passions with his disciples, and
                            overcame those in himself by the cross ; and he encouraged his disciples by bidding them be
                            of good cheer; for if it were possible for him to conquer the world in himself, it would
                            also be possible for them. The same power is given in our own time ; if we will do the
                            works, we shall experience the same results. And it is a binding requirement upon every one,
                            who " names the name of Christ, to depart from iniquity," as he did, and to put on his life
                            and character, and follow in his footsteps, and strive to promote peace and good-will among
                            men. That blessed day is approaching, prophesied of old, when " righteousness shall cover
                            the earth as the waters cover the sea, and nation shall not lift up sword against nation,
                            neither shall they learn war any more." Dawn upon us, 0 glorious day of peace ! May the work
                            of self-denial diffuse itself throughout the length and breadth of our land, and the Sun of
                            Righteousness shed abroad its searching rays, penetrating the deepest recesses of the human
                            mind, banishing, forever, the dark clouds of idolatry and superstition.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Winship, Ella" TEIform="persName"/>Ella Winship, Son Yea, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Remarks at Steinway Hall" TEIform="index"/>REMARKS AT STEINWAY HALL</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="White, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>ANNA WHITE</byline><p TEIform="p">It is a satisfaction to me to meet with the audience before us, and to have an opportunity to
                            communicate a few thoughts, and to give expression to some of the deep feelings of my heart.
                            I come before you in the humble garb of a Shaker. Yet I am not an alien. New York city is
                            the pla,ce of my nativity — the home of my early childhood. Fortune favored me with a few
                            years' residence in the State of New Jersey, where I roamed in those beautiful green meadows
                            in sight of the majestic ocean, and I never tired of watching the flowing and ebbing of the
                            tide, or listening to its surging waves. I was a child of nature, and believed in the saying
                            that " God made the country, man made the city." When I again returned to the city I could
                            not feel at home. My father, mother, brothers and sisters were here, all of whom I tenderly
                            loved, and many would have j udged that I was in possession of all that would tend to make
                            life happy and joyous. But to me it was not home. My heart was pained when I saw the
                            inequality and injustice that existed — the wealthy rolling in affluence and splendor, the
                            poor clothed in rags, and suffering from cold and hunger, I often said, " Where, O where, is
                            God's justice ! " City life seemed so artificial. It did not meet the demands of my nature,
                            nor satisfy the cravings of my immortal spirit. I turned from it all to seek a city which
                            hath foundations where love and equality reign, the fruit of which is peace. From a
                            knowledge I had obtained, through reliable sources, I believed the Shakers were in
                            possession of that which my spirit yearned to find. Accordingly in the year 1849, I visited
                            the Society at Mt. Lebanon. The childlike simplicity of their manners, and the purity of
                            their lives, won me to them, and after due deliberation I concluded that the home of the
                            Shakers should be my home, " their people my people, and their God my God." With them I have
                            toiled with my hands, and with them I have engaged in the worship of the living God, and to
                            me those seasons have been as joyous as heaven, and as solemn as eternity — the sweetest
                            hours of my life. After twenty-five years' experience, almost to a day, I return to the city
                            of my birth to testify that God dealt kindly and tenderly with me, when he sent some good
                            angel to lead me to my beautif ul consecrated home. I have never ceased to give thanks, and,
                            henceforth, all the powers of my being shall be dedicated to His service in sustaining the
                            cause of truth and righteousness upon the earth.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A man diseased in body..." TEIform="index"/>A man diseased in body...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A man diseased in body can have little joy of his wealth, be it ever so muc h.. A golden
                            crown cannot cure the headache nor a velvet slipper give ease to the gout, nor a purple robe
                            fray away a burning fever. A sick man is alike sick, wheresoever you lay him — on a bed of
                            gold or on a pad of straw ; with a silk quilt or a sorry rag on him. So no more can riches,
                            gold and silver, land and living, had a man much more than ever any man had, minister unto
                            him much joy ; yea, or any true or sound joy at all, where the mind is distract and
                            discontent.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Petition" TEIform="index"/>PETITION</head><p TEIform="p">O Lord, my God, I love thee With all my heart and soul! Do in thy loving mercy, My mind and
                            thoughts control. Thy power alone can raise me, Above the shades of death; Therefore, O God,
                            I'll praise thee, So long as I have breath! May I, to Thee, come nigher — My Light, my Life
                            and Stay; With truths, my soul inspire, O hear me when I pray! And may thy blessing, Father,
                            Descend like heavenly dew; Thy promises remember — Thy Covenants renew.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lewis, Lydia" TEIform="persName"/>Lydia Lewis, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Light" TEIform="index"/>LIGHT</head><p TEIform="p">One of the Apostles in his version of the word glory — made three divisions — "glory of the
                            sun, glory of the moon, and glory of the stars." So when speaking of Light, it may also be
                            classed under three heads, viz.: artificial, natural and spiritual. Artificial light is
                            obtained through a variety of means — gas, petroleum, whale oil, wax candles, down to the
                            rush taper. In the natural, visible heavens, luminous bodies, called suns and fixed stars,
                            revolve around the center of gravity ; they do not reflect the light of other planets, but
                            are themselves primary sources of light. Secondary planets, like the moon, have their place,
                            their glory, as well as the Primary, varying in magnitude and degree; but the nearer the
                            Secondary is to the Primary, the greater the amount of light received. Light is the agent
                            through which objects become visible to our senses, and it is indispensable to the growth
                            and development of all material substances ; without it there can be no perfection. Plants
                            that are kept in dark cellars are pale and sickly in appearance, while those of the same
                            kind, when exposed to the vivifying rays of sunlight, present a deeper, richer hue. Natural
                            things are symbols of spiritual things; the spiritual being superior, for the reason that
                            the natural is designed to meet the temporary wants and physical needs of humanity, while in
                            a terrestrial state of existence. The spiritual is created for, and adapted to, the
                            soul-needs, and reaches to the life beyond. As the solar rays are essential to animal and
                            vegetable life in the outer world, or rudimental sphere, so also are rays of divine light,
                            which emanate from the Central Sun of all worlds, indispensable to the soul's growth in the
                            ever unfolding truths pertaining to the life that is eternal. There are bodies terrestrial,
                            and bodies celestial, and there is a glory and light pertaining to each. On the natural or
                            generative plane of life, those who are the most just and moral, most strict in the
                            observance of Nature's laws, are stars, or lights to those who are lower in the scale of
                            morality than themselves. Those who, by reason of gross sins, are in darkness, are like
                            plants in a cold dark cellar, morally and spiritually diseased; and they need the power of
                            truth to lift the curtains that the light may shine upon their souls, and convict them of
                            wrong-doing, and cause them to forsake it. And they need to be acted upon, and to receive
                            the influence of the more progressed in their own Order. Those who have risen to the higher
                            Angelic Order— into the "resurrection"—above marriage, are bright spiritual lights that act
                            upon those who stand the highest, and are the most progressed in the Natural Order. And they
                            who are the most spiritually progressed, approach the nearest to the redeemed in the spirit
                            world, and receive the most directly from the Central Source of all Light, and are thus
                            enabled to shed effulgent brightness through spheres below them. Such become living,
                            hallowed temples for the indwelling of the Holy Spirit — receptacles of Light and Glory.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Offord, Emily" TEIform="persName"/>Emily Offord, Canaan, N. Y.</byline></div2><pb n="7" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Industry" TEIform="index"/>INDUSTRY</head><p TEIform="p">" Let us toil, for all that lives, Sacrifice of labor gives." To be alive in the work
                            assigned us in life's busy sphere of action, is to be fulfilling the design of our existence
                            on the earth. High powers and capacities enfolded within, need but the developing process
                            (education) to bring them forth to uses best calculated to benefit ourselves and others. Why
                            idly dream of pleasure, or languish in indolence ? Why seek rest in sloth and ease, instead
                            of uniting with living moving forces which are actively engaged to progress and hasten the
                            growth of all in Nature's realm ? Toiling myriads therein, mock the trial. " Go to the ant
                            thou sluggard, learn of her ways and be wise." Untiring industry marks the life of the tiny
                            creatures, as they build, and gather, and store away their food for future use, on the real
                            communistic plan, as do the bees. It is proverbial that the busy bee through all the sunny
                            hours toils unceasingly sipping honey drops from fields of fairest bloom; yet God
                            replenishes their cups with sweetness ; and their toil is not in vain. Nor are the curious
                            little workers selfish; they fill many a cell beyond their own need, and man with all his
                            intellect, not half so " wise in his day and generation," feasts on the fruits of their
                            industry, without realizing the worth of hard earned labor, spent in its accumulation, which
                            he would be quite unwilling to give for others. Thus it is with all the sweets and blessings
                            of life and home; they come not by chance. Heaven has not ordained that they should drop
                            down upon us to curse, instead of bless, our existence. These are the well-earned fruits of
                            industry, gathered and secured to us through cheerful sacrifice in duty, and a lofty purpose
                            of doing good. It is in the beautiful well ordered system of Christianity, that we behold,
                            outwrought, those glorious principles which create the com- mon brotherhood of man, and
                            sustain mutual, fraternal industry, in its highest and best forms. The Gospel never repealed
                            the rulings, " In the sweat of thy face shalt thou eat thy bread;" but in
                            justice—righteousness and equality — gives to labor new dignity, and transforms it from
                            menial slavish servitude, to pleasant, active occupation. Herein lies the Christian's
                            warfare against selfhood, with heart wrapt in coat of mail — shrinking closely within its
                            narrow sphere, in constant terror of being drawn too far from its contracted limits, into
                            the broadening field of true philanthropy, where it will be robbed of that ease-loving
                            spirit, which fixes bounds for the soul's expansion, and dwarfs the powers of mind and body.
                            It is this low sordid selfishness that makes the world just what it is,— "a school of wrong
                            — " where a greedy, grasping love of gain to waste in prodigality, and sensual indulgence,
                            and where selfdestructive pleasure is the ruling motive. In our beautiful love-built Zion
                            home, I behold, with exceeding joy, the actualization of the highest and purest ideal of
                            life, which many have longed and waited to see, but were not able to attain unto. Here is,
                            indeed, a spiritual communion of self-sacrificing souls, devoted unreservedly to each
                            other's good, influenced by chaste soul love, they form a heaven upon earth. " Always busy,"
                            I once remarked to an aged sister, who was plying her needle with the quiet but queenly air
                            of one whom indolence had never dwarfed nor selfishness bemeaned. '•I never spent many
                            moments idly in my life," was her pleasant response. Her long life, like that of many
                            others, had been given in a noble service. Such fulfill the apostolic injunction " Not
                            slothful in business ; fervent in spirit, serving the Lord." It is this real fervency of
                            spirit, enlisted in a good cause, that gives zest to labor, sunders the soul from
                            selfishness, and lights it with a glow of expansive life, akin to the benign influence of
                            sunlight. 0 may the young, who are sharing the blessing of consecrated toil, make firm their
                            resolve to live for lofty aims and benevolent purposes, to strike their roots deep in the
                            soil of usefulness — spread wide their branches of industry, and let their clustering leaves
                            be the growth of well filled moments ; then like grand old Oaks, their shade will, in time,
                            be a grateful retreat for the toil worn and weary, and the blessing that faileth not shall
                            be the reward of well doing.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>Martha J. Anderson, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Duty of children to superiors" TEIform="index"/>DUTY OF CHILDREN TO SUPERIORS</head><p TEIform="p">The editorial upon "Government of Children," in December No. of Shaker and Shakeress, is
                            calculated to awaken thought concerning the duty of youth and children toward their parents,
                            guardians and seniors. When I read, " 'Tis the duty of parents and guardians to study the
                            germinal traits of character in children, and make due allowance for peculiarity of
                            disposition, circumstances of birth, and how they can best secure their confidence," it came
                            home to me; and I felt that I had cause to render thanks for the kind consideration extended
                            to me in my more youthful days. True, I had passed the period of early childhood before I
                            found those who really understood my nature, and could comprehend my needs. Constitutionally
                            I was impulsive — strong-spirited — and independent; but the voice of reason, mixed with
                            love and tenderness, led me to self-conquest. I have yet many years to pass before I reach
                            the meridian of life, and I still feel the need of wise counselors to aid me; that all my
                            physical, mental and spiritual powers may unfold, expand and grow, and be a blessing to
                            myself and others. I have learned one important lesson, i. e.: Those who, through love and
                            kindness, restrained me when I was running too far, and too fast, and guided my wayward feet
                            in the path of wisdom which leads to peace, were my truest and best friends. And I do not
                            cease to give thanks to God for such Angel guides, as they have been to me. I am confident
                            that youth and children who are the most submissive, obedient and teachable, receive the
                            greatest benefit from the instruction of parents and those who watch over them for good.
                            Children and youth bear the same relation to advancing life that time bears to eternity. If
                            children are dutiful, there is a modesty and pliability attending that period of life. It is
                            their normal condition; and they are adorned with innocence and simplicity which makes them
                            beautiful. They who possess those adornings, if attentive and industrious in learning, and
                            practicing the lessons taught them, will increase in knowledge and goodness, instead of
                            having those virtues turned to arrogance and self-conceit, which bar the way to cultivation
                            and moral growth. Habits formed in early life are the most en- during. Impressions made in
                            childhood are slow to fade. The mind is then free from the cares and burdens which riper
                            years impose — is ready for ideas — the memory is clear and retentive, suited to gather and
                            retain the first seed sown, whether good or bad. Therefore, children and youth should have
                            the opportunity afforded them to obtain true and just conceptions of life. The right use of
                            instruction and knowledge, is to free the mind from ignorance and prejudice, whether
                            inherited or acquired. Life might be a paradise of beauty, if the seeds of disobedience had
                            no soil wherein to germinate and grow. May we not hope the time will come when that woe will
                            be removed? This state of things can be attained unto only by individual exertion and
                            self-sacrifice. Obedience to conviction of right and duty in all things, will dispel the
                            darkness and sorrow caused by disobedience. The result of adher- ing to principle would be
                            to elevate individuals ; then, to exalt nations. Those who regard the laws of their being,
                            and are true to their convictions, are ~the stronghold of the earth, and assist the public
                            conscience in rising to a higher plane of action ; and those who begin in early life to
                            perform good deeds, may stand in the innocence and beauty of life through time, never
                            feeling the blight of sensuality. I rejoice to know that there is an Order of people where
                            principle is first, and pleasure derived from the senses is subordinate. From their
                            standpoint of observation, they discern the wrongs and evils of society — and mourn their
                            fearful ravages ; while they toil and battle to destroy the dragon power that is devouring
                            the youth of the land. What then shall be the duty of the rising generation toward those who
                            are giving their lives for the good of humanity, if not humble, submissive love and
                            obedience? Outside of the Shaker Order, there have been parents who instilled right
                            principles into the minds of their children, and reared them to be national guides — lights
                            — in their day. To Washington, Lady Jane Grey, Margaret Prooper, Abraham Lincoln, and many
                            others, is honor due. They were stars in the terrestrial heav- ens. Believers in Christ's
                            Second Appearing are called to be stars in the Celestial heavens, to teach the higher truths
                            and the law of love. Under the power of that love the impulsive child is made penitent; the
                            irreligious to feel reverence for sacred things. All this I have seen; and I am thankful
                            that, within my Zion home, children are governed in justice and love, and are taught to be
                            pure and truthful. The same impression cannot be made upon all minds. If some turn to the
                            weak and vain things of the world, to seek indulgence in carnal pleasure, after having been
                            taught the higher life, they never forget the lessons which have been given them; and
                            inasmuch as they sin against light, they have to feel the stings of a guilty conscience.
                            While those who study well and are true to conviction, will be as the flowers of heaven that
                            bloom with beauty in the spirit-land.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Byrdsall, Charlotte" TEIform="persName"/>Charlotte Byrdsall, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Missionary" TEIform="index"/>MISSIONARY</head><p TEIform="p">Go forth little "Shaker," your mission fulfill: Proclaim the glad tidings of peace and good
                            will, Lift up thy bright banner, and on it inscribe, "Love is our motto, and truth is our
                            guide." Encourage the falt'ring, and strengthen the weak; If man would be happy, God's law
                            he must keep ; For sorrow must follow departure from this, And, just in proportion, diminish
                            his bliss. Go say to our Brothers and Sisters abroad, Though erring, fear not; for our
                            Parents are good ; They send to earth, Saviors, in mortals to dwell, That souls may shun
                            evil, and learn to do well. And thus, by progression, mankind will ascend In spirit with
                            Father and Mother to blend; As true sons and daughters, complete the great chain Encircling
                            humanity's Ocean and Plain.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cantrell, Eunice" TEIform="persName"/>Eunice Cantrell, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Suggestion" TEIform="index"/>A SUGGESTION</head><p TEIform="p">Ministers often hold conventions, to which delegates are sent from various churches, lo-
                            cated in different parts of the country. Would it not be a good thing for ministers' wives
                            and some earnest, pure-minded women, to hold conventions also, and take counsel together,
                            and construct some rules of propriety to be observed by the spiritual leaders of the people,
                            and exert a saving influence, over the Clergy, in this way ? By timely effort in this
                            direction, they might do much to save the reputation of their husbands, ward off shame,
                            confusion and disgrace from the churches; and be help-meets, in a spiritual point of view,
                            as well as in the domestic relations of life. Where could man look for an impartial ad-
                            vocate and supporter of his character, if not in the partner of his life, if she be a true
                            woman V In his ministerial duties, she might shield him from temptation, in many ways, and
                            also be a Mother, in a degree, in the Church over which her husband presides; to whom
                            burdened, suffering females might find access, and unbosom their griefs and sorrows and find
                            some relief. If they would become ensamples to their sisters in the Church, in dress and
                            manners, and strive to silence the tongue of slander — discourage envy and jealousy, I be-
                            lieve God would bless their efforts.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pirley, Nancy" TEIform="persName"/>Nancy Pirley, West Pittsfield, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker and shakeress" TEIform="index"/>THE SHAKER AND SHAKERESS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Postage prepaid. It is decided to let the outside subscribers have the paper for fifty cents,
                            as heretofore, and to charge all Believers fifty cents.</p></div2><pb n="8" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Coming year" TEIform="index"/>THE COMING YEAR</head><p TEIform="p">1. Hail! hail the glad New Year! Its comingjoy our hearts will cheer; The errors of the past
                            we leave, And truth's advancing light receive. By whose diffusion we may see, The Lamb
                            and lion yet agree, This happy coming year, This happy coming year. 2. Though labors new
                            await our hands, We will not bind in iron bands The talent God to us hath given To make our
                            home on earth a beav'n. But sow anew the precious grain, And scatter broadcast o'er the
                            plain, This joyous coming year, This joyous coming year, The seeds of goodness, love and
                            peace, Of kindness with its rich increase, These in our hearts' best soil shall live, Till
                            blossoms sweet their perfume give, While rlpen'd grain in sheaves well bound, Shall in our
                            garner-room be found, This joyous happy year, This joyous happy year.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Welcome: to our missionaries" TEIform="index"/>WELCOME. TO OUR MISSIONARIES</head><p TEIform="p">Welcome as the sight of haven to the starving sailor crew, Welcome as the sparkling waters to
                            the desert trav'ler's view, Welcome as the fresh'ning showers to the parched and thirsty
                            earth, Welcome as the truth of heaven to the soul that feels its worth, Welcome as love's
                            healing balm is to the bruised and wounded breast, The return of Zion's mission to their
                            Gospel kindred blest. Yea, we greet you, well beloved ! Ye have nobly fought the fight,
                            Victors' laurels wreathe the brows of those who conquer wrong with right, Hate with love,
                            and selfishness supplant with feelings good and kind, Who exhale a peaceful sphere of love
                            and purity of mind. Ye have cast upon the waters —but ye have not lost the seed; It shall
                            germinate in souls that saviors on Mt. Zion need; They shall flock to Zion's borders, sick
                            of sin and selfish strife, They shall find a promised land and eat the precious bread of
                            life. Freely have ye sown the seed, and bounteous harvest shall ye reap ; Ransom'd souls
                            shall yet rejoicing heartfelt blessings on you heap. Not of the redeeming power of
                            slaughter'd martyr's sacred blood, Shed for ev'ry erring mortal drown'd in sin's o'er-
                            whelrning flood, Waa the burthen of your message to the mixed and motley throng. Nav, a more
                            exalted theme— a testimony stern and strong, 'Gainst a selfish life of sin, against
                            hypocrisy and sham That gives carnality free scope while trusting in a slaughtered Lamb.
                            (Lamb or man, it matters not, the principle's the same; who seek Salvation through the grace
                            of God and faith in Calvary are weak.) Help thyself and God will help thee was the burthen
                            of your song; Self-reliance, active effort is the maxim of the strong. Ye have taught the
                            law of kindness, not to fellowman alone, But to ev'ry living creature that can cruelty be-
                            moan ; Ye have inculcated justice, mercy, charity and love; Ye have blest all honest effort
                            pain and suff'ring to remove. And the angels bless your labors; we most heartily unite: — We
                            who here at home, in peace, remember'd those who fought the fight, Braved the storm, the
                            moil and turmoil, found in Bab'lon's busy mart, Spreading Gospel tidings : —lovingly we
                            clasp you to our heart. Welcome, father, mother, sister, brother, Gospel kindred dear,
                            Welcome, Zion missionaries, kindly welcome here!</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Brown, Hewson" TEIform="persName"/>Hewson Brown, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Forethought" TEIform="index"/>FORETHOUGHT</head><p TEIform="p">New Year's Gift. I'll write it on the snowy page That now before me lies ; I'll blend it with
                            the roaming themes That to my vision rise. I'll call it when emotions swell, To check their
                            flowing tide ; I'll wear it as a gift of God, To humble all my pride. I'll bring it as a
                            helping hand, Wherever need is found; I'll sow it as a precious seed Upon the holy ground.
                            I'll prize it as parental love, To keep regret afar; To bless the harvest of the year, And
                            be its ruling star. I'll wrap my spirit in its light. That darkness may not come, I'll hold
                            it as a motto bright, Within my sacred home.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Devyr, C." TEIform="persName"/>C. Devyr, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editors" TEIform="index"/>EDITORS</head><p TEIform="p">Editors cannot always help themselves. They are at the mercy of the agents they employ. But
                            the engagement of such agents ought surely to form one of the sacraments of life. A man who
                            undertakes to report what he sees, or hears, ought to make truthfulness his religion, and to
                            be ready to cut off his right hand rather than let it write down falsehood. The lies and
                            slanders which go up and down the land, blighting fair fames, impeding holy causes, and
                            doing the devil's work of perpetuating evil, will take decades of years to undo. And on the
                            authors of those misrepresentations will lie the heaviest guilt — the guilt of perverting
                            good to evil, of wantonly turning the best instrument of truth to the base service of
                            falsehood, and of betraying the confidence reposed in them, and thus weakening trust between
                            man and man all the world over. — </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Vosey, Charles" TEIform="persName"/>Charles Vosey</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="According to Bayard Taylor, the women of ancient Egypt..." TEIform="index"/>According to Bayard Taylor, the women of ancient Egypt...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">According to Bayard Taylor, the women of ancient Egypt enjoyed many of the rights for which
                            the strong-minded sisterhood contend today. The wife's name was often placed before that of
                            the husband, and the sons often bore the names of the mothers, instead of those of the
                            fathers. Indeed, the man possessed no important right which was not equally shared with the
                            woman.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sonnet" TEIform="index"/>SONNET</head><p TEIform="p">Is future life a shadowy dream A myth that puzzles still the brain ? Or closely folded as a
                            ream Of unwrit leaves, without a stain? Closed volume, to material sense, That governs with
                            imperial rod, And brings the meagre recompense A final home beneath the sod ? * * * The soui
                            recoils; a secret spark Flames with the light of endless day; No longer veiled in dungeon
                            dark, Or screened by perishable clay, It rises up on Hope's bright wing, Of immortality to
                            sing.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>Martha J. Anderson, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Jefferson, Sarah E." TEIform="index"/>Sarah E. Jefferson
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Jefferson, Sarah E." TEIform="persName">Sarah E. Jefferson</persName>, aged 18 years, June
                                16,1874, Harvard, Mass.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Smith, Hannah" TEIform="index"/>Hannah Smith
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Smith, Hannah" TEIform="persName">Hannah Smith</persName>, aged 66 years, November 26,1874,
                                Second Family, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div3></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>