<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2412" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">28</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">East Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">24</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">12</biblScope><date value="18941201" TEIform="date">December 1894</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">269-292</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="24" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="12" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
DECEMBER.
MANIFESTO
PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES.
VOL. XXIV.
' Cast thy brkad upon thk waters ; for thou Shalt find it after many days."
Eccl. XI: i.
East Canterbury, N. H.
1894.
THE
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
hardy Nursery Stock, and Seed Potatoes, full and complete line. Many varieties can only be obtained through us.
Commission or salary paid weekly, and
promptly. Exclusive and choice of territory given. Don't delay, write at once
for terms.
ALLEN NURSERY CO.
Rochester, N. Y.
THE  ALTRUIST.
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetk
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is published by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all
their property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing
officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. 50 cents a year,
specimen copy free. Address A. Longlky
901 Olive St.,   St. Louis, Mo.
cMATSJRADE Marks
COPYRIGHTS.
CAN I OBTAIN A PATENT? Fora
prompt answer and an honest opinion, write to
MUNN tfc CO., who have had nearly fifty years'
experience in the patent business. Communications strictly confidential." A Handbook of Information concerning Patents and how to obtain them sent free. Also a catalogue of mechanical and scientific books sent free.
Patents taken through Munn & Co. receive
special notice in the Scientific American, and
thus are brought widely before the public without cost to the inventor. This splendid paper,
issued weekly, elegantly illustrated, has by far the
largest circulation of any scientific work in the
world.   $3 a year.   Sample copies sent free.
Building Edition, monthly, $2.50 a year. Single
copies, '25 cents. Every number contains beautiful plates, in colors, and phptographs of new
houses, with plans, enabling builders to show the
latest designs and secure contracts.   Address
MUNN & CO., New Yoi:k, 361 Broadway.
SHAKER'S   ANSWER
TO  THE  OFT REPEATED   C2UESTION,
""What   will   become   of   the
World, if all become Shakers?"
Price, 10 cts.
HOW TO GET RICH,
To make money rapidly, become independent, and enjoy a life of ease, has been
the ambition of mankind since the days
of Adam! "Show me how, and quickly,"
is the cry. While the ways of making
money are many and varied, the most
successful, and that in which the largest
fortunes have been accumulated can be
told in one word, Speculation!
In a measure we are all speculators,
whether we buy merchandise which we
expect to sell at a profit, houses and lands
which we hold for an advance, or stocks,
bonds and grain. But of all commodities,
stocks and grain pay the greatest profit.
The values are better known and you can
always find a market. No long tedious
waits, perhaps for months before you
realize a profit (as in the case of the development of land,) but a constant and
rapid change in values, registered daily
on the "Ticker," and which if taken
advantage of lead to large gains. It is
impossible to set forth in an article of this
character, the ways of speculating and
the many advantages to be obtained 1 y
a Broker who is constant y on the
ground. Suffice it to Fay: We have had
a large experience in the Stock Brokerage
business, and our book on Stock Speculation fully explains in all its details tljj
method of speculation.
We charge a commission of but 1-16 in
the execution of all orders, and where the
trader does not have easy access to the
markets, we give him the benefit of our
experience by accepting discretionary
orders, or in other words, buy and sell
to the best of our judgment for his account and profit.
We deal in Stocks, Grain and Provisions in lots of ten share and upwards on
a margin of from 3 to 5 per cent., and all
orders receive personal and prompt attention. Orders can be sent by mail or telegraph at our expense. Deposits received
subject to check, and satisfaction guaranteed.      Correspondence solicited.
STANDARD STOCK
4O BROADWAT,
 YORK, US. Y.
Provincial Department, Room 36.
Reliable   men   to
sell our choice and
WANTED.
EXCHANGE,
A--><pb n="269" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="History of South Union, Kentucky, [no. 14]" TEIform="index"/>HISTORY OF SOUTH UNION, KY.
                            No. 14.</head><p TEIform="p">MAR. 8. 1864. Two Federal soldiers by the name of Proctor are on a visit to their father, who
                            is one of our neighbors. Sunday, Mar. 9. The Federal Officers have been making arrests, of
                            Southern sympathizers and want the Brethren to take one man to Bowling Green. Our Brethren
                            are quite unwilling to give so much aid in the interests of the war, and beg to be excused,
                            fearing it might bring more persecution on the Society. The Officers, learning that we have
                            a carriage and horses, say to the Brethren, "You must do it." .,. This was a military order,
                            and one of the Brethren was appointed to attend to the duty. The ride to Bowling Green was a
                            very quiet one, and at that place the Officers and prisoner left the carriage, so that the
                            Brother returned to the Village the same evening. ., Mar. 30. We receive several letters
                            from gospel friends which give us much comfort, after our long, forced imprisonment under
                            military orders. The letters are from Mt. Lebanon, Union Village, White Water, Watervliet,
                            O. and from Canterbury. We are still remembered, and this comforting assurance is to us a
                            heavenly treasure. Mar. 31. A quantity of food is prepared and sent to Bowling Green for the
                            sick soldiers. Elder Solomon goes on this mission of mercy, and is able by this deed of
                            kindness to make many hearts glad. To-day we record the death of our Brother, John McLean,
                            who has been sick with Pneumonia only three days. He was sixty-five years of age, and
                            universally beloved. April, .10... The U. S. Mail arrives at our Post Office, it being the
                            first time since Sept. 17, 1861. DECEMBER <pb n="270" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 270 THE MANIFESTO. May, 11.
                            Rumor tells us that Col. John Morgan and his company have entered the state of Kentucky, and
                            haw already burned some fifty-six loaded freight cars. They captured four thousand dollars
                            from the Adam's Express and also s veral Union Soldiers. Additional supplies of food are
                            sent to the sick soldiers at Bowling Green, also several loads of strawberries, sent to the
                            same place, are sold. The berries find a ready market. May, 29. Four hundred Union Cavalry
                            camp near our Village. They came from Springfield, Tenn. and are going to Bowling Green.
                            They are all very orderly. We saw them as they came in groups to the well to obtain water,
                            to the kitchen for bread, and to the dairy for milk. In the evening the band favors us with
                            a beautiful serenade in front of the family Dwelling. They then march to the North family
                            and on to the East family, playing several pieces before their dwellings. On their return to
                            our family they are invited to a lunch, which they accept with many thanks. May, 30. Several
                            of the Brethren and Sisters are busy nearly all night preparing a free breakfast for the
                            whole battalion that is encamped on our premises. The dining tables are moved into the
                            door-yard and placed under the maple trees, The Officers aie accommodated at the Trustees'
                            Office. After the tables in the yard are prepared, the soldiers march to them in good order,
                            and seem to enjoy the repast. The breakfast consisted of beef, veal, fried ham and eggs,
                            sweet and Irish potatoes, hot biscuit, corn bread, canned peaches, fresh strawberries and
                            the best of coffee. Col. Williams said he must go and see the soldiers at their table before
                            he could eat his breakfast. Some of the soldiers who disobeyed their orders by going to the
                            families after milk and bread were punished by leading their horses on their way to Bowling
                            Green, a distance of fourteen miles. All the soldiers take leave of us at 7-30 a. m. The
                            band stop in front of the family dwelling and play two more pieces. Then four hundred voices
                            give three cheers for the hospitality of the Shakers. Our hearts are filled with pity as we
                            reflect upon the duty of this large body of men who have left their pleasant homes and
                            peaceful occupations, to engage in all the horrors and privations of a cruel war. June, 1,
                            Sunday. The two beautiful horses which Br. Urban has just bought, were stolen last night. On
                            the 6th we learn that our stolen horses were found hitched in the street in Elkton, Todd
                            Co., Ky. Several of the Brethren went in search of the horses, and on the 7th they were
                            found as above stated, and the man who had them in charge, only accepted ten dollars for his
                            trouble. June, 18. Br. Urban goes to Louisville to meet the Ministry of Mt. Lebanon. He
                            waits till the 21st. inst. and then returns without them. On the 26th, the Ministry arrive
                            at Bowling Green and are met at that place by Br. George Rankin. The Ministry are with us
                            till July 9th, when they take the cars for Louisville, and then to Pleasant Hill. <pb n="271" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 271 July, 10. Our company of three who accompanied the
                            Ministry to Louisville, take the cars for home. After riding about twenty miles the
                            conductor received a dispatch from Gen. Boyle to return to the city, as it was not sale to
                            proceed. On the 12th we again take the cars for home. A company of soldiers are on board,
                            and many others are stationed as guards by the side of the road. We, however, reached home
                            in safety. July, 22. The Confederates are still sanguine of success, and are holding
                            meetings in our neighborhood. July, 28. Thirty Union soldiers passed through our Village
                            last night, but moved so quietly that few heard them. Aug. 5. We prepare breakfast for one
                            hundred and twenty. They say they are very hungry. As the company does not offer to pay for
                            this repast, we remain quiet and receive only their thanks. Aug. 6. A large bay horse was
                            stolen last night. Companies are being formed in our neighborhood, to enter the southern
                            army, and they say that if they do not take the horses, the northerners will. Aug. 10.
                            Sunday. No cars pass to-day, and it causes some uneasiness in our minds. Aug. 11. One of the
                            Brethren is stopped on the road and three men dismount to examine his horse. They are quite
                            thorough, but when they go in the rear of the horse, the Brother uses his spurs, leaving the
                            company in wonderment. The Brethren are obliged to hide our horses, and to watch them day
                            and night. We are now asked to furnish twenty-five loaves of bread a day for the soldiers in
                            Russellville. We receive three cents per pound. Aug. 13. A Brother and two Sisters go on a
                            visit to Bowling Green. When they reached the pickets, they were ordered to halt and told
                            that they could not pass. Finally they were allowed to drive on as ladies were in the
                            carriage, but thought there would be trouble in getting out of the place. As Br. Urban was
                            so well acquainted with Col. Bruce, he had no fears and drove on. We now learn that Col.
                            Faust with eight thousand soldiers, has made a raid on Gallistan, Tenn. and destroyed a
                            large amount of property. We also learn it was expected that Gen. Morgan would make a raid
                            on Bowling Green and surprise the Federals. Morgan captured four hundred Federal soldiers
                            and then left the place. This so frightened the Union people, that every able-bodied man was
                            ordered to be armed and in readiness for action. Br. Urban and the Sisters returned without
                            harm, after spending most of the day at Bowling Green. (To be continued.)</p></div2><pb n="272" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Instruction divine" TEIform="index"/>INSTRUCTION DIVINE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName"/>By Abraham Perkins.</byline><p TEIform="p">OUR Heavenly Father draweth nigh, and our Heavenly Mother appeareth. They give us words of
                            eternal life ; a testimony that teaches the power of salvation, and the means to obtain it.
                            1 hear it every day. I hear it in the hills and in the valleys. I h ar it at my work and in
                            my hours of rest. I hear it at our convocations for worship, which then especially awakens
                            my responsibility. It causes me to question my life and to examine my works. It scrutinizes
                            closely the preparation made for that baptism for which so much is asked in our prayers. It
                            seeks to know how thoroughly the work has been done to prepare the soul for Chrisiian
                            baptism, by honest confession in the order of God, thus showing my deeds, bringing them to
                            the light, as did Achan in the presence of God's image, a living witness, without reserve
                            and no dissemblance, as was witnessed in the act of Ananias and Sapphira for selfish ends.
                            It teaches where the light of God is revealed and is to be found,a trust committed to the
                            Christian Church, where stands the altar with its Melchisedec priesthood, unto whom is
                            committed the keys of Christ's kingdom with power to bind and to loose as it is done in
                            heaven, as Jesus declared. It teaches us to prune and dress our own gardens and not look for
                            weeds in others; to cast the beam from our own eyes ere we can see clearly, motes in other's
                            eyes. It teaches thankfulness of heart for the degree of goodness we have found, even though
                            we have not obtained all we seek, or attained to the condition which gives the most perfect
                            control of our spirit. It teaches that our ministrations should portray the best, the
                            strongest and brightest side of life, and not the weakest, the discouraging and hopeless
                            conditions; and teaches the spirit of kindness, love and peace, opening channels to sanctum
                            sanctorum, the holy of holies. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shirley shakers" TEIform="index"/>SHIRLEY SHAKERS.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The Community Celebrates the 102nd Anniversary. ON Saturday the Shaker
                                    Communities of Shirley completed 101 years of existence, but the day was not
                                    observed by any public manifestation. Sunday, however, at the Community's morning
                                    devotions, Elder John Whiteley made a brief allusion to the fact, and spoke a few
                                    words specially appropriate to the interesting event. The thoughts of all the
                                    Community went back to the stormy times of 100 years ago when the little band of
                                    Believers were just growing into prominence. The names of the leading lights of the
                                    Community in the past arose before the mind's eye; then their thoughts drifted to
                                    the little cemetery on the hillside, "Where the rude forefathers of the hamlet
                                    sleep." <pb n="273" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 273 The past has for these earnest,
                                    industrious, honest and simple-minded people an irresistible charm. Noble men and
                                    women rest in their soil, who gave up the baser forms of life for the more serious
                                    and higher form of existence. Actuated by a desire to follow more closely in the
                                    footsteps of the carp -nter of Nazareth, they left the world and its allurements and
                                    joined with fellowmen in a simpler and purer life. On Sunday, the Shakers looked
                                    with pardonable pride on the past and not without hope to the future. True, time has
                                    somewhat thinned their ranks, and men hnd women, to-day, do not readily volunteer to
                                    assume the obligations of Shaker life, yet in spite of this the future is not
                                    without encouragement. The industrious and frugal Brothers and Sisters of the past,
                                    built up a strong and noble family; they grew from almost nothing to comfort and
                                    contentment, if not to affluence, in spite of opposition and persecution. Today, the
                                    Community, while smaller than thirty and forty and fifty years ago, is strong in the
                                    faith, has thousands of broad acres and no incumbrance. All that is needed to give
                                    the family the strength former days is willing hands and faithful hearts. When men
                                    and women pause and think, when they will compare the life of the city, or rather
                                    the struggle for existence in the cities, with the quiet, peaceful and contented
                                    life of the Shaker Communities, the revival in Shakerism will commence and they will
                                    gladly throw aside the baser passions and become believers in a faith that tends
                                    only to elevate and ennoble. The Shirley Community has made all preparations for the
                                    winter. The harvest has been bountiful and well cared for. The apple crop, now one
                                    of the most important to the Community, has been good, and in addition to the 1500
                                    barrels shipped to England and to the West, a large quantity were ground up into
                                    cider, which has been boiled preparatory to being used in the manufacture of their
                                    famous Shaker apple sauce. The Community will commence the manufacture of this
                                    famous sauce within two weeks and will have a large quantity made and ready for
                                    shipment before Thanksgiving day. So well established has this product become, that
                                    the market is now usually larger than the product.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>�Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Millennium" TEIform="index"/>THE MILLENNIUM.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, Catherine" TEIform="persName"/>By Catherine Allen.</byline><p TEIform="p">T I THROUGH the various ideals for which this word has long been a synJL onym, we are able to
                            trace the evolution of races and the general progress of humanity. In the hearts of all
                            nations and races (save the most barbarous,) have glowed ideals of some future "golden age,"
                            and through all time have been brave prophet souls quickened from the inner spheres whose
                            teachings have <pb n="274" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 274 THE MANIFESTO. gradually refined and elevated these
                            ideals from the gross and selfish, to the grand conception of the Brotherhood of Man, in
                            which is recognized: "One God, one law, one element, And one far off divine event To which
                            the whole creation moves." What shall be this "divine event," and how may those conditions
                            be attained through which its glory will be wiought? As we understand it, the Millennium
                            will not consist in any ultimate beyond which advancement will be undesirable, but in the
                            placing of man in such relation to his fellows as will give to each individual equal
                            opportunity to develop all his powers;a condition of society in which no distinctions will
                            be recognized save those of usefulness and worth, and the differences of natural endowment.
                            A government carrying out the principles of pure Democracy alone, can give these
                            opportunities. Liberty, Equality, Fraternity, must be the stepping stones in the attainment
                            of all for which the human heart has ever yearned or aspired, of all for which the prophets
                            have been stoned, and countless martyrs given their blood. Of their grand significance and
                            the results to which they will lead, we can give but a few hints at the present time. It is
                            generally acknowledged that a crisis in the near future awaits us, from which will be
                            evolved or revolved great changes in the social and civil polity of nations. Those who look
                            to the underlying causes of present disturbances, perceive that the forces which are arrayed
                            for the destruction of existing systems, are gathering power on every hand, and as they
                            sweep from continent to continent are also quickening the people with an impulse to
                            associate, organize and combine on new foundations and in a new spirit. Blindly the love of
                            greed is serving the people, for .while one industry after another is taken into the hands
                            of corporations, and again consolidate, thereby daily increasing the oppression of the
                            laboring classes, on the other hand, the struggle for freedom is more intense than ever
                            before, and the intelligence of the people, divinely awakened, will soon use for their
                            deliverance those very means which have added most to their enslavement. Then gradually will
                            come into existence that New Heavens and New Earth wh3rein shall dwell the righteousness of
                            God's perfect law. When each one has an equal inheritance in all natural wealth, (that
                            uncreated by labor,) and equal opportunities for education, it will be impossible for man to
                            hold property in his fellow man, hence the abolition of war, poverty and all consequent
                            crime and the complete overthrow of the financial system. Brotherly co-operation will then
                            take the place of selfish competism, and woman will be fully recognized as a citizen, making
                            it possible to establish all the relations of life on a basis of justice, wisdom and purity.
                            The drudgery and servitude of labor will soon disappear unier a system that will secure to
                            each one, the just return of his toil, and which will utilize <pb n="275" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. 275 the wonderful labor-saving machinery of our time for the relief instead of
                            the oppression of the masses. Then, no longer dwarfed, degraded and crushed by overtoil,
                            anxiety and a home life shorn of all that would make it attractive or desirable, man's
                            shriveled soul will expand, and the culture of his higher faculties find reflex in outward
                            surroundings that will correspond thereto. His desire for liquor, tobacco and other means of
                            low indulgence, at present largely a necessity, will th &gt;n disappear. In the natural course
                            of evolution, a vegetarian diet will be universally adopted, making the slaughter-house with
                            all its horrors and debasing influences, a thing of the past. All normal physical appetites
                            will be abundantly supplied, and esthetical tastes gratified, but the labor of providing for
                            these will not be allowed to encroach on the higher necessities of the soul, for, in the
                            near future man will have such command over the forces of nature as will make them his ready
                            servants, and earth will be converted into an Eden of beauty far surpassing that of ancient
                            story. Thus with the causes removed which are now so prolific of disease and suffering, and
                            with all the humanitarian efforts of the people embodied in the very heart of the nation,
                            prisons and pauper houses will be converted into the best of training schools and their
                            future necessity disappear. Under such conditions a portion of humanity will naturally
                            evolve from the earthly into a purely spiritual life wherein they can fully actualize the
                            teachings of Jesus. Such will be the dome on the new temple of humanity, receptive to the
                            light of celestial spheres, to that influx of divine truth which will irradiate in blessing
                            to those below. J;i that time Doctors will have nothing upon which to build up a profession,
                            because the people will learn the laws of being, body, soul and spirit, and when these have
                            been transgressed, they will look only to the true source of all healing, the power of
                            Christ within. Lawyers will not be needed because when natural rights are secured to all,
                            those laws of justice which are engraved in the divine consciousness of every soul, will
                            form the statute books of the nations. The Clergy will cease to exist distinctively as such,
                            for the hearts of the people will be the temple of the Most High, and the indwelling Christ
                            will voice the oracles of truth to each soul, will wait upon those altars whose flames are
                            never dim, accepting sacrifice, and imparting his own spirit a saving baptism and living
                            sacrament. All will be "kings and priests unto God" and ministers of good one to another.
                            Thus through Deific impulse the better life in man will be quickened till all realize the
                            essential unity of the race, and gradually merge into one great family of nations, speaking
                            one tongue, having one Bible and one religion, all written in the simple words:"Love one
                            another." Progress is eternal. Then as now, life will be fraught with ceaseless efforts, but
                            all will be for the highest possibilities of the race and each one's strife to aid his
                            neighbor. <pb n="276" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 276 THE MANIFES TO. Then will the vision of the ages have
                            been fulfilled when the old heavens and earth consumed by the fire of God's love, will have
                            vanished as a scroll, and from their ashes been re-create 1 the new, glowing in perennial
                            beauty, the glory of the Millennium. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Invisible echo" TEIform="index"/>THE INVISIBLE ECHO.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, Oliver C." TEIform="persName"/>By Oliver C. Hampton.</byline><p TEIform="p">A THOUGHT is as much a substance as a brick. Its elasticity is far greater than that of a
                            rubber ball. If a thought be sent in any direction or toward any object whatever, it will
                            rebound as surely as a ball thrown against a stone wall. If it meet no resistance but the
                            wall, it will in its return obey the law of incidence and reflection. If it meet with other
                            modifying forces, it will obey the law of elliptical motion, like the Australian Boomerang
                            which a native may twirl in such a manner that it will go round a house and surely return to
                            his hands. By some route every thought returns to its originator, laden with the results of
                            its mission. How weighty and awful a matter is the power of thought. You can not think a
                            good thought of another without doing him good and then your thought will return to you
                            laden with blessing and peace. And it will not only result in your spiritual but your
                            physical health and comfort. Whether you give audible expression to your thought or not,
                            will make no difference in the results. But alas for us; without thorough dicipline of our
                            thoughts we are capable and in danger of sending out sorrow, ruin and death along their
                            wake. Thousands of skeletons of dead hopes, joys and comforts, lie bleaching among the
                            cinders of desolation along the ghastly road of undiciplined and misdirected thought. We
                            need not speak of words, for without previous thoughts, no improper words would ever be
                            uttered. "From the abundance of the heart, the mouth speaketh." The indescribable horrors of
                            all past historysacred and profane, have bubbled up from the fearful Maelstrom of
                            misdirected thought. The deliberate indulgence of one thought of anger, jealousy, vengeance
                            or lust, has in hundreds of instances ended in murder. These thoughts of ours often reach
                            their destination through the instrumentality of invisible media. These invisible media
                            consist of five subtle ethers besides our crude and coarse atmosphere. The general current
                            of thought of a city, state or nation, is capable of deranging not only the peaceful
                            conditions thereof, but also of expressing its horror and hideousness in cyclones,
                            cloud-bursts and droughts. In fact every phenomena of Nature and the visible universe is
                            merely a. crystalized thought. As a nation, by our selfish and misdirected thoughts, we make
                            all our criminals and then electrocute or hang them for what we call their wickedness. <pb n="277" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 277 For the good of humanity, let us enter anew the
                            school of Christ and learn the lesson of cultivating pure and peaceful thoughts all the
                            time, and living for one another's happiness and contentment. Suppose every Believer in Zion
                            should so successfully discipline his thoughts for one year that not one word unworthy of
                            the purity and charity of the gospel of Christ and Mother, should be uttered; What a Church
                            we should be ! I am determined that one member of the Church shall live just that kind of a
                            thought life. Who will join me in this solemn resolution? I might rather ask who will not?
                            For this is not only the way to invulnerable peace of mind, but it is a new and living way
                            to escape dispepsia, rheumatism, cancer, heart-disease, sciatica, kidney affections and
                            other diseases. At least this is the plan Jesus took to preserve his physical and spiritual
                            health, and he succeeded perfectly. Union Village, O.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To my little sister" TEIform="index"/>TO MY LITTLE SISTER.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Vinneo, Cora C." TEIform="persName"/>Cora C. Vinneo.</byline><p TEIform="p">I look and see you standing by a stream, A thoughtful, happy, trusting little girl; Half
                            wrapped in mystery, half wrapped in dream, With wonder, watching every wavelet's whirL With
                            nimble feet I see you press the grass, Or pluck with dimpled hands the violets blue, Then
                            listening to the song-birds as they pass, Repeat again the song they sang to you. Through
                            deep dark forest, and through mossy glade, Where sun and shadow loiter hand in hand, Where
                            water-birds in gentle freedom wade, Again, I see your little figure stand. What thought was
                            that that bowed your sunny head? That made you pause and rest beside the stone ? Was it a
                            sudden sense of fear or dread At being left beside the stream alone ? Ah, 'twas the music of
                            an angel voice, Calling to you to cross the river wide; I see you meditate as if in choice,
                            And linger fondly by the rolling tide. The time passed on, through weeks and months and
                            years, Till youth matured where childhood smiled before; Again the angel called, and bathed
                            in tears Pointed the pathway to the farther shore; <pb n="278" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 278 THE MANIFESTO.
                            The pathway o'er the blessed bridge of prayer, That crosses where the stream is rough and
                            swift; And gave to you a promise of God's care, And confidence to rest upon his gift. In
                            meek submission to the precious call, How glowed your soul with fervent love and trust, How
                            firm your covenant to give up all, And bow your haughty nature to the dust. The vision
                            deepens : Once again you stand Where wave on wave before your spirit rolls; The angel comes
                            and takes you by the hand, And leads you to the stream that cleanses souls. "Not yet, oh nay
                            not yet," I hear you say, "Spare me the washing, O I fear the tide !" The angel pleads,
                            "There is no other way By which the spirit may be purified." Down 'neath the limped waves I
                            see you go, You, and the angel that repentance brings, And from the water's sparkling
                            overflow, Comes the sweet echo of the song she sings. And rising from the billows, pure and
                            white, You felt new courage for the work of life, New zeal to enter in the Christian fight,
                            Against the sins that fill the earth with strife. Oh may you ever know where safety lies,
                            Nor turn to Marah's dark and bitter streams, But seek the cooling springs that have their
                            rise Where rocks are smitten, and where sunlight gleams. And when you stand beside Death's
                            peaceful sea, Watching the coming of the tide that swells, May life's last music to your
                            memory be, Like wave-tones in the ocean's pearly shells. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Act well your part" TEIform="index"/>"ACT WELL YOUR PART."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Mason, Moore S." TEIform="persName"/>By Moore S. Mason.</byline><p TEIform="p">ALL lovers of English poetry are doubtless familiar with the above quotation, and perhaps the
                            author had in mind the language of the Christ to "him who overcometh," which at once shows
                            us there is a battle to wage, <pb n="279" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 279 a victory to win,
                            and while I shall ever plead for a true and noble manhood, the essentials are reverence and
                            purity, and while not a heresy hunter, I wish that much prevailing notion were destroyed,
                            that young people can not be pure in heart, as its awful consequences are that the terrible
                            temptations of early life which all have to meet, may drive them with their force down the
                            stream of passion. One often hears it asserted, that young people are destitute of the
                            quality without which no man can see God. It is true it calls for a struggle, but we are
                            bidden to struggle after goodness out of love to Him, and can we be cautioned too often of
                            the sorrows brought about by the few old traps laid on the highway of life, set with the
                            same old baits,thirty pieces of silver, a wedge of gold, a purple rag, or a bottle ? all
                            these belong to an unclean carnival in which we only get the cayenne pepper and the bill.
                            The conscientious cultivation of small natural capacity, will do far more than large power
                            rusted away by sloth, still there is a temptation to say, "I am only an insignificant unit,
                            it is best for me to wrap up my talent and put it away," forgetting that responsibility does
                            not diminish with the size of the gift. The motive, not the magnitude of the act determines
                            the whole character of the life of which it is a part, and if we truly employ whatever gifts
                            God has given us, we shall be accepted, for in the struggle the appropriate reward belongs
                            to perseverance. This gains for us a fuller measure of His love, and makes each day bright
                            with the knowledge that He careth for His children. What a true application in regard to
                            Christian efforts is that old fable of the man who told his children to dig all over the
                            field, and they would find treasures ; true, they found no gold but they improved the field
                            and benefited their health and muscle which is better than gold. So all of us ought honestly
                            to use what we possess and use will make growth. The final reward of all faithful service,
                            "Enter thou into the joy of thy Lord," was not said to those of large endowments, but to the
                            faithful servant. Union Village, O.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Universality is the watchword..." TEIform="index"/>Universality is the watchword...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Univeesamty is the watchword of the age. If "God hath made of one blood all the nations of
                            the earth," then shall mankind eventually become one brotherhood. The easy communication
                            between the countries of the globe makes it possible. The exchange not only in the
                            commodities necessary to physical life, but in thoughts, ideas and religious experiences,
                            seem to be the moulding or leavening process. Intelligence grows apace, and the barriers of
                            narrow sectarianism, and the monopoly of God and heaven, must give way to the broader ideas
                            of enlightened reason and soul expansion. God is love, and when man grows to divinity of
                            character he too will be loved, and will enlarge the sphere of his activities.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian character is not an act..." TEIform="index"/>Christian character is not an act...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Christian character is not an act, but a process; not a sudden creation, but a development,a
                            growth. It grows and bears fruit like a tree, and like a tree it requires patient and
                            unwearied attention.</p></div2><pb n="280" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our work" TEIform="index"/>OUR WORK. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">WITH this number of The Manifesto which has through many years been a faithful representative
                            of the social, domestic and religious life of our Community, the door of the outgoing year
                            closes forever. What a ponderous volume of good and ill could be filled with the rights and
                            wrongs of the army of saints as well as of sinners who are on their pilgrimage through this
                            world. And then how fortunate it is that we are not obliged to go over the road more than
                            once so that we can kindly anticipate that the good things of the past will be greatly
                            distanced by the good things that are to come ; that the sins and sorrows that have been
                            known in the closing year will be known no more. It has been the object of The Manifesto
                            from its first number to bear testimony of the manifestation of the spirit of God among men,
                            and to work zealously for the establishing of practical righteousness on the earth ; to
                            scatter seeds of kindness and to publish the gospel of "good news." That we have been
                            successful in a small degree, we are quite well assured, and are like the good brother of
                            earlier days wl o made a note of his religious experiences and found to his surprise that
                            lie was much better than he had expected. We share the same pleasure in regard to The
                            Manifesto and are quite ready to believe that much good has been accomplished, not only in
                            our own homes, but in its circulation abroad. If we have our faith in God, and really
                            believe that we are engaged in his service, then duty impels us to give as we receive. In
                            some instances a penny may do more good than a large sum, and a good word sent into the
                            world in God's name may possibly accomplish more for the peace and happiness of humanity
                            than a beautifully studied discourse. While it may not be in the province of any one paper
                            to present all the "good gifts from God's holy mountain," each one may give as they receive
                            from the bountiful hand of a kind Providence, and in this way help to establish on the earth
                            the Fatherhood of God and the brotherhood of man. If the Christian sects are narrow in their
                            religious views and, no doubt, many of them are, yet if they work with a free-will in all
                            that they are able to do from the light they have received, then no more should be expected
                            of them. Every person, whether Christian or heathen, who is working for the good of humanity
                            is certainly worthy of our interested care and confidence. <pb n="281" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. 281 Salvation, either of the body or soul, comes by degrees and through God's
                            light is made permanent in the life of man. To be wholly saved is a wonderful attainment.
                            The "old inheritance"' which has been forced upon us, and which includes our eating and
                            drinking, our thinking and acting, "is not cast out but by prayer and fasting." Not many,
                            however, are inclined to pray or to fast that they may be delivered from those appetites and
                            passions that they, at the same time, are fostering with patient and tender care. To stand
                            erect as sons and daughters of our Heavenly Parents, having cleansed both soul and body
                            will, certainly, insure us a right in the King's highway, and open to us the gates of the
                            Holy City. Those who have worked for the prosperity of our little paper or have given it a
                            kind thought in their prayers, can look with pleasure at the work in which they have become
                            interested. It is our pleasure to hold these good gifts in loving appreciation, and at the
                            same time, casting our bread upon the waters, believing and trusting that our Heavenly
                            Father will bear us in kind remembrance. All may not be able to write as they would wish,
                            nor speak to the edification of all who should hear them, but the possessor of even one
                            talent is able to bless the earnest workers, and in this way do much effectual work. The
                            remark of Prof, liuskin is to the point, "The greatest thing a human soul ever does in this
                            world is to see something, and then tell what it saw in a plain way." Indeed, the more
                            simple the better, whether it may have reference to science or religion. Jesus has been
                            complimented on illustrating the gospel truths in the most simple and easily expressed
                            language, so that even the common laborer could readily understand it, and yet his mission
                            was superior to any that had preceded it. The many kind words that have been expressed in
                            favor of our little paper during the present year are all pleasantly appreciated, and will,
                            no doubt, be the means of accomplishing much good. We hope every reader of "The Manifesto"
                            will have with us the desire for a more extended representation of the truth of our gospel
                            work. "Freely ye have received, freely give." lease write the articles that are intended for
                            publication on sheets of NOTE SIZE; 5x8 inches; Write with ink on one side of tli3 pap^r,
                            only and much oblige the printers of The Manifesto.</p></div2><pb n="282" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Infinite goodness" TEIform="index"/>INFINITE GOODNESS.</head><p TEIform="p">"God is our refuge and strength, a very present help in trouble.'"1Psalm, xlvi., 1. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y. 1. Thro' ev'ry hour of sunlight, Storm and fear, Thro' 2. Why should our
                            hearts grow hardened, Sad with woes, When 3. Yet for the poor and erring, Thou hast peace,
                            If 4. Thine ever Heavenly Father, Thine true praise, For darkest hours of shadow, Thou art
                            near. Like in Thy light and presence, Pure love flows, Oh, at Thy gentle bidding, All wrongs
                            cease, What light, and pow'r, and wisdom, All our days. Thine, gentle dews of Hermon,
                            Falling free, Come ... holiest we have wandered, wandered, From Thy way, Remembering can
                            compare in virtue With Thy care, Bestowed on ever, Heavenly Mother. Thine sweet love, Like
                            ... incense of blessings, Oft from Thee, Oft from Thee, not Thy mercies, Given each day,
                            Given each day. all Thy children, Ev'rywhere, Ev'rywhere. rising up to Thee above, Thee
                            above.</p></div2><pb n="283" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. DECEMBER, 1894. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is published by the
                            "United Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued
                            regularly by the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the
                            religious views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. All
                            communications should be addressed to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. rr&gt;:B
                            zincs. One copy per year, postage paid " " six months, " " .75 .40</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. October. Thermometer. Rain. 1893. 50.71 l.%in. 1894.
                                50.36 3.75 " Highest Temp, during this mo. 70 above 0. Lowest " " " " 29 " " Number of
                                rainy days " " 8 " clear " " " 10 " " cloudy" " " 13 C. G. Reed. Nov. 1894. Fruits and
                                vegetables now being safely stored for the winter, our theme for the present, is a
                                lively gratitude to "The Lord of the Harvest" for the bounties which it has been our
                                blessing to reap. "We have harvested a generous supply of rare apples for use, and the
                                later market, while hundreds of bushels have been sold on the ground at 10 cts. a
                                bushel, to our neighbors who though near us, had only a light crop. For our spiritual
                                blessings also we have an oblation of praise. Our Society meetings have continued up to
                                date, later than usual, owing to the mild autumn weather. Nov. 6. Mild autumn weather?
                                Such was our verdict yesterday, when we saw geraniums fresh green, and blooming on the
                                lawn at the Center family, and we could gather a bouquet of dandelions buttercups
                                daisies and clover from among the thick green grass. But to-day? Several inches of snow
                                cover the ground, and the evergreens with their long white hands hang heavily, as though
                                waiting for some one to relieve them of their burden. Such is life! Yet it is a
                                beautiful variety, all needed to accomplish the great and grand law of growth; and while
                                surveying the landscape before me, an attempt at poetry in my youth returns to mind.
                                Should we thus change and in the winter time Our hearts which once were warmed by love's
                                bright beam, Be frozen o'er, and we no more be kind, Ah! then would be no time for
                                thoughts serene. But 'tis not so, though hard the winds may blow, Nor from the sun
                                proceed one cheering gleam With love and friendship still the heart doth glow. Ah!
                                surely then there's time for thoughts serene. Amelia J. Culver. South. Family. Nov.
                                1894. Dear Editor:By this you will see that we are not asleep, but rather quite wide
                                awake and can still pen a few lines. This morning we enjoyed a beautiful meeting at the
                                Church. Eldress Anna White spoke as I wish we might all feel It was full of hope,
                                courage and zeal, even to make the best of life while looking on the bright side. That
                                we should feel the dignity and independence of life that is for us. <pb n="284" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 284 THE MANIFESTO. We have much for which to he thankful, far more than of which to
                                complain. Our temporal needs are supplied and we are able to make some improvements on
                                outbuildings. Our store-houses are well rilled and we have some to spare for the needy.
                                We have shipped a quantity cf apples to New York for poor children. It is blessed to
                                receive and also to give, indeed w7e are surrounded with blessings in our Mt. Lebanon
                                home, as we think that no place is more favored on the earth, or inside of the earth.
                                Several new members have entered our family the past season, and we like the quartette
                                very much. At the present time sickness is not to be found among us. We have been
                                enjoying many months of activity, but time may prove how far we may be wholly free from
                                the ills that flesh is heir to. Last Sunday evening there was an accident on the
                                mountain, caused by a runaway horse. Our people went up with a carriage and conveyed the
                                injured people home. Twice this season we have extended a care to wrecked wheelmen. One
                                was from Boston and was so badly cut and bruised that he remained at our office for
                                several days and was taken home on the cars. Mother Lucy Wright once remarked, "People
                                must live at the South family that they may care for those who need help on the
                                mountain." We think however, that a little more care on the part of these people, nearly
                                all these accidents might be avoided. We wish to be a thankful people, especially at
                                this time of the year, and are very glad that we are able to lend a helping hand to
                                others. We have some of the luxuries of life, and among these are beautiful springs of
                                never-failing water. These supply our homes,our bath rooms, our laundry and our kitchen.
                                Water is one of the great blessings. We can use it freely and be made clean. It is good
                                for the inner and outer man, and helps us to be thankful, more ready to praise than to
                                censure, more willing to assist others than to be assisted. Sarah Collins.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">becond Family. Nov. 1894. So many of our gospel friends express pleasure at reading "Home
                                Notes," that we lay aside other cares for the time, and with pen try to add our mite to
                                help the cause as well as to interest those who peruse the pages of The Manifesto. We
                                have all our crops secured for winter, and are busy with fall plowing. We expect to
                                thrash our wheat and rye the coming week. Oats were thrashed as we brought them from the
                                field. We hai over 1,000 bushels. We had fine weather to secure crops, no frost since
                                our last writing. Ripe tomatoes, were served at breakfast this morning, Nov. 4th picked
                                from the vines yesterday. It is not very often we can say this at this season of the
                                year. The Sisters say some pansies are still in bloom. The recent rains have made the
                                grass much greener than in the summer. Were much pleased with the company of our good
                                Western friends; we had some regrets that their stay was so short, and the weather was
                                not on its good behavior, it was so damp and chilly; but we hope the love of gospel
                                kindred supplied the warmth that the season withheld. The spirit of our Mother must have
                                felt some recompense for her toil and sufferings, if she beheld our good friends
                                standing in respectful silence at her grave, with their hearts filled with love, not
                                only for the mortal part, but also for the principles she established, and for the cause
                                that still exists, a blessing to her name, and a saving power to all who obey it. Isaac
                                Anstatt. North Family. Nov. 1894. If medals would be a fit recompense, our Brother,
                                Simon Emery is certainly entitled to one for the ideas expressed in his letter published
                                in Nov. Manifesto. The least we can say is, that it is the gospel truth; and we want to
                                use it as an incen- <pb n="285" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 285 tive to our spiritual
                                energies to work more diligently for the consummation of what every good Believer is
                                anxious to see attained. We thank him for such good testimonies and hope to receive
                                more. The band of Spartans who defended the pass of Thermopylae were men of great
                                physical courage; who were willing to die in the defense of their country. Those who
                                to-day stand in the vanguard upholding the advanced truths revealed to mankind, and
                                clearing the highway that future travelers may proceed with safety must be endowed with
                                something greater than physical courage. But everyone who is honest in his intentions
                                will have strength according to his day. How many of my young friends have ever perused
                                Pilgrim's Progress? to those who have not it would be a profitable season spent in
                                reading it. Striving to come into rapport with the spiritual interpretation of the
                                narrative. We consider it one of the inspired books, for it certainly portrays very
                                clearly the travel of the soul from the lower through the successive stages of growth to
                                the higher life. If the old adage is true that "short visits make long friends," the
                                ties of friendship must be strong that bind us to our gospel kindred in the west. We had
                                a call from the Western Ministry and Elders when on their way home. It was short; but we
                                will be thankful for small favors. We are having a beautiful autumn, one with which we
                                can not find fault. Indications point to an open winter; but it may be rather early to
                                predict correctly. Work is progressing favorably on the waterworks, and if the weather
                                continues favorable they will be completed this iall. ilam'ltnn VeU-iato.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>West Pittsfield, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 1894. We have not had a picnic or play-time of any kind to speak of this month, nor
                                are they necessary to our happiness. If contentment reigns in the home, pleasure may be
                                found in small things. "Our common joys, O what are they? The brightest and the best;
                                They glad us in our busy walks, Are with us when we rest. ******** The consciousness of
                                doing good With every passing day." We have long anticipated the possession of a new
                                ice-house, with modern improvements. Within the last two months it has been erected. The
                                building is 22x34 ft. with brick walls 18 ft. high, laid in redcolored mortar. One half
                                of the lower story is finished inside with Southern pine, to be used for cold storage.
                                The ice-hall and chamber will hold nbout two hundred tons of ice. The outside wood-work
                                is painted a light gray color, and presents quite a nice appearance. There are rooms for
                                vegetables, fruits, ments, and many things that we may wish to keep for a long or short
                                time. Kight here in our Shaker Village they are building a new road, or ritlier changing
                                the i\&gt;ad, that runs east and west io a State highway. There has been some thirty men
                                with nearly as many teams at work here since tie mMdle of October. They change the grade
                                where they can, and cover the road with top rock stone; then roll it down with a roller
                                weighing 17 tons. The one mile of road to be done this season is to cost several
                                thousand dollars. We understand there has, or will be built, one mile in a number of
                                places in the State, this year. If they give satisfaction more will be built another
                                season. We may expect some good roads across the State some time in the future. We hope
                                it will not be long before they continue this new highway over the mountain to Mt.
                                Lebanon. We have had some fine rain-storms of late. The last one caught us unprepared.
                                We had been opening some ditches for new water-pipes, and rain is not apt to enhance the
                                pleasure of such work. Sunshine and wind have dried up the mud now so that the
                                enterprise can be continued. <pb n="286" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 286 THE MANIFESTO. Thanksgiving day
                                will soon be at hand. As we review the year and consider the countless blessings with
                                which it has abounded, we feel that our gratitude is inadequate. While we wish our
                                friends in the several Societies a happy and prosperous season on the 29th inst. we will
                                reord a determination to keep each day a Thanksgiving day to the Lord in recognition of
                                the kind and loving way he has led us "all the days of our life." Em tretta Belden.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station, Conn.</head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 1894. "Lift the standard higher up, Let Truth in regal glory reign." A great injury
                                is done by lowering the standard of truth. Let us cherish a high ideal of a Christian
                                life and strive to live up to it. Let us pledge ourselves to nothing less than this. The
                                highest standard is none too high. Anything less than the highest is too low. How
                                beautiful is truth! To say of any one, "his word is reliable," is an honor, a meed of
                                praise more desirable than all emoluments of office and the flatteries of multitudes.
                                Truth is sure to win. Let us strive for a life that shall portray this virtue, for no
                                good effort is lost. It requires constant watchfulness to follow the path of truth. Let
                                us help others to be pure and true and we are doing the work that is ours to do. It is
                                the constant care exercised over every part of the household, and the constant endeavor
                                to improve and apply our best powers to our work that alone gives peace, happiness and
                                prosperity. "The largest railroad station in the world is in St. Louis. The station
                                proper with the train sheds occupy an area of more than 11 acres. The cost of the site,
                                the building and the entire system of tracks amounts to $6,500,000." ******* The morning
                                feed of soft mash, bran, ground oats and chopped onions and turnips for hens should not
                                be given up. A small amount of wheat fed daily will be beneficial, but as an exclusive
                                diet it means few eggs and fat poultry. Eggs hatch better with more grain and less soft
                                food. Success in growing poultry is due to systematic feeding. A few spoonfuls of
                                sulphur mixed with soft food will increase egg production; a tablespoonful to four
                                gallons of food is plenty for seventy-five liens. Daniel Orcutt.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 1894. As this is Thanksgiving month and so many are interested in one or more days
                                of this much honored season, and as it has even enlisted the attention of the President
                                of the U. S., and also of several of the Governors who have told us just what we had
                                better do on that one day, would it not be quite as well to accept the whole month and
                                study to give thanks for all the blessings that are conferred upon us from day to day.
                                Possibly those who have been caught napping while the earth was being covered with
                                "beautiful snow" may find it a little difficult to be thankful for this special
                                offering, but while they sorrow the great army of children are out with their sleds and
                                are filled with' rejoicing. To them the first snow of the season is a cause for greater
                                thanksgiving than even the President's proclamation. Br. Arthur Bruce who has the charge
                                of the stock, reports very favorably of the feeding of ensilage, and he wishes he had
                                more. The readiness with which the stock receive it for food is an evidence that they
                                know it is just what they want. Now that we have harvested a hundred tons, we would like
                                an additional hundred tons at the close of another season. In addition to the 100 tons
                                of ensilage, cut from the five acres of land, there was gathered some 437 bushels of
                                ears of Sanford corn, and a large part of this is good for seed. From our small field of
                                yellow corn we obtained 200 bushels. The cows <pb n="287" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 287
                                also have in store 190 bu. of beets, and 280 bu. of carrots and 40 bu. of turnips. Our
                                crop of apples has far exceeded our earlier expectations, and this gift has been a
                                subject of many thanksgivings. Apples whether for summer, fall, or winter hold an
                                exalted place among the fruits of our northern climate. A few varieties of good pears
                                and some nice specimens of peaches are also found at the north; and for all of these we
                                are now giving thanks. Our supply of excellent winter apples is quite liberal, and not
                                less than 1000 bu. of fall and winter apples have been cut and dried. Those not suitable
                                for drying have been left to decay in the orchards. Cider-making at our home is a thing
                                of the past, but for vinegar a feAv apples are hauled some two miles to the mill
                                belonging to our neighbors. Several barrels of good winter apples have been sold by our
                                upper family for which they received $1.50 per barrel. The "eclipse" windmill is in
                                beautiful woi'king order at our North family. A system of water-works has also been
                                added to the building and this with some needed repairs has produced quite a bill, and
                                even here we may be thankful for all that has been done, and that the expense was no
                                larger. H. C. BKnn.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 1894. On the evening of the 16th ult. the Centennial League entertained t!:e Society
                                with original compositions, dialogues and music. It was especially appreciated because
                                it was all prepared without the aid of teachers. Our anniversary supper, in
                                commemoration of the founding of our Society in Enfield, one hundred and one years ago,
                                was given on the 18th ult. The dininghall was beautifully dressed in autumn leaves and
                                evergreen, and the occasion was one of pleasure and thanksgiving to all. One of our
                                Sisters at the Infirmary picked some ripe raspberries on the 20th of Oct. which would
                                indicate that the Weather Bureau has got the seasons a trifle mixed. In September Elder
                                William had an auction sale of the property and live stock of our South family, and
                                again on the 7th inst., a sale of farm produce. The aggregated sales amounted about
                                $2,000. Our large Grist-mill at North Enfield has recently been sold, with all the
                                privileges belonging to it, for $13,000. Sisters are busy drawing the window sash in
                                several of our houses. Pipes are being put in order, and buildings banked to keep out
                                the frosts of winter. The first snow-storm of the season came on the 6th. So far we have
                                had about 6 inches of snow. O. 11. Kirldey.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Sabbathday Lake, Me.</head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 1804. As I commence writing, the chirp of a robin is borne to my ears. Poor foolish
                                bird to tarry thus long in this cold region! The first snow fell here the 5th inst; more
                                has since been added and the weather has continued quite cold. To-day the prospects are
                                that it is going to be a little warmer and we may yet have a pleasant season before
                                winter sets in. Lovely bouquets were brought into our rooms from the gardens the day
                                before the snow fell, but we shall get no more from outside until another year. Now we
                                must depend upon our house plants. With us it takes eight months of the year to provide
                                for the other four and we find no time to lay up for ourselves "treasures upon earth."
                                Yet at the same time that we are struggling for existence we can be laying up treasures
                                in heaven by a discipline of spirit in every good word and work. Thanksgiving will soon
                                be along which will draw out a chord of good cheer: "When, the gray-haired New Englamler
                                Sees round his board The old broken links Of affection restored." Ada 8. Gummings.</p></div3><pb n="288" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harvard, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Harvard, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 1894. Time is a gentle reminder of present duties. Each flitting moment tells us
                                there is work to do and it requires the ! combined energies of body soul and spirit, to
                                keep pace with the present fast age. Not only in the development of the inventive, but
                                the increasing revelation of spiritual light and truth in the religious world. The
                                present teachings of religion are no longer a mere matter of beliefs, but selfdenying
                                works. We look forward each month with earnest pleasure to the arrival of our dear
                                Manifesto, for it brings us nearer to other Societies and through its influence we learn
                                to love and be loved by all. The sudden advent of winter, or wintry weather, is a
                                hindrance to the rapid progress in the re-building of our barn which we anticipated, but
                                we hope for more favorable weather. With us the springs that were famished by the
                                summer's drought, are well filled. Although the drought was severe, we did not suffer as
                                much from it as in many places around us. Thanks for our fine water system and its good
                                care. Farm woi'k is nearly over, so we have more leisure for spiritual communion with
                                ourselves and loving friends. Mar da M. Bullard.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Alfred, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Alfred., Me.</head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 1894. The President has appointed the 29th of this month as a National Thanksgiving.
                                Our Society can well unite in the thanksgiving. Our fields, orchards and the work of our
                                hands have all been blessed, therefore we have cause for thankfulness. Not for one day
                                only but every day in the year we rejoice and give thanks to the Giver of all good gifts
                                that we have a knowledge of the truth as revealed through Christ in His first and second
                                appearing. Obedience to this truth, lifts us above the selfishness and sinfulness of a
                                worldly life. The cross of Christ is burdensome, only to those who seek for
                                self-pleasure instead of self-denial. Christ said "take my yoke upon you and learn of
                                me, for I am meek and lowly in heart, for my yoke is easy and my bui'den is light."
                                Every soul who is willing to wear this yoke in humility of spirit will find it easy, and
                                the burden light. It is the burden of sin that is heavy, and grievous to be borne. We
                                are saved from such burdens by an honest confession of all sin. Thank God for this
                                blessed knowledge of the truth. May we continue in the way of well-doing, glorying not,
                                save in the cross of Christ. For a few days the ground has been white with snow, and the
                                atmosphere quite like winter. As late as the 4th of this month one of the young Sisters
                                made a beautiful bouquet from flowers grown in the open air without protection, showing
                                how long the warm days continued with us. Let us magnify the good things and we shall be
                                less inclined to dwell upon our trials. To Br. Alonzo Hollister we extend our love and
                                sincere thanks for the little books of Bible Lessons. We realize the vast amount of
                                labor it must have cost him to prepare such a book, but be assured kind Brother your
                                labor is not lost. Our young people are delighted with it and will peruse it with deep
                                interest. Dear Gospel kindred accept our love and kindly greeting. With you we earnestly
                                pray for the prosperity of Zion upon earth. Fannie Casey.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We should regard the faults of others..." TEIform="index"/>
                            We should regard the faults of others...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">We should regard the faults of others tenderly with helpful sympathy, our own seriously with
                            prayer and earnest effort for overcoming power.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, C." TEIform="persName"/>C. Allen.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Leggett, Ezra T." TEIform="index"/>Ezra T. Leggett
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Ezra T. Leggett, at Un ion Village, Ohio. Nov. 9, 1894. Age 7*7 years and 10 mo.</p></div3></div2><pb n="289" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">INDEX. Page A.. Aspiration, - - - - - 108 Another, Love One - - - 112 Anderson, M. J.Letter -
                            - 127 Alone, In Silence and - - ,- 135 Arithmetic, Ciiristian - - - 1(52 Again, Try - : - -
                            - - 204 Acrostic, - . - - - - 218 Angus, JanetteTribute to - - 2(i.*) Autumn, ..-.-.- - -
                            26J IB. Birds, Unnoticed - - - - 48 Blest, - - - - - . 50 Bits, Cold Iron - - - - 51
                            Buckingham, S.In Memory of - (&gt;2 Better, The World Would be the - 74 Belief, The Shakers' -
                            - - 81 Bell, Columbian Liberty and Peace 152 Birthday, Our National - - 153 Beauty, - - - -
                            - - 176 Ball, StephenLetter, - - 181 Bassett, W. N. " - - - 202 Blossoms, Hazel - - - - 248
                            Boisseau, S.In Memory of - - 267 C. Christ, The Church of - - 10 Cyrus, - . - - - 12
                            Christmas-Day, - - - 32 Cultivation, - - - - - 61 Childhood, - - - - - 203 C. C. C. - - - -
                            - - 252 " D. DeGraw, H.Letter - - ' ' - ' 37 Danforth, N. G.Tribute to - - 50 Death, The
                            Bitterness of - - 59 Do, What Can You - - - - 75 Dream, A - - - - - 122 Do we, A. W.Letter -
                            - - 157 Days, The List - - - - 208 Divine, Instruction ... 272. Eventide, The Storm at - - -
                            34 Evolution, Christianity and - 59 Evans, F. W.Letter - - - 178 Elam, Wm,Letter - - - 180
                            Elopement, An - 217 Echo, The Invisible - - - 276. Forces, Spiritual - - - 6 Faith, The
                            worldly - - - 111 Faith, - - - - - 253 Good, Doing - - - - - I3f, Greatness, True - - - -
                            218 Government, - . - - - 227 Heart, Prepare thy ... 13 Home, Notes About 17, 42, 68, 90,
                            115, 140, 164, 187, 211, 235, 259, 283 Hall, SarahLetter - - - 110 Hills, Morn on the - - -
                            138 Heart, The Well-kept - - - 194 Health, - - - - - 195 Hast, Hold Fast that Thou - - 232
                            Health, - - - - - 249 <pb n="290" id="n24" TEIform="pb"/> 290 THE MANIFESTO. Page. R. Page J. Russell,
                            R.tn Memory of- 63 June, Welcome to - 129 Run, Let us 75 K. S. Kaime, James S.Tribute to 49
                            South Union, History of 3, 25, 53, 77, 101, 125, 149, 173, 197, 221, 245, 269 I,. Soliloquy,
                            - 31 Learn, Live and . - - . 38 Suggestion, A..... 84 Life, Regenerate - - - - 40
                            Spring,...... 123 Life, A True - - - - - 130 S- - - - -G. J.Letter - - - - 146 Locomotive,
                            The - - - - 146 Suffering, The Cry of the - 225 S. I. S.Brief Report of 242 Shakers,
                            Shirley, - 272 Meeting, At a recent ... Mantle, HKindly Remembered 75 97 Sister, To my
                            little, - 277 McKee, N.In Memorium 122 T. Meeting, The Gift of our Mission 200 Times, Hard -
                            64 Millennium, The True - 206 Times, One of the Signs of the 104 Mission, The Christian 256
                            Thought, Take - 159 Millennium, The, - - - - 273 Testimony, My 182 Thought, For .... 201
                            :sr. Text, Scripture .... 205 Night, Watchman, What of the - 132 Thoughts, Solemn - 254 N E.
                            E. Letter 182 U. o. Uno, Tria Juncto in 56 Orcutt, D.Letter - 23, 123, 267 Us, Too Many of -
                            74 Offering, Peace - - - - 29 Unity, Purity and - - - - 184 Observation, - - - - - 57 Unica,
                            O Crux Spes - 226 Personality, Truth Above - 8 Vanity,...... 9 Petition, A 11 "W. Prayer, A
                            Child's - - - - 74 Word, Preach the - - 87 Potter, A. Z.Tribute to - - 98 Wilson, Wm.Spoken
                            by - - 107 Powers, C. R.Letter - 110 Words, Kind - 123 Past, The Dead..... 160 Waste, The
                            Money we - - - 145 Prayer, My - - - - - 204 Wrong, Going - ... 201 Promise, The Mouse's - -
                            - 218 Well-doing, Continuance in - 250 Prayer, Pluck and - - 219 Walker, C.In Memory of -
                            266 Progress, Human - 230 Work, Our..... 280 Pleasant Hill, Reminiscence of - 241 Y. Part,
                            Act Well your, - 278 Year, The New - ... 14 Q. Youngster, A Profound 50 Queries, - - - - - -
                            36 Zion,...... 155 <pb n="291" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 291 DEATHS. Angus, Janette Bussell,
                            George Billington, Martha W. Buckingham, Stanton Brainird, Jane S. - Boisseau, Stephen L.
                            Clark, Mary Carr, Martha Ann - - Danforth, Nancy G.French, Mary Hanks, Burdett Hunt, Polly -
                            - - Kaime, James S. Love, Susan - - - Leggett, Ezra T. Monroe, Charles Mantle, Henry - ,
                            McKee, Nancy Page. Page Potter, Adah Zillah - - - 99 268 Quiggin, James - , 243 23 Russell,
                            Rachel - - 76 51 Taber, Ida H. 23 76 Whitcher, Nancy - - 76 19J Walker, Catherine 243 243
                            MUSIC. 171 243 City of Light, -Faith, - - 139 114 23 Gather Home, ... - 16 268 God Our
                            Trust, - 89 Goodness, Infinite 282 148 196 Higher, - - 186 K1 My Coining, - 163 O -L My
                            Home, - - W8 196 Reign of Peace, - 210 288 Ransomed, - - 234 23 67 99 Tempest-tossed, - -
                        41</p></div2><pb n="292" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Journal of Hygeio-Therapy" TEIform="index"/>The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy. Con tents. November.- Disease Bacteria; The Law of Hygiene
                                and the Law of Cure; Anti Vaccination; The Pride of Companyy The Temperature of the
                                Body; Way to Injure Health, etc., etc. Dr. T. V. Gifford &amp; Co., Kokomo; Intl.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bible defended" TEIform="index"/>The Bible Defended
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Bible Defended, by R. 8; Webber, is a work of 339 pages, and the author has thrown
                                his whole soul into this great subject. Possibly he fears the influence that may be
                                circulated by that class -who have written or spoken against this time-honored book,the
                                Bible. In ,his work the author makes an extended review of Thomas Paine's "Age of
                                Reason," and of Col. Ingersoll's "Mistakes of Moses." It is wonderfully interesting and
                                Christians and Infidels will take pleasure in its perusal, and we are assured that the
                                reader who reaches the end of th&amp;first page will be quite likely to keep
                                fellowship with the book till he closes with the 339th page. Published by H. L.
                                Hastings, 47 Cornhill, Boston, Mass. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological Journal and Science of Health" TEIform="index"/>
                                The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health for
                                November is filled with excellent matter. The frontispiece is a very hand some portrait
                                of Prof. Nelson Sizer at eightytwo. He is also the subject of a phreno-biographical
                                sketch by Mrs. Charlotte F. Wells, which will especially interest many friend of the
                                veteran phrenologist. The second number is a strong plea for Woman., by Ellen B.
                                Dietrick. An interview with Dr. Beall, by the editor of the New York Presi on the future
                                of the human race, will appeal to all lovers of progress. Prof. Sizer continues his
                                series, How to Study Strangers. The eminent Dr. H. A. Buttolph discusses Phrenology and
                                Insanity in a masterly manner; and Dr. Charles de Medici startles us with a
                                demonstration of the old problem of squaring the circle. J. S. Van Cleve, Ph. D.,
                                discourses on musicians and poets in his usual brilliant style. Dr. Dray ton adds an
                                illustrated little poem to the department of Child Culture. Dr. Beall, the editor,
                                vigorously answers an attack on Phrenology, and gives a study of Criminal Ears. Price,
                                15 cents, $1.50 a year. Address The Fowler &amp; Wells Co., 27 East 21st St., New
                                York. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cosmopolitan" TEIform="index"/>The Cosmopolitan Magazine
                            </head><p TEIform="p">
                                A FAMOUS SHOW OF BEAUTY. The show of distinguished beauty, transfixed by famous
                                artists, which is now taking place at the Academy of Fine Arts in New York, has been
                                anticipated by The Cosmopolitan Magazine in its November issue, in an article by Win. A.
                                Coffin, withillustrations of some of the more beautiful faces. The "Great Passions of
                                History" series bus for this month's subject the romantic career of Agnes Sorel, who
                                influenced, the destinies of France under Chsirles VII. "The Art Schools of A nierica,"
                                "The Great British Northwest Territory," "The Chiefs of the A merican Press," and the
                                "Public Library Movement," are amongst The Cosmopolitan's table of contents. Survivors
                                of the war and their children will fin.l intense interest in "The St &gt;ry of a Thousand,"
                                a personal narrative begun in this number by Albion W. Tourgte, who tells in a graphic
                                way, of a regiment which saw fierce serviceof its organization, its marches its sports
                                and its death-roll. John Kendrick Bangs' quuint humor is to enliven the pages of The
                                Ladles'' Home Journal with a series of twelve articles depicting the club talk of four
                                men about women's affairs. Mr. Bangs calls this club "The Paradise Club," "paradise," he
                                says, "because no woman nor serpent ever entered into it." ' - :</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="O my mortal friends and brothers..." TEIform="index"/>O my mortal friends and brothers...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">O my mortal friends and brothers, We are each and all another's, And the heart
                                    that gives most freely From its treaures, hath the more. Would you loose your life,
                                    you find it, And in giving love, you bind it, Like an amulet of safety To your
                                    hearts forevermore.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>�Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Still higher" TEIform="index"/>STILL HIGHER.</head><p TEIform="p">[Contributed by Amelia J. Calver.] 
                            High hearts are never long without hearing some new call, some distant clarion of God, even
                            in their dreams; and soon they are observed to break up the camp of ease, and start on some
                            fresh march of faithful service. And looking still higher we find those who never wait till
                            their moral work accumulates, and who reward resolution with no rest; who do the good only
                            to see the better, and see the better only to achieve it; who are too meek for transport,
                            too faithful for remorse, too earnest for repose; whose worship is action, and whose action
                            ceaseless aspiration.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Martineau, J." TEIform="persName"/>J. Martineau.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The envious heart is like thistles..." TEIform="index"/>The envious heart is like thistles...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The envious heart is like thistles among wheat and wild flowers, piercing the hand that would
                            bind the sheaves or gather life's sweetest things.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. A.</byline></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p27"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
A CONCISE HISTORY OF THE
SHAXEES.
Just Published.     The book is printed
with large type   and  on  excellent  paper.
It  contains   130 pages and has
ILLUSTRATIONS
of the Shakers and their
'OM?CUNJ)  CONCENTRATED
SYRUP of SARSAPARILLA,
With 1 oz. Hydriodate of Potassa to 12 Bottles.
 PREPARED AT
 Shaker "Utillage, Merrtmacb So., B.
The  work  gives  quite an extended ac- j
count  of  the  Several SOCIETIES, their ^
i
organization and general management.
Price  in cloth 75   cts;   in boards 50 cts.
Address    H. C. Blinn,
East Canterbury, N. H.
AUTHORIZED RULES
() F
THE   SHAKER   GJMMQNjTY.
The religious basis of the Okdek must
be a foundation resting on the principle of
righteousness, which principle is God.
This should rule the life of the  individual for the protection of his Ovwn soul, for
the peace of the family and as an evidence
of his upright standing before the world.
Prire,  10 rts.
A Visit to the
>f EAST CANTERBURY,   N. H.
LLOYD H. CHANDLER. U. S. MT.
Liberally Illustrated with half tone
pictures of peksons and places.
The Village of EAST CANTERBURY
is situated in one of the lovliest spots of
New Hampshire, and is high enough to
overlook the surrounding country.
Price  15 cts.
This medicine has proved to be most.
valuable in the following diseases :
Chronic Inflammation of the Digestive '
Organs ; Dyspepsia, or Indigestion; Weak- 
ness and Sourness of the Stomach; Bheu- 
matism ; Salt Bheum ; Secondary Syphilis;'
Functional Disorders of the Liver; Chronic
Eruptions of the Skin, and all Scrofulous
diseases and disorders arising from impurities of the blood.    It is also an excelUni.  remedy for the Erysipelas, Asthma,
Dropsy,  Dysentery,  and Diarrhoea,   and
for the complicated diseases of females,
so apt to end in consumption*
Dose.For an adult, a teaspoonful
four or five times a day, with or without
a little water, which may be increased to
a tablespoonful, as best suits the patient.
To guard against counterfeits, observe
the signature of the inventor on each
label and on each wrapper.
BRIEF EXPOSITION
OF   THE
Principles and Regulations
of /;/;e
SOCIETY   OF   BELIEVH:Ka.
Price, 10 cts.
Should have the beautiful 36-page Monthly
 J
 O         J
5O cts. a year.   Sample free.   Agents wanted.
THOMAS @. UEWIfiAK & SQET,
CHICAGO, ILL,
BY
SHAKERS
<pb n="" id="p28"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure.
A cream of  tartar   baking   powder
Highest of   all :n   le;.veiling strength.
Latest   United   States    Governmen
Food Report.'
Roy; l Baling Powdeh Co.,
106  Wall St., N. Y.
HO W I CAME
TO  BE
Price 5 cts.
Much knowledge for a few pennies.
Sent Postage paid to any address in the
U. S. We have on Land a few copies of
"Kip Van Winkle and other Sketches."
240 pages, 4x'5.                          10 cts.
"A treatise on The Horse," by Dr. B.
Kendall. 90 pages. 5x7//o- Profusely illustrated.                                  12 cts.
Second  vol. of Cassandra written originally in French by Sir, Charles Cotterell.
Published 1725.                                  .25
Sacred Roll and Book written by Inspiration in 1843.    A wonderful Book.     2.00
Hamlet, Prince of Denmark.
From Shakespeare.
.10
An old, brass eight day clock, in long
case, in excellent order.           $70.00
An eight day brass time  piece made in
1810   by Dr.   Thomas Corbett.    $20.00
Several small, old-fashion clocks at reasonable prices.
\ ulre^   H. C. Blinn, K. Canterbury, N. H.
(Established 1861.)
IS Oldest, LarMesi, Bent,
Cheapest and the Only
weekly Bee-Paper in all
America.  32 pagip. $1.00
a year.   Send for Ivee Sample.
$1.00 BEE-BOOK FREB
Q. W. YORK & CO., 199 Randolph St., Chicago, 111.
PLAIN TALKS
ON
PRACTICAL RELIGION
B-sivg    Candid   Answers   for Earnest
Inquirers.
By  Geo.  A.  Lomas.
Price, 10 cts.
American Bee Journal,
A   SHAKER.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>