<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm0902" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title><editor role="editor" TEIform="editor"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/></editor></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">9</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">2</biblScope><date value="18790201" TEIform="date">February 1879</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">25-48</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="9" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="2" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                        <pb id="p1"/>
                        <p> FEBRUARY, 1879. MANIFESTO. (OFFICIAL MONTHLY.) G. A. LOMAS, Editor. Published by the United Societies. : OUR HOME AT
                        SHAKERS, N. Y. "And they shall turn to you for a testimony: "Go preach the Kingdom of God/" ADDRESS ALL
                        COMMUNICATIONS TO " The Shaker Manifesto, Shakers, N.D. G. B. AVERY, PUBLISHER. 1879. Vol. IX. No. 2. 60 Cents Per
                        Annum.</p>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <pb id="p2"/>
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p> [ads deleted] </p>
                    </div2>
                        --><pb n="25" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="First morning thought" TEIform="index"/>FIRST MORNING THOUGHT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>MARY WHITCHER</byline><p TEIform="p">I've waked to duty, waked once more To view the labors of the field, And put my hand, as
                            heretofore, To work for what the earth may yield. Alike, my spirit life must toil For golden
                            grains of love and peace ; Alike, kind Providence will smile, And give my soul a rich
                            increase. Canterbury, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hygienic and Christian consistencies" TEIform="index"/>HYGIENIC AND CHRISTIAN CONSISTENCIES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, G. B." TEIform="persName"/>G. B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p">Christianity and its religion are often tabooed and cumbered with fashions and customs that
                            have their origin in accidents, incidents of climatic comfort or necessity, or the product
                            of popular opinion; and often this is of such gigantic strength, that Christian influences
                            make slow progress in eradicating errors and freaks of inconsistency. Popular opinion is,
                            commonly, a thing of gradual and slow growth ; being hampered by the thongs of custom,
                            fashion, prejudice and sympathy. Patent to the observation of all active minds is the fact
                            that, however true and useful an innovation may be, to conform society to the laws of
                            hygiene concerning the physical or spiritual man, it requires much time and labor to make a
                            change. This applies to the entire train of life's duties and practices ; for popular
                            opinion is the conservator and modifier of fashions, though not the projector nor inventor
                            of them. It is the monitorial tutor of custom in conversation, of written correspondence,
                            and largely the promulgator of habits of life and the etiquette of manner. Popular opinion
                            relative to what is conducive to health, comfort and happiness of the physical man, is
                            measurably influenced by the climatic provisions of nature. As an illustration of this, we
                            refer to the customs of the Esquimaux ; the inhabitants of Sibe- ria and Kamschatka having
                            five meals a day, and consuming immense quantities of seal's flesh, brain oil and candle
                            fish, all of which is necessary to supply the fuel for the im- mense combustion constantly
                            in operation by the intense cold and condensed atmosphere of those countries, and which
                            nature has abundantly provided in those climes for use. Also, the peculiar styles of dress
                            of both sexes in those regions, wrapping the limbs and entire frame in furs, and the
                            extremities in socks sufficient to smother an inhabitant of the torrid zone ; these
                            necessities nature has provided in those zones of frigid clime, accessible to man, but
                            denied them existence in the torrid regions. Thus the inhabitants of South America, Africa,
                            and the Society Islands, in contrast with the former, go almost, and oft times, entirely
                            naked ; subsisting upon sour fruits, blood thinners and farinacia of the most simple and
                            nitrogenous quality ; and of these they have and need but two, or but one meal a day. Thus,
                            measurably following the wake of necessity, the fashions and customs of nations and
                            individuals become inaugurated and perpetual ; and incidents of necessity teach the
                            philosophy that environs society with its customs, fashions and idiosyncrasies. Nature has
                            given those races of men who inhabit the temperate and frigid zones<pb n="26" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 26
                            THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. Straight, long, flowing, thick hair, and a beard covering a large
                            portion of the face, while those who inhabit the torrid zone have thin, short, curly hair,
                            and but little or no beard. The custom of shaving the beard appears to be of comparatively
                            modern introduction ; and, so far as we know, not originated in conformity to, or in
                            consideration of, hygienic principles; in fact, the practices of shaving and beard wearing
                            have alternated among certain nations for two thousand years, and, at one time shaving was
                            rather a sacerdotal badge, and mostly or entirely confined to the priesthood. The Turks have
                            ever held the beard a sacred trust, and, on no occasion will permit shaving it off ; while
                            at certain epochs, shaving the beard obtained prowess among other nations, possibly from
                            motives of cleanliness, convenience, or, may be the fashion obtained sympathetically. But,
                            asidefrom cleanliness (which, by the way, is no inconsiderable motive), there appears to be
                            little to recommend shaving, when hygienically considered, and its practice must be
                            considered more as the subject of fashion, than as an institution of propriety, arising from
                            necessity or climatic expediency. Mankind are so sympathetically inclined the creatures of
                            influence and circumstance, that fashion has an immense power upon society, both for good or
                            ill, according as it is wisely or unwisely adopted, and made applicable or inapplicable to
                            human needs and comforts. That religion has any just claims to fashion, consists in the fact
                            that, through the medium of the sympathies, mankind are largely influenced both for good and
                            ill ; and, through their influence there is an innate desire in human beings, devoted to the
                            maintenance of one and the same principles of philosophy or religion, to be uniformly
                            clothed and badged, as uniformity of dress, language, manner and custom, tends to harmony of
                            feelings and unity of pur pose; thus, approximately, embodying in the individual, the
                            strength of the whole multitude of the pi'ofession. Arising from these considerations and
                            tending to these results, is the institution of specific badges worn by members of a certain
                            league or order, and the effect is always beneficial to the cause instituting it and often
                            magical in its power. These considerations form the basis of any and all reasonable demands
                            of any religious institution, for a conformity of its members in fashion of dress or the
                            cutting of the hair or trimming of the beard ; and it necessarily follows that propriety, in
                            reference to the introduction of changes of fashion or custom , would consist in educating
                            the general mind into the conviction of the consistency of the proposed innovation before
                            the attempt to enforce a change, or institute an innovation upon former customs or fashions.
                            Peculiar religious habitudes of life, as the practice of virgin celibacy and others, have
                            their origin in an evolution of humanity confirmed by a spiritualistic revelation. These are
                            the constituents of man's onward march of progress into superior soul life ; carrying man
                            out of, and beyond the hygiene of the earthy rudimentary sphere of a mere physical
                            existence, and are justifiable on the basic philosophy that man's being in its entirety,
                            comprehends the evolution and development of soul, as well as physical body. The harmonious
                            and innocent development of both the animal and angel of man's being was the evident design
                            of our Creator; but, inasmuch as the angel nature of man has been subverted by and subjected
                            to the animal of his being, through his own misdirected will, a reconstruction can take
                            place only through the process of a regeneration —a new birth into an angelic sphere ; this
                            is Christianity's present object, and only consistent, life-long labor of love— to make man
                            a new creature, and to create for himself new earthly and heavenly conditions— a new earth
                            and new Heaven. Shakers. N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Herald or the Messenger of the New Covenant" TEIform="index"/>Herald or the Messenger of the New Covenant
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Teed, Cyrus Romulus R." TEIform="persName"/></byline><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">We have received a small paper called The Herald or the Messenger of the New Covenant,
                                edited by our friend, and opponent, Cyrus Romulus R. Teed. It appears to be designed to
                                prepare the public mind for a grand step forward of the human race in recognition of the
                                principles of community life and celibacy. Would it not be well for<pb n="27" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/>
                                Mr. Teed to join the Shakers? They believe in community of interest, a life of celibacy,
                                and in prophecy. Why should he not become one of them ?</p></div3><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Truth seeker" TEIform="persName"/>Truth Seeker</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Factory" TEIform="index"/>THE FACTORY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>MARTHA J. ANDERSON</byline><p TEIform="p">[At one of the meetings for social converse and mutual information, held at the North Family,
                            Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., a paper was read upon "Monopoly, Labor, Capital, and Factory Life." The
                            following articles are the result of reflections thereupon. It is a curious incident, but
                            true, that neither writer knew, nor will know till our types reveal the fact, that both
                            chose the same subject. Ed.] Down the dingy and cheerless street, Lo ! the treading of weary
                            feet Sounds as if they were going to meet Some dread and final doom ; For, from the distant
                            factory tower, Rang the bell at an early hour, Calling with tones of grasping power To loom,
                            to spindle and loom. So, with hands that are tired and worn, Clad in garments dirty and
                            torn, Cherishing ever a hope forlorn, Buried in time and sense,— They plod their way with
                            one lone thought, How shall our scanty fare be bought 1 Only as each day's work is wrought
                            Cometh our recompense. With faces wan and furrowed with care, Follows the old, the young and
                            fair. Up the narrow and winding stair, Each to their place assigned ; Never a moment glad
                            and free Like birds of the air, or fish of the sea ; But one dull round of monotony, Dwarfs
                            both body and mind. Broad and lofty the grim walls rise, Mocking the glory of earth and
                            skies, Prisons of human sacrifice. Reared by monopoly ; Shut from beauties of mount and
                            wold, Slaves to masters who hoard their gold ; Strong in the greed of power they hold, Deaf
                            to the poor man's plea. There in the dim light doomed to toil, Honest earnings the rich
                            man's spoil; Well may the feeling soul recoil From flagrant wrongs like these. Threads from
                            the myriad spindles" twirled, There from the flying shuttles hurled, Tell a tale to the
                            thinking world, And set hearts ill at ease. Coarse or fine be the fabric made, Bartered, or
                            sold by change of trade, Never can value be on it paid, For none its worth shall know; Ye,
                            who are wrapped in many a fold Of costly raiment, priced with gold, Think of the miseries
                            yet untold Through which your comforts flow! Capital wielding its arm of might, Ruletli not
                            with a love of right, Nor with equity will it requite Labor and industry ; Stately palaces
                            for its kings, With scheming plans, and plotting rings, Unto the toiler's hovel brings Woe
                            and penury. There are the waifs in mortal form, Scarcely sheltered from rudest storm, With
                            little to keep the life-blood warm, The heirs of poverty ; Generations may come and go,
                            Never a better state to know, Only to suffer while here below, Where blessings flow so free.
                            But as the law of justice stands, Air, and water, and fertile lands, Should be given into
                            the hands Of people in every clime ; Man, woman and child should be, liaised into glorious
                            liberty, Borne to a knowledge full and free Of destinies sublime. It is not noble work we
                            spurn, Nor from the marts of business turn, Only for higher motives yearn, Which prompt to
                            impulse true ; And that a grander love of right May turn life's sorrows into light, May make
                            the home and factory bright With aspects fresh and new. Then shall the glad earth, joyous
                            teem With fruits of hope's elysian dream ; And all its wondrous wealth shall seem Like gifts
                            from heaven above ; And the Millennial star of Peace Shall usher in the truth's increase ;
                            Then poverty and crime shall cease, For man shall rule by love. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Factory girl" TEIform="index"/>THE FACTORY GIRL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Byrdsall, Charlotte" TEIform="persName"/>CHARLOTTE BYRDSALL</byline><p TEIform="p">Slowly and sadly she trod along, With a weary heart that had no song. To her there was not a
                            joyous look On mountains, meadow, or sparkling brook ; But her spirit throbbed unto deep
                            despair, As she thought of the labor her life must bear. Anon, she reached her living tomb,
                            With its harsh-toned bell and days of gloom, And as she mounted the high stairway,<pb n="28" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 28 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. Her soul burst forth 'neath its weight to pray, That
                            the time of suffering might be o'er, And the wail of poverty heard no more. And as she
                            enters the place so drear, And meets no kindly word of cheer, But a frowning look from her
                            master cold, Whose soul in the greed of the world is old, And she breathes again an earnest
                            prayer That he the judgment of truth may bear. With a tired brain she begins her task,
                            Strength to perform them is all she asks ; But the threads, like those of her soul were
                            crossed, Broken and tangled, matted and lost ; Her spirit shrinks as her master hears, For
                            his threatening voices she dreads and fears. He looks not on with a pitying eye, But bids
                            her toil, and cease to cry ; For the work of the day must surely be done Ere the slow
                            decline of the setting sun ; Or the wages fail, and the place be filled By another whom
                            penury's woes has stilled. He reigns like a king on his guarded throne, Through means he has
                            shorn from the poor alone ; In his stolen wealth, that sinful man Knows naiight but the
                            schemes of the money plan; While she to the city street must turn, To beg of the selfish,
                            the proud and. the stern. O ! what is life to the children of toil, The fruit of whose labor
                            is seized as spoil ? And where is the love the Saviour told Should human hearts in sympathy
                            hold, When capital's system of plunder and gain Hath warped the being, again and again ? O,
                            Father of Justice ! with Thee I plead, To send thy Spirit against this greed, To level the
                            mountain, and lift the vale, Till goodness shall conquer, and right prevail; Then over the
                            land shall the sweet song roll Of love that delivers both body and soul. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="War, shameful" TEIform="index"/>WAR, SHAMEFUL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dibble, Chauncy" TEIform="persName"/>CHAUNCY DIBBLE</byline><p TEIform="p">Governments make war to maintain their honor. Such nations glory in their shame! How many
                            such wars haye been engaged in by England, France, Russia, Germany! Our own boasted
                            Republic! Our Indian wars, Mexican war, and our late lamented uncivil war! Were they not
                            instigated chiefly by idle politicians ? Were they wars of honor to our nation ? England,
                            not long since, was fighting a small nation, whom she ought to protect, not to fight. This
                            is her conception of honor. Her flag had been slighted. The poor Afghans had hesitated to
                            comply with her arbitrary demands. Some high fed officers tired of camp duty were thirsting
                            for military fame. The policy of rulers is for more territory. Oh, England! who, but a few
                            months since pretended to hold the balance, between Russia and Turkey ; who but lately sent
                            delegates to a Convention, of Nations assembled to discuss the propriety of settling diffi-
                            culties between governments by peaceable arbitration! Art thou first to break the peace, and
                            manifest thy impetuous tyranny over a weaker nation, not so favored with life's com- forts,
                            with literary knowledge nor gospel light as thine ? Dost thou, professing to maintain the
                            National Church of the Prince of Peace, contrary to his divine precepts, sacrifice the lives
                            of thy subjects, and oblige them to smite those who are not enemies ? Professing the
                            sanctity of the Christian, dost thou not act the heathen ? Where are thy hundreds of thou-
                            sands paupers ? Wouldst thou not reap more honor to the Christian cause, to relieve the
                            necessities of thy poor at home, than by expensive war and taxation to increase their
                            misery, by<pb n="29" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. 29 creating widows and orphans at home
                            and abroad ? Dost thou pray for the millennium, and wait for its dawn, and know not that its
                            glorious Sun of truth hath arisen ? That its life-giving atmosphere of love, peace, purity
                            and equality is circulating through the enlightened classes of minds in all countries ? And
                            dost thou, professing to be foremost in evangelical truth, reject the light of this
                            millennial day which has waited long for thee? Beware, lest by slighting the invitation,
                            thou become like the Jews of the first appearing, cast away! Look not in the clouds for the
                            Saviour ; lo! his spirit is near even in thy midst. Inasmuch as ye have done it to the least
                            ye have done it unto me. Shakers,. N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Secret of happiness" TEIform="index"/>THE SECRET OF HAPPINESS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sutton, Elizaette" TEIform="persName"/>ELIZAETTE SUTTON</byline><p TEIform="p">" The pleasure of doing good is the only pleasure that never wears out. Then should we not
                            live with the great truth constantly in mind, that unless we live to the glory of God, and
                            the highest good of our fellow men, life would be to each one of us a failure ? " If this is
                            so, how guarded we should be against self ease and pleasure. Who would not wish to bear glad
                            tidings of love and good will to all within the circle of their influence ? Home is where
                            our good works should begin — right in the little group called Home. With so many privileges
                            permitted me, I see that / can do some good if it is but little. Something smiles within me
                            when I say to my friends : "good morning!" or in a pleasant mood I lend a helping hand to
                            lift the burdens of life, or smooth the pathway of some one under trying circumstances. If I
                            see any one dejected have I a balsam to administer, in kind words of heaven-born love and
                            deep soul interest, which may reflect sunshine, and give relief to half the disaffected
                            feelings which too often arise ? Some love, with no hatred, removes a load of
                            unpleasantness, and opens avenues of real good as a final result. I will live to do good;
                            and strive to do no harm, that heaven may bless me; that my superiors may approve of and
                            love me, and my associates truly appreciate my intentions to live as a Christian should
                            live. This is the result, when full obedience to my Shaker faith is complied with. ML
                            Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Extraordinary prophecy" TEIform="index"/>"EXTRAORDINARY PROPHECY."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, Frederick W." TEIform="persName"/>FREDERICK W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p">Such is the caption to an article in The American Socialist, of a late date. "The Christian
                            Dispensation is drawing to a close. A new dispensation will be inaugurated in countries
                            occupied by AngloSaxons, in the year 1881. The bible will receive a more spiritual
                            interpretation. Modern Spiritualism was needed to show men its hidden, actual, spiritual
                            meaning. There will be notliing under the new dispensation out of harmony with the teachings
                            of Jesus, but these teachings will be better understood and more conscientiously and
                            thoroughly brought to bear on daily life. In three years hence, a man and woman will set up
                            the new dispensation. Wonders, surpassing<pb n="30" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 30 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. any
                            thing previously seen, will soon appear in connection with spiritualism. Mediums will be
                            controlled in large public halls. The controlling spirits will then materialize themselves
                            and deliver addresses, the medium sitting entranced on the platforms. The materialized
                            spirits will speak through their own materialized organisms, and will be seen by every
                            person present, whether believer or unbeliever; whether gifted with the powers of
                            clairvoyance or not. No cabinets will be necessary. All that may be required will be that
                            persons who have been sitting together in seances, and who are mediumistic, occupy the
                            places nearest the platform, so as to increase the power. As a result, men will be bound
                            together, not by creeds, but by personal purity, a desire for holiness and a love to God and
                            one another." The above prophecy is through W. J. Colville, an English medium now in this
                            country. The remarkable salient points are (1.) The definite time set, agreeing with so many
                            other prophecies of 1880 and 1881. (2.) The confining of the coming events to the
                            Anglo-Saxon race. (3.) Recognizing the male and female principles as cooperating in the new
                            dispensation. (4.) The substance of the prophecy agreeing with Shaker faith and prin-
                            ciples, and its minute coincidence with prophecies given during our weeh of seances, last
                            fall, at Mt. Lebanon. (5.) The practical end to be reached through helping spiritual agency.
                            'l Man's extremity is God's opportunity." Help, or we perish ! is the cry going up from
                            thousands upon earth to the spirit world. Not for idle curiosity ; not for personal
                            aggrandizement ; not to exalt some individual sect or people, but to help humanity by such
                            means as humanity requires. If individuals, societies or peoples are exalted in the process,
                            let it be inevitable—a consequence of their usefulness. Let all receive as their works shall
                            be. The controlling spirit—Brown—at Ohittenden, four years ago, promised the Shakers that
                            the spirits would materialize at Mt. Lebanon. Again, when materializing here, he promised to
                            do just what this English medium predicts ; to materialize (under Shaker auspices), and
                            speak to large public assemblies. The cry of the people is for bread ; for the loaves and
                            fishes. Under the present competitive system, bread exists, but the hungry cannot get it. It
                            is merchandise, to be bought and sold, after being made by machinery. Even the " souls of
                            men" are numbered as among the items of merchandise, in Christendom that would cease to be
                            objects of traffic. The radical, organic truths that alone can revolutionize society and
                            begin to fulfill the predictions of the 21 of Revelations, will be heralded by the extending
                            agency of physical materializations, as being adapted to the receptive forces of the human
                            soul. The material loaves and the spiritual agency must be combined to produce the desired
                            result. Man shall not live by bread alone, nor by philos- ophy alone, but by every word that
                            proceedeth out of the mouth of God through prophets and prophetesses inspired by the
                            Christ-spirit since the world began. The land reformers ; the abolitionist of wages, slavery
                            ; the woman's rights man ; the peace advocate ; the physiologist; the temperance lecturer
                            and the dress reformer will all be vitalized by spiritual influences that will send their
                                truths<pb n="31" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 31 home to the hearts and consciences
                            of the people, apparently without any reason. What may be called the foolishness of God will
                            supplant the wisdom, and scientific knowledge of man, because the one is included in the
                            other. " If one rise from the dead they will believe." We shall see how that is, for the
                            dead will be more alive than the living. They will speak to mortal man, though his hair
                            stand erect upon his head like quills upon the fretful porcupine. Blessed then will be the
                            pure in heart, whose lives are clean from selfish, sinful, monopolizing worldliness. Such
                            will be welcome helps on the platform, kindred souls with just men and women from spirit
                            homes, who have died to self and who live to G-od and for humanity. Hail the day so long
                            predicted, Hail the final jubilee ; Hail, all hail! triumphant gladness, Be to ransomed
                            souls set free. " Blessed are they who keep the sayings of this book "—Revelations— and of
                            the living prophets of our own day and time. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Echoes" TEIform="index"/>ECHOES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, Catharine" TEIform="persName"/>CATHARINE ALLEN</byline><p TEIform="p">On the banks of some placid sheet of water how many persons, almost unconsciously, have
                            picked up pebbles and cast them one by one into the crystal depths, and watched the circles
                            form and widen until their ripples reached the shore. The atmosphere surrounding the earth
                            is a vast ocean whose susceptibility to motion is far greater than that of water ; and all
                            sound is received by vibrations or waves in the air, similar to those we see in water when
                            its tranquillity is disturbed by any thing dropped therein. But the ocean of air is compara-
                            tively limitless, and, surrounding a globe, it can have no shores. Where, then, do its waves
                            cease their expanding circles? Philosophers tell us that they never cease ; that the active
                            principle which produces sound continues its vibrations and repeats its echoes throughout
                            the universe eternally. Sublime thought! Who can contemplate the magnitude of the wondrous
                            laws which pulsate the heart of creation without turning in reverential aspiration to the
                            supreme origin ? And when we remember, as one said anciently, that " he who knows God only
                            through His creation, knows Him merely by his shadow," and that even when the veil is lifted
                            from nature's rich arcana, the fragments of scientific truth which are perceived by the
                            intellect are only outward expressions of spirit forces more subtle and interior, which
                            emanate from the great soul of all being. Then, if the little telephone — as yet imperfect —
                            seems a wonderful thing, because of its capacity to reproduce the messages which have once
                            been conveyed through it, what must be the chorus of the myriad voices whose echoes are
                            perpetually rolling through the boundless universe of soul? Let us close the senses to
                            outward things, that with quickened spirit-powers we may list to the tones of God's voice
                            which comes down to us from the unknown infinitude ; that we may learn something of the
                            means by which they have reached us, and mark their effect upon our present being. There
                            have been and are individuals here and there who, by an inner sense, could learn and
                            describe the early location and surroundings and much of the subsequent history of pearls
                            and shells from the strand, mossy rocks from the forest, ancient coins from desolated
                            cities, and other things which we are accustomed to think of as utterly inert, even when
                            these are far remote from their native homes. This proves the susceptibility of the most
                            inactive substances to impressions from surrounding objects, and the echo of all with which
                            they have come in contact rebounds upon sensitive minds. Others, through the powers of
                            reason, illumined and quickened by intuition, have<pb n="32" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 32 THE SHAKES
                            MANIFESTO. listened to the music of the mighty laws by which God called the universe into
                            being, and whose harmonious action, through whirling centuries, has sustained and held
                            within their orbits the countless systems of worlds which fill immensity of space. The
                            refraction of this music reached Galileo's superior perceptions, when, in face of dungeon
                            bars and fiery stake, he made the then startling declaration, " The world moves!" Years
                            later its refrain was echoed to Newton by the falling of an apple from its parent stem. From
                            that moment the mystery of the grand dual forces, vitalized by the central soul, and
                            extending to the smallest atom of creation, has been gradually disclosing. When Franklin
                            bottled the lightnings from the sky, and some of his scientific successors sent it flying
                            over mountain and plain, and through the billowy deep, bearing the thoughts of men, it was
                            another expression of the same law reflected from the invisible world which prompted their
                            ideas, and the pressure of unseen powers which urged and sustained the projectors in the
                            enterprise, when the tongue of ridicule was rampant and gaunt poverty stood ready to seize
                            them should failure mark their efforts. Tones caught from the sphere of causation have
                            exercised a strong influence in developing more rational philosophies and a higher
                            civilization, particularly in the western world, and they still repeat themselves in
                            advancing waves of thought; but far more potent in the elevation of man have been those
                            influences which have acted upon his higher religious nature — the echoes from the inner
                            spiritual spheres, which have been borne by superior intelligences to all receptive minds
                            down through the ages ; and there have ever been agencies through which the will of the
                            Infinite has been made known to mortals. In the motions of the little ship anciently carried
                            by priests, veiled in a sacred shrine, whose sails were moved by spirit wings, in the
                            letters on the breastplate, illumined by Shechina's light, in the voice between the Cherubim
                            and from the burning bush, in the laws engraved on tables of stone, in the thunders which
                            rolled from Sinai's height, from mouths of prophets and holy witnesses, and through
                            innumerable instrumentalities, the oracles of God have been sounded to the denizens of
                            earth, whatever may have been the means employed or the ideas received, some important
                            principle has always been embodied. The more spiritual class, unsatisfied with outward
                            signs, have earnestly aspired for communion with divine teachers, that they might know of
                            the nature and destiny of the soul ; that they might learn truth and establish its immutable
                            laws among mankind. For this purpose many beautiful souls have nobly struggled with inward
                            foes until the wild tumult of passion was hushed and the voice of earthly pleasure silenced
                            by conquest. Then in the pure air of the mountain heights, the solitudes of the valley, or
                            the stillness of the lone chamber, away from outward obstructions, with uplifted hearts,they
                            have sought the Divine presence. The inspirations which then flowed into their inner
                            consciousness was the music of angel bands floating through celestial air. They caught the
                            strains, and transmitted those echoes to other souls, and history proves to us that their
                            melodies have reverberated from mind to mind down through the long corridors of time, whose
                            walls yet vibrate with lofty sentiments, and humanity bear the impress of their refining
                            influences. Linked in the great chain of being, no one can live for himself alone ; even our
                            inmost thoughts bear upon the individual character, and are manifest through deeds.
                            Conscious of this great law, let us, through rational self-denial and deep spirit- ual
                            devotion, ascend to those holy heights where we, too, may have our beings raptured with the
                            music of the spheres ; the bells of truth are ever pealing forth their harmonies from the
                            glory-lighted dome of life's stupendous temple. The heavenly archways resound their
                            chimings, and the invisible hosts chant their sweet symphonies and draw near to earth
                            seeking receptive minds to whom they can impart what they have learned, that all the strains
                            of music which have ever reached the ears of mortals are<pb n="33" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. 33 but parts of the one song of the universe — " God is love." Let our life so
                            accord with all truth that its echo forever shall be, " God is love." Mount Lebanon, N. Y.
                        </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Renovation" TEIform="index"/>RENOVATION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Collins, E. F." TEIform="persName"/>E. F. COLLINS</byline><p TEIform="p">The principle of renovation has been working ever since the creation of spirit and matter.
                            All of material nature tends to death and decay, as we term it, but is only undergoing the
                            continuation of change through the chemical action of unseen forces. All force, spirit and
                            power are too subtle for the natural organ of sight, though we are made aware of their
                            potency by effects produced on every thing movable, tangible or auricular, from which we
                            draw conclusive evidence that the unseen is the powerful, active and living motor of all
                            creations, spiritual and natural. Like the leaven in the wheat, God has striven in the heart
                            of man to quicken his sensibilities and convictions of right and wrong, as also the powers
                            of evil have labored to maintain a claim and hold on his being, as a medium for the working
                            of darkness. From the first efforts of the little child, we trace the unfolding of the two
                            natures —the appreciation of the divine and religious, and the tendency to violate a con-
                            sciousness of right and seek its own covering of falsehood. As the bud of infancy opens to
                            years of understanding, so is the choice made which to serve, vice or virtue. To those who
                            form a covenant with life to their souls, and embrace virtue as their standard, to wave
                            above the legion of temptations, follies and insinuations of its antagonist, there is a long
                            struggle, a contest which shall keep the soul in the battle field till the giant wrong is
                            felled to the ground and peace is proclaimed through self conquest. But right over might,
                            and good over evil, Will sway in the heart that is valiant and strong ; As ebony darkness
                            gives place to the sunlight, So truth shall succeed every error and wrong. To those who
                            established our peculiar Order on the rock of true principle — " founding the fabric we
                            love"—we are indebted, for they, through hardship, toil and voluntary sufferings, founded
                            our Zion home. Though necessity in its sternness brought upon them the burden of heavy
                            labor, hunger, and the denial of bodily comforts, the ardency of spirit with which they
                            worshipped God and destroyed evil, was as a never-failing spring of sweet waters, whose
                            powers to refresh were often miraculous. These pillars were brought into the temple during
                            the prevalence of a religious revival, which had spread extensively over the land —one of
                            God's revolutions in the spiritual elements which have ever marked past history, and will
                            continue to bear impress on the future annals of time. Conviction for sin, and desires for
                            redemption, strengthened endurance of trials in our dear gospel fathers and mothers, the
                            realization of which we who live in a day of plentitude may never know. The baptism
                            descending on those good old worthies, extended its influence down through future
                            generations, to bless and inspire the people, even when their saintly shadows had long
                            ceased their casting within the limits of their transient home. Like all other religious
                            waves that have passed over nations, these waters receded to the great eternal ocean,
                            gradually leaving the world to move on in the career of sin and folly till spiritual
                            destitution has seemingly written despair on the rushing throng of humanity, and nearly
                            everywhere the soul is seen silently begging the bread of life, too often to receive a
                            stone. But God lives on, and will again strike conviction in the hearts of the people, to
                            waken to righteousness. To every age He has sent a Chrishna, a Buddha, a Jesus or an Ann Lee
                            ; and shall not many Saviours appear, for the salvation of the race, according to the time
                            and need ? Tho' truth, like a slumbering volcano, may be inactive for a time, the trembling
                            of distant thunderings, of great causes, are indicative of the approach, or outbreak, of
                                a<pb n="34" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 34 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. revival of soul-life that shall again
                            show that God and truth are eternal, and are alone exempt from the laws of change and decay.
                            Who has not some time in life, even though perhaps at the eleventh hour, heard the soft
                            footsteps of an angel without the gate, and answered the gentle knock at the door of the
                            heart for an entrance, whose presence has unsealed fountains long dry, and sent forth
                            streams of repentant tears ; when the misdeeds of sleeping conscience have been brought from
                            the many secret chambers, where they had been stored away in hoped-for forgetfulness ? And
                            who in that hour has not longed for a confiding friend, to whom the troubled mind might be
                            relieved of its burden; and failing to find such, has seen, with sadness, the angel re-
                            cross the threshold, to vanish from sight; the fountains run dry, and the deeds of life
                            replaced in the little closets of the heart and locked up, to remain until a second visit
                            from the angel of conviction brings them forth with greater vividness ? Who has not, when in
                            Methodist, Presbyterian, or other revival meetings, tasted the sweet and heavenly showers of
                            divine life, desired and resolved to live more godly—to " cease from doing evil and to learn
                            to do well ? " God toes and will never forsake humanity. Mortals, through sin and
                            waywardness, may wander like sheep from the fold, forsaking the good shepherd and
                            shepherdess, but God will never forsake. The manifestation of spirit-force has ever found
                            mediums through whom to flow — either in bodily exercise, in tongue, or profound silence —
                            in whose depth a lasting substance could be gained; such oracles have been and are a
                            blessing. As the foundation of our Zion is spirituality, purity and true religion, these
                            elements must be sustained by the same effort that laid it. And as time has added many years
                            to the lives of our present exemplars, let us who are young feel the weight of the burden,
                            and prepare ourselves to cheerfully relieve them of their care, that they may see their
                            latest sun set in peace, and bless the work of God as it is borne on by the earnest and
                            strong. Let us, through exertion, send a thrill of power through Zion that shall awaken
                            vitality, and set her pulse throbbing anew with the life-blood of spiritual testimony that
                            shall declare, " God lives and will revive His people." Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Music vs. theology" TEIform="index"/>MUSIC VS. THEOLOGY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p">The gift of music was co-eval with theology among believers called Shakers. There came a time
                            when the singing proved to be defective, not meeting the spiritual wants of the order. A new
                            step was taken — music began to be cultivated as a science, but not until, in some families,
                            it absorbed much Christianity to endure the singing. A Quaker visitor once said of us, " I
                            feared they would take the roof of the house off." Were I to say that about the same time,
                            the Theology of our Zion was in a similarly dilapidated condition, would it be a hard saying
                            ? Does it trench upon our infallibility any more to acknowledge our imperfection in theology
                            than in music ? I think not. The one is as susceptible to progressive influences as the
                            other. Coming, as did Mother Ann, from the down-trodden, laboring class in Babylon,
                            revelation had to supply the place of education with herself and followers. I trust that
                            science and revelation will never more be separated in either our music or theology. [As our
                            grand, old leader in Shaker theology, Elder Evans, shows a tremendous humility, consistency
                            and good sense, to acknowledge the evolutions and progress in our theology, we commend these
                            ideas to the New Jerusalem Messenger. Ed.</p></div2><pb n="35" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religion" TEIform="index"/>RELIGION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bullard, Marcia M." TEIform="persName"/>MARCIA M. BULLARD</byline><p TEIform="p">I saw my brother bending beneath a weight of care, Hie tottering footsteps tending to sorrow
                            and despair; His feeble spirit failing for want of kindly aid, No friendly hand availing
                            when sorest sorrows weighed ; I saw the hoary wanderer bereft of kin and home, In this fair
                            earth a stranger, for want had made him roam ; Through dreary snows of winter, beneath the
                            tempest's blast, His only hopes were centered, to find the grave at last. I heard the cannon
                            booming, the mingled din of war, And saw the gallant falling beneath the battle star; I
                            heard the wounded groaning upon a bed of pain, The wailing of the widow for those in battle
                            slain; I saw the orphans toiling for bread they could not gain, With tiny hands uplifted,
                            alas! they plead in vain; To them but crumbs were falling from tables spread by wealth, Till
                            forced by want appalling they took their bread by stealth. I saw a fair-haired first-born, a
                            mother's hope and joy— A father's pride and promise, his only darling boy; I saw him in his
                            manhood, so noble in his mind, In honor rising upward, exalted place to find; But ah! I saw
                            him bending to sip the flowing bowl, Hi3 steps were downward tending to degradation's goal;
                            I saw him when in horror he shrank from human eye, When those who seemed the warmest but
                            sadly passed him by. I saw my sister languish—temptation's snare endure; I saw her keenest
                            anguish while striving to be pure; Her little cup o'erflowing with misery, want and woe, I
                            heard her soul outpouring for help she could not know ; I saw her weakly yielding, for she
                            could bear no more, Within her heart was grieving that she had been so poor, With garments
                            torn and tattered, a stain upon her brow, While those who fondly flattered, turned coldly
                            from her now. I saw a loving maiden, in simple raiment clad, Her countenance all beaming
                            with love that maketh glad, She came unto the sorrowing — the heavy- laden heart. And to the
                            wearied mourner true comfort to impart, She gently took the burden from off the care-worn
                            breast, Then led the way through quiet paths into the home of rest; She gave the lonely
                            stranger a shelter from the storm, The tattered wretched ranger she clothed in garments
                            warm. The stricken mourning widow was comforted and fed, The famished toiling orphans she
                            blessed with needed bread ; She stretched her hands out bravely toward the field of blood,
                            Her magic wand was powerful to stay the fiery flood ; She poured the healing balsam into the
                            deadly wound, And o'er contending forces she spread a calm profound, Through all her land
                            was twining the Olive and the Vine, For Peace had here a temple, and there a sacred shrine.
                            Unto the foul inebriate she gave a helping hand, Uplifted from the fallen state she made him
                            firmly stand Against the tempter's dire assaults, with reason armed his soul, With
                            resolution filled his heart, to hate the cursed bowl; She smote the chain that bound him—the
                            tyrant's fetters fell— No more the serpent charmed him, she broke the magic spell, • She
                            laved his burning temples in nature's cooling tide, And to his beating bosom brought back
                            his manhood's pride. She bathed the fallen sister, with water from the brink Of life's
                            reclaiming river, and there she bade her drink, She taught her how to cleanse her robes —
                            her innocence restore, Then said in gentle accents, " go thou and sin no more."<pb n="36" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 36 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. She tills the heart with tenderness, with charity
                            and love, Spreads o'er the earth a gentleness—the spirit of the dove— Eedeemer of the
                            erring, unknown to worldly fame, From heaven hath descended, Religion is her name. Canaan,
                            N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Manifesto: we cannot do it" TEIform="index"/>THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. WE CANNOT DO IT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Several letters lie before us, each very smoothly, yet respectfully asking u if Shaherism
                                cannot be made more palatable," so that our present numbers of a few thousands, might be
                                multiplied into as many millions ? Thanking the good intentions of our corre- spondents,
                                we have only to reply: We, the Shakers, did not originate Shakerism ; would never have
                                made it as it is; but had it waited existence at our selfish, mortal inclinations, we
                                would very likely have made it as " palatable " to poor, fallen, fleshly human nature as
                                they could have desired ; and as attractive to the millions, by the absence of the
                                Christian's cross, as is the Catholic, Methodist, Baptist, Presbyterian, or any
                                man-made, man-pleasing theology. Our chief concern is, not to be self-pleasers in the
                                lusts of the world ; but God pleasers in all the self-denials necessary to make of us
                                Christians. The world do not ask us in plain terms to be less pure ; less unselfish ;
                                less peaceable; but every line of such sympathy as pities our self-denying lives and
                                constant cross-bearing, and wishing us more worldly, palatable indulgence, and promising
                                as a consequence, great numbers, is of the world, and very unchristian. In believing
                                Christianity as best for us, and for our certain elevation above the passions of human
                                perversion, as well as mere worldly good, we accepted Shakerism, so called, as the best
                                exponent, to-day, of the ancient faith of Jesus; and just as Jesus crucified himself to
                                the world, lived apart from its generative, selfish, warring tendencies, so we have
                                voluntary pinned ourselves upon that identical cross; and though all the world promise
                                to join us, if we will come down from the principles of the Shaker cross, tve cannot, we
                                will not do it. We have derived too much unworldly happiness, too much serene
                                justification, in our more than accepted vows of consecration to virgin celibacy and
                                chastity, to come down now. Our lives are none too near the Master's, with all of the
                                rules regulating Shaker life, that we can justifi- ably pause for worldly refreshment.
                                Our lives are not now too fully hid with Christ's in godly unselfishness that we can
                                with any Christian consideration deny ourselves of less. Our lives are not so free from
                                those entangling turmoils, that rise from fleshly taint to disturb a Christian peace,
                                that we can turn our battles from within, and fight a little without, and still be
                                Christians. Not so, dear friends; do not ask us to come down from the cross which Christ
                                bore, but be drawn nearer unto him by similar denials and similar life. There is too
                                little of radical Christianity now in the world ; the tendency of the world is ever away
                                from it. Bather join us in the endeavor to be living samples of the faith delivered to
                                the apostles and to us, in and by the life of Jesus, the gdii0rtat.<pb n="37" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/>
                                THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 37 Christ of his day. Look we all around us, and in the almost
                                forgotten past, to see wrecks upon wrecks of institutions which aimed at an improvement
                                of Shakerism, by leaving out its " unpalatable " features ! Virgin Celibacy and Chastity
                                unpalatable ? The Christian Unselfishness of Jesus unpalatable ? Peace, unpalatable ?
                                Separation from the world — its carnal, corroding, scorfcative loves and lusts,
                                unpalatable ? Ask us not, to make these unpalatable, we cannot do it. </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sum total" TEIform="index"/>THE SUM TOTAL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">While theology is good as a guideboard, the end to be accomplished is to live the very
                                best, possible life. 'Tis not to live under illy-considered denials to self, nor to make
                                ourselves unhappy with the idea that our unhappiness is in the least pleasing to God, or
                                • to mediators between us and God. Self-denials and crosses are ever accompanied by
                                tribulations, and out of these tribulations, if the denials and crosses are
                                well-considered, as means to better ends, the denials and crosses will cease to be such
                                —will be worn out as such denominations—and a re-generation ensue which will shed a halo
                                of happiness from a course of life which once was obnoxious, and thought to be
                                unbearable. If there is any system of life, whose sum total will foot up for our benefit
                                a greater amount of a happiness which gold and silver cannot buy—which the world cannot
                                give nor take away—than Christianity gives us right here, we want to know of it. We do
                                not now know of it. Skeptics decry Christianity because of its supposed selfish, carnal,
                                fleshly and its many worldly attachments, but any system called Christianity having such
                                features, hanging like barnacles to it, is unworthy of the name, and the end thereof is
                                disappointment. There are many professions called Christianity; there are many noble men
                                and women who are as yet unable to deny themselves of all that Jesus, the Christ, denied
                                himself, but whoso would be an uncompromising, radical Christian, and reap and en joy
                                the sum total which Jesus right- fully earned, will accept the " follow me" as meaning
                                all that it meant in him, and his followers cannot engage in the good nor bad of worldly
                                principles which Jesus discarded, and at the same time expect to share in the glories,
                                which shine out as sums total in his career, and to which we all pay such fulsome praise
                                in admiration, song and speech, but which too many think cost too much to earn—too much
                                of self-denials. "When Jesus comes," he will ask of us, not what we have believed, but "
                                how nearly have you followed the example I have set you in purity, peace and
                                unselfishness ?" How useless then to talk of creeds; how more than useless then to say :
                                " I thought," " I was told," " I had faith to believe," " I hoped, etc." " Where is your
                                unselfish manhood or womanhood?" "Where, your selfdenials to live better than the world,
                                and like unto me ? " " My virgin purity, meant consecration of self to higher purposes,
                                where is yours ?" "My life taught peace and unretalia-<pb n="38" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 38 THE
                                SHAKER MANIFESTO. tion, does yours v " "I might have been owner of wife, children,
                                houses, lands, and been King in the world ; these I denied as an example for all who
                                would be my disciples—Christians —nobler men and women than the surrounding world." "
                                Why have ye called me Lord, Lord, yet followed not me, nor done the things I commanded
                                you ? " " Go, learn now, that as you sow, so shall you reap; and as you choose to live
                                like Christ, or rather as a worldling, so will be your sum total in the eternal world."
                                Such will be some of the utterances of Christ to the world, " When Jesus Comes." </p></div3><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>NOTES</head><div4 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian progress" TEIform="index"/>Christian Progress</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The Shaker Manifesto is much pleased because the Boston
                                            Investigator—rational- istic—has pronounced Shakerism a form of primitive
                                            Christianity. The Investigator applied that epithet simply because the
                                            Shakers live in a community in very much the same way the early Church
                                            lived, in view of the supposed near Jiteral Coming of the Lord. But even if
                                            the Investigator had meant that the Shakers were like primitive Christians
                                            in their purity, we ask, Does Christianity make no progress in history ?•
                                            Must the advancement be downhill so that we must ever look backward for
                                            purity ? We much prefer to look forward and to be able to say: This is the
                                            Christianity which shall prevail in the future, rather than: This is past
                                            Christianity.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New Jerusalem messenger" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit> We clip the above from the New Jerusalem Messenger, of which we have had many
                                    good words to speak. We are sorry our contemporary is jealous of us, particularly
                                    when we are praised for our Christian tendencies, by so radically an infidel sheet
                                    as The Investigator. But amid our sorrow, we will render to it corroborative and
                                    com- forting answers. 1. Certainly, Christianity does not make much noble progress
                                    in history ; it progresses carnal, flesh-loving, selfish men and women, while they
                                    yet live on earth, into sinless, angelic, Christlike individuals —the progress being
                                    in the individuals more particularly than in the system. 2. Nay, the advancement is
                                    uphill, forward, ascending and eternal for aught we now know. 3. "We," too, " much
                                    prefer to look forward and be able to say:" This is past Christianity, present
                                    Christianity and most assuredly, this Shakerism is "' the Christianity which shall
                                    prevail in the future!'' Permit me to correct you, friend Messenger'. The
                                    Investigator did not " pronounce Shakerism a form of primitive Christianity ; " but
                                    it did say: " Shakerism is primitive Christianity," for which we render it our
                                    thanks. </p></div4><div4 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True ring" TEIform="index"/>The True Ring</head><p TEIform="p">The Churchman says : " Men judge of Christianity by the lives of those who profess
                                    and call themselves Christians," which we most assuredly agree with others, is a
                                    truth worth heeding in our Church. If we desire to proclaim our doctrines, we must
                                    live them.</p></div4><div4 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To those interested" TEIform="index"/>To Those Interested</head><p TEIform="p">We hold ourselves open to lecture engagements for any further fuller exposition of "
                                    Shaker Faith and Principles," also upon " The Jews, Jesus and Christians," "
                                    Spiritualism among the Shakers," " The False and the Truth of Spiritualism" "The
                                    Gospel of Common Sense." Our only stipulation would be to be paid our expenses in
                                    transitu, and a sum equal to twentyfive subscriptions for The Manifesto.</p></div4><div4 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><pb n="39" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Great need" TEIform="index"/>A Great Need</head><p TEIform="p">Will there not be a unanimous desire expressed for the re-issue of the paper
                                    Fractional Currency? Silver is heavy, unmailable and inconvenient, excepting as a
                                    necessity. Will not the press of the country urge upon our Senators and
                                    Representatives in Congress, for a bill that will give us paper money of frac-
                                    tional values, even as we now have legal tenders in greenbacks of larger
                                    denominations? In the meantime, let our subscribers comfort themselves with the
                                    pleasant assurance that a One Dollar Greenback will ensure a copy of The Manifesto
                                    to them for 1879, and also a copy to another of similar appreciations.</p></div4><div4 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Timely reminder" TEIform="index"/>A Timely Reminder</head><p TEIform="p">This office does not own a dollar, and its incumbent gets no salary ; do not then
                                    forget us in your charities, and let those who desire replies to their letters,
                                    please inclose the return postage.</p></div4><div4 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bad prophecies" TEIform="index"/>BAD PROPHECIES</head><p TEIform="p">An almanac maker, who it must be admitted has prophesied correctly in several re-
                                    markable instances, says: "1879 will be a year of troubles. In February, Saturn and
                                    Mars will come in conjunction, stirring up trouble in Europe, Mexico and India. In
                                    March, many deeds of vengeance will be perpetrated in Russia, and on March 11 danger
                                    will lurk about Emperor William. A great church scandal will be developed in
                                    England. War and famine in China and India. Great discord between President Hayes
                                    and his people ; also with the Indians. In April, great religious agitations. In
                                    May, great adversity with railway securities. In June, war in Austria, Turkey and
                                    Greece. In America, cruel epidemic fever and cattle disease. Good fortune to the
                                    ADVOCATES OF WOMEN SUFFRAGE. In DECEMBER, Socialists of Europe will become a terror,
                                    and shake many dynasties." This London astrologist has gained celebrity by coming
                                    within 24 hours of the earthquake at Cumana in which 4,000 lives were lost ; also of
                                    the Ashtabula railroad horror, and by the terrible sunstrokes of last July. We wish
                                    him good luck in better prophecies. </p></div4><div4 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="One dollar per capitum" TEIform="index"/>One Dollar Per Capitum</head><p TEIform="p">The primitive Methodist church of England is considered the poorest Christian
                                    community in that country, and yet it raised last year $150,000 for missionary
                                    purposes. This was an average of one dollar for every member of the denomination,
                                    and a higher average than that of most of the wealthier denominations.</p></div4><div4 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hark!" TEIform="index"/>Hark !</head><p TEIform="p">— A new religion has appeared in India. It is called the " Arya Somaj," and of its
                                    tenets The Pall Mall Gazette says, they " comprise a revival of most of the fair
                                    humanities of old religion which are associated with some of the mysterious rites of
                                    which the trustees of the British Museum prudently keep the memorials in a cellar."
                                    An English member of the sect declares that it is " the purest religious movement of
                                    modern times, and a reformatory agitation which inculcates a morality of almost
                                    unattainable severity," adding that so far from being a secret society, as has been
                                    said, it is '' the most active and public propaganda now existing in India, or
                                    perhaps in the world, not excepting the Christian missionary enterprises, to which,
                                    no doubt, it is bitterly opposed."</p></div4></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>FARM ITEMS.</head><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Take care of the ashes" TEIform="index"/>Take care of the ashes...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Take Care of the Ashes.—Many fires occur through careless disposal of ashes. The ash
                                house should be at a safe distance from any other buildings. A safe way is, to keep the
                                ashes in an iron can or holder, until cool, and then throw them into the box or
                                receptacle provide d for them. Wood ashes are too valuable to waste, and coal ashes make
                                an excellent absorbent in the earth-closet, and are very good for making hard foot
                                paths.</p></div3><pb n="40" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In stormy weather..." TEIform="index"/>In stormy weather...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">In Stormy Weather the stock are better under cover than exposed to the wintry blasts. It
                                is a mistake to suppose that exposure makes them hardy; on the contrary, they are
                                weakened by it.</p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A barrel of plaster should be kept..." TEIform="index"/>A barrel of plaster should be kept...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A Barrel of Plaster should be kept in a handy place in every stable and manure cellar.
                                Where this is used constantly, there will be freedom from the usual strong odor of
                                stables and fermenting manure, and a saving of valuable material which would otherwise
                                escape. </p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ewes" TEIform="index"/>Ewes
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Ewes.—A chilled lamb may be restored by a warm bath and a teaspoonful of hot ginger tea.
                                The lamb should be thoroughly dried and wrapped round witli a strip of woollen cloth.
                                The ewes should be well nursed with warm gruel for a few days. Provide warm pens for
                                early lambing ewes</p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A curr-comb or card and brush..." TEIform="index"/>A curr-comb or card and brush...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A Curry-Comb or Card and Brush, freely used, will help to keep the cows, calves, and
                                other cattle, as well as horses, in good health and comfort. If there is a doubt about
                                this, a short trial will convince any one that the practice is a profitable one.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>Home Topics</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dr. Warren states 'a simple, easy and effectual cure..." TEIform="index"/>Dr. Warren states 'a simple, easy and effectual cure...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Dr. Warren states " a simple, easy and effectual cure of stammering " is, simply at every
                                syllable pronounced to tap at the same time with the finger; by so doing " the most
                                inveterate stammerer will be surprised to find that he can pronounce quite fluently, and
                                by long and constant practice he will pronounce perfectly well. </p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ginger-bread nuts" TEIform="index"/>Ginger-bread nuts
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Ginger-bread nuts. Rub half a pound of butter into two pounds of flour; add one pound of
                                coarse sugar, and one ounce of pounded ginger ; mix all well together with one pound and
                                two ounces of molasses; form it into nuts, or roll it out and cut it into round cakes ;
                                bake them upon tins. </p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rice snow" TEIform="index"/>Rice snow
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Mice snow. Put to cook four spoonfuls of ground rice—it can be ground in any
                                coffeemill—-in one pint of water; stir well and cook about fifteen minutes, then add two
                                spoonfuls of butter, a little salt, two spoonfuls of white sugar, and a few drops of
                                lemon essence; have boiling one pint of milk ; pour it over the rice; stir well and let
                                it boil until thick ; then pour into a dish for table. It is excellent, either warm or
                                cold. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Odors from cooking prevented" TEIform="index"/>Odors from cooking prevented
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Odors from cooking prevented.—Put one or two red peppers on a few pieces of charcoal into
                                the pot where ham, cabbage, etc., is boiling, and the house will not be filled with the
                                offensive odor. </p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fruit-cake" TEIform="index"/>Fruit-cake
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Fruit-cake.—Three-fourths of a pound of butter, one pound of sugar, one pound of flour,
                                eight eggs, one cup of molasses, two tea spoonfuls each of cinnamon, cloves and
                                allspice. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To remove a glass stopper..." TEIform="index"/>To remove a glass stopper...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">To remove a glass stopper, put a drop or two of glycerine or sweet oil in the crevice
                                about the stopper. In an hour or two the stopper will be loose. </p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nice way to cook eggs" TEIform="index"/>Nice way to cook eggs
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A nice way to cook eggs. Butter a saucepan ; break into it the eggs; do not crowd them ;
                                put in a little butter, salt and pepper over each ; set iii a heated oven until the
                                whites set. Thus treated they are more delicate than fried eggs. </p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Egg balls" TEIform="index"/>Egg balls
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Egg balls.—To make egg balls beat up the yolks of three hard-boiled eggs in a mortar with
                                the yolk of one raw egg; make into balls and drop them into boiling water for two
                                minutes.</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wafers" TEIform="index"/>Wafers
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Wafers.—Beat up an egg thoroughly, and stir in enough flour to make a stiff paste. Add a
                                pinch of salt, roll out very thin and fry in boiling hot fat. Keep them spread upon a
                                platter if possible, as they lose their crispness when piled upon one another. </p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ground tea" TEIform="index"/>Ground tea
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Ground tea.—A French chemist asserts that if tea be ground like coffee, immediately
                                before hot water is poured upon it, it will yield nearly double the amount of its
                                exhilarating qualities.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ants" TEIform="index"/>Ants
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Ants.—It is alleged that alum water is good, or rather bad, for ants. Brush all the
                                crevices which they inhabit with hot alum water, and sprinkle pulverized borax freely
                                wherever they are most numerous. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ventilate the beds" TEIform="index"/>Ventilate the beds
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Ventilate the beds.—It has been a valuable Shaker custom from time beyond mem-<pb n="41" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. 41 ory, to strip the beds every morning, laying the
                                clothes over the backs of chairs in such a manner that the morning air can circulate
                                under as well as over them. The windows are raised at bottom and lowered at top, and
                                things are left thus apparently untidy for an hour. Then the sisters make up the beds,
                                and put the rooms " to rights." On Friday the beds are thoroughly shaken up and left
                                unmade for nearly the whole day. Thus is health promoted.</p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Another Shaker custom would aid..." TEIform="index"/>Another Shaker custom would aid...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Another Shaker custom would aid in feeding the world. We feed thousands, annually, of
                                poor creatures, some of whom eat a pound or two—the first mouthful seeming to strike the
                                bottoms of their stomachs ; and this is the way we are enabled to do it. No Shaker takes
                                any thing on his or her plate* nor more of any thing than they wish to eat. At the close
                                of Shaker meals all plates are found to be empty, excepting the positively refuse
                                material. We save enough to feed many in this way, and ask of all: " Is not this a
                                method worth copying ? "</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>THOUGHTS FOR TO-DAY</head><div3 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A royal decree has been issued..." TEIform="index"/>A royal decree has been issued...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A royal decree has been issued that every slave escaping from Cuba to Spain,
                                        or any of her provinces, shall be declared free., and their value will be paid
                                        the owners from the public treasury. This is something on the old Jewish system
                                        of providing " cities of refuge," and is in marked contrast to the inhuman
                                        fugitive slave laws which once disgraced the statute books of civilized America.
                                        The sword of American freemen has severed the chains of slavery, but the old
                                        spirit of the driver remains a hard inheritance for the black man. Every teacher
                                        of civilization and humanity should prompt the nation to protect these
                                        uneducated people, whose labor and lives for generations have been spent in
                                        adding millions to the nation's wealth without benefit to them selves.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Chicago Inter-Ocean" TEIform="index"/>—Chicago Inter-Ocean.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If two men are united..." TEIform="index"/>If two men are united...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">If two men are united, the wants of neither are any greater, in some respects, than they
                                would be were they alone, and their strength is superior to the strength of two separate
                                men. </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A more glorious victory cannot be gained..." TEIform="index"/>A more glorious victory cannot be gained...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> A more glorious victory cannot be gained over another man than this, that when the
                                injury began on his part, the kindness should begin on ours.</p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is not what people eat..." TEIform="index"/>It is not what people eat...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> It is not what people eat but what they digest that makes them strong. It is not what
                                they gain but what they save that makes them rich. It is not what they read but what
                                they remember that makes them learned. It is not what they profess but what they
                                practice that makes them righteous. </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I am a farmer, and I recognize..." TEIform="index"/>I am a farmer, and I recognize...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> 1 am a farmer, and I recognize that my lands belong to the Lord. The corn and wheat are
                                his, the horses are his, the cattle are his. " For every beast of the forest is mine,
                                and the cattle upon a thousand hills." (Ps. 1, 10.) I am a merchant; all my goods are
                                the Lord's, and I am his. I am a banker; all my silver and gold are the Lord's. " The
                                silver is mine, and the gold is mine, said the Lord of hosts." (Haggai ii, 8.) All I
                                have is thine, and I am thine ; I am thy steward. Dost thou call for thy money 1 Here it
                                is Lord. Pardon my past neglect. In the future I will give back that which is thine. To
                                this I pledge myself in thy name, O Lord. </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We hear it asked if doctrinal zeal..." TEIform="index"/>We hear it asked if doctrinal zeal...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">We hear it asked if doctrinal zeal can, in this country, be fanned into war. I answer,
                                mix it with state matters, and see. Show me a people, whether Catholic or Protestant,
                                who persistently shut their eyes and ears to free discussions and candid investigation—
                                who see no good, no honesty, and no religion outside the picket lines of their own
                                church —who are so destitute of moral sense as to base their regard and respect for
                                their fellow man upon the doctrine he professes, rather than upon the solid substratum
                                of character he is known to possess, and I will show you people who carry perpetual war
                                in their hearts.—Clarke. </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bishop Jagger, of the Protestant Episcopal Church..." TEIform="index"/>Bishop Jagger, of the Protestant Episcopal Church...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Bishop Jagger, of the Protestant Episcopal Church, said in a recent sermon : " The true
                                corrective for wrangling controversies and dangerous extravagances of teaching is the
                                strengthening by every means, by preaching, by teaching, by prayer, by example, of a
                                living, positive faith in the Saviour. This<pb n="42" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 42 THE SHAKEE
                                MANIFESTO. draws men in toward the center; this softens their asperities of feeling ;
                                this restores the balance of their minds ; this anchors them so firmly in essentials
                                that they cannot be shipwrecked."</p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Men may think and talk as they please..." TEIform="index"/>Men may think and talk as they please...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">" Men may think and talk as they please," writes Bishop J. Weaver; "but of this lam
                                satisfied, nothing will do the church so much good as the baptism of the Holy Ghost.
                                Cold, abstract reasoning will do some good; but it will never unite divided hearts in
                                the work of the church. Jesus is the great center. As we draw nigh to him, we draw nigh
                                to each other. All are one in Christ. I know of no other way to lead people away from
                                the follies of this world except to lead them nearer to Christ. When he becomes all in
                                all to a soul, there is but little desire for the follies and amusements of this world."
                            </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The following from the Voice of Truth..." TEIform="index"/>The following from the Voice of Truth...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> The following from the Voice of Truth has the true ring: " The true reformer never stops
                                to question the opinions of the populace, but with the awakening of a new idea, he gives
                                birth to grand truths that add a stronger impetus to every reformatory movement ; no
                                suppression, no cringing or holding back for policy's sake, but an outburst of
                                fearlessly uttered words, crushing error and overthrowing all obstacles in the way to
                                freedom." </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My working sympathies go with the evangelical, orthodox ministry..." TEIform="index"/>My working sympathies go with the evangelical, orthodox ministry...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">" My working sympathies go with the evangelical, orthodox ministry. I refuse to be held
                                to consistency with any dogmatic system of theology of the past. I am with Calvin, and
                                against Calvin ; I am with Arminius, and against Arminius; I am with Episcopacy, and
                                against Episcopacy; I am with the Roman Church, and against it—my object being, not to
                                build or to defend any system of theology or government, but to bring men near to God,
                                and build them up in holiness of life.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Beecher, Henry Ward" TEIform="persName"/>—Henry Ward Beecher. </byline></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Rev. Graham Taylor, in a recent paper..." TEIform="index"/>The Rev. Graham Taylor, in a recent paper...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> The Rev. Graham Taylor, in a recent paper on the " Heresy of Life," gives expression to
                                the following sentiments. They should be matters of serious thought with us. " More
                                heresy is lived than is written or oelieved. Although less talked of and condemned, the
                                heresy of life is more culpable and disastrous than that of opinion. The Gospel has
                                suffered more from the underestimate of the one than from the overrated influence of the
                                other. * * If the church was only as orthodox in life as in faith, if it guarded as
                                jealously against heretical living as against disbelief, surely the Word would have '
                                free course, and run and be glorified.'" </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A charitable untruth, and uncharitable truth..." TEIform="index"/>A charitable untruth, and uncharitable truth...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> A charitable untruth, and uncharitable truth, and an unwise managing of truth or love,
                                are all to be carefully avoided of him that would go with a right foot in the narrow
                                way—Bishop Hall. </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Rev. Julius H. Ward, in a recent lecture..." TEIform="index"/>The Rev. Julius H. Ward, in a recent lecture...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Rev. Julius H. Ward, in a recent lecture delivered on the subject of " Christian
                                Socialism," says : " The people want teachers who shall stand behind their teachings and
                                not in front of them," A good doctrine to remember. </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What artificial light is to sunlight..." TEIform="index"/>What artificial light is to sunlight...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">"What artificial light is to sunlight that is the theory of truth to the truth which is
                                lived. The one but lights up the depths of the surrounding darkness, the other dispels
                                it."—Christian Intelligencer. </p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Elder Evans, of the Shakers..." TEIform="index"/>Elder Evans, of the Shakers...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Elder Evans, of the Shakers, attributes to the use of animal food the thirst for
                                intoxicating drinks. " I have found," he says, " by many years' experience, that
                                whenever I get a man to abstain from the use of flesh meats, much salt and other
                                condiments, he quite easily leaves alcohol, tobacco and other drugs."—Yates Co.
                                Chronicle. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="War" TEIform="index"/>WAR</head><p TEIform="p">The father of Louis Napoleon thus writes in one of his letters: " I have been as en
                            thusiastic and joyful as any one after a victory, but I confess even the sight of a field of
                            battle has not only struck me with horror, but even turned me sick ; but now that I am
                            advanced in life I cannot understand any more than I could at fifteen years, how beings who
                            call themselves reasonable, and who have so much foresight, can employ this short existence,
                            not in loving and aiding each other, and in passing through it as gently as possible, but,
                            on the contrary, in endeavoring to destroy each other, as if time did not do this with
                            sufficient rapidity. What I thought at fifteen years, I still<pb n="43" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            SHAKER MANIFESTO. 43 think ; war, which society draws upon itself, is but an organized
                            barbarism, and an inheritance of the savage state, however disguised or ornamented."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="For peace" TEIform="index"/>FOR PEACE</head><p TEIform="p">While the most popular Congregational clergyman of America has just loaned himself as a
                            chaplain to a regiment in Brooklyn we are pleased to read that " the English
                            Congregationalists take hold of the war question vigorously, and there is no doubt where
                            they stand. The London Congregational Union met on the day after the speeches of Earls
                            Beaconsfield, Salisbury, Derby, and Mr. Gladstone in Parliament. They passed a resolution,
                            with but five dissenting voices, that ' no cause has been shown by which England would be
                            justified in going to war.' This is a political question, perhaps ; although that may be
                            doubted, since Mr. Forster withdrew his celebrated amendment and the Opposition decided not
                            to ask a division. Only one or two voices were raised against this expression of opin- ion
                            by the Union, to which the Rev. J. G. Rogers replied that if the Union could not protest
                            against an unnecessary war, the sooner the Union was brokenup the better ; and Dr.
                            Waddington cried out: " Good God! am I to stand here, and when I am told on the highest
                            authority that there is no necessity for the shedding of one drop of blood, see my fellow
                            countrymen, who have no vote in the matter, dragged into war and slain, perishing1 body and
                            soul, without raising my voice against it ? If to raise such a protest is out of order, then
                            perish your order !''</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Temperance in verse" TEIform="index"/>TEMPERANCE IN VERSE</head><p TEIform="p">It is said, but on somewhat doubtful authority, that Sir Wilfred Lawson will contribute a
                            teetotal ballad to an early number of The Nineteenth Century. The water-joker of the House
                            of Commons is already known as a writer of smart epigrams, one or two specimens of which I
                            have given in this column. I snbjoin his latest jeu d'esprit, composed in answer to Lord
                            Sandon's statement that forty-six head of cattle have died in Lincolnshire from the effects
                            of drinking water: " When forty-six cattle have perished by water, To alter our system it's
                            time to begin ; Let's feed them in future on beer or on porter, On rum, or on brandy, on
                            whisky, or gin. " Like beasts let them drink without stoppage or pause, Refilling their
                            buckets again and again ; Till at last we are able to say with just cause, 'Those beasts are
                            as wise and as worthy as men.' " Then hail to the system promoted by San- don ! Henceforward
                            our life will more pleasantly glide; When our flocks and our herds shall water abandon, And
                            our cattle lie peacefully drunk by our side." —English Paper. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Unjustifiable independence" TEIform="index"/>UNJUSTIFIABLE INDEPENDENCE</head><p TEIform="p">It is one of the sequels of personal power, even in a public place, that before very long its
                            possessor comes to feel as if he were born to it, and in no way personally amenable to the
                            people. Unconsciously, almost, he comes to feel an immunity of responsibility and of action.
                            This is never good for him ; and in a republic, at least, he must be forever held re-
                            sponsible to the people who have uplifted and hold him.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Glemmer, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>Mary Glemmer</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Time will tell" TEIform="index"/>TIME WILL TELL</head><p TEIform="p">Froude, the historian, has written an article in which he holds that the present state of
                            religious opinion throughout the world is extremely critical; that theologians no longer
                            speak with authority ; that those who uphold orthodoxy cannot agree on what ground to defend
                            it; that materialism all over Europe is respectfully listened to when it affirms that the
                            claims of revelation cannot be maintained ; and that the existence of God and of a future
                            state, the origin of man, the nature of conscience and the distinction between good and
                            evil, are all open questions. He says that no serious conse-<pb n="44" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. quences, at least in England and America, are yet outwardly apparent, and that
                            the entire generation at present alive may pass away before the inward change shows itself
                            in marked external symptoms ; but that it is certain that religious opinion is moving with
                            increasing speed along a track which it will never retrace, and toward issues infinitely
                            momentous.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>The Children's Grotto</head><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sunbeam's story" TEIform="index"/>THE SUNBEAM'S STORY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Calver, Amelia J." TEIform="persName"/>AMELIA J. CALVER</byline><p TEIform="p">I am a little sunbeam, bright, A very small one too, Yet there is many a pleasant thing,
                                That I can find to do. Then listen to my narrative, Desponding ones of earth, And see if
                                there is aught so small It cannot be of worth. It was a time of storms and gloom, And
                                dreary were the days, The sun had hid behind the clouds, With all its cheering rays. And
                                hope with all had seemed to fail, The crops were spoiling fast, For damp and cold with
                                drenching rain, Had brought the mildew's blast. I plainly saw that famine sore, The
                                fruits of this would prove, And 0! how earnestly I wished These miseries to remove. I
                                said to my companions dear, " Let us together blend, And with a hope some good to do
                                Unto the earth descend." But ah! my sisters fearful were ; They said they were too
                                small, And could not penetrate the clouds Which formed so dense a wall. And e'en suppose
                                they could, what then 1 They knew not where to go, The earth so broad, would never show
                                The little they could do. But still the hope in me was strong, I started all alone ;
                                Eesolved to aid the first I met, A plant, or weed or stone. And thus be blest for doing
                                good, Though little it might be, If others failed in duty's path It would not do for me.
                                And as I went, I first beheld A tender plant bowed down, A large and heavy drop of rain
                                Had bent it to the ground. But when I came the drop rolled off, The plant then stood
                                upright; And 0 ! the sight I next beheld Enwrapt me in delight. My sisters could not
                                bear to see Me doing good alone, And when they saw me safely through They followed
                                swiftly on. And thus the clouds were swept away, The sun shone brightly forth, And I
                                beheld with pleasure sweet The smiling gladdened earth. Therefore take heart ye feeble
                                ones, Though clouds obscure the day, Bestow a smile, or pleasant word To each one by the
                                way. And thus your paths will be made bright And should the rains descend, The sunshine
                                with the falling drops In rainbow hue will blend. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div3><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker: its mission" TEIform="index"/>THE SHAKER—ITS MISSION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hastings, Marcia E." TEIform="persName"/>MARCIA E. HASTINGS</byline><p TEIform="p">The Shaker, a name that is hallowed and blest, And will be revered more and more ; Your
                                work and your mission will yet be confessed, And souls will acknowledge its power. The
                                Shaker,—and will He not "terribly shake " The earth, and the heavens as well ? With
                                earth, this is being fulfilled, no mistake, As present conditions can tell. Look forth
                                to the East, to the North, and the West, The South keep not back in the train;
                                Upheavals, convulsions,—a common unrest, Are prevalent through every domain. Eruptions,
                                and fevers, and fires and flood, Which no human hand can prevent ; Disasters and
                                tragedies, shedding of blood,"] Are doing their work in extent. A shaking of matter, and
                                trying of mind Are greatly the work of the day ; An epoch of change and of progress com-
                                bined, And Shakers are forcing their way. There 're those agitators, both female and
                                male,— Reformers,—they're Shakers indeed, Though diverse their gifts, one for right,
                                they'll prevail; God for them,;we wish them good speed.<pb n="45" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                                MANIFESTO. 45 These agents are shaking and sifting throughout, And fanning the chaff
                                from the wheat; One stone on another, when all's brought about, Is not left, as
                                falseness nor cheat. The work will go on, 'tis of God, can't be stayed, Though its
                                agents unpopular be ; And may, being human, some veerings have made; Yet truth,
                                ultimately, we'll see. Offenses may come, we'll not marvel at that The good may be
                                scourged, made more good, The dross more apparent by every attack ; And shaking, the
                                dross will exclude. Let us who have long borne the title, and claim Pre-eminent heirship
                                thereto, See to it, and never dishonor the name, By vaunting ourselves more than due. Be
                                wise as are serpents and harmless as doves, Discreet, take good care not to hurt " The
                                oil and the wine" in religion and loves; No good may we ever subvert. 'T were better a
                                millstone were hanged 'bout the neck, Than one who owns Christ we offend. The work is
                                momentous, keep human in check, And let Divine wisdom transcend. That wisdom is
                                peaceable, — being first pure,— It raiseth its subjects above The gross elements, and
                                will help them secure, A mission that worketh by love. Ah who, more than Shakers, that
                                people should be To whom will be turned a pure speech ? * May nominal Shakers of every
                                degree Work in the reform this will teach. Then we must divide between Spirit and flesh,
                                Make use of the sharp two-edged sword And pray that God's spirit may dictate and bless
                                Each sentence, and every word. Success to " The Shaker !" let all raise one prayer: "
                                Our Father, and Mother Divine: As one, bless our efforts, and help us prepare Thy Zion
                                in glory to shine." Canterbury, N. H. * See Zephaniah, 3: 9. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Book Table</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Preacher and homilitic monthly" TEIform="index"/>The Preacher and Homilitic Monthly</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sunday afternoon" TEIform="index"/>Sunday Afternoon</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bible of the ages" TEIform="index"/>The Bible of the Ages</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stebbins, G. B." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">The Preacher and Homilitio Monthly: Published by The Religious Newspaper Agency, 21
                                Barclay street, New York. Each month this collection of the best thoughts of a great
                                variety of leaders of denominations comes to our table. It is one of the best means of
                                arriving, with correct judgment, at the true status of the theological world — its
                                decline or progress. The January number seemed more replete with good things than usual.
                                The Manifesto meets at many homes where The Preacher would be a welcome addition. Sunday
                                Afternoon: This is a rival of The Atlantic, to all intents and appearances ; and since
                                the latter has chosen to pander to the tastes of the people, and lower its dignity as
                                desired by lovers of the sensational, however untruthful, the sooner it has a
                                successful, superior rival, to lead, not follow the people, the better. The Afternoon
                                seems determined to give the people better mental food, and is deserving the many
                                encomiums bestowed upon it. Send for sample copy to Merriam (inclosing 15 cents), Spring
                                field, Mass. The Bible of the Ages, by G. B. Stebbins, is a very thoughtful book ; to
                                any student of theology this would prove invaluable as an eye-opener. The grand cause of
                                deadness among theologians is, it is chosen for them by their Alma Maters, that they
                                should go it blind ; but so soon as they prefer truth to theology, then we have noble
                                heretics like Swing, Thompson and others, whom the churches would burn if they dared.
                                Get The Bible of the Ages and read, if you dare; for Colby &amp; Rich, of Boston,
                                Mass., have copies to spare — price $1.50. Can be obtained at this office. Biographical
                                Sketches of Prominent Spiritualists. The Ileligio-Philosophical Pub. House, Chicago,
                                111., has put in large octavo form the biographies of a dozen of the most prominent of
                                Spiritualistic leaders. Twenty-five cents will be pretty well spent by the individual
                                who secures a copy of this beautifully compiled book of life stories.</p></div3></div2><pb n="46" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Raise the standard" TEIform="index"/>RAISE THE STANDARD</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Martin, E. (words) and M.R.H. (music)" TEIform="persName"/>Words by E. Martin. Music M. R. H.</byline><p TEIform="p">Con Bxpressione. Canterbury, N. R. 1.O lift the standard higher up, The Virgin banner wide 2.
                            The narrow way by Christians taught, Is up the rugged heights 3.Whoever bears the standard
                            high, With purpose loyal to 4. Then fearlessly the standard raise, And let a gazing world
                            unfurl, Proclaiming life and liberty In dual Christ un of truth; Then lift the standard
                            where you've fought, To mark the way for its name, Can ev'ry principle defy, Which would a
                            Christian's behold, The cross of Christ is purity, The crown, a blessing CHORUS. CON
                            ANIMATO. to the world. age and youth, honor stain. in the soul. Yea, lift the standard
                            higher up, Let truth<pb n="47" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. in regal glory reign, Till
                            nations clasp her golden 9 0-0cup To drink the power that shall sustain.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Passing the street recently we observed great improvements in the sidewalks at the "
                                Centre " — Second Order — which will be so denominated in the future, and in other
                                respects is looking up. The North has been making reservoirs for catching and preserving
                                soft water, laying large pipes therefrom to their new washhouse and laundry. The
                                Ministry are at the Mt. The composition of our music typography is done here. Received
                                from Elder P. W. Evans, $55.00 ; also from D. C. Brainard, $20.00.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">The large " red mill," which has been considerably out of repair, has been renovated, and
                                will do a good custom business in future. Received of Philip Smith, $55.00. </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harvard, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Harvard, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">Received from E. Myrick, $25.00. </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shirley Village, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Shirley Village, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">is sending us some nice clubs of subscribers. Received from Elder John Whiteley, $21.40".
                            </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Received from O. Pease $16.00; also from H. S. Kellogg, $25.00.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Village, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Village, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p"> Received from N. A. Briggs more than two hundred subscriptions for 1879 ; also cash,
                                $66.05. This is the banner village. Received from B. H. Smith, $13.00. </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="North Union, Ohio" TEIform="index"/>N. Union, O-</head><p TEIform="p">Received of Q. W. Ingalls, $28.00. </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Union Village, Ohio" TEIform="index"/> Union Village, O-</head><p TEIform="p">Received from Chas. Clapp, $81.50. </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watervliet, Ohio" TEIform="index"/>Watervliet, Ohio.</head><p TEIform="p">Elder S. W. Ball writes us: " We have derived more good the past year from The Shaker
                                Manifesto than it has cost us in many years ! " '' According to thy faith, so be it unto
                                you," with best wishes of both its Pub. and Ed. Received, $20.00.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="South Union, Kentucky" TEIform="index"/>South. Union, Ky.</head><p TEIform="p">Vast improvements are being made here, in and about the streets of the village. Mud is
                                giving place to some perfect, expensive macadamized pavements. The entire village counts
                                up a much improved appearance, from various causes. Here presides Elder H. L. Eads, from
                                whom we received $103.00.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="White Water, Ohio" TEIform="index"/>White Water, O.</head><p TEIform="p">Received of H. B. Bear, $40.00.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hancock, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Hancock, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">Received from I. R. Lawson, $26.00; also from Elder Thomas Damon, $11.00. 47</p></div3><pb n="48" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Received from Henry Cummings, $35.00. The Shaker Societies in the South and Southwest
                                have been experiencing some unparalleled cold weather. Who has ever associated 25
                                degrees below zero at Pleasant Hill, Ky., or 24 degrees below for several successive
                                days at White Water, O. [Short, pithy, representative paragraphs for this department
                                solicited.—Ed.]</p></div3><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>DEATH</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rubush, Susan" TEIform="index"/>Susan Rubush
                                </head><p TEIform="p">At White Water, O., Dec. 28, 1878, our much-beloved sister, <persName reg="Rubush, Susan" TEIform="persName">Susan Rubush</persName>, aged 75 years. </p></div4></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Manna" TEIform="index"/>MANNA</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL FRASER</byline><p TEIform="p">Every thing connected with the emancipation of the Hebrews from servitude until their
                            settlement in Judea is to me a matter of more than mere historical interest. The conduct of
                            Pharaoh in holding on to the services of an able-bodied people, irrespective of human
                            rights, is noiv repeated by those in power. That Moses, a man of eighty years, having a
                            stammering tongue, should demand from a strong government the releasement of all his people,
                            is evidence that he was inspired. The anxious labors of himself and his brother Aaron would
                            have been a failure, had not spiritual aid in tangible manifestations been given. The man-
                            ner in which his people were hurried out of Egypt, leaving their old stuff behind, is a
                            matter for thought, and for practical application. The manna and its daily supply underlay
                            their ability to travel, and also of the physiological, moral, and social life of the
                            people; intimating, that equality in food and labor was a necessity. As a man thinks and
                            wills, so is his spirit; as a man eats and digests, so is his body. The wisdom and knowledge
                            opened up, in Jewish life and law, may well excite the attention and deep thought of the
                            most advanced minds of our day. They embody a clear outline of the commandments of God, as
                            written in the nature of things. The filling up of that outline is reserved for those who
                            have these commandments written on their hearts, whose delight it will be, to fulfill them
                            every jot. I desire it may be said of us, " these are they who keep these commandments, and
                            the Faith of Jesus also." The Jews were counselled to speak of their law on all favorable
                            occasions; well they might do so, for it involved the whole range of human action. What they
                            should eat, and what to avoid • sanitary law ; the avoidance of impure air; the proper use
                            of money ; not to lend upon usury ; moral law, and social habits; land limitation, and a
                            periodical adjustment of landed property; Sabbatical rests; and the treatment of cultivated
                            land. Also, how to treat the poor, a stranger, and a tramp! In obedience to these laws,
                            single and whole, they would be prospered, and have good success. See Josh. ch. 1. Even as
                            the manna underlaid Jewish every thing, so in this day, diet underlies every thing we do,
                            think, or feel. Therefore, the non-procreative man and woman, the virgin sons and daughters
                            of God, standing in their true order, must have a diet appropriate to their life. To build
                            our system of diet according to that of the world, and cook our food to suit worldly
                            acquired tastes, is not fitting, and is a shiftless way of trying to redeem either soul or
                            body. Our wisdom and policy will ever be identical; the clearer the lines of distinction
                            between us and the world, the better for inward and outward growth. From the wisdom and
                            profound knowledge manifested by the spiritual powers who redeemed Israel, I readily infer,
                            that the manna diet was calculated to release the people from the diseases and false tastes
                            acquired in Egypt. The nearer we come to the grains and fruits, the nearer we come to the
                            order, and benefits of a manna diet.</p></div2><!--
                     <pb id="p29"/>
                     <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p> [ads deleted] </p>
                    </div2>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>