<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ss0300" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">Shaker and Shakeress</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">10</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Society</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Mount Lebanon, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">3</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">YYYXXX</biblScope><date value="18730801" TEIform="date">August 1873</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">1-10</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="3" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="Social Gathering issue" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><pb n="1" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><!--
                    <p>THE JUNIOR ORDER OF BELIEVERS, OF MOUNT LEBANON, The Pine Grove, Canaan, Columbia County, N. Y AUGUST 19th, 1873.
                        F.W.EVANS,] One Copy, 10 Cents—Four Copies, 25 Cents—Sixteen Copies, $1.00 —One Hundred Copies, $5.00. [Editor.</p>
--><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Listening" TEIform="index"/>LISTENING</head><p TEIform="p">A good listener is a choice rarity. To listen like an Indian is an attainment — a perfection — which but few of
                            the talking AngloSaxons ever reach. Stock-still is the position of a good listener — an attitude of humble,
                            respectful attention. As a subsoiled soil will draw moisture from the atmosphere, so does a good listener, who
                            is drained of the element of self, absorb knowledge, and learn wisdom, from men, women, and children, in whom
                            the egotist would be unaware of its existence. COMMUNITY OF IDEAS. Why not have community of ideas, as well as
                            community of goods, or a republic of letters ? What have we in the realm of thought that we are certain is
                            original ? When I was young, I used to think there was much in my mental treasury that I could justly call my
                            own — the result of my own labor. But, now that I am older, I am inclined to the opinion (which is knowledge in
                            process of formation), that what I have is not my own, but ours—the result of community of thought. We hear, and
                            read, and think, and are subject to intuition and inspiration — the influx of ideas from other minds in the
                            spirit land; how then can we say, this, and this, is mine! Is it not safer to assume that all ideas, every
                            thought we possess, is not mine, but ours; and that we have nothing but what we have received ? This would leave
                            us untrammeled, and free to appropriate every truth, and all the beautiful conceptions with which we may be
                            favored to meet. My conclusion is, that in the Christ heavens self is not; that all thought is common property ;
                            and individual identity, the degree and quality of Love seeking to confer the greatest possible amount of
                            unalloyed happiness upon the greatest number.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Village, New Hampshire, August 15, 1873" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Village, N. H. August 15th, 1873</head><p TEIform="p">To our dearly-beloved Gospel Friends, assembled at the Social Gathering, Canaan, N. Y. greeting: We are again at
                            our New Hampshire home in Canterbury, having arrived here all safe, about noon on the 13th inst., having, since
                            leaving New Lebanon on the 6th, spent one day with our friends at Hancock, and four days at Enfield, Conn.
                            Common health and prosperity is found both at home and abroad, as far as we have extended our visits. We now
                            have with us, Elder John Whiteley, of the Ministry, Harvard, and Eldress Sophronia Ager, Julia Persons, and Rosa
                            Morse, of the Church, Shirley, Mass. They will remain here until the 20th, when they will visit Enfield, N. H.,
                            and we shall accompany them. Our interview with the Canaan Families, in connection with the North Family, at the
                            North House, New Lebanon, on the 3d inst., is numbered, as one among the happiest seasons of our lives. The
                            company, the associations, the occasion, and the influences, were all beautiful, and will long be remembered.
                            The rock was there smitten, and waters gushed out for our refreshment and a deeper baptism of love. We never
                            think of that meeting, but to bless the hour and the company composing the circle that ministered so effectually
                            to our comfort and strength. You. are before us to-day, as then, a host from the heavens, blessing, and being
                            blest. We again renew to you our kindest love, praying that the riches of the Gospel may be multiplied in your
                            souls; that, at this anniversary, you may enjoy a Pentecostal feast. As progression is the right of Believers,
                            so we pray that increased light may be yours, and corresponding strength given for justification in all the acts
                            of life. We want your emanations to better fit us for coming duties. May all Zion share in these influences ;
                            and, from the power of the redeeming qualities of the Gospel Institution, become a mightier power, and a greater
                            praise in the earth. We pray God to smile upon your offerings, and strengthen you to the renewing of life, to
                            the unfolding of more advanced truths, not only for the bettering of the condition of our own ranks by a higher
                            resurrection, but for the elevation of humanity as a whole.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName"/>Abraham Perkins</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Very dearly loved gospel friends" TEIform="index"/>VERY DEARLY LOVED GOSPEL FRIENDS</head><p TEIform="p">How do you all do this lovely morning ? Pleased to see you, good Elder Frederick. Let us shake the friendly hand,
                            my good Mother, Eldress Antoinette. Here, too, is Brother Daniel, Sister Anna, and little Margaret, who so
                            lately visited our people in Maine; feeling nicely, are you ? Your hearts are all right I know ; we love all our
                            dear brethren and sisters, and take them right into our hearts to bless. This is a happy meeting, and kindles
                            anew feelings of Gospel union and affection; and renews ties of friendship, which have for many years been too
                            strong to be broken. A feeling of gratitude is awakened in my heart, to my Heavenly Father and Mother, for my
                            early call to this self-denying Gospel, which brings an abundance of peace, joy, and comfort, as a reward for
                            the sacrifice that I have made, for the durable riches, the crown of life eternal. Two short years have passed,
                            since I was favored to meet with you at your social feast, in the land of Canaan, where with you I gathered
                            clusters of sweet grapes; thanks to you dear Gospel companions; they were happy moments; such social
                            interblendings fill my soul with higher, holier thoughts and aspirations than could be enjoyed in the fine city
                            halls of to-day (unless Shaker brethren and sisters were there). In spirit I often exclaim, Blessed is the
                            Shepherd and Shepherdess of this lovely flock ! and the sheep and lambs also, who obey of choice. Such are
                            indeed " the first-fruits unto God and the Lamb ;" and, when brighter days shall shine upon us in the summer
                            land, and the great jubilee of angel spirits commences with us there, we shall find this but a foreshadowing of
                            that beautiful season, when all our inspirational feelings will be aroused, and the balmy air of Heaven will
                            waft to us the realization of those inner joys and comforts we have so often anticipated here. Blessed pastime!
                            away from the turmoils of everyday life, and its toils; from the din of carriages filled with worldly-minded men
                            and women, rolling along in the streets, seeking pleasure through vain fashion; and, while they admit of every
                            foolish thing, there is within their hearts an aching restless void, never filled, never satisfied ; while the
                            true Believer, through the self-denying cross, has, at all times, a safeguard, and feels a holy calm. How holy
                            the theme, to be learning to live the angel life, living in quietness and peace, forming a heaven here below,
                            blessing and being blest. In all our efforts to live the higher life, angels minister strength and courage, to
                            help us carry out so noble a purpose. To-day we will unite with you in every good determination, and in every
                            resolve to be true disciples ; and we will take you by the hand, and move with you; final redemption is our
                            resolute strife; we will win the prize. And, should dark clouds gather, and for a time no silver lining be seen,
                            we with you will stand firm and unshaken, frequently washing our spirits in the river Jordan, even as angels dip
                            their robes.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Adams, Hester Ann" TEIform="persName"/>Hester Ann Adams, West Gloucester, Me.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dearly-beloved Elder Frederick," TEIform="index"/>Dearly-Beloved Elder Frederick,</head><p TEIform="p">In the spirit of humility, feeling our incompetence to do justice to even our own thoughts and wishes, at this
                            time, owing to the preparation necessary to be made by the writer for a journey to the two New Hampshire
                            Societies, in company with three of our sisters, to-morrow A. M. We would very briefly say: That we have great
                            interest in your Social Gatherings. Would dearly love to drop in personally — as we shall certainly strive to in
                            Spirit. Our love and sympathy will surely be there, rejoicing with you in the precious Gospel of salvation from
                            sin ; in the sweet hope that, at no great distance of time, it shall be extended in love and mercy to the needy
                            sons and daughters of this sinstricken world. Consecrating anew (in union with you), our every faculty—our all—
                            to support, build up, and extend the truth of God, as revealed to us ; loving, blessing, and, if need be,
                            forgiving each other; that God may love, bless, and forgive us. May you realize abundant blessing, as we doubt
                            not you will; and may the blessing go out, and be a power in the earth, to uplift, strengthen, and encourage the
                            poor and needy ones outside, as well as inside our Zion, is the earnest prayer of our heart of hearts. With this
                            accept the united love of the Ministry (we have nothing better to send). </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whiteley, John" TEIform="persName"/>John Whiteley</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Antichristian Theology and Antichristian Infidelity are two ends of the same stick..." TEIform="index"/>Antichristian Theology and Antichristian Infidelity are two ends of the same stick...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Antichristian Theology and Antichristian Infidelity are two ends of the same stick. Luther and Calvin founded,in
                            blood, two antagonistic systems of Theology. Jefferson and Payne founded, in blood, an Infidel Republic that
                            separated Church and State; thus ending religious persecution, and proclaiming civil and religious liberty.</p></div2><pb n="2" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Welcome to the New Lebanon ministry" TEIform="index"/>WELCOME TO THE NEW LEBANON MINISTRY</head><p TEIform="p">When the first soft flash of morning Stole o'er the eastern sky, Now we hear the gladsome voices From nature's
                            vast domain; And the stars' last gleams were fading From yon blue vault on high; They have caught the welcome
                            chorus, And echo back the strain, The earth was robed in beauty, Yet fairer than its grace, Appear'd to us the
                            dear ones Whose presence bless this place. The trees with music tremble, The sunbeam glances tell Of the
                            unclouded pleasure That reigns where angels dwell. Chorus. O, welcome! welcome to our feast I On this fair
                            hallow'd ground, From ev' ry heart responding, Sweet welcome echoes round. O. welcome! welcome we repeat, To
                            call your blessing down, Your loving presence with us, Our feast with joy shall crown.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our Mother Ann" TEIform="index"/>OUR MOTHER ANN</head><p TEIform="p">I see her by the forge fire's light, A guileless, thoughtful Quaker child ; The glowing embers burning bright,
                            Her meditations have beguiled. Sweet lessons from the Holy Writ, That on her heart impression made, Before her
                            fancy swiftly flit, In colors that will never fade. Afar she sees the falling rain On Noah's lonely struggling
                            ark; Then views the cities of the plain That would not to the waning hark. The youth that was to Egypt sold, The
                            infant hid where rushes sigh, And him whose innocence was bold, That softly answered, "Here am I." Then comes
                            the vision of that birth, Whose music seems her soul to thrill, When angel hosts sang, "Peace on earth," God's
                            glory, " and to man, good will." One, on his Father's business bent, Sat with the Doctors of the Law, To
                            question them, with mind intent On truth that they but dimly saw. In him it was a quicken'd seed, That yet would
                            yield its hundred-fold, 'T was his to fill its utmost meed, And still a higher life unfold. And when that youth
                            return'd to grow In favor with both God and man, The past to him was all aglow, With types of God's great future
                            plan. But she, whose childhood now we trace, Rose like a star above the sea, To usher in the day of grace, The
                            Heavenly Mother's majesty. Stern sat the Ages in their pride, And boasted of each noble son, For they of
                            daughters were denied, Till man's great prowess should be won, And till he proved his power to fail, In all
                            attempts to free the race, And know that he could not prevail, Till woman held her rightful place. Earth needed
                            dual heart and brain, To learn the song that Heaven sings, To echo the melodious strain, From harps that chime a
                            thousand strings. It needed hands that God could teach, To deal with priestcraft and with sin, The Temple's
                            inmost vail to reach, And there disclose the Ghoul withia. It needed one whose gentle soul Could sorrow with a
                            tender grief, Of whom the Christ could take control, And make a fountain of relief. And she was called in early
                            days, Not by loud thunders from above, But by the "still small Voice " that stays Among the elements of love.
                            Sweet in her lowly home she grew, 'Neath Heav'n's watchful angels' care, And spoke far wiser than she knew, And
                            pray'd the soul-redeeming prayer. No human heart could hers sustain, Though like a fruitful vine she clung, Or
                            lonely wept and strove in pain, While yet her wondrous life was young. When persecution's demon-band Made dark
                            the pathway that she trod, She turned her eyes to Freedom's land, For she was serving Freedom's God. Oh, had
                            that land in part received The saving truth her spirit bore, No war nor slavery would have grieved Its vast
                            domain from shore to shore. But on its soil the tree of life Was planted, and beneath its shade We have a home
                            with blessings rife, A home her faithful children made. We have her spirit with us here, And His whose holy love
                            she found; Our Heavenly Parents, blest and dear, Are with us, and our feast is crown'd.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="De Vyr, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/>Cecelia De Vyr</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beloved friends" TEIform="index"/>BELOVED FRIENDS</head><p TEIform="p">Three years have pass'd since last I met With you upon this hallow'd ground, And, while there's much that I
                            regret, My heart with gratitude abounds, That I am favor'd still to be Number'd among the good and true, Who
                            live for God and purity, And Wisdom's holy way pursue. And as I look around with joy, Upon this smiling happy
                            band, Whose time and talents they employ, With consecrated heart and hand, I miss the dear and much-loved forms,
                            Who often with us gather'd here, Their voices tuned to heavenly songs, Our souls to bless, our hearts to cheer.
                            But I would not of this complain, Or even wish it were not thus; Nor selfishly call back again Those who have
                            mingled dust to dust. And others have obey'd the call, To go to new and distant fields, Where they, by sacrifice
                            and toil, May help move on Progression's wheels. Such souls are worthy of all praise, And will be bless'd from
                            spheres above ; To God my aspirations rise, To crown them with his grace and love. And some with quiet gentle
                            mien, Whose looks bespeak a joining true, I never here before have seen, Most gladly do I meet with you. I know
                            that Mother loves and folds The tender lambs beneath her care; That Father in affection holds All those who live
                            for work and prayer. For, in this day, when sin abounds, And passion seems to rule the hour, How few do seek
                            Mount Zion's ground To learn her laws, and feel their power. All such are welcome to the feast Our loving
                            Parents have prepared ; Naught they withhold unto the least, But every one their goodness share. That " God is
                            Love " no one can doubt, Assembled in this grove to-day: That we 're encircled all about With love, it does
                            indeed portray. The ground arranged with taste, so neat, The canopy above our heads, Our ample board, full and
                            complete, By loving hands prepared and spread. The reading and the speaking too, Like " golden apples " on us
                            fall: Appropriate subjects, choice and new, And interesting to us all. The poetry and music, both In harmonious
                            cadence blend, Lifting our souls above the earth, To angel spheres we can ascend. But best of all —(delightful
                            thought) Our Gospel Parents with us meet — With love and blessing richly fraught; This fills our hearts with joy
                            replete. Receive my love, my thanks sincere, For my, blest privilege here to-day; With you I'll toil and
                            persevere, Till life's few sands shall wear away. And then on Upper Canaan's shore, The "feast of tabernacles "
                            keep, With Gospel kindred gone before, And an eternal harvest reap.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Rhoda R." TEIform="persName"/>Rhoda R. Hollister</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Again in this beautiful grove..." TEIform="index"/>Again in this beautiful grove...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Again in this beautiful grove, We have met for our annual feast, And thither the angels haye come, To bless, and
                            our joy to increase. Loved Parents our welcome shall feel; Our measure is flll'd with pure love, And thankfully
                            here we shall pledge Our spirits in union to move. We ask of the treasures you bear, To strengthen each covenant
                            made; Then, every effort for good, Shall be with a blessing repaid.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Tyson, Fannie" TEIform="persName"/>Fannie Tyson</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Presented on a card in form of a heart" TEIform="index"/>PRESENTED ON A CARD IN FORM OF A HEART</head><p TEIform="p">I'll write upon my heart the words Of chastity and love, And gather home, unto their strength, The "pure,
                            white-breasted Dove." 'T is this shall be my golden theme, To strengthen all my toil: To weaken every act of sin
                            That round Its life would coil. The fire of purity and truth Shall glow with radiance there, And stir anew the
                            life of faith To consecrated care. And, when the angel fingers touch The golden chords of love, The sweetest
                            notes within my heart Shall thrill with theirs above. Through holy efforts, thus I'll form A resting place for
                            truth, And grow into the life of God, In everlasting youth. This is my off'ring, simple, true, An emblem of a
                            heart ; And every promise traced thereon Shall strength to me impart.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Byrdsall, Charlotte" TEIform="persName"/>Charlotte Byrdsall</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Amy (12)..." TEIform="index"/>Amy. (12)</head><p TEIform="p">How brilliant is the orb of day, Continually it gives The glowing light, and heated ray, By which creation lives
                            ; How vast it is, how great its worth ! Yet some have been so wise As to compare it with the earth, And tell us
                            just its size. Eleanor. (12) — Yea, I have heard it mention'd too, But 't is so great to tell, More than a
                            million worlds like this, (If I remember well;) Some thousand added, it would take Four hundred, seventy-two, A
                            body like the sun to make: Though wondrous, it is true. Nellie. CD — 'T is very strange about the sun, Why so, I
                            cannot think ; But when I look toward it, How fast it makes me wink. It is so very dazzling bright, And yet so
                            far from me, Those who live upon the sun, I should not think could see. Amy — AVell, how that is I cannot say, I
                            have it yet to learn; But to the pleasant sunshine bright, My thoughts I often turn ; Without its rays, and
                            pleasant showers, No fruitage would appear, And this delightful home of ours, Would soon be dark and drear.
                            Eleanor — "I would be a never-ending night, And soon we all should die, For every thing that liveth Doth on the
                            sun rely; All — Then, will we not more thankful be, And love its cheering light? For health and strength it
                            daily gives, And makes our pathway bright.</p><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Three girls" TEIform="persName"/>three Girls — Canaan</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="When enraptured with the sound of poetry..." TEIform="index"/>When enraptured with the sound of poetry...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">When enraptured with the sound of poetry which breaks like silvery music upon our ear, what beauty, what
                            loftiness of thought and feeling comes to us through the unwritten musical creation of worlds on worlds,
                            pointing us to the Supreme Ruler and Law-Giver, who holds and directs them in their course, and causes them to
                            move in harmony like one great musical instrument; each key sounding its note in its proper time and place !</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., C." TEIform="persName"/>C. B.</byline></div2><pb n="3" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dearly-beloved in the Lord:" TEIform="index"/>Dearly-Beloved in the Lord:</head><p TEIform="p">Precious Brethren and Faithful Sisters, I have come for the purpose of enjoying a rich feast of heavenly union
                            with you to-day; and I stand before you as a little child, asking your blessing for myself and people. I would
                            drink with you from the fountain of inspiration which is deep and inexhaustible, that my soul may be filled with
                            the love that perisheth not, but which abideth forever. The songs of Zion, sung by the good and true, are always
                            inspiring to me. I would have a part with the children of the resurrection, those who have risen above dead
                            works, and who, by a life of self-denial, watchfulness, and prayer, have gained the victory; and, if I live as
                            they have lived, and walk as they have walked, I feel sure of reaping the same reward. Accept heartfelt thanks
                            for the welcome which you have extended to absent friends who have come to visit you in spirit to-day; and, in
                            return, we would extend love and blessing in full measure to each brother and sister. The Lord promised, by an
                            ancient Prophet, that in the latter day he would fill his house with glory, and open anew his fountains of
                            eternal truth; even so it is, and so let it be. Priceless gems shall be added unto you who are already numbered
                            as jewels in our Father and Mother's house, and blessing shall rest upon you a hundred fold. Take courage and be
                            strong, young brethren; let us fight the good fight of faith manfully, and falter not, nor grow weary of
                            well-doing. He who putteth his hand to the plow, and looketh back, is not fit for that glorious kingdom which is
                            to be our inheritance. If we lay hold on eternal life, we may claim every blessing that was ever promised to the
                            children of God, and the whole army of the Lord will be on our side ; but, if we retreat from the ranks, we
                            shall be counted as traitors and cowards — a name which any young man of honor would despise. I promise you, as
                            brother Daniel Offord (who recently visited us) said, " I will stand up like a man, and lay down my life— a
                            selfish generative life — for the cause ;" and, like you, my beloved brother, I will gain the beautiful gifts of
                            humility and child-like simplicity, which adorn every faithful follower of Christ. I give my hand as a pledge,
                            to each brother, that I will endure unto the end. I will sow to the spirit that I may reap life everlasting. I
                            am thankful for the Gospel of salvation ; and it gives me great joy to know that I have a Heavenly Mother, and
                            dear Gospel sisters, whose gentle tones of love are so wisely calculated to subdue that proud, ambitious nature,
                            so strong in man. I have heard that voice, and it has been a blessing to me. I ask your prayers, and will
                            forever remain your brother in the truth.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Vance, John B." TEIform="persName"/>John B. Vance, Alfred, Me.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beloved Elders:" TEIform="index"/>Beloved Elders:</head><p TEIform="p">I address you all unitedly as one, because I have reason to believe you have one Faith, one Lord, and one
                            Baptism; and that you are unitedly striving, according to your several gifts, to build up the cause of Truth,
                            Purity, and Holiness among your fellow-beings. And such as can truly appreciate your labors of love, and the
                            deep solicitude you feel for an increase into the higher life of all souls committed to your charge, cannot but
                            love, respect and reverence you, for your work's sake. Not as lords over God's heritage, but as examples to the
                            flock, in meekness and Christ-like humility. The world are accustomed to bow To men of ambition and pride ; But
                            who shall be reverenced now, The Gospel alone must decide ; For he that would stand in the lead In this
                            Dispensation, must know, That he is the greatest, indeed, Who is the most humble and low. That you, beloved
                            Elders, may have health and strength to perform the many arduous duties devolving upon you, and be the faithful
                            medium through whom the Divine Spirit may bring many souls to feel the blessings of this heart-cleansing,
                            sin-consuming work, and be your Epistle read and known of all men, is the sincere desire and prayer of your aged
                            brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bushnell, Richard" TEIform="persName"/>Richard Bushnell, (near 82 years of age.)</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My dear gospel friends:" TEIform="index"/>My Dear Gospel Friends :</head><p TEIform="p">I HAVE come here to-day, with the expectation of taking much comfort, and solid satisfaction, in a legitimate way
                            ; and, while desirous of receiving all the good compatible with my profession as a Believer, I also wish to
                            contribute to the comfort of all who have come to spend this day for like purposes. But I shall not attempt to
                            go beyond my depth ; for I know it is dangerous for an individual, who is not a swimmer, to go into deep water;
                            hence, I shall confine myself within my sphere, or limit. I purpose saying a few words on Friendship. Many
                            essays have been written on this good and grand theme, that have done great good in the world of mind, and still
                            the subject is far from being exhausted. Can we buy true friendship with gold, or silver, or by flattery ? Nay,
                            those are not the agencies by which we obtain so desirable a treasure. True friendship comes from mutual
                            sacrifices ; for the law of compensation is as immutable and eternal as God Himself We cannot think, feel, or
                            act justly and righteously, without its redounding to our good; neither can we do the contrary, but we feel the
                            result of law transgressed. When we sow wheat, do we not expect wheat in return ? Obviously, wheat is the
                            legitimate product. And if we sow the seed of virtue, then we shall have peace and happiness as our reward; for,
                            as surely as the day follows the night, and winter succeeds the summer, so shall we all reap what we sow. As
                            virtue cannot be bought with gold, so neither can true and lasting Friendship ! It is not a marketable commodity
                            ; and we cannot procure it, without giving an equivalent in kind. Let us not forget to mete out to others just
                            the kind of spirit that we wish to receive in return ; do good for the sake of the good, regardless of the
                            smiles or frowns of others, and we shall in nowise lose our reward. Virtuous acts are SELF-approved. God and his
                            Angels bless them, and good men and women rejoice in them. Some persons are so inherently selfish, that every
                            thing must be made subservient to their low and morbid desires, otherwise they are in a state of unrest; they
                            cannot see others in the enjoyment of any good, without envious feelings. Not so the TJNselfish soul. The
                            large-hearted individual feels a degree of satisfaction in seeing others the recipients of good, that those who
                            are sordidly selfish cannot feel. Then, with uplifted voice, my choral song this day shall be, Friendship and
                            Fraternity ! All hail the great Brotherhood and Sisterhood developed here on the broad basis of Liberty,
                            Justice, and Equality ! I was weary, and a place I sought, Where rest and friendship I could find ; Friendship
                            from hallow'd deeds outwrought, That purifies and lifts the mind Above all selfish aims and thoughts. The gilded
                            words of cant or praise May from a treacherous heart outflow ; But friendship true — a treasure rare — Is what I
                            sought to feel and know, And wealth of consecration share. Many have tried to find this prize (With which to
                            serve some selfish end) But found it not; nor could they rise Into the sphere where love divine Controls the
                            innocent and wise. If ask'd, where I have found this gem, So beautiful, so pure and rare; I answer, 'Tis with
                            ease obtain'd ; If we the cross of Christ will bear, True, lasting friendship we shall gain.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Rayson, Timothy" TEIform="persName"/>Timothy Rayson</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vision" TEIform="index"/>VISION</head><p TEIform="p">Gospel Friends: I recall, to mind many pleasant seasons enjoyed with you at our Annual Social Gathering, and have
                            always looked forward with pleasurable anticipations for the recurrence thereof. It is with regret, at the
                            present time, that I realize that my health will not admit of my attendance at a feast always fraught with
                            blessings for soul and body. Yet will I participate with you in spirit, and gather strength from the living
                            faith and goodness that shall be manifest in your midst. And here please allow me to add a brief communication
                            received on the evening of the fifth of August, from a departed sister, as real to me as though a mortal was
                            conversing with me. We had just retired from a spiritual meeting, satiated with the good things of the Spirit;
                            refreshing, soul-cheering, and invigorating were the influences that descended upon us from the angel spheres.
                            We felt the breezes of heavenly life, and were moved as leaves in the wind, or as " willows by the water courses
                            ; " there were " divers operations, but all of the same Holy Spirit." One of the sisters ministered the power,
                            under the divine influence, and said that she heard the winds of heaven moving the forests of the spirit land.
                            The meeting room was immediately filled with a heavenly power, and all felt that we were indeed blessed. The
                            same magnetism permeated the whole dwelling. Eldress Antoinette remarked after meeting: "I never realized such a
                            spiritual atmosphere as fills our house to-night; " and she continued, " Sisters, you must rest in it." After
                            retiring, I relapsed into a state of mental composure, but was not asleep, when I sensibly felt the presence,
                            and saw the spirit of Sister Miranda Barber. She addressed me thus: " I have come with a message from Mother
                            Ann," the substance of which was as follows: " Brethren and sisters, the testimony of the Gospel (with which you
                            are blest), will never be destroyed. Individuals may fail in fulfilling their call to this work, and Zion's
                            numbers be even less than now; but the faithful remnant will be more powerful for good than all the kingdoms of
                            the earth. Those who endure in the contest for the maintenance of righteousness and truth, will have a mighty
                            struggle ; tribulation and suffering of soul awaits them ; yet God will hold them as in the hollow of His hand,
                            guarded and protected ; and they will shine brighter than the stars in the firmament, and be as magnets to draw
                            truth-loving, sin-sick souls home to God. "I would say to Elder Frederick, Eldress Antoinette, and their
                            co-laborers, toil on, with renewed strength and courage, feeling that God's blessing attends your consecrated
                            labors in the cause of truth ; your unselfish devotion to the good of humanity, will yet be crowned with the
                            fullness of joy, and the fruition of hope. Those who have advanced in redemption's work in the spirit world,
                            bless and strengthen you; for you are a blessing in Zion; and we are bound to support all such. And, brethren
                            and sisters (true and faithful in duty), you are called upon to aid and sustain them ; hold up their hands when
                            weary; help them in their cares and burdens, for they are anointed of God, His chosen witnesses, vigilant
                            watchmen, standing on the walls of Mount Zion, speaking the word of the Lord, administering the testimony of
                            Christ's Second Appearing, which is the truth unto life eternal to those who receive it." Here the message
                            ended, the spirit spoke a few kindly words, and I was aroused to consciousness, and found myself among
                            terrestrial things; but not without a full impression of the vision on my mind. " It tarried " with me, and I
                            have written it, hoping it may be accepted as my offering for our precious feast; with it, asking a place in the
                            remembrance of Gospel friends.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Offord, Rhoda" TEIform="persName"/>Rhoda Offord</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gather up the fragments" TEIform="index"/>GATHER UP THE FRAGMENTS</head><p TEIform="p">We live in a day when there is almost a miraculous profusion of knowledge, pouring forth from the press, from
                            those who run to and fro, and from those who are called to instruct. Amidst all this profusion, I hear the call,
                            ringing in my spirit ears, " Gather up the fragments." The object of gathering up the fragments of bread and
                            fish, was, that they might be used on a future occasion to help to sustain life, by being incorporated into the
                            bodies of men and women. Knowledge, if not incorporated into habits of life, is to us lost. The higher
                            departments of knowledge include, first, the laws of health and nutrition. Second, morals and manners. Third,
                            the truths appertaining to the higher life — the life of God. SHAKEEE8S. 3 <pb n="4" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> These three
                            departments are so inseparably interwoven, that a person of no mean standing, in summing up and concentrating
                            his thoughts, exclaimed: " The history of a people, is but a chapter in' Physiology." In other words, the habits
                            that you form, determine your destiny. There are thousands, I may say millions, who are every day forming
                            habits, that utterly exclude the life of God from their spirits. Hence, whenever the Spirit goes forth to awaken
                            the dead, the word is Repent — throw aside your old habits, and cease to associate with those who continue to do
                            as you have done. This word was the burden of the life and testimony of the witnesses of the first and second
                            appearing of Christ. And, in the nature of things, will continue to be the word, till not one iota of any habit,
                            thought or emotion, contrary to the life of God in our spirits is found. We know from our experience, that we
                            are in the work of the second appearance of Christ, for it brings forth the same fruits as did its first
                            appearing. First, it separates from the world : " Ye are not of the world, even as I am not:" Jesus Christ.
                            Second, freedom from sin. (ib.) " Those who commit sin are of the devil." (ib.) Third, a life of purity, peace,
                            and goodness : " Blessed are the pure in heart." (ib.) Now, my young friends, in this day of profusion, " gather
                            up the fragments ;" save the crumbs. Let your souls be alive, and awake to the slightest movement of the
                            emotions of your lower natures; keep them in the light—kill evil in the germ. The farmer, when he turns up the
                            soil, kills unprofitable weeds, and, at the same time, admits the air to quicken the inert soil, and the
                            sunshine to warm into life the precious grains. So we, in harrowing up the old man and woman, admit the
                            breathings of our heavenly Parents, and the sunshine of their presence creating us anew in their own likeness.
                            It is for you to bring forth not only Pentecostal gifts, but also to destroy the works of the devil in
                            yourselves. Wisdom is profitable to direct.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="F., D." TEIform="persName"/>D. F.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Conversation" TEIform="index"/>A CONVERSATION, BETWEEN Louisa Sherman Elvah Leavenworth Catharine Allen Mary
                            Barnum, and Martha A. Burger Sarah J. Burger</head><p TEIform="p"> Catharine—Another year of our earthly pilgrimage has passed since last we met on this consecrated heaven-blest
                            spot, to partake (unitedly) of the spiritual, intellectual, and temporal fruits which are so bountifully
                            provided. The verdure which then robed the vegetable kingdom hath changed form. Earth hath slumbered long, wrapt
                            in a snowy mantle, and has again been renewed from her hidden source of wealth by active but unseen agencies.
                            Louisa — And no less change has been wrought in the spiritual elements. Our souls have oft been refreshed by
                            living water-brooks, and the bread that imparts life-everlasting; and I hope we can all feel that, through toil
                            and aspiration, we have woven new and purer robes for our spirits. Martha—I hope we can realize an increase ;
                            for what should be the object of our lives, unless by successive steps in truth, we climb the ladder which
                            extends from an earthly to a spiritual sphere ? Elvah — For this purpose we are called to the Gospel work,
                            wherein our opportunities for developing all our better faculties are very great. Bat underlying the spiritual
                            growth, and every true reform, is a law, the transgression of which, is manifest in the diseased, dwarfed, and
                            degenerate beings which people the earth. This law is Physical Health; a diseased and enfeebled body cannot be
                            the tabernacle of a sound and healthy mind. Mary — Do you think this rule universal ? We are acquainted with
                            some, of uncommon spiritual and mental culture, who often suffer from bodily infirmity; and again, we notice
                            those whose physical development is powerful, but who manifest only the inferior qualities of mind. Elvah — That
                            may be true. With many, infirmities are hereditary; and, where such strive to rise above and outgrow them by
                            righteous living, they attain strength of spirit — power of mind — which they otherwise could not, while in the
                            contrary practices which have their inevitable effects. However, the fact is not altered, that the mind, which
                            is spirit acting through the brain, is, in a greater or less degree, enfeebled by disease. Can the germ of the
                            most beautiful tree, planted in an unhealthf ul soil, expand in equal beauty and vigor, as where under
                            conditions congenial to its growth? or, can the mind, while subject to morbid matter, unfold in the same
                            perfection and spiritual energy, as when the channels of life to both are unimpaired, and all the functions of
                            mind and matter work harmoniously together, which are the only conditions of real health ? Mary — I think not.
                            Sarah — We need but glance upon the progressive dispensations of God's work with man, to see how important a
                            good physical foundation was considered by the Creator, for the development of the spiritual faculties. We trace
                            the history of the Jews, the then chosen people of God, and perceive how thoroughly they were educated by
                            tutelary divinities adapted to their conditions in every particular, relating to the laws of life while on the
                            mundane sphere. Cattiarine—That is true; and Christianity should rest upon Judaism. Jesus, in whom was exhibited
                            a mind so fine and well harmonized, united to a highly-organized physique, was the fruit of ancestry who, for
                            generations back, had very closely observed the statutes given through Moses. And it was the Jews who, in that
                            sacredly-remembered Pentecostal day, received the mighty outpouring of divine inspiration from the Christ
                            heavens that baptized them into that pure, unselfish love which they actualized in a universal brotherhood in a
                            comparatively-perfect community of temporal and spiritual blessing, with a Virgin Life basis, forming the Jewish
                            Christian Church. Louisa — The discipline to which the Israelites had so many years been subject, prepared them
                            to be the mediums of this influx of advanced truth. The Gentiles could not have received it, as is shown in
                            succeeding history. We have abundant evidence, that practical religion must have a foundation in a system of
                            physiology which gives health to body and mind. Agriculture, in its various and interesting branches, should be
                            the Christian's employment. Elvah — Our beautiful home, from which we view the woodland hills, so lovely to
                            behold, the rolling meadows, and extended gardens, all teeming with the fruits of well-cultured soil, witness to
                            the truth of your statement. And also, the durable, commodious, and well-preserved buildings ; the many
                            ornamental and fruit-bearing trees which shade our common walks ; and the surrounding orchards, so nicely
                            pruned, yielding luxuriantly; all speak praise to those whose love and consecration to God and humanity have
                            established this home, whose doors are ever open to seekers after truth. Martha — It certainly is a true
                            religion that provides so bountifully for the wants of all, knowing no distinction save goodness; and we, who
                            enjoy so blessed a heritage, should prove our gratitude by fully dedicating all the energies of our being to
                            retain the wealth, temporal and spiritual, which has already been accumulated, raising the standard of truth
                            still higher; but, to do this, we must have health. Sarah — As the subject of physiology is so importantly
                            connected with our well-being, and the accomplishment of our highest aims, would it not be well to give it more
                            thought,—discover the cause of disease, that we may avoid its effects ? First, Is its origin physical or
                            spiritual 1 Louisa —" The spirit world is a world of causes ; this, of effects." Mind is the primal cause of all
                            material existence. Our physical being is in every way subservient to the spirit that animates it; therefore the
                            origin of disease is spiritual. It is through the mind that we learn the laws of our physical being; and through
                            ignorance, and the perverted appetites of the mind, these laws are transgressed. Mary — It was an adage among
                            the Spaniards, that "a man was either a physiologist or a fool," showing that every rational person would
                            consider the rules of health to be a study of the first importance. Catharine — The practical effects of such an
                            idea, would soon dispense with the great system of doctors, and all their poisonous drugs. This once abolished,
                            and the universal acknowledgment that all sickness is the effect of sin, we should then only take the position
                            which the Jews occupied over three thousand years ago. They had no order of physicians, made no provision for
                            sickness, and consequently had very little to bear, and the few who were so unfortunate, were looked upon as in
                            disgrace, and were denied the privileges of the rest, till restoration was made through the priesthood. Elvah —
                            It is evident that, with such a standard, greater care would be taken by all, to preserve good health. We should
                            be more particular to adapt our clothing to the changing atmosphere; more willing to deny our abnormal appetites
                            of injurious food, and irregular habits ; and should never be guilty of throwing away the best portion of wheat
                            (the most precious of cereals), in which is contained every element of vegetable and animal existence. Sarah —
                            Which is the most valuable part 1 Martha—The inner and outer bran, in which is contained, brain, nerve, and
                            bone-making material. Next the bran, is gluten, the fleshforming element, and the inner substance is starch,
                            consumed in breathing. The practice of living upon bread made of superfine flour, and often adulterated with
                            carbonate of soda, and other poisons, which cannot assimilate with the blood, is one great cause of the
                            degenerate physical conditions, so prevalent. Mary — And we may add, deteriorated mental state ; and quite an
                            important question is, Does the mind, injured and weakened by a disordered state of the earthly tenement,
                            recover from this, by a separation therefrom ? Louisa — I should think not, reasoning on the ground, that the
                            origin of this derangement is mental, and that development depends upon the same laws in future as in present
                            existence. And we have reason to believe, that any habits, or desires, cultivated in this life, remain as strong
                            when the spirit is severed from its material form. Thus we see the importance of strictly observing all the laws
                            cri our being, physical, mental, moral and spiritual. " Every sin, is an act of suicide." In God alone is life.
                            Sarah — W» believe that all the spiritual gifts of the Primitive Church, will be restored to God's people in the
                            present day. Many of them we do receive, but why, if health is so necessary for the reception and enjoyment of
                            the Gospel, doesn't the gift of healing have more place among us ? Catharine — We must remember that the dawn of
                            only the second of the seven cycles of progress in the Church of the Millennium is opening upon us. W"e of the
                            Gentile Church, do not yet hold that relation to the Jewish Church in the spirit world, by which the gift of
                            healing can be administered; for as yet we are unable to receive the word, " Go and sin no more." Elvah—With
                            these conclusions, we will unitedly determine to live righteously, in full comprehension of the word. We have
                            been called before the blight of a worldly life had cast its impress on our spirits, and ere the sun of
                            advancing years had wiped away the dews of youth, to a life in which we may find celestial birth to all the
                            faculties of mind and soul; and let us improve this most precious opportunity. SHA.KEH .A-ND 4 <pb n="5" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> An—i will. Catharine — Surely the lines have fallen to us in pleasant places. We are surrounded by a sphere
                            of purity; overshadowed by the protecting wings of spirit guides; connected, socially and spiritually, with
                            those whose lives comport with Christian principles, and whose influence is a continual impetus to our upward
                            growth. In Zion there is a standard raised, by which we may know whether we are upon the rock of eternal truth,
                            and are actuated by pure motives, with this motto clearly graven on the tablets of our hearts, " Do right for
                            the sake of right." Louisa — This, I believe, is the only safe ground. While thus established, the storms of
                            adversity may gather around, and the billows of affliction roll over us, but can never remove our foothold. Mary
                            — We should bear in mind, that with all these advantages our own exertions must be combined. We are weaving the
                            web of life ; every thought and action, add threads thereto; may these be sinless and spotless, blending in the
                            soft shades of innocence and love ; for just as we are, the angels view us. Catharine — The presence of this
                            truth in our hearts will be a safeguard to our motives, and cause us to appreciate more the time measured to us
                            on earth. A deed cannot be undone; an unkind word cannot be recalled; a moment once lost, is ever lost! Eternity
                            is long; but time is precious, because the gift of a wise and merciful Creator; a season in which we may prepare
                            for the society of heavenborn souls ; an opportunity in which to sow the seeds, whose harvest shall yield to us
                            eternal joy; or, if we so unwisely choose, with vision blinded to true happiness in present existence, and to
                            our everlasting weal, we may use our earth-life as the nursery to inferior groveling desires, perverting the
                            faculties of our souls and the forces of nature ; burying the germs of divinity deeply beneath their noxious
                            soil, which will necessarily cause long years of deep sorrow, and intense struggling, before we can rise into
                            the pure, solar light of heaven. Sarah — This sad picture shall never be the reflection of our lives. We will
                            closely guard the avenues through which foreign, subtle powers would enter and possess our souls. Mary—How may
                            these inroads of the mind, be securely defended? Martha — By giving conscience the throne in our hearts,
                            yielding ready ascent to the sceptre she sways, that we may not form bad habits, especially in morals, for
                            these, like little rills, small in their beginnings, swell in their onward course, and are frequently supplied
                            by other tributaries, till that which a very little effort at first might have checked or turned into another
                            channel, becomes a power uncontrollable. Bar all—It is wise to thus reflect; and encouraging, to know that fixed
                            principles in virtue, open equally the flood-gates of the mind to divine influences, which illuminate the
                            understanding, accelerate growth in angelic life, and give birth to holier, loftier aspirations. Louisa — It is
                            evident that the spiritual quickens the mental, because, in the higher life, with Eternal Progress our
                            watchword, nothing in our lives need conflict with, or impede, the inflowing of truth. The natural is ever the
                            basis for the spiritual, and we find in the progress of the Gospel-work, that simple, unperverted science, and
                            religion, abide together in peace. The purer our lives, the closer our relation will be, and the better mediums
                            we become, to the impressions of spirits who possess the treasures of wisdom and knowledge hid in Christ. Mary —
                            Jesus and Ann Lee were the first-born among many brethren and sisters in the new and spiritual creation ; they
                            were, in the usual acceptation of the term, uneducated, yet their perceptions of divine truths were lucid ; and,
                            through the gift of revelation, they were able to penetrate the depths of human loss, and establish a system,
                            through which mankind might find deliverance and redemption therefrom. Wonderful indeed are the accomplishments
                            in the scientific world. Astronomers bring the heavens near them, and describe, with accuracy, the course of
                            tiny stars which spangle eternal space. The subtle electric fluid serves man in conveying his thoughts
                            momentarily to almost any part of the civilized world. Geologists read the age and history of the earth, from
                            the pebbles on the seashore ; and tell of her mighty upheavals and convulsions, from the silent rocks, which lay
                            imbedded in her bosom. Many other achievements, equally remarkable and usef ul, might be mentioned ; but none
                            that could begin to compare, in importance and blessing to the human race, with the revealments of heavenly
                            truth, of which the unlettered, but spirtually-taught, Jesus and Ann were mediums. Martha — It is right for us
                            to cultivate our intellectual faculties well; for the mind is the garden of the soul. But we should never permit
                            them to supplant the spiritual, which are higher, and should control our whole being. Catharine — The civilized
                            world at present holds forth great advantages, for intellectual attainments, and the acquirement of extensive
                            scientific knowledge; but (generally speaking) how destitute of the true moral and religious element is the
                            human race to-day ; and why? Because of the strong tendency to sensual indulgences. While the body is fed and
                            reared on various mixtures and compounds, pleasing to the taste (which are not only injurious, but result in
                            premature death), the mind also demands and creates a literature and theology corresponding; with which society
                            is filled, and we witness the result. Restless, pleasure-seeking (but not pleasure finding), demoralizing,
                            soul-stultifying, conditions are produced ; showing that, as the body is diseased in itself and its appetites,
                            so is the mind, of which we have been speaking. Of the fashions in dress, and other foolish and sinful customs,
                            we need say but little ; they speak for themselves. Sarah— 0 the contrast 1 I exclaim, as I compare the
                            conditions of those to whom you have just alluded, with the privileges we enjoy. While they walk the broad road
                            of se(f-indulgence and self-destruction, which leads down to the depths of misery and woe, every step of which
                            they must retrace through suffering ; we are living for eternity, treading the narrow path of self-denial, which
                            is strewn with pearls of wisdom, and gems of truth, and leads ever upward to the realms of purity and light; —
                            to the Source of immortal wealth ! Elvah — No system, nor society, affords such opportunities for spirtual
                            development as a Shaker community ; and certainly nothing is so desirable or necessary as soul culture.
                            Therefore let us consecrate our lives anew to God, and make a covenant with Him, by the willing sacrifice of all
                            that would intercept our communion with the inmates of celestial spheres. Let our aspirations reach upward, that
                            we may quaff freely from the living fountains of inspiration, which gush forth from their eternal Source of
                            truth. And to these, our loved and faithful Parents, and to all, to whom we are indebted for the blessings we
                            share, may the blossoms of our spring time, be a prophecy of fruit perfected in a life wrought in Christ. Louisa
                            — This shall be our aim. N. B. The above Conversation originated exclusively with, and was spoken (not read) by,
                            the young Sisters whose names are thereto affixed.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Indian celibates" TEIform="index"/>INDIAN CELIBATES</head><p TEIform="p">The question has often been asked," Are there any celibates among the Indians?" From the most remote period to
                            which their traditional history extends, there has been a class of prophets among the Indians. They have always
                            been held in great reverence by the tribes, and regarded as having special intercourse with the Great Spirit,
                            and as receiving gifts from Him not granted to others of the race. They are celibates, and live retired from the
                            others, in a separate lodge, in the depths of the forest, and in a great measure sway the destinies of the
                            nation. Chiefs and warriors all bow to their behests as to the voice of the Great Spirit. They are believed to
                            have great influence with all good and bad spirits ; and that they can send blessings on the heads of all those
                            for whom they invoke them; that they can give them success in hunting and fishing, prevent disease, accidents,
                            and disasters, and grant success and victory over enemies, and that they can also, if their counsels are not
                            obeyed, smite with sickness and famine, send a wind to break the fisher's nets in pieces, and send their deadly
                            influence through the air in such a way that all the wild beasts will flee from the hunting grounds, and leave
                            the hunter to return faint and unsuccessful from the chase to his starving ones at home. Some of them are
                            believed to hold intercourse with the dead, and have deposited in their wigwam, the skeleton of some wise man of
                            the tribe who has passed away, which skeleton they consult with unearthly mutterings, heard by the frightened
                            women and children outside, who speak of it in whispers one to another, and which are listened to with awe and
                            reverence by the warriors and old men of the tribe. Such an one accompanied Black Hawk, and held him in his
                            power, and urged him into his disastrous war with the whites, promising him success, which never came. Hence he
                            was ever afterward, called the " Lying Prophet." There are also prophetesses; they are celibates, and preside at
                            ths Mitawa, or Sacred Dance. It is their office to bless the worshipers, more especially those who have held out
                            longest in the dance; for such are considered as having special strength given them by the Great Spirit. The
                            prophetess places her hands on their heads, while they kneel before her, and invokes a blessing on them ; she
                            also chants a song of thanksgiving for the gift of strength which they have received from the good Spirit. They
                            believe themselves strengthened by the ministration received through her invocation, and go forth prepared to
                            fight the battle against Mujimanito the Spirit of Evil, and the whole class of lesser evil spirits ; for the
                            Indians believe there is an evil spirit for every crime, and for every disease incident to the human frame.
                            There are very many of these evil spirits. They believe the spirit of Lying is a miserable little hobgoblin,
                            with sharp, crooked talons, and beak like that of an eagle, who skulks into the wigwam, and whispers into the
                            ears of children, also of adults, and tempts them to tell lies. Theft they believe is a still more abominable
                            little imp, with cunning, sneaking face, and eyes like those of a snake, who hides himself in a corner of the
                            wigwam, and tempts foolish ones to steal; also that sickness is produced by evil spirits entering into any one,
                            and producing pain and terrible distress, which can only be cast out by invocation, and help from the good
                            spirits. These prophetesses also live in solitary wigwams, in a remote part of the forest, and are consecrated
                            to a celibate life. Traveling one day, in the region that lies north from Lake Superior, I suddenly struck upon
                            a path that led to a solitary lodge that had over the door the sign of the white dove, or pigeon, the emblem of
                            a prophetess. I entered it, and found, seated within, a very aged woman, her head white with the snows of a
                            hundred winters. She said that she had been a prophetess of the tribe for three generations, and had talked with
                            the Great Spirit ever since she was a child of seven summers. She asked me to read to her from the muzeniagun,
                            or sacred book of the pale faces. I read to her a portion from Christ's sermon on the mount, I had not proceeded
                            far, when she started up, and lifting her hands toward heaven, with a sudden burst of inspiration exclaimed: "
                            He has come again ! the White Spirit has come again! I know his voice ! 'tis the same ! he is speaking to me
                            just as he did before !" She then told me that when she was a child, about seven years old, a White Spirit came
                            down through the opening in the top of her SHAKEEE8S, 5 <pb n="6" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 6 SHAKER A.ND father's wigwam, and
                            sitting by her bed-side, in the silence of the night, had spoken to her the words I had just read. " There were
                            many wigwams around," she said, "but to mine only did the White Spirit come, and speak to me these very words.
                            'Tis he! 'Tu he! He has come again ! 'T is the voice of the White Spirit, my son !</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sproat, Granville" TEIform="persName"/>Granville Sproat, late Missionary (for many years) among the Indians</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Brethren and sisters:" TEIform="index"/>Brethren and Sisters :</head><p TEIform="p">We have met here, in our favorite Grove to-day, to complete the circle of another year; to blend the joys of the
                            past with the hopes of the future, and also our feelings of union and love; to sing our hymns of praise, and our
                            beautiful songs of thanksgiving and worship ; to strengthen the social compact that is to carry us through the
                            coming year; giving pleasure and satisfaction to each of the Families represented in this Social Gathering; and
                            to every individual who now has the privilege of casting his and her mite into the Lord's treasury, a foretaste
                            of the good hope we possess of meeting in our future home in the spirit land, where we shall realize the
                            fullness of the joya of those purified souls who have passed on before us. But how shall we prepare ourselves to
                            enjoy life in the spirit spheres ? By coming in rapport with those who have left the shores of time ; or shall
                            it be by comprehending our own spiritual nature as it upholds itself under the operations of the Gospel? I think
                            both are necessary. The one may please; but the other will not only please, but will give us a knowledge of
                            ourselves as spiritual beings. The unfoldment of our spiritual natures does not depend upon what others may
                            think they know of us, but upon what we know of ourselves. It is both pleasing and strengthening to have the
                            approbation of those with whom we toil. But, in the growth and unfoldment of the spiritual t&gt;art, is
                            found that well of living waters spoken of by the good Teacher, who said, "If I be lifted up, I will draw all
                            men unto me." I earnestly hope that all who are here will feel the power of that drawing love which bids us
                            ascend and come up to where he who was " the First-born of many brethren stands, clothed with the glory of his
                            Second Appearing, which shines forth, through the Sisterhood, with beauty and lifting power. And now the First
                            and Second Appearing, with the love and tender eare of Father and Mother, blend their drawing influences into
                            one; and, as good Shepherds, they have gathered us together, and lead us to green pastures, and by the side of
                            living waters, which are found in abundance in this our fair land of Canaan.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Greaves, John" TEIform="persName"/>John Greaves</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Discussion" TEIform="index"/>DISCUSSION</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Five young sisters of Canaan" TEIform="persName"/>FIVE YOUNG SISTERS OF CANAAN. Adelaide Sherman Ola Whitcomb
                            Maria Shultz Elmina Hull Emeline Houseman</byline><p TEIform="p">Adelaide — I have been thinking, of late, upon the subject of keep ing Christmas, or the anniversary of the birth
                            of Jesus ; — what propriety there ia in celebrating the birth of Jesus,— any more than that of many other
                            Believers in the Gospel which he preached, and who practically follow Him, and are doing so much for the
                            salvation of the race. Maria—The custom of keeping Christmas originated in the early daya of the Catholic
                            Church, and has been handed down through successive generations to the present day. Ola — Jesus was a Benefactor
                            of the race. But why not celebrate the birth-days of all the noble men and women who have toiled for humanity 1
                            Elmina — If we should do that, we should have to keep all the days of our lives. Ola — Well, you have touched
                            the right point now; that is j ust what we are called to do ; i. e., to keep every day of our lives to the honor
                            and glory of God, and in honor of all good men and women who have lived in obedience to their highest
                            convictions of truth and right. Maria — To me, Christmas is one of the most precious seasons of the year; ever
                            full of sacred ministrations of spiritual joy. It is not held by Believers, as I understand it, with particular
                            reference to the natural birth of Jesus; but, in commemoration of the first, and indeed of the second advent
                            also, of the Christ Spirit on earth. Adelaide — Very true. The mission of Mother Ann is a theme for thought and
                            contemplation, and of commemoration, as much as that of Jesus. The Gospel was preached and planted in America,
                            in the time of the Revolution ; and, without doubt, Washington, and other men at that time, were providentially
                            raised up to prepare the way for the preaching of the testimony of Believers, by establishing liberty of
                            conscience under a free government; and, how much they benefited the country! Emeline — Washington, and those to
                            whom you refer, were warriors. How could the country really be benefited by war ? Maria — No country was ever
                            made better by war! War is terrible ! God is not in it. A description of one battle fills the mind with horror;
                            and makes us wonder how the workers for good could resort to such savage measures for the attainment of their
                            laudable objects! Ola — War, in principle, is wrong." I do not think that Washington was a blood-thirsty man, —
                            like many ambitious warriors; but he determined that America should be a land of freedom ; and he saw no other
                            means by which to accomplish his purpose, than war. And, while we honor him for his undaunted courage, his noble
                            intention, and love of country, we never fail to wish, that his victories had been won by more humane means.
                            Emeline — The cause of the Eevolution, which ended in the establishment of the Eepublic, lay in the jealous
                            tyranny and oppression of the British Government. Was not that war justifiable, or a necessary evil ? Elmina —
                            It is beyond my capacity to decide whether it was,_ or was not, a necessary evil ; but as I think of the cruelty
                            and suffering it brought, I know it was an evil, even if good resulted from it. Maria — We read in history that
                            " the rulers of the ' old world' were the rich and great; and that the rod of empire was swayed by no gentle
                            hand; that the cries of the down-trodden and oppressed arose faintly through the gloom which surrounded them;
                            yet they entered the ear of the Most High, and He, in His own good time, formed a plan for the civil and
                            religious emancipation of the world." Emeline — Do you think it would have been possible for God to have carried
                            out his designs without the aid of war ? Adelaide— Certainly. If the two nations had gathered the Christlike
                            spirit of " peace on earth and good will to men," in proportion to their profession of Christianity, the work
                            would have been accomplished easily. Elmina — If we neglect to be thankful for the securities which shield and
                            protect us from the olden religious persecution, in which even children suffered martyrdom, we shall prove
                            ourselves unworthy of our privilege. Ola — Then, let us all unite in heart and hand, now in the morning of our
                            life, to consecrate ourselves anew to the Gospel work, that, as we increase in years, we may also grow in truth,
                            and in the knowledge of those things that will cause us to become substantial women of God, true and upright in
                            all things.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Higher life" TEIform="index"/>THE HIGHER LIFE</head><p TEIform="p">O mortal man, from low estate of earth ! Thou sentient being! bound, yet made so free ! Had'st them the lofty
                            thought, e'en from thy birth, That God Himself forms no small part of thee, Then wouldst thou rise from grosser
                            forms of life, And seek thy inner being to expand ; For the immortal wealth would be thy strife, To sow and reap
                            for the celestial land. The higher life is not a myth, or chimera, evolved from erratic minds, without
                            reasonable evidence of reality ; although it may seem so to those whose thoughts never ascend above gross
                            materiality; whose mental and spiritual perceptions are on a level with sensual appetites, and earthly desires;
                            who, in their daily living, actualize this ancient maxim, " Let us eat, drink, and be merry, for to-morrow we
                            die ;" realizing nothing beyond momentary pleasures, and those things surrounding the earth-sphere, tangible and
                            perceptible to the outward senses. Man is a two-fold being, having a spiritual and interior, as well as a
                            physical and exterior, existence. His finer and more etherealized nature finds but little outgrowth and expanse,
                            while he is incorporated in flesh, save under the law of progressive development. " First that which is natural,
                            afterward that which is spiritual," remarked the spiritually-enlightened Paul; clearly intimating an ascension
                            from the inferior to the superior. This was the design of the All-wise Creator from the beginning, that
                            intelligent beings should occupy a higher plane than that of mere procreation. While so large a proportion of
                            the human family set aside the claims of the higher life as mystical dreaming of what is not, a few are awakened
                            to its substantial realities ; considering it that for which every thing else was made; and that the things of
                            this world are secondary in importance, and should be subservient to the things of the Spirit, which are
                            eternal. Progressed souls of all ages demonstrated this in their lives, through self-denial of the animal
                            propensities, and an absolute recision from works of generation. Saints sacrificed their earthly forms in
                            devotion to it. Gifted Seers in beatific vision, beheld with ecstatic joy the consummation of soul travel in the
                            regeneration. Inspired bards extolled in song the state of those who had risen from earth. Prophets, by
                            revelation, declared the excellency of the way of truth and virtue, proclaiming blessing to those who walked in
                            light everlasting. For said one, " I have heard from the uttermost parts of the earth,' Glory to the righteous.'
                            " Philosophers by rigid asceticism denounced the voluptuousness of their time, as bemeaning the real man, and
                            gave to the world a moral tone, that rings out rich and full in the gradation of God's harmonious scale of
                            being; thrilling the ears of many, and touching the hearts of a few with vitalizing power. " They who elevate
                            their souls above the material world, by the practice of virtue, and the contemplation of spiritual things, are
                            enabled to pierce through the outward letter (or form), into the interior idea " (or inner life). Thus wrote
                            Philo, an eminent teacher of ethics. Man, as a mere natural creature, but meagerly exemplifies God's crowning
                            point of creation; not better than the beasts that perish. " Being made a little lower than the angels," implies
                            a diviner type of His glorious workmanship, and reveals the innate powers of immortality, though wrapt in form
                            of clay. Gross living buries the beautiful and eternal beneath the clods of earthliness, and dims the light of
                            the interior vision. Here is where humanity lies ; enveloped in matter, they revel in sensuous pleasure, and
                            plunge into the vortex of worldliness, still feeling the aching void they seek to fill. Soul-needs can never be
                            met, nor spirit-longings satisfied, in the whirl of excitement created by unsubdued passions. For, " She who
                            liveth in pleasure is <pb n="7" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> dead while she liveth," dead to the nobler, better life, the germ of
                            which is latent in every soul. " Know then tl s truth, enough for man to know, Virtue alone is happiness below,
                            The only point where human bliss stands still, And tastes the good unmingled with the ill." Observation teaches
                            us that external circumstances have somewhat to do with germinal unfoldment. A plant raised in a dark, damp
                            cellar, will be colorless, distorted, and feeble, and consequently devoid of pleasing beauty. Place the same in
                            friable soil, exposed to the genial sunshine, let it drink in the crystal dew drops and penetrating showers, and
                            all the hidden forces eombine with the elements for expansion in glory and perfection, to complete the design
                            for which it was made. So the spirit, possessed of beautiful germs, early reared in the dark, foul haunts of
                            vice, surrounded by naught but that which prompts the action of the lower nature, will bear the blight of sin
                            with but little apparent trace of redeeming goodness. Like the fabled pebble, whose adamantine nature, riveted
                            to earth, yielded not to any higher influences. So, preferring their low condition, they cannot be lifted up.
                            Such, ingrafted on the tree of heavenly life too soon, produce no spiritual fruit, and seem entirely out of
                            their element. Yet there are exceptions in those who, unfortunate in their creation, seem wholly buried in the
                            basilar region of the brain with a lowtoned mental and spiritual organism. Contrariwise on that same spirit
                            would be the action of divine precept and example ; turning the current of life, and the strength of growth, in
                            the realm of the lovely and true. The sins of the fathers and mothers are indeed visited upon the children unto
                            the third and fourth generation, in this our day. And what is the result ? Physical, mental and moral
                            degeneration and degradation. That which is lacking in the real and true, is made up in the artificial; and
                            society at large is "a sham, a mockery of life. Unmask it in the light of truth. Take from it " The lust of the
                            flesh, the lust of the eye, and the pride of life," and what is remaining ? A mere skeleton of what should be a
                            divinely-rounded form, beautiful in the proportions of goodness, and robed in the habiliments of angelic
                            loveliness. " Vanity of vanities" is human life, when it is not based on the religious principle, inherent in,
                            and God-given to, the immortal soul. Unless that is awakened and quickened, and becomes the motive power of
                            action, there can be no security for happiness here, nor permanency of hope for future bliss; nor will the
                            spirit taste the sweets of existence in its perfected sphere of reality. Jesus of Nazareth beautifully
                            exemplified the higher life ; not in the many mighty works he did, to convince the people of the supernatural ;
                            not in the physical manifestations wrought through him as a medium of spirit power; in which he stood not alone,
                            nor unequaled; many had preceded and others succeeded him. But, in the glory of self-denial, his character,
                            nobly perfected in truth, gleams with the radiance of the constellated heavens. The Christ baptism harvested him
                            from the field of nature—generation — and lifted him up to the resurrection sphere. Hence, taught of the Holy
                            Spirit, he enunciated truths that shall judge every soul with the exactness of righteousness ; and make a
                            separation between flesh and spirit, truth and error, right and wrong. For there is no amalgamation in the
                            Christ testimony; many truth-loving souls have proved it a " savor of life unto life," and rejoice in its
                            purifying action upon their spirits ; and, standing on Mount Zion, inhabitants of the eternal city of Truth,
                            holding sacred forever their vow of virginity, they are indeed the children of the resurrection, who, through
                            obedience to the Christ baptism, are becoming " as the angels in heaven." And as they are here, so shall they be
                            hereafter; rising from star to star — from glory to glory — in the progressive cycles of the circling sphere.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>Martha J. Anderson</byline></div2><div2 type="shaker-history" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Origin of Canaan upper family" TEIform="index"/>ORIGIN OF CANAAN UPPER FAMILY</head><p TEIform="p">The Canaan Upper Family commenced its existence by a gathering of eleven persons on what used to be called the
                            Patterson Farm, a little below the North Family in Mount Lebanon. The gathering of the Family took place sixty
                            years ago, in December, 1813, under the care of Dan Higley and Eunice McCarter. The year following, viz., in
                            November, 1814, the Family moved from the Patterson farm to a house called the Mill House near a grist mill
                            about half a mile west of the village of Mount Lebanon. After living in the Mill House seven years, the Family
                            moved on to the farm in Canaan (its present location), called the Peabody Place, May 9,1821, at that time the
                            Family consisted of thirteen brethren and fourteen sisters. But of the twenty-seven persons who moved into
                            Canaan at that time, only four are now living, all of whom have for many years, been members of other families,
                            namely, John Lockwood, Wm. Thrasher, Rufus Ames, and George Curtis. So that fifty-two years have passed since
                            the Upper Family was established in the land of Canaan; its future destiny who can tell ?</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sizer, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Sizer, Canaan, August 19,1873</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Procrastination" TEIform="index"/>PROCRASTINATION</head><p TEIform="p">I vividly remember that, in my early school-days, committing to memory " Thomas Jefferson's Ten Rules of Life ;"
                            one, of which I took particular note, was the following: " Never put off till tomorrow what can be done to-day."
                            Every word of this sentence is full of meaning; by the omission of the first word, the sentence is materially
                            changed, Never is a strong term ; no one ever makes use of it, without feeling its force. It is often spoken
                            with a will, and to some purpose, in making good resolutions, many of which have been forever sealed, by this
                            word of five letters. I would here resolve, to never defer till to-morrow, the tasks and duties of to-day,
                            thinking that perchance, a better time may come. Not so ; it is never too soon to " put shoulder to the wheel of
                            action." There is a certain amount of labor to be performed, on whom does it depend, and to whom can the well
                            tried pillars in Zion look for support, if not to the rising generation ? Though seemingly incapable, yet there
                            are, here and there, buds of promise to be seen in the garden of the Lord, which in course of time will bloom in
                            beauty and perfection, to adorn his Temple. Let us pause for a moment, and call to mind the self-forgetfulness
                            of our predecessors in the Gospel. There are those with us to-day who have suffered want in a temporal point of
                            view, while they have toiled, and given their strength for others; but we are in possession of every needful
                            comfort. Nay more ! spiritual food, according to the soul's travel, is meted out by Zion's faithful watchmen,
                            who stand as sentinels to guard the chosen city. They count not their lives dear, but toil, oft-times beyond
                            physical endurance, to ransom souls from a sin-polluted world. Such will not have to Wait till the morrow for
                            their reward; it is ever with them ; their lives attest the truth. One might ask, How has this intrinsic
                            goodness been attained? The returning answer is, By beginning now. Society is made little or no better off, by
                            persons who are always just beginning, and never bringing any thing to pass. Strength of mind, and force of
                            application, are essential qualifications to a well-balanced, mind. If in possession of all these important
                            traits of character, the hill of Difficulty, which Bunyan saw in dream will be reached by dint of perseverance ;
                            though we have to pass through the " slough of Despond." We will keep our eye on the light, that shines from the
                            Watch-tower, on the summit, all the way down, even to the first round of the ladder. It seems quite an
                            undertaking to climb from earth to heaven ; why not fly, as machines for the purpose are being made? and from
                            all accounts, they must closely approximate Jupiter; but I guess it will be best to wait awhile ; at least till
                            after the trial trip across the Atlantic. Procrastination would be wisdom in this case : yet if that should
                            prove a failure, there doubtless will be some other new method contrived. No telling; " for great are the
                            inventions of man." There is one thing however, that I hope will never be postponed a day later than is
                            necessary; that is our Social Gathering.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cleveland, Margaret" TEIform="persName"/>Margaret Cleveland</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gospel friends, one and all:" TEIform="index"/>Gospel Friends, One and All :</head><p TEIform="p">We have come to-day to blend our spirits with your spirits, and to sing with you the beautiful songs of joy and
                            gladness ; and we say " Good Morning" to every one ; each brother and sister has a place in our hearts' truest
                            and best affections. Would you like to know how we came to be here ? Well, we took the early train, the " train
                            of thought," as the speediest, safest, and best way to reach Mt. Lebanon in season ; and then we remembered that
                            the goodly land of Canaan lies just beyond, and we came hither. We took a '' Palace Car" — it was beautifully
                            wrought without and within—the seats were soft and easy, and we came along very comfortably. I like a " Palace
                            Car " ever so much, I think it must resemble the car of Progress, whose wheels roll so rapidly along. And while
                            we behold the beauties of nature, which are spread out before us, our minds are drawn upward, and we continue
                            our march still onward to the bright Elysian fields, viewing the wondrous works of God until we are lost in
                            admiration. The atmosphere is balmy with the sweet odor of purity and love, which is healthful and invigorating
                            to both soul and body. In looking around upon the tall forest trees, which now wave their branches over our
                            heads, we are reminded of other trees more beautiful than these; fruit-bearing trees in the vineyard of God ;
                            with righteousness and peace they are laden, the golden fruits of harvest time. On each leaf is written some
                            sweet expression of goodness, some new truth from the heavenly land, aglow with holy inspiration. Now another
                            scene presents itself to view—a table spread with food to sustain the physical part. We read of a Prophet in
                            ancient days, who was fed morning and evening by the fowls of the air, also of the children of Israel, who were
                            fed with manna in the wilderness, and perhaps, at some future time, others may read of us who are assembled here
                            to-day ; who knows but it may be so ? We frequently hear of family gatherings in the natural order, where
                            children are called home, where fathers and mothers, and brothers and sisters, re-unite around the family altar.
                            And now we are all home again in the land of our Fathers, and as we sit at the table, let us raise a shout of
                            thanksgiving that we have been spared to enjoy this rich feast with Gospel Parents, and brethren and sisters. By
                            dissolving the ties which bound us together as brothers and sisters in the old creation, or generative order, we
                            have been enabled to hear the voice which said " Come up higher, into a new, holy relation, on the platform of
                            Truth, where superior joys are found." To-day, dear young brethren and sisters, let us renew our early vows to
                            be wholly consecrated to the Lord. How often we have thought of the little ark, so neatly constructed;
                            containing those beautiful covenants by the brethren and sisters, which we hope and trust will ever remain
                            unbroken. The memory of that day, spent with you on this hallowed spot two years ago, is still sacred and sweet.
                            Let us ask, where is the ark now ? does it still rest with you on the Mountain of the Lord, where grow the lofty
                            cedars of Lebanon? We rejoice that there are so many righteous men and women — prophets and prophetesses — on
                            the earth at the present time; and we believe that there are inspired souls standing on this ground to-day who
                            are able to tell us of the coming events of the great future. God bless you every one, and may you live long in
                            this beautiful land of peace and prosperity, is the united prayer of your Gospel friends in Maine.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Gillespie, Mary A." TEIform="persName"/>Mary A. Gillespie, W. Gloucester, Me.</byline></div2><pb n="8" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beloved Elders, and brethren and sisters:" TEIform="index"/>Beloved Elders, and Brethren and Sisters :</head><p TEIform="p">It is now somewhat over twelve months since I arrived here from England, and I frankly confess that I feel the
                            importance of becoming a real Shaker; and am very thankful that I have found a people who are living pure,
                            spiritual lives, and who are denying themselves of those things which the world values the most highly. The
                            Apostle might well observe : " What fruit had ye in those things whereof ye are now ashamed ? for the end of
                            those things is death." The things of which we all ought to be ashamed, and of which the Apostle speaks, are "
                            the works of the flesh — adultery, fornication, uncleanness, lasciviousness," etc. On the other hand, he says: "
                            The fruits of the Spirit are love, joy, peace, long-suffering, gentleness, goodness, faith, meekness,
                            temperance," etc.; and these virtues, I am happy to know, are cultivated in a remarkable degree by the Shakers.
                            It is true that, to a great extent, the surroundings make the man or the woman; so that when a body of men and
                            women are gathered together, imbued with the Christ Spirit, and who are living from pure motives, and for noble
                            ends, and who keep the animal nature in subiection to the spiritual, they cannot fail to draw down heavenly
                            influences among them ; thus proving that the kingdom of God has come, and that his will is being " done on
                            earth as it is done in heaven." Brethren and Sisters, I feel that the work to which we are called, is the
                            upbuilding of Zion upon these principles and virtues, of which the Prophets had some faint foreshadowings. The
                            Apocalyptic John saw the new Jerusalem representatively; but it is our high privilege to labor for its actual
                            embodiment, first in our own hearts and lives, and then in the world around us. The religion of Christendom has
                            had a great deal to say about saving souls, but scarcely any thing about bodies. In fact, they have considered
                            the body to be of very little importance. But it should be remembered, that the object of Jesus was to establish
                            a system and order in and by which the physical bodies of its members should be supplied with all necessary
                            temporal things, as well as to afford to each one an opportunity of working out the salvation of his and her own
                            soul. Man, even in regard to his physical organization, is " fearfully and wonderfully made," so that we cannot
                            be too careful in the cultivation of our bodily as well as mental powers. Attention to the physiological laws of
                            our being is of the greatest importance, so far as our earth life is concerned ; this being the basis for the
                            superstructure of the second life. We should move in harmony with Nature's laws, and with Nature's God; that,
                            ultimately, we may attain to that high, spiritual altitude for which we originally were designed. When one looks
                            into the world, and sees what the works of the flesh have done, and are still doing, in producing and extending
                            iniquity and crime of every name and nature, how can he but exclaim, " O Lord, how long !" But there is a better
                            time coming to all. Thank Heaven, it has already come to a few. The great gulf which divides the rich from the
                            poor is now being bridged over. The cries of the oppressed and enslaved have ascended to Heaven, and the answer,
                            as of old, has been given: " I have seen the affliction of my people who are in Egypt; and now come, I will send
                            thee, that thou mayst deliver them." We see these deliverers and Saviours who have come upon Mount Zion. We also
                            see them in the political reforms which are shaking the nations from center to circumference. We see them, too,
                            in our social, sanitary, and religious reforms ; indeed, in every effort that is being made for the uplifting of
                            humanity. Let us hope that, by the influence of their agency, instead of war, we shall have peace ; instead of
                            sensuality and adultery, we shall have chastity; instead of drunkenness, sobriety; instead of slavery, true
                            liberty; and instead of discord, concord; as it is written : " They shall not hurt, nor destroy, in all my holy
                            mountain ; for the knowledge of the Lord shall cover the earth, as the waters cover the great deep." " Haste,
                            happy day; that time I long to see, When every sou of Adam shall be free ; Then shall the happy world around
                            proclaim, The pleasing wonders of Immanuela name."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Brown, David" TEIform="persName"/>David Brown</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My Elders, brethren and sisters:" TEIform="index"/>My Elders, Brethren and Sisters :</head><p TEIform="p">I am happy to meet you here to-day. My heart is fall to overflowing with gratitude to God, for the many
                            blessings, temporal and spiritual, showered upon us during the past year. I also feel grateful for the privilege
                            I now have of celebrating with you the " Harvest Home ;" a festival held in ancient times by the children of
                            Israel, after they had gathered in the fruits of the land. They then rejoiced before the Lord ; and now that our
                            harvest is gathered in, it is quite as appropriate and becoming for us to rejoice and be glad. For,
                            notwithstanding the severe drouth we had, to us the season has been one of plenty, peace, and prosperity. The
                            earth, like a good mother, has yielded a, bountiful supply of food for her children ; the result to us is a
                            large ingathering to our barns and store-houses ; and we will be thankful. There is probably not a family in the
                            land more abundantly blessed than ours with the various kinds of fruit, such as strawberries, cherries,
                            raspberries and currants. Our tables have been so bountifully supplied therewith, that they almost ceased to be
                            a luxury. Our grape vines look promising, and bid. fair for a great yield. The pear trees, many of them, are
                            heavily laden with fruit; and the apple trees will yield us a fair supply. Our kitchen garden, under the good
                            management of Brother Daniel, is doing its full share in supplying the various kinds of vegetables. Nor is the
                            dairy behind in furnishing its share. That is directly under the good management of Sister Ann, who sends to the
                            table, neatly prepared, some of the very best butter and cheese in the State of New York. And, while we have
                            thus been living so richly upon physical food, and enjoying the good things of this life, our Elders have not
                            been unmindful of the wants of the soul. Like faithful watchmen standing on the walls of Zion, they have, from
                            time to time, delivered their messages of love and inspiration ; so that our souls have been fed and
                            strengthened with spiritual and heavenly food, and we go on our way rejoicing. Brethren and Sisters, in view of
                            all these various and abundant temporal and spiritual blessings, so bountifully bestowed, let us cultivate a
                            spirit of gratitude to God, the beneficent Giver thereof, and always be willing to yield cheerful obedience to
                            the instruction in righteousness ministered to us by our kind Elders. Then shall we grow more and more in the
                            knowledge and love of God. Truth and love combined are mighty in power, and they can and will redeem the world.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leggitt, James" TEIform="persName"/>James Leggitt</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Child's offering" TEIform="index"/>A CHILD'S OFFERING</head><p TEIform="p">We read, " The foxes have holes, and the birds of the air have nests, but the Son of Man hath not where to lay
                            his head." So it was with our first Parents, who settled in the wilderness of America nearly a hundred years
                            ago. They suffered persecution, endured hardships and privations, and many sacrificed their physical lives for
                            the Gospel's sake ; and, when the wicked raged and blasphemed against the testimony, they stood firm as a rock,
                            to defend the Mother Church, which was in process of being built on earth. Thus the Gospel of Jesus Christ and
                            Mother Ann was planted in this country under adverse circumstances. It has gradually increased from that time to
                            the present, till 18 societies, or 60 communities, are now established in this " new world." The foundations of
                            truth are laid firm and strong, and those of us who are young should embrace every opportunity to cultivate the
                            truth in our own hearts. Honesty of purpose, and purity of life, shall ever be my motto. I will toil unselfishly
                            in the Gospel field, that I may merit the love, union, and blessing of my Elders, brethren, and sisters. To me
                            this is a happy season, and while meditating upon it, the following occurred to my mind : "Where are thy joys, O
                            babbling earth ? Whence does thy glory come? Hast thou the pearl of priceless worth? Art thou the pilgrim's home
                            ? In thee, does Mammon reign supreme, And seas of passion roll ? In thee, does pleasure's fickle dream Bring
                            sorrow to the soul ? When toss'd upon life's billowy sea, Thy glittering hubbies burst; Then all thy pleasures
                            quickly flee : — Such are thy joys, O earth ! So, I have turn'd from thee, and seek, Tn Zion's blessed fold, The
                            joys which do of heaven bespeak, Affording peace untold; Joys (far surpassing Ophir's gold) •Which yield eternal
                            bliss, And which adorn the youthful soul With perfect loveliness. These are the joys that I will seek ; They
                            lift the soul above. And clothe it with the spirit meek Of the celestial Dove.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Burger, Ida" TEIform="persName"/>Ida Burger, Canaan. (14.)</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Blessed gospel kindred:" TEIform="index"/>Blessed Gospel Kindred :</head><p TEIform="p">I REJOICE to meet with you, in this beautifvil Grove of fair Canaan, to-day, where the sun pours its golden rays
                            upon us, as if to make us feel cheerful while we share in this feast of heavenly things, which are pure in the
                            sight of God and his Angels. I always feel thankful to drink in, with you, this pure Gospel love which flows so
                            free from soul to soul. It is good to be here, to sit beneath the shade of these beautiful trees, where the soft
                            winds of heaven are blowing over us all. These gifts and offerings are food to my soul. I am thankful for the
                            many blessings which surround me in my good Gospel home ; and I will endeavor to so improve my condition, that I
                            may be in harmony with every gift. I cannot conceive of any thing better for a young person than to put away all
                            that is worldly, and gather that which is spiritual. My desire is to be more simple in my ways, and to be more
                            humble before God, and my brethren and sisters ; and to be fully given up to the Spirit of Truth.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Vanderbeck, Richard" TEIform="persName"/>Richard Vanderbeck</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kind Elders, brethren and sisters:" TEIform="index"/>Kind Elders, Brethren and Sisters :</head><p TEIform="p">I have a desire to contribute something toward the general good of our Social Gathering, and to cast in my mite
                            to help along the good work. I feel quite an interest in our Social Gatherings, and look eagerly forward to the
                            time when they come. This is the second time I have had the pleasure of making one of your number ; receiving
                            some good from the first, may I not hope to gather something from the present one also, that will benefit me in
                            my spiritual progress ; something that will bind me more firmly to you, and to the Gospel, into which I am
                            called. It is, indeed, a great work. 1 have faith in it, and believe that no one can find salvation from sin,
                            unless they work it out for themselves, by an honest confession thereof, and forsaking it, taking up a daily
                            cross against it, by walking in the way which is kept open by our Elders, and by all truth-loving souls. Thus
                            living to know and do the will of God, I believe I can find complete redemption. It is only a question of time.
                            I often feel that there is not enough consecration on my part; that I am not doing enough for my brethren and
                            sisters, or for the cause of the Gospel. This consecrated spirit I do most earnestly desire ; that I may labor
                            and toil, not for my self, but for SHAKER J^NJD 8 <pb n="9" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> my brethren and sisters. I feel a geat
                            desire to overcome a selfish spirit. I am thankful for the relation which I am forming, a relation that will
                            never end, and for the degree of union I have found, I am thankful for my home; my beautiful Gospel home; every
                            thing surrounding it seems dear to me; the barns, out-houses, gardens, the trees, and the flowering plants the
                            sisters have cultivated, all are dear to me. And I would be one with you, brethren and sisters, to make our home
                            beautiful in both a temporal and spiritual sense ; to make it look as much as we can like our destined home, in
                            the Spirit Land, that we sing so much about. I desire to labor with you for substantial riches ; a treasure that
                            I can realize when this life is over; a home that I can go to, and meet with kindred spirits, to live with and
                            enjoy their society. This is my hope, and for this I will labor.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Clark, George" TEIform="persName"/>George Clark</byline></div2><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Silver Lining" TEIform="index"/>THE SILVER LINING</head><p TEIform="p">1. Though dark clouds may often gather That would make our pathway drear, Angel voices sweetly utter Lo, the
                            silver lining's near, 2. Hope and faith shall e'er sustain us, While for heaven we prepare, For beyond the
                            darkest shadow Lies a silver lining there. Chorus. O the glorious silver lining, See the clouds now break away,
                            Inspiration's light is shining, Ush'ring in the heav'nly day.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beard" TEIform="index"/>THE BEARD</head><p TEIform="p">To shave, or not to shave, that is the question, whether it is nobler on the whole, to suffer the smart and pain
                            of an old, dull razor, or take up arms against that sea of troubles, and, by opposing, end them —let the beard
                            grow; and, so doing, to say we end the sore throat, the frosted cheeks, the stuffed up nose, and all the
                            multifarious ills to which our head is subject, is a consummation devoutly to be wished. So let it grow,
                            perchance to our discomfort — aye, there's the rub. For, if we let it grow, how we shall feel, when we have a
                            large and fullgrown beard, must give us pause. There's the respect that makes us go without a beard so long a
                            time ! For who would bear the searching, piercing wind, the driving sleet, the dashing hail, the pelting rain,
                            the pangs of a dull razor, and all those numerous pains, with a bare face, when he himself might their quietus
                            make, by laying aside the razor ? Who would fardels bear, to apply the brush and razor twice a week, but that
                            the fear of being out of union, and treading in bye (forbidden) paths, subdues the will, and makes us rather
                            bear those ills we have, than fly to others that we know not of. Thus union does make brethren of us all. With
                            this regard, we shave our faces clean.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="S., W." TEIform="persName"/>W. S.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beauties of nature" TEIform="index"/>THE BEAUTIES OF NATURE</head><p TEIform="p">How lovely the scene which Nature has wrought, So richly diversed o'er the land, They 're perfect and useful, and
                            with blessings fraught The works of an Almighty hand. The soft, tender grass that grows 'neath our feet, Forms
                            carpets of verdancy bright, Which gives to the earth its aspect, replete With beauty, our eyes to delight. The
                            sweet-scented flowers that grow 'mid the green, And blossom in many rich hues, Are pleasant to view ; but, like
                            all earthly things, Will flourish, then pass like the dews. The tall, stately trees, with wide-spreading boughs,
                            'Neath whose shade we love to repose, Are shelter for warblers in bright sunny hours, And homes when the days
                            gently close. The beautiful stream that glides gently by, With waters so limpid and clear, Refreshes the earth,
                            that brings forth her supply, In gladness and joy to appear. And the deep azure sky, so lovely and fair, That
                            canopies earth far above, Is emblem of purity, and ever declares, That God, its Creator, is Love. And the
                            glorious sun, that bright orb of day, The source of rich blessings to earth, In the morn's golden hours, by ray
                            after ray, To new happy thoughts it gives birth. And, while I thus think of external things, Of whose beauty I
                            never can tire, I turn to my heart to see if therein Is growth which the angels admire. To see if sweet flowers
                            are blossoming there, Well water'd by streams of pure love ; To see if the trees, with their foliage, are A home
                            for the heavenly Dove ; To see if some verdure's springing up there, Which thrives in the sunlight of truth; To
                            cultivate this, so rich and so rare, Is the labor and toil of my youth.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bowers, Lucy" TEIform="persName"/>Lucy Bowers. (14)</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My best desires" TEIform="index"/>MY BEST DESIRES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stephens, Annie" TEIform="persName"/>Annie Stephens, (11)</byline><p TEIform="p">What should be my best desires? Should they be for pleasure vain, Which would me lead from truth and good —
                            Casting on my spirit stain ? Nay! my strongest, true desires, Shall be virtuous and pure, Ever tending
                            Angel-ward, Gospel graces to secure. I desire to be increasing In the gift of holy love, And by effort without
                            ceasing Reach the heavenly spheres above. I desire to be advancing In the way of truth and light, And, by
                            casting error from me, Learn to think and act the riglit. O good spirits gather near me, Fill my mind with godly
                            things, That daily I may feel the bliss Which true goodness always brings.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pleasure" TEIform="index"/>PLEASURE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bowers, Grace" TEIform="persName"/>Grace Bowers, (10)</byline><p TEIform="p">Now the last month of summer has come, and Nature still retains her beauty. The azure sky above, the beautiful
                            verdant grass below, and the sunny air all around, still continues to make the earth a pleasant habitation,— a
                            home of pleasure and happiness. But what of winter? Jack Frost's icy fingers touch every thing beautiful on
                            earth, and cause its verdure to fade, and the pleasure that it brings also. Yet there remains a pleasure that is
                            not blown to and fro by the winds, or caused by the earth's revolution ; but that which is felt in the human
                            heart, and is caused by the knowledge of having done right. One way to make pleasure, is to watch every chance
                            to do good for others, although it might seem disagreeable to me at first, and cause me to deny myself of many
                            things which I might enjoy ;—but, by trying to please others, I gain their love, and this brings great pleasure
                            to me. Another way is, when I am tempted in any way, to do that which I know is not right, to resist it, and
                            this I will strive to do. I will also strive to be so good and respectful toward my brethren and sisters, that
                            it will be a pleasure to them to have me in their company. After the above three children had well spoken their
                            respective pieces, they, standing together, recited the following lines, by Lucy Bowers: Beloved Ministry,
                            Elders, and friends very dear, We kindly would thank you for consenting to hear Our simple expressions, and
                            heartfelt desire For knowledge, and growth in a life that is higher. So, humbly we ask you for blessing and
                            love, A treasure we value as sent from above, The wealth it contains is more precious than gold, O bless us, and
                            own us as lambs of the fold.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Two planes" TEIform="index"/>THE TWO PLANES</head><p TEIform="p">Two planes there are for mortal manOne level with the earth ; The second is the Gospel plan, Which leads to the
                            new birth. We see and choose with open eyes, If but the first we ask ; Our joy is here, the earth we prize, And
                            in her pleasures bask. But if the light of higher life Should break upon the mind, And this we love, how vain
                            the strife For peace on earth to find. We 're like the bird that's fledged for flight, Mount up we must and
                            will; For, how can we, with wing and might, Remain as nestlings still ? Nay ! God ordain'd that we should soar
                            Till truth shall all control, And we with praise forevermore, Find life that's for the soul. We shed the earthly
                            " man of sin," Put on the new and pure, And with the angels here begin That life which will endure. And then, by
                            virtue of the cross, In God we live and move, Redeem'd, arisen from our loss, Our life and home is love.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>Mary Whitcher, Canterbury</byline></div2><pb n="10" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="First founders" TEIform="index"/>"FIRST FOUNDERS."</head><p TEIform="p">What bright examples of purity and godliness were Mother and her little band who first settled in the wilderness
                            of Watervliet. These faithful disciples of Christ maintained their allegiance to their faith, in hunger and
                            thirst, in labor and fatigue, in watching and prayer. How numerous and severe were the trials of these true
                            cross-bearers, who followed Christ in the regeneration : They hated their own lives, that they might obtain life
                            eternal. How severe a life of extreme self-denial did they choose! What long-continued temptations did their
                            perseverance overcome ! What soul-trying conflicts did they sustain ! How earnest were their prayers ! With what
                            zeal and power did they aspire after higher and higher degrees of spiritual possession ! With what earnestness
                            and resolution did they wage war against sin ! And how ardent and sincere was their love to God ! The day they
                            devoted to labor, and the night to prayer and praise ; and, even in their hours of labor, their hearts were
                            lifted up to heaven in continual aspirations. With respect to all earthly possessions they were poor; but they
                            were rich in heavenly gifts and durable treasures. Outwardly, they were many times in absolute want; but
                            inwardly, they abounded in Divine consolation. They were the despised and the outcasts of the world, but Sons
                            and Daughters of God. In their own estimation, they were nothing; but, in the sight of God, they were "elect and
                            'precious." By deep humiliation, strict obedience, heartfelt charity, and persevering patience, they made
                            continual advances in spiritual life, and obtained greater and greater degrees of spiritual power. Such were the
                            First Founders of our Gospel Homes, in the New Jerusalem on earth, and such are all their faithful followers.
                            Let them be our Pattern; let us tread in their footsteps, and imitate their virtues.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt, Enfield, Conn.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bombay, India, July 23, 1873" TEIform="index"/>Bombay, India, July 23,1873</head><p TEIform="p">Elder Frederick : Dear Brother and Father :—Reaching this great city (of 600,000), in India, my heart was made
                            glad by receiving a number of letters from America, among which was one from you. Reading, I thought of the
                            poet's lines: " Ev'ry sentence, O how tender ! Every line, how full of love !" I also received a long and most
                            excellent letter from Benj. Starbuck. The Shaker papers, and the books, interested me deeply. They must do good
                            service for Zion. The " Shaker and Shakeress " are really beautiful copies, and do honor to Believers, and to
                            the principles they enunciate. Truly is not " Zion putting on her beautiful garments?" India is a great country,
                            with a marvelous people. Marvelous because here was the cradle of civilization and religion. Egypt borrowed as
                            largely from India, as did Greece from Egypt. I went up the Ganges, to Benares, from Calcutta; saw human bodies
                            floating in the river, and also saw them burning their dead. The Brahmins are very intelligent ; some of them
                            are fine English scholars. They eat no meat; and one sect among them — the Mararajohs — are celibates. They are
                            priests. There are one hundred and fifty thousand Englishmen in Bombay; and multitudes of them all through
                            India. I found a number of Spiritualists in Calcutta, and there are some in Bombay. In Calcutta, there is the
                            groundwork for Shakerism. A number were interested in my descriptions of the Shakers — some English, some
                            half-castes, and some natives. The Hindoos are certainly a superior race, or rather, combination of races. Young
                            Hindoo lads sent to English colleges usually come out with the highest honors. They excel in mathematics and
                            metapJiysics. The country along the great rivers is just adapted to rice growing. The weather is intensely hot;
                            one could hardly live here, in Bombay, were it not for the sea breezes. The streets are narrow and filthy,
                            compared to American cities. The native men of the cities wear only hip clothes ; the women do not do much
                            better. Such exposures of the persons tend to excite the animal; hence the lower classes are very licentious. In
                            fact, lust, and the love of gold, are the damning sins of the age. Oh! the curse of selfis7mess ! We sail
                            to-morrow for Egypt, through the Red sea. Expect to switch off at Alexandria, to go to Jaffa; then to Jerusalem;
                            then back to Alexandria, in Egypt, to sail for Trieste; then down the Rhine to England. I am getting anxious to
                            reach my native land, and clasp the hands of friends. I often think of you, and the dear souls in Zion. Give
                            them my love. Ask them to sing me one song to be borne by spirits to my hungry soul. In great haste — love to
                            all. Most affectionately thine,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Peebles, J. M." TEIform="persName"/>J. M. Peebles</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My saints" TEIform="index"/>"MY SAINTS."</head><p TEIform="p">Who are" my saints" of whom the Spirit speaks—"Gather my saints together, those who have made a covenant with me
                            by sacrifice" —if it be not those men and women amongst the Spiritualists who are continent; who, like J. 3f.
                            Peebles, and other prominent persons whom I could name, and for whom I often pray, as for the scattered sheep of
                            the fold (or Community) of Christ; those who have listened to, and. heard, the voice of the Christ Spirit,
                            calling upon them to come up higher— into the Resurrection—henceforth to live and walk in newness of life, as
                            pure spiritual celibates f I have confidence in J. M. Peebles, that, although away from the external centres of
                            protection, on a voyage round the world, and subjected to temptations that but few withstand, he is not only
                            true to his marital vows, but he is also obedient to the voice of conscience, and to the " covenant" he has made
                            with God and his people, to live as Jesus lived—as the Shakers live—a Christian celibate. These continent
                            Spiritualists, like the first Founders of our Order, are living to God in Babylon; testing their powers, and
                            growing strong " in the hour of temptation." They are being purified in affliction, and through tribulation. Not
                            only are married persons living as brother and sister; but many are banishing the use of stimulating drinks,
                            tobacco, and unphysiological food, as far as is possible in an order where all things are adulterated; from the
                            marriage relation to the milk upon which their offspring are fed, and by which they often die ; from bread— the
                            " staff of life"—to the mineral drugs and medicines—the substitutes of vitality—which cut off its already "
                            brittle thread." These saints will be gathered together into Shaker Communities. And, if there was not a Shaker
                            upon earth, the same laws of ascension and spiritual progress that have hitherto raised up peaceful Shaker
                            Celibate Communities, would produce them spontaneously, as fire is often produced without tinder, flint, or
                            match. Peace principles ; Woman's Rights, (including the right to live a virgin life); Physiological truth, that
                            shall cure all manner of diseases, j ust as did Jesus; Labor, that is man's rightful inheritance ; " using this
                            world as not abusing it; are the atonements which will " take away the sins of the world ;" and, although " they
                            be as scarlet, they shall become white as snow; and though they be as crimson, they shall become like
                            well-washed wool." The Jewish Chronicle thinks that it was partially owing to their nice discrimination in the
                            use of food that the Israelites reached at so early an age a cultured and civilized condition. It observes,
                            concerning the modern laxity in this matter: " We are aware that in certain circles amongst our community, it is
                            the fashion to condemn as antiquated, and therefore worthless, that delicacy as to what we shall eat enjoined by
                            the Levitical law; but, until a sneer arrive at the dignity of an argument, we shall continue to advocate close
                            adherence to the dietary laws laid down by the Mosaic code, and to regard as a declension in true civilization
                            any divergence to the cosmopolitan opinions of our so-called social reformers."</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ask, and ye shall receive" TEIform="index"/>"ASK, AND YE SHALL RECEIVE."</head><p TEIform="p">Very good. But how shall we ask ? Earth, and Heaven, are literally deluged with words. Heaven, especially, is
                            fearfully bored with words — words — words — everlastingly teasing the Lord for blessings — Blessings, he can
                            never bestow, without violating Heaven's organic law. And he won't do that. Blessings, as well as cursings, are
                            the result of conditions. " Whatsoever a man soweth, that also shall lie reap." And so of women. " Blessed are
                            the pure in heart." Already blessed — Blessed all the time. And their blessing crops out in their lives. " In
                            blessing, ye shall be blessed." No better way to ask a blessing than to bless humanity, in general — and every
                            body in particular — by doing all the good you can. By being examples of righteousness, worthy of all imitation. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="P., O." TEIform="persName"/>O. P.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Little things of life" TEIform="index"/>Little Things of Life</head><p TEIform="p">It Is the babbling spring that flows gently, the little rivulet which runs along day and night by the farm house,
                            that is useful, rather than the swollen flood, or the roaring cataract. Niagara excites our wonder, and we stand
                            amazed at the power and greatness of nature there, as she pours it from her hollow hand. But one Niagara is
                            enough for a continent, or the world—while the same world requires thousands and tens of thousands of silver
                            fountains and gentle flowing rivulets, that water every farm and meadow, and every garden, and that shall flow
                            night and day, with their gentle, quiet beauty. So with the acts of our lives. It is not by great deeds, like
                            those of martyrs, that good is done; it is by the daily and quiet virtue of life—the kind temper, the meek
                            forbearance, the spirit of forgiveness.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="When will the end come?" TEIform="index"/>WHEN WILL THE END COME?</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Holmes, O. W." TEIform="persName"/>O. W. HOLMES</byline><p TEIform="p">"When legislators keep the law, When banks dispense with bolts and locks, When berries, whortle, rasp, and straw,
                            Grow bigger downwards through the box— When he that selleth house or land, Shows leaks in roofs or flaw in
                            right, When harberdashers choose the stand Whose window has the broadest light — When preachers tell us what
                            they think, And party leaders all they mean— When what we pay for, that we drink, From real grape and coffee
                            bean— When lawyers take what they would give, And doctors give what they would take— When city fathers eat to
                            live, Save when they fast for conscience sake— When one that has a horse on sale Shall bring its merit to the
                            proof, Without a lie for every nail That holds the iron on the hoof— When, in the usual place for rips, Our
                            gloves are stitch'd with special care, And guarded well the whalebone tips, Where first umbrellas need repair—
                            When Cuba's weeds have quite forgot The power of suction to resist, And claret bottles harbor not Such dimples
                            as would hold your listWhen publishers no longer steal, And pay for what they stole before — When the first
                            locomotive wheel Rolls through the Hoosac tunnel's bore :— Till then, let Cumming blaze away, And Miller's
                            saints blow up the globe ; But when you see that blessed day, Then order your ascension robe.</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>