<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0708" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shakers, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">7</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">8</biblScope><date value="18770801" TEIform="date">August 1877</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">57-64</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="7" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="57" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="8" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">THE SHAKIER. OFFICIAL MONTHLY.—PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES. " S° grfflrtl the kingdom of
                        0od!" jpb testimony of eternal tmtth. Yol. VI. G. A. LOMAS, Editor, ) \ Shakers, N. Y. ) AUGUST,
                        1877. ( N. A. BRIGGS, Publishes, ) \ Shaker Village, N. H. \ No. 8.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watchfulness" TEIform="index"/>Watchfulness</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL ORCUTT</byline><p TEIform="p">" Watch thou hi all things." Without constant watchfulness it isL impossible to progress
                            heavenward. To \ be ever vigilant is one half, at least, in i obtaining victory. If
                            continually on the watch-tower when temptations assail, we give the alarm to the powers of
                            the soul, and they unite in our defence. Would we see and know ourselves as we are seen and
                            known of God ? Then we must keep a watchful eve upon our hearts, our appetites and passions.
                            A more needful injunction there cannot be than this: "Keep thy heart with all diligence, for
                            out of it are the issues of life." The heart is the seat of principles. As is the heart, so
                            will the tenor of the life be ; as is the fountain, so will be the stream ; as is the tree,
                            so wiil be the fruit. "The heart (by nature) is deceitful above all things;" and without
                            this constant self-inspection, we cannot obtain self-control, nor power over sin. Sinful
                            pleasure possesses a peculiar faculty to allure, deceive and destroy. To all its votaries it
                            promiseth pleasure and perfect security; but "the wages of sin is death ! " As sin is
                            deceptive in its promises and fatal in its results, how important that all should heed the
                            counsel of the wise and pure, also the injunction: " Watch and pray that ye enter not into
                            temptation," which would save from many wrong steps and much misery in after life. The
                            inexperienced of all ages, for the lack of understanding, frequently act without considering
                            the consequences of their actions. They know not how to judge correctly at all times, of
                            objects that present themselves, but are in danger of receiving evil for good and good for
                            evil. Hence the need of the enlightening influences of the Holy Spirit to enable them to
                            discern that which is excellent, to "prove all things, and hold fast that which is good."
                            This want of understanding displays itself in the wrong choice of companions; while the
                            person of plain appearance, who may possess much wisdom and goodness, is rejected, the
                            accomplished deceiver, with his showy exterior, is accepted as a confidential friend.
                            Appearances are often deceitful. " Beware of the iseeming friend,' who comes to you in
                            sheep's clothing, but inwardly is a ravening wolf." Satan is never asleep nor idle. It is
                            his business to "sow tares." He selects his opportunity when some " sheep," weak in the
                            faith, ceases watching. Self-confident, they suspect no danger. But the wolf comes, not in
                            hi^ true character, not as a wolf, but as a sheep ! The sheep are deceived. He mingles with
                            them ; talks gospel truths ; he insinuates and flatters, until he gains their confidence ;
                            he marks his time. First one, then another, now another, fall victims of this arch deceiver.
                            Wolves are now abroad in sheep's clothing. Watch ! "By their fruits shall we know them."
                            Enfield, Conn.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian and philosopher" TEIform="index"/>The Christian and Philosopher</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Andrews, Watson" TEIform="persName"/>WATSON ANDREWS</byline><p TEIform="p">Philosopher. Christian, does your religion satisfy your1 Christian. It does. Does your
                            philosophy satisfy you ? P. It does not. C. Why does it not? P. Because. I find myself the
                            victim of numerous unwholesome desires, clamoring for gratification ; and because of a vague
                            uncertainty which I feel with regard to the future. You say your religion satisfies you ; by
                            what, I pray you, does it do it? C. By inspiring me with a feeling of certainty with regard
                            to the future. P. What, may I ask, has produced that feeling? C. The fruition of hope. P.
                            What was that hope ? C. That I might be rid of unwholesome desires. P. And you have become
                            rid of them ? C. I have. P. By what means? C. By the power of God and the force of habit. P.
                            How did you establish this habit? C. By the help of others who had gained the victory before
                            me. P. And they ? C. By the aid of others before them. P. But there was some one who
                            established this system ? C. Yea ; the genius of Christianity — the Christ. P. Then the
                            genius set the example of self-denial. C. To the fullest extent. P. And is the force of
                            habit, as practiced by this wonderful genius equal to the subjugation of human passions?—the
                            silencing of illicit desires and does it bring that peace and rest 1 which Christians so
                            much talk about? ] C. A thousand living witnesses make answer: Yea, verily. 1 P. Then will I
                            become a Christian. North Union, O.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Demands of the new cycle" TEIform="index"/>Demands of the New Cycle</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p">The Shaker seems to strike against ' coarse living and materialization, or other sensational
                            theories," some of which, to me, underlie the whole gosDel svstem.* How can any be saved
                            from generative lusts unless they begin where Satan Degan to create those lusts—at the mouth
                            and stomach? "If any man among you seem to be religious, and Dridleth not his tongue, know
                            that man's religion is vain." So said James. I say, if any, in this day, seem to be
                            re.igious and claim to be progressive, yet continue unchanged in their physiologic and
                            hygienic habits, common to antichristian sects, their seeming and claims will prove
                            illusory. We want—must have—as solid a foundation for the second cycle as we had for the
                            first. " If the trump give an uncertain sound, who shall prepare him, or herself, for the
                            battle ?" And if the second thunder of the season sound not so long, loud and clear,
                            reverberating through the heavens of the first cycle, as did the ¦first, through the old
                            Babylonian heavens, who, then, I ask, will know how to prepare for the battles of Shaking,
                            in the Judgment, that must begin at the House of God — the Zion of God — among the holy
                            people of God ? " Hate the flesh, with all its affections and lusts," was the testimony of
                            Jesus, through Mother Ann and her compeers, the founders of the first gospel degree. They
                            fought directly, with neither small nor great evils ; only with the King—Generation. They
                            preached the resurrection of the human soul, from sexual relations and processes ending in
                            reproduction.' And this they did in * We cannot admit that The Shaker, at any time has even
                            apparently taken ground of denial to the truths of coarse living, materialization, etc., but
                            do admit of an abhorrence to mere " sensational theories," etc. Personally, we are very
                            favorable to coarse diet; and strong in the belief of the truths of materialization. Our
                            Brother Fletcher, in July No., did not take exceptions to these truths, but properly
                            recommended that old truths receive no neglect, to "expand too fast" into other things that
                            all cannot yet accept to be as foundational, as does our gooc Bro. Elder F. W. Evans. Let us
                            be liberal, brethren.—Ed. the power and demonstration of the Holy Spirit. They earned the
                            enmity of the Dragon—winged serpent—intellectual, spiritual and religious people— iving in
                            generative lusts. God was with them, and the whole world, lying in that wicked one—lust— was
                            against them. A victory is gained, but that victory will be turned into a Sheridan rout,
                            uness the lusts of the stomach, in Egyptian eating and drinking, are as effectually
                            conquered by as practical, welldefined a course, as was the cross against generation and all
                            generative iusts. Are we, as a people, ready for the question : What is the second thunder
                        ?</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian culture, no. 5" TEIform="index"/>Christian Culture. No. 5</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName"/>WM. H. BUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p">LITERATURE. Literature, like those who originate it, changes from age to age. We have, it is
                            true, what are called classical works, which, by reason of the unusual talent displayed by
                            their authors, both in thought and style, have been transmitted, unchanged, from generation
                            to generation, through many centuries. Yet these standard works, cherished, as they have
                            been and still are, by persons of taste and culture, have in themselves, both in subject and
                            style, a certain obsoleteness that no modern writer would think of imitating. Homer, Virgil
                            and Dante possess a peculiar charm for the classical scholar, even in their original dress,
                            but for most persons they must be reclothed by the modern poet. Milton and Shakspeare, with
                            all their beauty and solemnity, and the profound knowledge of human nature displayed, have
                            comparative few readers. New times require new thoughts and new modes of expressing them ;
                            and, it is not too much to say, that, by the better classes in these newest times, thoughts
                            of a more elevated character are demanded than were prevalent in the olden times. So will it
                            be in the coming years. The best literature of the present age will create a demand for
                            still better in the future. But the great mass of the literature of ages either passes
                            entirely away, or else is laid up, portions of it, like mummies, in receptacles, to gratify
                            the curiosity hunter, or to aid the historian and others who are desirous of presenting old
                            ideas I arrayed in modern garb to those wIiq <pb n="58" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 58 THE SHAKER. are
                            interested in viewing the past under its numerous aspects. Truth never changes in its
                            science, nor is lost to human view, in whatever dress it may appear, from age to age. It has
                            been supposed that a great loss was sustained in the burning of the Alexandrian library by
                            the Mohammedan Caliph Omar. Whatever particular facts may have been accumulated there, it is
                            certain that truth itself has never been diminished. It shows itself under myriad forms.
                            Mankind were making history long before the first historian undertook to record its facts,
                            but the main, guiding principles have always existed, though the historian's pages have
                            often exhibited falsehood and fable, as well as clearly ascertained truths. Much has been
                            written respecting the "lost arts;" as though something of inestimable value had
                            irretrievably slipped away from human sight and use. There is not the least necessity, nor
                            any propriety, in ignoring the past nor in deploring it. The All-Providential Hand can be
                            perceived guiding and sustaining all, from their earliest moments down to the present.
                            Theologians have adduced as an argument in favor of the divine origin of the whole Bible,
                            the fact that it has been carefully transmitted through so many centuries, down to the
                            present time. The same argument would apply as well to all other books that have come down
                            to us from remote ages. The fact is, errors and mistakes are transmitted side by side with
                            truths in all books. But is this a cause of complaint? As well complain because human beings
                            are imperfect and have been liable to error all along through the past, and still commit
                            them. As well censure the infinite Creator because he has not made the earth in all its
                            parts equally beautiful; because he has left so much to be done by man against the
                            inclemency of the seasons, against wild beasts, wild woods and deserts ; because, in a word,
                            he did not make him perfect at once, and thus save him the disagreeable necessity of doing
                            something for himself! But the Christian prefers to act for himself. The idea of growth,
                            culture, refinement, and ultimate perfection, is like sweetest melody to his soul. Labor is
                            pleasant to him, because of its immediate and prospective results ; but more especially when
                            the higher inspirations convey the divine life through every avenue of the physical, mental
                            and moral man, imparting the vigor necessary to endure and accomplish whatever tasks are
                            necessary for his highest welfare. Literature, of whatever kind, is merely representative.
                            The literature of the physical sciences is not those sciences themselves, which are to be
                            acquired actually and thoroughly only by a direct application to things. But in this brief
                            life it is impossible for the most gifted even to acquire them all, hence the principal
                            resource left is to substitute the literature of the things for the things :hemselves, in
                            order to gain some in'ormation respecting what lies before us in the varied fields of
                            knowledge. Books, then, seem to be indispensable n human culture. To reap the most useful
                            harvest from the various fields of literature, careful labits must be formed. What is really
                            valuable abounds everywhere, and so does that which is pernicious. The discriminating
                            judgment is needed that discerns and appropriates the useful and rejects the useless. Many
                            things are to )e discarded at once ; others to be examined with care, and, if found to be
                            valuable, enjoyed, even though a critical judgment may object to this thought or that mode
                            of expression, and subject the whole to a careful analysis. There is an absolute necessity
                            of forming such labits ; but when they are once formed, it is not an irksome task to subject
                            whatever is read to the crucible of a keen and searching judgment. This will not essen the
                            enjoyment one may derive rom that which is wholly or partly excellent in itself. Culture is
                            the most desirable thing for every human being ; and only the indolent and self-indulgent
                            will refuse to subject themselves to whatever is necessary to gain it. The selfmdulgent may
                            have their transient de.ight, subject to a thousand interruptions and drawbacks, but only
                            rightlyx&gt;rmed habits, acquired by ceaseless attention to even the minutest things
                            that make the perfect character, are attended with constantly increasing enjoyment.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Memorandum, no. 3" TEIform="index"/>Memorandum Number 3</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL FRASER</byline><p TEIform="p">The people of the English colonies of North America had their sentiment of justice outraged
                            by the British government. Hence they were led to cooperate, and they founded a republic,
                            freeing themselves from the expenses of regal pomp and aristocratic extravagance ; their
                            object being, security of life and property at the least possible cost. This republic like
                            co-operative societies, confines itself to secular affairs. The adage, " Corporations have
                            no souls," is true ; therefore, they have no religion. The moment a co-operative society
                            makes any religious distinction between its members, it ceases to be just. The moment a
                            republic discriminates between beliefs, it becomes unjust also, and consequently destroys
                            itself; for its organic law (as with co-operative societies,) is "Justice to all." Public
                            sentiment and intelligence created the republic, as they do co-operative societies. But, as
                            a whole, the sentiments and intelligence of a people are in advance of their individual
                            integrity. Men and women, honest in thought, purpose and deed, are rare. This lack of
                            integrity is the cause of the non-prevalence of co-operative efforts. Even persons of
                            education, culture, and of high social position, are found plunging their hands into the
                            public moneys. Republics and co-operative societies are the advanced points of human
                            progress ; but the truth of humanity is not Drepared to sustain them. The perpetuity of this
                            republic is in jeopardy every day, because of the almost universal desire to acquire
                            property without individual, honest labor. In plain language, almost everybody desires to
                            steal. This state of things has been so ong in existence that conventional and common law
                            throw their sanction over doing wrong, as evidenced in monopoizing the necessaries of life,
                            etc. As stated, republics and co-operative societies are the advanced points of hunan
                            progress; but they are not the most advanced. Communities having goods in common are beyond
                            them, as the heavens are from the earth. The creative organic law of the heavens is, ' The
                            love of the neighbor at the exDense of self.* Communities on earth, laving, and manifesting
                            the same law, are of the heavens also ; provided, aninal emotions have no place in their
                            procedure. But where animal emotions are recognized, there can be, (organicaly speaking,) no
                            community. There may be a joint stock company, one of the dividends of which is systematic,
                            animal gratification. However much such gratifications may be regulated, no matter, organic
                            law remains intact. The hells are also regulated. The order of government in communities,
                            the organic law of which is of the heavens, must necessarily be severe on the lower nature
                            of man. "The woman clothed with the sun, the moon under her feet, and on her head a crown of
                            twelve stars ; brought forth a man-child who was to rule all nations with a rod of iron."
                            Why? Because the animal in man, as manifested in the nations of the earth, is diametrically
                            opposed to the organic law of heaven ; the propensities, and the life thereof, can have no
                            place there—they are of the kingdom of the Beast. "The nations of the earth should wail
                            because of him,"—the manchild. "A great mourning ; every family apart, and their wives
                            apart." The government of heaven in its lowest degree, is as fire to the natural man ; hence
                            the necessity of a baptism of the Holy Spirit to endure it. Modify the heavens to suit the
                            natural man and woman, and they will be as ill at ease as before. Therefore, let the
                            testimony of the resurrection out of our animal selthoods roll. Proclaim martial lavj
                            against the life of the propensities^ and all the emotions and proclivities thereof. That is
                            the word. Do so, and the heavens are with you. Modify the heavens to suit the procreative
                            man and woman, and neither the heavens nor the earth will be with you. To our lower natures,
                            the government of heaven is as an iron rod—a twoedged sword to kill; but to all who stand in
                            victory over the beast within themselves, it is, and ever will be, as ' the music of the
                            spheres. Here is truth in its most condensed form " Nearly all churches are composed of work
                            ers and grumblers. Grumblers scarcely ever work, and workers scarcely ever grumble."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Affirmative goodness" TEIform="index"/>Affirmative Goodness</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Neal, Sarah Ann" TEIform="persName"/>SARAH ANN NEAL.</byline><p TEIform="p"> What good things are we doing? and iow and under what motives are we doing them ? These are
                            questions we leed often to ask ourselves, in consideration of the advancing light of
                            increasngly religious dispensations—now, in our day. A time for doing good was never more
                            opportune than the present, and the world never needed truly good workers—those who are
                            willing to pattern Jesus, in precept and example, love and live as nobly as he did—more than
                            t needs such to-day. Jesus taught; and lis were the teachings of affirmative goodness, being
                            intensely practical—to be good, and be so by doing good. Jpon those who claim discipleship
                            of resus, rests the responsibility of doing good, even as he taught and as he did. There
                            probably never was greater motive power connected with Christianity than there is to-day ;
                            the heavens never Drompted well-directed action more than now ; and the needs of the present
                            hour are wills submissive to divine commands ; then would the world be filled with saved,
                            and saviors ; and who will accept the responsibility? Every day is as a leaf in life's book,
                            that should be turned for humanity's good; yet at every turn, can we answer affirmatively,
                            that we are improving our time to make the world better, humanity happier—making returns of
                            goodness for having lived in the world? Do we avail ourselves of all knowledge, and of every
                            means to do good? How very many our opportunities ! Only a word spoken in kindness ; a
                            little act rendered in love, in proper time and due season ; these fill up the sum of useful
                            lives. Do we who claim the honor of wearing the Christian name, hold ourselves susceptible
                            to the evolutions of the system, to grow better and better? Freely we may have, and do
                            receive ; are we as liberally anxious to share the gifts which have evolved from
                            Christianity, as we have been willing to receive ? Are our prejudices ejected, so that we
                            may accept of good from any quarter? Are we aiding the progress of humanity toward a higher
                            standard of Christianity than that of mere profession? Or are our own profession and
                            goodness merely, positively negative ? If we are performing our mission as disciples of
                            Christ, our claims to an exceeding spiritual inheritance are just; but if we are not, we
                            have no rights to such claims; no rights to wear the name ; no rights to ask for Christian
                            blessings, nor to remain in possession of what we already have, more than he who had one
                            talent, and buried it. But let us, Christian friends, love so dearly, live so truly, using
                            our every ability and opportunity to extend the cause of Christ, that we may realize of a
                            truth our endeavors for humanity's good. Let our religion be to love God by our service to
                            and for humanity; then, and then only, will the name of Christian be an honor to us, and the
                            blessings that will flow from such a re- <pb n="59" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. 59 ligion will not
                            be the results of a blind, negative faith, but every-day evidences of the presence of a
                            living providence. Shakers, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Epitomic history of the Watervliet shakers, no. 4" TEIform="index"/>Epitomic History of the
                            Watervliet Shakers. No. 4</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Buckingham, D. A." TEIform="persName"/>D. A. BUCKINGHAM</byline><p TEIform="p">AGRICULTURAL, AND OTHER IMPROVEMENTS. Forty or fifty years ago, every laboring man among us
                            went into the field with his scythe, cradle or hand-rake, according to the business to be
                            performed, and by much hard labor, the work of the day was accomplished. In the corn and
                            potato fields, the plow and the hoe were the utensils used for planting, weeding and hoeing;
                            and these tools were often of inferior quality. But as we now enter our fields of labor,
                            what do we behold ? Instead of a handscythe, we see the mowing-machine, compelled by
                            horse-power; one man performing what it took a dozen or twenty hands to do some fifty years
                            ago ! Instead of the hand-rake, as formerly, we now use the horse-rake, with its long iron
                            or hickory fingers, rapidly propelled by the same power—one man accomplishing the work of a
                            dozen men in the old way. So also in the grain field; instead of swinging the handcradle,
                            day after day, when the thermometer ranged from 85 to 90 degrees, with the sweat flowing so
                            profusely that scarcely a dry thread remained upon our backs, we now behold the majestic
                            reaper, manned by a lad, driving the half-enchanted team through the fields of golden grain,
                            laying prostrate the ripened harvest, and pushing from the platform of the machine the cut
                            grain, binding it into bundles, ready for the barn or threshing! So in the corn and potato
                            fields, we perceive the same great change, where the cultivator and side-plow accomplish
                            nearly the whole work necessary. Where we used to plow, sow and reap, around and over
                            slough-holes and open ditches, we now, by the use of underground drains, slip along over the
                            level surface, hardly knowing that it was not once the "Garden of Eden." As in our
                            agricultural, so in our horticultural business, much has been done to facilitate labor. Our
                            barns are on the improved scale. Instead of pitching the greater part of our produce of hay
                            or grain by hand, up and over high beams into the ridges of the barns, we now drive nearly
                            into the top of the barns with the whole load, and tumble it down into the bays below ! So,
                            too, we find improvements many among our sisterhood. As we strive for equality of feeling
                            and action, we endeavor to give them the right hand of fellowship in most things. Instead of
                            their washing and ironing in some old building, poorly fitted for the purpose, as was the
                            case forty years ago they now perform the labor in "double quick time" by steam-power, in th
                            most improved, modern mode. They wash and boil the clothing by steam, nd wring them and iron
                            them by the ame power! They have ranges for ooking, soapstone ovens for baking, oal stoves
                            for heating, and refined oils "or giving light. Of the different kinds of fruit adapted :o
                            our climate, we have not been backward in their cultivation, even of the most improved kinds
                            of apples, pears, reaches, plums, cherries, with all the mailer kinds of fruit indigenous to
                            our limate. We, the Shakers, have not been altogether dependent upon the outside world for
                            inventions ; some very useful ones have sprung up among ourselves. Garden seeds were
                            introduced into marcet by the Lebanon and Watervliet Shakers as early as 1790 or 1791. The
                            manufacture of corn-brooms originated mong the Shakers at Watervliet about he same time ;
                            and these were presented to the city markets. An improved timing lathe, with screw feeder,
                            for urning broom-handles, was invented in this place. Shaker herbs and extracts are noted
                            throughout the States, and need no comment. Also, a machine for sizing broom-corn brush was
                            invented at Harvard, Mass.; and the '•'•Improved Shaker Washing Machine" at Shaker Village,
                            N. H. Mowers and reapers were invented in the Society of Shakers at New Gloucester, Maine.
                            The first circular saw ever made was invented by the Lebanon Shakers, and may be seen to-day
                            in the " State Geological Department," at Albany, N. Y., where it was deposited by Bro. G.
                            M. Wickersham. When the Watervliet Shakers made " sopus whips" for market, they invented
                            machinery for twisting the handles. A pipe machine, a pea-sheller and a butter-worker, were
                            invented here. The printing presses used by the Shakers of Lebanon and Watervliet for
                            printing their seed bags and herb papers, were invented at Watervliet, and improved by the
                            Shakers of the former place. Also, at Watervliet, a machine for filling seed-bags, which has
                            long been in use. The planing-machine was invented by the Lebanon Shakers, since which all
                            others have come into use. A self-acting cheese-press was invented by the Lebanon Shakers.
                            Clothes-phis, an invention though small in itself, yet of its utility almost every family in
                            the United States can bear witness, originated, it is said, at the Shaker Settlement at
                            North Union, in the State of Ohio. The inventions and improvements made by the sisterhood,
                            in their fancy articles for market, are too numerous to mention- The above, with many other
                            not here noted, show the fact, (withou boasting,) that the inventive faculties o: the
                            Shakers have not been dormant dur ing the one hundred years just passed by The farmer who
                            gets the largest crops from the smallest number of well-husbanded acres is the one who will
                            reap the largest prof from his investment of time and money.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beecher on the resurrection of the body" TEIform="index"/>Beecher on the Resurrection of the
                            Body</head><p TEIform="p">[That all may see the advances being made )y the churches toward original Shaker tesmony on
                            this subject, we gladly copy from le Christian Union the following testimony. STow, Bro.
                            Beecher, tell us of the Resurrecion of Christ, and how we may enjoy it in lis world, to the
                            fulfillment of the prayer, Thy kingdom come, thy will be done on artk, as it is done in
                            heaven." How, then, bout " marrying, giving in marriage," tc. ?] Curiosity is continually
                            going to the ' gates ajar " and peering through the crack o see, what there is on the other
                            side. This s fascinating but unprofitable employment. ^he Bible is profitable for "
                            instruction in ighteousness ; " correct information respectng the kind of body we are to
                            have in anther life, even if we could get it, would have ut small influence in determining
                            what we hall do with the body we have in this. Yet, f we may judge from the multitude of
                            letters we receive on this subject, there is no other vhich interests a greater number of
                            readers; ertainly none which evokes a greater amount f correspondence. We have no special
                            theory to propound on his subject, except the very general one that nen know less about it
                            than they think they o. We are here cooped up in very narrow uarters, on shipboard. What
                            sort of habitation we are going to have when we get on shore we do-not know,—and we do not
                            care. We are quite content to leave that to our Heavenly Father. " God giveth it a body as
                            it pleaseth him" expresses the Christian creed about the resurrection. One thing, however,
                            is very clear: that there is absolutely no authority whatever in scripture for the doctrine
                            of a literal resurrection of the buried flesh and bones. It is unphilosophical,
                            unscientific, irrational, unscriptural. It has nothing to commend it except to those who
                            delight to approve their faith by believing the impossible. It sprang historically from a
                            low and materialistic conception of the spiritual world. It belongs to an intellectual
                            condition that buries the tomahawk and the bow and arrows with the chief, that he may have
                            them to use in the spirit land. It belongs to a materialistic philosophy that identifies the
                            soul with the body, and denies the existence of the one except in the brain of the other. It
                            is directly repudiated by Paul, by John, by Christ. Animal nature is inherent in the body.
                            In the heavenly world there is neither marrying nor giving in marriage. Weakness, weariness,
                            decay, are essential characteristics of matter. In the spirit world there is no night, for
                            no weariness; and no death, for no disintegration and decay. The body is flesh and blood. In
                            the spirit world is neither; for flesh and blood cannot inherit the kingdom of God. The
                            resurrection of Lazarus and other analogous cases throw no light on the resurrection for the
                            spiritual life. Nor does the resurrection of Christ indicate a resurrection of bodies which
                            have been devoured by the earth and mingled with the clay. Christ rose from the dead in his
                            own earthly body. It was the same body in which he lived and which was crucified. His disci
                            pies did not believe this at first; he demon strated the fact. He invited them to handle
                            him, to feel the nail-print and spear-wound he took food and ate before them. But atth same
                            time he distinctly declared to them, UA spirit hath not flesh and bones as ye see m have."
                            Whatever the spiritual body may be we have Christ's own words for it that th body in which
                            he appeared to them was no a " spiritual body." One correspondent asks what became o: this
                            terrestrial body. We do not know; bu we can venture an hypothesis. "This cor ruptible must
                            put on incorruption, and thi mortal must put on immortality." It is per fectly conceivable
                            that this mysteriou change, which the living bodies must the ndergo, Christ's body underwent
                            at the moment of his ascension; that he was thus joth the first-fruits of them that slept
                            and of lem that shall not fall asleep, but shall still je waiting when the Lord comes. We do
                            ot assert this to have been the case. We are not wise above what is written. But when one
                            wiser than we asserts the repulsive dogma that the minutest particles of the decayed corpse,
                            disintegrated and taken up into vegetable and animal matter, and so scattered throughout the
                            globe, are to be sought out and, by a miraculous sifting and sorting process, brought
                            together again into a rejuvenated and transformed body, and then cites as a triumphant
                            demonstration of his hypothesis the fact that Christ rose from the dead in flesh and bones
                            such as " a spirit hath not," his evidence is as unsatisfactory as his conclusion is
                            unwelcome. Our bodies admirably serve the purpose of a terrestrial and animal existence.
                            When that existence ends there is no more use for the body, and God takes it away, dissolves
                            it into its constituent elements, and reproduces them in new forms of life; in the grass
                            that grows and the flowers that bloom above the grave. To suppose that he is shut up to
                            reproducing the body for the spiritual state is to suppose that the Divine Father provides
                            for manhood only the long clothes of the baby made over and refitted. God has not exhausted
                            either his ingenuity or his love in what he has furnished us here below. He has given us so
                            good a tent in the wilderness that we can afford to trust him to provide a permanent house
                            when we get to the land of promise. As to the other question of our correspondent, we can
                            only say that the whole drift of scripture appears to us clearly to teach that the soul
                            passes directly from its earthly to its spiritual life; that there is no "intermediate state
                            ; " that death is not death but only transition. It is the theory of Swedenborg that at
                            death the terrestrial body drops off and the spiritual body emerges; that this is the
                            resurrection ; that the day of judgment has already begun; that every soul goes from its
                            death-bed to the judgment-bar of God. There are some weighty objections to this view; but
                            there are some weighty objections to all views ? if one must have a theory this is perhaps
                            as good as any. That death summons the Christian to judgment, and judgment ushers him into
                            immortality, is the clear revelation of God's Word. What is the architecture of the
                            court-room, what the proceedings, how long they last, and what is the domain that lies
                            beyond, no one knows; and they know least who are most dogmatic. There is no objection to
                            imagining anything if you do not frame your imagination into a creed. The piled-up clouds
                            may often pass for snow-capped mountains ; and indulgence in the pleasing delusion is quite
                            harmless. Nevertheless, clouds are not mountains. The boy delights to dream of what he will
                            do when he is a man. But the realities of manhood are never like the dreams of boyhood. Of
                            one thing we may be very sure : whatever the future is it will not be a reproduction of our
                            day-dreams ; the mountains of God will not be patterned after the clouds of our own
                            creating. For " it doth not yet appear what we shall be."</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Faults" TEIform="index"/>Faults
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Faults.—Do not attempt to cover your faults, but try to get rid of them. Every person does
                            wrong at times, and confession is no new thing in this world. One must own that all is not
                            right, or become ridiculous as well as hypocritical. Other people will see, whether we try
                            to blind them or not; and just for what we are worth will they value us. Let us all be
                            honest, no matter what else we may be, and not pretend to be better than we are.</p></div2><pb n="60" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Remarkable prophecy" TEIform="index"/>A Remarkable Prophecy</head><p TEIform="p">[Our readers will thank us, we feel assured, for reproducing in print the following
                            remarkable prophecy and interpretation. As will be observed, it is copied from a book
                            published in 1854; an^ its first special notice, through the Chicago Inter Ocean in 1876,
                            attracted considerable attention. As we circulate largely among a Bible-reading people, we
                            ask that the book be opened at Daniel, xi., 40-45 verses; and compare them with what
                            follows.—Ed. Shaker.] A book out of print entitled "Armageddon, or the United States in
                            Prophecy," written by the Rev. S. D. Baldwin, a Presbyterian minister of Nashville, Tenn.,
                            then President of Soule Female College, but long deceased, was published in 1854. When the
                            work appeared it attracted very wide attention. Among the predictions was a bloody and
                            furious war to begin in 1861, and to end the 117th day of 1865- -a war which exactly
                            fulfills the term of the late rebellion, Johnson having surrendered to Sherman April 26,
                            1865, and thus terminated the array of arms. From this remarkable exposition of the
                            prophetic parts of the Bible we copy so much as relates to the first four verses of our
                            quotations from Daniel, as follows : "And at the time of the end." This period was to be
                            that between the first and last endings of the three and a half times, or between 1776 and
                            1878, or between the 1200 and 1235 days. During this period this willful king was to come to
                            his end; but, before his end, he was to engage in war for some outlying countries, and was
                            to be interrupted by two great powers, but was to conquer and prosper till the "last end of
                            the indignation." As this was to be the great monarchy power represented by the image that
                            was to be broken by the stone (since it was Rome), it is evident that its head must be in
                            Europe, and must be the empire represented by the septimo-octave head of the beast in
                            revelation. Now, the great power which fills half of Europe and overshadows and controls the
                            rest of the rising colossus, — Russia, — therefore, must be the power intended as falling in
                            the holy mountain. Now, as Ezekiel, almost literally, describes Russia as falling on the
                            mountains of Israel, in the latter day, he furnishes further evidence that the fourth
                            kingdom, in the time of the end, was to be resurrected in or by Russia. The willful kingdom
                            was an autocrat among nations, and so is the Russian kingdom. "The king of the south shall
                            push or butt at him; and the king of the north shall come against him like a whirlwind, with
                            chariots, and with horsemen, and with many ships." The two kingdoms, under the names north
                            and south, are to be identified by their relative positions to the Russian power, or to each
                            other. The king, or kingdom, of the south would very naturally apply to Turkey on the south
                            of Russia \ but as Turkey exists by the sufferance of France and England, it is possible the
                            two great western powers, which hold to each other the relation of north and south, may be
                            intended. At any rate, the southern king makes short fight of it, if anything is to be
                            understood by the figure of butting at the willful king, or he brings on the fight. The
                            kingdoms of Syria and Egypt, called the kingdoms of the north and south, held about the same
                            close relation to each other, and to Rome, that England and France do to each other and to
                            Russia; only they were on the east of Rome, and the case is now just reversed. The king of
                            the north is Great Britain. This is evident from its northern position, as a great power,
                            and from the immense naval, as well as land, forces it possesses. No nation but a very great
                            one would attack the autocratic king; and no nation has such a navy as Britain. This north
                            nation was to come like a whirlwind, with his great naval and land forces, which are
                            indicated by " many ships " and " chariots anc horsemen." The attack was to be great anc
                            furious, but finally unsuccessful; for the autocrat moves right on to his purpose, and more
                            than gains it, according to the prophet. " He shall enter into the countries, and shall
                            overflow, and pass over." His entering the countries intimates that this was his original
                            design, in which he had been interrupted by the two great powers that confederated against
                            him. England and France, or England and Turkey, will unite against Russia. And it seems as
                            if considerable effort was to be made to check Russia's designs ; yet Russia is to take the
                            countries this side of the crossings, and then to pass over into Asia, it would seem. The
                            word "overflow" signifies the great increase of his armies and triumphs. To " pass over "
                            implies the advancement of conquest, by some great crossing, into a new scene of warfare. "
                            He shall enter the glorious land." This at once reveals his advancement into Palestine, and
                            shows that the passing over related to the conquest of Asia Minor and the Turkish empire
                            generally. " Many countries shall be overthrown; but these shall escape out of his hand,
                            even Edom and Moab, and the chief of the children of Ammon." This would literally imply the
                            conquest of a great portion of Asiatic Turkey, with some exceptions. These were conquests in
                            Asia. " He shall stretch forth his hand also upon the countries, and the land of Egypt shall
                            not escape." This expression . implies the exertion of severe sovereignty. African countries
                            are here referred to, as Egypt is specific for a generic term or a part of the whole. " He
                            shall have power over the treasures of gold and silver, and over all the precious things of
                            Egypt." "The Libyans and Ethiopians shall be at his steps." This still further teaches the
                            unlimited dominion over Africa in the west and south. Thus having obtained nearly all
                            Europe, Asia and Africa, he becomes indomitable and his empire almost limitless : it
                            emulates old Rome as the possessor of three continents. According to the views of Mr.
                            Baldwin the accomplishment of Daniel's prophecy was to begin in 1S76, continue through 1877
                            and terminate before the close of April, 1878. Should his prognostications turn out to be
                            true the near future will develop startling and profoundly interesting events. In that case
                            the efforts of the European powers to patch up a peace will prove abortive ; the actual
                            occupation of the revolted provinces by Russian troops will take place; England will oppose
                            the Czar's progress with a sudden, tremendous onset in magnificent array, but without avail;
                            Russian armies will victoriously cross the Dardanelles into Turkey, making a conquest of the
                            European portion first, then pour triumphantly into Asia Minor, reduce it to subjection,
                            together with Egypt, Palestine, and some African countries besides. If Daniel's prophecy has
                            been accurately interpreted, Russia is to become the autocratic colossus among nations in
                            the old world with in eighteen months from this date, and then precipitately tumble into a
                            vast and wonder ful ruin. Our readers, with this prophetic map of the future before them,
                            will be able quickly to determine, by the concurrence o the divergence of approaching
                            events, ho\ much truth or falsity there is in our quotec exposition of scriptural dates and
                            occurrence foreordained. In these times of European up heaval and change, when diplomacy is
                            bafflec and desiring, and when the strong attention of the two hemispheres is fixed upon the
                            war like situation, any fact or even hypothesi bearing upon its aspects, from whateve
                            source, must prove interesting.</p></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="There are two ways of going through this world..." TEIform="index"/>There are two ways of going through this world...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">There are two ways of going througl this world. One is to make the best of it and the other
                            to make the worst of it. Thos who take the latter course work hard fo poor pay.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="More shakers" TEIform="index"/>More Shakers</head><p TEIform="p">An account is given in the Indian Evangelical Review of the rise of a sect in Travncore
                            called the " Six-Years People." The evival movement of 1873-4 iri Travancore trongly
                            affected the Syrian Christians who were brought under its influence, and some f the native
                            Christians connected with the Church Missionary Society. The revival was accompanied with
                            those physical maniestations which attended the preaching of lie early Methodists in England
                            and Ameria, and whole congregations might- be seen baking or daiicing with cxcitemeiit. One
                            of the preachers professed prophetic discernment; he announced that the end of the world
                            will come in 1880. This prediction was made in 1874, and hence the name " SixYears
                        People."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Russian sects" TEIform="index"/>Russian Sects</head><p TEIform="p">Many of the sects have persons among hem whom they believe to be Christ, incarnate for the
                            second time, and the Virgin. One sect was founded by a peasant-soldier, Daniel Philipitch,
                            about the middle of the seventeenth century, and is now strong in many parts of the empire.
                            Philipitch's doc:rines, as reported by Hepworth Dixon, who las made a special study in
                            Russia of secret and curious sects, Avere : first, " I am God ; " second, " There is no
                            other God; " and third, ' There is nothing new." He gave nine precepts to his followers,
                            which I quote from Dixon's text: "Drink no wine. Remain where you are, and what you are.
                            Never marry. Never swear, nor name the devil. Attend no wedding, christening, nor othei
                            feast. Never steal. Keep my doctrine secret. Love each other, and keep my laws. Believe in
                            the Holy Spirit."—Ex.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Equality of sex" TEIform="index"/>Equality of Sex</head><p TEIform="p">If any person should ask me for the best evidence I have that the religion of Jesus is
                            superior to that of Zoroaster, Buddha, or Mohammed, or that his social philosophy is vastly
                            superior to that of Socrates, Aristotle, Plato, or any other ancient Greek or Roman
                            philosopher, or anj^ philosopher or scientist of modern times, I should say it is furnished
                            in the fact that it makes no distinc tion between man and women in respect to their right to
                            life, liberty, and the pursuit o happiness. When the great apostle said tha in Jesus Christ
                            there is neither male nor female, he gave birth to a thought that covers entirely the
                            governmental, political, social and family status of mankind under Christian ity. He laid
                            the foundation for a system o practical relationships that makes it as im portant that a
                            husband should think well o his wife as that he should think well of him self; that a father
                            should think as well of his daughter as of his son ; that a brother shoulc think as much of
                            his sister as of any man friend; that society should respect woman and treat her on the same
                            basis that it does man ; that the state should recognize woman to have the same rights, and
                            under both or ganic and statute law be entitled to the same immunities, privileges, and
                            franchises tha man has. That the church should make no distinction between men and women, in
                            it respect, regard, or affection : nor in the con ferment of its powers, nor in the working
                            ou of its grand functions. In fine, that all the conditions of living, which are to be
                            regard ed as forcible and authoritative, which socie ty, the church, or the state may take
                            unto itself, are to be, under law. as directlj' ac corded to woman as to man. In other words
                            that men and women shall, before the law be equal in the family, in society, in th state,
                            and in the church; and that whateve differences are seen to exist between the two shall be
                            only those which grow up in the na ture of things.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Jackson, J. C." TEIform="persName"/>Dr. J. C, Jackson</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Necessities for the new Earth" TEIform="index"/>Necessities for the New Earth</head><byline TEIform="byline">[The concluding number of The New Age,—and we are pained to say concluding, —contained a
                            very brilliant letter from one<persName reg="W., M. S." TEIform="persName"/>" M. S. W." We copy a portion of it
                            below, giving the title above. Few subjects demand more thought and action than does this.—
                            Ed. Shaker.]</byline><p TEIform="p">Education is a grand thing; but simply hat which is gained from the books of toay will avail
                            little. We need an education vhich will develop our young men and womn of to-day into fit
                            fathers and mothers for hildren " a little lower than the angels." What are our children,
                            and what their fathers ind mothers,—ninety-nine out of a hundred? 3oor, weak, ignorant,
                            fashionable, selfish, dissipated creatures,—just what will people our world with a class
                            worse than now dwells upon it. And yet, few seem alive to the fact; or, if alive to it, they
                            have not the courage, or daring, or whatever it need be, to show the people their condition.
                            Realty, it seems to me, when I seriously think of it, that it is a crime for our young
                            people to marry as they do, ignorant as they are, and fill the wrorld with children who can
                            only become just what their parents' indecision and weakness, as well as ignorance, must
                            make of them ! Will the time ever come when as much thought will be given to the creation of
                            immortal souls as to-day is given to the improvement of the brute creation? Is it not
                            strange that we take the brute first? If I was truly Darwinian in belief, I might conclude
                            such way the only way for elevating the race; for it sometimes seems to me that people will
                            not listen to reason, and will in their selfishness only be governed by impulse and desire;
                            and even when they have learned the folly of their ways, they cannot or do not try to warn
                            others. Who can wonder that we have criminals? Had I strength sufficient, I would throw the
                            whole weight of it against this breeding of criminals, and would take only interval time to
                            encourage and make effort for the elevation of the result of an unrighteous and abominable
                            ignorance.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fitting rebuke to fighting Christians (?)" TEIform="index"/>A Fitting Rebuke to Fighting
                            Christians (?)</head><p TEIform="p">Bishop Coxe, of Western New York, recently sent a poem to the Buffalo Commercial Advertise?',
                            brim-full of the spirit of war, calling to arms everyone, to help the Russians and to kill
                            the Turks ! So very unlike the Jesus this poet-priest pretends to worship, the poem has
                            attracted large attention from the secular pi'ess. Hie Albany Express delivers a most
                            denunciatory lecture upon such, so-called, Christianity, and prints the following poem, from
                            The Graphic, by W. A. Croffut, which is so full of rebuke to those who think Christianity
                            admits of any physical violence, that we gladly transfer it to our columns, as an aid in
                            diffusing light upon the character of the Prince of Peace, and to use a whip of large-corded
                            testimony against the Christianity of such a Bishop ! BY A NEWSPAPER HERETIC. Thou man of
                            God (?) who thus implore Thy brother's sacred blood to pour In hateful tides of turbid gore
                            From Dardanelles to Danube's shore, Be still—be still! Blaspheme no more! God help the babes
                            ! God bless the wives ! Shame on the priests that whet the knives ! Shame on the church
                            whose altar thriyes By wrecking peaceful peasants' lives? Be still—be still! 'Tis Hell that
                            drives! How long, O, Lord, before thy shrine Shall men pray, "Vengeance, God, is thine,' <pb n="61" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. 61 Then worship Moloch as divine, And drink the battle's
                            bloody wine? Be still—be still— O, heart of mine ! ***** Come holy Peace ! May Muscovite And
                            Moslem end their wretched fight; Women with songs shall hail the light, And children flock
                            with flags of white— Be still—be still— O, sacred sight!</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wilmington, Delaware, July 1, 1877" TEIform="index"/>Wilmington, Del., July i, 1877</head><p TEIform="p">My dear friend: Being somewhat interested in Shakerism, I would like to ask you a few
                                questions : 1. Should I conclude to join your people what inducements, more than the
                                world presents, will Shakerism offer me? 2. My companion and self, and children, now get
                                on comfortably; tell me plainly, without scripture quotations, what Shakerism will give
                                me in exchange for these? 3. 1 ask no prominent position, but will I be in any manner
                                degraded to maintain others in an exalted office? 4. Do you fare and share alike in
                                temporal things ? 5. Do all eat at a common table? clad in similar raiment? feel equally
                                interested in hand labor? or, 6. Are some permitted to be " lords and ladies," while
                                others are expected to do their bidding? 7. I am earnest for a better religion than can
                                be found outside of Shakerism; do you think Shakerism will supply my demand? 8. I have
                                read your Covenant thoroughly: and if you can assure me it is in full operation among
                                your people, or will be exercised toward me and companions as therein stated, I believe
                                it far preferable to any other theory yet advanced. Can you give me the assurance? 9.
                                After answering the above, tell me what I must do first, to enlist under your banner.
                                10. I am a minister; have been for many years, and have never made any change from my
                                first convictions; and I now propose to do so only on the basis of the soundest
                                convictions, that you Shakers live as j^ou profess, and will not disappoint me in the
                                matter of the general carrying out of your Covenant. Can you convict me? 11. I candidly
                                believe that many stand ready to be converts to Shaker practice, when you can answer
                                favorably query 10, and give them a certainty of an equality with others, without
                                exception, by their yielding to the cause a full consecration. Can we have these? 12.
                                Where do you advise our making the attempt at being Shakers, that the fullness of the
                                Shaker Covenant may be found only as binding on us as on others? 1 am yours, truly,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bishop, John B." TEIform="persName"/>John B. Bishop</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What shall I do to be a shaker? answered by bro. Thomas Smith" TEIform="index"/>WHAT
                                SHALL I DO TO BE A SHAKER? ANSWERED BY BRO. THOMAS SMITH</head><p TEIform="p">Mt. Lebanon, July 3, 1877. Esteemed Friend John B. Bishop.-. Your favor of the 1st inst.
                                is at hand, and reply to your questions in the order they are presented. 1 st. Shakerism
                                offers no inducements to the average man or woman; but to those whom the "Father" hath
                                drawn hither, it offers peace, joy and rest, coupled with the active duties of life. 2d.
                                If yourself and companion, etc., are happily satisfied with surroundings, let Shakerism
                                alone. If looking for something broader, more unselfish, more permanent, Shakerism will
                                yield it, after much toil and labor; as it gives you a close relation to many brethren
                                and sisters, whose interest and care, love and affection, are centered upon and cjrawn
                                out by those things which tend to universal peace. 3d. It depends upon what you consider
                                degrading. Physical labor in contact with the earth is a requisite in this case. I know
                                of no exalted offices in the institution. 4th. Practically, yea; comparatively, nay. The
                                members of each Shaker family fare and share alike, as per first answer; different
                                families in Shaker communities may have local differences in these respects as per
                                second answer. 5th. All eat at one common table, dress similarly, and feel interested in
                                hand labor according as they are more or less unselfish. 6th. Lords and ladies form no
                                component part of Shakerism; but strict obedience to constituted authority, for order's
                                sake, is required. 7th. Shakerism is a better religion than is found outside of it; but
                                it would take some time for me to ascertain whether it would supply your demands. 8th.
                                You need have no scruples as to the Covenant being faithfully carried out toward you;
                                our main trouble commonly proceeds from the opposite direction. 9th. Yourself and
                                companion must come to a mutual agreement am the subject. All just debts and obligations
                                must be fulfilled. LTpon entering the order, each heart must open the book of life to
                                the order's representative ; in other words, confess all its sins. 10th. Frankly, I am
                                sorry you have been a minister so long, because of the tenacity with which this class
                                adheres to dead issues. But no answer of mine would be equal to your mingling with this
                                people, and seeing for yourself. Do not change your opinions until you are satisfied.
                                nth. lam aware that many seem ripening up for the harvest, but no covenant, creed or
                                promise will cover the case. Human nature, is the same to-day as in the past; and only
                                as the fire of Pentecost touches the human heart, will it forget its selfhood, and break
                                its bread from door to door. "Can we have these?" Are j'ou numerous? If so, select some
                                of j'our best; let them come and investigate rigidly, and report as they comprehend the
                                case. 12th. Wherever you are the best acquainted and are the most attracted. Finalljr, I
                                write you, not as by authority, but from the basis of my own experience and belief. I am
                                yours for the investigation of truth,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Smith, Thomas" TEIform="persName"/>Thos. Smith</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Poetic sermon—'judge not'" TEIform="index"/>Poetic Sermon—" Judge Not."</head><p TEIform="p">In speaking of a person's faults, Pray don't forget your own ; Remember, those with homes of
                            glass Should seldom throw a stone. If we have nothing else to do But talk of others' sin,
                            'Tis better we commence at home, And from that point begin. Some may have faults—and who
                            have The old as well as young! Perhaps we may, for aught we know, Have many where they've
                            one. I'll tell you of a better plan, And one that works full well: e sure your own defects
                            you cure Before of others' tell.</p></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sound critic" TEIform="index"/>A sound critic</head><p TEIform="p">—A religious old lady, when asked her opinion of the organ of a church, the first time she
                            had seen or heard one, said : " It's a vera bonny kist fu' o' whistles ; but oh, sirs, it's
                            an awfu' way o' spending the Sabbath-day !"</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If you wish to be happy..." TEIform="index"/>If you wish to be happy...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">THE SHAKER. Monthly—60 cents per annum. A DUAL ADVOCATE OF CHRIST PRINCIPLES. If you wish to
                            be happj', keep busy. Idleness is harder work than plowing, a good deal. There is more fun
                            in sweating an hour than yawning a century.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Unmistakable Christianity" TEIform="index"/>Unmistakable Christianity</head><p TEIform="p">PLAIN SHAKERISM. Jesus was a Christian—his manner of life made him so. Whoso lives as Jesus
                            lived—whose lives are guided by the same principles—are Christians ; none others are so.
                            Belief in this, that, or any theology, is no designation of a Christian ; only a pure life—a
                            virgin character—combined with equality in worldly goods, noncombative disposition, and
                            separation from worldly practices generally,— these alone constitute a follower of Christ.
                            Worldly practices are the lusts of the flesh, of evil, adulterous eyes, pride, vanity, and
                            all intemperance in life. The multitudes of theologians are stumbling-blocks ; hiding the
                            real life a Christian should live ; covering, as with an ambush "of unmeaning words, the
                            unvarnished, plain, indisputable truths of Jesus' life. Who can engage in ' the lusts of the
                            flesh ; marriage, reproductions—fruitful or unfruitful practices of sexuality— and claim to
                            follow Christ in them? Did Jesus ever do such things? Can his followers—Christians—engage in
                            acts so foreign, opposite to his life, without relinquishing all right or title to his name
                            ? People are not desirous of thinking of these things ; and man-made theologies pleasantly
                            blind their eyes to these truths. Marriage was a Jewish rite; proper and good for Jews and
                            worldly people to practice. Who have made it a sacrament, and dubbed it as Christian ?
                            Worldly, lustful men and women ! Jesus called men and women away from marriage, lustful,
                            sexual, and defiling indulgences. His early disciples dissolved their marriage relations,
                            whereever they were bound by them ; became "as though they were not married"— as brotherly,
                            sisterly men and women. Have not the churches reversed this rule, and many others that Jesus
                            instituted, practiced, and which his immediate followers, and all genuine followers,
                            engaged, and do now engage in? Whom do the majority of professedly Christians follow?
                            Surely, not Jesus. Surely, the very reverse of Jesus is illustrated in their lives! Where,
                            then, is the title Christian applicable? Is there any salvation in the title? Does it save,
                            or prevent any from unchristian practices? Does our Christianity abolish marriage, war,
                            private property, selfish relations, with all the constituents of a married life? Does it
                            cause us to live the life of the heavens, in excess of Judaism? Then, and then only, is it
                            better. We arraign every one who, professing to follow Christ, does not pattern his life, in
                            its general characteristics at least, of living and acting under false pretences — as real
                            hypocrites — and from whom the title of Christian should be erased. We declare that
                            propriety demands the erasure of that portion of the Lord's Prayer that petitions, " Thy
                            kingdom come, thy will be done on earth, as in heaven !" from every one's prayer who does
                            not try to live as they believe life in heaven to be. Thus does Shakerism demand of its
                            communicants: Be what you seem to be ; be what you ought to be ; be chrisHans, or disown the
                            title. Be virgins, as was Jesus ; be as unselfishly with all earthly goods ; hate the flesh,
                            war, and their constituents. Let your relations be those only who live as Jesus lived— who "
                            do the will of his father," as he did. All other relatives are worldly, unchristian. Be
                            brethren; share all things together, and equally—blessings and tribulations. Let your
                            uprightness exceed that of the world ; and inasmuch as you "name the name of Christ, depart
                            from all iniquity," even as Christ did. Can any do less and be christians? Let it be plainly
                            understood that Jesus aspired to, and lived above the very best practices of Judaism. He not
                            only abstained from worldly evils, but worldly good; and this latter abstinence is the
                            peculiar designation of his true followers. Thus have we written plainly. We ask, have we
                            written truly? Does following Jesus embrace and demand selfdenials? If so, how much and how
                            many ? God forbid that we, professing Christianity, , should evade its laws; preach or
                            practice any other doctrine or life than did its author ; and with these considerations
                            prevailing, do we, as Shakers, live very unlike the great, first Shaker, Jesus? or do we
                            demand of ourselves, or of Christians, too many sacrifices of selfishness?</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>EDITORIAL NOTES</head><p TEIform="p">Many of the cities of the Union, on I July 4th, set a good example, by refraining from
                            celebrating the national anniversary by a prpfuse use of gunpowder. It is to be hoped that,
                            the first century having" passed with extreme noise, and the worse than wasting of thousands
                            of millions of dollars for fireworks, the second century, at its very beginning, will
                            inaugurate a much more sensible and humane system of celebrations than the momentary burning
                            of pyrotechnics, followed, as it invariably is, with loss of limbs, lives, and an
                            incalculable amount of valuable property. If small boys must have the incendiary Chinese
                            cracker, let them be sent to China to use them. After years of deliberation upon the causes
                            and effects of America's civil war, North and South are shaking hands over the bloody chasm,
                            and filling this up by forgiveness and forgetfulness. While they " sti'ewed flowers on
                            federals and confederates alike," the bitter thoughts would rise, of the uselessness of the
                            sacrifices, and of the insanity that prompted the strife on both sides. If <pb n="62" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER,. the war ofi86i, and following years, had any foundation of good,
                            it was a goodness of the Jews, not Christians ; it was the worship of the God of battles,
                            after the similitude of Israel's leader, not of the Father of the Christ—the Prince of
                            Peace. And the people are learning the grand differences of the characters of the Gods of
                            war and of peace, and to know that the God of the Christians is not the God of the Jews. We
                            enter our solemn protest against such unusual display as is commonly engaged in by some
                            portions of the press of our country, in advertising revolvers, and other disreputable
                            weapons, to be carried, concealed on the person. To "such base uses" has advertising
                            arrived, that were it not for the protests of some, we might all despair of getting any good
                            through this medium of intelligence. When such so-called religions papers, The Church Union,
                            New York Independent, etc., and agricultural and scientific journals like Rural New Yorker,
                            Country Gentleman and Scientific American, stoop to encourage the sale of three-dollar
                            shooting-irons, thus placing them within the reach of almost every boy in the land, it is
                            high time to protest against the practice, or appeal to heads of families to expunge such
                            papers from the household. The use of such weapons is wrong in principle, and their advocacy
                            naught but barbarous. Let the editors of such papers, who stoop to the mercenary in this
                            way, but suffer from the accidental or other discharge of one of these crimemultiplying
                            irons, and then we shall be treated, if the heathens still live, to a first-class rebuke
                            against what they have sold themselves to encourage. We anticipate advertisingjin the volume
                            succeeding this—Vol. VIII.—and would now warn all such—venders, emissaries, quacks, frauds
                            generally—they " need not apply." By many believers of to-day, Elder Ebenezer Bishop, (who
                            succeeded to the ministry on the decease of Mother Lucy Wright,) will be "remembered as a
                            most beautiful spirit—a very saintly man. His administration was one of exacting justice,
                            everywhere that it was known. In counsel, wise ; in advice, fatherly in the extreme ; while
                            it is difficult to recall one who illustrated humility in a greater degree. It is claimed,
                            by those most familiar with his method of government, that, guided by "The Covenant" and
                            "Sacred Laws," he would ever make these the arbiter of his decisions. When there arose
                            differences between brethren, he was wont to take the Covenant, and say: " Brethren, here is
                            our guide; to it we have attached our signatures ; to it we look for justice to ourselves
                            and to others ; and by it we must live and die. Its decisions are my decisions ; let us see
                            what it says." Perhaps, to this pertinacity may be attributed his abundant success. Our
                            music for this number is an excellent selection from the Shaker Casket of Pearls. To some of
                            our own people, it will not be especially new ; but sang with the harmonious accompaniment,
                            arranged by some individual of talent, it will be none the less acceptable. We would, right
                            here, commend, to all interested in Shaker music, the labors, in this line, of Elder H. C.
                            Blinn, and coadjutors. They have favored us with some excellently-prepared sheet music. Send
                            a few dimes, and get diamond samples. Address Shaker Village, N. H. We received, not long
                            since, from Bro. Gra}', of Pleasant Hill, Ky., a letter having some admirable ideas, aroused
                            by "Shall we have a revival?" Strong intimations were given therein, that we, as Believers,
                            are more willing that others should have revivals than ourselves. We do not know, cannot
                            predict, when we as Believers will awake to the facts of our necessities; 3ut think it will
                            be ere long. We have 3een praying for years, in special meetings of united prayer throughout
                            the Societies, that the world may wake up to true Christian life. Is it not now in order
                            that we .pray for the revival or VIother Ann Lee's influences, for our own baptism ? And
                            becoming baptized Therewith, will not our prayers materialize into heads, hearts, hands and
                            feet? Will they not inspire us with new tongues, kind feelings, and with a good deal of
                            self-immolation ? Remember, brethren, however much good God lias given us to start with, it
                            is only that good evolved by self-denial that we get any special credit for ! We would go on
                            record as avowing our detestation of any theological prejudices that deny civil and
                            respectable conduct toward Jews, Gentiles, Christians or Infidels. The recent disgraceful
                            action of Judge Hilton toward the better, nobler man, Seligman, in refusing the latter
                            accommodations at his hotel in Saratoga, because of his Hebrew belief, should arouse the
                            unexceptionable condemnation of every one. What can be meaner than the meanness of a
                            professedly Christian gentleman? We observe that our article in July number, " After the
                            Flood," is attracting considerable attention from the press of our country. Some journals
                            have kindly copied it entire, adding respectful comments thereto. After so much vituperation
                            and unkindly criticism as was manifested by so large a portion of the press, on the subject
                            of that article, we esteem the above favors as signs of returning reason, love and good
                            will, and hereby return thanks. If any one feels desirous of realizing how«diminutive is the
                            largest of human exaltation ; how comparatively worthless all human learning ; how little
                            our earth, and bewilderingly extensive is stellar space ; we advise a few doses ot "Views of
                            our Heavenly Home," now running in chapters through The Banner of Light. Truly, we may
                            therein forget ourselves, be lost in admiration of the works of an almighty hand, and
                            exclaim, with all our hearts, with one of old: "When I consider the heavens the work of thy
                            fingers ; the moon and stars which thou hast ordained ; what is man, that thou art mindful
                            of him ? and the son of man that thou visitest him ? " We perceive, with some delight, a
                            novel method of punishing offenders against public property and peace, instituted at Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y. They love their enemies so well that they promote them out of the
                            country—send them to Europe, whence they came— with an insisting permission never to return
                            again ! May they need to exercise such love very, very seldom.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>Read and Think</head><div3 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="That the U. S. army is to be reduced..." TEIform="index"/>That the U. S. army is to be reduced...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">That the U. S. army is to be reduced to 19,000 men! </p></div3><div3 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="That Wm. H. Vanderbilt's money..." TEIform="index"/>That Wm. H. Vanderbilt's money...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">That Wm. H. Vanderbilt's money is his greatest trouble in this world. </p></div3><div3 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="One pound and a half of eggs..." TEIform="index"/>One pound and a half of eggs...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">One pound and a half of eggs is a legal dozen now, not Hvclve units of uncertain size.
                            </p></div3><div3 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sewing machines must be cheaper..." TEIform="index"/>Sewing machines must be cheaper...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Sewing machines must be cheaper. The most important patents have failed of a renewal.
                            </p></div3><div3 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Chinese will send missionaries..." TEIform="index"/>The Chinese will send missionaries...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Chinese will send missionaries to America, for similar purposes that ours go there!
                            </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To comprehend the beginning and ending of things..." TEIform="index"/>To comprehend the beginning and ending of things...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">To comprehend the beginning and ending of things is an infinite thought, and therefore it
                                requires an infinite mind to grasp it. Why, then, should a finite being darken his soul
                                by doubt because he cannot compass infinity? </p></div3><div3 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A woman was arrested in New York..." TEIform="index"/>A woman was arrested in New York...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> A woman was arrested in N. Y. city for wearing male attire. She conclusively proved the
                                clothes were made for her, fitted to her, and the Judge discharged her, saying, there is
                                no more law against her dressing thus than there is against the more abominable style
                                women wear to attract attention! </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A word to the aged" TEIform="index"/>A word to the aged
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> A word to the aged.—It is well for the old to be cheerful. They may have much to depress
                                them. Health is failing. Friends are passing away. Another generation is on the stage.
                                Other hands take up the world's work. They feel, perhaps with bitter regret, that they
                                are not needed as they once were. Nevertheless, they should cultivate every source of
                                happiness which remains. The love of children and grandchildren, the greater dignity and
                                larger leisure of life, and the quiet hours they can have for communion with God, should
                                be appreciated highly. They should get into the habit of saying good-morning every day
                                to this world, where they have had so many eager, busy, happ_y and holy days. </p></div3><div3 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A late number of The Bible Banner..." TEIform="index"/>A late number of The Bible Banner...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> A late number of The Bible Banner (Advent,)contains "The Banner Sermon," which sums up:
                                "To be a Christian demands the practical life of Jesus." </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bad men, even in their prosperity..." TEIform="index"/>Bad men, even in their prosperity...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Bad men, even in their prosperity, are unhappy. The fate they have been told they merit,
                                they are in the continual expectation of.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-press" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Cleveland (O.) Post lately gave..." TEIform="index"/>The Cleveland (O.) Post lately gave...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Cleveland (9.) Post lately gave " Ann Lee's Disciples" nearly three columns of
                                creditable illustration ; and we found therein many excellent items of general
                                information. The Shaker came in for a handsome compliment, and those shirts, received by
                                its editor some time since, were held up for the hundredth time, as evidencing^Shaker
                                generosity ! Let the people hear! </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-press" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Harbinger of Light, Melbourne, Australia..." TEIform="index"/>The Harbinger of Light, Melbourne, Australia...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Harbinger of Light, Melbourne, Australia, contains extensive extracts, duly credited
                                to our society pamphlet, " Plain Talks." Bro. Peebles, in Australia, is doing our cause
                                good service, and "ends of the earth shall know thereof."</p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Every man should perform..." TEIform="index"/>Every man should perform...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Every man should perform as much physical labor as will supply his own practical wants.</p><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Taylor, Frank B." TEIform="persName"/>Frank B. Taylor</p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="As individuals we must love before we criticise..." TEIform="index"/>As individuals we must love before we criticise...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> As individuals we must love before we criticise. Criticism bathed in love, wounds but to
                                heal. Bathed in personal feelings, it leaves in the wound poison. There is great
                                sensibility in most persons to criticism. The nerves of egotism are wonderfully
                                delicate, and cringe at the slightest touch; and it requires wisdom to criticise
                                faithfully, and yet avoid unnecessary irritation. Criticism should carry no savor of
                                condemnation."—Mutual Criticism.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>FOR OUR HEALTH</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In what does nerve-food consist?..." TEIform="index"/>In what does nerve-food consist?...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">In what does nerve-food consist? In what do we find it? Is it meat? No. White bread? No.
                                Potatoes? No. If it is not found in these staples, in what is it to be found? I answer,
                                in the exterior of the white kernel, in the skin of the potato, and in milk, partially;
                                also in eggs and fish. I answer, the chief food staples, in the present dietetic system,
                                are almost entirely deficient in brain and nerve building material. In view of these
                                facts, is it a result to be wondered at, that the starving nervous tissue in the
                                overworked masses attempts to satisfy an intolerable sense of craving of physical hunger
                                bv the use of stimulating poisons ? — Herald of Health. </p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tyndall's advice" TEIform="index"/>Tyndall's advice.</head><p TEIform="p">Take care of your health. There have been men who, by a wise attention to this subject,
                                might have risen to any eminence, but who by unwise neglect on this point, have come to
                                nothing. Imagine Hercules as oarsman in a rotten boat; what can he do there but by the
                                very force of his stroke expedite the ruin of his craft? Take care then, of the timbers
                                of your boat, and avoid all practices likely to introduce wet or dry rot among them. And
                                this is not to be accomplished by desultory or intermittent efforts of the will, but by
                                the formation of habits. No doubt the will has sometimes to put forth its strength to
                                strangle or crush a special temptation; but the formation of right habits is essential
                                to your permanent security. They diminish your chance of falling when assailed, and they
                                augment your chance of recovery when overthrown.</p></div3><div3 type="home" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To those who dislike the odor of burned grease..." TEIform="index"/>To those who dislike the odor of burned grease...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">To those who dislike the odor of burned grease, or find their digestion too delicate to
                                bear it, can, by using beeswax instead of the grease, obviate the above
                                disagreeableness. They will find their cakes, when cooked on a griddle prepared with the
                                beeswax, a nicer brown, and they will turn with no trouble. </p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker dietetics" TEIform="index"/>Shaker dietetics
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Shaker dietetics. Their diet is simple, but sufficient. Pork is never eaten,
                                        and only a part of the Shaker people eat any meat at all. Many use no food
                                        produced by animals ; denying themselves even butter, milk and eggs. At Mount
                                        Lebanon, and in some of the other societies, two tables are set, one with, the
                                        other without meat. They consume much fruit, eating it at every meal; and they
                                        have always fine and extensive vegetable gardens and orchards. Father Evans (the
                                        Shakers call him Elder Evans, but we like Father better), now about 70 years old
                                        and at the head of one branch of the Shaker community at Lebanon, has not eaten
                                        flesh for nearly forty years, and he is hale and hearty; 62 <pb n="63" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/>
                                        THE SHAKEN. 63 much more so than most men of his age ; yet when he commenced his
                                        vegetable diet he was in a declining state of health ; as he tells us, "a
                                        candidate for consumption."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Herald of health" TEIform="index"/>Herald of Health.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What posterity will think" TEIform="index"/>What posterity will think.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">"Our enlightened posterity will look back upon us who eat oxen and sheep just
                                        as we look back upon cannibals." So says the late Winwood Reade, in his essay on
                                        "The Future of the Human Race." There are several other practices they will
                                        perhaps look back upon with a slight disgust. One is war, one intemperance, and
                                        one licentiousness. Hurry up, oh, good time coming! if you want us to enjoy jour
                                        delightful society.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Herald of health" TEIform="index"/>Herald of Health.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="'Marbleized iron' ware gives off lead, and sometimes arsenic..." TEIform="index"/>'Marbleized iron' ware gives off lead, and sometimes arsenic...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Professor Brewer, of the Sheffield Scientific School, in New Haven, Conn., by a chemical
                                analysis, has confirmed the assertion that the so-called "marbleized iron" ware gives
                                off lead, and sometimes arsenic, when used for cooking sour fluids or fruits, and he
                                says that its use is deleterious to health.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>BOOK TABLE</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Radical review" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian unions extra" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Truth seeker collection" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">The Radical Review : This is a large, quarterly magazine, claiming as its intention, "
                                the thorough, fearless and impartial discussion of all sides pertaining to human
                                welfare." If it carries out this intention thoroughly, it must needs have the support of
                                an inexhaustible bank of funds, for there is not yet sufficient sympathy for those who
                                would promulgate radical truths, to maintain a magazine of such magnitude ; and it is
                                difficult for us to see at present a willingness on the part of many to have radical
                                truths affect or interfere with their present course of very desirable selfishness. When
                                men and women are anxious to learn truth, and to apply it practically, so that the
                                "golden rule" will be noticeably operative, then, and then only, can radically truthful
                                periodicals obtain even a living support. </p><p TEIform="p">The Christian Union Extras are very neatly executed pamphlets, and are filled with choice
                                thoughts upon the subjects they treat of. Four have been issued. The'last number treats
                                of the "Russo-Turkish War," and gives information about both nations, cause of the war,
                                and the probabilities for the ft ture, which would be obtained with difficult elsewhere.
                                Address the above, 27 Park place New York City. </p><p TEIform="p">The Truth Seeker Collection : D. IV Bennett, publisher, 141 Eighth street, New York. To
                                many, in this age of intelligence the old forms, collects, prayers, hymns anc
                                benedictions, between the covers of the "Boo of Common Prayer," and verses for churc
                                use, are very stale and unprofitable. Her we have presented, forms of the above, wit
                                musical arrangement of verses, that are su ficiently iconoclastic to serve the purposes
                                o the most unpopular dissenter. S. R. Wells &amp; Co., of New York, send t us a
                                printed discourse of Rev. S. H. Pratt, A M., upon the " Responsibility of Parentage. It
                                is a most fitting rebuke to the progenitor of a deteriorating race, and we would tha
                                those engaged in such worldly business woul read this discourse and regard it. " Alone,
                                yet not alone," is a prett hymn from John Church &amp; Co., Cincinnat Ohio. The
                                poetry is admirable ; but we are still more pleased with the musical compo sition and
                                arrangement, which exhibit extra ordinary talent in this line. The latter ar the
                                artistic labors of our rising young frienc John C. DeBaun, son of our esteemed neigh
                                bor, H. DeBaun, of Wiskayuna, N. Y. A neat contrivance for pointing out text n the Bible
                                without marking the page with pencil or ink, is the " Bible Verse Indicator," which Eben
                                Shute, of 36 Bromfield street, Boston, offers for sale in sets of twelve for 25 ents. It
                                is a light metallic finger point, to t on to the edge of the page to be marked; n
                                improvement, in its lightness, on a simar article formerly in use.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Signs of the times" TEIform="index"/>SIGNS OF THE TIMES</head><p TEIform="p">Believers in a new religion, called Moranism, are gathering in Walla Walla, Washington
                            Territory, in expectation of a second coming of Christ. In marrnage we begin by knowing
                            little and believing much, and often end by inverting the quantities.—Geo. Eliot. A writer
                            on horticulture, in the Boston Traveller, points out that the culture of humanity advances
                            with equal step with the culture of fruits, vegetables, and flowers. He argues that as
                            agriculture banished cannibalism, an improved horticulture will result in more nutritious
                            fruits and vegetables, so that a diet of fish, flesh or fowl, which is only a few removes
                            from cannibalism, will give place to a fruit and vegetable diet. This, he says, will develop
                            a finer strength of body and brain, sober all the raging passions of humanity into peace,
                            and cause men to look upon war, and the shedding of the blood of the lower animals, as
                            relics of barbarism. The rumor is current that the queen has a horror of war, and has said
                            so to Lord Beaconsfield, her prime minister, and that she is averse to taking any part in
                            the conflict between Russia and Turkeyv—Christian Intelligencer. It is reported in a German
                            newspaper that Russia is about to abolish her usury laws, and leave borrowers and lenders to
                            contract for the rate of interest to be paid on money according to their own discretion,
                            simply fixing a rate, where none has been agreed upon. This is the sensible view adopted by
                            Englanc and some of the states in this country. In striving for perfection of character, le
                            us remember to nourish the moral sensibility that makes us ashamed of indifference or dis
                            like towards any human being. Let us in tensify the sentiment of human brotherhood and
                            insist on the sacredness of the universa family tie, in the faith that they will at length
                            produce the same sensitiveness to dishono and reproach when vice stains any human being, the
                            same joy and hope when virtue crowns any human being, that we now fee' when vice debases or
                            virtue exalts any of ou own personal kin.—Netv Age. War is cruel, very inhuman, barbarous
                            and in the late rebellion there was much bru tality on both sides.—President Hayes. "The
                            battle-cry has been heard, O God, and hostile nations have already confronted each other and
                            begun the fierce work of destruction and bloodshed. WTho will arrest the evil? Who can?
                            Almighty God, thou alone canst humble nations to the dust and dissuade them from bloody
                            deeds. We humbly look up to thee and pray that hostilities may cease and peace may prevail
                            once more in Europe." We do not find the above prayer in a Christian paper, but in the
                            Calcutta organ of one of the Hindu religions which have most felt the influence of the
                            religion of Jesus. We reverently say, Amen.—New JToj'k Independent. " What a fine-looking
                            thing is war! Yet, dress it as we may, dress and feather it, daub it with gold, huzza after
                            it, and sing swaggering songs about it—what is it but murder in iniform,—Cain taking the
                            sergeant's shill- i ng?"—Douglas yerr old. Dr. Blauvelt, a very talented minister of he
                            Reformed church has been finally deposed or heresy. Personally and socially he had the
                            entire sympathy of the Synod, which ignorng any inspiration not laid down in its church
                            catechism, advertised its own bigotry, and its persecuting spirit, by its action upon
                            Blauvelt, because he regarded the Old Testament as of no binding force on Christians of of
                            the present day. The teachings of the Apostles he regards more advisory than mandatory. The
                            form of doctrines commonly mown as Christianity he does not regard as necessarily synonymous
                            with evangelical religion ; although he admits that the two may go together, and sometimes
                            do. He does not reject the divinity of Christ, nor the doctrine of a future state of rewards
                            and punishment. We could wish that the gifted Bishop Coxe lad not written that crusaders'
                            song. In fact, we do wish it. He has done other things much better. He has done nothing
                            ¦worse. God help the Russ! God bless the Czar! Shame on the swords that trade can mar! Shame
                            on the laggards, faint and far, That rise not to the holy war. To arms ! to arms ! The Cross
                            our star. The Cross a star?—that will never do, Bishop. But it is only a minor defect. There
                            are other and more serious ones.—Christian at Work. It is curious how much science just now
                            does for an attack, and how little for defence. If only the development of humanity kept
                            pace with the improvements in the art of war! In an elaborate article, in June Evolution G.
                            W. Cook argues the origin of Christianity to be an outgrowth of perfected Judaism. This is
                            another evidence of the growth of Shaker ideas outside of our societies. We have long held
                            that Judaism was the proper school to introduce Christianity to souls, anc now Cook writes :
                            "In fact, in every direction Christianity was a natural evolution from Judaism, as
                            influenced by Greek, and other thought." Hundreds and thousands are flocking to Shaker
                            testimony.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>DOMESTIC ECONOMY</head><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cucumber pickles" TEIform="index"/>CUCUMBER PICKLES</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">In answer to B. G. H. in Country Gen tleman of May 10th, I would say that
                                        from twenty years' experience I find the quickes and most sure method of
                                        pickling cucumbers by the quantity or less is thus: For one hundred cucumbers,
                                        say about three or foui inches long, take one pint of salt and sprinkle ' over
                                        them (for larger ones, more salt is re quired, or longer standing in the
                                        brine—say forty-eight hours) in tubs, having ready boil ing water to pour over
                                        them sufficient to cover them well. Let them stand twenty-four hours, stirring
                                        occasionally that all may be : affected by the brine, then wipe dry, and pack in
                                        stone jars. Scald your "spices to your taste" in the vinegar, and pour over ¦
                                        hem hot; lay a plate over them to keep them all under the vinegar. Now paste two
                                        pieces : of factory cloth together, and then paste this over the neck of the jar
                                        securely, to keep from the air. Place them in the cellar where they will not be
                                        injured by the frost, anc your pickles will keep two years (if sealed) as well
                                        as one, and hard and crispy. I use red pepper and horseradish, and sometimes add
                                        one cupful of brown sugar to the jar which improves it much. I have found this 1
                                        a much easier way than salting them dowi ¦ and freshening in the winter. Try
                                        them 1 once and you will again. N. B.—Use noth ing but pure cider vinegar, as
                                        manufactured 7inegars will not preserve fruit for any length of time, and for
                                        cucumbers in particular; nothing but pure cider vinegar will keep them good. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Country gentleman" TEIform="index"/>Country Gentleman</bibl></cit></p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W in</byline></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Remedy for insect bites" TEIform="index"/>REMEDY FOR INSECT BITES</head><p TEIform="p">When a mosquito, flea, gnat, or other noxious insect, punctures the human skin, it
                                deposits or injects an atom of an acidulous fluid of a poisonous nature. The results are
                                irritation, a sensation of tickling, itching, or of pain. The tickling of flies we are
                                comparatively indifferent about; but the itch produced by a flea, or gnat, or other
                                noisome insect, disturbs our serenity, and, like the pain of a wasp or a bee sting,
                                excites us to a remedy. The best remedies for the sting of insects are those which will
                                instantly neutralize this acidulous poison deposited in the skin. These are either
                                ammonia or borax. The alkaline reaction of borax is scarcely yet safficiently
                                appreciated. However, a time will come when its good qualities will be known, and more
                                universally valued than ammonia, or, as it is commonly termed, "hartshorn." The solution
                                of borax for insect bites is made thus : Dissolve one ounce borax in one pint of water
                                that has been boiled and allowed to cool. Instead of plain water, distilled rosewater,
                                elder, or orange-flower water, is more pleasant. The bites are to be dabbed with the
                                solution so long as there is any irritation. For bees' or wasps' stings, the borax
                                solution may be made of twice the above strength. In every farmhouse this solution
                                should be kept as a household remedy.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Piesse, S." TEIform="persName"/>S. Piesse</byline></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If your room needs deodorizing..." TEIform="index"/>If your room needs deodorizing...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">If your room needs deodorizing, or a change of air seems very desirable therein, throw
                                open the windows for a few moments, and burn on the stove-hearth, or over the
                                lamp-chimney on some metal substance, a lump of sugar as large as a hickory-nut. Almost
                                any one unfamiliar with this method, will be most agreeably suprised at the result. </p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is a fact, seldom realized..." TEIform="index"/>It is a fact, seldom realized...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">It is a fact, seldom realized by those engaged in the culinary department, that any fruit
                                that is fully ripe, is materially damaged in flavor, and as a food, by cooking. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Some one has lately tried to make us believe..." TEIform="index"/>Some one has lately tried to make us believe...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Some one has lately tried to make us believe, that considerable of the acridity of life
                                is dispelled by letting in additional sunlight into our apartments, and dropping an
                                extra lump of sugar into our tea. Let us try it.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>AGRICULTURAL</head><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Weeds" TEIform="index"/>WEEDS</head><p TEIform="p">Among the earliest plants to start in arable ground are weeds, and the presence of weeds
                                is more or less indicative of slovenly farming. But what is a weed? inquires one. As
                                good a definition as can be given is : A plant out of place; or, in other words, every
                                plant different from the crop under cultivation, and growing therewith to its detriment.
                                Weeds are propagated in two ways, to wit: by seeds and roots. To the former sort belong
                                annuals and biennials, and to the latter, perennials. Professor Buckman, of the
                                Cirenster College, England, discovered in a pint of clover seed, 7000 weed seeds ; in a
                                pint of cow-grass seed, 12,000; in broad clover, 39,440; and two pints of clover seed
                                yielded, one 25,560, and the other 70,400 weed seeds. These statements show the
                                neceesity for care in buying clover seed. The same necessity for care in purchasing
                                grains and grass seeds is manifest, as shown in reference to clover seeds. The above
                                professor counted four thousand seeds ripened by one plant of charlok, or "wild turnip,"
                                as the weed is sometimes called by farmers. The stinking chamomile, a single plant of it
                                produced 36,000 seeds, and a burdock 26,000, and a plant of common dock 17,000 seeds.
                                These few specimens show with what wonderful <pb n="64" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> prolificness weeds
                                furnish seeds for propagation. Thistles, and some other kinds of weeds, furnish winged
                                seeds, which are scattered by the wind. No farmer should suffer such plants to go to
                                seed. Another way of propagating weeds, is by putting the cuttings of hedges and other
                                waste places into the compost heaps. Such are some of the ways of propagating weeds. As
                                prevention is better than cure, exercise it when and where it can be done; but be sure
                                and eradicate weeds in the garden and the field. </p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We have seen the value of sowing rye..." TEIform="index"/>We have seen the value of sowing rye...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">We have seen the value of sowing ryeamong corn, after it has received its last hoeing and
                                hilling. Ihe value is twcFirst, where the rye is sown thickty, no weeds can supersede
                                it; and when the crop is harvested, and ere the ground freezes, a good coating of green
                                manure is thus furnished, to be turned under. Farmers are getting wise in the knowledge
                                that a heavy green crop for turning under is by far the cheapest method of manuring
                                farms well. </p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Here are a couple of items worthy of being told..." TEIform="index"/>Here are a couple of items worthy of being told...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Here are a couple of items worthy of being told. Farmers who have tested them say they
                                are effectual as good scarecrows : The best scarecrow is a suspended lookingglass. Take
                                two small, cheap mirrors, fasten them back to back, attach a cord to one angle, i
                                elastic pole. When the glass swings in the wind, the sun's rays are reflected all over
                                the field, even if it be a large one, and even the oldest and bravest of crows will
                                depart precipitately should one of its lightning flashes fall on him. The second plan,
                                although a terror to crows, is especially well suited to fields subjected to the inroads
                                of small birds, and even chickens. It involves an artificial hawk made from a big potato
                                and long goose and turkey feathers. The maker can exercise his imitative skill in
                                sticking the feathers into the potato so that they resemble the spread wings and tail of
                                the hawk. It is astonishing what a ferocious bird of prey can be constructed from the
                                above simple material. It only remains to hang the object from a tall bent pole, and the
                                wind will do the rest. The bird will make swoops and dashes in the most headlong and
                                threatening manner. Even j the most inquisitive of venerable hens have been known to
                                hurry rapidly from its dangerous vicinity, while to small birds it carries unmixed
                                dismay.—Scientific American.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christ's sufferings" TEIform="index"/>CHRIST'S SUFFERING'S</head><p TEIform="p">Canterbury, N. H. 1. When sorrowing in spirit, O do we think of one, Whose soul o'erflowed
                            with 2. Thus did their friendship wither, and sympathy depart, While He, their Lord and
                            anguish, yet, suffered it alone? For ev'ry friend forsook Him in that most trying Master,
                            alone endured the smart. Bereft of His disci pies, a smitten and stricken spot And they
                            whose love seemed strongest, declared they knew Him not, Declared one, Yet bowed in sweet
                            submission,— could say, "Thy will be done," Could they knew Him not, And they whose love
                            seemed strongest, Declared they knew Him not. say "Thy will be done," Yet bowed in sweet
                            submission,— Could say "Thy will be done," 3. And who has ever fathomed such keenness of
                            distress, Or who has ever tasted the depths of bitterness ; Like Him who cried in anguish,
                            and sorest agony, "My God !- My God !- why is it, Thou hast forsaken me?" 5. Let us be
                            likewise able to show forgiving love, With wisdom of the serpent, and mildness of the dove :
                            Thus prove ourselves true members of Christ, the heavenly Root, Producing in abundance, the
                            blessed gospel fruit. 4. Remember 'twas our Savior who drank this bitter cup, And gave both
                            soul and body, a willing offering up ; Whose voice in pitying accents, for persecutors too,
                            Was heard to say, "Forgive them, they know not what they do. 6. Then, never fear, my
                            brother, though seemingly alone ; And grow not sad, my sister, when heavy sorrows come.
                            Since our dear Savior suffered,—we can endure the rod; And tribulation leads us, the lovely
                            road to God.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>EVERGREEN SHORES</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dewitt, Alluri" TEIform="index"/>Alluri Dewitt
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Union Village, Ohio, May 13, 1877, <persName reg="Dewitt, Alluri" TEIform="persName">Alluri
                                Dewitt</persName>, aged 73 years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hathaway, Abigail" TEIform="index"/>Abigail Hathaway
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., May 29, 1877, <persName reg="Hathaway, Abigail" TEIform="persName">Abigail
                                Hathaway</persName>, aged 56 years.</p></div3></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>