<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1005" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">10</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">5</biblScope><date value="18800501" TEIform="date">May 1880</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">97-120</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="10" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="5" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                <pb id="p1"/>
                    <p> MANIFESTO. (OFFICIAL, MONTHLY.) G. A. LOMAS, EDITOR, SHAKERS, N. Y. Published by the United Societies. OUR HOME AT
                        HARVARD, MASS. "And they shall turn to you for a testimony:" *' Go preach the Kingdom of God I " ADDRESS ALL
                        COMMUNICATIONS TO " The Shaker Manifesto, Shakers, N.D.' G. B. AVERY, PUBLISHER, 1880. Vol. X. No. 5. MAY, 1880. 60
                        Cents Per Annum The Shaker </p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --><pb n="97" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sow what we would reap" TEIform="index"/>SOW WHAT WE WOULD REAP</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Erickson, Larz" TEIform="persName"/>LARZ ERICKSON</byline><p TEIform="p"> It appears to be one of the most difficult accomplishments for us to acknowledge our faults,
                            just as they are. We seem ever determined to make our own side of the case appear better
                            than we would look upon the same in our neighbors. If we would dear with other's faults as
                            we would deal with our own, or have others deal with our own, it would result in a blessed
                            experience. We know we do not like that others should speak evil of us, yet are we as
                            careful not to do so by others ? If we have any reasonable anticipation of a residence with
                            the redeemed, we had better learn to practice the habits of the redeemed here, and strive
                            for the highest good and welfare of our fellows, by the most charity, forbearance and
                            forgiveness of their faults. But we can never approach the condition of the redeemed, if we
                            make the best of our own faults and the worst of those of our associates. If we do not like
                            to be faulted, let us get thoroughly rid of a faultfinding spirit. If we sow words and deeds
                            of kindness, we will rejoice in the time of our harvest. Let us think of this, and let us
                            sow love and respect, ceasing to sow evil and entertaining malice, and just as surely we
                            will reap the rewards of our sowing. Perhaps there are but few who would willingly reap what
                            they carelessly sow, therefore, let us guardedly sow only the good and reap the heavens.
                            Pleasant Hill, Ky.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Character" TEIform="index"/>CHARACTER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL ORCUTT</byline><p TEIform="p"> Defects in character, though concealed for a time, will appear. It cannot be otherwise. The
                            characters of many persons present a damaged appearance, because the foundations are not
                            laid deep enough. The superstructure of character is important; the foundation is more
                            important. An enduring character cannot be built upon an unstable basis. The character that
                            will stand the shocks of time and endure forever must be founded on Christ, the chief corner
                            stone. "Other foundations can no man lay than is laid, which is Jesus Christ." Complete
                            thoroughness in forming the basis of a true Christian character is the essential feature.
                            Look well to the foundation. " Better be sure than sorry." It is by self-denying struggles,
                            and a conscience void of offense, that we establish characters for uprightness. Practicing
                            the true and pure makes us so in daily life. Bad habits, which <pb n="98" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 98 THE
                            SHAKEK MANIFESTO. produce bad characters, creep on apace un til from an occasional
                            indulgence they grow to be a ruling power, and if persisted in will wreck the immortal soul!
                            As the tempest hurls the avalanche down the mountain, and overwhelms the inhabitants, so
                            passions, acting upon the elements which bad habits have accumulated, overthrow the
                            principles of truth and virtue. " Better suppress the first wrong desire than try to satisfy
                            all that follow it." If the heart is open to a " small vice," a great one may enter. Small
                            things have a telling influence on character; they make or unmake us all. " Take care of the
                            thoughts and the actions will take care of themselves." A wrong thought or a wrong
                            principle, once taken root in the mind, may scatter its offspring through the whole region
                            of the soul. A little thought is often a mighty instrument, and like the tongue, it may be
                            the cause of a world of evil, or a world of good. " Habits are second natures," and they are
                            continually forming like solid masonry. Thoughts and actions seem small, as bricks seem
                            small. In a brick house, small as bricks are,one by one laid day by day, the walls have
                            thickened, solidified, and risen to a huge structure. Our lives are made up of thoughts and
                            actions, any one of which may seem small, but the multitude of which are like bricks in the
                            hands of the builder. The walls of our characters are going up daily, and we are building,
                            not alone for time, but for eternity. Then how important that we maintain a sleepless,
                            watch, and carefully guard each thought and action. Enfield, Conn.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Living waters" TEIform="index"/>LIVING WATERS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cornell, Jane" TEIform="persName"/>JANE CORNELL</byline><p TEIform="p"> Give us, dear Lord, that living water Which thou didst offer to Samaria's daughter Thirsting
                            we cry ; All other streams to quench this thirst we've sought; Not one of them did e'er
                            avail us aught To satisfy. Vain pleasure, too, hath filled her chalice up And to our lips
                            the world hath held the cup, And we did drink. Until an angel touched our eyes with light,
                            And in the draught we saw sin's deadly blight, And back did shrink. And those who deepest
                            drank the tempting draught, Who to the dregs, almost, the cup have quaffed, Now thirst the
                            more. And to thy fount now press with eager hope ; Lord, on these thirsty *ouls the
                            flood-gates ope — The waters pour. We know Salvation's streams are free to all; For we have
                            heard thy loving, gracious call, Bidding us come ; But, Lord, our wanderings have made us
                            weak; Thy wells are deep ; and we thine aid must seek ; Help us to draw. Do thou in love our
                            empty vessels fill, That we may drink and feel the inward thrill New life doth bring. For in
                            the soul these waters pure shall swell Into a clear, deep, everlasting well — A living
                            spring. Shakers, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Explanatory" TEIform="index"/>EXPLANATORY</head><p TEIform="p">Beloved Editor, G. A. Lomas : I have the pleasure of sending to you the enclosed
                            communication from one of our aged mothers in Israel, who, although 87 years of age and
                            feeble in body, is yet bright and beautiful in spirit. She has a growing interest in all
                            that is good and pure. She is an interested and constant reader of The Manifesto — a lover
                            of truth, with whom there are " no backward steps, no halting between two opinions," her
                            spirit reaches upward, and twining around the sturdy oak of our faith, she lives for the
                            good she can do, and not for herself alone. As the blossom sends up its sweet incense, so
                            there arises from such souls the blessings of veterans in the cause, and surrounded by
                            angels they have left the thorny paths of life to walk in the gardens of Paradise ever more.
                            I am, your sister,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Gillespie, Mary A." TEIform="persName"/>Mary A. Gillespie</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Veteran's blessings" TEIform="index"/>A VETERAN'S BLESSINGS</head><p TEIform="p">Dearly Beloved in the Lord. In the year 1877, in the sixth month, I felt to bless those who
                            had taken such a deep interest in the publication of " The Shaker " as it was then called,
                            and I wished also to leave upon record my Life Testimony ; the same appeared in the July
                            Number. I have now been taking a little review of <pb n="99" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO.
                            99 the past year 1879, as written out in our " Shaker Manifesto," and I find so much to
                            admire, I hardly know where to begin or how to address you. In turning the pages of this
                            small, yet beautiful book, my eye rested upon these words : " No Backward Steps," November
                            Number, 1878 ; and so deeply did they impress me that I again read the article, while I said
                            in my heart, as 1 had many times before : '' God bless the writer." I am aware that change
                            is written upon every thing of an earthly nature ; and why should it be otherwise in the
                            Heavenly World ? Is not truth the great moving power of to-day ? And are not the angels of
                            conviction abroad in the land working toonders in the hearts of the people ? Blessed are
                            they who receive and obey their teachings. Though the car of progress moves slowly, yet the
                            rolling of its wheels is sure. The Lord is in it. Well may we sing with the poet: — " Down
                            from the heavens, Comes sweet inspiration ; Molding, and holding, Our lives to truth and
                            love." We call ourselves " Children of the Resurrection." Are we resurrected from dead
                            works? Have we risen with Christ ? Do we walk in newness of life ? Do we take " no backward
                            steps 1" If we are thus living, then are we being created anew in the likeness of Our
                            Heavenly Parents ? Grand and noble principles remain with us. Let us be true to them and
                            keep our faith unmarred to the end of the journey. Dear brethren and sisters I sometimes
                            fear that in our anxiety to become bright and beautiful, we shall miss the mark. May we not
                            so far blend with a wordly sense and spirit as to lose sight of ourselves, and of our sacred
                            calling. Let us not be guided nor led by a wordly pride, nor selfish ambition ; neither let
                            us try to ape the vain fashions of the world. We are called to be a plain people. We want to
                            be Christians ; Christ-like, angel-like, plain in our dress, honest in our lives, and
                            cleanly in all things. The wise founders of our faith laid down their selfish lives at the
                            foot of the cross, and is it not through their continued prayers and cries unto God, that we
                            are made able to call this goodly inheritance ours f The prayer which they prayed was : "
                            Thy will O Father not ours be done." It was an earnest prayer, so deep and so fervent, that
                            it reached the Throne, and the angels heard and answered it. 0, the sweet and heavenly
                            ministrations which we often realize in our seasons of devotion, when those dear departed
                            ones, who have long since entered the pearly gates into the Holy City, return to us on their
                            missions of love, laden with peace, joy and comfort! Such the world know not of; they come
                            to us with songs of gladness such as the angels sing to cheer the heart of the weary
                            pilgrim. Blessed spirits ! come nearer and help us to be more angel-like ; inspire us with
                            your heavenly influence, that we may be more and more like our Divine Master. We claim to be
                            followers of Him, who trod the wine press alone ; let us see to it that we walk as he walked
                            ; that we deny ourselves as he did ; of all ungodliness and every worldly lust; we shall
                            then take " No Backward Steps," but In the Master's service working, For the Holy Spirit
                            yearning, There will be no backward turning With the true Believer. Jesus said," I came not
                            to do my own will, but the will of my Father who sent me." '•' Search the scriptures, for in
                            them ye think ye have eternal life." I love to read the bible. We may learn much from those
                            sacred histories, but the New Testament (to my mind) is more clear and better adapted to our
                            real needs. " What shall it profit a man though he gain the whole world and lose his own
                            soul ? Or what shall he give in exchange for his soul ? " We may have riches, but how often
                            these take to themselves wings and fly away ! We may have honors and worldly applause, but
                            what's in a name ? The world may speak words of flattery, and in this may seek to blind our
                            eyes and lead us captive ; but let us keep an eye single, that we may see the glory of God,
                            and that our whole body may be full of light. Let us beware of false prophets, who strive to
                            insinuate their strange doctrines. Believe them not, truth and false- <pb n="100" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/>
                            100 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. hood cannot blend. All who preach God and him glorified, Christ
                            and him crucified, will preach truth. While those who advocate the doctrines of self-love,
                            and cry aloud, " Come down from the cross (self denial) and we will believe on you," are
                            deceivers, and sooner or later they will be compelled to "Tear off the Mask" of hypocrisy
                            and appear in their true light. 0 may ice walk worthy of our calling and abide the cleansing
                            fire of truth, which burns brighter and clearer each day, is the fervent prayer of your aged
                            friend, for all Zion's children from Maine to Kentucky. It is ours to sing of the triumphs
                            and glories of the higher life. Ours to tell the story of God's boundless love, and ours to
                            wear the conqueror's crown, set with ten thousand stars all aglow with brightness and
                            beauty. We are not mistaken, we know the Lord is on our side. We have given our little all
                            without any selfish reserve. The question is often asked, what would become of the world if
                            all were Shakers ? Were it not better that it should come to an end by men and women who
                            seek to live pure and peaceable lives, than that the Lord should be necessitated to send
                            judgments upon the earth to destroy a large portion of its inhabitants ? The cry of famine
                            in far off lands has reached our ears, children begging for bread and dying for the want of
                            it. In our daily papers we read of wars and rumors of wars, while thousands are stricken
                            down by pestilence or fall by the sword ; fires and floods lay waste great cities ; vessels
                            are wrecked upon the stormy ocean; "many go down to the sea in ships," but the voyage is one
                            fraught with perils and dangers, and instead of returning again to home and friends, they
                            pass beyond the veil. What meaneth all this? Let us consider and be wise. How shall these
                            plagues be stayed ? Let us walk in humility and seek the mercy of God. " Blessed are the
                            pure in heart for they shall see God. Blessed are the peacemakers for they shall be called
                            the children of God." Purity and peace dwell together, and all wars and fightings cease in
                            Christ's pure and peaceable kingdom. Let us have peace. Now, my precious friends, I have
                            written at some length, but I can bless every one who has a desire to be and do good. I am
                            with you in the strife. This earthly Jife of mine is nearly finished, as I have already
                            lived four score and seven years, but my soul is in the work. 1 shall never die. I have kept
                            sacred my early vows of consecration to the Lord, and when my sun of life shall have set for
                            the last time here, I shall go home to my spirit friends and dwell in that beautiful city,
                            where never any die. Yours in gospel love, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hurd, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>Anna Hurd, 87 years of age.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Virgin life is not contrary to law, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>A VIRGIN LIFE IS NOT CONTRARY
                            TO LAW No. 2</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL FRASER</byline><p TEIform="p"> In the great book of Creation, which God has opened wide for all to see and read, there are
                            but few facts of more importance to us, or more closely connected with our existence, than
                            that there is a time to sow, and a time to reap. And we all know that the object of sowing
                            is not that we may merely sow again, but that we may appropriate the greater part to our own
                            use for higher purposes than mere propagation. Jesus read carefully his Father's book ; had
                            he not done so, he would not have been able to have opened up the nature of his own kingdom.
                            The whole scope of Christ's teachings sustains the conclusion, that the natural world is but
                            a figure of the spiritual. The parables are all drawn from natural objects, and from the
                            common actions of men ; every one of them is a casket containing a gem illustrative of some
                            heavenly thing. Even the fleeting clouds, and colors of the sky he called into requisition.
                            When the south wind blows ye say it will be warm, when the sky is red and lowering ye say
                            there will be foul weather, and it cometh to pass; cannot ye then discern the signs of the
                            times ? " The harvest is the end of the world, the angels are the reapers, and ye are they
                            on whom the ends of the world have come" — the end of lust, pride and <pb n="101" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/>
                            THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 101 worldly ambition in the spirits of those whom the Father draws —
                            ripens up, and whom the angels can harvest. Now what do men reap? They reap grain, grain
                            contains the elements of muscle, bone, nerve, etc. When grain is gathered home the process
                            of threshing begins, then comes the fan. " This fan is in his hand, and he will thoroughly
                            purge his floor," and nothing is left but the grain — the elements of the bodies of the
                            reapers; in short, they have been reaping something like themselves. So they " on whom the
                            ends of the world have come"— have ripened up, to whom the religions of the world are as
                            chaff, and the churches thereof respond not to their wants, nor answer to their aspirations
                            after a religion that knows no guile, is as pure as the heavens, and as benign in its
                            operation as is the spirit of the Saviour. Blessing when cursed, and doing good when evil is
                            present; forbearing from war, hatred and strife : and where the great are only great in the
                            service of goodness ; such can the angels gather. As the husbandman in gathering grain
                            gathers the elements of his own body, so in the harvest of the world, the angels gather
                            those who are like themselves — human spirits in whom the elements of angelic life are
                            quickened, who are no longer of the world, cut off from it; as evidence thereof, they
                            neither marry, nor are given in marriage ; forming an angelic order of human society. God,
                            the center of their affections, and in loving that which is of God in one another, they love
                            Him. The signs of the times are indications of coming events, and no great discernment is
                            required to perceive that vast numbers, form, ing an important element in society,are
                            ripening up to a fitness for a higher life than the world affords ; and not a few will be
                            ripened up beyond the power of procreative law, and be appropriated to the Master's use ;
                            and instead of multiplying and replenishing, they will be kings and priests unto God and the
                            Lamb. The least of such will be greater than the greatest born of woman. If all things
                            having procreative life were intended to have no other use than again to multiply
                            themselves, then the law of multiplication would subordinate every other law. Should such be
                            the case, this world would be a scene of the wildest confusion ; grains could not be
                            digested, they would grow because they were made to multiply, and for no other purpose ;
                            they would sprout in the stomach, throw out leaves in the duodenum and take root elsewhere.
                            Those who have but the one idea, that man and woman were made to multiply,and for no higher
                            purposes, may carry out the absurdity. In the very nature of things, the law or power to
                            procreate must be subordinate to the not momentary, but permanent, happiness of the parties
                            concerned, and of the race. That hereditary and moral diseases should be entailed cannot for
                            a moment be entertained as being agreeable to the will of God, or that beings claiming to be
                            in the least degree rational, should multiply themselves till their numbers should press so
                            severely on the means. of subsistence, as to utterly preclude a life of physical, moral and
                            spiritual culture is absurd, and irreconcilable with common sense. The social and moral
                            relationships of man, as well as the nature of things, teach and impress the sons and
                            daughters of Adam, with a view of the absolute necessity of approximating to a virgin life,
                            if they would escape misery and destitution. In full view of these facts, is it not
                            marvelous that when the ends of the world have come upon a few souls, and they follow Christ
                            — are harvested from the earthly animal order of humanity into a higher sphere, no more to
                            follow Adam, having progressed beyond his life, manners and desires, that a wide spread,
                            groundless and perhaps hypocritical anxiety should be expressed lest the race should be run
                            out ? But when this continent is being swept of its aboriginal inhabitants by fire-water,
                            the cruel bullet, and communicated diseases — when four millions of Irishmen die from lack
                            of food, and as many more of British subjects in India perish in the same manner, and by the
                            hands of the same men; when half a million of men are destroyed on the field of carnage, or
                            pestilence carries off millions annually, there is no apprehension that the race will be run
                            out, neither are <pb n="102" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 102 THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. there corresponding
                            efforts made to meet these stupendous causes of human suffering and destruction of life.
                            These thoughts lead us to dwell more particularly upon The Population Question. The
                            continually increasing population of the earth has during the past eighty years, from time
                            to time, arrested the attention of thinking men, Malthus, Sadler, Doubleday, Rickordo,
                            Spencer, and lastly, Nathan Allen of Mass. The conflicting conclusions of these authors led
                            Nathan Allen to the conclusion " that a true theory of population had not yet been reached."
                            Before such an array of thoughtful men, we may inquire, may not a solution of this terrible
                            problem be found, first in humanity approximating to, and secondly in entering the higher —
                            the non-generative life ? Certainly it cannot be the destiny of man to be forever under the
                            power of his animal propensities, and governing one another as lions and tigers do. In
                            despite of all the destructive causeg which have swept races, armies and millions of people
                            away, the population of the earth has increased till the number is about one billion four
                            hundred millions. Let this number be doubled geometrically but five times, and there will be
                            more than one person to every available acre of land. In view of such a crisis, would it not
                            be well to pause a little, and inquire whether the earth is peopled according to law. or as
                            lust dictates ? Also whether the inferior animals under the law of instinct are not a great
                            deal nearer their Creator than is man ? In created things the higher the organism, the more
                            of law it is subjected to. Vegetable life involves more law than the inorganic mineral, and
                            the animal kingdom more than the vegetable world. A. being capable of reasoning, capable of
                            receiving knowledge from the past, and of transmitting it to his successors, must in the
                            nature of things be subject to more law than are the brutes. They are subject to times and
                            seasons, so ought man to be subject if he will be just to his offspring and to himself. In
                            addition, he ia required to yield obedience to Providential Law. Providental law is that
                            man, being able to judge of the past, is required to provide for the future. The farmer sows
                            in spring so that he may reap in harvest time ; he-provides in summef.'so that he may,not
                            suffer in winter. So,^also, he arranges before hand to raise _no more stock than he can
                            provide for. Should he double his stock without reference to the yield of his grass lands,
                            or to the seasons/^they being variable, he would find on the approach of winter, after a
                            scanty crop of hay, that he had only fodder enough for about one-half ol nis animals. And
                            the^ farmers all over the country being in the same predicament, infatuated with the'idea,
                            that they must multiply and replenish the earth with animals, otherwise the great primal
                            command would not be obeyed. Under such circumstances, the farmer has no alternative but
                            to'kill off one-half of his stock. Human beings in a like condition, stimulated by the
                            intense selfishness generated by want, would hoard up the grain and aggravate the universal
                            calamity. Famine, violence and pestilence would sweep the earth with the besom of
                            destruction. j/That such calamities will visit the humanfamily is as certain, as that it
                            unlawfully doubles itself. They will not take place all over the earth at once ; but
                            extensive districts as was lately the case in China,* will Selected. * 1877-78. North China.
                            A telegram dated 26th January, 1878, said: "Appalling famine raging throughout four
                            provinces of North China. Nine million people reported destitute. Children daily sold in
                            markets for [raising means to procure] food." Total population of districts affected,
                            70,000,000. Mr. Fred. H.Balfour, of Shanghai, said: " The people's faces are black with
                            hunger; they are dying by thousands upon thousands. Women and girls and boys are openly
                            offered for sale to any chance wayfarer. When I left the country a respectable married woman
                            could be easily bought for six dollars, and a little girl for two. In cases, however, where
                            it was found impossible to dispose of their children, parentshave been known to kill them
                            sooner than witness their prolonged sufferings, in many instances throwing themselves
                            afterwards down wells, or committing suicide by arsenic." The Chinese Government sent a
                            Commissioner to investigate, who said in his report: "' The roads are lined with corpses in
                            such numbers as to distance all efforts for their interment; while women and children,
                            starving and in rags, know not where to look for the means to keep body and soul together."
                            ^5 I have mentioned only b'7 famines out of a total of more than 350, given by Mr. Walford.
                            Many of those which I have passed are characterized as "awful." <pb n="103" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            SHAKER MANIFESTO. 103 feel their overwhelming power ; and as the stream of population
                            deepeas and widens, one crisis will succeed another, and pestilence which always follows
                            famine will finish the work of devastation. The sorrowing remants enshrouded in the gloom of
                            fearful judgments, broken down and dispirited, may learn, that the Moral as well as the
                            Material universe is governed by law. And that our heavenly Father gives unto men, nations
                            and races, according to their works. And that the procreative faculty must be subject to the
                            moral government of Gk&gt;d. Man being a free agent, is called to cooperate with his Creator,
                            being able to act in the whole matter as a voluntary, intelligent and accountable being —
                            able to yield obedience to physiological law as regards himself, moral law as regards
                            others, and divine law — the law of the higher life, when called upon to do so. Instead of a
                            virgin life being contrary to law, it is in perfect accord with the highest of all laws —
                            the law of the spirit of life as it is in Christ Jesus, in whom " are hid all the treasures
                            of wisdom," goodness and knowledge. Even in the natural order of man's existence, a degree
                            of approximation towards a virgin life is an imperative necessity. For if there is no
                            hygienic, nor moral restraint laid upon the propensities, especially the reproductive
                            function, then lust is the law, disease, and moral infirmities will then be propagated, and
                            more population brought forth than can be properly cared for, or made happy, as is now
                            lamentably the case. And ultimately, such destructive culminations as have been alluded to
                            will take place. Indeed, in the procreative order of human society itself, there is a growth
                            towards a celibate condition of a negative kind, as is evident from the history of
                            intellectual men and women. Fourier, in his works on society, gives prominence to this fact
                            ; and a voluminous American author (A. J. Davis), whose personal history is a special fact
                            confirmatory of the growth of humanity towards celibate condition, says: " Down in the lower
                            stratum of society, behold how populous. Rise higher in the scale, and the married have
                            fewer children. Rise still higher, and you can easily believe, that the time will come with
                            such, when reproduction will cease, neither marrying nor giving in'marriage, becoming as
                            angels, having risen above the mission of ^reproduction. Only friends to truth, dare to
                            speak the whole truth on this subject." On this subject we dare speak, indeed, it is our
                            mission, to declare the whole counsel of God, as manifested in our lives, and opened in our
                            testimony. Man as already stated is dual in his nature — can live and have his being in the
                            higher life., "In me (Christ) ye shall have life." When man ascends from the lower—the
                            procreative life, into the higher, then he is the subject of the law of the spirit of that
                            higher life, and not only brings into subjection the propensities, but crucifies the life
                            from whence they come ; as the inferior life dies, so then he can rise with Christ — have
                            life in himself as he had. For further information on the foregoing important subjects I
                            would refer to the Publisher of the " Manifesto.''</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>HOME</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Witham, Maria" TEIform="persName"/>MARIA WITHAM</byline><p TEIform="p"> How many hallowed associations are vividly presented to my mind whenever the beautiful song|
                            " Home, Sweet Home" is pathetically sung in'my hearing ; and it'not only brings up the past,
                            but the impression stands out in clear, bright and ^effulgent rays : What a home I have in
                            Zion ; secure from those trials and temptations that 1 was wont to experience not many years
                            since ; and language of mine can but feebly portray the thankfulness that swells my heart
                            for the privilege to be numbered with the faithful in my Shaker Home. Here I can be
                            preparing for that state which qualifies me to enjoy that eternity to which I am hastening.
                            I desire to appreciate every privilege I am made partaker of- " In my Father's house there
                            are many mansions;" therefore, we can but anticipate a home where kindred spirits will enjoy
                            a hereafter, wherein the home circles formed here will be greatly enlarged. Whatever we may
                            believe that our Heaven or that home 'may be, it is a <pb n="104" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 104 THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. spiritual belief that shapes itself according to our life; a power to grasp and
                            conceive that which is only born of spirit which we may adopt. No revelator can reveal
                            anything to us until 'we are endowed with a spiritual power to comprehend it. Therefore,
                            Jesus reserved what he might have said until those that heard him should become exercised in
                            the three eternities, Faith, Hope and Love. With the assistance of that Divine being whose
                            love knows no bounds, we are preparing ourselves to enjoy that Home "not made with hands,
                            eternal in the Heavens." Enfield, Conn.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spring of life" TEIform="index"/>THE SPRING OF LIFE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hooser, Horntense G." TEIform="persName"/>HORTENSE G. HOOSER</byline><p TEIform="p"> Blessed season ! spring is coming— See the shrubs and flowers all blooming, Bees and insects
                            sweetly humming/ Welcome to the pleasant May. All the trees and forests showing, Nature in
                            her beauties growing ; Streams and rivulets merrily flowing, Down and onward to the sea.
                            Youth, the spring-time of the human, Bud and flower of man and woman, With the seasons are
                            forthcoming, As the hoary heads decay. Youth matured soon take their station, Guide the helm
                            in every nation, Bone and Sinew of creation, But they quickly pass away. The son of course
                            succeeds the Father, The daughter too, survives the Mother, And so races the wide world
                            over, Rise, flourish and decay. This is the law throughout creation, With animals and
                            vegetation; With individuals and with nations They rise, flourish and decay. O'er the broad
                            land wealth is abounding, Food in the valleys, on the mountains, Thro' the air and 'mid the
                            fountains, Life sustaining gifts we share. Let all intelligence and nature, Adore their God,
                            the great Creator, Who thus provides for every creature, Whether in water, earth or air.
                            When mother earth receives her children, Back to the dust whence they were given, The spirit
                            reascends to heaven— To regions where there's no decay. Celestial bands of shining hosts,
                            Give welcome, when they've safely crossed The stream of time.whose waves have tossed Them on
                            the shores of endless day. Pleasant Hill, Ky.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Celibacy or virginity, which?" TEIform="index"/>CELIBACY OR VIRGINITY, WHICH ?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, Elijah" TEIform="persName"/>ELIJAH MYRICK</byline><p TEIform="p"> Man is a series of ascending developments, and every standard of assumed finality is swept
                            away by the increasing light which ever shines on the pathway of progress. God gives to each
                            and every one, A lengthening chain from causes spun. And link by link we do obtain, The
                            knowledge of our Godly chain ; As onward we advancing go. These links will tell how much we
                            know — how much the virgin life links us to the divine. A person may be a celibate in the
                            full significance of the word, and yet lack the essentials of a virgin character. A celibate
                            may be gross, natural, earthly, unspiritual' or living a life of "single blessedness" on the
                            earth plane, blameless, " Good as other people." Virgins are those of whom Jesus said, " If
                            I be lifted up (from the earth plane), I will draw all men unto me" — unto the virgin, the
                            divine life. Thus introduced into the realm of the heavenly, we experience these higher
                            spiritual joys which the earthly man (celibates included), can never realize. The pleasures
                            of nature become sinful to those born into the new, divine life ; to be confessed and shaken
                            off as an incubus which the new fledged spirit cannot carry. Entering this supernal domain,
                            the spiritual affections dominate in a superior relation of fathers and mothers, brothers
                            and sisters — offspring born into the new and living way, such as Jesus recognized as his
                            relation. To stop short of this — to be a celibate merely — is abnormal ; neither natural
                            nor spiritual. Virginity must be the central idea around which cluster the divine graces ;
                            unalloyed by the lusts of our lower natures, selfish aims, and unworthy ambitions. To think
                            by confessing our sins, restraining our lower passions and appetites, and directing our
                            course by the polar star of complete purity, while by undignified manners and absence of
                            humility, we challenge <pb n="105" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 105 the graces which
                            adorn the higher life, we are qualified for heaven, is a delusive error. It is as a garden
                            well fenced, without fruit or flowers. A house without paint, as inward adorning. A
                            sentiment, without the charm of music. The prime essentials to a harmonious household are
                            confidence, respect, affection, and that charity which is kind after long forbearance.
                            These, when well cultivated and trained 'to duty, form a lasting friendship. Christianity,
                            though rough hewn were its pioneers, is not a foe to courteous deportment. Refinement
                            flowers in kind words and acts. It is the perfume of the virgin life. Harvard, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Theology: prentissiana" TEIform="index"/>THEOLOGY: PRENTISSIANA</head><p TEIform="p"> Every age, every race, every nation, every individual, must have a Theology. It is an
                            inherent right. The theology will accord with the mental expansion and the elevation from
                            the animal — the earthy — to the Angelic — the Heavenly. As we climb the ascending grade, we
                            make the sublime discovery that the universe, through every gradation, from the Cherubim —
                            masculine — and SerapMm, — feminine — Angels of the most advanced heavens to which we can
                            stretch our spiritual vision — all the way down through man, animal, vegetable, mineral —
                            all proclaim the Holy Eternal Parentage — Father and Mother the vitalizing centers of all
                            vitality . When, by indomitable, persevering selfdiscipline, we achieve full emancipation
                            from all lower law influences, the Divine Afflatus from the Eternal throne thrills every
                            fiber of our being — the morning stars sing together and the daughters and sons of God shout
                            Amen ! Hallelujah ! No trait of character is more valuable than the possession of a good
                            temper. Home can never be made happy without it. It is like flowers springing up in our
                            pathway, reviving and cheering us. Kind words and looks are the outward demonstrations;
                            patience and forbearance are the sentiments within.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My Dear Albert — The editorial remark in the April Manifesto that ..." TEIform="index"/>My Dear Albert — The editorial remark in the April Manifesto that ...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Sonyea, April 4, 1880" TEIform="index"/>Sonyea, April 4, 1880</dateline><p TEIform="p">My Dear Albert — The editorial remark in the April Manifesto that the number " will be
                                found full of grand articles from talented contributors " is true. But among them all I
                                assign the first place to " Fruits of the Harvest," by O. C. Hampton. Here there is no "
                                beating about the bush," the fittest arrow is chosen from the quiver, and sent direct to
                                the center of the target. The question — What is the gospel of Christ? is answered by a
                                living witness in a manner that shows the priceless value of that gospel. It tallies
                                completely with the old experiences that were published years ago. How much better is
                                this than all the theories that theological argument has ever presented ? I don't know
                                but theoretical speculations may be of value to some minds, but the presentation of
                                absolute truth gained by experience seems to me a thousand fold better. But I did not
                                commence this brief epistle for the purpose of opposing theories, but to express my high
                                appreciation of Bro. Oliver's article, and to express the hope that other similar ones
                                will see the light through the same monthly medium of light, love and wisdom. I
                                congratulate you, dear Albert, on having so many valuable contributors as you have,
                                whose articles show that the " glory of the Lord has arisen." We are all in fair health
                                at the present time. Eld. Lydia is constantly improving, and will probably gain full
                                strength as warm weather advances. As ever, in love,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName"/>Wm. H. Bussell</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We cannot reach men's hearts till..." TEIform="index"/>We cannot reach men's hearts till...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">We cannot reach men's hearts till we can reach their ears. When Jesus uttered that wonderful
                            cry: " If any man thirst, let him come unto me and drink," it was not in the presence of the
                            few that believed in him, but in the great Jewish temple, and on the greatest day of the
                            feast, when the largest concourse was assembled. We also should seek to get the attention of
                            all the people we can. They will not come to us ; therefore we must go to them. If we cannot
                            reach them in one way, we should try another, and another.</p></div2><pb n="106" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Living issues" TEIform="index"/>THE LIVING ISSUES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> "Putting; on Christ" in our daily walk and conversations is Christianity indeed. The day
                                is past, when^the simple profession of faith in [Christ could be relied upon as the
                                insignia of a genuine Christian. " By their works shall thev be known," is now the
                                reasonable and growing demand of the majority of the churches; realizing that there may
                                be much dead faith in a great deal of humanity. "Is he a Christian?" is not now answered
                                by naming the denominational church of which he is a communicant; but the answer is
                                determined, yea or nay, from the intentions and actions of his life. "Joining the church
                                " is well indeed ; and the reasonable intent of such a junction is indicative of a
                                resolution to " put on more of the Christ" life. If the degree of one's Christianity is
                                denoted by the measure of Christ put on in individual life, then he or she is a full
                                Christian only who puts on the whole Christ in their lives, discarding all selfish
                                tendencies, which will not bear a resemblance to the life of Jesus, the Christ. The
                                issues in the Christian strife with human, unregenerate selfishness are living ones—
                                affecting our human lives down deep to their very cores. All the trials of the goodly
                                saint Jesus were based upon his superior Christian faith, and the question whether or
                                not he should obey that progressive faith unto greater righteousness, or live to please
                                himself. It was often a living issue with him — live, under the self-denying restraints
                                of the angelic life, or live as other good Jews lived, very selfishly, compared with
                                Christly directions. We know the result in the case of Jesus. We may know the results in
                                our individual experiences. "How much of a Christian is he r Is she ? " can only be
                                satisfactorily answered by a comparison or contrast with the amount of denial to human
                                selfishness engaged in, and the amount of Christ put on, and lived. Let Christian faith
                                have its proper place and appreciation ; for this prompts us to live more like Christ,
                                and the true, living issue of that faith teaches us all, that we are as far or as near
                                being the followers of Christ — Christians — as we live as Jesus, the Christ lived.
                                Enter we our closets, friends; there let us meet the Christ, face to face with our daily
                                lives ; viewing in him those excellences which are so exalted and adorable to our better
                                and best religious inspirations. See, then and there our inclinations to cling to the
                                earthly, while those of Christ are resurrected to the heavenly. View in that
                                countenance, radiant with all the active, Christian virtues, the virgin purity of the
                                master; the nonresisting, y,nretaliating peaceful exampler; the broad, Umpartial,
                                unsectarian affection for his Tinman relations, regardless of race, color, sex or
                                condition! And let us draw the grandest inference of what our lives should be as
                                Christians, by comparison or contrast of our lives now, with the worldly unspottedness
                                of his every lineament. Faith we may have in abundance that Jesus was very good ; his
                                life was very Christian and best, and thab as his was, so toe wish our lives were; yet,
                                unless we rise to the realization of the grand sequel of hav <pb n="107" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                                SHAKER MANIFESTO. L07 ing our faith and lives agree, we cannot have even the appearance
                                of a genuine Christian about us. Simple, even to the children, is the truly Christian
                                life, for it is living as Christ lived — only this and nothing less nor more. Will not
                                the people see this ? Will not the Churches whose doctrines are made by the people "cry
                                aloud" of this simple truth, this evident Christianity, and "spare not" the sword of the
                                spirit in its excoriations and executions upon selfish, worldly loves and lusts r There
                                is no power on earth nor in heaven that will compel us to be Christians — angelic men
                                and women on earth — but let us not.longer close our eyes in willing blindness, hiding
                                the simple, living issue, that to be a Christian truly, is to live as unworldly as Jesus
                                lived. Better admit we cannot, will not live so ; better ask "to be excused" from all
                                the abnegations which Christ demands of his followers; but let our superior humanity
                                also add its voice in aid of the spread of truth ; and while knowing how Christ lived,
                                how his immediate and faithful followers lived, admit, frankly, that thus living, is
                                only Christianity proper, then listen if we choose and can, with imperturbed feelings,
                                to that indignant, scathing rebuke of the Spirit: " Why call ye me Lord, and do not the
                                things that I say?" . </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Justice to the cook" TEIform="index"/>JUSTICE TO THE COOK</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> The Rev. Joseph Cook, we think, has demonstrated to the world to what unusual depths and
                                heights the human mind can range in reasoning. We know of none whom we can name, so
                                capable of entering so far, and dwelling so long, upon the deepest and almost
                                incomprehensible philosophies pertaining to the religious elements of humanity. Yet
                                while we know this reverend friend has seemingly forgotten hoiv simple was the Christian
                                exampier's life, and that this life was and is Christianity; and while we feared he was
                                unconscionably bigoted, |we lately behold an unexpected nobleness of his nature, in his
                                willingness to investigate, even after his condemnation of the subject of Spiritualism,
                                and in attempting to be just, setting all of his contracted admirers aghast by
                                delivering the folio wins depths of " ifs ": -^ " If both evil and good spirits are
                                around us in modern times, we can understand why they were directed of old to believe
                                not every spirit, but to try the spirits, and to regard not those who have familiar
                                spirits. " If evil spirits may now move the tongues of speaking psychics, we can
                                understand how it was that the serpent said unto the woman, ' Thou shall not surely die
                                !' " If there is modern experience of seeing and even of photographing spirits, we can
                                understand how it was that the eyes of a young man were once opened so that he saw a
                                mountain full of horses of fire and chariots of fire round about Elisha. ' If the hand
                                of the psychic Home burned not in the fire, we can understand how three men once came
                                out of a furnace ; nor was a hair of their heads injured, nor the smell of fire on their
                                garments. " If hands appear among modern psvchical phenomena, we can understand how it
                                was that theAfingers of a man's hand Iwrote on the walls of Belshazzar's 'palace, '
                                Mene, Mene, Tekel, Upharsin.' "If levitation has indeed occurred in moderivtimes, we can
                                understand how Peter was found not, for he was at Azotus, and how one of eld walked on
                                the sea. "If matter can pass through matter, we can understand how One who was raised
                                again <pb n="108" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 108 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. passed through the doors that
                                were shut, and was present with his disciples when they were in an inner room. "If there
                                have been faces which have shone in modern times so as to produce a shadow against the
                                light, we can understand what was meant when it was written that when thine eye is
                                single thy whole body is full of light, and when it was written also that Moses' face
                                shone, and that angels have appeared with faces like lightning, and that onejwho was
                                transfigured was like the sun when he shineth in his strength. "If the followers of
                                Edward Irving and others in modern times have spoken with foreign tongues, then we can
                                understand how at Pentecost every man heard from the apostles the tongue in which he was
                                born. " If prayers are in modern times besought by spirits in a purgatorial state in the
                                next life, we can understand what was meant by preaching to spirits in prison. " If bad
                                spirits are near us in modern times, we can understand how it is that we wrestle not
                                with flesh and blood, but against principalities and powers, against the rulers of the
                                darkness of this world, and against wicked spirits in heavenly places."</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Exampler—redeemer" TEIform="index"/> EXAMPLER — REDEEMER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> A dear friend of ours, a Rev. D. D. neighbor, recently sent us an affectionate note in
                                which this remarkable passage occurs: "You see Jesus, the exampler, may you come to know
                                Jesus Christ, the Redeemer!" Well, friends, are we not really on the right road to this
                                knowledge ? It is, however, an indisputable fact, that the sectarian world, too
                                generally, has overlooked the necessary gradations unto the Christian Redemption ; and
                                most assuredly fails to see that the redemption of the Christ is attainable only,
                                through following the life example of him who became Christ, by reason of his excellent
                                life. The Revelator saw a multitude of ""the redeemed;" and they were " Virgins," as was
                                Jesus; "undefiled" with lusts; "who had come up out of great tribulations, and had
                                washed their robes, making them white, 'in the life of the Lamb" — Christ. We cannot
                                think it an open question: " Can we be redeemed without following the example of Jesus
                                Christ?" We believe this question is closed by the answer: We must live like the Christ
                                before we can know of his redemptions. Is not this true ?</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thanks, friends!" TEIform="index"/>THANKS, FRIENDS!</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> Every one will be or ought to be pleased to know that some kind friends are responding
                                to the request for some simple aid in the wider circulation of The Manifesto. Thanks for
                                such friends, and may they increase. For one dollar, we will circulate one hundred
                                copies to new readers. One such writes us from Florida, thus glowingly: "I have just
                                received your Manifesto; it must be God sent it; I never saw such a paper before!" etc.
                                Who would be more philanthropic than usual, and lend us the aid ?</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kindly notice" TEIform="index"/>KINDLY NOTICE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> The editor of The Manifesto, appreciating the kind invitations to deliver addresses in
                                Albany and Auburn, N. Y., Worcester, Mass., and Philadelphia, Pa., is under the necessity
                                of declining, on account of increasing duties and burdens at home. We must be excused.
                            </p></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True religion is simply following Christ..." TEIform="index"/>True religion is simply following Christ...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"True religion is simply following Christ. The more closely our modern churches conform their
                            standards of doctrine to this brief, vital core truth, the more orthodox they will become,
                            and the less will they be rent into factions and distracted with schism."</p></div2><pb n="109" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OVER THE CRYSTAL SEA</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bennett, Roby" TEIform="index"/>Roby Bennett</head><p TEIform="p"> At Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., March 14, Roby Bennett, aged 82 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Taylor, Leah" TEIform="index"/>Leah Taylor</head><p TEIform="p"> Also, March' 29, , aged 72 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Carney, Sarah" TEIform="index"/>Sarah Carney</head><p TEIform="p"> At Alfred, Me., March20, , aged 87 years</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Warner, Catharine M." TEIform="index"/>Catharine M. Warner</head><p TEIform="p"> At W. Pittsfield, Mass., March 27, , aged 37 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Godfrey, Lucretia M." TEIform="index"/>Lucretia M. Godfrey</head><p TEIform="p"> At Shirley, Mass., March 28, Eldress , aged 72 years. " A true mother in our Israel;
                                    and a great loss to those of us left behind."</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Buckingham, Joseph Chapman" TEIform="index"/>Jos. Chapman Buckingham</head><p TEIform="p"> At Shakers, N. Y., March 25, , aged 83 years. The deceased was the oldest of a large
                                    and prominent family at this place. On attaining his majority he came, in the full
                                    flush of his young manhood and joined the Society. He was the means of gathering to
                                    our people both his parents with four other brothers and sisters, all of whom are
                                    greatly prized for their past trustworthiness, and their now sprightly silvery
                                    years. The day the deceased departed he was as lively as a boy</p></div4></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Received" TEIform="index"/>Received</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> : Prom A. Perkins, $11.00. From Otis Sawyer, $10.00.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>The Children's Grotto</head><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let girls learn" TEIform="index"/>Let girls learn
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">LET GIRLS LEARN. To be pure in mind and heart. To be modest in demeanor. To
                                        be helpful at home. To be followers of Christ. And then there are less vital
                                        things that they should learn ; as To sew neatly. To do simple cooking. To buy
                                        with economy. To dress with taste. To read aloud well. There are many other
                                        useful and ornamental accomplishments within the reach of most girls, but those
                                        which we have given are indispensable.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Our monthly" TEIform="index"/>Our Monthly.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bit of a sermon" TEIform="index"/>Bit of a sermon
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A BIT OF A SERMON Whatso'er you find to do, Do it, boys, with all your might!
                                        Never be a little true ; Or a little in the right. Trifles even Lead to heaven,
                                        Trifles make the life of man ; So in all things, Great or small things, Be as
                                        thorough as you can. Let no speck their surface dim — Spotless truth and honor
                                        bright! I'd not give a fig for him Who says any lie is white ! He who falters,
                                        Twists or alters Little atoms when we speak, May deceive me, But believe me, To
                                        himself he is a sneak ! Help the weak if you are strong, Love the old if you are
                                        young ; Own a fault if you are wrong, If you're angry, hold your tongue, In each
                                        duty Lies a beauty, If your eyes you do not shut, Tust as surely And securely As
                                        a kernel in a nut! Love with all your heart and soul, Love with eye and ear and
                                        touch ; That's the moral of the whole. You can never love too much ! 'Tis the
                                        glory Of the story In our babyhood begun; Our hearts without it, (Never doubt
                                        it), Are as worlds without a sun ! If you think a word will please, Say it, if
                                        is but true, Words may give delight with ease, When no act is asked from you.
                                        Words may often Soothe and soften, Gild a joy or heal a pain ; They are
                                        treasures Yielding pleasures It is wicked to retain ! Whatsoe'er you find to do,
                                        Do it then with all your might; Let your prayers be strong and true — Prayer, my
                                        lads, will keep you right, Pray in all things, Great and small things, Like a
                                        Christian gentleman ; And forever, Now or never, Be as thorough as you'can.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Good words for the young" TEIform="index"/>Good Words for the Young.</bibl></cit></p></div3><pb n="110" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our daily reckoning" TEIform="index"/>Our daily reckoning
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">OUR DAILY RECKONING. If you sit down at set of sun And count the acts that
                                        you have done, And counting, find One self-denying act, one word That eased the
                                        heart of him who heard ; One glance, most kind, That fell like sunshine where it
                                        went, Then you may count that day well spent. But, if through all the livelong
                                        daygi You've cheered no heart by yea or nay; If, through it all, You've nothing
                                        done, that you can trace, That brought the sunshine to one face ; No act, most
                                        .small, That helped some soul, and nothing cost, Then count that day as worse
                                        than lost!</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Young reaper" TEIform="index"/>The Young Reaper.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="'How did you come to know her?'" TEIform="index"/>How did you come to know her?
                            </head><p TEIform="p">"How did you come to know her?" asked a mother of her little girl, as she saw her bidding
                                good-bye to a poorly-dressed child at the church door. " Why, you see, mamma, she came
                                into our Sunday school all alone, and I made a place for her on my seat, and I smiled
                                and she smiled, and then we were acquainted," was the pleasant answer.</p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="'Will the angels come down for me...'" TEIform="index"/>Will the angels come down for me...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">"Will the angels come down for me with a chariot and horses when I die," asked a little
                                boy of his Sunday school teacher. "I guess so, if you are a real good boy," said the
                                teacher. The little fellow's eyes sparkled with anticipation as he eagerly exclaimed : "
                                And, [oh ! do you think they'll let me sit on the front seat and drive ? "</p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="'Ma,' said an inquisitive little girl" TEIform="index"/>Ma,' said an inquisitive little girl,...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> "Ma,"' said an inquisitive little girl, "will rich and poor people live together when
                                they go up to heaven?" "Yes, my dear, they will all be alike there." " Then, ina, why
                                don't rich and poor Christians associate together here ?."</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The little boy who asked the Lord..." TEIform="index"/>The little boy who asked the Lord...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> The little boy who asked the Lord, in prayer, to make him better so that he would not
                                get angry any more, and added, " Lord, make ma's temper better,'too," taught his mother
                                a lesson she should never forget.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What we are now, and are daily striving to be..." TEIform="index"/>What we are now, and are daily striving to be...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> What we are now, and are daily striving to be, in the better land we shall be, and
                                eternally strive for a greater likeness to him who is our resurrection and life.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>Agricultural</head><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Visit to and observations upon a forty acre fruit farm" TEIform="index"/>VISIT TO AND
                                OBSERVATIONS UPON A FORTY ACRE FRUIT FARM.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Fraser</byline><p TEIform="p"> [Our very observing and talented brother, , has beea taking notes as stated above, and
                                he writes us some very worthy considerations.—Ed.] First. Raspberries, (black and red)
                                the rows of which are seven feet apart, and about three feet apart in the rows. A
                                leading feature in their culture is, that the canes when about two feet six inches high
                                are pinched. The results are, side shoots are thrown out, increasing the bearing wood,
                                and improving the fruit. The canes being low, winter better, and are not so liable as
                                long canes are to'be lashed about with the winds. Only two canes are allowed to a hill.
                                A plantation when the old canes are removed has a fine appearance ; each cane with its
                                branches is like a little tree, several acres together have quite a pleasing effect.
                                When the side shoots get too long they are cut to the right length. The old canes are
                                removed to a heap, not to be burnt, but to decompose, and then applied to young
                                plantations. Such a heap, composed of earth and sods, and brush, and on the top a layer
                                of wood ashes, and a layer of lime, and exposed to gentle rains so as to saturate the
                                heap, becomes a chemical laboratory, wherein the nitrogen of the atmosphere is detached
                                from the air, forming the nitrate of potash, the most valuable of all manurial salts.
                                Berry culture can never be a permanent success without a system of rotation. The black
                                raspberry may be renewed every six years, the red, eight; the blackberry, every ten
                                years ; strawberries, every two years ; if grown in hills and well cared for, they will
                                run well for several years. One of the best dressings for fruits of all kinds is wood
                                ashes, two bushels ; lime, two bushels ; salt, two bushels ; in all six bushels per
                                acre. If the land is rich in potash and lime, salt and plaster will be good. On laying
                                out a raspberry plantation, plant so as to be able to cultivate both ways, and every
                                four rods leave narrow roads to facili tate the removal of fruit and brush. <pb n="111" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEli MANIFESTO. Ill On this berry farm, the strawberries are
                                renewed every two years ; planted in the spring one foot apart in the rows. Spaces are
                                left so. that the fruit can be picked without stepping on the plants, and to admit of
                                cultivation. After the first fruit crop is gathered the cultivator is run through the
                                spaces, and then the whole bed is harrowed leaving the land loose and smooth for the
                                runners to root in, thus furnishing plants for new plantations. Seventy bushels of
                                strawberries were picked on this place one day. Of raspberries, in the fall of the
                                season, a greater number of bushels is daily shipped. Berries in some degree create
                                their own market, the fruit is mostly sold within twenty miles of the place. (Berlin,
                                Rens. Co., N. Y.) Small fruits enter increasingly into the diet of the people, and
                                inasmuch as they supersede the use of butter and meat in warm weather, all the better.
                                Butter is hard on the liver, and yields but little support to the muscular and nervous
                                tissues. In addition to the great quantities of fresh fruits consumed, to a considerable
                                extent they are also preserved. The single article of red raspberry jam consumed within
                                fifteen miles of Boston amounts annually (according to the New England Grocer) to five
                                hundred tons. The dried fruit is bought by the manufacturers at eighty-four cents a
                                pound. The blackberry succeeds the red raspberry, and connects with early apples and
                                pears. The Wachusett blackberry in this locality completes the list of fruits. It
                                embodies more good qualities than any other blackberry we know of, it bears abundantly,
                                berries of good size, and of good quality. The canes are remarkably free from thorns,
                                and being early, the fruit has brought even in panic times in the Boston market,
                                thirtythree cents a quart. The Wachusett was presented to the public by the Shakers at
                                Shirley, Mass., by Leander Persons.</p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Things I have noticed" TEIform="index"/>Things I have Noticed</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="N., J. C." TEIform="persName"/>J. C. N.</byline><p TEIform="p"> .—I have noticed that there are farmers who are afraid to trust their farms, and their
                                farms show it. I have noticed that there are farmers who feed their mowings spring and
                                fall, and usually a considerable portion of their barn room can be rented. I have
                                noticed that some farmers plant no corn, saying they can buy it cheaper than they can
                                raise it, and have seen the cattletlook as though they had waited a long time for their
                                owners to raise money to buy the corn. I have noticed that some farmers' horses have a
                                habit of stopping at every liquor saloon they have come to. I have noticed also that the
                                horse and driver resemble each other in this respect; each wears a staring coat. I have
                                noticed that the man who can manage his own and his neighbor's business successfully1 is
                                the coming man. At any rate he has not arrived yet. I have noticed that some farmers
                                swear with their tongues, and some with their milking stools. The cows prefer the former
                                style, but the devil don't care which. I have noticed that poor fences make unruly stock
                                and bad neighbors. I have noticed that if a team gets " set," it is better economy to
                                take a part of the load from the wagon than to take a part of the flesh from the horses.
                                I have noticed that it is a good plan to take notice of the good and the bad, so that we
                                may follow what is good and shun that which is bad.— in llecord and Farmer,</p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Production of agriculture in the census" TEIform="index"/> PRODUCTION OF AGRICULTURE IN
                                THE CENSUS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Walker, Francis A." TEIform="persName"/>Francis A. Walker</byline><p TEIform="p"> We call special attention to the following, as giving a hint to all ^productive
                                interests, to prepare an accurate report in due time.—Ed. The agriculture schedule
                                annexed to the act of 1850, which is also made part of the act of March 3, 1879,
                                providing for the tenth census, requires a report of the -chief productions of
                                agriculture " during the year ended June 1." Now, there is no distinct agricultural year
                                which ends on the 1st of June, and there is reason to believe that the statistics of
                                agriculture from 1850 to 1870, in regard to many of the principal products, em- <pb n="112" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 112 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. braced portions of two different crops,
                                inasmuch as the enumeration was protracted through three, four, and even five months. By
                                the act approved March 3, 1879, it is provided that the tenth census shall be taken and
                                completed during the month of June, 1880. This provision greatly reduces the liability
                                to error which has been noted. As the enumeration commences on the 1st of June and
                                closes on or before the 80th, all the crops which are gathered once a year will fall
                                pretty clearly on one side or the other of the dividing line. Thus the cotton crop
                                reported in the census will be that of 1879, gathered in the fall of that year; while
                                the wool clip or " wool crop " will be that of the spring of 1880— except in portions of
                                California and Texas, where both a fall and a spring clip are secured. For certain of
                                the productions of agriculture, however, there is no harvest, in the usual sense of that
                                term; but the product is gathered week by week, or day by day, as it matures—milk,
                                butter, cheese, meat, fall into this class. In view of the requirements of the law, and
                                of the great importance of accurate statistical information relative to agriculture, it
                                is deemed to be highly desirable that farmers should prepare themselves in advance to
                                give the information with promptness and accuracy. It is urgently recommended,
                                therefore, that agricultural journals and officers of agricultural societies and clubs
                                give publicity to this announcement, and that all persons engaged in agricultural
                                pursuits, who shall receive this circular, or shall see it in public prints, make notes
                                from time to time of the quantities and values of their several crops gathered, and the
                                number of acres of land planted, in order that their statements, when made to the
                                enumerators, may be of the highest possible value. To remove any doubts that may arise
                                concerning the crops to be returned in the census, the following table presents the
                                several crops specifically mentioned in the agricultural schedule, arranged accordingly
                                as they fall into the calendar year 1879, or that of 1880, or are to be returned for the
                                twelve months beginning June 1, 1879, and closing May 31, 1880 : PRODUCTIONS OF
                                AGRICULTURE DURING THE YEAR ENDED JUNE 1, '80. I. Of the crop of the calendar year 1879.
                                Wheat — acres ; bushels. Corn—acres ; bushels. Rye — acres; bushels. Oats — acres;
                                bushels. Barley — acres; bushels. Buckwheat—acres ; bushels. Peas and beans —bushels.
                                Rice—acres ; pounds. Tobacco— acres; pounds. Cotton—acres; bales. Potatoes—acres ;
                                bushels. Orchards—acres ; value of products, dollars. Vineyards— acres ; value of
                                products, dollars. Small fruits—acres ; value of products, dollars. Hay — acres; tons.
                                Clover-seed — bushels. Grass-seed—bushels. Hops—acres ; pounds. Hemp—acres ; tons.
                                Flax—acres ; pounds. Flax-seed—bushels. Bees—number of hives, pounds of wax ; pounds of
                                honey. Sugarcane—acres ; hogsheads of sugar ; gallons of molasses. Sorghum—acres ;
                                pounds of sugar ; gallons of molasses. II. Of the crop of the calendar year 1880.
                                Wool—number of fleeces: pounds. Maple sugar—pounds. Maple molasses—gallons. III. Of the
                                yield of the twelve months, June 1, 1879, to May 31, 1880. Butter—pounds. Cheese—pounds.
                                Milk sold—gallons. Value of animals slaughtered— dollars. Market gardens — acres; value
                                of products, dollars. Value of forest products, dollars. Value of home manufactures,
                                dollars. Supt. of Census.</p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sixty lbs. carried 1,000 miles for six cents" TEIform="index"/>Sixty lbs. carried 1,000
                                miles for six cents</head><p TEIform="p"> :—Any farmer who has raised wheat knows how heavy a bushel of wheat feels, after he has
                                carried it half a mile or so. We have found it a full day's work with a good span of
                                horses, to take 30 to 40 bushels 14 miles to market, and return with an empty wagon. How
                                would it be if we had no railroads or canals, to transport to the sea-board shipping
                                markets the immense grain products of the west and northwest? During July of this year,
                                the average rate paid for carrying wheat all the way from Chicago to New York, by the
                                lakes <pb n="113" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 113 (1.7c.) and canal (4.3c.) was
                                only six cents per bushel of GO lbs., and for a bushel of corn, 56 lbs., 5 1-3 cents!
                                The distance sby this route is some 1,500 miles. The railroads, to compete with the
                                water routes, have had to carry grain at about the same rates, and the shortest distance
                                by railroad is nearly 1,000 miles. Allowing a team and driver only $4 a day for wages,
                                feed, and other traveling expenses, carrying 40 bushels, and going 33 1-3 miles each
                                day, the expense would be $3 per bushel,jproviding that the team got loading enough
                                homeward, to pay expenses and wages back. So, at the best, it would cost fifty times as
                                much to carry grain to market by wagon as it does by railroad. The same reckoning
                                applies, in a lesser degree, to shorter distances. Shall we tear up the railway tracks,
                                or abuse the owners, who do not receive 4 per cent on the average for the money
                                invested? Ought we not rather to have a good deal of sympathy with the original builders
                                of these roads, a large number of whom never got any thing for the money expended —
                                either for the principal or the interest ? Not a very profitable business certainly.—
                                American Agriculturist.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>Home Topics</head><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let me help you to brains!" TEIform="index"/>Let me help you to Brains !</head><p TEIform="p"> In relation to a new system of curing diseases by suitable variation in foods, which is
                                attracting considerable attention and praise, the Rev. Henry Ward Beecher wittily says:
                                " For thousands of years men have eaten without a scientific motive, without rational
                                appreciation of the relations of foods to bone, muscle, nerve, and so on. The whole
                                motives lay in the mouth. Men ate because it tasted good, but by-and-by we shall have
                                bone-building, fat-producing, nerve-replenishing and muscle-forming dishes. The host,
                                instead of asking guests to take beef or pudding, will say to a lean or cadaverous
                                visitor, ' Let me fill up your tissue,' or ' my dear sir, your bones are brittle, allow
                                me to pass this compound ; better bones were never made than this produces.' To some
                                exigent a scholar, thin and nervous, the jolly host will say, ' My dear fellow let me
                                help you to brains. What do you affect? This dish runs strongly to poetry ; or, is it
                                philosophy? Why, sir, philosophy is only food etherealized !'" Reverend joking apart, it
                                is not incredible that a great scientific advance may be made in this direction, and the
                                day may come when food will be so nicely adjusted to the human wants that disease will
                                be, in a measure, controlled, and the highest physical satisfaction come to be
                            enjoyed.</p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dutch rolls" TEIform="index"/>Dutch Bolls</head><p TEIform="p">.—There used to be a steam packet that went out of Amsterdam that gave first-class
                                feeding to her passengers, and once I mixed up with the Dutch cook, as I was a Swede,
                                and got this receipt from him for his rolls, which were very good and light, and 1 have
                                made them since with brilliant success: Sift three quarts of flour; break three eggs
                                into a pint of cold milk, in which put a teaspoonful of yeast and stir up ; cut a
                                spoonful of butter up fine and work it into your flour; mix the milk and eggs and yeast
                                with the flour ; knead thoroughly. Make into rolls, butter the pan, and stand by the
                                stove to rise. Bake in a quick oven.</p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fried oysters" TEIform="index"/>Fried Oysters</head><p TEIform="p"> . — Get the largest and finest oysters, rinse them in clear water, and dry them quite
                                dry in a cloth. Beat up the yolks of two eggs, and thin with half a gill of milk. Dip
                                each oyster separately into the egg and milk, and then into very finely powdered
                                cracker-crumbs. Let them lie an hour, and dip them in the egg and cracker again, and
                                then fry them in plenty of melted butter, which must be so hot that it will brown them
                                at once. They must be turned over in the boiling fat, and the whole operation must not
                                take over five minutes.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Grafting-wax may be made by melting together four pounds of..." TEIform="index"/>Grafting-wax may be made by melting together four pounds of...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Grafting-wax may be made by melting together four pounds of common resin, two pounds of
                                beeswax, and one pound of tallow. If to be used in the orchard in cool weather, add a
                                quarter of a pound or more' tallow, or a little raw linseed oil.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In some places rats have become a great pest in farmhouses and barns..." TEIform="index"/>In some places rats have become a great pest in farmhouses and barns...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> In some places rats have become a great pest in farmhouses and barns. Copperas is the
                                dread of rats. In every crevice or every hole where a rat treads, scatter the grains of
                                copperas, and the result is a stampede of rats and mice.</p></div3></div2><pb n="114" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vision of Emir Abdoul or in union alone are we conquerors" TEIform="index"/>THE VISION OF
                            EMIR ABDOUL, OR In Union Alone are we Conquerors.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sproat, Granville T." TEIform="persName"/>granville t. sproat</byline><p TEIform="p"> Among all the Caliphs of the East there was no one more beloved than Emir Abdoul, the
                            venerable Caliph of Damascus.(1) He was a lineal descendant of the family'of the Prophet,
                            and'was known throughout all the East'as "the'" wise and good Caliph." Whenever j^he
                            appeared in the streets of Damascus the old men stood still at his approach, and put their
                            fingers to their lips; and the young men bowed themselves three times to the earth, and
                            stretched forth their hands to touch the hem of his mantle, on which were inscribed verses
                            from the Koran, written by Allah, the Great, and the Good. About the middle of the month
                            Sivan, the Caliph summoned into his presence the four captains who had charge of his
                            faithful band of followers, and said unto them, " Make ready and prepare on the morrow to go
                            with me on a pilgrimage to the Holy City, and to the Mosque of St. Omar — for whom Allah be
                            praised. I long to gaze once more on the Sacred Stone, and the prints of the Prophet's
                            footsteps, and the fingers of the Angel Gabriel impressed on the solid rock.(2) Let the
                            Koran—the Book of the holy Prophet — be placed before me on the camel on which I shall ride
                            — that I may gather gems from its golden treasure, on my way to the Holy City.(3) So, on the
                            morrow, the whole company assembled before the palace of the Caliph, and with them their
                            beasts of burden — elephants, and camels, and dromedaries, loaded with the fruits of the
                            East — dates, and figs, and pomegranates; and bottles of the sweet wine of Lebanon ;(4) with
                            rich presents of gold and silver for the adornment of the walls and roof of the beautiful
                            Mosque of St. Omar, at Jerusalem. With many prayers and invocations to Allah they started on
                            their journey. They traveled all day over the beautiful plains of Damascus, called by the
                            Persians " one of the four Paradises of the East."(5) Groves and gardens were like those of
                            Eden ; and crystal fountains sparkled on every side. They crossed the " Plain of Roses "
                            where Allah first planted the beautiful damask rose. At night they made their encampment
                            under the shadow of Mt. Hermon. There the good Caliph pitched his tent, and called on all
                            the Faithful to worship. He read to them, standing in the door of his tent, from the Koran,
                            words of wisdom uttered by the Prophet, and the story of Adam and the first Eden.(6) Then
                            they all knelt with their faces toward the Holy City, and repeated the closing words of the
                            Muezzin, calling on all the Faithful to prayer.(?) The next morning they started on their
                            journey, and soon reached the sultry plains of Petrea, in Palestine. After traveling all day
                            over those parched and burning plains, they rested at night under the shade of the palm
                            trees, by the well—Ozoff. Here the Caliph again pitched his tent, and they gave their beasts
                            of burden drink from the cool waters of the well.(8) A repast was spread under the palm
                            trees, consisting of dates, and figs, and honey from the valley of the Jordan, and, for
                            bread, the sweet wafer cakes of Palestine.(9) Early the next morning two messengers were
                            sent out on swift dromedaries to prepare the way for the company, when they should travel
                            the mountain passes of Lebanon. (10) Toward evening the messengers returned with these
                            words: " A rock heavy and massive has fallen from the hoary summit of Lebanon,(ll) crushing
                            the cedars in its way, and has buried itself deeply in the valley below; so that none can
                            pass over it on their way to the Mosque of St. Omar and the Holy City." Then arose Emir
                            Abdoul, the Wise, and called for the four captain s of the company, and said to them, "
                            Arise, take with you the elephants, the camels and the dromedaries, and take ropes of
                            camel's hair, very strong, and hasten to remove the rock from the mountain-pass of Lebanon,
                            that the Faithful may pass over." So these men arose, and with them went a large company to
                            remove the rock; but the Caliph remained under the palm trees, by the well—Ozoff. <pb n="115" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. 115 On the second day a messenger returned to
                            the Caliph, and bowed himself before him, and said with many tears, and much trembling, "
                            Oh, son of the Prophet of the Highest! it is with shame and confusion of face I come before
                            thee, to bring the tidings of evil this day! — in vain, with our elephants, our camels, and
                            our dromedaries have we strove to remove the rock that blocks the way to the Holy City. It
                            stands firm as the cedars of Lebanon, and strong as the hills that surround the city of the
                            Faithful. It is as if Azael, the Angel of Death, or hosts of darkly-veiled, head-covered
                            spirits whom the Prophet cursed,(12) had arisen from the cavern with seven gates,(13) and
                            were brooding over the stone, and crushing it to the earth. Surely, the wrath of Allah, the
                            Terrible, is kindled against his children ! In vain they cry, " Allah ! Hu I" and beat their
                            breasts before him ! He does not regard their prayers, or listen to their cries ! No longer
                            does the Prophet of the Holiest intercede for us ; or come to our help with a whole escort
                            of angels, and horses and chariots of fire, as in the former days. He turns away from us
                            with scorn! The impious Gallilean rejoices.(13) The hosts of the aliens triumph ! Oh, Allah
                            ! Hu ! Allah ! Hu !—to whom shall we fly for help if Allah forsakes us !(14) That night Emir
                            Abdoul went to his couch weary and broken in spirit, and his sleep departed from him ; and
                            about midnight the curtains of his tent shook and trembled, and a light, like the brightness
                            of the sun, shone around him, and the mighty angel Gabriel stood before him. Emir Abdoul
                            covered his face with his hands, and bowed himself three times on his couch. And the angel
                            said to him, " Son of the Prophet ©f the Holiest, Allah the All Wise hath sent me to. thee
                            with these words : "There is evil lurking in the hearts of the four captains —¦ the captain
                            of the leaders, the captain of the march, the captain of the rest, and the captain of food
                            for pilgrims. They do not work together as one man. Two of them are pulling toward
                            Jerusalem, and two toward Damascus. Each one is seeking his own honor, and loves the praise
                            of men. Send, therefore, for them, and let them come and confess their sin before thee, and
                            humble themselves in spirit, and seek the protection of Allah ; so shall he send them help
                            to remove the rock from the valley of Elon, in Lebanon." So, in the morning, Emir Abdoul
                            sent a messenger to those four captains of the band, and they came and bowed themselves
                            before him, and he spake to them all the words that the angel had uttered. And these men
                            humbled themselves before the Caliph, and confessed their faults, and arose and embraced
                            each other ; and the Caliph stood by, and with many tears gave thanks to Allah for the love
                            that was in them ; and he laid his hands upon them and blessed them with the blessing of the
                            Prophet—the father of the Faithfnl. On the morrow he said to them, " Depart in peace; for
                            now I know that Allah will be with you, and you will be able to move the rock out of the way
                            of the pilgrims." So these men departed, rejoicing, on their journey, and with one heart put
                            their hands to the rock, and lo ! it moved ; for the angel Gabriel with a host of strong and
                            loving spirits took hold of the rock, and removed it out of the way, for the Faithful to
                            pass over. Then Emir Abdoul, when he came to the place, and saw what had been done, gave
                            thanks to Allah, and all the people with him ; and he had written over the door of his tent
                            in letters of gold, so that all who were with him might read, these words: (15) " Blessed be
                            Allah I who has not left himself without a witness among the Faithful; and who unites the
                            hearts of his children, as many drops of water mingle into one." And above it, as on a
                            scroll, was written in letters of naming light: "In Union Alone ake We Conquerors." (1)
                            Caliph. A successor or representative of Mahommed. (2) " The Sacred Stone," says the Moslem
                            Tradition, " was dropped by Allah out of heaven, to mark the spot where the Mosque of St.
                            Omar should stand. At the time of the flight of the persecuted seers from Jeru-" salem, it
                            rose from its bed, like a thing of life, to follow after them. But the strong angel Gabriel
                            seized it with his right hand, and left the prints of his fingers on. <pb n="116" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/>
                            116 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. the solid rock. He held it fast for a time, but the Living Stone
                            struggled to get free. Gabriel sent a messenger to the Prophet, at Mecca, and he came with
                            seventy-five thousand winged horses, and horsemen, and placed his feet on the stone, and
                            nailed it to its rocky bed forever. It stands in the middle of the Mosque, and is an object
                            of great veneration to the Faithful. (3) The ceremony is still observed, among the
                            Mussulinen, of wrapping the Koran in silk, and carrying it in front of them on the back of a
                            camel, richly adorned with the same material. Burchard saw a copy of the Koran, the leaves
                            of which were four feet long, and more than two feet and a half broad, thus carried. (4)
                            Sweet wine is that which is made from the grapes fully ripe, and unfermented. The vessels,
                            or leathern bottles in which the wines are kept, are often referred to in scripture. The
                            Arabs pull the skin off goats, in the same manner that we do from rabbits, and sew up the
                            places where the legs and tail are cut off, leaving one for the neck of the bottle to pour
                            from, and in such bags they put up and carry, not only their liquors, but dry things which
                            are apt to be broken ; by which means they are well preserved from wet, dust, and insects.
                            (5) The city of Damascus, in Syria, stands on a plain about sixteen hundred feet above the
                            level of the sea. This plain is shaded by trees of luxuriant growth, and ornamented with
                            fountains. Its extensive orchards, computed to be thirty miles round, abound with every
                            variety of fruit. The Persian poets call Damascus the " Beautiful Queen of the East," and
                            the "Pearl of Islam." They say " there are four Paradises in Asia. One at Damascus, one in
                            Persia,one in Chaldea, and one in the island of Ceylon. The one in Damascus excels them all.
                            " When Mohammed," says the Moslem Legend, " first beheld Damascus from a height that
                            overlooked the city, and was gazing intently on its wondrous beauty, the devil, I who had
                            followed him hither, said to him, ' Seest thou, Mohammed, this beautiful city? She holds in
                            her hands all the treasures of the East! She shall be thine, and thou shalt reign a king
                            over her, only renounce thy allegiance to Allah, and be no longer called his Prophet.'
                            Mohammed turned upon him with a look of scorn. Pointing upward, 11 have already one kingdom/
                            he ' replied, ' promised me by Allah. Why then should I ask for another?' The spot is marked
                            by an arch, called ' The Arch of Victory.' " » (6) The Mussulmen do not believe that the
                            Paradise in which Adam was placed was terrestrial; but that it was one of the seven heavens;
                            and from this heaven he was thrown down into the Island of Ceylon, where he died, after
                            having made a pilgrimage into Arabia, where he visited the place appointed for building the
                            temple of Mecca. More marvelous still is the account given in the Talmud. It says, " Adam's
                            body was made of the earth of Babylon ; his head of the land of Israel; his other members of
                            other parts of the world. God took twelve hours to make him. So hlige was his stature that
                            he extended from one end of the earth to the other, and with his hand he touched the
                            firmament. When he sinned God laid His hand on him, and pressed him down into a moderately
                            small shape." (7) The muezzin, or call to prayer, as proclaimed from the lofty minaret, is
                            observed in all Mohammedan countries. When proclaimed by a fine voice, the effect is solemn
                            and beautiful; "more so," says Chateaubriand, " than all the bells in Christendom." These
                            are the words — in which all the Faithful join — " God ! (Allah !) most high ! I bear
                            witness that there is no God but God, and Mohammed is his Prophet. Come to prayer ! Come to
                            the asylum of salvation ! Great God ! there is no God but God! " (&amp;) In some parts
                            of Palestine the streams are dry during the heat of summer. During the rainy season water is
                            collected into wells, or reservoirs, for irrigating the lands. The water is drawn from the
                            wells by a Persian wheel called " nozia"— a simple contrivance for raising water, and used
                            all over the Levant. (9) The usual form given to bread in Palestine is that of the broad,
                            thin, flat cake. The inhabitants bake it in an oven, called " taanowr," which may be
                            compared to a large stone pitcher open at the top, in which they make a fire. When it is
                            well heated, they mingle flour and water, and this paste they apply to the outside of the
                            pitcher. It is baked in an instant, and is taken off in thin pieces, like our wafers. There
                            is a tradition among the Orientals that Eve's oven was of this kind — that it was left to
                            Noah, and that the boiling water which ran over it occasioned the deluge — a symbol of the
                            extent and effect of her sin. (10) The dromedary is a species of smaller camel, having on
                            his back a kind of natural saddle composed of two great bunches. At full speed the dromedary
                            is computed to travel a hundred miles a day without showing signs of fatigue. The Arabs say
                            that it will, in one night, and through a level country, traverse as much ground as a horse
                            will in three. The Arab poets call them the " swift ships of the desert." (11) The summit of
                            Mt. Lebanon rises nine thousand feet above the level of the sea. It is covered with eternal
                            snow, and in ascending it you experience every variety of climate. The resident of Tripoli,
                            in the month of January, beholds under his windows the orange tree loaded with fruit, and
                            the flower <pb n="117" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 117 opens its bud to the sun, while
                            the hoary head of Lebanon is covered with ice and snow. The poets of Arabia have said that "
                            Sannin (Lebanon) bears Winter on his head ; Spring on his shoulders ; and Autumn in his
                            bosom, while Summer lies sleeping at his feet." (12) That covering of the head worn by all
                            Christendom — the hat — is an abomination to the Turk. It marks the followers of the
                            Nazarene, called by them, " Infidel dogs," and was cursed by the Prophet. The severest
                            malediction that one Moslem can utter against another is, May God put a hat on your head.
                            "All the inhabitants of hell," says the Mussulman, " wear hats ! " It is nailed, as a mark
                            of disgrace, to the door of every traitor, and is a badge of deepest infamy. (13) " Hell,"
                            says the Mussulman, " has seven gates, guarded by seven dragons, each with a hundred eyes.
                            Heaven has eight gates, guarded by eight angels, with flaming swords. It is approached by a
                            bridge, called Al-Sirat, narrower than the thread of a famished spider, and sharper than the
                            edge of a sword. Over it the Mussulman passes with the speed of lightning. The Infidel drops
                            into the yawning gulf below." (13) The Mussulman calls Jesus the "Qdllilean." Hence, Julian,
                            the famous Saracen warrior, and bitter enemy of the Christian faith, in the war of the
                            Crusades, being wounded by an arrow, wrenched it from his side, and a torrent of blood
                            flowing, he took a handful, and cast it toward heaven, exclaiming, "Thou hast conquered, 0!
                            Qallilean !" (14) Allah Hu is not only the Mussulman's war-cry, but his cry for help in the
                            hour of distress and danger. It is the last word of the muezzin's call to prayer. (15) The
                            tent of a Turkish noble is often entirely covered with silk, and lined with the same
                            material. A recent traveler mentions one that cost twenty-five thousand piasters, and was
                            three years in being completed. It was beautifully decorated with festoons, and sentences
                            from the Koran, wrought with pearls and precious stones. It was the tent of the sumptuous
                            Nadir Shah. Canaan, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Oh, lead me, Lord..." TEIform="index"/>Oh, lead me, Lord...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Oh, lead me, Lord, that I may lead The wandering and the wavering feet; Oh feed me, Lord,
                            that I may feed Thy hungering ones with manna sweet. Oh strengthen me, that while I stand
                            Firm on the rock, and strong in Thee ; I may stretch out a loving haad To wrestlers with the
                            troubled sea.</p></div2><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mother Ann Lee" TEIform="index"/>MOTHER ANN LEE</head><p TEIform="p">In a recent discourse upon the " Unfoldment of Truth," A. J. Davis thus pays some pretty
                            compliments to our founder, and also renders some doubtful compliments to the sagacity of
                            her people : " I like to think how these glorious ideas got into the world. Just think of
                            that woman, Ann Lee, a woman whom Paul discouraged with his thoughts, not with his ideas. By
                            the way, it is difficult to find an idea in Paul. Paul had many glorious thoughts,
                            enthusiasms, heroic bursts of noble nature in religion, and was willing to do and die for
                            the truth. But he said that women must keep silence. Could Ann Lee keep silence ? She could
                            not. She had an idea that had to be born through her. Oh, the newspapers made great fun of
                            her ; the Nast of that ¦ period caricatured her. How many persons had their fun while she
                            suffered, more than words can tell, under the divine pressure that evolved, through her, its
                            expression ! ' There is a mother as well as a father side to God." Mother God! The woman
                            nature will cling to the Father. That is because vines always grow up toward the sun. The
                            feminine nature will grow up toward the Father spirit above and the masculine toward the
                            Mother's side. " Ann Lee said, ' God is Mother and Father too.' How beautifully Theodore
                            Parker expressed that, so long after, in a great hall in the city of Boston, and surrounded
                            by the best, bravest, some of the noblest of that great center. When Ann Lee brought her
                            great idea into the world she did not see its import. I tell you the Shakers do not
                            understand it any more than the Methodists understand John Wesley or the Presbyterians the
                            works of John Calvin. I tell you the Shakers do not understand, any more than the Quakers
                            do, the beautiful spirit that was at the very heart of their first worker."</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In the French revolution it is said..." TEIform="index"/>In the French revolution it is said...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> In the French revolution it is said the republicans found twelve silver images of the
                            apostles in a Catholic church, where they had probably stood a long time; but they were to
                            stand there no longer. They were melted and coined into money, that they might, like the
                            living apostles and their Master, " go about doing good." There are many in the churches
                            like those images. We wish they might be melted, and put into circulation.</p></div2><pb n="118" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Crown and cross" TEIform="index"/>CROWN AND CROSS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/>G. A. Lomas</byline><p TEIform="p"> Unison. Moderato. 1. There's a crown and Oh how beautiful Are those above who wear it; 2.
                            Time and change can never separate The bearer from the wearer, 3. Gospel blessings we'll
                            enumerate, And praise the Lord of glory, There's a cross and Oh how beautiful Are those who
                            daily bear it; Heav'nly graces here we cultivate Adorn the rightful sharer, Who in fullness
                            doth remunerate To all who're meek and lowly, Bear the cross wear the crown, Saving cross
                            and Bear the cross wear the crown, Saving cross and Bear the cross wear the crown, Saving
                            cross and Savior's crown. Savior's crown. Savior's crown. 07w. Forte Allegretto. Salvation
                            is our theme, Salvation is our song, Salvation is our theme, Salvation is our song,
                            Salvation is our theme, Salvation is our song, <pb n="119" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO.
                            119 Salvation we will shout, As we triumph over wrong, Salvation we will shout, As we
                            triumph over wrong, Salvation we will shout, As we triumph over wrong, Mezzo Moderato. And
                            while we bear the cross, There's a heav'nly crown in view, The glorious prize is ours, None
                            can ever take a way,— Rememb'ring that the cross, Will in sure a glorious crown,— Salvation
                            we will sing As we bid the world adieu. Salvation we will sing As we rise to endless day.
                            Salvation we will sing As we lay our own lives down.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Marriage as a test" TEIform="index"/> MARRIAGE AS A TEST</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whiteley, John" TEIform="persName"/>John Whiteley</byline><p TEIform="p"> [From the Public Spirit.] <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Dear Friend— My attention has been called to the following paragraph, which
                                    appeared in a recent issue of the Broome '(N. Y.) Republican: How remarkable it is
                                    that whenever an enthusiast in religion gets new light, and adopts what he considers
                                    " advanced views," he almost, invariably begins to tamper with marriage ! In this
                                    tampering he always betrays the charlatan, and sufficiently warns all who are
                                    tempted to follow him to beware of him. There is no better test of a new system or
                                    scheme of life than its relation to Christian marriage. If it tampers with that it
                                    is always bad, and can by no possibility be good. The Shakers form a community built
                                    on this rotten foundation. They destroy the family, root and branch. They have no
                                    place for love, and enter into a determined and organized fight with the God of
                                    Nature, who, by the strongest passions and impulses He has ever implanted in the
                                    human soul, has commanded them to establish families and homes. Shakerism is good
                                    for nothing if it is not good universally — if it ought not to be adopted
                                    universally. But universal adoption would be the suicide of a race, and a race has
                                    no more right to commit suicide than a man. Besides, the damming of one of the most
                                    powerful streams in human nature only sets the <pb n="120" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/> 120 THE SHAKER
                                    MANIFESTO. water back to cover the banks it was intended to nourish and to drain. It
                                    is too late to talk about the superior sanctity of the celibate. We have no faith in
                                    it whatever. The vow of chastity simply emphasizes in the mind the passion it is
                                    intended, for spiritual reasons, to suppress, and fixes the attention upon it. The
                                    Shaker, in denying love to himself and all the hallowed influences growing out of
                                    family and home gains nothing in holiness, if he does not lose irretrievably. He is
                                    the victim of a shocking mistake, and he disgraces his own father and mother by his
                                    gross views of an institution before whose purity and beneficence he and his whole
                                    system stands condemned. May this not be regarded as proof, rather, that there is
                                    something in the popular sense and practice of marriage that needs modification ?
                                    Perhaps, as stated, " there is no better test of a new system or scheme of life than
                                    its relation to marriage." The above writer says " Christian" marriage ; but by what
                                    right or authority, I would ask ? Jesus did not marry. The apostles and the Jewish
                                    Christians in the church at Jerusalem lived celibate lives. Were they " charlatans,"
                                    or did they build on a " rotten foundation 1" And is it because the Shakers strive
                                    to follow their example that the writer aforesaid forms or expresses such an
                                    unfavorable idea of their organization 1 He says " they destroy the family, root and
                                    branch." But suppose they do forsake father and mother and houses and lands (see
                                    Matthew 19:29), do they not in this life receive the "hundred fold?" Have they not a
                                    more Christian family arrangement in the order, where " all that believe have all
                                    things common, as every man hath need 1" — where there are none poor or rich, in a
                                    worldly sense ? The Shaker, or truly Ch ristian method of dealing with marriage, is
                                    bad only to the " carnal nature," which is enmity against God and all that is truly
                                    good. Those who have honestly and most thoroughly tried the Shaker life, find it
                                    very good for them, but that does not prove that all men are able to receive or live
                                    the Shaker life. He that is, "let him," is the language of Him who " who spoke as
                                    never man spake." He who confesses and forsakes the evils of his carnal life, will
                                    not suffer badly from the damming process the writer speaks of. There is another
                                    form of the word, however, which applies with much more force and applicability to
                                    the other side of the subject; that is, there is probably nothing so damning to the
                                    souls of men as the unrestricted exercise of the sexual functions, with or without
                                    the sanction of " sacred matrimony." The Shaker does not " deny love to himself."
                                    Love is the mainspring of his whole life, even toward those who write so ignorantly
                                    of his motives and acts. Love to God and to his fellow brother man — the sisters
                                    included—not selfishly, but with such feelings as He who said, " Who is my mother,
                                    and who are my brethren ?" And himself gave the answer — "Whosoever shall do the
                                    will of my father who is in heaven, the same is my brother and sister and mother."
                                    With regard to his disgracing himself, or his parents, I will say that it may
                                    probably be the fact that a majority of the Shakers were placed ifi the order by
                                    their parents — were accompanied by them, or have (as in many cases is the fact)
                                    been followed by them ; therefore, I fail to see where the disgrace comes in. Of
                                    course, the writer of the above article is unknown to me; but I conclude he must be
                                    a very young man who needs " more light," and who perhaps may live long enough to
                                    attain more " advanced views ;" or, that he is a very narrow-minded sectarian who
                                    would be glad to see the Inquisition re-established, provided his own notions could
                                    be favored by it. All I would say further respecting him is, that I know, from over
                                    thirty years' experience, that his remarks regarding the Shakers — those who are
                                    Shakers indeed—are unworthy a Christian, and would pray as Jesus did.— "Father,
                                    forgive him, for he knows not what he does." Shirley Village, Mass.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Public spirit" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We believe the change from the present to the eternal state of existence..." TEIform="index"/>We believe the change from the present to the eternal state of existence...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> We believe the change from the present to the eternal state of existence is one of
                            condition, more than of the essentials of life. All that makes men true, pure and godly,
                            goes with them everywhere. All that makes them false, impure, wicked, abides with them.
                            Every man goes to his own place.</p></div2><!--
                    <pb id="p29"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>