<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0204" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Mount Lebanon Bishopric</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Albany, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">2</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">4</biblScope><date value="18720401" TEIform="date">April 1872</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">25-32</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="2" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="25" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="4" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">I WILL SHAKE ALL NATIONS, AND THE DESIRE OF ALL NATIONS SHALL COME J AND I WILL FILL THIS HOUSE
                        WITH GLORY, SAITH THE LORD.' Published Monthly, by and under the direction of the Mt. Lebanon
                        Bishopric. Vol. II. G. A. Lomas, Editor. SHAKERS, ALBANY CO., N. Y., APRIL, 1872. Ko. 4. Fifty
                        Cents per Annum.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spiritualism of shakerism" TEIform="index"/>The Spiritualism of Shakerism</head><p TEIform="p">The Shakers are, and ever have been, Spiritualists. The childhood of Ann Lee was rife with
                            spirit communications. By spirits she became the prepared subject of the Christ spirit, and
                            the medium for its communication to other souls. From time immemorial in Shaker history,
                            spirit communions have been active, operating like the seasons. In their spring, they
                            affected the children and amused the adults; in the summer the adults became thoroughly
                            affected ; between summer and autumn there was a flood-tide of communications, when the very
                            atmosphere seemed pregnant with spiritual influences, which affected nearly the whole of
                            society in almost every conceivable manner—physically, and with great power; mentally, and
                            with wondrous performance; spiritually, and with an irresistable conviction of sin; and then
                            we have known of "the full corn in the ear" of Spiritualism's first cycle, and are ac-
                            quainted with its winter, though never bereft of spirit gifts and manifestations. The
                            association of Shakers with Spiritualists has been the cause of much comment by the press,
                            and the expression of much regret on the part of those who have a deep respect for the
                            Shakers, but who are avowed opponents of Spiritists and of the spiritual philosophy. We do
                            not wonder at these fears and comments; we should wonder were they not expressed. Spirit-
                            ualists—the bona-fide class—are now, in their theology, where we once were. The philosophy
                            is doing for them what it has already done for us. The church multitudes are quite familiar
                            with our radical estrangement from the theologies of every other church; and of our
                            adoption, on the earth, of a heavenly practice in life ; which, while the churches are
                            forced to admire, they well know would be death to any other church than our own, should the
                            same life be adopted and be generally enforced. The clergy and laity, generally speaking,
                            are not aware of the elementary forces that are fledging all true spiritualists for their
                            flight into immortal, eternal life. Of these, we are aware, and are far more happy in the
                            disenthrallment of true Spiritists from erroneous theological bondage, than we have ever
                            been at the emancipation of oppressed races from physical servitude ; and equally happy for
                            them as for our own freedom from obstacles in our way of spirit progress. Spiritualism
                            impresses upon its communicants a thorough infidelity to the frame work of manmade
                            creeds—non-communication with the departed; the physical resurrection ; the Trinity and the
                            vicarious atonement by Jesus! Upon these, and many other points, Shakers and Spiritualists
                            are of one faith. What has Spiritualism given for what it has taken away ? If it has built
                            up nothing, we will still thank God for what it has knocked down. It has confirmed commu-
                            nications between the visible and invisible worlds; and these have broken into myriads of
                            pieces the erroneous theologies of the day. The Shakers have ever found the Books of
                            Revelation open; so do the Spiritualists. In exchange for the physical resurrection, the
                            Shakers and many leading Spiritualists have accepted the practice in life that elevates the
                            soul above the earthly, pro-creative plane, up to the angelic. Both have exchanged the mon-
                            strous Trinity for the eternal duality of deity—Father and Mother God ! while both are
                            assured that their salvation will never be accomplished by another, but by their own
                            efforts, aided by the reform circles of the spirit world. Both view Jesus as a Jew; made the
                            medium for imparting very spiritual truths for the guidance of true spiritualists' lives.
                            Both see the possibility of other Saviours arising, as did Jesus, above the common lives of
                            the multitude, to testify the necessity of advancement and against error in all that
                            pertains to life. Thus far have progressive spiritualists followed and accompanied the
                            Shakers. We love them for all the reforms they have made for the better. Some, in their
                            illuminations of the heavenly relations of " the better land," have mistaken (purposely or
                            otherwise) the fraternal unions there existing, for the freelove tendencies of sensualists;
                            thus abrogating the bondage of marriage by substituting something worse ! With these we have
                            no fellowship. Wherein do we differ from true Spiritualists ? To answer this, necessitates a
                            reference to the line of demarcation, beneath which we will not go ; and above which we are
                            certain every spiritualist who is true to his or her spiritual instincts, will and must
                            ascend. Very few Spiritualists will ever permit themselves to go back to the vomit of
                            theological fooleries they have forsaken. To go forward is the only alternative left them;
                            and so sure as the same causes lead to the same results, so sure are all true spiritualists
                            destined to be at-one-ment with all true Shakers; and all conjoined to the innumerable
                            company of thoroughly spiritualized individualities—the angels. The difference between
                            Shakers and Spiritualists exists in the degrees of spirituality attained to by each, rather
                            than any difference in the principles of life—the Shakers being rad- ically in the advance,
                            having spiritualized strong points in life where spiritualists are yet on the earth. The
                            time is near, has already arrived to some modern spiritualists, when selfish interests, such
                            as houses, lands, husbands, wives and children—all that is called mine —will yield to the
                            spiritual impress of the pentecostal church. Here we yet differ in too great degree—we plead
                            guilty to a little impatience. Again, Spiritualists, as a body, are not yet convinced how
                            very unspiritual are the lusts of the flesh—how very much beneath the inspiration and
                            aspiration of an angel to engage in at all! The verj name of spiritualist should signify one
                            freed from the lusts of the flesh and of the mind—an elevation of character that despises
                            sensual indulgence. Generally speaking, we differ widely here ; yet more in practice than in
                            convictions; and none are better aware of this fact than true Spiritualists themselves.
                            Spiritualism will yet present crosses of self-denial to the believing in its ranks; and then
                            will come the test of sincerity, and moral courage. Many will decline to make the advances
                            called for, while it is in their power to save their earthly, generative lives; while others
                            will lose their nnspiritual lives with pleasure, and on the earth begin a life that never
                            needs change to be eternal. Wherein must the Spiritualist change, here or hereafter, who is
                            surrounded by or filled with the same affections for unspirit<pb n="26" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            SHAKER. uality that his neighbors, Methodist or Presbyterians engage in, (excepting their
                            theology), that he may be numbered with seraphims ? Wherein must the Shaker change ? As our
                            aims are both heavenward, whose lives comport nearest with our convictions of the angel life
                            ? Spiritualists will not, cannot ask the Shakers to participate with them in any unspiritual
                            practice ; nor need any, friendly to the Shakers, fear their demoralization by associating
                            with those who alone have " despised the shame " of religiously comingling with the Shakers;
                            and, excepting the materialistic infidels (who are not so far from the kingdom of heaven as
                            the socalled orthodox churches), the Spiritualists alone have invited the Shakers to their
                            pulpits, granted them unrestricted liberties to preach, and who have become exstatic over
                            their ministrations. In various reforms, some Spiritualists are in advance of some Shakers;
                            herein those Shakers must advance or find themselves in the rear of advancing Spiritualists.
                            We live in a day of theological revolutions—and these will never go backward—and the cry of
                            the spirit is : " Forward, Shakers, forward !" and to the Spiritualists: "Be true to your
                            convictions of right!" And then in yonder heaven—a condition attained unto here or
                            hereafter, we shall be one in faith and in life. Until then we shall enjoy just that degree
                            of fellowship that proceeds from self-denial to ourselves of erroneous, earthly, unspiritual
                            conditions; by which self-denial we may " walk in the spirit and not fulfill the lusts of
                            the flesh. Amen. *</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Liberty, what is it?" TEIform="index"/>Liberty, What is It ?</head><p TEIform="p">I was led to the following thoughts by reading an article in the January number of the
                            current volume of the Phrenological Journal, entitled Political Klkgs. While I can approve
                            of much of the article referred to, I must confess that I was surprised at language like the
                            following, evincing, as it seems to, the spirit of bigotry and intolerance. And the more
                            surprising from the candor and liberality usually evinced by the editorials of the Journal,
                            and its progress in liberal ideas, and freedom from intolerance and bigotry, that forms so
                            prominent a feature of the Journal as a whole. After portraying, to some extent, the evils
                            of the political parties of the day, and of Tammany in particular, it goes on to discuss the
                            means for correcting this state of things in this wise: " We would require every man—not
                            imbecile, insane, criminal, or idiotic—to take part in the municipal State or National
                            affairs, whether he be Shaker, Quaker, or Communist. All who enjoy the privileges of our
                            free institutions, should be required not only to pay taxes, but to vote and to fight!" "
                            Should be required," of course, implies the right and power to compel to the acts required ;
                            and a disposition to use the compelling power. Now, as we, the Shakers, are one of the
                            classes named above, and may pass as representatives of the whole, let us look into this
                            matter; as the editor, a little farther on, informs us, that "eternal vigilance is the price
                            of liberty," civil or religious. And he also speaks, as dear and inalienable, of the right
                            to worship God according to the dictates of our own consciences. Perhaps the editor is not
                            aware that it is a part of the religious faith of the Shaker order to take no part in the
                            political movements of the times, either municipal, State or National, either directly or
                            indirectly; that, as Christians, we are called to be separate from the world, and that we
                            cannot, under any circumstances, mingle or take part in the affairs of the civil government,
                            or of political life, without sacrificing one of the foundational principles of our
                            religious faith and life. Then if we were to be compelled to do this, contrary to our honest
                            convictions of right and duty, what becomes of the so much boasted liberty of conscience,
                            the right to worship God according to its dictates ; which implies also the right to serve
                            God as our faith may lead us. If the editor is aware of our faith and real position on this
                            subject, I think there is, at least, an apparent inconsistency in the article referred to.
                            If he is ignorant in these respects, we advise him to read the ' Shaker,3 and other
                            publications of the Society, before stating, so positively, what he would do, or what he
                            would compel others to do, had he the power. But further—"should be required to vote and to
                            light." We can hardly think so wrell informed a writer as the editor of the ' The Journal'
                            can be ignorant of the fact that the Shakers, Quakers, and some others of the numerous
                            Communists of our country, have always been averse to war and bloodshed ; and have, from
                            motives of faith and conscience, abstained from, and refused to bear arms, or to learn the
                            arts of war as practiced by so-called Christian nations of our day, our own included. And
                            that they have steadily adhered to this course, not only when policy and prudence might seem
                            to dictate it as the path of safety, but also when persecution for this refusal stared them
                            in the face, or fell on their unoffending and unresisting heads; and the strong arm of
                            military and despotic power was stretched out for the purpose of compelling obedience to its
                            requirements; just as the editor would do, it seems, had he the power. It would seem that
                            so-well informed a man could not be ignorant of these facts; or that he should attribute our
                            adhesion to these principles and exemplifications of our faith and principles in our lives,
                            in these and other respects, to any other than honest conscientious motives; of obedience to
                            the light God has given us; and, that this being the case, he would think twice before he
                            again advocates such an arbitrary and unjust course as that marked out in the article
                            referred to ; and that while he prizes so highly the right to worship God, he will at least
                            be willing to accord to others, even Shakers, Quakers, or Communists, the same privilege and
                            the same rights.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cumings, Henry" TEIform="persName"/>Henry Cumings, Enfield, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Oneness of faith" TEIform="index"/>Oneness of Faith</head><p TEIform="p">Christ's Church is a school; the spirit of Christ the authorized and inspired teacher, and
                            believers are the pupils. Perpetual revelation of truths, new to the pupils, is the law of
                            eternal progression, the guiding star of destiny for the School of Christ. The scholars of
                            the primitive school announced a oneness of faith as the governing element in Christ's
                            Church, or School. " One Lord, one faith, and one baptism ; one God and Father (and Mother)
                            of all, who is above, and through, and in you all." Eph. iv. 5, 6. Should the question arise
                            what this oneness of faith has referenence to, or consists in, the Prophets and Apostles
                            conspire to answer it: First, to the Divine character of the School, and the authority of
                            the Master. For the Church of Christ is the Heavenly Jerusalem prophesied of by Zechariah
                            xiv. 9, in the day of which " there shall be one Lord and his name one." "And the seventh
                            angel sounded, and there were great voices in Heaven saying, The kingdoms of this world are
                            become the kingdoms of our Lord and of his Christ; and he shall reign forever and ever."
                            Eev. xi, 15. "And I saw a new heaven, and a new earth, for the first heaven and the first
                            earth had passed away; * * and I, John, saw the Holy City, New Jerusalem, coming down from
                            God out of heaven, prepared as a bride adorned for her husband." The primitive Church, of
                            Jesus and his Apostles, was the church of the bridegroom; the Church of Christ's second
                            appearing, is the Church of the Bride, the female dispensation of the coming of Christ. "And
                            I heard a great voice out of heaven saying, behold the tabernacle of God (the Church of
                            Christ) is with men, and he will dwell with them, and they shall be His people, and God
                            himself shall be with them and be their God." Rev. xxi, 1 to 4. Second. To the harmonious
                            union of the scholars. " For the Church of Christ being " one fold," John x. 16, and of "
                            one heart," Acts iv. 30, will have " access by one spirit" (Christ) "unto the Father," Eph.
                            ii. 18. Third. To the travel or progression of the pupils in the perception and reception of
                            truth and knowledge of godliness. " But unto every one is given grace according to the
                            measure of the gift of Christ," Eph. iv, 1; and on "till we all come into the unity of the
                            faith, and to the knowledge of the Son of God, unto a perfect man, unto the measure of the
                            stature of the fullness of Christ." " That ye henceforth be no more children, tossed to and
                            fro, and carried about with every wind of doctrine by the sleight of men, and cunning
                            craftiness, whereby they lie in wait to deceive." " But speaking the truth in love, may grow
                            up unto him in all things which is the head, even Christ." Thus, oneness of faith refers
                            prominently to the principle of an ever increasing revelation of the truths of God in
                            Christ's Church, manifest through the quickening spirit—Christ. And as truth is eternal,
                            there will be a oneness of faith in all souls who have traveled, or progressed to the same
                            degree of light and Christian baptism, so as to perceive, receive, feel and live the same
                            Christian testimon}'; 26 <pb n="27" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> THE S H .A. K E !R . that is, those who have
                            learned the same leasons in Christ's School. But these lessons are practical life lessons,
                            taught by facts. " Go and tell John the things ye see and hear " (Jesus). " If ye believe
                            not my words, believe for the icork's sake, for these are they which testify of me" (Jesus).
                            Yet, as all souls in the kingdom of Christ have first to be begotten, then born of God, when
                            they may gradually travel in growth to become of full stature; so infants and children in
                            Christ's School cannot have the same standard of development of faith as attained by men and
                            women of God, yet, " one faith Will govern their lives; that is, confidence in, and reliance
                            upon obedience to every degree of revealed truth, for justification. But the word faith
                            implies more than mere belief; it expresses an inclination of the heart, an impulse and
                            confidence of the soul, while belief is simply an action of the mind, and may be entirely
                            speculative and erroneous ; hence, a person for a time may entertain a very false
                            conception, belief, or creed concerning God or Christ, and yet have a true faith,
                            confidence, or trust in Him, which may guide his life in righteousness, so that he will
                            eventually come to the belief of truth only. The expression is often used with propriety, "
                            I have faith to believe thus and thus." Hence, persons of different beliefs, in some points,
                            may live in obedience to the same and one faith. Belief is not always regulated by the
                            reasoning faculties, or the truth of things. Persons often believe, from predjudice and
                            ignorance, things to be true which are very false, or in false principles, sophisms,
                            &amp;c. " Oh, I've heard him talk " Like the first-born child of love, when every word,"
                            " Spoke in his eyes, and wept to be believed," And all to ruin me.'¦—Southern. One person
                            conceives of, and believes God to be a personal being, having form, dimensions, and
                            passions, to which those of man are analogous, thus necessarily finite as to the occupation
                            of space, the wield of power, and the assumption of dignity, therefore not a supreme, but
                            only a superior being. While a different mind cannot conceive of God as a finite being
                            having form, but rather etherial; an inexpressible and inconceivable, subtile, and
                            infinitely dispensed latent power, different throughout all creation—a creative principle ;
                            the former of all forms, but surpassing the extent of form conceivable to the human mind —a
                            power that, saith the poet, " Lives through all life, extends through all extent, Spieads
                            undivided, operates unspent.1' One person conceives of evil as originating from an evil god
                            called, in common parlance, the devil, whom they understand to be coeternal with the good
                            God, and equally self-existing, and as independent of the good God, as God is of him; hence,
                            that evil is no more destructible than good. While another mind conceives that some of the
                            created intelligences o: the good God originated evil by putting things of God's creation
                            out of order; hence, thai evil is not eternal, and the devil can be destroyed. And yet,
                            while the mental conceptions and beliefs of these different individuals so prominently
                            oppose each other, they may all have one faith in the work of God, through Christ, for
                            salvation, and their lives conform .0 one standard of righteousness. And it may not be
                            anticipated nor desired, that, in all hings a sameness of intellectual perception shall be
                            attained, and that the thoughts of all minds shall flow in the same channels. And he saints
                            of the Church of the "Latter Day" lave no need to teaze their zeal into a foam to make
                            converts to some creed of so-called Christianity, by torturing the bodies of unbe- lievers;
                            nor to bathe their hands in human gore to reclaim heretics; to do what God lever attempted
                            to do—make all human minds to think alike ! The history of the ages is bathed in the )lood
                            of martyrs to creeds ; but creeds—theoogical dogmas—perhaps the sophisms of metaphysical
                            philosophy—the mere objects of faith, shut and bar the door of revelation from God, ind
                            narrow the human understanding to the application of one specific for all the diseases the
                            soul is heir to, and all the doses in the same proportions ; they tether the soul to the
                            sounds of the present degree of understandingconcerning God and Christ, however far short of
                            the whole truth that may be. They are ;he fevered pulsations of life that generate those
                            foul ulcers of hatred and strife which aave put millions of persons to the sword and
                            instruments of torture and death, because they were heretical to what ? Not to a godly life,
                            but to an idea 1 While the true Christian faith, a soul baptism of life in God, opens the
                            pathway of unlimited progression in the knowledge, and practice of godliness and grace,
                            adapting the gift of God and the means of salvation to the ever varied and changeful
                            vicissitudes of lost souls in every situation, and its fruit is love to the whole family of
                            man ! The final answer, then, to the great question, " What is the essential principle of
                            unity of faith ?" is to live wholly to God; "If any man will do His will he shall know of
                            the doctrine, whether it be of God, or whether I speak of myself," John vii, 17. " But
                            whosoever shall do and teach them (these commandments) shall be called great in the kingdom
                            of heaven." Hence, " oneness of faith " in the Christian Church, radically considered,
                            refers to the credit and confidence of the mind and trust of the affections of the heart to
                            a truth manifested to the understanding, or illustrated by practical life ; for the power of
                            God, of principles, of persons, and the virtue of things, are the only proper objects of
                            faith; and these are substantially learned only by their fruits. If, then, the souls of the
                            children of God, all led and governed by the spirit of Christ, flow together to partake of,
                            and disseminate the feast of His great salvation and redemption to humanity, it is well and
                            it is enough !</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>Giles B. Avery</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Which is the greater?" TEIform="index"/>Which is the Greater?</head><p TEIform="p">How is it that Christians place so much stress on the bodily crucifixion of Jesus, and have
                            fixed their hopes for ages in the atoning blood of one man ? For certainly the Spirit of
                            God, the essence of deity in the man Jesus, could not have been the sufferer by a physical
                            death. If there is an inherent virtue and an atonement for sin in the Master's physical
                            crucifixion, why ignore the atoning effect of a disciple's dying; and teaching the gathered
                            multitudes through the space of three days, tied to a cross ? For whom did the myriads
                            suffer; who endured death in its most terrible forms, by beasts of prey, burnings, and the
                            vilest passions of men ? Was it for their own atonement ? or was the death of Jesus, upon
                            the cross, but an example to his disciples to suffer all things, even cruel physical pain,
                            to maintain that liberty of spirit which the truth had given ? How vastly exceeding any
                            mortal agonj)was the mental anguish, buffetings and temptations of which Jesus shared with
                            his brethren ! Is that severe ordeal, passed through in the comparatively short space of
                            forty-eight hours, to be compared with the recorded wrestle with the spirit of temptation in
                            himself, after his baptism, forty days and nights ? We believe that many Christians now liv-
                            ing can testify by the same spirit to the like experience, in all but degree; who feel that
                            the daily crucifixion of their carnal lives in obedience to Christ's command, " follow me,"
                            is infinitely more tedious and painful, humbling, and finally atoning, than to walk
                            resolutely to the stake and burn. Where ambition, finds no room, no patriotism is required;
                            no hero worship allowed nor opportunity given for the display of great and ennobling deeds;
                            nought but the almost unnoticed performance of duties with faithfulness every day to keep
                            the energy of a Christian life at fervent heat—this is certainly a cruci- fixion with and
                            following Christ; and Christ thus followed, will carry the spirit in victory over all
                            physical pain. If the prescience of Providence designed for aught the sorrowful, though not
                            uncommon end of Jesus, how much more consistent that he should meet it as an example to his
                            disciples, who could not do otherwise than bleed freely for the principles of the cross,
                            under the power of the savage human nature of that day. What but the self interest of a
                            deliberate life of sin, contrary to the life of Christ, could so blind the reason and
                            pervert the understanding of the educated, powerful, and apparently pious minds, who have
                            studied the atonement of Jesus for their own hope, and to sustain the hope of others, that
                            salvation in their sins is possible, and that salvation from the practice of sin is not a
                            necessity ?</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, H." TEIform="persName"/>H. HOLLISTER Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Golden age" TEIform="index"/>Golden age
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Golden Opinion of " The Golden Age."—Elder Evans, in a late letter to this office, says : '•
                            Of all the newspapers I have seen, The Golden Age has my largest esteem. Its columns fairly
                            overflow with exuberant truth. Among its contributors may be observed men and women who are
                            thoroughly in earnest after truth—a class of reformers who know what truth is, and are
                            determined to find it in its fullness. It deserves success, and I believe will' enjoy
                        it."'</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Babel builders" TEIform="index"/>Babel Builders</head><p TEIform="p">It would seem that Noah's posterity became quite as corrupt as the antediluvians. Instead of
                            placing their confidence in a life of virtue that would elevate them above judgments, they
                            conceived the idea of escaping by a high 27 <pb n="28" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> THE SH^KEH. tower; and it
                            is even intimated in Gen. 11, 6, that they might possibly succeed. Taken literally, it was a
                            senseless proceeding to attempt to reach heaven after this manner, however much flood might
                            be escaped. But do we not find among so-called Christian sects to-day as much Babylon in
                            theologies and as much error in their anticipations ? No complicated system of theology will
                            save any one, no matter how extensive its display, nor flattering its prospects. Those who
                            build up as a substitute for a pure life any structure of mere faith, will find they are
                            Babel builders ; the whole will come tumbling down and necessitate a new foundation. While
                            the only true theology and religion is the practice of Christ's life in all of its
                            self-denials, this being eternal because it is pure, containing no elements of error nor
                            decay.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dibble, C." TEIform="persName"/>C. Dibble. Shakers, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phenomenal" TEIform="index"/>Phenomenal</head><p TEIform="p">The following questions and answers will be interesting to all. One peculiarity will bo
                            observed, that the answers were given through a Shaker Sister—A. Z. Potter—months before the
                            questions were propounded, and both purporting to come from the same spirit—Seth Y. Wells.
                            The Shaker Sister writes : " On the evening of March 25, soon alter I had retired, I heard
                            m3T name called distinctly. I arose, went to the door, but found no person there. Soon after
                            Seth Y. Wells came to me, and invited me to go with him. I reluctantly complied. We went to
                            a telegraph office, where were many spirits I knew, and more I did not know. I was requested
                            to copy all that came over the wires. I did so, though the substance was quite
                            unintelligible tome; for, as nearly as I could understand, it was answers to questions some
                            person had put to some other person ; who, or what the questions were, I could not tell.''
                            The boy did not know of the answers being already given ; and yet the questions were given
                            and numbered, seriatim, with the answers. The following questions were given through the
                            mediumship of a boy 12 years of age, at the house of D.D.Phelps, in Stratford, Conn.,
                            September 7th, 1850. The sentences were rapped out letter by letter. The medium was an
                            entire stranger, never having previously seen a Shaker. 1st. 1st. Why are spirits per-
                            Because, in this mitted to visit differmerciful dispensation the " Answers were given in
                            vision through the mediumship of a Shaker Sister, on the evening of March 25th, 1850, five
                            months and eighteen days previous to the questions. Answers were given at Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.
                            A. Z. Potter, Medium. ent denominations ? 2d. Will the Lord manifest himself to all
                            unbelievers ? 3d. Why are relatives the ones employed to make these communications ? Lord
                            sees fit to become all things to all men. 2d. Yes, He "will con- tinue to meet each one in
                            his own path, and show them his power according to their dark views of his all-wise decrees
                            and mysterious doings. 3d. Because there is a more nearness of feeling and affection between
                            relatives, and a knowledge of many things can be obtained in this way, that is be}rond
                            contradiction. 4th. Why is there no injury ever done to any person ? 5th. Does the Lord
                            in;end these manifestations to become universal ? 6th. Can all persons command the spirits ?
                            7th. Will the knockings soon cease I 8th. Will man have power to control the knockings by
                            defi ance ? 9th. From whom do they receive the correct information i 10th. Why do the
                            spirits not speak without the knockings and other manifestations ? 11th. Is it not confined
                            to any particular people ? 12th. Then it does not oelong to the Shakers only ? 4th. This,
                            also, is an indulgence from a for- bearing God. 5th. I cannot answer you myself; but my
                            friend will soon. 6th. No; there will be means provided by a more holy power than we
                            possess; and the spirits will proceed in conformity to the will of the sincere, so far as
                            they have permission. 7th. This almighty work will increase and go on till every nation,
                            kindred and tongue shall taste of the mer- cy that quickeneth the rod sent forth by a just
                            and equitable God 8th. No mortal will have power to do that; although some have presumed to
                            defy the spirits to give them a sat- isfactory answer. 9th. From the angels and spirits of
                            the justified before death. 10th. The Holy Spirit suffers it now for a more perfect
                            confirmation ; but the power is sufficient without the aid of philosophy or any material
                            substance to act upon the mind. 11th. No. God nor the Holy Spirit has any respect to person,
                            sex, condition, color nor persuasion. 12th. No; but their declarations are literally
                            fulfilling; and I doubt not that they, as a first favored people, will rejoice that their
                            fellow-creatures are sharing a similar notice of God.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Word in prose with a poetical illustration" TEIform="index"/>A Word in Prose with a Poetical
                            Illustration</head><p TEIform="p">We have received the following from some friend whom we do not know, but whose sympathies,
                            conjoined to many others, to us made manifest, we appreciate. The undersigned is decidedly
                            of the opinion that the so-called " Shakers " have a providential place in the economy of
                            the " Kingdom of Heaven," of which the sects in general are, as yet, not sufficiently
                            cognizant. I am quite certain that, in various particulars, I should essentially differ from
                            them; but, for all that, there is a certain principle in their practical formula and vital
                            life which should be specially considered by the religious world at large. Not to enter into
                            this topic more fully at present, let us test the point in question by the following brief
                            Psalm or Hymn. To whom is the " door " of the " Kingdom " more fully opened to-day; and who
                            have more entirely entered in to the spirit and practical adaptation of its principles, than
                            have the disciples of Mother Ann Lee ? Many of the truer and vital forms of Faith can speak
                            of " rest unto the soul," but merely from the influence of their beautiful convictions;
                            while in their external relations they are yet attached to " the world," and are joined in
                            with its selfish methods, and fully (?) subject to its corrosive cares and vexations, to say
                            nothing of its falsities, frivolities and ferocities. Such, in sentimental measure and
                            feeling, can sing, in the expression of our rhythmical subject below—we have sought—we have
                            found the Lord—we arc happy in our trust in Thee, etc. ! but yet what class, like the
                            Shakers, can absolutely and genuinely speak of themselves as " from the world won away ? " "
                            In the soul's calm retreat, safe and blest." " Till self-styled Christian society makes its
                            system practical and vital in Christ," the special unction of a spiritual song, like the
                            following, will find its most appropriate re- sponse from the hearts and lips of a people
                            who are so unific in the spirit of Christ, as are our Shaker friends. Those who, under the
                            name of Spiritual-ists, are assuming just now to control the great spiritual movement of the
                            age, can surely lay scarcely the shadow of a claim to any particular appreciation to our
                            poetic theme; it is indeed a question whether they have, in any degree, the estimate of
                            Jesus Christ as the "Master," "Lord" or "Savior," which would enable any of their Journals
                            to publish it as expressive of the finer element of their cause. The real "first fruits" of
                            the spirit movement, however, are up to the point presented in this effusion, and the people
                            of the Shaker Communities can sing the annexed verses from the hearts and voices of true
                            workers in religion and reform. "Knock and it Shall be Opened unto You." We wait and we
                            watch at thy portals, dear Lord, We invoke thee with patience and prayer ; We remember the
                            counsel and call of thy word And we knock—Blessed One art thoii there ? Our hearts are not
                            faint though we come from afar, Though we've struggled and toiled to the end ; For thy love
                            has sustained us—thy door has no bar, Yet we knock—dost thou hear us, dear friend ? We
                            listen in silence ; no sound of thy voice Has announced that thy presence is nigh ; But we
                            smile through our tears, for in Faith we rejoice, As we knock—wilt thou now make reply ? Lo
                            ! the door opens wide, and Jesus appears Full of goodness and cheer—conie to win ; And he
                            cries, as his hand wipes away all our tears, " Y*e who knock, welcome home ! enter in. !" 0,
                            happy are we, from the world won away, In the soul's calm retreat safe and blest; And to all
                            who yet wander we earnestly say, Come and knock—and with Christ be at rest.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Mandell, D. J." TEIform="persName"/>D. J. Mandell</byline></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="F. W. Evans and G. A. Lomas occupied the platform..." TEIform="index"/>F. W. Evans and G. A. Lomas occupied the platform...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">F. W. Evans and G. A. Lonias occupied the platform of the Troy Spiritualists, morning and
                            evening of Feb. 25.</p></div2><pb n="29" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Providence" TEIform="index"/>Providence</head><p TEIform="p">"With dark, foreboding thoughts oppressed I wandered forth one summer's day : Hoping abroad
                            to ease my breast, And grief allay. Deep in a lone and green retreat I laid me down, with
                            many a sigh; When lo! a daisy at my feet Allured my eye. Methought, with sympathetic smile,
                            It seemed to pity, and reprove; And thus my bitter cares beguile With words of love : " Sad
                            mortal, cease thy anxious sighs! Why sit you down in sorrow here ? Does not each leaf that
                            meets thine eye Reprove thy fear? " Although a mean, unheeded flower, My daily wants are all
                            supplied; And he who brought me to this hour, Will still provide. " The light and dew, the
                            sun and rain, Are daily seen to foster me; And fearest thou God will not deign To think of
                            thee ?" Ashamed, I rose : rebuked my care, And blest the teacher of the sod; Resolved, to
                            chase away despair And trust in God.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Immaculate conception" TEIform="index"/>Immaculate Conception</head><p TEIform="p">The immaculate conception doctrine of the Catholic Church, results from the belief of the
                            possibility and practicability of a pure spiritual gospelized generation, in past ages, as
                            recorded in Jewish history—Isaac, John Baptist and Jesus, being only instances under a
                            general law. This doctrine is the basic foundation of Gentile—generative—Christianity. While
                            the Catholic Church numbers marriage among the sacraments, it yet recognizes celibacy as the
                            highest form of Christianity; and requires it undeviatively of the priesthood and of all the
                            monastic orders, as being essential to a true life of spirituality. With Protestants, that
                            "light has become darkness; " to them, salvation is by faith, independent of works. " The
                            man of sin sitteth in the temple " or church, and is sanctified out and out. Commencing with
                            the dogma of " total depravity," they depend en- tirely upon the " imputed righteousness "
                            of somebody who suffered for their wrong-doing, and " in their stead; " and not at all upon
                            their own good, true, and honest works, to form to themselves a genuine Christian character.
                            Believing Jesus to be God, they look for him to come, personally, to each "seeker," without
                            the intervention of any mediators; either man, woman, tutelar or subordinate gods. Salvation
                            is a matter of will and favor, rather than of character and principle. Hence the vilest
                            sinner can be transmuted into the best of saints in a moment of time, and just before they
                            draw their last earthly breath. As " there is no repentance in the grave' no probation in
                            eternity—at death, each becomes, instantaneously, a devil, or a saint anc angel. After
                            admitting such premises, it easy to swallow a camel, and to accept the remainder of the "
                            doctrines of devils," which have no foundation either in reason or revelation. The
                            reanimation and transmutation of the physical bodies of mankind into spiritual bodes, with
                            corollary dogmas, equally absurd, ire some of the logical sequences which flow rom the
                            interblcnding of the dispensations and spheres—of natural and spiritual ideas— ,hat commence
                            with the confused notion of a spiritualized, holy, generation, that ultimated n an
                            "immaculate conception," by the Holy Ghost or the Virgin Mary, of the most abused man Jesus
                            of Nazareth. In plain English, reproduction appertains exclusively to the material earths,
                            which are ;he ultimates of all spiritual spheres and worlds—the lowest,-most outward and
                            external of all the " many mansions" or planes of existence in the realms of thought, or
                            known ;o human consciousness. Consequently, while natural generation—the reproduction of
                            souls conjoined to animal human bodies—has its proper appropriate plane on the earth and in
                            she earth ; for there are corresponding invisible spheres, which are the sources of
                            vitality, back to deity—the innermost of all spheres— and agents as angels in them, who are
                            God's ministers—as parents are creators, in the place and stead of deity—intermediate and
                            subordinate powers and principalities—as is the order of existences in the world we inhabit.
                            Human association exhibits ascending spheres from the most low and animal, to the most
                            interior, intellectual and spiritual. The Shaker Order is but the innermost and central
                            sphere on the earth. " That which is born of the flesh is flesh ; " and Jesus was as truly
                            born of the flesh as were Adam and Eve, and as have been all their posterity. " That which
                            is born of the spirit is spirit;" and Jesus needed to be begotten and born of the Spirit as
                            really as any other man of the race of Adam, before he could become a Son of God in the
                            spiritual order of the resurrection. Adam was a " Son of God" on the natural plane, by his
                            first birth, and was as " holy a thing" as was the child Jesus. And it was as impossible for
                            Jesus to be born the Christ— a spiritual being—as it was for x^.dam to have been born a
                            spiritual being; that which is natural is first, and afterwards that which is spiritual. It
                            is the only way that God can do things, because he is governed by law just as much as we
                            are, or ought to be. Right here must commence a line of demarcation between a believer of
                            pure simple Chris- tianity, and a Babylon Christian, who mixes generation and regeneration,
                            natural and spir- itual, light and darkness, good and evil, and the good of one plane, with
                            the good appro- priate only to a different plane, together—thus making confusion or Babylon.
                            Without faith in Christ — interior to all earthly and generating spheres—visible or
                            invisible—as the mediator between God, who is spirit, per se, and man who " also is flesh,"
                            there can be no spiritual begetting as " new birth" into the Christ sphere. For if Christ is
                            the second Adam and Eve—a quickening spirit—it is just as impossible for any natural son or
                            daughter of the race of the first Adam and Eve—Jesus included—to become a son or daughter of
                            God—a spiritual man or woman— resurrected from the natural order of generation, up to the
                            spiritual order of regeneration— except by a baptism of the second Adam and Eve, as a
                            quickening spirit, to beget and bear them, such as Jesus was the subject of, as it would be
                            for a natural child to be begotten and born, except through representatives—successors—of
                            the first Adam and Eve; and it would be as unnatural and unreasonable to expect the first
                            Adam and Eve to beget and bear all human beings, as it is for the generating Babylon
                            Christian to first call Jesus " the second Adam," and then look to him as their only and
                            immediate spiritual Savioiir and father, when he has left to them no spiritual posterity—no
                            successors or representatives. It is the Christ outside of the first Adam— that is, the
                            great Mediatorial Sphere—the sec- ond or spiritual Adam and Eve—which is the agent to
                            transfer all the forces and powers of man and woman from the natural to the spiritual plane
                            of their existence. Yea, " though I have known Christ after the flesh, as Jesus, yet now
                            henceforth know I him no more," in that way. In the Jewish generative heavens there were
                            prophesyings, as there was on earth, of a human being who should be the first to be begotten
                            from the dead order of the flesh into the living order of the Spirit. And when the event
                            occurred, there came prophetesses and prophets from both the generative earth and the
                            generative heavens, to announce the advent of the coming extraordinary man. Not that the
                            prophets or angels of either sphere com- prehended the significance of the event they
                            celebrated—but, the Christ Spirit moving upon them, modified their utterances. Of themselves
                            they did not, could not understand the spiritual resurrection, of which Jesus was destined
                            to be the first fruits; a specimen of what each and every one of the race, to which he
                            belonged, might become in time or in eternity. The Christ heavens were "far above all of the
                            generative heavens" of these inquiring angels; hence they earnestly desired to "look into
                            them," and to understand what the inspiring spirit in them did signify by the words of their
                            own mouth. The wise men of the East, and the angels, united in singing a joyful generative
                            song. But how widely different was the " new song " of the resurrection, which John the
                            Revelator heard while in a visionary condition, and of which he wrote—that was a song which
                            no generative man or angel could learn; Jesus himself could not sing it until after John had
                            baptized him with the Christ Spirit. When the Christ " Spirit descended in bodily shape as a
                            dove," it claimed Jesus as the first begotten from the dead, the first born among many
                            brethren, who confessed and forsook sin—all generative sin— the primary cause of all death
                            —and called upon him to die to his generative life—that he might be quickened into a true
                            Christ life—become a Christian. Thus Jesus was born of a woman, under the Law; but was not
                            born the Christ until thirty years of age. Of that second birth, the angels and the wise men
                            of the East knew no more than Nicodemus, for no one could call Jesus by his spiritual name,
                            unless like Peter, he had a similar baptism. And true Christians are only known to each
                            other in that way. Antichrist adheres to the man, <pb n="30" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 30 THE SHAKER and
                            ignores the Christ. " But as a living dogis better than a dead lion," so is a living elder
                            of to-day of more value to a lost soul, in protecting, directing, and saving it, than all
                            the dead saints of the past, Jesus and Ann included. He is of more value than a legion of
                            angels without a medium. The father and mother of Jesus, when he lay in a manger, were
                            better to him than would have been Michael and Gabriel, with all their angel companions. The
                            second appearing of Christ is necessary to lead us into a knowledge of the first appearing,
                            as we are led into a knowledge of our natural ancestry, through the kind offices of our
                            papillary nurse. Personal travel in the spiritual order of the resurrection will demonstrate
                            to any soul the fact, that as is the union between Christ and Belial—flesh and spirit—so is
                            the union of a genuine Shaker with the immaculate conception of Mary and the most holy
                            generation of Jesus. As the baptism of fire burns up the generative life—the testimony of
                            the Christ Spirit pierced, as a sword, through the bowels or womb of the Virgin Mary.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="E., F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. E. Mt. Lebanon, Columbia Co., N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reform" TEIform="index"/>Reform</head><p TEIform="p">"----is joined to idols ; let him alone." Hos. 4, 17. Editor op the Shaker : The signs of the
                            times emphatically point to a period in the future, when believers will, in all human
                            probability, enjoy the blessing of a re-vitalization of all their now dormant energies; and,
                            as we fondly hope and fervently pray, a rich harvest of honest and faithful workers, and an
                            advent of spirits from the ranks of the sincere and sin-sick of the world, into our midst,
                            who are more than satisfied, even disgusted with the low, groveling pleasures of the
                            rudimental plane of existence. But I have a very strong impression, that before this
                            glorious day of gladness and prosperity shall be ushered in, and a dispensation of truly
                            spiritual growth, and development in purity, peace, and personal righteousness, be the un-
                            speakable boon of Zion to enjoy, a thorough and radical Physiological Reform must indis-
                            pensably precede. And this, inside of, as well as outside of Zion; and from the child of
                            five years old, up to the octogenarian. T am persuaded that, abnormal, unnatural, artificial
                            stimuli, by which the passions and animal powers of man are terribly and ruinously
                            intensified, far beyond the control of reason or religious conviction, and by which these
                            are actually destroyed oftentimes, are now, and have been for years, the potent cause of our
                            failure in obtaining valuable and reliable material from the world, wherewith to build up,
                            support, and retain intact the interests and behests of this, our beautiful and glorious
                            organization ! And parry the matter as we may, the truth must and will remain, that a holy
                            spirit cannot exist in an unhealthy, physical organization. For instance, if one's blood,
                            brain, nerves and muscles, are saturated with the narcotic principle of that filthy,
                            detestable drug, tobacco, how is it possible that normal energy and activity of the spirit
                            can be enjoyed, and that those calm heavenly inspirations should be accessible, which pure,
                            healthy, physical structures are constantly blessed Avith. 0 how excessively nasty and
                            loathsome is the tobacco inebriate ! I am weary unto death with the detestable practice of
                            chewing and smoking tobacco among believers ! But this is going but a very little way into
                            the subject, and I fear I might encroach too narrowly upon the tender feelings of some, if I
                            should define my ideas of sincere, physiological integrity in regard to food, drink, air,
                            exercise and sleep; the only really therapeutic agents in the earth or sky. But really we
                            shall be forced, ere long, to overhaul this whole subject, if the signs of the times are at
                            all to be depended upon. Thousands, outside of our institution; are probing this terrible
                            abscess on the vitals of society, to the very core, and coming into a conscientious,
                            practical atonement, with physiological truth. These are upright men and women of God;
                            determined, at all sacrifice, to live in holy allegiance to their convictions. These are the
                            salt of the earth, full of a sweet and salutary virtue; and if we, as a Christian
                            institution, desire an accession of such noble souls, to help us carry on to perfection the
                            noblest, mental, moral and spiritual structure ever reared for the benefit and happiness of
                            the race, then must we get right into the forefront of this great physiolog- ical conflict
                            with time-honored errors, sinful habits and animal indulgences, and cleanse our temple of
                            all filthiness of flesh and spirit; that when sin-sick and sin-ridden souls come into our
                            midst, we can welcome them to an asylum of peace and righteousness, where, in deed and in
                            truth, their highest, holiest aspirations for a sinless life can, and may be realized. How
                            mortifying, not to say humiliating and shameful, to have to begin to apologize to one of
                            these physiological reformers for our use of tea, coffee, tobacco and alcohol! For fourteen
                            years we abjured these drugs, and why can we not do it now, since our illumination upon this
                            subject is far greater than when we cheerfully submitted to their prohibition ? How often
                            have I thought, how happy I should be, to be one of a family, or society, who, for ten
                            consecutive years, would agree to abstain from tobacco, tea, coffee, flesh meat, and every
                            species of intoxicating liquors, by way of experiment. It seems to me I am inspired by
                            heaven itself, to see the perfect beauty of holiness, such a family would exhibit to the
                            world, and enjoy among themselves ! Just consider for a moment the present, terrible state
                            of the world, through the instrumentality of artificial stimulation ! It is absolutely
                            frightful ! One generation has followed another in an increase of indulgence in this
                            abnormal process of stimulation, until the whole civilized world is a hideous mass of
                            disease and sin, voluptuousness and lust, followed up closely and inexorably by the
                            seething, red-hot indignation of insulted, violated, physiological law (which never
                            forgives), in the shape of idiocy, crime, insanity and "suicide, to crown the black,
                            infernal brood !" This horrible excitement from poisonous drugs, beverages and improper
                            aliments, develops the animal passions so precociously, that they blaze out in
                            uncontrollable fury, far ahead of the normal, animal instincts; and still farther ahead of
                            the reasoning and moral faculties ; consequently, thousands of boys and girls are, every
                            year, hopelessly ruined in body and soul, long before any instinct of selfpreservation,
                            moral or spiritual restraint, is possible to be brought to bear upon them, either by
                            themselves or by their friends. Is it any wonder then, that out of such material scarcely
                            any can be found who are able to live lives of uprightness and purity ? And is it Christian
                            tenderness that would refuse to love, cherish and suffer for the restoration of such ; or
                            that would saddle upon them the entire iniquity and conseqvient responsibility of a hundred
                            or a thousand generations of sinners before them ? It is not. It is simply cruel and utterly
                            uncharitable ! Poor young creatures, ma)r God and all heaven help you ! And I will
                            cheerfully add, what little I can do or say, for your reconstruction in holiness. Now, if we
                            were living in a manner perfectly normal and natural, we should be able to furnish
                            facilities for final, physiological perfection, and (gradually) spiritual redemption and re-
                            construction to these our unfortunate fellowbeings, which we never can furnish while
                            allowing amongst ourselves iniquitous accessories to abnormal development. It is as if we
                            were trying to baffle and restrain the unnatural and precocious development of impure and
                            unholy tendencies, by one class of means and incentives, while we are keeping in activity
                            another class directly calculated to stimulate and precociously develop these very
                            tendencies. Consequently, I am persuaded we should begin right here to lay the first stone
                            of that sublime structure, which it is now full time to begin to build upon, and which is to
                            exceed in glory, righteousness and beauty, all which up to this time, in the history of the
                            world, have preceded it. In consideration of this momentous subject, and my bright
                            anticipations thereupon, I feel happy in my unqualified endorsement of Elder Frederick
                            Evans' sentiments relative thereto; and should be happy to see his theories, in regard to
                            diet and physiological correctness, generally, fully experimented upon, for a number of
                            years; still more, I should like to be one of a family who should volunteer therein.
                            Finally, may the Lord make his face to shine upon us, and, by the serene brightness thereof,
                            may we be able to see our way clearly out of this present transition state, into the
                            undimmed glory, prosperity and happiness of that "new cycle," to which we are all looking
                            with such fond anticipation, is the sincere prayer of yours, faithfully,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, O. C." TEIform="persName"/>O. C. Hampton. G. A. Lomas, Editor Shaker</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Friendship" TEIform="index"/>Friendship</head><p TEIform="p">It is commonly the case, when we meet with trials of our faith, to feel that we have no
                            friends. But, do we realize what a true friend is ? Are we able to appreciate true
                            friendship ? We all want friends ; yet are quite unwilling, sometimes, to recognize them in
                            those "who tell us of our faults and show us how to correct them." Those who are willing to
                            bear with our faults, while we are exerting our<pb n="31" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHA.KER. 31 selves
                            to overcome them, are true friends; while those who are indifferent to our evil ways, bad
                            habits, unchristian behavior, etc., or who chastise us merely to display authority, are not
                            our friends, but enemies to our souls' best good. To be worthy of the forbearance of true
                            friendship, I realize T must give evidence of an improved disposition ; that there is a
                            proper length to forbearance—a point where mercy is encouragement to vice, rather than an
                            illustration of Christian friendship. Those who are ever singing the need of more charity,
                            are too often chanting desires for continued indulgences ; while to grant them such charity
                            would not be friendship; but rather, as President Lincoln expressed it, "mercy to the
                            individual is murder to the State !"</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Conroy, Henrietta" TEIform="persName"/>HENRIETTA CONROY Shakers, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Seed-time and harvest" TEIform="index"/>Seed-time and Harvest</head><p TEIform="p">Beneath the dark November sky, With the cold rain falling drearily, And the bleak wind
                            moaning and shrieking by, The seed o'er the land is cast; In the grave-like furrows the
                            grain doth lie Till the weary months are past. In curling mist and frosty air, And. weeping
                            skies, it lieth there; Or buried in the snows; or bare To every wind that blows, And night's
                            deep darkness, like despair, Hangs o'er it while it grows. It grows in spite of cloud and
                            blast And sullen rain, descending fast; And snow-wreaths thickly o'er it cast, And
                            thund'rous dark'ning skies. And every tempest, roaring past, Strengthens it as it lies.
                            Anon, a kindlier season shines— Warmth and light—the spring's soft signs, With many a
                            beauteous balsam, twines The breast of icy death; And the grain, in delicate, emerald lines
                            Springs up, a fairy birth. Then sunny months, in swift career, Bring up the lusty ripened
                            ear; And the golden, harvest-time draws near And the reaper whets his scythe; Till on the
                            day, the rich sheaves rear Their shapes on the landscape blithe. Sown in the dark, cold,
                            desolate daysReaped in the sunshine's mellow blaze Thus, in the dim and wond'rous ways Of
                            fate, are the deeds of men— Sorrow and trial, defeats, delays, Like storms, that soften the
                            grain, Must test the heart's aspiring claim; But every just and noble aim Shall pass the
                            ordeal, clear of blame; And, in the appointed hour, Bring forth its fruit of wealth or fame,
                            Of knowledge, wisdom, power. In the winds of scorn, the storms of hate, In the darkness of
                            hope, deferred full lateThrough days when the world shows deso;ate, Must sleep the good
                            deeds thou hast done. Patiently labor, patiently wait, Thy work shall see the sun. That
                            which was sown in the wintry air, Shall blossom and ripen when skies are fair; Though thine
                            should be many an anxious care Ere the harvest is gathered in ; Be stout to toil, and steady
                            to bear, The heart that is true shall win.</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">To J. B. V. and others: We do not know, as yet, the price of J. M. Peebles' pamphlet, soon to
                            be issued, entitled "Spiritualism, Shakerism, or Free Religion— Which ? '' but presume the
                            same will be about or less than the subscription price of The Shaker. Let us have a few
                            orders.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sympathy" TEIform="index"/>Sympathy</head><p TEIform="p">There is a power pervading the entire Universe, which manifests itself variously, yet with
                            quite similar results. That degree of it which permeates the solid spheres, flowing from
                            each to each, and uniting them together in indissoluble bonds, has received a name
                            significant of the influence exerted upon bodies of vast size and which are usually at
                            immense distances from each other. Other degrees of it, more subtile than this, are no less
                            potent, though they may not be so apparent to outward observation. That which exists in the
                            vegetable world manifests itself in a great variety of forms—in grasses, shrubs, trees,
                            fruits and flowers—yet there is in them all a similarity sufficient to determine the rank of
                            the botanic kingdom in the scale of existences. From the numerous aversions and repulsions
                            displayed by mankind and the inferior orders of animal existence, one might infer there
                            could be no common influence pervading the animal kingdom; yet the science of Animal
                            Magnetism unmistakably proves its existence. Were there not any, man could not obtain
                            control over the animals that he makes subservient to his use, nor be able to tame and dally
                            with the most ferocious of beasts. And were there no common feeling of brotherhood among
                            mankind, vain would be all efforts for the improvement and progress of the race, and our
                            expectations of a world where harmony forever reigns would be idle dreams. It is not
                            necessary to enter here into the numerous details of facts which the modern sciences of
                            Psychology and Spiritualism furnish to prove the truth of one common influence pervading the
                            entire race of man. These facts have been abundant, throughout the civilized world, for
                            years, and are within the reach of all who desire to acquaint themselves with them. There is
                            a prominent doctrine of Christianity which this diffusion of a common or sympathetic
                            influence serves to illustrate, and that is the doctrine of Christ's sacrificial offering.
                            Jesus is said to have died for our sins, or, more correctly, on account of our sins; to have
                            offered himself a sacrifice in our behalf. This has been construed as importing that he died
                            to suffer the penalty of all the sins of mankind, from the first one that transgressed the
                            divine law to the last of earth's inhabitants. The question is often asked how he, an
                            innocent person, could have died on account of the sins of all men; how "the chastisement of
                            our peace was laid on him, and the Lord laid on him the iniquity of us all," unless it was
                            to bear the penalty of sin in our stead. By his death is meant his crucifixion by the Jews
                            and Romans ; yet Jesus was not the only person who has suffered innocently. Many have died a
                            more aggravated death than that of Jesus, for no offence whatever; but no one is so
                            unreasonable as to suppose that a single transgressor of divine or human law could escape
                            punishment because of the death of these; and only because Jesus has been regarded as the
                            Supreme God, is infinite merit attributed to his death at the hands of his enemies. An
                            outrage was committed against him by the bigoted persons that demanded his death, but Divine
                            Justice holds even balances to re-weigh every human wrong. That " Jehovah should have made
                            his soul or life an offering on account of sin," was but an evidence of infinite love, both
                            towards Jesus and those in whose behalf he was offered; for he was to " see his seed,
                            prolong his days, and the pleasure of Jeiiovah was to prosper in his hands." Jesus certainly
                            suffered on account of the sins of all men, and in their behalf. How? By sympathy with all
                            as a human being. As one of us, he felt as we feel, participated in our miseries and shared
                            our burdens, so as to be a " merciful and faithful High Priest." For our sakes as well as
                            his own, " he endured the cross and despised the shame," throughout a life consecrated to
                            God. Whatever iniquities of mankind were laid upon him, he offered up in sacrifice by means
                            of his holy life of selfdenial. The Apostle Peter says to Christians : " Ye are a holy
                            priesthood to offer up spiritual sacrifices." In the same epistle in which these words
                            occur, our English version makes him say, speaking of Jesus Christ: " Who his own self bare
                            our sins in his own body on the tree." The same verb — anenengkai — which the translators in
                            the former passage have rendered to offer up, in the latter, without any sufficient reason,
                            they have translated bare. Rendering this, as it should be, to bear up or offer up, the
                            passage would read: "Who, himself, offered up our sins in his own person on the cross."
                            Hence the propriety of the inference drawn, " that we, being free from sin, should live unto
                            righteousness." Christ, as Head of the Church, offered up the sacrifices of sin in behalf of
                            all men; his Church, also, offer up the same sacrifices in behalf of all. " Christ suffered
                            for us, leaving us an example that we should follow his steps." Bearing or offering up the
                            sacrifices of sin is not confined to Jesus Christ nor to his Church, but is common to the
                            whole human race, by reason of the universal sympathy existing in the race—parents for their
                            children, and children for their parents; brothers and sisters for each other; the skillful
                            physician for his patients, who sometimes offers for both physical and moral diseases.
                            Healing mediums among Spiritualists are obliged to make an offering for sin in behalf of
                            those who apply to them for relief. Often, by magnetic sympathy with their patients, they
                            undergo sufferings similar to those endured by the latter before a cure is effected. There
                            never was a better example of sympathy with others and of offerings in their behalf, than
                            that of Mother Ann. This was conspicuous throughout her whole ministration of the gospel of
                            Christ. She frequently participated in the conditions of others, who were borne down by the
                            weight of their sins and afflictions, even when they were miles away from her, to such a
                            degree as to suffer extremely, both in body and spirit, on their account. And when they were
                            lightened of their burdens, and she, in consequence, was filled with the joys of the Spirit,
                            by ministrations from the heavenly world, thejr shared in her exceeding joy. By this she
                            proved herself a true spiritual Mother. The offerings of Mother Ann, as well as those of
                            Jesus Christ, were intended to be final; that is, to remove sin and its conse- quences
                            entirely from the Church; to raise <pb n="32" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 32 THE S H A. K E R . every member
                            of it from the sensuous to the spiritual life—from the life of earth to that of heaven. In
                            their own case, the offering was complete; and the result, eternal redemption, has been
                            experienced by each. If the Head is holy, so must the body be. The sympathy between Christ
                            and his Church can be only that of souls saved from their sins and born into the life of
                            heaven; who are wholly dissevered from the wars and contentions of earth, its lusts,
                            passions and pleasures, and live in the elements of peace and purity. Only when the Church
                            is such, can it be a true sympathizing priesthood or medium for those sacrifices that bring
                            eternal salvation to a sinning world. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, W. H." TEIform="persName"/>W. H. Bussell</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Truth, faith, and reason, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>Truth, Faith, and. Reason.—No. 2</head><p TEIform="p">God is truth. Truth is Increate—never began to be. It eternally was, and is, and will bo the
                            same unchangeable reality. How infinitely absured then is it for man, who is but of
                            yesterday, to try to alter or bend the truth to his inclinations ? We illustrate the
                            eternity and ubiquity of Truth by the following mathematical problem: " The three angles of
                            a triangle are equal to two right ones." The truth of this relation of angles to one-
                            another never began to be. It is eternal and ubiquitous. It exists equally in any and every
                            imaginary portion of the universe. It is as unchangeable and omnipresent as Deity. There are
                            certain moral relations, which have been discovered or revealed, that are as fixed in
                            Eternal and unchangeable Truth, as any mathematical problem whatever. "A rich man cannot
                            enter the kingdom of heaven." This is a truth revealed by Christ, and is a simple truism. It
                            informs us that the principles of the Kingdom of Heaven or Christian institution, which he
                            was about to establish, consisted in " Righteousness," a rigid equality of enjoytnents, and
                            that therefore a man possessing individual wealth could not enter or be admitted. " Ye
                            cannot serve God and Riches." Defining the " service of God," love, as we must, to signify
                            that perfect devotion to the Divine will, which Christ taught and exemplified, then we say,
                            that such " service of God," and the service of personal wealth can no more coexist and be
                            performed by any intelligent being in man's condition, than two parallel lines can cross
                            each other. Hence the impossibilit}^ of serving God as a Christian, and at the same time
                            serving Mammon or possessing personal wealth. The brotherly love, and perfect equality of
                            enjoyments which Eternal Truth enjoins on Christians, forever debars them from the
                            possession of individual wealth, and requires them to support a joint interest, and to have
                            all their goods in common. The possession of individual wealth, and equality of enjoyment,
                            are forever repugnant one with the other. Therefore no man while holding individual wealth
                            can ever enter into the Christian institution. The generative order and Church order, or
                            joint interest, are forever repugnant, and cannot coexist. The young man who came to Jesus,
                            and all others who would be his followers, were required to divest themselves of all
                            personal property, and were thus unfitted for raising offspring. As the generative order
                            necessarily requires a separate interest and the possession of personal proper^, it is
                            forever repugnant to the Christ order which requires a relinquishment of personal wealth. In
                            the generative order, the man and woman are " one flesh," and their relation to each other
                            is a flesh relation; but those joined to the Lord are " one spirit." " The flesh lusteth
                            against the spirit," that is, the flesh relation lusteth against the spirit relation. "And
                            these two are contrary, one to another." The truth of this antagonism is eternal—it is
                            founded in the very nature of things. They can never harmonize any more than truth and
                            error. " The flesh lusteth against the spirit, and these two are contrary to one another."
                            The truth of this irreconcilable conflict between flesh and spirit, did not then begin to
                            exist in the day when it was promulgated by Paul; it is eternal and ubiquitous—exists every
                            where in God's universe. The flesh relation existed from Adam to Moses, and from Moses to
                            Christ. Unceasing efforts were made to bring it into order and subject it to law. " Divers
                            washings " and carnal ordinances, with many restraints, were imposed by divine sanction, but
                            all without success. The eternal truth was thus developed as declared by Paul, that "the
                            carnal mind, the fleshly nature, is not subject to the law of God, neither indeed can be."
                            And "witnessed by the Martyr Stephen. " Ye do always resist the holy spirit, as your fathers
                            did, so do ye." Thus an experiment extending through 4000 years, develops an unbroken
                            testimony to the existence of an eternal truth—a fixed Law, that the flesh always resists
                            the spirit.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pelham, R. W." TEIform="persName"/>R. W. Pelham</byline></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Resolutions. Troy, February 25th, 1872" TEIform="index"/>Resolutions. Troy, February 25th, 1872
                        </head><p TEIform="p">At a regrnar meeting of the Board of Trustees of the Progressive Spiritualists, of Troy, the
                            following resolution was unanimously adopted : Resolved, That we extend a cordial invitation
                            to our Brothers and Sisters of the Shaker fraternity, residing in the Societies of Mt.
                            Lebanon, Watervliet and other places, to join us in a two days' Convention (or Conference),
                            in Troy, to be held on the 23d and 24th of March; to the end, that the ties of sympathy and
                            love may be strengthened and extended between us, and the truth matte manifest. (Signed.) B.
                            STAUIiUCK, President. B. C. BAKTO, Secretary. This invitation has been accepted, and will be
                            the occasion of a meeting of delegates, from various Shaker Societies, to a number exceeding
                            forty. * </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We anticipate a beautiful piece of music..." TEIform="index"/>We anticipate a beautiful piece of music...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"We anticipate a beautiful piece of music, for May number of The Shaker, from Canterbury.
                        </p></div2><div2 type="shaker-press" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In a late number of Woodhull and Claflin's Weekly..." TEIform="index"/>In a late number of Woodhull and Claflin's Weekly...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> In a late number of Woodhull and Clafl-iri's Weekly, we read with pleasure " The March of
                            Events,'1' ac- credited to a "Quaker Lady;'' but we soon substituted, By a Shaker Sister --
                            A. Doolittle</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In our leader of this number..." TEIform="index"/>In our leader of this number...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> In our leader of this number we use the terms "Spiritist" and "Spiritualist." The suffixes
                            are synonyms; but some Spiritualists, and nearly all eminent lexicographers, make a marked
                            distinction between Spirit-tste and Spirit-iialists—one, Spiritists, determining merely the
                            sensational phenomenalists,—who are content with table-tipping, raps, and all the physical
                            movements made by spirit agency, but who do not strive to become pure and heavenly
                            &gt;through its influence. In our leader we did not make this distinction as apparent as
                            we might. Again, we intended to remark therein, that what is denominated modern
                            Spiritualism, was, with us, a matter of prophecy thirty or forty years ago. Many eminent
                            Spiritualists have seen the Shaker Societies in full operation in " the better land," before
                            they knew of their whereabouts on the earth. Spiritualists take great pride in naming Robert
                            Owen as one of their number; but the fact that he was converted to a faith in the unseen, by
                            the mediumship of Daniel Offard, of Mt. Lebanon Shakers, is not commonly known, the details
                            of which we hope to present at some future time. We give Spiritualism the largest credit for
                            introducing Shaker theology to the attention of reformers, and we hope yet to admit that it
                            has been the most successful medium for accomplishing the fruits that grow from real,
                            Christian self-denial. * </p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ann Lee once prophecied, that..." TEIform="index"/>Ann Lee once prophecied, that...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Ann Lee once prophecied, that she saw individuals flocking to the standard, of which she was
                            hearer, hy hundreds and by thousands ! In view of the few representatives of Shaker
                            principles, this sounds oddly enough; but there have been millions flocking to the doors of
                            our theology for many years—the prophecy is more than fulfilled in a very marvelous and
                            encouraging manner. * </p></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="J. M. Peebles and Dr. E. C. Dunn spent an                             agreeable season at                                 Watervliet, New York" TEIform="index"/>J. M. Peebles and Dr. E. C. Dunn spent an agreeable season at Watervliet, New York...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">J. M. Peebles and Dr. E. C. Dunn spent an agreeable season at Watervliet, N. Y., on the 26th
                            of February. An impromptu Society meeting was called, and all moved satisfactory to all who
                            participated. *</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Members of society" TEIform="index"/>MEMBERS OF SOCIETY</head><p TEIform="p">Appointed to answer Correspondents, among whom are the Board of Editors. Elder F. W. Evans,
                            Mt. Lebanon. Columbia Co., N. Y. " Issachar Bates, Shakers, &gt;J. Y. " Calvin G. Keed,
                            Mt. Morris, Livingston Co., N. Y. " Simon Mabee, West Pittsfield. Mass. " Stoughton Kellogg,
                            Thompsonville, Conn., Shakers. " Albert Battles, Tyringham, Berkshire Co., Mass. Wm.
                            Leonard, Ayer, Mass., Shakers. " Jonas Nntting, Shirley Village, Middlesex Co., Mass. "
                            Benj. H. Smith, Shaker Village, Merrimack Co., N. H. " Henry Cummings, Enfield, Grafton Co..
                            N. H. " John B. Vance. Alfred, Shakers. York Co., Me. " Alonzo Gilman. West Gloucester,
                            Cumberland Co., Me., Shakers. " Chas. Clapp, Union Village. Warren Co., O., Shakers. " Ezra
                            Sherman, Preston. Hamilton Co., Ohio, Shakers. " Stephen Ball, Dayton. Shakers. Ohio. "
                            Jacob Knlp, Pleasant Hill, Mercer Co., Ky. " J. B. Eades, South Union. Logan Co., Ky. " J.
                            S. Prescott, Cleveland, Ohio, Shakers.</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>