<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm0904" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title><editor role="editor" TEIform="editor"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/></editor></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">9</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">4</biblScope><date value="18790401" TEIform="date">April 1879</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">73-96</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="9" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="4" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                <pb id="p1"/>
                        <p> APRIL, 1879. MANIFESTO. (OFFICIAL, MONTHLY.) G. A. LOMAS, Editoe. Published by the United Societies. OUR HOME AT
                        HARVARD, MASS. "And they shall turn to you for a testimony: " '' Go 'preach the Kingdom of God ! " Vol. IX. j No. 4.
                        ! 60 Cents Per Annum. G. B. AVERY, PUBLISHER. 1879. ADDRESS ALL COMMUNICATIONS TO " The Shaker Manifesto, Shakers,
                        N.D." </p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
--><pb n="73" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spirituality" TEIform="index"/>SPIRITUALITY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Devyr, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/>CECELIA DEVYR</byline><p TEIform="p">'Tie not in loving God afar, In overstraining human powers, In spirit flights from star to
                            star, In quest of bright eternal bowers. 'Tis not in weighing scriptural words, Nor studying
                            cabalistic signs, *'Tis not in watching flights of birds, Nor poring over sulphur shrines.
                            'Tis not in wild, ecstatic thought, The zeal that madness close allies, Nor in conversions,
                            lightly caught, From passing meteors in the skies. 'Tis not in formal rite or prayer; 'Tis
                            not in all perfected creeds ; 'Tis not in saintly robe nor air, In chalice font,, nor sacred
                            beads. The heavenly kingdom is within The common things that mortals slight And love alone
                            can entrance win, Into its holy pure delight. The heart must love, and loving, know By
                            intuition's subtile powers— The" undercurrent tides that flow, Throughout this wondrous life
                            of ours. The rapturous soul, that soars above The vale that true affection yields, Will find
                            a realm too cold for love, In planet-seeded, ether fields. Yea, he who does not prize the
                            laws Of life, in tiny flower and blade, Will darkly, vainly seek the cause, That vast
                            creation's structure made. No warbler builds her nest in air ; No blossom climbs the solar
                            ray ; No life develops full and fair, But in its God-appointed way. And God's appointed-way
                            is law ; Its revelations are from Him ; The promises the prophets saw, Beside its workings,
                            are but dim. *Old Roman customs. For, as the pulses of the spring Throb through all nature's
                            vast domain, So, true religion's breath will bring The soul its blossom-time again. Yea,
                            true religion will redeem From every blight, and cumbering thorn; And cause the heart, and
                            earth to teem With fruits of the Millennial Morn. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sacred places, sacred seasons" TEIform="index"/>SACRED PLACES, SACRED SEASONS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, G. B." TEIform="persName"/>G. B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p"> Robert Owen declared, that " Man is solely the creature of circumstances." Were this a
                            truism, no efforts, on his own part to avert evil, and attain good, could modify his
                            condition ; he simply would drift as the waves of surrounding influences float his bark
                            seaward—toward the vortex of interminable ruin, or shoreward, toward the haven of truth and
                            blessedness. In other words, he becomes the tool of all other influences but his own will;
                            or, weaker still, without a will power! That man is measurably characterized by
                            circumstances, is a fact supported by universal experience. " Moore" the Psycho-Moralist,
                            says that ' dirt upon the person, needlessly and careessly suffered to remain there, is not
                            merely dirt, for, no sooner is it carelessly left upon -he skin, than it begins to travel
                            soulward." A ragged, shabby dress instinctively invites to carelessness of dirt and filth,
                            and ndifference to contact with them. This is o well understood by reformers, that in the
                            Reform Schools" of our country it is conidered almost impossible to produce much eform in
                            children while shabbily and dirty dressed. There is intuitively in the hu- <pb n="74" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 74 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. man understanding a measurable sense of the fitness
                            of things and conditions ; hence, the common custom of dressing nicely for church or meeting
                            ; of erecting nice buildings for churches, and neat halls held exclusively for the purpose
                            of meetings for sacred devotions to spiritual and heavenly themes ; and, by the laws of
                            spiritual affinity and sympathy, it is much easier for a person to feel cleanly in spirit,
                            when washed and dressed cleanly, than when in filthy or tattered garments. This law of
                            sympathy between soul and body was so well understood by the ancients, that, in cases of
                            national sorrows, or extreme personal sufferings of spirit, it was customary even for nobles
                            and kings to rend their garments ; to dress in sackcloth and ashes ; and to put dust upon
                            their heads. Every tatter of a garment, quietly worn ragged, is gnawing a rag into the
                            wholesome completeness of a sound, clean feeling. The soul writes upon the tablets of
                            sympathy every character of experience in human life ; and also all that the senses have
                            inhaled, be it beauty or deformity, cleanliness or filthiness, sickness or health, pain or
                            pleasure, sorrow or joy. It is much easier to feel sorrowful when in the presence of those
                            who suffer, and joyful when convened with those who are happy and glad. A tatterdemalion is
                            an enclyclopedia of unfinished woes, whose every rag creeps soulward, and steals a portion
                            of one's sense of fitness for good society. It is easier for the soul to fraternize with
                            angels in the spirit spheres, while in apartments kept sacred for devotion to heavenly and
                            pure themes, than it possibly could be in a stable or butcher's stall, or in the
                            distractions of a factory. It would seem that any human being could realize the difficulty
                            of feeling a heavenly stillness, a worship to God, on the plains of a battle-field, mid the
                            roar of cannon, the rattle of musketry, and clashing of resounding arms. Yet, we find people
                            pandering to an indifference and disregard for sacred places, and sacred seasons, and would
                            abandon churches, meeting-halls and retiring rooms, to the common uses and abuses of secular
                            life. " But, thou, when thou prayest, enter into thy closet, and pray in secret, and thy
                            Father, who seest in secret, shall reward thee openly." Ah, it is when retired to the
                            consecrated hall of worship, or the closeted sanctuary of the dwelling, that the closet of
                            the heart can be most accessible, where the soul can most readily free itself from earthly
                            toils and conflicts, and yield up itself to sympathies of the heavenly hosts. If society has
                            no sacred places, the earthly home is but a market place, where earthly gains and pleasures
                            are traded for sensual delights, and spiritual gifts and graces are unknown ; man becomes a
                            mere earth-worm, a ground hog. . If sacred places are abandoned to secular uses, cumbered
                            with the truck of trade, papers, books, literature of a worldly character, or needless
                            furniture inappropriate to a place of retirement and worship, there is unavoidably added
                            much labor of obtaining, in those retreats, a heavenly, devotional, worshipful spirit;
                            because of the sensitiveness of the human soul to surroundings. When Jesus entered into the
                            Jewish Temple for the worship of Jehovah, and found there the tables of money changers, and
                            seats of dove sellers, he thus reproved the people. " It is written, ' My House shall be
                            called the House of Prayer/ but ye have made it a den of thieves; " and He drove them out.
                            There is, in the social economy as real necessity for sacred seasons, as for sacred places;
                            Sabbaths—times for devotion, principally to spiritual gifts and pursuits. True the Christian
                            Sabbath, in its widest sense, is that order of life in the New Heavens and New Earth,
                            instituted by obedience to the law of Christ's Kingdom, which shall ransom man from
                            selfishness and sin, and make his whole life a consecration to God ; but, to obtain the
                            advent of this Sabbath, par excellence, many minor Sabbaths and their fruits are necessary.
                            The mind and spirit as really need seasons of retirement, rest from earth's turmoil, as does
                            the physical body. As well think of obtaining sweet, inspiring, refreshing soulfood, while
                            subjected to the noise and bustle of the factory, mid the whirl of business, the thundering
                            of locomotives, screechings of steam-whistles, clashing of saws, <pb n="75" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            SHAKEK MANIFESTO. 75 and din of hammers or ringing of anvils ; tlie belchings of Vesuvius,
                            the thunderings of Niagara, the roarings of the billowy deep dashing its breakers upon the
                            rock-bound shores, as \o obtain sweet sleep for the body mid the commotions of the hurricane
                            ! The more subtle and delicate the sense, and refined the influence, the more retired and
                            sacred must be the opportunity for its development. Who could anticipate that a connoisseur
                            could detect and appreciate the delicate flavor of a choice wine, immediately after having
                            tasted aloes, or sharp vinegar? Or who could hear the delicate tones repeated by the
                            telephone, while the ears were dinned by the roar of cannon? As the murmuring of rills, the
                            purring of spindles, the soft strains of the viol, and the faint whisperings of the iBolian
                            harp, are the harbingers of sleep, so the soliloquies of reflection, the sequestrations of
                            retirement are the necessary provisions for the manifestations of spiritual influences and
                            gifts. Thus is man, both body and soul, the subject of influences, though not wholly the
                            creature of circumstances ; but he is moved by all characters of passing events, toward .
                            some new goal of thought, feeling and action. Let us hold fast to our Sacred places and
                            Sacred Seasons. Shakers, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God's laws immutable" TEIform="index"/>GOD'S LAWS IMMUTABLE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/>ANTOINETTE DOOLITTLE</byline><p TEIform="p"> As the husbandman waiteth for the precious fruit of the earth and hath long patience for it,
                            believing that in due time he will receive the early and later rains, and reap an abundant
                            harvest, the fruit of his toil, even so hath the great Husbandman of all worlds and heavens
                            awaited the growth and development of races and kindreds toward the soul of the Universe of
                            Mind and matter. Finite minds, however piercing or enlightened, and even when aided by
                            prophetic lens, cannot comprehend and traverse the length and breadth of God's laws, which
                            are, and will ever remain, unchangeable. He saw "the end from the beginning;" and worlds on
                            worlds are but an outward expression of the Deific will of Wisdom and Love, the creative and
                            harmonizing forces in all material or spiritual substances ; and to counteract or destroy
                            those laws, would be to destroy a part of Deity itself. Man and woman in their
                            incompleteness fail to grasp and comprehend the fullness of the God-head, or the laws by
                            which the worlds move with exact precision from age to age; yet by searching may find out
                            sufficient to enable them to be co-workers with God, in maturing and perfecting the original
                            plan touching the welfare of the human race, and be instrumental in adapting those laws to
                            present needs and conditions according to times and seasons; and may form new codes of laws
                            subservient to the higher and subject to change as the increase of light and truth may
                            demand; and each successive change should advance the race one degree nearer the great
                            Center of all. Corrective agencies must be employed to reform and better conditions,
                            physically, morally, and spiritually. Without such cogency to work change of thought and
                            action, there would be no expansion and growth. The effectual needed change from inferior to
                            superior conditions, must come to us through mediators— higher intelligences above and
                            beyond us. Through them we reason with God; they are our ministers; with them <pb n="76" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. we learn to think, and by them our thoughts are borne to
                            the great Originator of thought, and adjudged. How wise and prudent for all to learn to
                            reason and think justly and truly! The soul's progress may be hastened or retarded as we
                            will it, in a large degree. As a child looks to a father for strength, and yearns for the
                            tender embraces of a loving mother, so does the heart of humanity go forth to the universal
                            Father for strength to hold, and wisdom to direct; and for that charity, love and care which
                            only a mother in God can feel and impart. When we are convinced that corrupt desires, and
                            gross habits, inherited or acquired, impede the soul's growth into the higher life, then, if
                            honest and sincere, we ask for a change, for a power of emancipation, and we long to burst
                            the bands which bind, and hold us to inferior objects and creature loves; and we then put
                            forth efforts to effect such change through inward strivings, and outwrought works of purity
                            and love. By thus changing individual character we become co-workers with God, and are in
                            harmony with divine law, which is unchangeable. While in the earth sphere, soul and body are
                            closely allied, and the spirit cannot progress Godward while the body is subject to gross
                            and sinful passions. As with individuals, so with collective bodies. If the civil rulers of
                            a nation are governed by political intrigue instead of sound principles; if they frame and
                            execute unjust laws, they to the same extent place barriers in the way of national progress,
                            morally and spiritually. There are boundary lines placed beyond which it is difficult to
                            pass without causing inharmony and breaking the connecting link of the chain that binds
                            individuals to society at large. But notwithstanding the strong hand of political power is
                            often laid upon the true prophetic spirit of the ages, still under the good providence of
                            God the car of human progress moves on, refining and maturing the natural, material world of
                            matter, while enlivening and hastening spiritual growth, causing large classes of men and
                            women to leave the narrow limits of the past and find new channels of thought; to enter into
                            new fields of action, and in every department seek to solve the problems of life in the
                            present, and thus to prepare for the future. Intensified by scientific development, the
                            human mind expands more and more, and seeks to brush away the clouds of sectarianism, of
                            whatever name or nature, that have hitherto blinded the sight or fettered the intellect, and
                            hindered the soul's growth into the divine. And with all the opposing 'influences in active
                            operation against scientific culture and moral refinement, every year makes its mark in the
                            world's great history, and adds to its pages some illumined thought beyond the past, and by
                            quickened and co-operative action, the seen and unseen worlds move on in harmony to greater
                            and still greater perfection and beauty, the lesser subservient to the greater; and all, as
                            they onward move, in one harmonious strain, chant the praises of the Universal Father and
                            Mother whose love and care extend to all. 76</p></div2><pb n="77" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good time coming, number 2" TEIform="index"/>THE GOOD TIME COMING, Number 2</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName"/>WM. H. BUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p">"There is no death; what seems so is transition." Reason as well as science proclaims the
                            indestructible nature of all things. Life reigns supreme throughout the universe. What has
                            been called death is simply dissolution of existing forms. Change is one of the modes of
                            active life. " Surely the mountain falling cometh to nought," but only as mountain. The
                            incessant action of the elements reduces it by degrees to a state from which superior forms
                            are produced — the grand and beautiful tree ; the flowers of varied hues ; the
                            life-sustaining grains, and the fruit which delight both sight and taste. The earth has
                            written upon its surface, to a considerable extent, its own history, which every geologist
                            can read. In the early period there was, as now presented, the sublime scenery of mountain
                            and valley, lake and river, sea and ocean. Then, by degrees, it put on its garments of
                            beauty. Then appeared the vast and varied multitudes of swimming, creeping, walking, running
                            and flying life. After that, as its crowning glory, came the being with capacity ultimately
                            to appreciate and enjoy all the grand operations hitherto effected or thereafter to be
                            performed. There is no fact in human history better established than that of the low grade
                            of life possessed by man in the earliest ages. The inhabitant of countries at present styled
                            enlightened has no reason to boast of his descent. Whatever books of heraldry may show him
                            with respect to his ancestry, the " living epistles " still here and there upon the earth
                            teach unmistakably that, even if Darwin's theory of his origin is not true, yet his
                            progenitors, if but " little lower than the angels," were, in fact, not much above the
                            beasts of forest and plain. But it is no less true that his present condition, physically,
                            intellectually, morally and socially, is vastly in advance of that in all preceding periods.
                            There is no need of entering into details. Human history, scanty as it is, sufficiently
                            corroborates the statement. It teaches progress toward higher conditions as man's destiny.
                            The radical teachings of Jesus Christ respecting the Divine character mark the grandest era
                            in the world's history. " God is love." " God so loved the world ! " Jesus not only taught
                            the universality of love, He exemplified it in His own life. The crowning act of His earthly
                            career was illustrative of the Divine love. The lesson seems a hard one for human beings to
                            learn. The theory is simple, but, alas, for the practice that has been exhibited by many
                            since the days of Jesus and His early disciples! Nevertheless the lesson itself has uever
                            been lost from view, however much it has been surrounded by absurd theories. It has
                            influenced the conduct of thousands all along, and should have influenced myriads more. It
                            is the central idea of progress. It is the grace in which mankind must grow or their
                            advancement in other respects will lack the essential characteristics of progress. All forms
                            of progress, indeed, must be regarded as the off-shoots of one universal spiritual element,
                            Divine Love. This is an ever active element, but little understood by undeveloped minds, yet
                            seen to be operative in all the affairs of life by those whose spiritual vision has been
                            opened. These cannot fail to perceive its steady, gradual working any more than they fail to
                            see the various operations of nature throughout the varied year. They recognize its action
                            in the past, but feel its power in their own times. To them " the darkness is past and the
                            true light is now shining." They feel it in the various reforms of the age in which they
                            interest themselves, whether against the tyranny of the individual or of society; the
                            tyranny of the passions or of the appetites ; hence the spirit of prophecy within them
                            breaks forth in predictions clear and strong as those of " Holy Writ." Slavery must end, and
                            every form of oppression cease in " the good time coming ; " men and women must be respected
                            because they are men and women ; all must have an equal share in all the blessings of life,
                            because by nature they are entitled to them, and Divine Love confirms to them the title ;
                            the future welfare of every individual is <pb n="78" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO.
                            secured to eacli, and lie has only to enter upon proceedings in the court of Divine Love for
                            judgment to be rendered in his behalf. Or, in other words, Divine Love must respect all the
                            objects of its love, and, in the blest future, provide that al] shall enter through the
                            gates into the city of Love, after having washed their robes and made them white in the life
                            and spirit of Love, which is " the blood of the Lamb."</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lost—saved" TEIform="index"/>LOST-SAVED</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>MARTHA J. ANDERSON</byline><p TEIform="p"> Lost! lost ! in the by-way turns That meet in the downward road, When the soul the narrow
                            highway spurns, Which upward leads to God. Lost! but a little slip at first, Then many a
                            foot-fall down, 'Till the fair of earth with sin accursed, Miss virtue's shining crown.
                            Lost! in the drunkard's shadowy path, First drawn by the sparkling bowl To enter the way of
                            sin and wrath, That ruins body and soul. Lost! how the tempting gleams of gold Sets honesty
                            aside, 'Till by degrees the heart grows bold In the stronghold of its pride. Lost! in the
                            vain and fruitless chase For honor, and wealth, and fame, Where glory wrapped in selfhood
                            base, Proved but an empty name. Lost! through the storm of passions wild Which led the feet
                            astray. Unconsciously, through wrong beguiled, They passed on the downward way. Lost! for an
                            awful dearth and blight Rests on the wayward heart, Who turned from a knowledge of truth and
                            right And walks from good apart. Lost! there are stealthy, subtle foes Who bind their chains
                            around, 'Till habits formed their power disclose, And the helpless soul is bound. Lost! to a
                            sense of blushing shame With a conscience seared and scarred, Rises no holy incense flame,
                            From out that vessel marred ? Lost! O ! shall we think for aye Are sealed their fate and
                            doom ? That through the blackness gleams no day Their dark haunts to illume ? Saved! saved !
                            from the depths of woe And endless misery ; Saved, though fallen ever so low, Each human
                            soul will be. Saved ! there are blessed angels sent From glorious spheres above ; Who cause
                            the erring to repent Through the pleading voice of love. Saved! when the steps shall be
                            retraced With a purpose to do right; Through sorrow alone is sin erased, Or the spirit robes
                            made white. Saved ! for eternal justice grand, Rules all above, below Unchanged and true
                            God's laws shall stand, " We'll reap just what we sow." Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Indians" TEIform="index"/>INDIANS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescott, James S." TEIform="persName"/>JAMES S. PRESCOTT</byline><p TEIform="p">"Who hath made of one blood all nations of men for to dwell on all the face of the earth. "
                            It is estimated that there are about nine millions of Indians in South America, and about
                            six millions in North America. Those in the United States and Territories, at the present
                            time, number about 316,000. Those civilized about 100,000 ; semi-civilized, 135,000, -and
                            those wild and barbarous, about 81,000. It is difficult to get the exact number of the nomad
                            tribes because of their superstitious reluctance to be counted. The great question before
                            Congress now is, shall the Indian Bureau be transferred from the Department of the Interior
                            to the War Department ? or, shall it remain where it is, under a " Peace " policy
                            inaugurated by President Grant? and under whose policy some 40,000 or more of the nomad
                            Indians have become civilized so far as to get their living by habits of industry, by
                            tilling the soil and cultivating the land, and thereby have become self-supporting
                            communities. This has been done by missionaries sent among them for that purpose, supported
                            mostly by the churches to which they belong, and ought to be satisfactory to all who wish to
                            see justice done the Indians. Every degree of civilization is good as far as it goes, to
                            prepare them for a higher life. The decision of this question is of vital importance to the
                            Indians, because it in78 <pb n="79" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 79 volves a principle
                            of life or death. It is civilization or extermination. Whichever way it is decided it cannot
                            but have an important bearing on the future destiny of the Indians. All parties agree that
                            the only way to save the nomad Indians, is civilization—educating them up to a higher
                            standard of morals —teaching them how to work for a living ; how to labor with their hands ;
                            how to build houses and inhabit them ; how to plant vineyards and eat the fruit thereof; how
                            to build fences and raise stock; how to till the soil on which they dwell, and to earn their
                            bread by the sweat of their brow. And these they are willing to learn if the whites will
                            give them a fair chance. Then why should they be exterminated in a free country, because
                            they are not willing to come under the iron heel of the War Department? When we speak of the
                            noble red man and the noble white man, we do not mean those fiends in liuman shape, who
                            indiscriminately ravish and slaughter the innocent, but we mean those noble traits of
                            character and generous impulses, which, as individuals, adorn the pages of history, and
                            which are characteristic more or less of both races. It is said that "¦civilization must be
                            done by force of arms, and that ' persuasion ' is wasted on the nomad Indians, and that
                            Peace Agents are a failure," etc. The advocates of the peace policy take issue with the War
                            Department on this ground, and are prepared to show from facts and figures to the
                            contrary—that the " Peace " policy is the only policy that has ever succeeded in civilizing
                            the Indians. Strong arguments are offered on both sides. Our limits will not admit of
                            reviewing these arguments in detail. The preponderance, however, of justice, truth and
                            right, are largely on the side of the Peace policy. One of the best arguments in favor of
                            the Peace policy that we have seen, is from Father Wilbur, so-called, a Protestant
                            missionary for the last 18 years in Washington Territory : " I accepted the office of
                            Superintendent of Instruction at Yakama Indian Agency in September, 1860. At that time there
                            were no farms, no churches, no school-houses worthy of the names. We organized working
                            parties of Indian boys, broke in wild cattle to the yoke, and began teaching the Indians to
                            plow. The Indians were as wild as the steers, and were as low down as humanity can get,
                            having been long at war. The first year we raised enough grain and vegetables for seed and
                            for the subsistence of the boarding-school. " From these little beginnings we have grown
                            into a self-supporting community, or nearly so. Some of the Indian boys were placed in the
                            shops to learn trades. The Indian girls were taught house-keeping. We now have thirty-five
                            miles of good, substantial post and board fence ; 6,000 acres under cultivation, and have
                            raised this year over 44,000 bushels of wheat. The Indians have 17,000 horses, 3,500 head of
                            cattle, besides sheep, swine and other domestic animals. " Nearly 400 families live in
                            houses like white people. We have two churches with a membership of 500, two native
                            preachers, who belong to the Columbia Eiver Church. Over 3,000 of the 3,700 Indiana wear
                            citizen's dress. The blacksmith shop, the wagon shop, and the harness shops are all under
                            the management of full-blooded Indians, who were ragged, worthless Indian boys, eighteen
                            years ago. We have built, unaided by Congress, a steam saw-mill, capable of making 12,000
                            feet of lumber per day; a planing machine and shingle machine, all worked by Indians, who
                            were wild, untamed savages a few years ago, with the exception of two, who are white men. "
                            The solution of the whole Indian question rests with Congress. The Indian must be taught to
                            labor. He can be taught successfully, as I have demonstrated. I have had no serious troubles
                            with my Indians. Have never had use for a soldier. Don't want soldiers nearer them than the
                            Bocky Mountains. So long as you feed the Indian without labor, you will have to feed and
                            fight him alternately. He must be taught to earn his own living. This is practicable. He
                            must have teachers who are imbued with God from head to foot — men who can hold the plow
                            handles or push a cross-cut saw; men who know how to work themselves, and are not above
                            setting a working example. We can solve this problem in five years, if Congress will agree
                            to it. Work . Work ! Send working, God-fearing men to teach the Indians how to work, and the
                            thing can be [settled. I am not mistaken Transferring the Indians to the army pro longs the
                            settlement, gives us blood anc carnage, demoralization and ruin. God be merciful to the
                            helpless Indian." In closing this series I wish to express my thanks to The Shaker
                            Manifesto, for giving to the public a brief testimony in favor of the Indians, which will be
                            more appreciated in the future, than can possibly be in the present.</p></div2><pb n="80" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How I found a happy peace" TEIform="index"/>HOW I FOUND A HAPPY PEACE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Kulp, Jacob S." TEIform="persName"/>JACOB S. KULP</byline><p TEIform="p">Every one seeks for happiness; but nearly every one seeks differently. Many there are who
                            think happiness depends on wealth; but wealth, unaccompanied by peace of mind, is
                            unhappiness. There is no happiness in passionate indulgences, nor but little pleasure — and
                            pleasure is not always happiness. Unless blunted by sinfulness, conscience finds stings in
                            such engagements outweighing the pleasure. The angels sung on the first Christmas morn,
                            "Peace on earth and good will;" and Jesus, on taking leave of His disciples, uttered, "My
                            peace I leave with you." It is one of the promises of God to those who would be happy: "
                            Their peace shall be like a river—a ceaseless flow of happiness." By some, happiness is
                            claimed as a myth — found only lettered in the dictionary. But my Christian experience
                            causes me to affirm that it is possible of attainment, and now, in this life. How? Follow
                            Jesus in self-denial; love Him by keeping His commands; follow the Lamb's life, by
                            abstaining from all ungodliness and worldly lusts. Our souls will bear us witness, and to
                            all around us we will give evidence that we are happy because enjoying a Christian peace.
                            Consecration of time, talents, and our whole lives to God — to what God requires of us,
                            ensampled by Christ's life — will yield a happy peace continually. To us this road to
                            happiness is so simply taught that " the wayfaring man or woman, though a fool" to worldly
                            wisdom, needs not err in finding it; and this by living the life of Christ, as did Jesus,
                            free from guile, and in possession of a happiness the world can never give nor take away.
                            Pleasant Hill, Ky.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Manna" TEIform="index"/>MANNA</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bretzner, Emil" TEIform="persName"/>EMIL BRETZNER</byline><p TEIform="p">This subject is a very important one, and involves a great deal. Much of interest could be
                            written about it from different points of view. There is first the word itself with its
                            different meanings, one of which is the mere exclamation " what is it ? " well exDressive of
                            the curiosity and astonishment of the people, when first beholdng the white deposit on the
                            desert wilds around them. The other meaning is that of something bestowed, or given, or else
                            a portion, as the margin reads. In that sense it must have come from the hearts and lips of
                            the more spiritually minded among them,. <pb n="81" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 81 who
                            had faith in the power of their God, and Jiere saw the fulfillment of His promise to them
                            through Moses. " It is the gift of the Lord, the portion He has given us for our support,"
                            they thought; and the simple word, with which they acknowledged their gratitude, was similar
                            to that with which the others expressed their surprise, and perhaps even doubt, or scorn; it
                            was manna. Secondly, there is the historical point to consider. Did it happen at all ? and
                            if so, what was it ? One class of minds easily dispose of the matter, at least to their own
                            satisfaction, by simply answering the first question in the negative, which of course
                            settles it all for them very comfortably. , Others accept it partly as a true statement, but
                            explain it as a merely natural occurrence. It was honey-dew, or one of the many kinds of
                            saccharine gum that exude from different species of the vegetable kingdom in that and other
                            parts of the world. That is all, and that satisfies them. Still others go further, and see
                            in it a manifestation of spirit power upon the natural elements. They are of two classes:
                            First, the strictly orthodox, who accept all the bible statements as true, and consider them
                            all as special acts of providence for special purposes, without reference to any law or
                            principle, that we may inquire into and understand. They were miracles, and the Almighty
                            wrought them by the power of His will. No matter what science and our reason may claim, we
                            must not ask any question on that point, and so we had better leave it. The other class are
                            Spiritualists. They recognize the law of materialization in the production of manna, a grand
                            manifestation on a large scale of the same power which now, in our modern seances, produces
                            flowers or fruits, a glass of water or a piece of ice, a bit of ribbon or a shawl, a
                            squirrel or a human form, living, breathing, and sometimes more full of power and energy,
                            both of body and mind, than any of the spectators present. What is this law of
                            materialization ? I think it is a law of nature as much as any. I believe it is something
                            like this: There is a seed of a certain plant. According to the common order of nature it
                            would take a certain period of time for it to grow up, and develop its stem, its leaves, its
                            blossom and fruit. Simple elements are gathered up from the atmosphere and the soil;
                            chemical processes take place ; new combinations are entered, varied according to the laws
                            of the different species, and the thing is done in the course of time, without anybody
                            wondering at it, unless it be some, who look below the surface. But when spiritual agencies,
                            who are well acquainted with these laws, put them all in action at once, and thereby produce
                            the same result in an instant, then we are apt to exclaim, 'tis a miracle, and so it is, but
                            no more than the other was, only in the time required. Exactly the same natural laws are
                            observed, only the process is hastened. It is the same with all physical manifestations. No
                            laws are broken, but on the contrary, the grander and more astonishing the experiment is,
                            the more perfectly and sacredly must the laws involved be ob- <pb n="82" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 82 THE
                            SHAKER MANIFESTO. served. And in this production of food for over a million of people, in
                            these daily showers of manna in the wilderness for forty years, it must have been so,
                            indeed. Finally, there are some, among whom I would be happy to be numbered, who look upon
                            this and other incidents in the history of the Jewish nation as beautiful types of the
                            travel of the human soul and body from a selfish existence in nature to a resurrection life
                            in Christ. To me they are true prophecies of what we all must do in the fullness of our
                            time, when the call shall come to us to arise and make haste out of the land of Egypt, out
                            of the house of bondage to the sins and evils of the past, or to that portion of them which
                            still lingers in the present. In this particular case of the manna of the Israelites, it may
                            be a historical fact, or it may not; that makes no difference. It might have been, if it was
                            not, for the principles involved are true, and are as consistent with and applicable to our
                            conditions and circumstances, as they were to theirs. As a people we have come out from the
                            world ; we have crossed the dividing line of a generative life, and moved on for a season in
                            short and prosperous journeys through the untrodden fields of virgin purity, a wilderness
                            and a barren waste indeed to the natural mind; but this is not the end. It is only the
                            beginning. In order to fulfill our calling, and be true to our relation to God and humanity,
                            do we not need to pass through a radical change ? Would it not be well to have a manna
                            dispensation, first for forty years, then for ever ? A dispensation of plain, simple diet,
                            suited to the virgin life, with nothing in its composition to mar the tender feelings even
                            of an angel. No bloodshed and killing to remind of cruelty ; no stimulants to kindle latent
                            fires; no artificial coaxing to pamper depraved appetites; nothing to tempt to sin. Some one
                            thing at each meal, prepared and partaken of in the gift of God, is enough; and a thousand
                            more, added without that gift, make only a thousandfold curse. This pleading for different
                            tastes is wrong; they are abnormal, either the results of our own transgressions, or else
                            the sad heirlooms of preceding generations, whose sins are visited upon their children.
                            Other animals, in their natural state, have no such tastes; those of the same kind feed
                            alike, and enjoy their food alike, as human animals ought to do. One deer in a flock does
                            not pick out a certain kind of grass, and his fellow another; why should human beings, if
                            they were not further away from the truth than the lower animals are in that respect ?
                            Blessed be the woman, for no man can do it alone, however much he may feel about and urge
                            the matter, who will take the bold step truthward and Godward, and redeem the kitchen and
                            the table from the sins there committed, as our first Mother redeemed the bed from its
                            defilement. Then disease and suffering will flee from our borders, and every sad heart will
                            leap for joy, when hearing the glad voices of them that truthfully sing the blended songs of
                            Moses and of the Lamb — the union of physical and spiritual righteousness — the mingled boon
                            of manna below and manna above.</p></div2><pb n="83" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>EDITORIAL NOTES</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ought I to be a Shaker?" TEIform="index"/>OUGHT I TO BE A SHAKER?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> "To be, or not to be" a Shaker; " that is the question." It is a soul matter; answered
                                only by " my soul and I"—nothing compulsory, nor urgent in "it, until conscience demands
                                an answer. To the casual reader, the question is a ludicrous one; but a little
                                reflection will persuade many to accept, as only its simple synonym, the precious,
                                serious, oftener-asked soliloquy : " Ought I tote a Christian f" As either question is
                                answered, the results in life will be the same. Yet to the vast majority, there appears,
                                but it is only apparent, an extensive difference between the questions. "To be," as was
                                Jesus, the Christ, is the soul answer to these queries. Not merely to think, nor believe
                                ; neither appear nor assent only; but to he what conscience and our profession dictate
                                we should be. To the cursory question " Ought I to he a Shaker ?" we would
                                unhesitatingly reply: "Nay." To the individual who has reflected upon the subject—who
                                has counted the cost, and is prompted by conscience to attempt it, we as quickly say "
                                Courage, brother." Will the reader recall the fact, that Jesus was called a Nazarene,
                                out of reproach"{ And that out from Nazareth came the adored, first Christian sample ?
                                Will the reader also remember that " Shaker " was intended as an opprobrious epithet ?
                                yet it only signifies one who aims to live primitive, radical Christianity, with all the
                                progressive sentiments of the age added thereto. Do you admire a Christian life, judged
                                by the true criterion—the life of Christ ? Then you ought to be a Shaker. And you will
                                be a Shaker, or lose your admiration for the Christ life. Do you find satisfaction in
                                worldly pleasures, either good or bad, which are not reflected from the goodly
                                life-pattern? you ought not to be a Shaker. Do you wish to marry ? do so; and this
                                decides you are not ready nor able to live as Christ lived, and ought not to be a
                                Shaker. Others, before you, have been excused from being Christians, because they had
                                married their husbands or wives, and therefore, "could not come" and be a Shaker. "To
                                forsake all else, and follow Christ," is the affirmative answer to the question heading
                                this article. The Christian profession is very distinct from the idioms of nomenclature
                                ; and regardless of the various terms of the,religious professions, 'Ho he a Christian"
                                only means, to follow Christ, to live like Christ. To any who finds a repugnance in the
                                term "Shaker," all unpleasantness ceases, when eliminating the unpleasant term, from the
                                very Christian practice of all true Shakers. Therefore, we ask none to answer in the
                                affirmative—that they ought to be a Shaker—whose admiration for Christian principles is
                                dimmed because of an uneuphonious adjective. Once, and not many centuries since,
                                "Christian" was a term of reproach; and those who dared to "despise the shame" of
                                bearing it, would suffer death, and contumely worse than death, because they thus dared.
                                "To he a Shaker, or to he a Christian," is simply summed up thus : 1. A Virgin Celibacy
                                of Life ; none, however, ought to he thus, <pb n="84" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 84 THE SHAKER
                                MANIFESTO. but those fully persuaded that it is a very Christian practice. 3d. Community
                                of Goods; but none should be so Christian and unselfish, as to "part their goods" with
                                others, until thoroughly convinced that Christ's life teaches this rule. 3d. Peaceable ;
                                but it is useless to ask any to be thus, who marry and hold private possessions ; but is
                                it a Christian requisite ? that is the question. 4th. Unwoeldlifess ; free from the good
                                and bad pleasures of every name and nature, which introduce any obstacle to the three
                                first mentioned. Go to your closet, kind reader, compare Shakerism with genuine, radical
                                Christianity, and ' then ask and answer, "Ought I to lea Shaker ?" </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mortal questions—spirit answers" TEIform="index"/>MORTAL QUESTIONS-SPIRIT ANSWERS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> A few weeks ago, we were invited by Dr. J.^V. Mansfield, to enter upon the very pleasant
                                task of making another test of his remarkable mediumship. We needed not to test him,
                                that we might personally fully believe in the truthfulness of his valuable gift of
                                giving ready, satisfactory answers from the world of spirits to questions secluded by
                                deepest tests of concealment. The Dr. guarantees no answer, but he is moved by
                                impressions to write what the spirits give him to write. Sometimes he gets no answers,
                                even after renewed sittings for the purpose. We wrote very finely, upon a half-sheet of
                                note, ten questions. We folded up our note, fastening the edges very securely, and when
                                fully folded, doubled the roll, and wrote across the edges of the double fold, fastening
                                the same by a small pin, gummed in, and thoroughly secured and marked. This we placed in
                                a small, white envolope ; and then put both into an envelope, chemically prepared, that
                                would immediately indicate moisture or steam. These we again enveloped, writing across
                                the edges of the securely-closed third envelope. Placing these into a large fourth
                                envelope, we sent the package to the Dr. on the 11th. of February, and received from him
                                the following answers on the 12th, or next day. We live 160 miles from New York, and
                                yet, regardless of postal delays, received our answers in less than twenty-four hours,
                                with not the least indication of any disturbance of our package, as witnessed by
                                several. We would say to those desirous of testing the wonderful powers of the Dr. that
                                they should address some spirit hj the full name, and sign their own full name. These
                                may be deeply imbedded and obscured, and if there is an answer for the parties so
                                addressing, it will be forthcoming. See adv. for the Dr.'s terms ; which, considering
                                how much he has freely and charitably done, is not a money-making occupation—being only
                                four and a half cents per sitting, since the development of his gift. These were the
                                tests: David Hawkins, My Spiritual Friend and Father:—Invited by Dr. Mansfield to make
                                some good, thorough tests of his mediumship, I would ask of you some questions lying
                                nearest my heart's ambition, hoping for comforting replies. Ques. 1. Are you in the
                                possession of enjoyments equal to the promises made you, by your Shaker preceptors, when
                                on earth ? 2. Had you your life to live over, would you live the same Shaker life, and
                                are its rewards In spirit life, good pay? 3. Do you, and companions in spirit, take an
                                interest in The Shaker Manifesto, and to what extent? 4. What is the will of the Shaker
                                spirits concerning its continuance ? 5. What are its effects upon those in spirit life,
                                as well as earth life ? 6. Are the Shakers of the spirit world pleased with its present
                                methods of conducting the evangelical campaign ? 7. What would be the effects of its
                                discontinuance ? 8. Do the " signs of the times " look more hopeful, religiously, to you
                                and companions, than to us in earth-life ? 9. How near is your location of habitation to
                                ours ? and 10. What is your greatest anxiety concerning us? THE RESPONSE. My Dear Oeo.
                                Albert: — Tours of the 11th is before me, for which loving and respectful remembrance
                                you have my soul. <pb n="85" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. 85 thanks. Much as I am
                                with you from day to day, I had not anticipated this free and uninterrupted talk, only
                                regretting my control is limited, from want of strength to communicate more fully. I was
                                attending a meeting of our people, when the presiding elder announced the arrival of a
                                messenger from other spheres, saying, " David Hawkins is wanted to speak with those on
                                earth!" I immediately responded "to the call, and to my great delight, learned it was my
                                dear Geo. Albert that would speak with me. Well, to your questions, lest time passes,
                                and my control breaks before I can notice all your queries. Ans. 1. Yea, Geo. Albert, a
                                thousand times more so ! the enjoyment-*—the beauties of my mansion in the spirit world,
                                no spirit could describe it, nor even give an approximate idea of its loveliness and
                                beauty. Ans. 2. Most assuredly I would. Had I ten thousands of lives to live, I would
                                live the Shaker life. I am aware all are not constituted to be Shakers on the earth, but
                                among all the sects I have met in the land of souls, the Shakers are the most happy. The
                                Shaker's rewards are a hundred fold on earth—I mean true Shakers — and a million fold in
                                this world of spirits! Yea, Geo. Albert, " it does pay." Ans. 3. We do. It was spoken of
                                in our meeting to-day, as you measure time. Richard Bushnell, George II. Evans, Betsy
                                Bates, Wm. Offord, Eliza Barbour, Wm. Doolittle, Thos. Rayson and myself were discussing
                                the matter, as to how its borders could be extended, that the starving minds, now ripe
                                and hungry for Shaker teachings, might have the desire of their souls. Ans. 4. I will go
                                and put this question to the meeting, and then give you the results : Those that are in
                                favor of its continuance are the entire meeting, some of whom I will enum. erate, and
                                you will recognize : Richard Bushnell, Josiah Bangs, Thos. Rayson, Gurdon Horton, Polly
                                Turney, Caleb M. Dyer, John Holt, Wm. Doolittle, Anna Smith, Philemon Stewart, Daniel
                                Brainard, Eunice Hastings, Wm. Offord, Melissa Soule, Ellen Rayson, Sarah Turner, Ruth
                                A. Green, Persis Stebbins, Sarah Ann Lewis, Betsy Bates, Robert White, Eliza Barbour,
                                Isaac N. Youngs. Jas. M. King (converted in spirit life), Benj. Moorhouse, Barnabas
                                Hinckley, Abel Knight, Polly Lawrence, Louisa Smith, Celia Saunders, and a. host of
                                others I have not time to enumerate—but their voices are unanimous for its continuance.
                                Ans. 5. The effects are extensive and most blessed. Ans. 6- They are ; and why should
                                they not be—so long as they have the sole management of it—so give credit to where it
                                belongs. You are their mouth-piece, or funnel ; through you they pour out the glad
                                tidings of great joy to the people. Ans. 7. To discontinue its publication would prove
                                disastrous to our fraternity, to an alarming extent; and we hope such a thought never
                                was, nor will be, seriously entertained. Ans. 8. The signs of the times are indeed
                                hopeful; sectarian bigotry is giving place to free thought, and where this abounds,
                                Shakerism will thrive, and hold its own among all the isms of the day. Ans. 9. The
                                spirit world is just around that which you inhabit—in other words, you live in the
                                spirit world to-day, as much so as though you were with me; the difference only is, we
                                see through spiritual eyes—there is no space nor distance between us now. Ans. 10. Our
                                greatest anxiety is, lest you become discouraged at the slowness of the progress of
                                Shakerism; but say to all the Societies : '" Look aloft, and read the signs of the times
                                in golden letters on the sky! Shakerism is approved of God and the angels—the brightest
                                of which is our dear Mother Ann ! " DAVID HAWKINS. To G. A. Lomas. [We will only add,we
                                are left without the shadow of a doubt of the genuineness of the communication, and are
                                equally happy and grateful for such soul-satisfying replies. The Editor.</p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We wonder if any grown-up children ever ever experience the thoughts of the little boy who..." TEIform="index"/>We wonder if any grown-up children ever ever experience the thoughts of the little boy who...
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We wonder if any grown-up children ever experience the thoughts of the little boy who had
                                two pennies given him—one for candy, and one for the missionary-box—who, on losing one,
                                immediately concluded that was the one intended for the spread of the gospel I</p></div3><pb n="86" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes" TEIform="index"/>Notes</head><div4 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="100" TEIform="index"/>100</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">With this issue of The Manifesto we complete our round number of an hundred. To those
                                    who have filed copies of all the volumes, it will be seen that we have held our own
                                    ground persistently, and how successfully. We aim, simply, through our pages, the
                                    illustration of the plain, undraped purity and unselfishness of genuine Christian
                                    life. Let none think that we hold a bigoted position in this ; for, being human like
                                    the rest of our fellows—having the same perversities and deficiencies to deal with
                                    religiously—we feel the power of the Christian's cross, to cut us off from the world
                                    and its pleasures, however inviting and pleasing to the senses ; yet are repaid, and
                                    more, by an elevated dominion over self and the world. We would not urge upon all
                                    the full cross of the Christian, knowing1 full well, how unable many are to endure
                                    it; but in this crowning, hundredth number, would call the special attention of
                                    believers and lovers of Christ to that question, treated upon elsewhere, which has
                                    come up for consideration with many, and may with thousands more: " Ought I to be a
                                    Shaker."</p></div4><div4 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God's acres" TEIform="index"/>God's Acres</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Not grave-yards; not burping-'places, but raising acres for God and the cause of God
                                    in the world. Let not the dead alone rest in our " God's Acre;" let there be reared
                                    for God, and the extension of God's cause, acres of consecrated corn or wheat, or
                                    potatoes, or flowers, or other merchandise. If we had a very superior friend, to
                                    whom we would present an acre of crops, we would present the best acre we had.
                                    Grave-yards are called " God's Acres ;" but there is little they produce for God.
                                    Let us have a living acre, and growing acre, that we may present unto the Lord's
                                    cause. It was no uncommon thing of old, to present an ox, or oxen and sheep, by way
                                    of sacrifice to the Lord. In behalf of The Shaker Manifesto, we will accept and
                                    devote to the cause of God, the income of the best living, growing " God's Acre; "
                                    or the fatted ox, or even the value of a good horse—all for the Cause, credited to
                                    God's Acres.</p></div4><div4 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Muddled ministers" TEIform="index"/>The Muddled Ministers</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">A large number of ministers recently congregated at Syracuse, N. Y., to take active,
                                    positive, forcible measures for the ejectment from our State of what they may
                                    honestly believe to be a very corrupt institution. Forgetful of the old-time adage,
                                    " Physician, heal thyself," they could see corruption in every direction from them,
                                    better than they would see it in themselves. They debated the question with much
                                    learning and ability, and closed each individual effort with pious rolling of their
                                    eyes, as they " would to God he would wipe out the foul blot." We join these
                                    ministers, in all sincerity, in desiring all foul blots erased from human lives ;
                                    but we would ask them and ourselves to begin the work of such erasures, not at
                                    Oneida, but with ourselves, themselves and our congregations. Remember, reverend
                                    gentlemen, that you take an unchristian part in joining man and woman in the
                                    unchristian but only civil contracts of marriage. That behind that certificate
                                    sanctioned by you, lies the legality of men or women, or both, of living the most
                                    sensual lives in sexuality—in libertinism or prostitution if they please — while
                                    there is nothing in the law nor your churches to hear appeals therefrom, neither to
                                    prevent the abuses of married life, nor to wipe out millions of such foul blots! How
                                    lax the laws of that country must be which does not punish fornication nor adultery
                                    ! Reverned gentlemen, the object of marriage is for the regulated reproduction of
                                    population alone; do you use it for aught else? Then begin right here, and " wipe
                                    out a foul blot," and be very still until it is erased. Oh, could the cries of women
                                    be heard, in their appeals from soul and body environments of the lusts of their
                                    husbands—their masters—what a tale would then unfold ! Judging from the best light
                                    we have, there are many things worse than midnight murders enacted behind the
                                    certificates legalizing such acts, and sold by these same Revs., who roll
                                    pious-looking eyes in holy horror upon Oneida. We are not championing complex
                                    marriage, but we have made the most<pb n="87" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 87
                                    searching investigations into the mysteries of Oneida complexity of life, and while
                                    it is far from Shakerism, it is, we truthfully believe, vastly purer than some of
                                    the most respectable marriages of to-day. Justice alone demands this of us.
                                    Now/while these Reverends were legislating, let us see what the Communists were
                                    quietly determining upon. " If our manner of life is illegal, or if laws are in
                                    future enacted that make it illegal, then we can and will change it, and live as the
                                    Shakers do! " Presto ! And with these statements staring those muddled Revs, in the
                                    face, we mentally see them, in what Webster calls a " Mare's nest ;" and while
                                    extending them sympathy in their ludicrous predicament, we welcome Oneida, and these
                                    Rev. Meddlers also, upon the simple platform of Shakerism. Bat we will not give any,
                                    full assurance of no further disturbance ; for a whilom, very popular paper of N. Y.
                                    city — " The Illustrated J¥ew Yorker " — not very long ago got muddled, like some
                                    recent Revs., and urging that " while the fold Hot of Mormonism should be
                                    immediately wiped out because they'married so much, the Shakers also should be as
                                    effectually squelched because they did not marry at all ! " and amid all of these
                                    bemuddled muddlers, we close comments with the advice: choose your God, and accept
                                    the fates that God imposes.</p></div4><div4 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mistakes needing correction" TEIform="index"/>Mistakes Needing Correction</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Elsewhere, we give proofs of Dr. Mansfield's powers of mediumship. We therein also
                                    allude, that he has charitably donated himself so much, for those unable to pay, as
                                    to make his gift any thing but a paying one. The Dr. is not able to meet such
                                    draughts upon his time and strength without payment. We solicited his advertisement,
                                    knowing of his genuineness ; he pays us fully therefor; and we hope none of our
                                    friends will trespass upon him by begging or sponging replies to sealed letters. We
                                    are made aware that this has been done, since we inserted his advertisement, by five
                                    or six persons, and our advice is sought. While we hope none will do so more, we
                                    hope, also, soon to hear that those who have made the mistake by doing so, have
                                    honorably made amends therefor.</p></div4></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society Record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dried sweet corn" TEIform="index"/>Dried Sweet Corn</head><p TEIform="p">which has been a staple to be relied upon by the Shakers for more than fifty years, as a
                                well-paying, merchantable article, has become almost a dead article of sale, because of
                                an over-production of inferior qualities, as well as great quantities of the good
                                article being thrown on the market by competitors, outside of Shakerdom. Present
                                prospects indicate that but little of the genuine article will be manufactured in future
                                years by our people. The price of Dried Corn, as we remember it thirty years ago, was
                                governed by the price of flour; and it was rulable to make one barrel of sweet corn buy
                                two barrels of flour. Then it was considered a good business, but not very enriching.
                                Now, a barrel of sweet corn will only buy one barrel of flour, and our people will have
                                to depend on other industries. The business was started in 1828, at Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.
                                It was cooked by boiling on the cob, in a large iron kettle; taken from thence, cut off
                                with knives, and dried in the sun, on boards. In 1840 the first dryhouse was erected,
                                having runways extending out from it, for large platforms on wheels to pass in and out,
                                thus more easily caring for the corn, exposing it to the sun, and preserving it from the
                                rains, or dews by night. On these platforms the corn was spread very thinly, aud raked
                                at intervals to let the warm air percolate every kernel. It was a slow, tedious process,
                                the dessication finding great impediments in the fall of the year by cold, cloudy days —
                                perhaps several rainy days in succession. Then, the whole " batch" would sour ; extra
                                help would be added to stir it more frequently ; and when the sun did favor it with his
                                rays, and a slight breeze would blow, the entire settlement would be " regaled " with a
                                hope, at least, that the corn would be saved, because of the extensive, unpleasant, very
                                sour smell departing the corn, in the atmosphere. Better times were in store for its
                                manufacture, and we will let the Chatham Courier introduce them : "The drying of corn
                                for the market has for years been one of the principal Indus^otUty g^jctfttf, <pb n="88" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. tries carried on by this busy people. Only a small
                                portion of the corn is grown upon the farms belonging to the community, but contracts
                                are made with farmers throughout the town, who deliver the husked corn at prices ranging
                                from sixteen to twenty dollars a ton, and nearly all the families are busied in taking
                                care of it during a portion of August and September. The establishment at the " Second
                                Family " is perhaps as extensive as any. Here Clinton Brainard — most genial and
                                gentlemanly of Shakers — presides, and has reduced the work to a method which seems
                                absolute perfection. Work begins very early in the morning, for the ten-hour plan does
                                not obtain here just at this time. The farmer drives his load of husked corn, carefully
                                covered from dust and sun, upon the platform scales, is weighed, then passes into a
                                building where ready hands pick the ears into small square baskets. They receive none
                                but perfect ears, excluding all less than four inches in length. If an ear is too
                                mature, it is used for seed. If any be too small, or mouldy, or otherwise exceptionable,
                                the farmer must take home a lunch for his porkers. The baskets of corn are closely
                                packed upon an elevator, to the extent of nearly a ton, a rope is pulled, and the engine
                                in the basement lowers them into a steam-box, where they are subjected to about six
                                minutes of rather intense cooking. This accomplished, a bell rings, and they rise, pass
                                the first floor, steaming from their bath, to the second floor, where they are removed
                                from the platform, which returns to repeat its office. The second floor is devoted to
                                removing the corn from the cob. Here are three machines operated by steam, each capable
                                of removing the corn from forty-five ears per minute. The machines are fed directly from
                                the baskets, while the cobs shoot through an inclined tube into the carts, and are drawn
                                away. The machines seem to belong to the workingman's party, inasmuch as they will not
                                work—sometimes. They are a new and novel invention, which does not seem to be quite
                                perfected as yet. Quite as interesting, if less rapid, are the movements of some comely
                                Shaker girls, who, in an adjoining room, by the aid of a peculiar series of fixed
                                knives, and the deftest of white hands, make the machine seem rather inferior after all.
                                The corn falls into larger baskets, which are placed upon a car, and then rolled along a
                                track which connects, by means of a long bridge, the building we have just left with the
                                kiln. The corn is then placed in long shallow pans, and subjected to an even heat from
                                the roaring furnaces below. In this manner two kilns full are dried in twenty-four
                                hours. The dried corn is then passed through a mill which winnows from it every particle
                                of silk or husk which may be with it, and placed in a large bin. A tube passes from this
                                to the lower story. A barrel is placed on the scales, a slide pulled in the conductor
                                and the barrel filled to a certain weight. It is then headed, marked, and is ready for
                                shipment. In this manner they expect to fill twelve hundred barrels this season. They
                                also put up a fine shelf package for grocers' retail trade. Every step is surprisingly
                                neat, and, unlike many establishments, seeing the preparation actually gives one a
                                relish for the thing prepared.</p></div3><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>DEATHS</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watmaugh, Henry" TEIform="index"/>Henry Watmaugh
                                </head><p TEIform="p">At South Union, Ky., Feb. 10, Henry Watmaugh, aged 84 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Babbitt, Aaron" TEIform="index"/>Aaron Babbitt
                                </head><p TEIform="p">At Union Village, O., Feb. 15, Elder Aaron Babbitt, aged 80 years. " For many years a
                                    leading member, occupying for years in the bishopric of the Ohio diocese. He was a
                                    good and wise man." W. R.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Farr, Elizabeth" TEIform="index"/>Elizabeth Farr
                                </head><p TEIform="p">Also, Feb. 22, while yet in the prime of life, the beautiful spirit of Eldress
                                    Elizaaeth Farr, of the ministry of Union Village, 0., took its departure, aged 58.
                                    Her loss is deeply deplored by all, and our Western Societies have the most genuine
                                    sympathy of all Eastern believers.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Goodwin, Laura" TEIform="index"/>Laura Goodwin
                                </head><p TEIform="p">At Canaan, N. Y., Feb. 26, Laura Goodwin, aged 16.</p></div4></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To those liberally inclined" TEIform="index"/>To Those " Liberally Inclined."</head><p TEIform="p">The office of The Shaker Manifesto returns its sincere gratitude to those who have so
                                kindly responded to the call of our publisher in March number. This is putting
                                yourselves in our place very appreciatively and acceptably.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/>Ed. </byline></div3></div2><pb n="89" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>The Children's Grotto</head><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Being kind to animals" TEIform="index"/>Being Kind to Animals</head><p TEIform="p">The Chinese are always kind to animals, and never pun ish ; hence, a mule, that, in the
                                hands of a foreigner, would be not only useless but dangerous to every one about it,
                                becomes, in the possession of a Chinaman, as quiet as a lamb and as tractable as a dog.
                                We never beheld a runaway, a jibing, or a viciou mule or pony in a Chinaman's
                                employment; but found the same rattling cheerful pace maintained over heavy or light
                                roads by means of a turr-r or cluck-k the beast turning to the right or left, and
                                stopping, with but a hint from the reins. This treatment is extended to all the animals
                                they press into their service. Often have I admired the tact exhibited in getting a
                                large drove of sheep through narrow, crowded streets and alleys, by merely having a
                                little boy to lead one of the flock in front; the others steadily followed, without the
                                aid either from a yelping cur or cruel goad. Cattle, pigs and birds are equally cared
                                for.— [Travels on Horseback.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Somebody else" TEIform="index"/>Somebody Else</head><p TEIform="p">A lady was walking quietly along the city street, not long ago, when the door of a house
                                flew open, and a boy shot out with a whoop like a wild Indian. Once on the pavement he
                                danced a sort of double shuffle all around a curbstone, and then raced down the street
                                in great haste, for it was evident by the books under his arm he was going to school.
                                The lady was thinking what thoughtless, noisy creatures healthy boys always are, when
                                just a few yards before her she saw something yellow lying on the stones. Coming nearer
                                she fancied it was a pine shaving, and looked after the boy again. She saw him suddenly
                                stop short in a crowd of people at a crossing, and come back as fast as he had gone, so
                                that just before she reached the shaving he did, and picked up —not a shaving at all—but
                                a long, slimy banana-skin. Flinging it into a refuse barrel, he only waited long enough
                                to say, " Somebody might have slipped on it," and was off again. It was a little thing
                                to do; but that one glance of the boy's clear, gray eyes, and this simple, earnest
                                sentence, made the lady's heart very warm toward the noisy fellow. He had not slipped
                                himself ; he was far past the danger, and when one is in a hurry, it is a great bother
                                to go twice over the same ground ; but the " somebody else " might slip, and so for the
                                sake of this unknown somebody the hurrying boy came back, and it may be saved the life
                                or limbs of a feeble old man or a tender little child. He might have said, " I can't
                                wait to go back. It is none of my doing, and so it is none of my business ; " but he
                                made it his business, and in this showed a trait of character which promised well for
                                the future. There is nothing nobler on earth than this taking care that " somebody else
                                " shall not suffer needlessly. The child who grows up with such a spirit always active
                                in him may make his home like a heaven upon earth, and he will never know what it is to
                                be unloved or friendless.—[Christian Secretary.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What boys should be" TEIform="index"/>What Boys Should Be</head><p TEIform="p">A philosopher has said that true education for boys is to " teach them what they ought to
                                know when they become men." What is it they ought to know, then ? First. To be true — to
                                be genuine. No education is worth any thing that does not include this. A man had better
                                not know low to read—-he had better never learn a etter in the alphabet and be true and
                                genuine in intention and in action, rather than 3eing learned in all sciences and in all
                                languages, to be at the same time false in heart and counterfeit in life. Above all
                                things, teach the boys that truth is more than riches, more than culture, more than
                                earthly power or position. Second. To be pure in thought, language and life — pure in
                                mind and body. An impure man, young or old, poisoning the society where he moves with
                                smutty stories and impure examples, is a moral ulcer, a )lague-spot, a leper who ought
                                to be treated as were the lepers of old, who were banished Tom society and compelled to
                                cry " Unclean," as a warning to save others from the pestilence. <pb n="90" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/>
                                90 THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. Third. To be unselfish. To care for the feelings and comfort of
                                others. To be polite. To be just in all dealings with others. To be generous, noble and
                                manly. This will include a genuine reverence for the aged and things sacred. Fourth. To
                                be self-reliant and self-helpful even from early childhood. To be industrious always,
                                and self-supporting at the earliest proper age. Teach them that all honest work is
                                honorable, and that an idle useless life of dependence on others is disgraceful. When a
                                boy has learned these four things, when he has made these ideas a part of his being —
                                however young he may be, however poor, or however rich — he has learned some of the most
                                important things he ought to know when he becomes a man. With these four, properly
                                mastered, it will be easy to find all the rest.—[Home Arts.</p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God knoweth best" TEIform="index"/>GOD KNOWETH BEST</head><p TEIform="p">Sometime, when all life's lessons have been learned, And sun and stars forever more have
                                set, The things which our weak judgments here have spurned— The things o'er which we
                                grieved with lashes wet, Will flash before us, out of life's dark night, As stars shine
                                most in deeper tints of blue; And we shall see how all God's plans were right, And how
                                what seemed reproof was love most true. And we shall see how, while we frown and sigh,
                                God's plans go on as best for you and me; How, when we called, He heeded not our cry,
                                Because His wisdom to the end could see. And even as prudent parents disallow Too much
                                of sweet to craving babyhood, So God, perhaps, is keeping from us now Life's sweetest
                                things, because it seemeth good. And if, sometimes, commingled with life's wine, We find
                                the wormwood, and rebel and shrink, Be sure a wiser hand than yours or mine Pours out
                                this potion for our lips to drink. And if some friend we love is lying low, Where human
                                kisses cannot reach his face, Oh, do not blame the loving Father so, But wear your
                                sorrow with obedient grace. And you shall shortly know that lengthened breath Is not the
                                sweetest gift God sends His friend, And that, sometimes, the sable pall of death
                                Conceals the fairest boon His love can send. If we could push ajar the gates of life,
                                And stand within, and all God's workings see, We could interpret all this doubt and
                                strife, And for each mystery could find a key. But not to-day. Then be content, poor
                                heart! God's plans, like lilies, pure and white, unfold. We must not tear the close-shut
                                leaves apart; Time will reveal the calyxes of gold. And if, through patient toil, we
                                reach the land Where tired feet, with sandals loose, may rest, When we shall clearly
                                know and understand, I think that we will say, " God knew the best!"</p></div3><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Men wanted" TEIform="index"/>MEN WANTED</head><p TEIform="p">It has been truly said that the great want of the age is men. Men who ai-e honest to the
                                heart's core. Men who will condemn wrong in friend or foe — in themselves as well as
                                others. Men whose consciences are as steady as the needle to the pole, men who will
                                stand for right, if the heavens totter and the earth reels. Men who can tell the truth
                                and look the world and the devil right in the eyes. Men who neither swagger nor flinch.
                                Men who have courage without whistling for it, and joy without shouting to bring it. Men
                                through whom the current of everlasting life runs still, and deep and strong. Men too
                                large for sectarian limits, and too strong for sectarian bonds. Men who know their
                                message and tell it. Men who know their duty and do it. Men who know their place and
                                fill it. Men who mind their own business. Men who will not lie, who are not too lazy to
                                work, nor too proud to be poor. When such men as these will fill places of trust and
                                responsibility, we shall have a Christian civilization, the highest, the best the world
                                ever saw. [Farm and Fireside.</p></div3></div2><pb n="91" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="home" TEIform="index"/>Home Topics</head><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good test of the purity of milk" TEIform="index"/>A Good Test of the Purity of Milk</head><p TEIform="p">A German paper gives a test for watered milk which is simplicity itself. A wellpolished
                                knitting-needle is to be dipped into a deep vessel of milk, and immediately withdrawn in
                                an upright position. If the milk is pure, some of the fluid will hang to the needle, but
                                if water has been added to the milk, even in small proportions, the fluid will not
                                adhere to the needle.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Look after the cellars" TEIform="index"/>Look after the Cellars</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> Many farmers use the cellars under their dwellings as a place to stow their
                                        root-crops, especially potatoes, beets, turnips, celery, and even cabbage, which
                                        is not a root. It is convenient to do so where there is no barn-cellar or where
                                        these vegetables' are not buried upon the premises. But it is a practice not to
                                        be recommended, except the best care is taken to keep the cellar clean and
                                        well-ventilated. Every day at about noon, when the weather will admit of it, the
                                        outer door should be opened for an hour or so, and even when the weather is
                                        extremely cold the door should for that length of time be partly opened. The
                                        refuse of vegetables also should be daily removed and not left to evolve a
                                        deleterious gas as soon as the temperature shall rise sufficiently to act upon
                                        it. The most danger is in the spring, when the mildness of the weather outside
                                        finds its way into the cellar, and operates, if the cellar is not ventilated
                                        freely, in producing decomposition in some degree. There is nothing that tends
                                        more directly to produce the most deadly fevers than filthy cellars. The
                                        poisonous gases permeate the whole house. And yet how frequently do we see
                                        cellars left untouched, with all their heaps of vegetable refuse, until April
                                        and even May ? We hope this word of warning will not fall on unwilling ears.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Germantown telegraph" TEIform="index"/>Germantown Telegraph</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To purify oil" TEIform="index"/>To Purify Oil</head><p TEIform="p">To make the oil pure, take a good sized bullet or other piece of lead which has a thick
                                coating of lead rust, cut it up fine, put it into the oil, and let it stand for two
                                weeks. This causes the acid to settle, and it then resembles milk at the bottom. Now
                                pour off the top, and your oil is pure. Common clock oil can be treated in this manner
                                and made better than some watch oil.</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lemon pie" TEIform="index"/>Lemon Pie</head><p TEIform="p">One grated lemon, two and one-half cups of boiling water, one-half cup of cold water, one
                                and one-half cups of sugar, three tablespoonfuls of cornstarch, and butter the size of
                                an egg. Put the cornstarch in the cold water and stir in the boiling water. This makes
                                two pies. Bake with under-crust. Beat the whites of three eggs for frosting.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Simple method of leveling" TEIform="index"/>Simple Method of Leveling</head><p TEIform="p">An exceedingly simple method of obtaining levels is described in The Manufacturer and
                                Builder. At each of two stations, perhaps a hundred feet apart, a pole is driven into
                                the ground. To each pole, near the top, a glass tube is tied. The lower ends of the
                                glass tubes are then connected with each other by means of a sufficiently long piece of
                                india-rubber tubing. Water is to be poured into one of the glass tubes till it fills the
                                tubing and part of the tubes ; it will rise to the same level, of course, in both tubes,
                                and the record of this height can be marked on the poles along*side. The method is
                                capable of surprising accuracy, and will serve where obstacles to vision intervene
                                between the stations.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>Thoughts for today</head><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Eyes to see God" TEIform="index"/>Eyes to see God</head><p TEIform="p">Augustine mentions a heathen once saying to him, as he pointed to the sun, to his idol
                                gods, and various objects about him, " Here are my gods, where is thine ? " Augustine
                                answered, " I show you not my God, not because I have not one to show, but because you
                                have not eyes with which to see Him."</p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christ is coming" TEIform="index"/>Christ is Coming</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Willard, Frances E." TEIform="persName"/>Frances E. Willard</byline><p TEIform="p"> exclaims : " Truly, Christ is coming, coming all the time, like sunrise from the east,
                                or summer from the south, or heaven to hearts that love and look for His appearing.
                                Happy are they who help to hasten, by a little, even, the day when He shall reign King
                                of nations as He now reigns Htfmc Qapits. <pb n="92" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 92 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO.
                                King of saints! " To all of which we say, Amen.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Keep good" TEIform="index"/>Keep Good</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bunyan, John" TEIform="persName"/>John Bunyan</byline><p TEIform="p">It is an easier matter to begin to do good than to continue therein; and the reason is,
                                there is not so much of a Christian's cross in the beginning of a work as there is in a
                                continual, hearty, conscientious practice thereof. Apples and flowers are not made by
                                the gardener, but are an effect of the planting and the watering. A life full of good
                                works is the only way on thy part to answer the mercy of God extended to thee. The heart
                                that is fullest of good works hath in it least room for Satan's temptation. Every
                                promise in the Bible is thine to strengthen, quicken and encourage thy heart.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wise man and the serpent" TEIform="index"/>The Wise Man and the Serpent</head><p TEIform="p">A wise man one day asked the serpent, " Of what advantage is it to thee to deprive men of
                                life ? The lion kills and devours his prey. The tiger, the wolf, and other fierce beasts
                                do the same, in order to satisfy their hunger ; but thou bitest thine innocent victims,
                                and sheddest mortal poison into their veins, without reaping any benefit from their
                                death, save the cruel satisfaction of destroying." " Why asketh thou me this question ?
                                " rejoined the reptile. " Ask rather the slanderer amongst thine own race, what pleasure
                                he finds in poisoning unto death those who have never injured him."</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Justice" TEIform="index"/>Justice</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Alcott, Bronson A." TEIform="persName"/>A. Bronson Alcott</byline><p TEIform="p">Says , in his " Concord Days : " "Let the sexes be held to like purity of morals, and
                                equal justice be meted out to them for any infraction of the laws of social order. Women
                                are the natural leaders of society in whatever concerns private morals ; lead where it
                                were safe for man to follow. About the like number of men, doubtless, possess gifts to
                                serve the country at large; while most women, as most men, will remain private citizens,
                                fulfilling private duties. Her vote as such will tell for personal purity, for honor,
                                justice, temperance, mercy, peace — the domestic virtues upon which communities are
                                founded, and to which they must be firmly rooted to endure. The unfalien souls are
                                feminine."</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>Agricultural</head><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Old Cato" TEIform="index"/>Old Cato</head><p TEIform="p">the Roman Senator, was not only a Senator, a true republican, but also a farmer. He wrote
                                a book upon farming. "Our ancestors," said Cato, " regarded it as a grand point of
                                husbandry not to have too much land in one farm, for they considered that more benefit
                                came by holding little and tilling it well." Virgil says, and this was after the empire
                                had begun : " The farmer may praise large estates, but let him cultivate a small one."
                                And Curtius, the Roman orator, went so far as to say : " He was not to be counted a good
                                citizen, but rather a dangerous man to the State, who could not content himself with
                                seven acres of land."</p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The farmer who keeps all the stock..." TEIform="index"/>The farmer who keeps all the stock...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The farmer who keeps all the stock his farm will safely carry, and " feeds them fat,"
                                soon has fat acres, even if they were not originally so, from the manure returned to the
                                soil. And the fatter the cattle are made the better the soil will become. So fat cattle
                                make fat farmers.</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Mexicans have a method of subduing fractious horses..." TEIform="index"/>The Mexicans have a method of subduing fractious horses...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Mexicans have a method of subduing fractious horses and such as are inclined to run
                                away, which might be introduced here with profit. A hood or winker is so arranged that
                                the driver or rider can in an instant draw it directly over the eyes of the animal,
                                effectually blindfolding him. When this is done the horse instantly becomes quiet, and a
                                repetition of the blindfolding two or three times gradually results in his becoming
                                permanently quiet and docile. Such an arrangement would be a valuable appendage to the
                                headgear of such horses as are disposed to run away.</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The London Omnibus Company, which ten years ago fed their horses..." TEIform="index"/>The London Omnibus Company, which ten years ago fed their horses...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The London Omnibus Company, which ten years ago fed their horses principally with oats
                                and beans, with hay, now feed almost exclusively on Indian corn and hay.</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Put a little sulphur in the salt for sheep..." TEIform="index"/>Put a little sulphur in the salt for sheep...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Put a little sulphur in the salt for sheep, not enough to make the mess distasteful to
                                them, and you will drive away ticks. The best time to give it is immediately after
                                shearing, then the ticks will drop from the wool easily. In winter if the hens can be
                                with the sheep they will pick off the ticks when thev come to the surface of the
                            wool.</p></div3><pb n="93" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let the farmers try sulphur and leave tobacco to the tobacco worm..." TEIform="index"/>Let the farmers try sulphur and leave tobacco to the tobacco worm...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Let the farmers try sulphur and leave tobacco to the tobacco worm, and its
                                        human companions. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New York tribune" TEIform="index"/>N. Y. Tribune.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Weights and measures" TEIform="index"/>Weights and measures</head><p TEIform="p">Here is a useful table of weights and measures as recognized by the United States: Bush.
                                Apples, dried.. .. Barley........... Beans, Castor " white..... Bran............
                                Buckwheat...... Corn, shelled .... '' in the ear.. " meal....... Lime, unslacked. .
                                Malt............ Oats............. Peaches,dried.... Peanuts, African . " Tenn'ss'e "
                                Virginia, lbs. Bush. lbs. 24 Peas............ 60 60 " ground..... 20 46 Plastering
                                hair... 8 60 Potatoes, Irish___ 60 20 " sweet ... 55 52 Rye............. 50 56
                                Salt............. 65 70 Seed, blue grass.. 44 48 " clover...... 60 30 " flax........ 56
                                39 " hemp...... 40 32 " H'ng'ry grass 54 33 " millet...... 50 32 " Timothy___ 45 28
                                Turnips___'..... 55 22 Wheat.......... 60</p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Twenty-five per cent gain in stock..." TEIform="index"/>Twenty-five per cent gain in stock...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Twenty-five per cent gain in stock is derived from giving them good shelter.</p></div3><div3 type="equipment" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harnesses should never be kept in the stables where manure is..." TEIform="index"/>Harnesses should never be kept in the stables where manure is...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Harnesses should never be kept in the stables where manure is constantly generating large
                                quantities of ammonia. This ammonia is rapidly absorbed by the leather, and the effect
                                upon the leather is about the same as would result from saturating it with strong lye.
                                In a word, ammonia rots leather, and hence, keeping a harness in the stable is sure to
                                result in its damage, more or less.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Book Table</head><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religiously speaking, we do not like lawyers;..." TEIform="index"/>Religiously speaking, we do not like lawyers;...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Religiously speaking, we do not like lawyers ; and yet, as a necessary evil, like doctors
                                —whom we are afraid of—we are forced to respect " Great Lawyers," particularly when we
                                are so fortunate as to stumble upon an honest attorney. Our father was a lawyer of
                                Brooklyn, N. Y., and this opinion of legal lights may seem like filial ingratitude ; but
                                we own to strong liking for lawyer " stories ; " and in a book published by The Law
                                Journal of Albany, N. Y., entitled " Short Studies of Great Lawyers," we found a
                                delightful and very instructive volume. The book is richly interspersed with
                                anecdotes,amid much valuable information concerning legal subjects. Were we a lawyer, we
                                should want this book on the shelf close by the Codes, and would frequently "make a
                                mistake on purpose," by selecting and reading law in " Short Studies," rather than in
                                the blue atmosphere of the more intricate Blackstone. The price is $2.00.</p></div3><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christ's first and second appearing" TEIform="index"/>Christ's First and Second Appearing</head><p TEIform="p">Shaker Manifesto, Shakers, N. Y., Publisher. Just at this time when so many books are
                                being issued upon The Second Coining, seems to us an excellent opportunity for calling
                                attention to the above standard work of The Shakers. It is a most replete work upon the
                                subject, and by far the most elaborate work ever issued by our people. Read as a history
                                of the rise and fall of ism.s, or as the chronicler of the events of Christ's
                                Appearings, it will be found unequaled in its line. It is a large octavo volume, bound
                                in leather, containing more than 600 pages of theology, history and biography, and sent
                                post-paid from this office for $1.50.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="world=news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Exemption from epidemics" TEIform="index"/>EXEMPTION FROM EPIDEMICS</head><p TEIform="p">In case of the London small-pox epidemic the remarkable fact has been noticed that only one
                            case of this frightful disease has engaged the attention of the medical officer of the
                            Jewish Board of Guardians. The same exemption from epidemic diseases has been noticed among
                            the Jews in all countries, and is attributed to their mode of living. It is an interesting
                            question, in a sanitary point of view, to what extent mortality from such diseases may be
                            limited to pork eaters. Bilious disease is largely attributable, it is well known, to the
                            use of pork. But the Jews not only reject pork from their dietary, but they also, under
                            their religious laws, exercise extraordinary care to secure the meat of animals that are in
                            a perfectly sound and healthy condition when killed. In our markets, for instance, they deal
                            only with certain butchers, who provide them with meat from, animals selected and killed
                            under the conditions of Jewish rules.</p></div2><pb n="94" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life's unfoldment" TEIform="index"/>LIFE'S UNFOLDMENT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>Martha J. Anderson</byline><p TEIform="p"> Mount Lebanon, N. Y. 1. Not all a dream, a passing dream, Is life's unfoldment here; 2.
                            Behold a silent work goes on, In nature's vast expanse; 3. Who clothes the lillies of the
                            field? And marks the planets' course? 4. O, what a glorious destiny, Awaits the human soul!
                            Earth's brightest glories are but gleams, Prom out the inner sphere. Where germs upspring in
                            beauteous forms, By law, and not by chance; Makes earth a fruitful harvest yield? Renews
                            each secret force? Beyond a brief mortality, Where higher powers control. What hopes and
                            longings fill the heart, And lift the mind on high— fTis thus the spirit's laten! force, In
                            ceaseless action strives, That same ereative power, beholds With tenderness and love, And
                            step by step, a starry way Will mark its progress on;<pb n="95" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. 95 They tell that the immortal part, Can never, never die. And fed from truth's
                            eternal source, In growth and beauty thrives. His noblest works where life unfolds, Like
                            types revealed above. Rejoicing in unclouded day, Where perfect victory's won. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Preaching and practicing" TEIform="index"/>PREACHING AND PRACTICING</head><p TEIform="p">" Forgive, forget," with fond regret We say to one another ; The words we speak, and yet we
                            wreak Our vengeance t'ward a brother. Vain is our speech, if each to each The practice
                            shames the preaching ; And toward our kind our hearts are blind, No friendly hand
                            outreaching. So easy 'tis to utter this, So hard to practice, uttered ; The angel kind that
                            moves the mind His snowy wings has fluttered, With grieving eyes has sought the skies While
                            yet our hearts are waiting, And all our chance of good is lost While we are hesitating. Oh
                            gentle Leech ! the what you preach Yourself must practice kindly, Nor point the way and lead
                            astray Your weaker brother blindly. By loving deeds our human needs Are filled direct from
                            heaven ; And every heart should share a part Of this most precious leaven. Forgive ! forget
                            ! if the regret Follow the harsh word spoken, Nor with a sneer receive the tear Which tells
                            the spirit broken. Our God is love, and from above He shall look down benignly. To err is
                            humanly to do, And to forgive, divinely.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Like angels" TEIform="index"/>LIKE ANGELS</head><p TEIform="p">Mother Ann Lee used to say her children should " pass and re-pass each other like angels,"
                            and although leaving us to imagine the love, joy and peace engaged in by the pure of the
                            other world, yet we feel through our imaginations a grand example from them. Swedenborg
                            speaks thus of the method that angels treat all with whom they come in contact: " I know
                            that a vast mass of the uncomforts of life depends upon the tendency to criticise rather
                            than to excuse or commend things which, in one view or another, deserve the latter as much
                            as the former. We may well remember Hamlet : 'If we all had our deserts, who would escape a
                            whipping ? ' "</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Practical religion" TEIform="index"/>PRACTICAL RELIGION&gt;</head><p TEIform="p">A man who has always been a close observer says, the religion we want is that which banishes
                            small measures from the tradesman's counter, pebbles from cotton bags, sand from sugar,
                            chicory from coffee, alum from bread, and water from milk cans. The religion which is to
                            save the world will not put all the big strawberries at the top, and all the little ones at
                            the bottom. It will not make one-half a pair of shoes of good leather and the other half of
                            shoddy, so that the first shall redound to the maker's credit, and the second to his cash.
                            It will not put Jouvin's stamp on Jenkins' kid gloves ; nor make Paris bonnets in the back
                            room of a Boston milliner's shop ; nor let a piece of velvet that professes to measure
                            twelve yards come to an untimely end at eleven and three-quarters. It does not put bricks at
                            $5 a thousand into chimneys it contracts to build with $7 material, nor smuggle white pine
                            into floors that have paid for hard pine, nor leave yawning cracks in closets where boards
                            ought to join.</p></div2><!--                     <pb n="96" id="p28"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p29"/>
                            <pb id="p30"/>
                            <pb id="p31"/>
                            <pb id="p32"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>