<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0602" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shakers, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">6</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">2</biblScope><date value="18760201" TEIform="date">February 1876</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">9-16</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="6" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="9" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="2" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">THE SHAKER Official Monthly.—Published by the United Societies. " WHAT IS TRUTH P" "THE ETERNAL
                        RESXilllNrQTJISIIMiHlNT OF ERROR." Vol VI V UX. V A. 11, FEBRUARY, 1876. SHAKER VILLAGE, J. H, |
                        NPAB ™eGkgs' { no. a</p><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Come, and be saved" TEIform="index"/>COME, AND BE SAVED</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Smith, Jane Emily" TEIform="persName"/>JANE EMILY SMITH</byline><p TEIform="p">"Whosoever will, let them come." O, ye who are halting on Babylon's plain, Come hither and
                            seek the new birth — Be stripped of your idols, seek heaven to gain, By bearing the cross
                            here on earth. Come, taste of the sweets which in Zion are found, By those who the full
                            price will pay; O list to the trumpet, and greet the glad sound, "From Babylon, come, come
                            away! " Come Fathers, come Mothers, come dear little ones, Who unto the kingdom are near; O
                            come ye loved daughters, and ye noble sons, Your souls are most precious, and dear. Come,
                            join the strong army of conquering souls, Who are turning the battle within, And freedom,
                            her banner with beauty unfolds, In token of victories they win. Come ye who are sin-sick,
                            and hunger for truth, Or thirst for the waters of life; O, come unto Zion, come aged or
                            youth, And enter the glorious strife. The way of salvation is open for all — Who are sick of
                            the world and its sins — ' Tis free for the patient, who run, yet not fall, And free for the
                            hero who wins. The virgins invite you to join their pure band, And march, from the sorrows
                            of earth, In ways that are leading to heaven's fair land — Thus seeking the heavenly birth.
                            O come from the north, from the south, east and west, And sit down in the kingdom, with
                            those Who from sin, death and darkness, enjoy a sweet rest, And their joy like a river
                            o'erflows.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hour in the day of progress" TEIform="index"/>AN HOUR IN THE DAY OF PROGRESS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, G. B." TEIform="persName"/>ELDER G. B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p">The present is, emphatically, a revolutionary age, a day of numerous revelations and
                            developments, of rapid transitions in science, art, morals, and religion — creedal faith or
                            profession. The character of Christians (so called), as a class, is being weighed in the
                            balance against reputation; and religious creeds, as well as their professors, are being
                            brought to the bar of judgment, to be tried by the light, which, for the last quarter of a
                            century especially, God, through ministering instrumentalities, has been widely dispensing
                            in some degree, throughout the world, among all people, of every nation and clime. To us, it
                            is manifest, this work of judgment will not stop, until it comes home to individual, even as
                            unto creedal, denominational, national, and society life. At present, conviction for sin is,
                            apparently, almost lost from earth; but, its advent will break forth in the near dawning of
                            a brighter day. It will return, like a morning shower, or the evening dew; and its pearly
                            drops will moisten the arid deserts of soul experience, and make plants of life to bloom
                            there luxuriantly. The crucible is heating, to apply the crucial tests to professions of
                            religion, by revealed Christian principles of righteousness. God's ministers, seen or
                            unseen, are blowing the fire! Let honest, sin-sick souls, through all the land, rally to
                            this crucial standard, and enlist; for God has so constituted the human soul it cannot live
                            (though it may exist in death) without religion; and the time is rapidly dawning when
                            irrational professions of religion, together with mere professors, will have to take
                            backgrounds among the dishonorable.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hope" TEIform="index"/>HOPE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Erving, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>ANNA ERVING</byline><p TEIform="p">As the earth, when parched by drought, suffers for want of the refreshing showers, so does
                            the agonized spirit mourn the loss of hope. But, when our spirits have been depressed by
                            sorrow, is there one of us but has felt and received courage from some kindly friend that
                            has bid us to hope ? Have not breezes of fragrant thoughts been wafted over us, as if an
                            angel had shaken from his wings the odors of paradise ? Hope is one expression of God's
                            enduring love for man, and ever encircles him as the light of day to guide and strengthen
                            him while on his earthly pilgrimage. But, not alone from sources above and around, does he
                            receive this soul-lifting boon ; for within the human heart is a hopeful fountain, ever
                            welling up fresh and pure, when not exhausted by neglect, nor hidden by despair. Hope is the
                            connecting link between the past and future ; the cheering ray that ever brightens the
                            present; it blooms in every season of existence, and, like the evergreen, preserves its
                            verdure throughout the year. Oh, how bright and beautiful is hope ! when I feel its magic
                            influence within me, my courage is restored; my drooping energies are renewed, and my heart
                            goes out in thanks to thee, my God ! I thank thee for the daily blessings I enjoy, while I
                            have faith to believe I shall merit the fulness of thy goodness in the future, when my
                            spirit shall have passed the narrow confines of mortality, and have entered the realm of
                            eternal life and heavenly felicity. God hath provided the balm of hope, to cheer and soothe
                            the sufferer. Oftentimes as the poor prisoner weeps in hopeless agony of spirit, a gentle
                            voice whispers " hope;" he feels he is an outcast from God and man. Again the voice
                            whispers, " God loveth all;" he trembles as though in the presence of a superior, yet
                            unknown power. Hope, at length, penetrates the suffering spirit, and inspires the degraded
                            one with new life; with a zeal to work for the redemption of his blemished character. Oh,
                            how thankful he feels, what joy elates him 1 what inexpressible happiness fills his being;
                            he longs to impart his simple experience to every guilty brother on earth; he is now happy
                            under the influence of hope; it has helped him to better his condition! How good is God, how
                            precious is hope!</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Human society, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>HUMAN SOCIETY. NO. 2</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL FRASER</byline><p TEIform="p">Referring to the advances of science, and to all the progress of our day, may we ask, what
                            are the moral, the religious and physiological manifestations of Christendom ? Do we not
                            find that four millions of persons in Ireland have died from want of food through land
                            monopoly? And that four millions more of British subjects, in India, have perished in a
                            similar manner, and from the same cause ? We are all aware that one of the most destructive
                            wars of modern times was begun and carried on for years, simply that four millions of
                            persons — the docile, the loving, the devotional African — might be held in perpetual
                            vassalage. Do we not see the red man of the American continent, the worshiper of the Great
                            Spirit, driven from his forest home, and withering under the influence of what is called
                            Christian civilization? Are not these enormities but the crests of the great waves of the
                            deep and wide current of "man's inhumanity to man ? " Do we not see, at this very hour,
                            Europe bristling with bayonets? its best blood abstracted from useful labor, and trained to
                            the art of war — the art of destroying life and property? Has the reign of the Prince of
                            Peace yet reached us? is there for him a quiet resting place amid such ungodly turmoil? Are
                            not the so-called Christian governnients based on fraud and sustained by violence ? Instead
                            of protecting the laboring poor, do they not rob them and crush their spirits? When we turn
                            to the domestic life of men and women, what do we behold? Do we find physiological and moral
                            law reigning supremely, or do not the effects of violations of the procreative and nutritive
                            functions fill the land with feebleness, disease and death? Is there one person in a hundred
                            who dies a natural death? Is not the long catalogue of their diseases a testimony against
                            their individual habits? Again, is there a single article of food or medicine a. a. lomas, )
                            mwn editok. f onAKJiiio, <pb n="10" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 1O THE SHAKER. capable of being manipulated,
                            which is not adxxlterated? Of clothing, is it not half sham and shoddy? It is far from being
                            pleasant to notice such a state of things; we being members of the human family, are we not
                            all representatives of that family? Can any one of us say, "stand off, I am organically
                            holier than thou?" "To see ourselves as others see us," is well, but to see ourselves in
                            others, is a humbling gift; it is being touched as Jesus was with a feeling of human
                            infirmity, teaching to remember, as we rise and journey upward, '' the hole of the pit from
                            whence we have been dug," and that pride and self-importance were not made for any one of
                            us. To conserve the good remaining in humanity, a religion based on physiological, and every
                            other God-instituted law, is needed; a religion which worketh by love? purifies the heart
                            and the body also — a religion in which all the bickerings of '' me and mine " are eternally
                            hushed — a religion in which the art of war is learned no more — a religion of peace, which
                            presents a diet involving no cruelty to animals, nor violates any of the higher instincts of
                            humanity. A finance that lendeth, but taketh no increase. An agriculture which leaveth the
                            land bettered, and covereth up every unclean thing. A religion in perfect accord with the
                            spirit of life, as manifested in Christ, a germ of which life inheres in every human^ being,
                            which, when operative, will bring forth manifesta. tions of God the Father, as did the
                            wellbeloved Son. A religion that accepts the human family as a unit, knows no personal
                            distinction but that which virtue creates, and blesses all nations with an example of purity
                            and peace.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Science and religion, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>SCIENCE AND RELIGION. NO. 2</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William H. (probable author)" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Science, as the term imports, is absolute knowledge. Religion, in its entirety, is the
                            fulfillment of all the obligations of human life. " This is pure and undefiled religion
                            before God the Father, to assist" — not merely to visit — '' orphans and widows in their
                            affliction, and to keep one's self unspotted from the world; " that is, this is a very
                            essential part of pure religion, not the whole. Religion implies the utmost activity in the
                            subject. " Whatsoever thy hands find to do, do with thy might; for in the grave " of
                            indolence, '' there is neither work, nor device, nor knowledge, nor wisdom;" — no work to
                            preserve the bodily and mental powers in vigor; no device to create a substitute for
                            activity; no knowledge of the Divine Life with its unlimited sources of mental, moral and
                            spiritual supplies; and no wisdom for self-guidance along life's devious way. It implies
                            openness of mind to receive all the truths of God from whatever intermediate source they are
                            derived. Bigotry forms no part of religion pure and undefiled. The divine inspirations flow
                            into every soul that is ready to receive them. '' When wisdom enters into the heart, and
                            knowledge is pleasant to the soul," they mould it into the divine image, removing by degrees
                            the prejudices which may have accumulated there when ignorance held sway. When they are
                            allowed to take the full control of the soul, they modify, strengthen and refine every
                            faculty, gradually unfolding them till the merely sensual man becomes the spiritual man, and
                            the whole is under the guidance of divine love. This is the science of the Christian life,
                            which every one who acquaints himself with it, finds to be as clearly demonstrated to his
                            internal consciousness, as the most precise of the exact sciences is proved to the
                            intellectual perceptions. Religious experience, as a science, is as widely extended as the
                            whole human race; for it includes the experience of every one whom the divine light has
                            awakened to a consciousness of the relations he sustains to eternal life. It embraces a
                            knowledge of the individual self as affected by perverted tastes, appetites, affections and
                            passions, and a knowledge of the divine power which restores these to their normal
                            condition, purifies them from their naturally gross and sensual state, and elevates them
                            finally to that which constitutes the life of God himself. Religious experience includes
                            association and conscious communion with those who partake of this life in its fullest
                            extent. The language of Jesus and Paul in reference to this experience was not used for mere
                            rhetorical effect,— '' Ye shall see heaven opened and the angels of God ascending and
                            descending ;" and, '' Ye are come to an innumerable company of angels, and to the spirits of
                            just men made perfect." Their own experience corroborated the literal truth of their words.
                            All the sciences, whether natural, intellectual, or religious, have had various theories
                            connected with them, which have been disproved by the accumulation of facts. The probability
                            is that there are yet many which will finally be discarded. Dogma is not necessarily truth,
                            fancy is not fact. This is, because man is a mere learner, with the power to ascertain truth
                            unfolding by degrees. On this score, one science has not much to boast of over another. It
                            is not therefore becoming in any one class to exalt their favorite science, whatever that
                            may be, as worthy of supreme devotion. Religious science has enough in it of the really
                            grand and beautiful to captivate every heart; and so has every other. But it is often the
                            case that the devotee of one class of the sciences disparages others, because, in his
                            estimation, they are of little importance. But the reason of this disparagement is his own
                            comparative or utter ignorance of them. In reality— '' Nothing useless is or low, Each thing
                            in its place is best; And what seems but idle show Strengthens and supports the rest." There
                            is needed on all sides, courage to look every one of God's truths squarely in the face.
                            Above all there is needed that candor which will induce every one to study carefully that
                            error, in his own mind at least, shall not usurp the place of truth. At some time in the
                            future there will be a oneness in the perception of truth, but not until every possible
                            means is used to eliminate error from whatever bears the name of science. Then divine
                            principles will bear the completest sway in the soul, producing harmony throughout. The
                            thoughts, taking their coloring from the internal harmony, will be orderly and consistent,
                            and actions, as streams from their fountains, will accord with the internal condition. This
                            alone can constitute the heaven to which Divine Wisdom points.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religion" TEIform="index"/>RELIGION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Patrick, Marion" TEIform="persName"/>MARION PATRICK</byline><p TEIform="p">In reflecting on the subject of religion, we are led to consider the saying of the wise
                            Solomon : " Her ways are ways of pleasantness, and all her paths are peace." Religion is a
                            cheerful and happy practice ; its neglect brings sadness and melancholy. That religion
                            demands of us the renunciation of all enjoyments in life, reserving nothing to balance the
                            sacrifice, is a sad mistake, and is a fearful drawback to its advancement among mankind. How
                            much wiser and better mankind would be, were all endowed with the full conviction that true
                            happiness consists in the cultivation and exercise of all Christian virtues ! As the gentle
                            dew falls on the flowers to revive their drooping leaves, so should religion inspire the
                            spirit, and renew its latent energies in times of affliction ; and remain as an abiding
                            solace for all the trials we may be brought to endure. The beauty of a truly religious life
                            is one of its valued recommendations. It teaches us how to live, to merit one another's
                            respect and love ; contributes to our present comfort and future happiness ; is an
                            invaluable gem which shines brightest in adversity; a sterling jewel that imparts godly
                            impulses to the heart, and a gentle spirit that leads to a far better world. Its influence
                            calms the ruffled scenes of life; gives assurance of an endless happiness, and is a
                            steadfast anchor to the soul. It shows itself in benevolent actions, proceeding from the
                            most unselfish motives, knows not the lust of power, nor seeks its own preferment. Its creed
                            is, " Do Good, love mercy, and walk humbly before God." Its sect is the pare in heart
                            wherever found, and its index, Him. who went about doing good — illustrating the spirit of
                            God in the human heart.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cincinnati convention" TEIform="index"/>THE CINCINNATI CONVENTION</head><p TEIform="p">[The following letters explain themselves. Those who have read of Elder F. W. Evans' masterly
                            address, at the above Convention, will be interested with the supplement he adds, at the
                            close of Dr. Miller's indorsement of nearly all therein contained.*] Dear Father Evans : You
                            have got at the fundamental principles of some of the most important reforms the world has
                            ever known. On the subjects of air, water and land, no one can dispute the fact, that these
                            should be free to all the inhabitants of the world. Every person born has a right to food,
                            to water, and a place to live. The very fact of existence ought to establish this in the
                            minds of all thinking people. That water and air are free, all are ready to admit, but
                            people seem to have an idea that the land is a subject of monopoly, and that those who
                            happen to have money, have a right to control large tracts of land, and prevent others from
                                <pb n="11" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> THE S BE A. K E 11 occupying it. Laws should be enacted prohibiting
                            any man from claiming possession of any more land than he can occupy and improve, and he
                            should have no further claim to the soil on which he lives than that which comes from the
                            products of the labor which he has placed upon that soil. Every one should have the
                            privilege of taking possession of a certain portion of land, and making such improvements
                            upon it as he desired. Improvements should constitute our right to the special spot which we
                            have selected, and no person should be allowed to deprive us of it, unless we are paid for
                            our improvements. If laws based upon this principle were enacted, what a wonderful impetus
                            would be given to the improvements of every civilized country. On the subject of public
                            debt, my mind is not so well established. To illustrate: Suppose some work of great public
                            importance is required, which the people of this generation will be compelled to make, like
                            completing a canal or railroad, or any other vast national work, the benefits of which are
                            to be reaped more by future generations, than by the present. In such case, I think there
                            can be nothing objectionable in requiring succeeding generations to pay a portion of the
                            cost. The Erie canal, I think, has been a great benefit to the people of this State. It
                            would have imposed a very hard task on our predecessors to saddle all the cost of that canal
                            on them, when we enjoy the benefits of it. On the same principle future generations will
                            reap the benefits of the preservation of the Union ; and it would, I think, have been
                            clearly unfair to impose on this generation the entire expenses of the war. Yours,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Miller, E. P." TEIform="persName"/>E. P. MILLER</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reply" TEIform="index"/>Reply</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Doctob: So magnanimously have you admitted so many points in my article, that I can well
                            afford to elucidate the one exception — national debts, entailed by a living generation,
                            upon a generation unborn. At first view, your argument for debt appears plausible, if not
                            logical. Let us look at it a little deeper. You see and admit, that " Laws, based upon the
                            principles of Right, as set forth in the Cincinnati Convention article — equal citizenship
                            and equality in landed property — would give wonderful impetus to improvements in every
                            civilized country." Why so? The causes of war being removed, the concentrated energies of
                            nations would be devoted to creating, not destroying. War-ships, monitors, rams, cannon,
                            ammunition, rank and file of army and navy, in time of peace, like the present, would be
                            saved as surplus capital. When right so far prevails over might, that woman co-operates with
                            man in legislation, destructive war will be a sheer impossibility. Then a tithe of the
                            money, now wasted in wars, will make all the improvements, in one generation, that that
                            generation has the courage and capacity to project. Accumulated capital in property and
                            scientific inventions will approximately annihilate space and time, by great national works,
                            as they have already done in railroad travel and telegraphic communications. '' Owe no man
                            any thing " — individually, nor collectively — is a sound practical maxim. Let us try it,
                            for as many generations as we have been running in debt, and then compare results. We are so
                            near now to total depravity, in Church and State, that almost any change will be
                            improvement.</p><byline TEIform="byline">Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. <persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Essential sacrifice" TEIform="index"/>THE ESSENTIAL SACRIFICE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Curry, Joseph T." TEIform="persName"/>JOS. T. CURRY</byline><p TEIform="p">"The Mighty God hath spoken — " Gather my zealous ones together unto me, those that have made
                            a covenant with me by sacrifice." These words of the Hebrew singer are better met by the
                            Shakers than by any other order now existing. Their great principle of sexual purity is the
                            very thing implied by the word •' sacrifice". The idea came from the Mosaic tabernacle,
                            which typified the perfect church or temple of the Living God, in which shall congregate the
                            144,000 sealed ones, " the first fruits unto God and the Lamb" Before the door of the
                            tabernacle stood an altar on which was sacrificed each morning and evening a lamb —a whole
                            burnt offering. The first one to fulfill this type was Jesus of Nazareth, of whom John the
                            Baptist said: " Behold the Lamb of God." Jesus was a virgin, a eunuch, sacrificing, in
                            obedience to the Father's command, the sexual propensity. He was an example of the kind of
                            men that shall compose the temple on earth. He knew that eighteen centuries would elapse
                            before his action and teaching would be fully appreciated, yet he announced the doctrine
                            plainly : " There are they that have made themselves eunuchs for the kingdom of heaven's
                            sake: he that is able to receive it, let him receive it." Here is a plain, positive
                            commandment to those who are " able." All who believe, as the Adventists, that the kingdom
                            of heaven is " near, even at the doors," are called by the logic' of their faith to '' stand
                            with the Lamb " — " follow the Lamb " — make the sacrifice prefigured by the Lamb. No one
                            can enter the Holy Sanctuary of Life Eternal without passing the altar at the door. They
                            must worship at the altar, or " the door " will be " shut " against them. This altar has
                            been erected by the Shakers, and they do right to call all of God's people to unite with
                            them in this work. They are certainly liberal enough ; saying in effect, " Believe what you
                            please, only make the sacrifice." Having very recently become acquainted with this Society,
                            and feeling it a duty to work with them in their inspired action, I announce myself a
                            Shaker, giving my own construction to the word. God is a Shaker; declaring that he will "
                            shake the heavens and the earth, and the sea, and the dry land." He " will shake all
                            nations, and the desirable things of all nations shall come *' into the House of God, and it
                            shall be filled " with glory, saith the God of hosts." We must either be Shakers or be
                            shaken. If we belong to God's army, we shall agree with him when he shakes, and will be able
                            to stand among the " things which cannot be shaken." Enfield, Conn.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Private property positively unchristian" TEIform="index"/>PRIVATE PROPERTY POSITIVELY
                            UNCHRISTIAN</head><byline TEIform="byline">[ <persName reg="Runyon, George R." TEIform="persName"/>Elder George R. Runyon has been speaking his mind
                            pretty plainly to the people of Nicholasville, Ky. From the appended extracts of his
                            address, we conclude that the Elder has lost all embarrassment when speaking the truth, if
                            he ever had any, and forgot to sugar-coat his potion, if he intended doing so. Listen to his
                            plain, blunt, wholesome, southern testimony *]:</byline><p TEIform="p">" The first Christian that ever lived, died, and went to heaven from earth, who taught all
                            men how they might gain salvation and heaven by the merits of their own working, or their
                            death and hell by their own demerits, was Jesus. He, the Father chose, prepared and
                            anointed, a leading example in all holy conversation and godliness, but gave him no private
                            property real nor personal—' not even where to lay his head.' * * * " Jesus and his
                            immediate disciples formed the first Christian Association that ever blessed the earth, and
                            they held their property in common, regardless of any previous property conditions. They
                            ceased to walk as men, and associated with angels and angelic conditions; then followed the
                            grand outpouring of the spirit at Pentecost, when was realized by many the divine baptism,
                            from which property distinctions were lost forever from among God's people. Hence no member
                            of the body of Christ has any right to the tree of life, nor to walk with angels, while
                            holding any claims to real or personal possessions. " From that date there has never been a
                            genuine Christian church nor association, having rich and poor members. If individuals do
                            not love Jesus well enough to divide their property with him, they do not sufficiently love
                            him to keep his commandments. And, from the time of the first advent, through the time of
                            the second, down to the present time, we know of no such thing as private-property
                            Christians; and only acknowledge such to be Christians as sell their possessions and share
                            with their Christian brethren as each has need; for ' inasmuch as ye have done it unto the
                            least of the brethren, ye have done it unto me!' Blessed change to all! the rich, who had
                            gathered much, gave until the poor had no lack, and they had nothing more than the formerly
                            poor; and as they treated one another, Jesus taught, they treated him. * * * " If the love
                            we have for Jesus is to be measured by the love we bear one another — and by this we are to
                            prove our discipleship — then how many friends has Jesus in all Christendom, after all that
                            has been said and suf. fered 1 Very few. The church of Jesus never was nor ever will be,
                            disgraced by either rich or poor members, and let all the people say amen. As Jesus, through
                            his godly life, became the anointed — Christ — so let all aim, by a life consecrated to God,
                            to become anointed, until the whole body will be Christ, and every member a self-denying
                            oneness with Christ and the Father." * * *</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Faith and works" TEIform="index"/>FAITH AND WORKS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fletcher, Richard" TEIform="persName"/>RICHARD FLETCHER</byline><p TEIform="p">"Words are but signs; they cannot show The fullness of the love we know, By living for each
                            other's good When words with melody unite, The gift of praise gives more delight; And prayer
                            brings more than earthly food. A nobler song, than power of art, God claims — an undivided
                            heart — Holding with sin an endless strife. By deeds alone, can love be shown, No other
                            proof can be made known, Of " Christ in us " the hope of life. Too long the truth has been
                            denied, By talk, about One "crucified Upon a tree," our death to bear— By which all sinners
                            may receive Free pardon, if they will believe — No cross to bear, but crowns to wear. <pb n="12" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 12 THE SBEA.KEH. Not Christ, an offering in our stead, But " Christ in
                            us " — the living bread — This truth men lay aside to rust. On worn-out words they try to
                            thrive, Pray God to " save their souls alive—" Poor souls! all honey-combed with lust. If
                            mere repeating, " I believe,'1'' Could bring salvation, to relieve The sting of unrepented
                            sin; Then might the farmer hope to gain An hundred-fold of golden grain, By sowing wild oats
                            to the wind ! Christ comes to save mankind from sin; Then how can those who live therein
                            Persuade themselves they are reformed? Can vines untrained, wild and deformed, Picture to us
                            the newly born? Does grafted fruit their lives adorn? Since root and branch of earthly love,
                            Trail downwards from the life above, Corroding mortals here with blight; Great is the need
                            —humanity should be Cut off from earthly loves, and free To live for Christ, up in the
                            higher life.</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE SHAKER. Monthly—60 cents per annum. A DUAL ADVOCATE OF CHEIST PRINCIPLES.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Greatest human foe" TEIform="index"/>THE GREATEST HUMAN FOE</head><p TEIform="p">Whest Ann Lee laid the corner-stone of the Shaker Church, she asserted that the lust of the
                            flesh was the root of all evil." Our subsequent efforts to keep Christian practice unspotted
                            from the world, and above the mire of perverted human lives, attest her statement to be most
                            righteous. Whatever controversy we have with the world, is mainly based on this issue.
                            Humanity will renounce every thing else — riches, poverty, power and worldly honor — before
                            it will yield for Christ, the pleasures of the lust of the flesh. We are charged with being
                            narrow in our religious views; yet we know the need of our concentration, and cannot afford
                            to leave this truth in obscurity, to enter upon any side issues of whatever name or nature.
                            The gift of God most needed by the whole people to-day, is a positive, and working
                            conviction, that those who engage in the lusts of the flesh, "shall not enter the kingdom of
                            G-od." All Christianity turns on the base of an exceedingly pure life. Jesus, the Christ,
                            never did nor could promise salvation nor heaven on any other principle, but "following him"
                            in the excellence of his purity. All other promises, of subsequent teachers, are
                            counterfeits, and will not pass the scrutiny of the Omniscient. Our hopes of humanity rest
                            on the belief, that its members will be honestly bold enough to lay aside all subterfuges,
                            and deal their whole violence to the lusts of the flesh — the giant devil of humanity —
                            which will not down afc the bidding of any, excepting those whose lives are rich in the
                            identical self-denials of Christ. Striking thus boldly at the root of evil, all the future
                            will be better and happier life; and those who will engage in the work of overcoming the
                            lusts of the flesh, will never be justly chargeable with being circumscribed in their
                            religious endeavors. There are many truths being evolved for our acceptance at the "present
                            hour — of spirit philosophy and physical necessity — and while not discarding these, we
                            cannot forget that our mission is the salvation of souls from the lusts of the flesh and
                            mind; and that an "eternal vigilance is the price of such liberty." We will accept all there
                            is of truth in materialization by the spirits; and the testimony that meets our needs of
                            stricter physical hygiene; and from these, if possible, draw aids in demonstration of the
                            great central fact, that the heavenly life discards all lusts of the flesh. There are
                            millions who believe in Shaker heavens hereafter; who hope to be transferred thither by a
                            process, which is an hallucination, knowing no self-denial against secret, giant evils.
                            While we promise such the bitterest disappointments, we exhort all to seek rewards, that
                            result from the purity of practical Christianity. Brethren, the world is the better for our
                            testimony; and although it feigns to doubt the possibility or probability of our
                            cross-bearing lives, it pays us a silent, but just tribute, which is severely condemnatory
                            of its own fleshly career. Let us continue. Let not the salt of our testimony lose its
                            savor. We are truly aware of the immense gratitude that rises from honest hearts, who derive
                            strength for their battles in fighting their monster evil. Let us preach and live courage
                            for the world, by precept and example. And while the thoughtless sneer, and the grossly
                            wicked ridicule, let us give assurance of the correctness of our faith, through the
                            exceeding righteousness and purity of our lives; than which, no more powerful testimony can
                            be delivered. Let the thoughtful be honest; let the preachers speak heaven's truth unbiased
                            by manmade creeds; let physicians do their whole duty, and reformers strike deeply at
                            humanity's greatest foe; and the lusts of the flesh will meet. with a check — the world will
                            quickly approach the millennium, and these triumphs will only be excelled by the precious
                            beatitude : Most blessed are they who overcome the lusts of the flesh !</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If you would bring up a child..." TEIform="index"/>If you would bring up a child...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">If you would bring up a child in the way he should go, occasionally skirmish along ahead of
                            him and point out the road.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Paul, first paper" TEIform="index"/>PAUL. First Paper</head><p TEIform="p">It is not a question in my mind, but an established fact, that the writings of Paul have done
                            more harm than good. Still we have in Paul the curious anomaly of a man, whose life is far
                            better than his theology. It is common with most people to let their faith precede their
                            works; but, with Paul, his life is to be admired of all, as are also many of his epistles
                            that are consonant with his life. But his '' becoming all things to all men," gained none to
                            his life nor to Christ, but gave ambush and defense to every theological stream with which
                            the world has since been sorrowfully flooded. We admit Paul's unusual ability; we give
                            credit to an exceeding humility, a consecration in his works with the people, and an
                            overpowering mastery of other minds that made him the acknowledged head of the so-called
                            Christian church. But it is useless to deny that Paul was a revolutionist among the
                            disciples, '' withstood them to the face," and charged them with hypocrisy (Gal. ii. 11,
                            14), and variously compromised the faith of the gospel first delivered to the apostles. That
                            Paul aimed more at the building up of a populous church, rather than demanding that all
                            should "follow" Jesus in the life of the New Creation, is apparent to all New Testament
                            readers; and the consequent fulfillment of the '' falling away" prophecy may be directly
                            attributed to Paul, rather than to any and all others who professed Christ in early days. It
                            is a matter of exceeding moment, whether we are " following Christ," or being led by
                            Paulism, into "by and forbidden paths," in the service of ourselves. If Paul wanted or wants
                            applause, he gets it from those who do not " follow Christ" as he lived, but by those whom
                            he permitted, to live as Christ did not. I accuse Paul of being an apologist for the flesh,
                            having an insane idea that he would " gain souls unto Christ" by and by ; of permitting the
                            practice of indulgences, which he knew, neither he nor others could practice any longer, and
                            be Christians; and I arraign Paul most seriously, for the elaboration of Habakkuk's digest
                            of Moses, 613 precepts — reduced by David to eleven, subsequently by Isaiah to six, later
                            still by Micah to three, and then almost lost to humanity by Habakkuk — • The just shall
                            live by faith," — an elaboration that frankly enjoins, among other things, faith without
                            works." (See Galatians.) If Paulism would save humanity from their sins to-day, as does and
                            will the life of Jesus, the Christ, I should have naught to say, and then would there have
                            been thousands saved who will not know what salvation is, until they drop Paul, and follow
                            Jesus. Strauss has labored earnestly in " The old Faith and the New," to harmonize the
                            various and numerous sects; but " there is no peace" this side nor the other side of
                            Christ's life. And when we conclude that the salvation of Christ is worth all and more than
                            it costs, we will take Christ's life for our guide, and say to Paul, or any other apologist
                            for the flesh or intervening human <pb n="13" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE 13 perversion, "Get thee behind
                            me." As a Christian(?) after PauVs permissions, I could engage in "the lusts of the flesh,
                            the lusts of the eyes, and the pride of life," and find apologies in his writings, as the
                            immense majority of so-called Christians do; but as a genuine "follower" of Christ, I find
                            my greatest opponent in Paul; and can see no hope of salvation for the world, until Christ's
                            life shall take precedence of Paul's permissions. Of Paul's coup d'etat among the apostles;
                            we must leave to our next paper, asking a patient kindly hearing. *</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Clarion" TEIform="index"/>THE CLARION</head><p TEIform="p">We have been plain in giving our testimony against any admixture of Church and State, because
                            we know, therein is a wedge, which, in the hands of either protestants or catholics, would
                            split any constitution, and reintroduce the Inquisition with increased horrors. We again
                            sound the clarion of warning. Councils, secret and open, are being frequently held, the
                            whole tone of which is inimical to the perpetuity of the rights of conscience. As we prize
                            our religious freedom, let us say to the whole clergical force, "Hands off from the
                            Constitution!" Let us enter protests against the presence of Bibles in the public schools,
                            the opening of political bodies with prayer; against the name of God on any coin, and an
                            eternal protest against the introduction of any religious term in the Constitution of the
                            United States. "Bender unto Caesar" (the State), what belongs to him," "and unto God" (the
                            Church), what is his — and this will maintain an eternal separation. Let the Nation be awake
                            on this subject. Our State (N. Y.), in its last election, gave a most telling rebuke to a
                            professional clergyman, anxiously aspiring to political preferment. First read this: * * *
                            The Hon. Felix R. Brunot, of Pittsburgh, president of the association, occupied the chair.
                            Steps were taken to secure articles of incorporation, under the name of the National Reform
                            Association. The maintenance of Sunday laws, the retention of the Bible in the common
                            schools, the defense of the judicial oath and other Christian(l) features of the government,
                            and the securing of suitable religious acknowledgments in all state constitutions, were
                            expressly recognized as among the objects of the society. Then find in the following, a
                            feeling of relief that the pulse of the nation beats healthily as yet:</p><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The State deals only with temporal affairs, and does not..." TEIform="index"/>The State deals only with temporal affairs, and does not...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The State deals only with temporal affairs, and does not attempt to usurp
                                        spiritual functions. Therefore the objects and methods of public education are
                                        wholly secular, but by no means necessarily, or at all immoral or irreligious.
                                        On the contrary, they are decidedly favorable to piety and morality. But,
                                        composed denominationally as the American people is, the State ought not to
                                        impart religious education. The moment such an attempt should be made the
                                        community would be in conflict as to what form it should take. It may be
                                        conceded, without danger perhaps, that the State should not teach ethics, except
                                        so far as the great fundamental principle of morals and politics as to which all
                                        Americans are agreed are concerned. The religious educationshood may and should
                                        be remitted to the family, the Sabbath-school, and the Church — the natural and
                                        divinely-appointed guardians of religion and ethics. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Zion's herald" TEIform="index"/>Zion's Herald.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="But the question is fairly up and will not go down at the bidding of the politicians..." TEIform="index"/>But the question is fairly up and will not go down at the bidding of the politicians...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">But the question is fairly up and will not go down at the bidding of the
                                        politicians. The American people are, as a whole, terribly in earnest in their
                                        devotion to their system of free secular schools for all the people; and they
                                        are justly and decidedly jealous of any and all priestly or ecclesiastical
                                        interference with them.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Christian advocate" TEIform="index"/>Christian Advocate.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Not as Protestants alone, but as American citizens..." TEIform="index"/>Not as Protestants alone, but as American citizens...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Not as Protestants alone, but as American citizens, sincerely desiring the
                                        preservation of our institutions under the protection of an advancing
                                        intelligence, and with no regard to any sectarian ends, we are to day called
                                        upon to settle the vital question of the perpetuity of our free school system,
                                        and to " denounce as a crime against liberty and Republican institutions, any
                                        project for a sectarian division or perversion of the school fund of the State."
                                        Let it be done.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Baptist weekly" TEIform="index"/>Baptist Weekly.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let us all labor for the security of free thought, free speech..." TEIform="index"/>Let us all labor for the security of free thought, free speech...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Let us all labor for the security of free thought, free speech, free press,-pure morals,
                                unfettered religious sentiments, and equal rights and privileges for all men,
                                irrespective of nationality, color or religion. Encourage free schools, and resolve that
                                not one dollar appropriated to them shall be applied to the support of any sectarian
                                school. Resolve that neither state nor nation shall support institutions save those
                                where every child in the land may get a common school education unmixed with atheistic,
                                pagan or sectarian teachings. Leave matters of religion to the family altar. Keep Church
                                and State forever separate.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Grant, U. S." TEIform="persName"/>U. S. Grant.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sectarian folly" TEIform="index"/>SECTARIAN FOLLY</head><p TEIform="p">Methodist Bishop Haven, having nominated President Grant for a third term "(poor business for
                            a bishop), the New York Tribune says: Would it not be well for Bishop Haven to be a little
                            more explicit? Else there may be danger of having Baptist and Presbyterian and
                            Congregationalist, and nobody knows how many more sectarian candidates for President, which
                            would be a very sad state of things; for when it comes to that, who knows but that the Roman
                            Catholics may hold a convention and nominate the Pope? And then—great heavens! where are
                        we?</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bread" TEIform="index"/>BREAD</head><p TEIform="p">Custom and habits too frequently make havoc with health. While this assertion applies, with
                            much propriety, to very many customs, we would ask attention to its bearing upon the use of
                            bread, made of superfine flour. We say, " we like it"; but it is because our appetites are
                            perverted, even the same as those who "like tobacco." We really mean, that we have learned
                            to love its use, through the almost innumerable "ills that flesh is heir to " — becoming
                            such an heir to the whole catalogue of headaches, costiveness, fevers, chronic diseases and
                            sweeping calamities, more through the use of superfine flour than we wot of. We take the
                            best wheat, hull it, and grind it as fine as we can; separating the hull and the coarser
                            particles of the berry by a bolt, we get the fine flour. This we mix with water, and add
                            thereto a mess of living putridity, knead it, bake it, eat it, are sick by it, and by the
                            bye, die of it! That which we should use as the "staff of life," we turn into a slow, but
                            sure poison. With the bran we act with greater humanity, when feeding it to our horses and
                            kine. We grind them oats, corn on the cob, and, knowing we should kill them if we bolted
                            this flour, conscience and exchequer both forbid. We mind, and our stock is healthy from
                            youth to old age. Let us reverse the rule, so far as feeding them the flour we eat, and soon
                            the sleek animal becomes the poor beast, that in a few weeks cannot get up in its stable.
                            Again, if sufficient constitution remains, feed it the Jbran we refuse, and it soon becomes
                            the titan of yore. Who is there but knows that fine flour leads directly to costiveness,
                            headache and other incipient ills ? Who is there that will refuse to know that coarse-ground
                            wheat bread, with the bran in, will not only relieve these but prevent them, and all those
                            ills that supplement them? As presenting a truthful but unhappy experiment, let any one
                            attempt living on superfine flour only, for a week or more — they will learn much by such
                            experiment — of suffering. Again, let any try cracked wheat, graham pudding, or
                            coarse-ground wheat in its various forms, for any length of time, and a happy experience
                            will be theirs; not only through the expurgatorious of quondam diseases, but in the new
                            life, of ruddy strength, and a corresponding health of spirit. If there is any thing that
                            truly represents food and medicine, it is good bread — and good bread means something more,
                            than material made of flour that has been killed by grinding, and poisoned by living
                            animalculse. The time is coming, and soon, when a person's religion may be estimated by the
                            quality of bread which they eat. Let us reflect upon and move in the matter. And when we
                            shall have less poor theology in the pulpit, and more genuine theology in the bread, it will
                            be more than well. *</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Confession" TEIform="index"/>CONFESSION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescott, James S." TEIform="persName"/>JAMES S. PRESCOTT</byline><p TEIform="p">In the revival movement of Moody and Sankey, we hear but little said about confession of sin.
                            Why is this? Can there be any thing lasting or radical in such revivals, without a thorough
                            cleansing of the heart, by an honest confession? Will not those who build their hopes of
                            heaven on such transient excitements be disappointed when they come to enter the spirit
                            world and see the record of their lives? Judging from past history, viz.: the days of "
                            Pentecost," and the " Kentucky Revival," the angels of conviction are not yet sent forth,
                            but they are coming — the way is preparing — and when they come we shall know it. Under a
                            former dispensation, when one wanted to know what good thing he should do to inherit eternal
                            life, the word was " Keep the law." What law? If he wanted to be a good Jew, keep the law of
                            Moses — physiological law; but if he wanted to be a good Christian, the law of Christ, and
                            then go on unto perfection. Water baptism is good as far as it goes to the cleansing of the
                            body, but as the baptism of the spirit is to the soul, so is the baptism of water to the
                            body, and it will take these elements combined, to regenerate the whole man and woman. ''
                            Verily I say unto you, except a man be born of water, and of the Spirit, he cannot enter
                            into the kingdom of God." To show the condition of souls when they enter into the "spirit
                            world," who vainly imagine they are going right to Jesus, when they die, because they belong
                            to some ortho8HAKEE. <pb n="14" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. dox church, we make the following
                            extracts of a communication from Margaret Bush, who died in England, many years ago, a
                            Methodist; in answer to inquiries made by one Thomas Bush, who had been a Methodist
                            preacher, and who was, at that time, a member of the Society at North Union: uJuly6, 1841.
                            '' My Dear Brother : " You wished to know where I am. I will tell you. I have lived among
                            the children of God, about six years, and that is all. I hope you will never have to suffer
                            as much as I have, before you enter into happiness. Perhaps you would like to know what
                            caused my sufferings. It was my righteousness founded on selfishness. I thought I was very
                            good. Yea, I thought there were not many so good as myself. '' Although I did not tell the
                            people I was good, yet I thought within myself that I was; so you see it was not
                            righteousness, but it was self-righteousness, and that you know will never stand the test. I
                            built upon a sandy foundation. I thought that I should surely go to heaven when I left the
                            world. Yea, I thought that the Saviour as I used to call him, would say unto me, ' Well done
                            thou good and faithful servant, enter thou into the joy of thy Lord.' "But ah! what a sad
                            mistake. I found that I had all my sins to confess, every one of them, and this I was too
                            proud to do. What, said I, after living in such a manner as I have, and being so highly
                            esteemed among general mankind, now to become so mean, I thought, as to confess my sins, to
                            relate them, just as I had committed them, I said I had confessed my sins! ''The question
                            was asked me, how did you confess your sins? I answered and said, ' O Lord thou knowest I am
                            a sinner. O merciful God wilt thou pardon all my sins. O heavenly Father, wilt thou save
                            this poor wretched worm of the dust, from thy burning wrath ?' Yea, this is the way in which
                            I confessed my sins. I confessed that I was a sinner, and I thought it was all that could be
                            required of me. I suffered, and suffered, until I was willing to confess every thought, word
                            or action, that was not acceptable to God. '' I tell you, I had all to confess before three
                            thousand faithful witnesses. Yea, I was thankful indeed for that privilege. I did confess my
                            wicked deeds before them all, upon my bended knees. * * * Oh, my crown is not bright, and my
                            robe is not white compared with those who have borne a faithful cross against the carnal
                            mind; and this is the cry of every unfaithful soul. Now what I have written to you is truth,
                            and nothing but the truth."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="All things new" TEIform="index"/>"ALL THUGS NEW."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prentiss, Oliver" TEIform="persName"/>OLIVER PRENTISS</byline><p TEIform="p">"No more death—no more pain, for the former things are passed away." How? How is this little
                            planet to be " replenished," withont pain? How are our mortalities to be disposed of,
                            without death f Materialization and Dematerialization are the keys to unlock the deep
                            mysteries of Holy Writ. If dematerialized spirits can be rematerialized, for a short time,
                            as from credible evidence doth fully appear, why not for a longer time? If a materialized
                            spirit can be dematerialized, for a brief period, why not as long as the Lord pleases. Who
                            objects? Not those, sure, whose part it is to perform the painful drudgery of reproducing
                            the old way — the maternal drudgery. Let us have the new way and make a clean thing of it —
                            the New Earth and New Heavens, so long foretold —¦ the ideal of all the truly great and
                            good, since the world began. Who knows but God put that ideal in their souls? Why not have
                            the ideal actualized, as the heavens have graciously pleased to vouchsafe the ways and
                            means?</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religion: what is it?" TEIform="index"/>RELIGION: WHAT IS IT?</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The religious world must yet be taught to see, that if a man's religious
                                    experiences, belief, or observances do not make him better, his religion is utterly
                                    worthless, and he might just as well be destitute of any. In fact, in such a case,
                                    destitution would be an advantage: for we have met persons, of whom, on personal
                                    acquaintance, we were sure that the worst things in their disposition and impulses
                                    were those they had borrowed of their religion; that they would have been more
                                    amiable, just, and loving, had their better instincts and affections not been
                                    blunted and stifled by the bigotry or the superstition they had received with their
                                    religious education. The necessity of being outspoken on this point is seen in the
                                    fact that the religious multitudes do not seem to be conscious of the wide chasm
                                    there is between the gospel they profess to follow and the doctrines and usages of
                                    any of the Christian churches. If we assume, even nominally, to be disciples of
                                    Jesus, there is no way but to study his ideas, principles, and methods: if we leave
                                    him to follow Moses, David, or Paul, so much do they differ from him that we are in
                                    sad danger of disregarding his words. Yet Jesus is almost entirely forgotten and
                                    neglected in Christian teaching, that Moses, David, and Paul may be heard, and
                                    heard, too, on points on which they are least in sympathy with him. Of all the
                                    sermons preached in this country in the last twenty-five years, we venture the
                                    estimate that the words of Jesus have not furnished the text for more than one in
                                    five hundred; and when any of his words are used, they often consist of some
                                    disjointed phrase, that means nothing out of its place : as, for example, when the
                                    simple words " follow me," used by Jesus merely as an invitation to personal
                                    association while he lived, are " spiritualized" into some impossible meaning, and
                                    made to signify " conversion," or something else, of which he never dreamed. If
                                    Jesus were to reappear on earth, as has sometimes been suggested, it might be a
                                    question whether his indignation at the notions for which in Christian pulpits his
                                    name was made responsible, would not after all be less than his astonishment that
                                    this should be called a Christian land. He would £nd churches costly enough, and
                                    services of worship in preparing which no expense was spared; but that the only
                                    thing for which no provision was made, was that of making religious worship a power
                                    by which human life may be purified and human character ennobled. We do not expect
                                    that our religious observances will be of much practical use to us, until, at least,
                                    the conviction that such is their only true end shall be firmly lodged in the
                                    popular consciousness. This is now so far from being recognized, that the statement
                                    that religion is essentially goodness, is sometimes mentioned with something like a
                                    sneer in our best religious journals. It is time there should be a fair
                                    understanding on this point. Something of a conflict has recently sprung up as to
                                    the use of the name Christian. We care but little for names — qualities are
                                    fundamental. We see no objection to call goodness by the name of Christianity: but
                                    if Christianity in its essential elements be not goodness, that venerated name no
                                    longer has any charms for us.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New age" TEIform="index"/>The New Age</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>GOLDEN SAYINGS</head><p TEIform="p"/><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kind words are among the brightest flowers..." TEIform="index"/>Kind words are among the brightest flowers...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Kind words are among the brightest flowers of earth; they help to convert the humblest
                                home into a paradise.</p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is said that President Lincoln once said to Senator Fessenden..." TEIform="index"/>It is said that President Lincoln once said to Senator Fessenden...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">It is said that President Lincoln once said to Senator Fessenden: "What is your
                                religion?" "Not much to boast of, but I suppose I am as much a Unitarian as any thing."
                                Oh, a Unitarian," said Lincoln, " I thought you might be an Episcopalian. Seward is
                                Episcopal, and I notice you swear about the same as he does." </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Every true hero grows by patience..." TEIform="index"/>Every true hero grows by patience...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Every true hero grows by patience. People who have always been prosperous are seldom the
                                most worthy, and never in moral excellence the most strong. He who has not been
                                compelled to suffer, has probably not begun to learn how to be magnanimous; as it is
                                only by patience and fortitude that we can know what it is to overcome evils, or feel
                                the pleasure of forgiving them. </p></div3><div3 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="After the death of Abdermen, calif of Cordova, the following paper was found" TEIform="index"/>After the death of Abdermen, calif of Cordova, the following paper was found
                            </head><p TEIform="p">After the death of Abdermen, calif of Cordova, the following paper was found in his own
                                handwriting: "Fifty years have elapsed since I became calif. I have possessed riches,
                                honors, pleasures, friends, in short every thing that man can desire in this world. I
                                have reckoned up the days in which I could say that I was really happy, and they amount
                                to fourteen." Oh, the consummate vanity of worldly fame and greatness! </p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Education does not commence with the alphabet..." TEIform="index"/>Education does not commence with the alphabet...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Education does not commence with the alphabet. It begins with a mother's
                                        look, with a father's nod of approbation, or his sign of reproof; with a
                                        sister's gentle pressure of the hand, or a brother's noble act of forbearance;
                                        with a handful of flowers in green and daisy meadows; with a bird's nest admired
                                        but not touched; with pleasant walks in shady lanes; and with thoughts directed,
                                        in sweet and kindly tones and words, to nature, to beauty, to acts of
                                        benevolence, to deeds of virtue, and to the source of all good — to God himself!</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Blackwood" TEIform="index"/>Blackwood</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is a libel on the holy and useful sacrament of work to call anxiety by its name..." TEIform="index"/>It is a libel on the holy and useful sacrament of work to call anxiety by its name...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">It is a libel on the holy and useful sacrament of work to call anxiety by its
                                        name; for work, real, honest work, is of all influences the most quieting, the
                                        most serious and consoling, a genuine happiness in disguise. Thank God for daily
                                        work! it is daily blessing, for God reaches us good things with our own hands.
                                        There is dignity as well as necessity in labor. The angels know no higher joy
                                        than service; "the silent heavens have goings on, the stars have tasks;" and to
                                        the true worker, his labor is not altogether a question of profit and loss.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Albany express" TEIform="index"/>Albany Express</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Can true piety exist without honesty..." TEIform="index"/>Can true piety exist without honesty...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Can true piety exist without honesty? We apprehend there are some persons who think it
                                can, but if so they are mistaken. The consistent Christian is a man of his word, a man
                                of integrity, an upright man in all his business transactions. There may be honesty
                                where there is no piety, but where there is piety there will be found honesty. Says
                                Longfellow: "Morality without religion is only a kind of dead 14 <pb n="15" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/>
                                THE SHAKER. 15 reckoning, an endeavor to find our place on a cloudy sea by measuring the
                                distance we have to run, but without any observation of the heavenly bodies." </p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A dyspeptic minister gorging his system with the rich food..." TEIform="index"/>A dyspeptic minister gorging his system with the rich food...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A dyspeptic minister gorging his system with the rich food prepared by the
                                        "sisters," and taking no exercise, is a spectacle to make only infidels and
                                        undertakers rejoice. It was gravely proposed to inscribe on the tombstone of a
                                        gluttonous young minister, who was cut off by disease induced in this way: "Died
                                        of going out to tea."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Science of health" TEIform="index"/>Science of Health</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>PHILOSOPHICAL BRANCH</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Warts may be removed..." TEIform="index"/>Warts may be removed...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">... .Warts may be removed, says a celebrated physician, by rubbing them night and morning
                                with a moistened piece of muriate of ammonia. They soften and dwindle away, leaving no
                                such mark as follows their dispersion with lunar caustic. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Glue frequently cracks..." TEIform="index"/>Glue frequently cracks...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">. .. Glue frequently cracks because of the dryness of the air in rooms warmed by stoves.
                                An Austrian contemporary recommends the addition of a little chloride of calcium to glue
                                to prevent this disagreeable property of cracking. Chloride of calcium is such a
                                deliquescent salt that it attracts enough moisture to prevent the glue from cracking.
                                Glue thus prepared will adhere to glass, metal, etc., and can be used for putting on
                                labels without danger of their dropping off. </p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A Dane has invented an arrangement..." TEIform="index"/>A Dane has invented an arrangement...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">__A Dane has invented an arrangement to take the place of crutches, by which the cripple
                                can go fast or slow, and up or down stairs without touching his feet to the ground or
                                working but one arm. </p></div3><div3 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A cubic inch of gold..." TEIform="index"/>A cubic inch of gold...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">__A cubic inch of gold is worth $146, a cubic foot $252,288. The quantity of gold now in
                                existence is estimated to be $3,000,000,000, which, welded in one mass, could be
                                contained in a cube of 23 feet.</p></div3><div3 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Recent investigations with new apparatus..." TEIform="index"/>Recent investigations with new apparatus...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> __Recent investigations with new apparatus, made by Professor Cornu, at Paris, show the
                                velocity of light to be 300,400 kilometres or 186,660 miles per second. This was the
                                mean of 508 observations. </p></div3><div3 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The signal recently erected on the summit..." TEIform="index"/>The signal recently erected on the summit...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">__The signal recently erected on the summit of Mt. Shasta, Cal., by the coast survey, is
                                a hollow cylinder of galvanized iron, twelve feet high, and two and a half in diameter,
                                surmounted by a cone of nickelplated copper. The reflection from this cone is so strong
                                that it is believed the signal can be used for observations at a distance of 100 miles.
                            </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A singular mathematical fact" TEIform="index"/>A singular mathematical fact
                            </head><p TEIform="p">__A singular mathematical fact. Any number of figures you may wish to multiply by 5 will
                                give the same result if divided by 2 — a much quicker operation ; but you must remember
                                to annex a cipher to the answer, whenever there is no remainder, and when there is a
                                remainder, whatever it may be, annex a 5 in the answer. Multiply 464 by 5, and the
                                answer will be 2,320; dividing the same number by 2 and you will have 232, and as there
                                is no remainder, add a cipher. Now take 357, and multiply by 5; there is 1,785. Divide
                                the same number by 2, and you have 178 and a remainder; you therefore place a 5 at the
                                end of the line, and the result is again 1,785. </p></div3><div3 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Manufacture of paper" TEIform="index"/>Manufacture of paper
                            </head><p TEIform="p">... Manufacture of paper. Of the 1,300,000,000 human beings inhabiting the globe,
                                360,000,000 have no paper nor writing material of any kind; 500,000,000 of the Mongolian
                                race use a paper made from the stalks and leaves of plants; 10,000,000 use for graphic
                                purposes tablets of wood; 130,000,000 —the Persians, Hindoos, Armenians, and Syrians —
                                have paper made from cotton, while the remaining 300,000,000 use the ordinary staple.
                                The annual consumption by this latter number is estimated at 1,800,000,000 pounds, or an
                                average of six pounds to the person, which has increased from two and a half pounds
                                during the last fifty years. To produce this amount of paper 200,000,000 pounds of
                                woolen rags, 800,000,000 pounds of cotton rags, beside great quantities of linen rags,
                                straw, wood and other materials are yearly consumed. The paper is manufactured in 3,960
                                paper mills, employing 90,000 male and 180,000 female laborers. The proportionate
                                amounts of the different kinds of paper are stated to be: Of writing paper, 300,000,000
                                pounds; of printing paper, 900,000,000 pounds; of wall paper, 400,000,000 pounds, and
                                200,000,000 pounds of cartoons, blotting-paper, &amp;c. </p></div3><div3 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Parisian police lanterns" TEIform="index"/>Parisian police lanterns
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">__Parisian police lanterns. Safety lamps of an original construction are used
                                        by the night policemen and watchmen of Paris. A small glass vial holds a piece
                                        of phosphorus as large as a pea, upon which is poured boiling olive oil
                                        sufficient to fill up about a third of the vial. The latter is then closely
                                        stopped by a cork. In use, the stopper is released for a moment, so as to permit
                                        the entrance of air to the phosphorus. The vacant inner space is thereupon lit
                                        up, diffusing a clear, and, of course, perfectly harmless light. When the light
                                        fades it may be revived by a fresh uncorking. A lamp so prepared will hold good
                                        for six months without renewal.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Journal of Chemistry" TEIform="index"/>—Journal of Chemistry.</bibl>Journal of Chemistry
                                </cit></p></div3><div3 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dr. Hooker, a London scientist, recently exhibited..." TEIform="index"/>Dr. Hooker, a London scientist, recently exhibited...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">__Dr. Hooker, a London scientist, recently exhibited before the British Association for
                                the Advancement of Science, a wonderful plant called Dional. A fly was captured and put
                                upon a leaf, which instantly closed, and on reopening, it was found that the fly was
                                completely dissolved. A bit of beef was consumed in the same way. The leaf was then fed
                                with cheese, which disagreed with it so much that it eventually killed it. "Dr. Hooker
                                explained that the plant's action was precisely similar to that of the human
                            stomach."</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>SPIRIT OF THE FARM</head><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is said that corn loses one-fifth..." TEIform="index"/>It is said that corn loses one-fifth...</head><p TEIform="p">__It is said that corn loses one-fifth by drying, and wheat one-fourteenth. From this the
                                estimate is made that it is more profitable for the farmer to sell imshelled corn in the
                                fall at seventy-five cents, than at one dollar a bushel in the following summer, and
                                that wheat at $1.25 in December, is equal to $1.50 in the succeeding June. In cases of
                                potatoes, taking those that rot and are otherwise lost, together with the shrinkage,
                                there is little doubt that between October and June, the loss to the owner who holds
                                them is not less than thirty-three per cent.—New York Bulletin. </p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Earth worms" TEIform="index"/>Earth worms
                            </head><p TEIform="p">__Earth worms. These insignificant and unattractive creatures are of the greatest benefit
                                to the fields which they inhabit, though many have supposed to the contrary. They are
                                very humble but efficient servants of the agriculturist; and far from injuring his
                                meadow and his garden, they devote themselves with praiseworthy assiduity to turning
                                over the soil to a greater depth and more thoroughly than can be done with the best
                                appliances known to science. These animals (for so they are classified by the
                                naturalists) are scarcely more than animated tubes. They seem to live by taking earth
                                and earthly substances in at one end and passing them out at the other. This simple
                                process of digestion is aided, however, by a mucous secretion; and the worm has a habit,
                                when he has filled himself with earth, of ascending to the surface, turning around and
                                working himself back again into the ground. This operation unloads him; and the process
                                repeated by millions of his fellows cannot but have a highly beneficial effect upon the
                                quality of land. It is said by Mr. Darwin that these worms have been known to cover a
                                field to the depth of thirteen inches in the course of eighty years. A slow process, to
                                be sure, but so are all the processes of Nature. This, however, is not all that they do.
                                They carry their shafts and galleries to a depth of several feet, and cross and
                                intersect in all directions, loosening the soil, opening it to the air and water, and,
                                in short, doing all that they can to help vegetation, without preying upon it or
                                injuring its roots in the slightest degree. </p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ten rules for farmers" TEIform="index"/>Ten rules for farmers
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> __Ten rules for farmers. 1. Take good papers, and read them. 2. Keep an account of farm
                                operations. 3. Do not leave implements scattered over the farm, exposed to snow, rain,
                                and heat. 4. Repair tools and buildings at a proper time, and do not suffer subsequently
                                threefold expenditure of time and money. 5. Use money judiciously, and do not attend
                                auction sales to purchase all kinds of trumpery because it is cheap. 6. See that fences
                                are well repaired, and cattle not grazing in the meadows or grain fields or orchards. 7.
                                Do not refuse to make correct experiments, in a small way, of many new things. 8. Plant
                                fruit-trees well, care for them, and of course get good crops. 9. Practice economy by
                                giving stock shelter during the winter; also good food, taking out all that is unsound,
                                half rotten, or mouldy. 10. Do not keep tribes of cats and snarling dogs around the
                                premises, which eat more in a month than they are worth in a life-time. Journal of
                                Chemistry.</p></div3><div3 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Oriental economy" TEIform="index"/>Oriental economy
                            </head><p TEIform="p">__Oriental economy. England washes most of the manure made by her people into the ocean,
                                and then hunts over the globe from Egypt to Peru for more to waste. The United States
                                does no better. But the natives of Japan and China maintain the fertility of their soil
                                by saving what those who pretend to be civilized throw away. They have no worn-out,
                                abandoned fields.</p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nine quarts of milk, on the average..." TEIform="index"/>Nine quarts of milk, on the average...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">__Nine quarts of milk, on the average, are required to make a pound of butter. </p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Since 1860 the wool-clip of the United States..." TEIform="index"/>Since 1860 the wool-clip of the United States...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> __Since 1860 the wool-clip of the United States has more than trebled; or doubled in
                                less than ten years.</p></div3><div3 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The fact that England is exporting humblebees..." TEIform="index"/>The fact that England is exporting humblebees...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> .. . The fact that England is exporting humblebees to some of her eastern domains, for
                                the valuable purpose of fertilizing red clover, calls to our mind that in one of the
                                earlier works of Darwin, this keen observer treated on the subject of cats and clover.
                                In said work, he estimated the number of mice hi the fields from the number of cats in
                                the vicinity; and the number of bees by the number of mice nests remaining for the bees'
                                households. He summed up thus: The more cats, the less mice; consequently the less
                                humblebees; and with these wanting to fertilize the clover, the Isss clover. England, in
                                transporting bees to New Zealand, is paying a grand tribute to the wisdom of Darwin.
                            *</p></div3></div2><div2 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Potato" TEIform="index"/>THE POTATO</head><p TEIform="p">We do not know what we could substitute for the potato. We are not anxious to have any thing
                            replace it; for while our Peachblows and Rose are greeted three times a day by untired
                            appetites, they shall continue to be most welcome on our tables. We change the complexion
                            and flavor of our bread for palate's sake; and the common white is made to give way to
                            graham, biscuits, buns, cake and variously. Bread, in some form, is ever agreeable ; but its
                            form must change, to be as agreeable as it is. But the potato is never really better, than
                            when coming to our tables in its simplest and original form, boiled, immediately after
                            paring. The too common practice of paring potatoes, and leaving them to stand in water for
                            hours, is wasteful and detrimental. The water that has surrounded pared potatoes for a given
                            number of hours, contains more gluten, which goes to replenish the wasted tissue, than do
                            the potatoes. The water is, of course, thrown away, while the potatoes, much less
                            substantial than before, are placed on the table; and if they do not repair mortal waste
                            only a little more than would saw-dust, the cause is plain. Leckey, the famous historian,
                            opposes their extensive use by any people ; ascribing the degeneracy of the Irish race to
                            this cause. We are strongly inclined to dispute the testimony of this eminent authority; and
                            to seek for the real cause of their degeneracy, in the direction of another very prominent
                            excess of the Irish, where, perhaps, their exclusive potato diet is insufficient to repair
                            their wasted human tissues. But we are confronted by too many scientists upon this question,
                            to doubt that it has received abundant consideration. Quite a number of German savants have
                            also been very disagreeably impressed by the potato from late analysis; considering its
                            extensive use as weakening, both mentally and physically. Carl Vogt speaks of it in very
                            inferior terms. Mulder, the Dutch physiologist, attributes the indolence of nations to*
                            potatoes among the poor, and tea and coffee with the wealthy. And O. S. Fowler's only
                            apparent recommendation of the potato seems to be that it fills up a vacuum that might or
                            would be occupied by something worse. We are really sorry that this humble and abundant
                            esculent should fare so unkindly at scientific hands. We are loth to look on the potato rot
                            as a blessing in disguise; and we are quite unwilling to part with a long-tried, every-day
                            friend, because it is discovered to be less valuable than some of its nobler relations. Nor
                            are we persuaded that an exclusively potato diet is any more detrimental, nor as much so, as
                            an exclusively meat diet; and the potato, being of coarser and milder material than meats,
                            may haps have saved stronger nations than the Irish, from greater degeneracy and worse, by
                            its being so usual an accompaniment of meats, excepting with the Indians, and they are
                            barbarous, and as savage as the beasts which they eat. *</p></div2><pb n="16" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Season of devotion" TEIform="index"/>SEASON OF DEVOTION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, James G." TEIform="persName"/>Jas. G. Russell. Enfield, N. H.</byline><p TEIform="p">Blessed season of devotion, When the saints in love do meet, Boundless as the waves of ocean,
                            Plows the spirit pure and sweet. Zion's children raise your voices, Freedom's glorious
                            strain prolong, While the heavenly host rejoices, Echoing back the conqueror's song. Angels
                            from the realms of glory, Join our ranks in tuneful praise, Bringing blessings pure and holy
                            From the heavenly Throne of Grace. Saints in darkness, bound no longer, Leave the shades of
                            endless night, Never more in sin to wander, Join the chorus with delight. Bless the day, the
                            happy hour, When tl*e gospel trump was heard, Bringing forth that light and power, That
                            would reach a dying World. Sin-sick souls the call obeying, Find deliverance from the fall;
                            While the faithless, still delaying, Lose their precious day and call. Shout again with deep
                            emotion, Let the joyful accents roll, Blessed season of devotion, How refreshing to the
                            soul. Heavenly guardians, now before us, Let your blessing crown the scene ; While we make
                            sweet praise our chorus, And salvation's prize our theme.</p></div2><div2 type="music" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Music, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>MUSIC NO. 2</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, J. G." TEIform="persName"/>J. G. RUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p">A certain eminent musician very aptly remarks, that " the voice may be regarded as a musical
                            instrument, and at least, as much care should be taken to avoid injury to it, as is taken
                            with other musical instruments." Under this consideration we resume the subject of music
                            under the head of physiological voice-training. As vocal melody becomes impaired when
                            carried beyond the proper limits of the voice, so likewise, the voice itself becomes
                            impaired when carried beyond its proper limits; thus making a two-fold objection to this
                            violation. But to arrive at conclusive evidence of the point at issue, we must carefully
                            consider the origin of the voice, and every part that has to do in the production of musical
                            tone. First, the Lungs — those great organs of the human body, whose active service is so
                            indispensable to life and health,—how are they to be rendered fit for continued service,
                            unless properly supplied with pure air, that all essential, vitalizing, and life-giving
                            element ? And yet, how often, and to what an alarming extent is this negligence carried by
                            many of the would-beproficient songsters of our day. An interesting incident of this neglect
                            occurs to mind, and may not be out of place for record here. A short time since, as the
                            writer was officiating as singing teacher, the choir was being exercised in that peculiar
                            part of music drill, called breathing. The command was given for each singer to inflate the
                            lungs, when an exasperated young songstress quaintly remarked that she would gladly do so,
                            had she any thing to fill them with. This timely hint was not without its desired effect,
                            for the doors were immediately thrown open, and the proper means of ventilation attended to,
                            as far as consistent, and the command again given to inflate, was promptly obeyed, with
                            satisfactory results. It is an observation of quite frequent occurrence that an
                            ill-ventilated singing apartment will have such a serious effect on the choir, that with all
                            the powers at command, the singers are utterly unable to sustain the key. But at such a
                            crisis, the simple opening of a door or window will affect a wonderful change for the
                            better. Elder Frederick W. Evans, one of our most worthy veterans in the great physiological
                            reform movement, once suggested to the writer that " in every church, music hall, or
                            wherever a mass of human bodies were assembled, there should be one or more individuals
                            officiating in the ventilating department : — stepping into the crowded room every few
                            minutes, and marking the exact condition there." If human life depends so much upon the
                            invigorating draughts of pure air, why should not the above suggestion be regarded of as
                            much necessity as that of a body of police at a camp meeting ? With the rapid march of
                            progress it is to be trusted that this fact will become acknowledged generally, and that our
                            musical assemblies will soon be ornamented with the presence of a physiological police.
                            Again, surprising as it may seem, it is nevertheless true, that many singers are very
                            deficient in the practical art of breathing! Whether this defect is occasioned by the
                            protracted habit of inhaling impure air, back, even, to the earliest days of infancy, or
                            from some other personal defect best known to the individual, remains a problem to be
                            solved. But the facts are apparent, that in breathing, but a very small amount of air is
                            taken into the lungs in proportion to the amount which the lungs are capable of retaining.
                            To prove this assertion would require no very extensive investigation into scientific
                            physiology further than individuals are capable of experimenting for themselves. However, a
                            few brief extracts from physiological authority may subserve the purpose of bringing the
                            subject to clearer light: but this we will leave for the coming number.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to keep the devil out" TEIform="index"/>HOW TO KEEP THE DEVIL OUT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leggett, E. T." TEIform="persName"/>E. T. LEGGETT</byline><p TEIform="p">What famous plans by man unfurled, Each era brings about, Whose promise is to save the world,
                            And keep the Devil out. How hope alternates with despair, Ab each new plan is tried, And
                            with "Old Evil" waiting there, Its merits to decide. Thus all our plans, like autumn leaves,
                            Have fallen one by one, And Satan homage still receives, As when the world began: There's
                            but one only plan that would Keep out this Son of Sin, 'Tis fill the heart so full of good,
                            The Devil can't get in.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mace, Sarah N." TEIform="index"/>Sarah N. Mace
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Poland Hill, Me., Oct 29, <persName reg="Mace, Sarah N." TEIform="persName">Sarah N. Mace</persName>, aged
                                81.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Woodsum, Oliver" TEIform="index"/>Oliver Woodsum
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Poland Hill, Me., Nov. 24, <persName reg="Woodsum, Oliver" TEIform="persName">Oliver Woodsum</persName>,
                                aged 72.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miller, Emma E." TEIform="index"/>Emma E. Miller
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Harvard, Mass., Dec. 19, <persName reg="Miller, Emma E." TEIform="persName">Emma E. Miller</persName>.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bates, Issachar" TEIform="index"/>Issachar Bates
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Shakers, N. Y., Dec. 14, <persName reg="Bates, Issachar" TEIform="persName">Issachar Bates</persName>, aged
                                85.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watkins, Almira" TEIform="index"/>Almira Watkins
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Shakers, N. Y., Dec. 26, <persName reg="Watkins, Almira" TEIform="persName">Almira Watkins</persName>, aged
                                70.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Annis, Emily" TEIform="index"/>Emily Annis
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Enfield, N. H., Dec. 8, <persName reg="Annis, Emily" TEIform="persName">Emily Annis</persName>, aged 69.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bruce, Angeline" TEIform="index"/>Angeline Bruce
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Enfield, N. H., Jan. 4,1876, <persName reg="Bruce, Angeline" TEIform="persName">Angeline Bruce</persName>,
                                aged 35.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Publisher's items" TEIform="index"/>PUBLISHER'S ITEMS</head><p TEIform="p">Our publisher asks for plainness of name and address of all subscribers. Let him have it. Our
                            advertising patrons will only be happier to know we have had to enlarge our February edition
                            by the thousand. We hope the happiness of every agent, who, like a lively, lovely one in N.
                            H., secured 300 names in a few days. Ohio is also well spoken of. Telegraphic reports of a
                            fire — a large barn and nearly forty head of stock, at Union Village, O. Recent letters from
                            there state nothing of it. We hope it is false.</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>