<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2001" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">28</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">20</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">1</biblScope><date value="18900101" TEIform="date">January 1890</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">1-24</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="20" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="1" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                    <pb id="p1"/>
                        <p>JANUARY. MANIFESTO Published by the United Societies, VOL. XX. "For what is a man profited, if he shall gain the
                        whole world, and lose his own soul? or what shall a man give in exchange for his soul."— MM. XVI., 26. Canterbury,
                        N. H. 1890. THE</p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                        <div2 type="none">
                        <p>CONTENTS. History of Mt. Lebanon, No. 7. Letter—Thomas Young, Association, Cause and Effect, Letter—Aurelia (i.
                            Mace, Believers of Indiana, The New Year, Meditation, Editoii.il, .. Letter—Charles Carter, Notes about Home,
                            The Bible Class, Kind word*, Juvenile They Say, .. Music—Good Samaritan, Books & Papers .. Deaths, -</p>
                    </div2>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    --><pb n="1" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. Published by the United Societies. VOL. XX. "For what is a man profited, if he shall gain the
                            whole world, and lose his own soul? or what shall a man give in exchange for his soul."—Matt. XVI., 26. East
                            Canterbury, N. H.. 1890,</p></div2><pb n="2" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/><pb n="3" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="History of the church of Mt. Lebanon, New York, no. 7" TEIform="index"/>HISTORY OF THE CHURCH OF MT. LEBANON, N.
                            Y. No. 7.</head><p TEIform="p">The first day of the New Year, 1842 was a continuation of the same wonderful display of divine manifestations of
                            spirit power. The first day of January will be remembered by the visitation of Holy Mother Wisdom. A large
                            number of messages were written, containing words of comfort and blessing to those who walked uprightly. It was
                            during this season that public service was discontinued and a notification was placed on the door of the church.
                            The Sabbath was kept more as a day of meditation and prayer, and this was better secured by dismissing that
                            service which invited a large company of strangers to visit the Village for many hours during the day. A
                            remarkable visitation of the spirits occurred about this time, embracing persons from many nations. Much of the
                            time during the service was oc- cupied by these different classes, as the Instruments were singing some new and
                            beautiful songs or engaged in exhortations. The 'general exercises during the hours of worship were similar to
                            those of former years. 1843. Many of the messages which had been written were now compiled and received the
                            title of "Sacred Roll and Book." A corresponding work began at Watervliet, N. Y., and the work written at that
                            place was entitled "Holy Wisdom's Book." The manuscript of the Sacred Roll having been prepared, it was printed
                            at Canterbury, N. H., by the Believers in that Society, and in 1849 the book of Holy Wisdom was printed in the
                            same place. 1844. The meetings during this year and also during 1845 were quite like those of an earlier date.
                            The receiving of beautiful songs and the manifestation of divine gifts, were the ever present privileges.
                            Testimonies of thankfulness, of simplicity and of love for the abundant gifts of the spirit broke forth from
                            every heart. The public Sabbath service which was closed in 1843 was again opened this year, and all who so
                            wished were permitted to attend. The order of exercises was as in former years and the ministration of the gift
                            of God was a living power which filled the assembly. Although the demonstra<pb n="4" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO.
                            tion of the spirit, as exhibited in so many wonderful ways, gradually faded away,' there was remaining in the
                            hearts of the people, a treasure which the world could neither give nor take away. A work of such magnitude,
                            filled as it was with wonderful and mysterious spirit manifestations could never have been anticipated by those
                            who were chosen as actors, or even by those who were privileged to be the witnesses. It came in the quietness
                            and in the obscurity of a dream, but it rapidly developed into a work of power and gave evidence that it was of
                            God. 1850. Although the mysterious noises that were heard at Hydesville, N. Y., in 1848 in the Fox family had
                            been attracting more or less attention, and the curious were investigating, it did not arrest our attention very
                            much till the present year. Several members of our Society visited the family that was attracting so much
                            attention, and were very much interested in what took place by "rappings and tippings." This strange work of the
                            spirit was foretold through the mediums of our own order, especially the rapping manner of communication.
                            Although we do not consider these manifestations identical with those that have been seen in our own order, yet
                            they have proved to be very interesting and given us an inspiring hope, that it was the opening of a way that
                            might lead to an increasing, gospel light among those who were strangers to nearly every form of spirituality.
                            Several of the mediums visited our Society and exhibited those singular manifestations, by rapping, by tipping,
                            or moving of tables, and by speaking while in a trance state. Some of these demonstrations were, certainly, very
                            remarkable, and were well calculated to attract the attention of nearly all classes of persons. SF [RITUAL GIFTS
                            FROM 1851 to 1856 INCLUSIVE. The form of the spiritual manifestations that took place within the boundary of our
                            Society, during the above period, presented nothing remarkably new, as worthy of special notice. The hours for
                            divine worship were attended with marked regularit}^, and were seasons of blessing to those who walked in the
                            light. A living testimony was manifested against all evil, as in this came the prosperity of the Community. Some
                            walked in tribulation, as they witnessed in some persons a departure from light, or an apostacy from the word of
                            God. A more direct testimony was held before the world, to show them that the spirit of Christ is found in the
                            path of righteousness and peace. During those several years we were blessed with many refreshing gifts, with
                            much consolation from soul to soul, and were still able to say that Zion yet rejoices in her God and gives glory
                            to his name. (to be continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Topolobampo Bay, Sinaloa, Mexico, September 15, 1889" TEIform="index"/>Topolobampo Bay, Sinaloa, Mex., Sept. 15,
                            1889</head><p TEIform="p">G. B. Avery, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. Dear Friend :—I received the Manifesto for April, May, June and August with many
                            thanks. I am very glad to hear from "you at all times, but 4 <pb n="5" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. cannot make
                            arrangements to join you at present, as I had fondly hoped to do. My wife is not favorable to my doing so at
                            present. She thinks that as we put all our possessions into the C. F. of S. we ought to remain here, so that if
                            we succeed in realizing our former hopes, we may be as happy here as elsewhere, especially as the climate is
                            very salubrious. And unless we do succeed we shall have no means to take us away. I wish to keep up my
                            correspondence with you. I am begiuning to feel quite at home with the writers of the Manifesto and turn first
                            to this Sister and then to that Brother as though we were old acquaintances. There is no doubt a fellow-feeling
                            between us of true Christian sympathy, although I may be regarded by your people as living upon the lower floor,
                            as Brother Eads would say until I renounce my former faith and mode of life, and adopt the Shaker plan. In my
                            case there were two in the compact, and each pledged our troth ; it is only fair my wife should have her choice,
                            being regarded as the weaker because three years the older. And there would be no virtue in the act of
                            sui'render on our part, as we could lay no claim to the "Virgin life," or the upper floor, by our giving the
                            remnant of our worthless lives, after sowing to the flesh and then to go cringing before God and ask him to
                            accept the dregs of our inability to sow to the flesh any longer. It seems too much to expect, our being
                            enrolled among the one hundred and forty-four thousand virgins ; after a life of sensual gratification. Where
                            does the self-denial come in, looking at it from your stand-point, Bro. Avery? Please accept my best wishes for
                            your prosperity, both in numbers and virtue. May all be happy in your temporal and spiritual relationships, and
                            may peace attend your efforts to honor our common Lord shall be my earnest prayer. I will put your Manifesto in
                            our rending room and so spread the light. Write me at your leisure. I am yours, fraternally.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Young, Thomas" TEIform="persName"/>Thomas Young</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Seven travails of the shaker church" TEIform="index"/>SEVEN TRAVAILS OF THE SHAKER CHURCH</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Offord, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Offord</byline><p TEIform="p">"I love the faith of the Gospel, The gift of free salvation; It will redeem the fallen race From sin and
                            condemnation. Then hold ye fast the living faith, 'Tis not of man's invention: It is from God, who reigns above,
                            And claims our whole attention." Jesus and Mother Ann Lee were the most perfect examples of the Christian faith,
                            and the most perfect witnesses of what the spirit of Christ could and would do with fallen humanity. The system
                            of government in operation when they were on the earth, was very far behind what it is in our time ; and as the
                            governments of earth progress, it opens the way, through the gift of divine revelation, for the Christian system
                            to be perfected. But the spiritual lives of Jesus and Mother will never be excelled. There seems to be, in the
                            minds of some, at least, great objections against referring to or speaking of land reform, dietetics, hygiene,
                            or any other reform, as though, these things had nothing to do with Christianity in its 5 <pb n="6" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/>
                            THE MANIFESTO. highest manifestation. And objections to any physical demonstration, operating through the human
                            body, like shaking or dancing, or any violence of spirit in our meetings, because it is not the worship of God.
                            Jesus and Mother have been the examples for souls to follow ; and, thank God, we have living witnesses, in our
                            own day and time, that are living out, through the gift of divine revelation, a far more perfect system of
                            Christianity than it was possible for Jesus or Mother to live out; still we have not attained perfection. But
                            our hopes are strong that, through an increased revelation, greater good will yet be obtained. Father James
                            said, "The Gospel is perfect; as straight as straightness and as pure as the heavens." Father Joseph said the
                            church would pass through seven travails or cycles. We are only in the first travail—if haply we are there ; and
                            if we are, we shall be found hating the flesh, vehemently. That was the testimony of our blessed Mother; and no
                            soul can enter the second travail or cycle, till they have passed through the first. Every soul must be baptized
                            with the testimony of Mother, to hate the flesh before they will find a successful travail into the second,
                            third, or seventh cycle or travail. I look upon Jesus and Mother as the greatest reformers that have ever
                            blessed the earth ; not reformers after the sense and spirit of the world, but according to the will of God.
                            Why? Because, in their practical lives, there was more divinity ; and under the in- spiration of the Holy
                            Spirit, they began by reforming themselves ; in other words, they practiced what they preached. Jesus was a
                            Shaker; a land reformer of the highest type ; the greatest hygienist that has ever walked the earth; and he said
                            his disciples would do greater works than he did, oi1 could do, in land reform and hygiene. They would more
                            fully crystallize or materialize the abstract truths which he uttered ; bring them down to practical every-day
                            life. Of what use is the revelation of truth, unless it enters the life of humanity? Jesus said that the foxes
                            had holes, and the birds of the air had nests ; (Where ? Why, on the land;) but the Son of Man, under the unjust
                            system where he was obliged to live, had no place to lay his head. No rights in the land, had he, that the
                            government was bound to respect. What was his prophecy and promise to those who would follow him? That for all
                            they "forsook of father, and mother, and sisters, and brothers, and houses, and lands, they should receive an
                            hundred-fold of fathers, mothers, sisters, brothers, houses and lands." Was not that land reform ? And is not
                            the system under which people are living to-day well nigh as bad as it was when Jesus lived on the earth ; and
                            especially in those countries whose governments are called Christian. We, whose privilege it is to live under
                            the infidel government of the United States, enjoy better things than they. But let this government get into the
                            hands of the so-called Christians, and the liberties we now enjoy will soon disappear, and everybody will be
                            compelled into the narrow limits of their creed, and 6 <pb n="7" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. circumscribed by their
                            very unchristian practices. In these so-called Christian countries, nine-tenths of all the people (just as much
                            the children of God as the other one-tenth) occupy the same position as regards the hind as did our Savior. They
                            have no place to lay their heads, and no rights on the earth that this Christian system is bound to respect. The
                            same principles are at work right here, in free America. Land monopoly in America, is exceeding that of Europe ;
                            single individuals well nigh oaviiing whole townships, and everybody that settles on their domain is more or
                            less at their mercy. And by the enactment of the Christian Sabbath laws, and the most anti-Christian doctorlaws,
                            are the liberties of the people being more and more curtailed. And when the Christian God gets into the
                            constitution of the United States, we can bid farewell to Liberty : her lamp hung out to enlighten the world,
                            will be darkened by the powers of AntiChrist, falsely called Christian; and then it will be possible for
                            Mother's prophecy to be fulfilled, and the powers of darkness to take another sip of the blood of the saints. Is
                            there no religion in warring against these powers of darkness ? "For we wrestle not against flesh and blood, but
                            against principalities, against powers, against the rulers of the darkness of this world, against spiritual
                            wickedness in high places." "Pure religion and undefiled before God and the Father is this : to visit the
                            fatherless and widows in their affliction, and to keep himself unspotted from the world." Visit them to
                            reconcile them to their afflictions ? to tell them to endure them with Christian patience ; for God, their
                            loving Father, has brought those afflictions to bear upon them to prepare them for the mansions of glory in the
                            unknown future, and in some ur.kr.own place? Did Jesus do so? He did teach them that, if they died in their
                            sins, whither he went, thither they could not come. And most certainly did he keep himself unspotted from the
                            world, the lust of the flesh, the lust of the eye, and the pride of life. These are the fundamental principles
                            of the world; and to bear a faithful cross against these, and to minister justice, in love, is true religion,
                            and the most acceptable worship. There is no place on all God's earth, where a Shaker family can exist in
                            perfect safety, except under the infidel government of the United States. And there liberty will not be made
                            certain, except by eternal vigilance ; by constant warfare against the powers of oppression. The Gospel, in its
                            purity, will not be maintained in souls upon this earth, except by eternal warfare against the powers of
                            darkness in battles of shaking. Jesus went about doing good ; healing the sick, cleansing the lepers, and
                            casting out devils ; and after healing them, he told them to "go and sin no more;" showing plainly that their
                            sickness, was the result of sin, sin being the violation of law. Was Jesus not a hygienist, then, when he
                            revealed to people the cause of their sickness, removed it, and instructed them what to do to keep their health
                            ? That, to me, was practical religion, that the common people could under7 <pb n="8" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO.
                            stand; though practiced on the Sabbath and in the temple. There were those who watched Jesus, and made (to
                            themselves) very weighty objections to his healing on their Sabbath. It is my faith that the spiritual power
                            manifested by Jesus upon the bodies of the people, will be manifested in far greater perfection in the Church of
                            Christ of the latter day ; because it will work with the rational understanding ; in union with hygiene, the
                            science of health. Thus, "religion and science as one shall agree." It has often been said, in this house, that
                            Jesus was a Shaker. He commanded his disciples to shake ; and would he tell his followers to do what he had not
                            done? I glory in the name, and mean ever to walk worthy of it; and if we, as a people, lose the gift of shaking,
                            we will lose the power of God that saves from sin ; and the god of this world, generative lust, will reign, in
                            his pride, to the utter destruction of our spiritual life. In my experience, I have seen those standing in the
                            assembly of the saints, those who had never confessed their sins, talk of love ; love to God, love to Christ,
                            love to his people ; that had no testimony against the flesh; and had it not in their hearts, but were bold to
                            express with their tongues, to those whom they thought they could allure, to introduce generation into the
                            Shaker Church, and among the saints of God, the virgin followers of the Lamb. Is it not "the abomination of
                            desolation ?"—the man of sin in the temple of God? And shall we all be dumb dogs that cannot bark, much less,
                            bite? Nay, never. Let the testimony roll, as thunder from Mount Zion, and let the lightnings play, and the
                            battles of shaking be renewed; that every heart may be inspired with Mother's gift to hate the flesh vehemently.
                            There are no expressions in the English language that are adequate to express the indignation of the holy spirit
                            against the body-degrading, the soul-defiling, and the humanity-sinking element of fleshly lust. May God be
                            revealed among us, as a consuming fire, to burn up the vile, filthy elements of the world ! They cannot be
                            reasoned with, any more than you can reason with a slimy serpent; nothing but the sword of the spirit and the
                            holy fire of God will ever set the soul free from the bondage of the flesh. "Think not," said Jesus, "that I
                            come to bring peace on earth"—to the generative life, with all its relationships ; "I come not to send peace,
                            but a sword. For I am come to set a man at variance against his father, and the daughter against her mother; and
                            a man's foes shall be they of his own household." All the generative relation. "If any man come to me, and hate
                            not his father, and mother, and wife, and children, and brethren and sisters ; yea, and his own" (generative)
                            "life also ; he cannot be my disciple." Could anything be plainer, or the line of demarkation clearer, than is
                            the testimony of Jesus? Nothing but the testimony of our blessed Mother Ann; which is more powerful, inasmuch as
                            it enables men and women, on this earth, to live together, as brethren and sisters, in perfect purity, in a
                            spiritual Community. Who, after having fought the battles of the 8 <pb n="9" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 9 Lord,
                            and gained the victory, are blessed with the peace of God; that peace and love, which the world cannot give,
                            neither can it take away. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Association" TEIform="index"/>ASSOCIATION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sears, Elizabeth A." TEIform="persName"/>Elizabeth A. Sears</byline><p TEIform="p">I think all who have arrived at the age of maturity, hnve realized the power and influence which our association
                            with others has upou us. Not that we are always sure to imbibe the opinions or ideas of those with whom we
                            converse, but let those whom we love, and delight to associate with, advocate that which our natural
                            inclinations would lead us to desire, how soon we see the silent workings of their persuasion bearing upou our
                            feelings, and leading us little by little, to embrace the same, or similar sentiments. We read that, "As it is
                            natural for sparks to fly upward, or water to run downward, so the heart of man is per- verse, and inclineth to
                            evil." Therefore I consider it much easier to lead the minds of others to seek ease and vain pleasure, than to
                            inspire them with fortitude to pursue the rugged path of virtue and self-denial, which is unavoidably attended
                            with crosses and trials. Then if we wish to do the greatest amount of good, and leave an example worthy of
                            imitation, we should have our conversation of that high and elevated character, which will inspire all around us
                            with respect and confidence for those noble principles which we are endeavoring to vindicate, both by word and
                            work, in our daily lives. In conversing with different individuals, what a contrast we sometimes observe, in the
                            effect produced upon our feelings and emotions. When we associate with the refined and educated, who are adorned
                            with true Christian grace, and stern integrity cf purpose, we admin: their cultivated bearing, aud seem to be
                            fascinated by their goodness and magnanimity ; we long to dwell ever in the sunshine of such brightness, and
                            drink forever from tie celestial springs of pure unalloyed enjoyment, produced by the communion of kindred
                            souls, and the expansion of mind into all that is lovely, pure and divine. But if, on the contrary,
                            circumstances oblige us to associate with the ignorant, selfish and unregenerate, we are disinterested and
                            dissatisfied, perhaps despondent ; for we feel that our better feelings are not appreciated, aud we can derive
                            no satisfaction from such communion. Again we meet with those who, with flattering smiles and winning words,
                            insinuate that they possess unbounded love and friendship for us, while their hearts are busy to deceive and
                            captivate the unguarded mind, by light and trifling conversation, implying by jesting remarks, that they do not
                            believe in so much gravity, and sober reflection as many others do. Thus it seems necessary in all cases to be
                            guided and governed by an enlightened conscience, being ever watchful and careful that no false allurement may
                            so absorb our love and interest, as to turn us aside from the high path of duty and safety. Considering the many
                            advantages derived from good society, and the injurious effects produced by the opposite, let us choose our
                            associates from the ranks of the pure and good, thus improving our own condition and endeavoring to benefit
                            others by our efforts to enliven the hours of social con- versation, with a cheerful, loving spirit. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><pb n="10" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cause and effect" TEIform="index"/>CAUSE AND EFFECT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dibble, Chancy" TEIform="persName"/>Chancy Dibble</byline><p TEIform="p">A spark of Deity, divine, In every intellect doth shine. In meditation's calm review, The conscience speaks in
                            accents true, And points us to a reckoning day, Where righteous deeds aloue bear sway. Endeavors, efforts,
                            motives, aims, Will be the test of wisdom's claims. Vice brings remorse and bitter gloom, While virtue yields a
                            sweet perfume. Whichever element we breathe, The impulse we in turn receive, To correspond with our desire ;
                            Vice leads lower, virtue higher. The fruit we cultivate will grow, In quality, just what we sow. No power can
                            righteousness impute Or change the nature of the fruit. If we our higher light obey, / There's purer joys along
                            the way, Given by unerring laws To all who work in wisdom's cause. For higher life the soul aspires, A uuion
                            with the angel choirs ; Step by step the race is run, Until the victory is won. By years of toil in virtues
                            field A rich increase our lives will yield Of patience, wisdom, meekness, love, As in these graces we improve.
                            Take courage toiling pilgrim, on, The prize is sure to every one. A sympathizing parent's care Assists our
                            progress, hears our prayer, And will not, for true mercy's sake, Ooe contrite spirit e'er forsake. Watervliet,
                            N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The value of any institution is to be measured by the truth it manifests, and the good it does" TEIform="index"/>
                            The value of any institution is to be measured by the truth it manifests, and the good it does
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The value of any institution is to be measured by the truth it manifests, and the good it does.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., G. B." TEIform="persName"/>G. B. A.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Gloucester, November 1889" TEIform="index"/>West Gloucester, Nov. 1889</head><p TEIform="p">Editor of the Manifesto. Kind Elder :—We send you many thanks for taking us along with you on that delightful
                            journey. We can go again and again as often as we read the graphic account from your diary in the Nov.,
                            Manifesto. .How kind you were to let us hear from those good Brethren and Sisters whom you visited, that we love
                            so well. The Nov., Manifesto is very in- teresting to us. The music "'Beautiful Shore" awakens memories of loved
                            ones who have gone on before, and are now enjoying the grandeur and beauty of that heavenly home, while our
                            homes here are so vividly described that we cannot but feel how good it is to be joined to all that is so
                            lovely, pure and true. And now I must own that the little lesson for ihe Bible Class is what lias drawn me out
                            to write you this letter. It will be very interesting to read the answers to the questions and I hope a goodly
                            number of pupils will respond, and by so doing be a credit and honor to their kind teachers. It seems to me good
                            Elder Henry, while reading over these questions, that, I would like to give you my ideas in regard to them
                            although they may diverge greatly from the opinions of others. 1st Ans.—The two verses of Psalms, used as a
                            prayer that to me are the sweetest and strongest are the 10th and Llth verses of the 84th Psalm. " For a day in
                            Thy courts is better than a thousand, &amp;c." 2nd.—Is there a more noble act of self-sacrifice recorded in
                            the Old Testa- ment than that made by Jephthah's <pb n="11" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 11 daughter, when she
                            yielded herself so willingly, that her father might keep the rash vow he had made unto the Lord ? 3rd.—-As the
                            opinion of an individual, I would say that the grandest character in the Old Testament is the Prophet Daniel.
                            The purity of his life wa&gt; very nearly like that of Jesus. He lived the augel, virgin life, approaching
                            divinity. It seems that Joseph and Job were spotless characters, but they were upon the plane of nature.
                            4th.—The Book of Daniel, is to me the most interesting book of the Old Testament, notwithstanding Robert Elsmere
                            tells us it is a fraud. In the last chapter is the sweetest prophecy of all,— "Blessed is he that waiteth, and
                            cometh to the thousand, three hundred and five, and thirty days." Has that time come? and is Daniel now standing
                            in his lot, at the end of the days ? 5th.—Matt. 11th chapter, commencing at the 28th verse. "Come unto me all ye
                            that labor and are heavy laden and I will give you rest," and so on. "And ye shall find rest unto your souls,"
                            with the conditions. What promise could be more comforting to the weary ? 6th.—Proverbs 13th chapter, 6th and
                            7th verses, are two very wise Proverbs. 7th.—The 45th Psalm is most joyous. "My heart is inditing a good matter
                            &amp;c." In New Gloucester we have had an abundant crop of winter apples, very fair and free from defects.
                            Many of these have been sold at a good price, but enough are stored, with other fruits and vegetables for future
                            use. Thus we are prepared to enter the cold season, happy in the anticipation of all temporal needs supplied,
                            while the loving companionship of good Brethren and Sisters crowns the whole with joy unspeakable. Home comforts
                            are not the least ot the many blessings bestowed upon us by our Heavenly Father and Mother. Yours in love to our
                            gospel relation everywhere.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Mace, Aurelia G." TEIform="persName"/>Aurelia G. Mace</byline></div2><div2 type="shaker-reports" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Believers of Indiana in 1811" TEIform="index"/>THE BELIEVERS OF INDIANA IN 1811</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Basting, Louis" TEIform="persName"/>Louis Basting</byline><p TEIform="p">Tim Great Revival at Bnsro at the Community of Shakers. The Indian war. The Peace principles of the Believers.
                            The kindness of Col. JBoyd. The work of Gen. Wm. II. Harrison in favor of the Shakers. The great revival which
                            in the first decade of the present centuiy swept over the western country, extended to the extreme frontiers of
                            the settlements. It struck in at Busro, on the Wabash river, and an energetic attempt was made to found a
                            Community of Believers there. This revival had been plainly foretold by Mother Ann Lee ; and as soon as tidings
                            of its occurrence reached the Believers at Mt. Lebanon, they sent a number of Brethren and Sisters to act as
                            missionaries, leaders and organizers to the regions of its activity. Issachar Bates, Archibald Meacham, and
                            others, were allotted to the work at Busro. Upon their arrival there in the spring of 1811, they found 200
                            people there professing faith, and shortly afterwards 140 more came in. It was a great task to organize such a
                            company into gospel order in the wilderness. Houses had to be built; crops had <pb n="12" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 12 THE
                            MANIFESTO. to be raised. In this latter labor they were so successful that while the surrounding district almost
                            suffered a famine, the Believers had plenty and some to sell and give away. Then were preparations made to build
                            a saw and grist-mill, and, writes Elder Issachar, "all things went on in a measure of peace and order, though
                            with much tribulation on our part." Then rumors of an Indian war broke out, and the Believers were charged with
                            being at the bottom of it. The governor called out the militia to be ready to fight the Prophet who was
                            determined for war. The Believers received notice every week to join the militia, which, of course, they refused
                            to do. Then the whites declared that if the Indians did not kill the Shakers they would. About the mid- dle of
                            June a number of Indians arrived with a quantity of fanning tools, principally hoes, to have them repaired at
                            the smith-shop ; whereupon the Believers wrote to the governor stating the case and asking for his counsel. He
                            replied that no smith-work was to be done for them, but that they might be fed and should be treated kindly ;
                            which orders were punctually complied with. The Indians very sorrowfully declared that they had not so much as
                            thought of war; here, they said, are our wives and children with us; we don't go to war so. About 200 of them
                            staid near Busro for over three weeks, singing and dancing to the Great Spirit, behaving very peaceably, and
                            "never took to the value of one cucumber without leave." The governor of Indiana Territory ¦was General Win.
                            Heniy Harrison, the grandfather of our present president; and to him President Madison had confided the control
                            of all Indian affairs. The head chief of the tribes was Tecumseh, a very able and ambitious man. Him the
                            governor summoned to appear at Vincennes and explain his conduct. Accordingly he appeared there with a large
                            party of his followers, proud, defiant, but still professing peaceable intentions. So the council broke up with
                            no good results and deep distrust on both sides ; an out-break of hostilities was expected at any moment, and
                            the people left their farms and moved into forts and towns. While all this excitement was at its height the
                            fever broke out among the Believers, as many as 50 being taken at one time. Elder Issachar among them, who for
                            two weeks was unable to leave his room. The Wabash coun- try has always, even up to the present day, borne an
                            evil reputation for malarial diseases. The soil is of very great fertility, but subject to frequent inundations;
                            its very richness is a source of danger. To add to their troubles, while the fever-epidemic was at its worst,
                            the Pottorvattonnies stole the mill-team one night. This team consisted of four of the best horses set apart to
                            help in building the mill, and the Brethren were not willing to submit quietly to the loss ; nothing would
                            satisfy them but to follow the thieves. So two of them, Abraham and James, with Capt. Robbins, a friendly
                            world's man, set out in pursuit. They followed the marauders about ninety miles, overtook them and secured the
                            horses without resistance and turned homewards ; then the Indians in their turn pursued <pb n="13" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/>
                            THE MANIFESTO. 13 them, ran them about ten miles, and not only re-took the four stolen horses but also the three
                            they had been riding on. About a week afterwards the poor Brethren and the captain arrived home on foot and in a
                            doleful condition ; but the Elders rejoiced that they had returned in safety and had obeyed the counsel given
                            them, which was, not to fight. A compensating feature of this episode was that it opened the eyes of their
                            neighbors, as it showed that the Believers had no secret understanding with the Indians, but were as much
                            exposed to suffer loss at their hands as anybody else. But there was much confusion ; what with sickness, the
                            Indian difficulties, the hardships of pioneer life, and the steady accumulation of fines for nonattendance of
                            military duty, the Elders had hard work to keep the spirit of the people up. On the 17th. of September the army
                            began to assemble at Busro. • A company of cavalry and two of infantry were quartered right among the Believers.
                            The commissary used the Elders' shop for a store-house, and the door-yard for a slaughter-yard. "¦Here it was,
                            drums and fifes, blood and whiskey, alas ! alas ! Here tlr.y staid waiting for the other troops to come on ;
                            they had their washing, baking and some lodging, and all the forage for their horses among us ; though they paid
                            for it and behaved civil towards the Believers, yet alas ! alas !" But now, while the war-excitement and
                            confusion was at its height, "the kind hand of God in his providence was stretched, out a little to help us."
                            For five hundred regulars from New England, under Colonel Boyd, from Boston, arrived, and these people testified
                            that they were acquainted with the Believers at the eastward and that they were good people. Col. Boyd bore a
                            public testimony at Vincennes and elsewhere that "the Shakers at the East were the best people on the earth."
                            "This," wrote Elder Issachar, "blunted the edge of every weapon formed against us; Col. Boyd appeared as glad to
                            see us as though we were his natural kin." There was also a Col. Davis, from Kentucky, who commanded the
                            cavalry; he being acquainted with the Believers at Pleasant Hill, was very friendly, and, because he was a
                            lawj^er, the Brethren told him their difficulties in regard to military service and asked him for his advice.
                            The governor had arrived on the 26th. and at 12 o'clock on that day all the drafted Brethren were ordered to
                            report for duty. According to Col. Davis' counsel the leading Brethren called upon the governor and told him
                            what they could and what they could not do. The governor replied that \n knew their faith and that the matter
                            might rest till he returned from his expedition, and that he would assist them in forming a petition to the
                            assembly for release. This being settled the Believers continued their kindness to the arnry, and the army were
                            all very friendly, and much applauded them for their kindness. On the 28th. the army started on their march
                            northward, leaving their sick with the Believers, and they "had news and company a plenty every day, such as it
                            was." On thr&gt;th. of November 1811 the army was attacked at 4 o'clock in the <pb n="14" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 14 THE
                            MANIFESTO. morning and tha famous battle of Tippecanoe was fought; the Indians were completely routed, the
                            Prophet's town raid all that was in it, including 5,000 bushels of corn, was burned, and the army returned to
                            Vincennes. Among the killed was Colonel Davis, honorably mentioned before. During all this distressing period of
                            confusion and constant sickness, the building of the mill and other business was steadily prosecuted. We can
                            well understand the feelings of Elder Xssachar when he writes: "These were trying times with us and we had use
                            for all the wisdom and patience we had ; and we labored faithfully to dis- pel the darkness and despondency
                            among the people. My health is not very good, probably in consequence of having to travel seven miles every day
                            to and from my work at the mill, some- times in mud and water up to my knees ; but my faith is Everlasting and I
                            mean to keep it." The years rolled on ; the ever present malignant fever of the Wabash at last compelled the
                            Believers to abandon Busro and settle in Ohio and Kentucky ; General Harrison defeated the English army in
                            Canada and brought his administration to a successful closeHe retired to Ohio and was elected a member of
                            legislature, and when, in 1821, the Believers who were still harassed by annual fines for non-compliance with
                            military duty, presented a petition to be permitted that instead of drilling three days in the year they might
                            work the same number of days on the highway, he made four able speeches in favor of said petition, and it was
                            largely due to his influence that it was granted. General ITarrison was a great man in his sphere of action, a
                            successful warrior, and his greatness of mind led him to esteem, respect and assist those who from religious
                            principle would not fight for any cause. West Pittsfield, 3fass.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New year" TEIform="index"/>THE NEW YEAR</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Witham, Maria" TEIform="persName"/>Maria Witham</byline><p TEIform="p">The new year is the awakening of promise, the revealment of the future. May it teach us lessons of endurance, of
                            fortitude, of thankfulness. We would have the new year ledolent with praise, not from the lips only ; from the
                            heart may sincere longings of our spiritual needs be awakened. Willing to lay all upon the shrine and altar of
                            devotion to the cause of Truth. The new year is the period for new beginnings, higher aspirations, and good
                            resolutions, when the brand of the interpreter of human thought is thrown, kindling the fire of examination and
                            self-criticism upon each and every one, and there lay before God an acceptable offering. Now may we plant the
                            seed that is imperishable. The treasures of earth soon pass away; and its glitter will vanish. Every word
                            becomes valuable, if we would make earth the gateway of heaven, and do good to all around us ; we will make the
                            new year bring happiness and peace to our homes and associates. Enfield, Conn.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Self-denial will develop Christian fortitude and gire energy and growth to the soul" TEIform="index"/>
                            Self-denial will develop Christian fortitude and gire energy and growth to the soul
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Self-denial will develop Christian fortitude and gire energy and growth to the soul.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="T., M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. T,</byline></div2><pb n="15" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Evening meditations" TEIform="index"/>EVENING MEDITATIONS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, Oliver C" TEIform="persName"/>Oliver C. Hampton</byline><p TEIform="p">It is not in Heaven that tlwu shonldst say '' Who shall go up for us to Heaven and bring it unto us that we may
                            hear it and do it?" Neither is it beyond the sea that thou shouldst say "Who shall go over the sea for us and
                            bring it unto us that ice may hear it and do it?" "But the word is very nigh thee in thy mouth and in thy
                            heart." Deut. xxx., 12,13,14. Neither shall ye say, Lo here, or Lo there, for behold the Kingdom of God is
                            within you. Luke, xvii., 21. For the kingdom of God is not meat and drink but righteousness and peace, and joy
                            in the Holy Ghost. Romans, xiv., 17. There is a place in spirits all, Where discontentment never strays, Where
                            blight and mildew never fall, Nor lurid lightningever plays. Where sad forebodings never brood, Where fear and
                            sorrow never strayed, Where all negations of the good, Are sent to their infernal shade. There death and
                            sickness are no more. There only health ;ind peace abound, There consolation opes her door And strews
                            contentment all around. 0 where? that bright and rosy land, 1 seek so oft when griefs beset; WThich all the
                            powers at my command, But dimly have discovered yet. Yet something says it is in me, That Kingdom of Eternal
                            bliss, Where cloudless comfort I may see, Not more in worlds above than this. This Beulah—bright sequestered
                            land. I'd give all gold of Earth to find, And build no more ujjon the sand By dead negations undermined. And yet
                            my Ego is the realm, Where I must find this glorious land; Where God Himself sits at the helm, And moves my fate
                            at his command. At-one-ment is the magic Word Which was with God and which was God; Which dwells in flesh as
                            Christ the Lord, Who made and moves Creation broad. Inmost Divine of all we are; Is both his kingdom and his
                            throne The silent halcyon region where I and my Father dear are one. Free from all fear—disease—despair, Would I
                            in perfect safety dwell, No more the agonies to share, Of Nature's rudimental Hell. I must within—yield all to
                            Christ, Who dwelleth in my inmost now, Where his creative word is voic'd And to that word in silence bow. In
                            peaceful silence listen long Say inwardly "Thy will be done;" Then shortly I will sing the song Of endless peace
                            and rest begun. But tho' Intelligence may see And recognize this Heaven sublime; Yet this alone can never free
                            My spirit from the throes of time. Sweet Love and Wisdom must combine, That Heaven within to realize;
                            Self-abnegation must refine, And peace to friend and foe must rise. And sacrifice of self each hour, And
                            sympathy for suff'rings all; On friend and foe with grace and pow'r, The peace and love of Christ must fall.
                            Then shall all pain and sorrow cease, Then shall my darkness turn to day; That inmost realm of boundless peace
                            Shall be my health and rest for aye. 0 word of everlasting Love And Wisdom,—wake within me now; At-one-ment with
                            my God above, To reach, in mercy teach me how. To find that pearly gate of bliss, All earthly good I now lay
                            down. Nor wait for other worlds than this, To gain that one immortal crown. Union Village, 0.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="When we see lacks in others of various ages..." TEIform="index"/>
                            When we see lacks in others of various ages...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">When we see lacks in others of various ages, let us consider what wore ours at those periods of life</p><byline TEIform="byline"> —<persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W.</byline></div2><pb n="16" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Manifesto, 1890. Office of Publication" TEIform="index"/>THE MANIFESTO. JANUARY, 1890. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION</head><p TEIform="p">The Manifesto is published by the "United Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work
                            issued regularly by the Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the religious views of
                            the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. All communications should be addressed to Henry C.
                            Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. TERMS. One copy per year, postage paid, " " six months, " " Send for
                            sample copy, free. .75 .40</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="1890" TEIform="index"/>1890</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">With the present number of the Manifesto we are privileged to enter upon a new volume. It is with surprising
                                rapidity that the last twelve months have whirled forever from our sight, and the morning of a new year has
                                so pleasantly dawned upon us. To keep pace with life, means life, as its revelations in the natural and
                                spiritual world are ever forcing themselves upon us for recognition. Those who through ignorance or
                                carelessness permit these revelations to pass unnoticed, must as a result consequent on such a course, be
                                left in the rear, or in the dark. The Manifesto professes to abide in the light of life and to teach,— that
                                to the increase and government of Christ's Kingdom there can be no end. Our writers and readers must not
                                lose sight of this very essential point, upon which depends so much of our temporal and spiritual success.
                                This we imperatively need, and indeed must have from day to day and then it must be of such a character that
                                all who know us may be assured of the fact, that our religious life leads us into one of practical
                                righteousness. This is the life work of the church of Christ upon the earth. To all the dear friends who
                                have kept us company in the past, we extend a cordial invitation to remain with us on the journey through
                                another, year. To those who have contributed to the columns of our little paper, we feel much indebted and
                                anxiously hope that their interest and zeal may never grow less. As the gospel work increases in light and
                                as greater confidence becomes established in the mind, we shall grow more and more, into the inspirational
                                life that comes from God, out of heaven, and be better able to present the same to our many interested
                                readers. We know quite well that the circulation of our little paper is not so extended as we might wish,
                                and when contrasted with the tens of thousands of papers that are flooding the land, it can be, only, as was
                                the drop of water in the bucket. Although JANUARY, <pb n="17" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 17 so small and
                                trifling we trust that its influence for good may be fully appreciated, as the one drop of water, under some
                                circumstances may be of great value. We console ourselves, however, that our little paper, in its advocacy
                                of a good and virtuous cause may be of pre-eminent worth to many of its readers. To know that we are doing
                                the best we can under the circumstances, is far better than to accept a careless and luke-warm spirit, which
                                neither anticipates nor works out any system of discipline for the benefit of man. Our order came into
                                existence through deep and earnest prayer, through the practice of daily selfdenial and through faithfulness
                                in every temporal and spiritual duly. Its prosperity depends upon the maintenance of the same care and
                                faithfulness and in the efforts which may be made for its perpetuity and increase. All this must be
                                accomplished in the simplicity which is characteristic of the testimony of Jesus, in his lessons of gospel
                                love. "Except ye be converted and be- come as little children, ye cannot enter into the kingdom of heaven."
                                That is, confiding, easy to be entreated, and with love one for another. These lessons are to be repeated
                                from month to month and from year to year, so long as unrighteousness is known or a circle of selfishness
                                remains among men. In this we have the fellowship of the prophet who in his sacred mission had learned that
                                to establish an interest in the things of God, it must be line upon line and precept upon precept. It is
                                highly important at the opening of a new year that a careful review should be taken of the past, and
                                everything done that is consistent to make the present and future more creditable to ourselves, to our
                                Community and more to the glory of our God. Important lessons should have been learned by the things that we
                                have suffered or experienced, that a more clearly defined chart may be executed for the safe conduct of
                                every pilgrim that takes upon himself the cross of Christ. If our social and secular home up- on the earth
                                is to be the representation of a home in the "new earth wherein dwelleth righteousness and peace," and the
                                light and love of our religious fraternity is to be as are the "new heavens," conformable to the will of
                                God, and where holiness or consecration shall be written upon the heart, and upon every article that has
                                been received into this new kingdom of God, then the incoming year may be to us as the valued field in which
                                was found the precious pearl, or as the life of Christ in which is hidden the beautiful treasures of wisdom
                                and knowledge. Treasures which God will award to those who diligently seek Him, and over which the world can
                                have no control. <pb n="18" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 1-8 THE MANIFESTO. Articles published in the Manifesto must be
                                referred to the authors for any explanation that may be required. New views and good views may be both
                                pleasant and profitable. Theological notions are of far less value than religion or practical righteousness,
                                and in order to be saved from the sins of the world one must live a life consecrated to God and to his
                                people. Through the kindness of a friend we are able to distribute several copies of the Manifesto,
                                gratuitously. Any person, not able to pay the subscription price, can have the paper sent to them fkee by
                                forwarding to us their address on a postal. Please write the articles that are intended for publication on
                                sheets of NOTE SIZE, 5x8 inches, and much oblige the printers of the Manifesto. Our Post Office address has
                                been changed to East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H.</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Henry C. Bum, Dear Brother :— After two years among Believers, I have come to the conclusion that Mother Ann
                                Lee is all that she claimed to be. I believe that she saw into the future. I believe there is an element
                                among Believers that will carry them on to victory, down through the ages.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Carter, Charles" TEIform="persName"/>Charles Carter</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York, November 1889" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. Nov. 1889</head><p TEIform="p">Beloved Elder Abraham :—I have been engaged with three hands to assist, in trimming one thousand apple trees.
                                Quite a job you will say. I got pretty tired so that I did not walk or write very straight. We have one
                                orchard of five hundred trees, and one of fifty trees finished. I have come to the conclusion after fifty
                                years experience in trimming trees, that the best time is as soon as the tree has been harvested of its
                                fi-uit. Then the whole system of roots is set to work to prepare buds for the next year's crop. No time nor
                                energy is wasted and the wounds will heal with nothing put on them, better than at any other season. I can
                                show when trimming has been done at different times, and the wounds show for themselves. They vary from a
                                nice, clean wound, healing kindly, to a black, poisonous wound and the black running down the limb,
                                unsightly. Of course the state of the tree has its effect, whether it be stagnant or thrifty.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="E., F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. E.</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watervliet, New York" TEIform="index"/>Watervliet, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Our business in the manufacture of shirts, promises to be a success. We trust that our expenses this winter
                                will not be so large as at a former date. It is a pleasant employ- ment, and the Sisters, generally, enjoy
                                the order of work.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, Conn.</head><p TEIform="p">We are hastening to get ready for winter, by banking and closing our buildings. Cold weather may overtake us
                                before quite prepared, though at present it is moderate. The water from the drinking-trough into the horse
                                barn has rotted the sill, and in conse- quence, a new sill has been put in which involved refitting the
                                whole side of the barn. Grain is threshed, and a good yield. Corn is excellent and all husked ; the fodder
                                will be in the barn the coming week. Boot crops are all harvested. More than twenty acres of land are being
                                fitted for sowing down just before the ground freezes; this method insures a good catch, although weeds
                                often <pb n="19" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 19 come in the first season : a liberal amount of large red
                                clover seed will be sowed on the same land on the last snow of next March. We could use two weeks of open
                                weather yet to finish our fall work. Many improvements could be made were tirce and opportunity available.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Witham, M." TEIform="persName"/>M. Witham</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, Connecticut
                            </head><p TEIform="p">We do not need to go to Egypt to buy corn. Our Cooley Creamer, with submerged cans is a success. Sixtj'-five
                                hundred pounds of butter were made the past year. It is the amount of butter which a herd of cows produces
                                in a year that determines their value, not what they have done in a week or a month. Corn alone, in any of
                                its forms, is not a fit, exclusive food for cows. It is too heating, and lacks in milk-making material,
                                which should be supplied in the form of wheat, bran, shorts, screenings or the like. When hens are exposed
                                to cold storms, rovp is apt to put in an appearance suddenly. To prevent this, close the doors and
                                ventilators, as a sufficient amount o.f cold air will enter from other sources to afford a supply for the
                                fowls. Belmont and May King strawberry plants are large and vigorous, and give promise of plenty of fruit
                                next season. Young currant bushes are looking well. Plenty of potash is needed by most fruits. Fall manuring
                                is good for all small fruits.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, D." TEIform="persName"/>D. Orcutt</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harvard, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Harvard, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">We visited the building where the herbs are pressed. They dry and put up in tasteful papers and boxes, a
                                great variety #&gt;r the Boston Market.—From the Visitors of last Summer. Elder Elijah Myrick has been
                                dangerously sick with neuralgia oi the heart.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Canterbury, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 15. We find, very much to our pleasure, that several of the Brethren have been engaged in trimming and
                                otherwise caring for the fruit trees, and from this we shall anticipate a more bountiful harvest for the
                                incoming year. This season we have harvested about a thousand bushf Is of apples, and eight hundred bushels
                                are secured for use during the winter. Having so valuable an article for food, and so easy of cul- tivation,
                                it would seem that more direct care should be given to its cultivation. To this harvest we would also add
                                the amount of some one hundred bushels of pears. Our farmers brought in seven hundred bushels of nice
                                potatoes. The past season some 350 tons of hay were stored away in the barns. The Post Office address of
                                this place having been changed, it is now ; East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">The Sisters are busy, as usual, making custom shirts for Hewins &amp; Hollis of Boston. They have their
                                work rooms in the fourth story of the large Stone Dwelling. From this height they have n, very picturesque
                                view of the surrounding scenery. The garments, are made mostly by hand-sewing, although they have several
                                Wheeler &amp; Wilson ma- chines which may be used as occasion requires. The Sisters average about six
                                dozen shirts per month. Another company are employed in the manufacture of "Sweaters," (a heavy knit shirt,)
                                and of late have been quite busy</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Groveland, New York" TEIform="index"/>Groveland, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 6. 1889. On the 20th of last month Br. Hamilton DeGraw made a very agreeable visit at the Watervliet
                                Society, in N. Y. We were very much pleased to hear from the friends of that place, and thrice glad to hear
                                from them through a living witness. His call there was made doubly interesting by meeting with the Central
                                Ministry who were with them at the time. The Society here is in favor of a "village improvement board," and
                                conclude it will prove to be the best board we have known for many years. Since Br. Daniel Offord, has
                                offered, we see, A plan for improving our Homes, we agree That "traipsing thro' mud," thro' bushes and
                                briers, Consumes useful tim, while patience expires. But "cast up a highway with stones gathered out,"
                                'Twill add to the beauty of Home, there's no doubt. Another blest feature, 'twill lighten life's cares, For
                                then we'll have less of the sowing of tares. <pb n="20" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 20 THE MANIFESTO. We are having a few
                                days of warm, sunny weather and some are improving the time to the best advantage possible, by trimming the
                                shade trees of which we are blest with almost an unknown quantity. Farmers finished harvesting beets, Oct.
                                22, of which we have twenty-three tons, all raised from one and one-eighth acre. (This beats all.) The
                                threshing of wheat was completed November 18, and by Scripture measure, we now count 2074 bushels. Surely
                                the sowers of good seed shall reap a rich reward.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="G., D. G." TEIform="persName"/>G. D. G.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bible Class" TEIform="index"/>The Bible Class</head><p TEIform="p">Answers to Bible Question No 2, published in Dec. Manifesto. 2. Which is the most noble act of selfsacrifice
                            mentioned in the Old Testament, and why? Number of writers from Canterbury, N. H., 23: Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., 14:
                            Enfield, Conn., 10: Hancock, Mass., 6: Enfield, N. H., 6 : Groveland and Gloucester, 1 each. Abraham's sacrifice,
                            mentioned in Gen. xxii., has 37. Why? Because at the call of God, he was willing to sacrifice his dearly beloved
                            son. Because it required a great deal of faith and trust in God to sacrifice his son through whom so many
                            promises were to be fulfilled. David spared the life of Saul, and this is thought to be the most noble act of
                            self-sacrifice, by 10. Because David resisted the temptation to take King Saul's life. Although having two
                            opportunities, David would not take revenge. The course pursued by Jonathan toward David is considered the most
                            noble act of self-sacrifice, by 8. Because when Jonathan endangered his own life to save that of his friend
                            David, who was to be the Lord's Anointed, we think that the most noble act of self-sacrifice mentioned in the
                            Old Testament. Because the act was purely voluntary on the part of Jonathan, and not in obedience to any command
                            from the Lord which would have made the sacrifice easier, as in the case of Abraham, Moses and others who
                            readily obeyed the word of the Lord. M. L. W. The sacrifice of Jephthah's Daughter has 6 The trial of the two
                            mothers before Solomon, has2. The kindness of Esau to Jacob has 2. The forgiveness of Joseph on meeting his
                            brethren, has 1. BIBLE QUESTION. No. 3. Who is the grandest character in the Old Testament and why?</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Government of the tongue" TEIform="index"/>GOVERNMENT OF THE TONGUE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="King, Emma B." TEIform="persName"/>Emma B. King</byline><p TEIform="p">A beautiful text to illustrate the necessity of governing the tongue is found in the 34th. Psalm, 13. "Keep thy
                            tongue from evil and thy lips from speaking guile." St. James describes the tongue as "an unruly evil, full of
                            deadly poison." Blest as we are with the gift of language, it is quite necessary that we have a restriction over
                            the words that fall from the lips. One sentence spoken, opens the avenue to many thoughts in regard to the
                            character of the speaker. The tongue has the power to utter sentiments of love, purity and kindness which may
                            fall like healing balm upon some suffering soul or it has the power to utter words of sarcasm, *slander and
                            hatred which may pain the soul of the hearer. Such words sting, O, so bitterly. How essential, that we cultivate
                            the tongue to speak only good words. We further read in the Epistle of James, "If any man offend not in word the
                            same is a perfect man, and able also to bridle the whole body." The idea which this text con- veys is that the
                            tongue is the most difficult member of the body to control, and whoever can do this can govern all the other
                            members as well as all the faculties of the mind. An incident is related of Pambos, an illiterate saint which
                            shows what a lesson it is to govern the tongue. Being unable to read he went to some one to learn a Psalm.
                                Hav<pb n="21" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 21 ing learned the verse, "I will take heed to my ways lest I sin
                            with my tongue." He immediately went away, saying, it is enough if it is practically gained. When asked many
                            years after, why he did not go and learn another verse, he answered, "I have never been fully abJe to master
                            this one." He had proved that "the tor.gue is a fire, a world of iniquity." How many heartaches have been caused
                            by evil speaking, and how much good the tongue has done. The beautiful expressions and the inexhaustible amount
                            of benefit which has been wrought by the tongue could never be written or spoken. We cannot cast all the
                            reproach uron the tongue for the mind controls it, and "He that ruleth his own spirit is greater than he that
                            taketh a city." "Doth a fountain send forth at the same, place sweet water and bitter?" If the fountain is kept
                            pure, all the streams will be like unto it. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kind words" TEIform="index"/>Kind Words</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York, August 1889" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., Aug. 1889</head><p TEIform="p">Beloved Elder Henry :—As regards our little publication, THE MANIFESTO, it is to us a welcome visitor; but
                                visitor is not the right name; it is our monthly Companion. When it comes laden with sweet music it starts
                                anew within us, our spring of joy. Your Brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Offord, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Offord</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, Connecticut, August 1889" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, Conn., Aug. 1889</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Editor :—I feel interested in our beautiful Manifesto, and would here express my thanks for the blessing
                                it brings to us. Who can read its pages and not feel emotions of gratitude for the truths it conveys?</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Witham, Maria" TEIform="persName"/>Maria Witham</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watervliet, O., August 1889" TEIform="index"/>Watervliet, O., Aug. 1889</head><p TEIform="p">Beloved Elder Henry :—Your kind note of the 12th. came duly to hand. We are very busy at this time. The
                                Brethren and Sisters who are coming to live with us, will be given a hearty welcome to all that we possess.
                                We are one family, heirs to one gospel privilege. This is the greatest blessing that coulJ be offered to
                                poor man in the flesh, and O, how little appreciated. "Darkness covereth the earth and gross darkness the
                                minds of the people." There seems to be but very little awakening, in the land, for the true light of God.
                                My prayer, is that God's work may be hastened, and that honest souls may enter the gospel work. Your
                                Brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ball, Stephen W." TEIform="persName"/>Stephen W. Ball</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, Connecticut, August 1889" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, Conn., Aug. 1889</head><p TEIform="p">Beloved Elder Henet:—Our everlasting love and prayers for the success of The Manifesto, and all other efforts
                                for good. Your Brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wilcox, George" TEIform="persName"/>George Wilcox</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>Juvenile</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, Connecticut, 1889" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, Conn , 1889.</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Children :—Golden opportunities are often not valued until they are gone. Hov* many and varied are your
                                opportunities. Opportunities for spiritual improvement meet you on every hand. Lose none of them, but be on
                                the watch to appropria e whatever will tend to your heavenward advancement. But opportunities are not
                                afforded you fur self-improvement only. The occasions when the helping hand may be extended or the kind word
                                in season spoken, how often they come to you. How much good you can do by trying to improve every
                                opportunity, whethdfr great or small. There are d*ily opportunities of doing good or ill, of giving pleasure
                                or pain to others; of lightening the cares and trials of those around you by little kindnesses, or making
                                yourselves unhappy by an opposite course. If selfishness rules your hearts, you will lose the happiness you
                                might otherwise gain, besides neglecting nmny duties. For selfish souls cannot grow and expand, nor feel the
                                blessedness of that holy love and communion which spiritual be- ings enjoy. The love of self is misery. Your
                                opportunities always lie before, not be- hind you, and God's promises of love and help are sure and many.
                                The duties and <pb n="22" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 22 THE MANIFESTO. opportunities of the present are yours now. ¦ Do not
                                be blind to them. To-day is yours— only to-day. The wasted opportunity comes not back. To-morrow is not
                                yours, and if you lose this opportunity what assurance have you that you will have another? Opportunities
                                well improved bring eternal gain to the spirit. Life is made of little duties, little opportunities ; all
                                attainment is reached step by step, and the way lies "through the sunshine and the storm." Beware of saying
                                "Oh! that is such a trifle it is not worth doing," for that is an error which has kept thousands from doing
                                half the good they might to their fellow-creatures. It is usually safe or right to follow the promptings of
                                the heart, when it bids you to offer a kindness or a helping hand to another, however small a matter it may
                                be. Your Brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt</byline></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mother Ann Lee" TEIform="index"/>MOTHER ANN LEE</head><p TEIform="p">Mother Ann Lee came from Manchester, England. She was the mother of all the Shaker Societies. She was a very
                                good woman. She said to the children, "O my little ones you should obey your teachers. On the Sabbath day
                                you should not do any work that is not necessary. You should not play with sharp tools."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Curtis, Gertna E." TEIform="persName"/>Gertna E. Curtis. 8 yrs old.</byline></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prudence" TEIform="index"/>PRUDENCE</head><p TEIform="p">God teaches us to be prudent which means saving. We should not waste any food, not even the cores of apples
                                but they should be given to the creatures. When we sweep a room we should save all the pins, needles, and
                                bits of thread. My teacher told me that those that save are rich and those that waste are poor.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leonard, Lou" TEIform="persName"/>Lou Leonard. 8 yrs. old.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, October 1889" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon., Oct. 1889</head><p TEIform="p">Dbae Elder Henry :—Last Winter Brother Orren gave me one of your little "Dew Drop" books, which you printed
                                thirty-seven years ago. I have read much in it, and like it very much. I was going to write to you about it,
                                but when I saw you were coming here I thought I would tell you what I like in it best. I have not seen you
                                only a few min- utes, so thought I would write to you. The verse for my birthday is very pretty. It says "By
                                your works and deportment, all that know you will form a judgment of what you are." For your birthday it
                                says, "Cultivation is as essential for the mind, as food for the body." The funniest verse is, "You may
                                shine, but take care not to scorch." I was so glad that you could come to the Bible class last evening, and
                                that our class could sit up late and come too. I hope you will come again, soon. From your little girl</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="St. Clare, Eva" TEIform="persName"/>Eva St. Clare. 7 yr,s. old</byline></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="They say" TEIform="index"/>"THEY SAY-"</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> "They say"—Ah ! well, suppose they do : But can they prove the story true? Suspicion
                                        may arise from naught But malice, envy, want of thought; Why count yourself among the "they" Who
                                        whisper what they dare not say? "They say"—But why the tale rehearse, And help to make the matter
                                        worse? No good can possibly accrue From telling what may bo untrue ; And is it not a nobler plan To
                                        speak of all the best you can? "They say"—Well, if it should be so, Why need you tell the tale of
                                        woe; Will it the bitter wrong redress, Or make one pang of sorrow less? Will it the erring one
                                        restore, Henceforth to go and sin no more? "They say"—0 ! pause and look within, See how your heart
                                        inclines to sin; Watch! lest in dark temptation's hour, You, too, should sink beneath its power :
                                        Pity the frail—weep o'er their fall, But speak of good or not at all.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To kill pain and drive off dull cares..." TEIform="index"/>To kill pain and drive off dull cares...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">To kill pain and drive off dull cares, think and do for some one beside yourself. 'Tis joy to feel you
                                gladden those Who need your daily cheer,— And better far, than seek repose Alone in selfish care.</p><byline TEIform="byline"> —<persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W.</byline></div3></div2><pb n="23" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good samaritan" TEIform="index"/>THE GOOD SAMARITAN</head><p TEIform="p">"Inasmuch as ye have done it unto the least of these, my brethren, ye have done it unto me."—Matt, xxv., 40.
                            Canterbury, N. H. I will walk with you,when the shadows fall, When err ing steps ye would recall, When
                            seemingly ye are by all Earthly friends forgotten. The Priest and Levite may pass by, And leave the wounded
                            one to die; The good Samaritan coming nigh Brings mercy and forbearance.</p></div2><pb n="24" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>
                                The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health, for December has portraits of several notable people of
                                to-day, and interesting articles illustrative of their life and character. Thomas C. Mendenhall, the
                                President of the American Association of Science; Mrs. M. E. H. G. Dow, ex-president of a Eailroad in Dover,
                                N. H. George M. Pullman, the originator of the Pullman Palace Car. Many other articles of valuable
                                information may be found in this number. The department of Science of Health has an excellent article on
                                Temperance and Reform and is well worth a careful study. Fowler &amp; Wells Co., 775 Broadway, N. Y. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Philidelphia musical journal" TEIform="index"/>The
                                Philadelphia Musical Journal
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The
                                Philadelphia Musical Journal for December has a portrait of Addie Reed Fleming, the contralto Soloist; of
                                Emma Juch, who has in possession that even quality of voice, which, combined with bird-like execution,
                                intelligent phrasing and charming manners contributes to her popularity; of Marie Halton and of Pauline
                                Hall. Open Questions will be studied with interest by the readers of the Journal, as it is to be a free
                                discussion of subjects of great importance to musicians. Other valuable contributions will be found in the
                                number for December. Gould &amp; Woolley, 1416 Chestnut St., Philadelphia, Pa. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/>Hall's Journal of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Hall's Journal of Health
                                for December. Looking Forward; The Chapin Home; Fingers before Forks; Proper Food for Consumptives;
                                Psychism; Christian Science; Child Whipping: A Cold and its Treatment; Measles; Whither are we drifting; A
                                Drop of Water; etc., etc. Office 206 Broadway, N. Y. The School Bulletin is an educational Journal published
                                at Syracuse, N. Y., by C. W. Bardeen. In it will be found a large amount of interesting and useful
                                information for those who teach, and no less for those interested in teaching. $1. pr. year. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nashua weekly telegraph" TEIform="index"/>Nashua Weekly
                                Telegraph
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Nashua Weekly
                                Telegraph, is from the Telegraph Printing Office, Nashua, N. H., and under the management of O. C. Moore. It
                                has come out in a new dress, and being well printed, becomes a pleasure to read it. Wonderful Advance has
                                been made in Calendar making of late years, and the enterprising proprietors of Hood's Sarsaparilla seem to
                                have completely mastered the business. For their calendar for 1890 is so beautiful in conception and general
                                effect as to be almost beyond improvement. Fourteen colors were used by the lithographer in producing the
                                beautiful head, the flesh tints being simply exquisite. To be appreciated this Calendar must be seen. Ask
                                for Hoojd's Calendar and Hood's Holiday Herald at your druggist's, or send 6 cents in stamps to C. I. Hood
                                &amp; Co., Lowell, Mass.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wing, Jane" TEIform="index"/>Jane Wing
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Wing, Jane" TEIform="persName">Jane Wing</persName>, at South Union, Ky., Nov. 20, 1889. Age 82 yrs. 4 mo. and
                                13 days. Sister jane came to this Society in 1811. Another veteran now has gone From earth to her eternal
                                home, The clay we place beneath the sod, The spirit "Wings" its way to God. H. L. E.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bennett, Abigail" TEIform="index"/>Abigail Bennett
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Bennett, Abigail" TEIform="persName">Abigail Bennett</persName>, at Enfield, Conn., Nov. 20, 1889. Age 82 yrs.
                                and 8 mo. Thy labors are ended, thy spirit set free, And the welcome of angels is now heard by thee; For a
                                true child of Mother has joined the bright throng, To swell in sweet praises the eternal song. M.
                            Witham.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nelson, Eliza" TEIform="index"/>Eliza Nelson
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Nelson, Eliza" TEIform="persName">Eliza Nelson</persName>, at North Family, Pleasant Hill, Ky., Nov. 29, 1889.
                                Age 71 yrs.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sauerborn, Catherine" TEIform="index"/>Catherine Sauerborn
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Sauerborn, Catherine" TEIform="persName">Catherine Sauerborn</persName> at Watervliet, 0. Dec. 2, 1889. Age 63
                                yrs. Sister Catherine was a faithful and devoted member for twenty-seven years. S. S. M.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rollins, Lavina" TEIform="index"/>Lavina Rollins
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Rollins, Lavina" TEIform="persName">Lavina Rollins</persName> of Center Family, at Union Village, O., Dec. 2,
                                1889. Age 83 yrs. 11 mo. £nd 23 days. Sister Lavina has been a faithful and worthy member of the Society
                                since early childhood. C. C.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Moore, Nancy E." TEIform="index"/>Eldress Nancy E. Moore
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Moore, Nancy E." TEIform="persName">Eldress Nancy E. Moore</persName> at South Union, Ky., Dec. 5, 1889. Age 82
                                yrs. 4 mo. and 5 days. Eldress Nancy came into the Society on the 11th. of Nov. 1811, and has been a
                                faithful soul ever since. She leaves the earth for heaven above, Where saints and angels dwell in love. H.
                                L. E.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Advertisements" TEIform="index"/>[Advertisements]</head><p TEIform="p">[Advertisements deleted.]</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>