<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0105" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Mount Lebanon Bishopric</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Albany, New Yorkdevp</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">1</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">5</biblScope><date value="18710501" TEIform="date">May 1871</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">33-40</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="1" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="33" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="5" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">" I WILL SHAKE ALL NATIONS, AND THE DESIRE OF ALL NATIONS SHALL COME ; AND I WILL FILL THIS HOUSE
                        WITH GLORY, SA1TH THE LORD." Published Monthly, by, and under the direction of the Mt. Lebanon
                        Bishopric, Vol. I. SHAKERS, ALBANY CO., N. Y., MAY, 1871. No. 5.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Right and light" TEIform="index"/>Right and Light</head><p TEIform="p">The First Cause of all causes we call God; by descending terms, Father and Mother; Being and
                            Will; Truth and Love; I am and I do ; Spirit and Matter ; Religion and Science. The
                            religious instinct is inherent in the human race. A recognition of God is the fountain of
                            goodness, and source of truth. The desire to be and do good, is religion. The desire to know
                            how, why, and when to be good, is theology. Spiritualism is the soul of all systems of
                            philosophy. The rudest of races have their philosophical theologicol cosmogony; and some of
                            the most civilized and cultured of the races have not been exceeded, in absurdity, by the
                            most savage, in their theories of creation, the being and attributes of God, the nature and
                            destructibility of matter, etc. This is under the general law, that "light is sown for the
                            righteous—the doers of right; and darkness of the understanding for the violators of law,
                            physiological and spiritual." It is a historical and present fact, that a highly-civilized
                            nation, like the French, are, to a large extent, seeking happiness through the exercise of
                            the same passions, and by the excitement of the same senses, that it is sought for by the
                            Hottentots. " In Paris, pleasure, or more properly, sensuality, appears to be carried to its
                            highest possible summit."—Swedenborg. The nobility and serfs of Russia, if not equally
                            sensual, in the use of their absorbing and procreating powers, the balance is in favor of
                            the serfs, who, by poverty and the necessities of existence, are kept in a more simple
                            physiological condition ; their passions not being inflamed by abnormal excitants, in drink
                            and food; while the nobles are as full-fed horses, each one neighing after his neighbor's
                            wife—the abuse of nutrition and reproduction. It has come to pass, that while in the wisdom
                            of God, " the world by wisdom "— material and sensual theology—" knew not God," it has
                            pleased God, by the foolishness of preaching, and the ministration of the Spirit of God,
                            acting upon the same senses that evil acts upon, has saved them that believe, from the
                            indulgence of gluttony and drunkenness, and from fruitless sexuality, which has been more
                            emphatically the work of darkness, whether by the married or unmarried, as it is the most
                            concentrated form of human evil. The priests of Nature—Pythagoras, Diogenes, Plato, Seneca,
                            and the Stoics, enjoined self-control, and, to a great extent, self-denial of the senses, as
                            did the Avaters, like Confucius, Buddha, Zoroaster, Jesus; they touched each other. The
                            material worlds ! the spiritual worlds ! Why, is it not all spirit, in dif- ferent stages of
                            unfoldment, from the stand-point of Deity ? All spirit, more or less externalized, down to
                            the earths, which are first, gas and ether, then granite, rock and diamond. All matter, more
                            or less attenuated, sublimated, etherealized, up to the lowest spirit sphere, and thence up
                            to the heaven of heavens. Jesus inherited physiological and moral conditions derived from a
                            long line of self-controlling, self-denying ancestry, con- creted into an organized body
                            like the Essenes, who, throughout the Jewish history, did not eat animal food; nor did they
                            fight or marry. This gave Jesus an advantage over all other human beings, Adam and Eve not
                            excepted: because their innocence and goodness was that of the baby-hood of the race. As a
                            child, his aspirations were upward, towards the seventh heaven. A comparatively-few of his
                            countrymen and women, of the Jews, approximated the high religious status to which he
                            attained. It should be distinctly remarked, that it was in goodness, rather than in
                            intellectuality—in religion rather than in theology, that he excelled. " Whence hath this
                            man this knowledge, seeing he knoweth not letters," plainly indicates that he belonged to
                            the order of human beings who were called to externalize God on this earth in their lives,
                            rather than in deep, great, and grand philosophical and scien- tific theories, explanatory
                            of the mysteries of creation to the human understanding. His work was to make human beings
                            good and true lovers of God, and companions of angels ; as social beings, to learn them to
                            love one another with a pure heart, fervently; to pray, rather than study. This was
                            religion; and "none but a good man can be a true philosopher." When Paul came up, who was
                            also of a good philosophical and intellectual stock, and had been educated in all the
                            learning and culture of the Jews, he taught theology—the science of the religion of Jesus.
                            It was an effort of the human mind to comprehend the height and depth, and length and
                            breadth of the work of human redemption, and to systematize and explain it logically. During
                            the first three centuries, the religious organizations having all things common, created by
                            the holy Christ Spirits acting upon the emotions and affec- tions, and operating in the
                            hearts of the lovers of righteousness (not mere lovers of knowledge), stood the test of
                            internal corruption and outward persecution ; but they finally succumbed, and a Gentile
                            bishop led the Jerusalem Pentecostal Church : a fit type of the " man of sin," who was to
                            inhabit the most holy temples in the Gentile world for twelve hundred and sixty years of
                            educational preparation of its heathen people to receive the Christ of God in the female
                            Order, through a female Messiah, as the Jews had received him in the male order through
                            Jesus—a male and female Christ manifested through male and female human beings. During the
                            reign of Anti-christ, Spiritualism operated to create a mixture of elements. Hebrew,
                            Christian, Heathen, Mahommedan, and everything in heaven and on earth—all the spheres being
                            confusedly blended together—the relation of the natural and spiritual worlds was abnormal,
                            represented by three unclean spirits, like frogs (amphibious) proceeding out of the mouth of
                            the dragon—heathenism ; of the beast—the Catholic, Protest- ant, and Greek Churches ; and of
                            the false prophet—the heretics and witnesses: false miracles, false relics, false
                            confessions and absolutions; false piety, which thought killing was doing God service ;
                            false marriages, doctrines of devils; false everything. Whoredom, adultery, fornication, are
                            terms plentifully used by divine religionists, to represent the commingled wickedness of
                            these so-called Christian Churches. " Babylon the Great, the Mother of Har<pb n="34" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHA.KER. lots—Whores;" by which obnoxious terms, the reforming daughters of the Roman
                            and Greek Churches, and State Governments, are not inaptly designated. As in the days of
                            Jesus, the Essenes— the ancient Quakers ; and the Sadducees— the ancient Materialists—alone
                            escaped his denunciations; so, in our own time, the modern Essenes—true Quakers; and the
                            modern Sadducees, organized into the American Governments, in our day, of all others, go the
                            most unrebuked by the "seed of the woman"—the followers of Ann Lee,—who are bruising, in
                            themselves, the head of the sensual powers and passions of Christendom, the lust of sexual
                            indulgence; the nude statue and black crooks of this " Murder of the Innocents " age, which
                            has legalized monopoly of the life elements; thus making war and the destruction of
                            embryonic human beings a society necessity, in order to hold in check population, which
                            continually presses on the means of subsistence in cities, towns, and villages. It is said,
                            that the private character of Swedenborg, from youth to manhood, was altogether
                            irreproachable. He opened the portals of the invisible world, which the Protestants had
                            closed, to keep wicked men and women from coming back to them, as they had been in the habit
                            of doing under the Catholic rule; so that they were like people who shut the door against
                            their enemies, by refusing to admit even their friends, the angels. Never was the simile of
                            the ladder which Jacob saw, so appropriately illustrated as in the case of this seer. He was
                            a believer and follower of Jesus in his first advent upon earth. He began, as Assessor of
                            Mines in Sweden, and went up the ladder of the sciences to the great First Cause. Like his
                            ante-type, John the Baptist, he lived a celibate life. "He complains that his scientific
                            labors were not appreciated ; that his productions are looked down upon, by a number of
                            political blockheads, as mere scholastic exercises, which ought to stand back, while their
                            presumptuous finesse and intrigues step forward. He said the beginning of nature was
                            identical with the beginning of geometry." " He discovered the science of crystallography,
                            or law of crystals. Every metal has particles of its own, of a peculiar form; the same being
                            true of all mundane substances, from the rocks to the most etheralized elements. The various
                            shapes of these atomic crystals cause the different tastes, smells, and feelings which
                            attach to them. He appears to have labored to apprehend the origin and arrangement of matter
                            in the earths, and also, to apprehend the nature and condition of the intelligent atoms
                            which compose their social organizations, and are the inner worlds, so far as he found
                            entrance thereinto. He affirmed that the object of his mission was, to ' demonstrate
                            immortality to the natural senses:' that is, Spiritualism. His prevailing idea was, that
                            external objects were the product of internal powers and and forces." 7</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Social evil" TEIform="index"/>The Social Evil</head><p TEIform="p">" And now, also, the axe is laid unto the root of the trees.'' John, 3:10. It was the
                            peculiar mission of the first founders of Shakerism to bear testimony against the " social
                            evil," in all its phases, legal and illegal, and in all its relations and bearings in human
                            life; hence, it was reported that they condemned marriage; but this was a mistake—they only
                            condemned the abuses and evils cloaked under it, holding it to be exclusively a civil right,
                            and not a Christian institution. And when it was incorporated into the Christian system, in
                            the outer court, in the Apostles' days, it was considered more of an innovation than from
                            divine authority— hence, it was said: " Brethren, the time is short that remaineth; that
                            both they that have wives shall be as though they had none." America is destined to take the
                            lead in all the reforms of the 19th century. Through the power of the invisible, operating
                            through a visible agency, great and mighty things have been accomplished, and still greater
                            things remain to be met and overcome. Seeming im- possibilities belong to the past and not
                            to the present age of the world. Various opinions are entertained by reformers as to the
                            best manner of disposing of the " social evil." It seems to be a principle inherent in human
                            nature, and been handed down from time imme- morial ; like some old chronic hereditary
                            disease, hard to eradicate, and too delicate a subject for public discussion. Yet, reformers
                            say something must be done, and this false delicacy must be laid aside before science can be
                            brought to bear successfully against it. True ! But, we say, the reason why reformers in the
                            past have not been able to reform the world, is, because they have not been sufficiently
                            radical on this point. Now we propose to begin at the root of human depravity, and put away
                            the cause, that the effect may cease. " And now, also, the axe is laid unto the root of the
                            trees," etc. Man in scripture is com- pared to trees and known by his fruit; and it may be
                            that we have all, in the past, eaten apples very improperly. Trees are in the plural and
                            implies both sexes, because both sexes are involved in the social evil. Perhaps there is no
                            sentiment more common concerning its origin, which is implied, if not expressed, than the
                            fact, that had it not been for the transgression of Adam and Eve, in the Garden of Eden, we
                            should not have been found in this fix; or, in other words, the social evil would never have
                            existed. The cause of the "social evil," and the root of human depravity is traced back to
                            Adam's transgression; to a lawless principle, which was never essential to the reproduction
                            of the human race—the excessive indulgence of which, is the great problem now up for
                            discussion. In scripture language, the principle is called by different names; "lust,"
                            "flesh," "old man," "forbidden fruit," "man of sin," "son of perdition," "carnal mind,"
                            "devil," "dragon," "evil," "which the Lord shall consume with the spirit of his mouth, and
                            shall destroy with ;he brightness of his coming," etc. (2 Thes. 2:8.) Which are all
                            synonymous in their signification. But the great question is, what shall we do with it ?
                            This is the problem :— How shall we eradicate it without destroying the human race? Science
                            cannot doit; if it ould, it would have been done long ago. Philosophy cannot do it; it has
                            tried, and proved a failure. But science and philosophy, combined with practical obedience
                            to law and order; can do it; it has been done. What has been done can be done again. It is
                            of so long standing and so incorporated into the very heart and core of humanity, that we
                            admit the difficulty. The principle in and of itself is lawless—is not subject to any law,
                            neither indeed can be, when left uncontrolled by a superior and higher power. The principle
                            is bad — it is wicked in the extreme!—it has been tried before the High Court of Heaven, and
                            found guilty of the most abominable crimes; the earth, itself, bearing witness against it;
                            and the sentence pronounced by the Court and Judge of all the earth, is, death. It is doomed
                            to crucifixion, by a daily cross and self-denial; that is, total abstinence; starving it to
                            death by inches, until the principle is entirely eradicated from the soul. This can be done
                            without extinguishing the human race, by recognizing two orders of people, viz.: the natural
                            order, and the spiritual order— separate and distinct. These two orders comprise the whole
                            family of man, and admit of different grades and degrees. Each order is governed by its own
                            laws. Two great problems have been solved in the United States within the last century,
                            viz.: the actual practice of a "virgin life," and "community of interest," without the aid
                            of nunneries and monasteries; where the sexes enjoy social and daily intercourse, and
                            preserve their chastity from year to year, and have for the last seventy-five years. They
                            prefer keeping the higher law. This was so new and strange at first, that the world did not
                            believe that this profession of life could be actually produced and carried out. Elder F. W.
                            Evans, of Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., one of the most progressive minds of the age, in a letter to
                            North Union, dated May 25th, 1868, said: "For the first fifty years, the question of there
                            being a resurrection order on the earth, and quietly living pure, celibate lives, was always
                            met with the scoffs and jeers of the world, with the charge that they did not so live; that
                            ended the argument. " Thus the world called in question the fact of any living lives of
                            chastity. Eighty years have passed away, and that fact, now, is no longer called in
                            question. Hundreds of men and women have lived together, maintaining a close, social
                            relation, upon the basis of pure celibacy, for eighty years in succession, known to the
                            thinking, philosophical mind as a prob34 <pb n="35" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHA-KER. 35 lem not to be
                            (but is now) solved. This fact, Henry Vincent will make known on his return to England."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="P., J. S." TEIform="persName"/>J. S. P., North Union</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Anastasis" TEIform="index"/>Anastasis</head><p TEIform="p">This word, which is rendered resurrection in our English version of the New Testament, has
                            two important meanings attached to it by Jesus and the Apostles, and these so intimately
                            connected that the use of one immediately suggests the other. One signification is, c new,
                            spiritual life, which succeeds the sensuous life in the Christian believer; and the other,
                            an endless existence. In fact, when the term is applied to Christians, the two ideas,
                            usually, are completely blended. We see how closely connected these were in the mind of
                            Jesus, from the words he addressed to Martha, who was bewailing the death of her brother.
                            "Jesus said to her, 'Thy brother shall rise again—anastesetai.' Martha said to him, 'I know
                            he will rise again in the resurrection in the last day—en te anastasei en te eschate
                            hermera.' Jesus said to her, 'lam the resurrection and the life; and whoever lives and
                            believes in me will never die.'" The same union of the two ideas is also observed in the
                            reply of Jesus to the Sadducees, who denied that there was to be any anastasis—any rising to
                            a future life. Which of the seven brothers, 'they ask, is to have the woman whom they each
                            married, if they all live hereafter ? The answer is, " Those having been deemed worthy to
                            obtain that life and the resurrection from the dead—tou aionos ekeinou kai tes anastaseos
                            tes ek nekron—neither marry nor are given in marriage; nor can they die any more." These two
                            meanings we find also blended in the Apostle Paul's argument in reply to those persons in
                            the Corinthian church who denied the resurrection of the dead. " There is a sensuous
                            body—soma psuchikon—and a spiritual body." u The first man is from earth, and the second is
                            from heaven." "As ice have borne the image of the earthly, we shall also bear the image of
                            the heavenly." " When this mortal shall have put on immortality, then will be fulfilled the
                            recorded saying, 'Death is swallowed up in victory.' " These two thoughts, it is safe to
                            say, are the prominent ones in the mind of Jesus and of Paul whenever they allude to a
                            future life. Life in God, the heavenly life, is the resurrection, and that is to continue
                            forever. So completely does the *dea of the Divine Life fill their minds that it is as
                            though there were no life in the human race where that is not—all else is death. The Apostle
                            Paul represents himself as eager to rise out of this state of death. " If by any means I may
                            attain to the resurrection from the dead," that is, from among those who are dead. All who
                            are destitute ftf this spiritual, heavenly life, are the dea-l. It matters not whether they
                            are in or out of the physical body. This spiritual life is .he life of the last day, the day
                            of the Messih, the eternal age; and this he was striv&gt;» % with all earnestness to
                            gain. It is worthy of notice that, in his argument for the resurrection addressed to the
                            Corinthians, he speaks only of Christians as actual subjects of the resurrection. From this
                            fact some have drawn the conclusion that a part of mankind, in the view of the Apostle, are
                            to be annihilated, or else to remain forever without hope of everlasting life. This is
                            because they have supposed the Apostle to be speaking of an event that is to be accomplished
                            in a brief period of time, and not to continue throughout the Messiah's reign until his work
                            shall be completed. A proper attention, however, to the course of his argument will satisfy
                            any one that no such idea can be deduced from it. Having given his proofs of the appearance
                            of Jesus among the living after his crucifixion by the Jews and the Romans, he exultingly
                            exclaimed, "Now has Christ been raised from the dead, the first of the sleeping ones. For,
                            since death has intervened through a man, resurrection, also, has come through a man; for,
                            as all die in Adam, so all will be made alive in Christ; but every one in his own order;
                            Christ, first, then those who are Christ's in his corning—en te parousia autou. Then—in due
                            course of time—comes the end—the completion of his work—when he shall have destroyed all
                            rule, and all authority and power opposed to God's. For he must reign until he put all
                            enemies under his feet. Death, the last enemy, shall be destroyed." It is to be observed,
                            that the Apostle declares all will be made alive, but they will be made alive in Christ.
                            None but Christians are subjects of the resurrection, in the essential, sublime sense of the
                            term, yet none are excluded from the privilege of becoming such. This he puts beyond a doubt
                            by the sweeping declaration, "All will be made alive in Christ," in which the all that are
                            to be made alive in Christ are contrasted with the all that die in Adam. He speaks
                            elsewhere, it is true, of those who are to be punished in the time of Christ's coming, but
                            the penalty meted out to them is just that which their offenses merit, according to the age
                            in which they live. It is the diken olethron aionion, a term similar to that which Jude
                            employed when speaking of the guilty inhabitants of Sodom and Gomorrah —the diken puros
                            aioniou—the penalty their offenses demanded in that age. Death and hell are to be destroyed;
                            and, unquestionably, the penalties resulting from violated law, which are more severe the
                            greater the light which one sins against, are means which the Being of Infinite Love uses
                            for the destruction of these enemies of everlasting righteousness. There can be no escape;
                            the penalty is just as certain to follow crime a» day to follow night. And as transgression
                            of the divine laws has been, in one way or another, universal amongmankind, there was no
                            impropriety in the Apostle's regarding all as in a state of death, while he proclaimed a way
                            of deliverance from it for all men. The mode of deliverance is not an arbitrary one; not
                            that of a partial, fitful, passionate being, nor of one who takes pleasure in displaying his
                            power so as to overwhelm with terror and amazement the human soul, and to confound the sense
                            of right and justice implanted in man. God works so as to confound the plans of the proud
                            and self-sufficient, yet always so that his methods of working commend themselves ultimately
                            to the highest reason of his creatures. The Apostle Paul speaks of the resurrection as
                            occurring in a moment, in the twinkling of an eye, and yet it is evident, from his statement
                            that each person is to be raised in his own order; that he refers only to the commencement
                            of the work in the individual soul, which may, in fact, be as sudden as the language
                            represents, and jet not occur, in many cases, until after a long preparation in the person
                            for it. His own conversion to Christianity was remarkable for its sudden- ness, and yet he
                            represents himself as striving to the utmost to attain to the resurrection from the dead. "
                            I have not yet gained, I am not yet perfect, but I am pursuing so as to gain the prize of my
                            high calling." The resurrection, then, in its essential nature, may commence in this state
                            of being, and in the case of the Apostle, it did so commence. It was to him the introduction
                            to a condition of happiness of which, while he adhered to his Jewish religion, he had no
                            conception. It was a sun, illuminating his entire spirit. It was the rain which waters the
                            tender plants of the new, spiritual life, causing them to grow and become strong. It was the
                            inspiration of divine truth within himself, which made him the effectual preacher of
                            righteousness wherever he went. It was the opening of heaven to his internal view, showing
                            him the heavenly messengers descending and ascending, earthward and heavenward; showing him
                            also, Christ himself, who stood by him and encouraged him in his efforts to advance his
                            cause, and inspired him with strength and courage to bear the numerous persecutions to which
                            he was subjected. The resurrection was to him a spiritual, heavenly life, whose
                            characteristics were joy and peace, gentleness, kindness, and the ardent and abiding love of
                            one who has been baptized into the element of love, in the place of pride, selfwill, hatred
                            and malice; unwavering faith in the infinite goodness of God that purposes and plans the
                            welfare of all his creatures; the substitution of new and living hopes for old prejudices;
                            the breaking down of old barriers that had been interposed by ignorance and folly between
                            different portions of human beings, enabling him to love as ardently and work as earnestly
                            for his Gentile brethren as for those of his own nation. This to him was a present
                            resurrection ; and so he represents it in his epistles to Christians. " If ye, then, are
                            risen with Christ," he wrote to them, "seek those things which are above, where Christ sits
                            at the right hand of God." And yet it is plain, from his own words, that he regarded the
                            resurrection, in its fullest sense, as something far beyond anything he had yet experienced.
                            He was looking forward to a grand consummation of hopes that he had been led to form. There
                            -v?as a prize at the end of his course which he purposed to gain, a crown of righteousness
                            which, as victor, he expected to wear. "When Christ, who is our life, shall be manifested,
                            ye also shall be manifested with him in glory." This glorious manifestation w?x to be the
                            fulfillment of his hopes, his complete deliverance from the state of death in which he still
                            found himself, though he had been elevated already " to sit in heavenly places in Christ."
                            That was to be not only freedom from the power of sin, but from the liability of ever again
                            falling into sin. <pb n="36" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 36 THE SH^KEH. In addition to this expectation of a
                            glorious deliverance from the death of sin, there was an assurance in his mind that this
                            blessedness was to continue forever. " For me to live is Christ, and to die is gain. I have
                            a desire to depart and 6c vrith Christ, which is far better." His song of triumph, at the
                            close of his argument for the resurrection, is not only that of the assured victor over sin,
                            but also of one who expects forever to wear his triumphal crown:—"0 death, where is thy
                            sting? 0 Hades, invisible world of the dead, where is thy victory ? Thanks be to God who
                            gives us the victory through our Lord Jesus Christ! Victory now, over that which gives to
                            death all its force and bitterness—sin; so that we are elevated completely above it, living
                            lives of purity and practical righteousness in spite of the enemies by whom we are daily
                            beset! Victory in certain prospect over all the foes we now have or may yet have to
                            encounter, until we shall, each, be able to say, ' I have fought the good fight, I have
                            finished my course, I have kept the faith,—henceforth the crown of everlasting life is
                            mine!'"</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName"/>Wm. H. Bussell</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Poetry" TEIform="index"/>POETICAL</head><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker" TEIform="index"/>"The Shaker."</head><p TEIform="p">Hail! hail, thou welcome messenger of truth— God speed thee, and sustain thee, thou art
                                forsooth Answer to long, long years of earnest x&gt;rayers And supplication to God
                                that somewhere, Or somehow his holy truths we should declare. Thy sacred pages yet will
                                light unfold, Moro precious to a sin-enrsed world than gold, Diamonds and rubies; all
                                the gems of earth Fall before thee—of more intrinsic worth Thou art by far. Thou art a
                                chast'ning rod Wielded in the mercy, truth and love of God. That all may read and
                                understand the Truth From hoary-headed sage to prattling youth, That whoever will, may
                                come and be partaker Of heaven's choicest boon, we send The Shaker, Which will reveal
                                the new and living way, From darkness to an effulgent day. The mission of Tins Shaker to
                                fallen man [Ann, Is, God's love revealed through Christ and Mother To teach mankind that
                                nnto him is given To do God's will on eai"th, as done in heaven, To break the shackles,
                                let oppressed souls free, Proclaim abroad the glorious jubilee. [sword To unsheath the
                                bright and glittering two-edged Of Gospel Truth, the spirit and power of God ; To
                                enlighten souls, convict them of their sins, And make them feel and knoto 'tis Truth
                                that wins Aye, Truth alone will stand, all else will fail, 'Tie God's decree that Truth
                                shall yet prevail. O speed, speed on thou sweet angelic sound, Convince the skeptic and
                                the wise confound; Strengthen the weak,—confirm the strong To battle for the right, and
                                to subdue the wrong. Teach all mankind this Truth to fully know, That in the depths of
                                earthly hearts do grow Germs of unrest, and, all learn this, would You feed on heavenly
                                manna—Angels' food, And be forever happy, then be good,— Take up thy cross and follow
                                Christ the Saviour, Serve God with thy whole heart, also thy Brother Love as thine own
                                self; and, wouldst thou at last A home in heaven secure ? All that thou hast, Forsake ;
                                houses and lands, children and wife, Brothers, Sisters, Father, Mother, thy life— Thy
                                carnal life surrender, lay it down If thou wonldst reign with Christ and wear the crown
                                Of Everlasting Life prepared for those Who've conquered sin, and all their inward foes.
                                Aye. friend, know this, and do this Truth believe, That Christ lies not, nor yet doth he
                                deceive ; Would'st thou be his, and enter heaven's door, Sell that thou hast and give it
                                to the poor ; All selfishness be wholly laid aside And all thou hast be willing to
                                divide. By this we do not mean that we must hate The person, or the thing—the selfish
                                state The carnal mind, that loves a selfish few, This is the meaning, the good and true
                                Are all of God, and we must love them all; These are universal—belong not to the fall,—
                                These are Christ's conditions, none else will do, For those who would the narrow way
                                pursue. Yea truly, 'tis a straight and narrow road That leads the Pilgrim home to heaven
                                and God, No vulture's eye hath e'er this pathway seen, Nor lion's whelp hath ever trod
                                therein; No ravenous wolf or other beast of prey Can walk this pure and holy, heavenly
                                way, That leads the soul to Life, and to eternal Day. Many shall be called—the Chosen
                                few— 'Tis they alone who daily will pursue The strait and narrow way, forsaking all For
                                Christ's sake and the Gospel; who will fall Upon the rock, and there will broken be, And
                                from all dross and sin be purged free, Who'll wash their robes in Blood, that of the
                                Lamb, Through living works come up, the great I AM Alone to serve ; who'll strive to
                                know and do His holy will, the narrow way pursue, Whose every breath to Father, Mother,
                                Son, Is, Not my will, but thine O God be done.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="F., E. E." TEIform="persName"/>E. E. F.</byline></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My shaker home" TEIform="index"/>My Shaker Home</head><p TEIform="p">i In a hamlet, remote from the thronged thoroughfares, Where business and pleasure with
                                folly abound, I dwell in retirement, and breathe the pure airs That flow from the
                                mountains which circle me round. My home is so pleasant, contentment draws near, i. And
                                bids me rejoice in its pleasant retreat So closely allied to that heavenly sphere, Where
                                discord no more may her tauntings repeat. No edict from monarch nor empress I dread, In
                                a President's frowns nothing piercing can see ; Christ, in his true order, I own as my
                                head, And love is the magnet which captivates me. To the goddess of fashion we never bow
                                down, Thus saved from the trouble her votaries share, A cap, smooth and modest, a neat
                                tidy gown, With kerchief and collar, my Sisterhood wear. Our shoes are for comfort, and
                                made to the feet, Not so small to compress them and freedom destroy; Yea, our
                                understandings would be quite a treat, To such slaves of folly as " Miss Afong Moy."*
                                Not with jewelled fingers our work we perform, And pendulums hang in our clocks, not our
                                ears, No pearls, nor yet ribbons, our persons adorn, They are deemed quite as useless as
                                crocodile tears. 4 Our costume throughout is well fitted for those Who prize health and
                                comfort, 'bove fashion or pride, And find in a neat humble garb, more repose, Than the
                                gay, pimping lady, whose heart is outside. What can adorn woman like virtue and love ? A
                                heart full of kindness and heavenly grace, These deck her with jewels and charms far,
                                above All that art can devise for the form or the lace. 5 O let me be clothed in
                                garments of these, And thankfully toil in my plain Shaker dress ; For Wisdom's bright
                                treasures which give the heart ease, And clothe me in raiment of true righteousness.
                                I'll toil for these blessings, these jewels of love, Ills patiently suffer, that cannot
                                be cured, From under the cross never seek to remove, To be by the world, or its follies
                                allured. *A Chinese woman who exhibited her small feet in this country some years since.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="K., B." TEIform="persName"/>B. K., Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="More easy than to live it, thrice..." TEIform="index"/>More easy than to live it, thrice...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">More easy than to live it, thrice, Was always found to give advice. Who plauds the great,
                                who helps the poor That spirit hate, this one adore. Love is a gem of priceless worth,
                                Aye, more than all the gems of earth.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="F., E. E." TEIform="persName"/>E. E. F.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Is war compatible with Christianity?" TEIform="index"/>Is War Compatible with Christianity?</head><p TEIform="p">How strange, that in the nineteenth century of the Christian era, there should be a doubt
                            upon this subject! but, inconsistent as it is, a majority of the professedly followers of
                            the "Prince of Peace " would, no doubt, answer unhesitatingly in the affirmative. How often
                            in religious tracts and biographies are soldiers taken as models of piety and of exemplary
                            Christian conduct, and among their other virtues they are often described as being very much
                            attached to their profession ! their horrible trade of blood, masked with the name
                            profession ! How often is a beneficent God invoked for a blessing on the murderous weapons
                            of war! Across the Atlantic we behold one of the fairest countries of Europe devastated by a
                            most needless and cruel Avar, where two millions of men endeavored to destroy each other by
                            every means which ingenuity could devise; and the melancholy results of the conflict are now
                            seen:—a desolated country,—towns laid in ashes—thousands upon thousands of men slaughtered
                            in the prime of life; with hundreds of thousands of wounded and disfigured human beings;
                            together with an immense burden of debt that will weigh heavily on their descendants for
                            ages. Friends of humanity, listen, for a voice of woe is heard through the land! The weeping
                            of desolate widows! The wail of the bereaved mother in her agony of grief,— and the pitiful
                            sobs of orphan children ! Even the victors, who, by the chance of war, are spared a
                            desolated and ravaged country, bear a heavy share in its miseries: four hundred fathers
                            killed in one regiment, in repulsing a sortie from Metz, leaving 1,070 orphan children,
                            tells a mournful tale. The Teacher, whom these warring nations profess to follow, said:
                            "Love your enemies." " Bless them that curse you." " Do good to them that hate you." "I say
                            unto you that ye resist not evil." "If a man smite thee on thy right cheek, turn to him the
                            other also." Instead of doing this, they aim the deadly riile at a brother's heart,—plunge
                            the cruel bayonet into his breast—mow their brethren down in ranks with the ponderous
                            cannon-ball, or cast their mangled bodies on the blood-stained ground with their worse than
                            diabolical .shells. What a commentary on human consistency is a battle-field,—a Christian
                            (?) battle-field! where enlightened (?) men professing to follow the gentle and loving Jesus
                            of Nazareth, meet in hundreds of thousands to tear each other limb from limb, like wild
                            beasts! What a picture! it makes the Angels weep! But, some will say, " It cannot be helped;
                            it is impossible to avoid it." Did Christ teach im- possibilities ? It has been avoided, and
                            it can be avoided. The example of William Penn and his peace-loving Quakers, for 70 years in
                            Pennsylvania,—where the government was sustained without any weapon more dangerous than the
                            constable's staff, and during which there was not one drop of Quaker blood shed, surrounded
                            as they were by powerful tribes of what have been called, " treacherous and merciless
                            savages ; " while the neighboring colonies were the theatres of Indian wars and <pb n="37" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. 37 bloody massacres—defiantly contradicts the assertion! Neither
                            soldiers nor savages will fight an unarmed peaceful people: Tecurnseh when asked why he did
                            not attack the Shakers at Busrow said: " What! attack a people who will not fight ? It would
                            be a disgrace to the name of an Indian ! " Witness again the instance recorded in history,
                            when Alexander, incensed at the Jews for refusing to violate their oath to Darius by
                            furnishing food for his army, marched to Jerusalem, with the intention of chastising them
                            severely. They went out to meet him unarmed, dressed in white, with the high-priest, Jaddus,
                            at their head. What a change was wrought in his conduct! After treating them with the
                            greatest kindness, paying marked respect to their highpriest and exempting them from the
                            payment of the seven years' tribute, he left them in the most friendly manner.
                            Non-resistance, as has been demonstrated in this and thousands of other instances, is
                            practical, politic, humanitarian and Christian; war, on the contrary, is unwise, impolitic,
                            unchristian and diabolical. We appeal to you, friends,—brothers and sisters of our great
                            human family—to unite your influence to banish from the earth this great curse of our race!
                            Let all nations see in the calamities of unhappy France, the fate that has, or will, sooner
                            or later overtake every warring nation. Let all who profess Christianity, see if their
                            practice will bear the only test of discipleship, as given by its founder. " By this shall
                            all men know that ye are my disciples: that ye have love one for another;" and let those who
                            would continue the barbarous anfi-christian practice of war, hear his last warning, which
                            has been fulfilled among the nations of the earth from that day to this: " They that take
                            the sword shall perish by the sword."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="C., W." TEIform="persName"/>W. C., Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Plain Talks, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>Plain Talks—No, 2</head><p TEIform="p">Our warfare and weapons are not carnal; but spiritual and mighty when exercised with
                            earnestness and wisdom. We are bold adventurers in a most extraordinary endeavor— overcoming
                            the world ! We have taken issue with the world; and against its allurements we mean to wage
                            the most unrelenting warfare —knowing no such word as failure. The world, against which we
                            turn our efforts, is composed of "the lusts of the flesh, of the eyes, and the pride of life
                            ! " We are charged with being contracted in our religious life working only to the
                            overcoming of the lusts of the flesh. We know this to be the root of the great tree of evil;
                            and had better work eternally here, than attempt to kill the tree of evil by pruning among
                            its branches. We find, that success in battling against the lusts of the flesh assures us of
                            that peace which humanity, generally, know not of; nor can they know until, beginning as
                            children in the school of Christ, they learn that A, B, C is self-denial to their animal
                            appetites, that have made their souls so dyspeptic that the least morsel of truthful
                            testimony against a carnal, fleshly life., afflicts them like a vomit, and they pour forth
                            the vilest thoughts, feelings and persecutions against the mediums of this testimony.
                            Thousands, while knowing the lusts of the flesh to be their greatest enemy, implore of the
                            Shakers not to destroy this god of sensuality. We find that sensuality does not pay,
                            physically nor spiritually; and that it is very unchristian in its mildest attacks—as
                            observed in marriage, etc. We do not abhor marriage— we get along with it in our warfare
                            against fleshly lusts, just as our great Captain did—by letting them severely alone! We ask
                            of Christians to do no better with them. And here the argument comes in: " It is natural to
                            desire marriage ! " So it is; and our choice is to aspire above earthly desires, to
                            inaugurate on the earth "thy kingdom come," which shuts out marriage, private property, and
                            their consequences—misery, disease, war and famine; these are of the world and belong not
                            among the resurrected ! Truly, we have taken an advanced step in a life of purity—under the
                            self-denying restraints of a celibate life—while living as spiritual Brethren and Sisters in
                            a common household— God's spiritual house ! And while the unselfdenying would feign
                            disbelieve in our accomplishment of this, and picture to themselves the horrors of " the
                            eunuch for the kingdom of heaven's sake," we assure them there is a continual increase of
                            comfort on our journey through life; that we never suffer anything, in. consequence of
                            self-denial, that will compare with their self-indulgences, even of the first nuptial
                            evening—and then, how different the results of their sufferings and of ours ! This brings an
                            increasing purity, eternal in character; that brings with it disgust, disappointment, bitter
                            anguish and soul-defilement, that grow not less with increased indulgence, but constantly
                            make wide the gulf between their souls and God ! " Oh, for a closer walk with God ! " "
                            Neanr, my God, to thee!" And while, as before intimated, some choose to disbelieve our
                            position in life, as regards our testimony against all fleshly lusts, in whatever form of
                            indulgence, we mean to advance still farther in the work of self-denial, and leave all who
                            love the world still farther in the rear. " Away from the world of fleshly lusts! " was the
                            first of seven trumpets; six more are to sound; and the worldly will observe true Shakers
                            engaging in advanced works of self-denial—progressing " from faith unto faith." Wre view the
                            habits of a worldly life—intemperance in fleshly lusts, in eating, drinking, swearing,
                            tobacco-using and fighting—to be the refusal of the soul to increase in godliness ; no-
                            thing can suppress these; but something can supplant them. And that religion is a false and
                            worthless one, that does not present its subjects with substitutes for these, that speak of
                            eternal enjoyment; that does not supplant them with food that stops that yearning for
                            something—which something is spiritual advancement, and the true remedy, resurrection of
                            life, and in our ways of life,—living as Christ lived; who neither lived in those lusts
                            which the world glory in; was not a tippler; was never seen with cigar, pipe nor quid; would
                            not fight; had good health—the result of temperance in all things. We admit the world of
                            humanity, generally, to be in our advance on the outward run; but, on the home-stretch, we
                            feel ourselves nearer our Father's and Mother's home. *</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Time is money" TEIform="index"/>"Time is Money."</head><p TEIform="p">Seated in an easy chair, last evening, after the muscles had performed their share of the
                            duties of the day, my eyes fell upon the above motto, ingeniously woven into an advertise-
                            ment. It was an incentive to industry. Summing up the spare moments that frequently slip oy
                            unimproved, I thought how much of the symmetry and beauty was lost from our ideal of perfect
                            manhood. " Time is money." We can account for the origin of so singular a proverb, when we
                            consider the fascinating influence of money on the human mind. Could three other words
                            express so much of the hearts of men ? While it speaks to us of the virtue of industry, it
                            would have us toil at Mammon's shrine ! The Angel of Wisdom lifting us upon the platform of
                            the World! We will not object to the elevation. If we are below it, we must need come up;
                            but I trust we shall not consider it the acme of human development. Sentiment is at fault if
                            it points us no higher. If it provides only for the body, it leaves a void within. Industry
                            should be one of the first lessons of life. It is the secret of growth; but if that growth
                            is too much toward materiality, it blunts the finer feelings and develops the animal rather
                            than the angel. When we Aveave our garland of mottoes to adorn the crown of Industry, we
                            will write it, by putting our hands to work and giving our heart to God: Time is moiie than
                            money.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="C., J. V." TEIform="persName"/>J. V. C.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hark, from the depths..." TEIform="index"/>Hark, from the depths...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">" Hark, from the depths!" This wail comes from Philadelphia: " I look upon the present laws
                            and relations of marriage, as the direct source of more pauperism, crime, disease, and
                            death, than rum, tobacco, war, pestilence, and famine; and I speak not at random when I say
                            this. Tobacco, rurn, and war, are chiefly male accomplishments: pestilence and famine are
                            confined to a few localities ; but marriage is nearly universal. No condition, sex, nor
                            locality where human beings exist, is exempt from the curse of this human foe ! * * * *
                            Perhaps I write too severely; if so, it is because I feel deepty that this truth is too
                            true. * * * I have been in the camp of marriage; I know" the rottenness of every fibre of
                            this gilded monster, and nothing shall shield it from my piercing shafts, until its
                            death-throes say— 1 the deed is done !' " Comments: There are thousands, who, having been
                            caught in the beautiful spider's web of marriage, feel as the above correspondent. But this
                            individual, and the majority of his sympathizers, would be among the last to live totally
                            abstinent from the gratification of their sexual appetites. The Shakers look upon marriage,
                            under Mosaic injunctions, to be honorable; but neither it nor the practice of any
                            lasciviousness is, or can be Christian. Neither Jesus, Angels of God, nor the Shakers are
                            ever afflicted with the pangs of matrimony ; neither soiled by sexual uncleanness nor
                            individual vices. *</p></div2><pb n="38" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="War between freedom and slavery" TEIform="index"/>War between Freedom and Slavery</head><p TEIform="p">FROM THE CHRISTIAN STANDARD. " Those whom Christ makes free are free iudced." Was Mother jinn
                            the first Enfranchised Woman ? Taking a view from the highest earthly standard, she was
                            truly the pioneer in the battle between Slavery and Freedom, as touching the human soul. She
                            was divinely inspired, and illuminated by the light of truth. She broke the shackles which
                            pinioned her to the affections of man on the earth plane; and by degrees arose, one fetter
                            after another being severed, and falling, which gave new impetus to hope and freedom. With
                            agony of spirit, so intense as to produce bloody perspiration, her mind being in-
                            vulnerable, she persevered with invincible courage, praying to God day and night, until she
                            triumphed. No wonder she was reduced to a skeleton, under such extreme travail for the birth
                            of freedom. In this prepared condition, the Christ Spirit proffered aid, illuminating and
                            extending the hand of sympathy, which endowed her with wisdom and power to break the
                            heaviest and strongest shackle, causing it to fall powerless. Then she arose in queenly
                            majesty; in royal grandeur! Beautiful; especially to those baptized with the Christ Spirit.
                            No powers of Earth nor Hades shall forge those fetters again. The powers of Liberty and
                            Truth triumphed. There was joy in the New Heavens, a grand celebration ! " A woman compassed
                            a man ! " " The wisdom of the wise was confounded ! " This was the commencement of a new
                            era, the beginning of the New Creation, the manifestation of the second Eve—coming forth,
                            opening the graves of conventionalism, unloosing the mantle of creeds and dogmas, which bind
                            both hands and feet. Thus untrammeled she was competent to compass man in every respect. She
                            penetrated the dark recesses of the heart; no iniquity was hid from her searching eye. Man
                            quailed and sank into insignificance before her penetrating spirit. Her love was equal to
                            her justice. Merciful, divine; forgiving her enemies, their bitter and cruel persecution,
                            their malignant slanders, scoffs and frowns. At length she reached the summit, where she
                            stood emancipated, clad in her freedom suit elevated above every sensual appetite and
                            passion—" having the light of the Sun in her countenance, the stars in her forehead, and the
                            moon under her feet." In this condition she could attract and lift mankind up to a higher
                            standard, regenerated and emancipated. And shall not her followers, who are baptized by the
                            Christ Spirit, M'ho are living the same life, reach this summit—have the same power to life
                            up humanity, and set all captives i'rec ?</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Olive" TEIform="persName"/>Olive, Har.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The fool gets mad at almost every call..." TEIform="index"/>The fool gets mad at almost every call...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The fool gets mad. at almost every call; The wise man ne'er gets mad at all. This rule is
                            simple, certain, true, Who takes offense will give one. too. I ask no greater treasure, than
                            To be at peace with God and man.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To possess emulation without envy, is a most enviable possession" TEIform="index"/>To possess emulation without envy, is a most enviable possession
                        </head><p TEIform="p">To possess Emulation without envy, is a most enviable possession.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="F., E. E." TEIform="persName"/>E. E. F.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Light and right" TEIform="index"/>Light and Right</head><p TEIform="p">Health. "It may be both interesting and profitable to notice the views and habits of
                            Swedenborg, in relation to physiology— laealth. ' Seership, as a general rule, is coincident
                            with abstemiousness, which is the directest means of putting down the body, and (by the law
                            of the balance) lifting up the soul; and, where seership is thus of itself, it leads to new
                            demands from the soul, or new exigencies of temperance. We might instance the Hindoo seers,
                            as examples of these remai'ks; or we might support them by numerous cases occurring in
                            Europe, and even at the present time; not to mention that the germs of the experience are
                            within every man's knowledge." As the man depends so much upon the dinner, and the dinner
                            upon the appetite and the self-control, it is advisable to know what was the diet of a man
                            so industrious, peaceful, and deep-eyed as Swedenborg. The following is his account of his
                            first baptism into the spiritual world : " 1 was in London, and dined late at my usual
                            quarters, where I had engaged a room, in which at pleasure to prosecute my studies in
                            natural philosophy. I was hungry, and ate with great appetite. Towards the end of the meal,
                            I remarked that a kind of mist spread before my eyes, and I saw the floor of my room covered
                            with hideous reptiles, such as serpents, toads, and the like. I was astonished, having all
                            my wits about me, and being perfectly conscious. The darkness attained its height, and then
                            passed away. I now saw a man sitting in a corner of the chamber. As I had thought myself
                            entirely alone, I was greatly frightened, when he said to me, ' Eat not so much.' My sight
                            again became dim; but, when I recovered it, I found myself alone in my room. I went home,
                            and the following night the same man appeared to me again. This time I was not at all
                            alarmed. The man said, ' I am God, the Lord, the Creator and Redeemer of the world. I have
                            chosen thee to unfold to men the spiritual sense of the Holy Scriptures. I will myself
                            dictate to thee what thou shalt write.' The same night, the world of spirits—hell and
                            heaven—was convincingly opened to me, where I found many of my acquaintance, of all
                            conditions." Again, he says: "In the middle of the day, at dinner, I heard an angel saying
                            that I should not indulge the belly too much at table ; and there clearly appeared to me, as
                            it were, a vapor exuding from the pores of my body like a mist, extremely visible, which
                            fell towards the earth where the carpet was, upon which the vapor, being collected, was
                            changed into various little worms under the table, which burnt, or flashed off, in a moment,
                            with a noise or sound. Seeing a fiery light in this vapor, and hearing a sound, I thought
                            that thus all the worms that could be generated from an immoderate appetite, were ejected
                            from my body, and thus burnt, and that I was then purified from them." From this time his
                            diet became a constant harmony and preparation of his eership. Sandel says, "He was never
                            ill; lie always enjoyed most excellent health; having scarcely ever experienced the
                            slightest indisposition, except when in states of temptation. Health is the ground which
                            great persons cultivate, whereby they exchange the light flying hours into golden usage. To
                            them it is industry represented in its power,—the human riches of time. The minute-glass
                            runs sand of centuries, when great ideas are in healthful moments. So it was with Swe-
                            denborg. The powers of his mind were matched with extraordinay strength of body. Health, in
                            its whole sense, is happiness. His life, in all respects, was one of the happiest that ever
                            fell to the lot of man. He says, 'I have had joys and happiness such as no other man, I
                            suppose, has felt in the universal world; and these both were more and more exquisite than
                            any mortal can imagine or believe.' " His biographer says, " It appears that he abstained
                            from animal food from dietetic considerations. At the same time. there dwelt in his mind a
                            vegetarian tendency, pointing towards the future, or at least, what is the same thing,
                            crying out. from the past. He writes on the subject* in his 'Arcana,'as follows: 'Considered
                            apart, eating the flesh of animals is somewhat profane. The most ancient people never, on
                            any account, eat the flesh of either beast or fowl; but lived entirely upon grain,
                            especially on wheaten bread, on fruits, vegetables, and herbs, and various kinds of milk,
                            butter, etc. It was unlawful for them to kill animals, or to eat their flesh. They looked
                            upon it as bestial, and were content with the uses and services that animals afforded them.
                            But, in process of time, when men became as cruel as wild beasts, yea, much more cruel, they
                            began to slay animals, and ate their flesh ; and, in consideration of this nature in man,
                            the killing and eating of animals were permitted, and continue to be so.' " God. His first
                            spiritual command of " Eat not so much," was placed over the portals of his study. His
                            childish supposition, that God had appeared to him in person, was <pb n="39" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            SHAKER. 39 owing to the gross physical condition of his body, the consequent dullness of his
                            faculties, and his low spiritual state, at that early period of his experience,—a fallacy
                            common to the seers and prophets of all ages, from Adam to Moses; from Moses to the modern
                            spiritual mediums; and from those mediums to the instruments in the early Shaker spiritual
                            manifestations. Subsequently, Swedenborg, like his brother, John the Revelator. became
                            disabused, and declared that " God cannot be seen in person by mortals on earth, or in the
                            heavens." He says, 14 there were angels who were sent to men, and who also spoke by the
                            Prophets; but what they spoke was not from the angels, but by them; for their state then was
                            such, that they knew no otherwise than that they were Jehovah. But, when they had done
                            speaking, they presently returned to their former state, and spoke as from themselves." This
                            is a true principle; and no human being, Jesus not excepted, has ever seen Deity. Swedenborg
                            further says, " The Patriarchal Prophets, Psalmists, and Evangelists, are not holy men ;
                            they are not even venerable, for the most part; but the voice of sacred history itself
                            generally assails them: their names are unknown in heaven. There are no saints with earthly
                            names; but only sinners, scarlet more or less. God's is all the glory. Abraham, Moses,
                            David, John, are plain mortals, like ourselves, entitled to no great consideration, when
                            their office is laid aside, and their divine insignia put off. The men after • God's own
                            heart' are only so for a time and a mission. Every one is after God's own heart for the
                            functions that he does best; holiness is not involved. The 1 chosen people of God,' were the
                            worst of people: for redemption begins at the bottom." FRAGMENTARY IDEAS. Stability of the
                            solar system.—" Though the solar system is liable to certain mutations, in the form and
                            eccentricity of its orbits, of very long periods; yet its orbits return again exactly to
                            what they originally were, oscillating between very narrow limits." "At once, by a single
                            effort of his genius, worlds innumerable, in congregated spheres, were beheld in harmonious
                            operation, without end or limit. The boundaries of the Universe, so to speak, became to man
                            at once illimitable; and the scattering goodness of the Divine hand, strewing mercies and
                            blessings amongst unnumbered worlds hitherto unseen and unknown, and unconjectured, was a
                            scene worthy of the Almighty." " The most glorious and magnificent region in the material
                            Universe,—the heaven of heavens,—formed, as Swedenborg expresses it, of innumerable heavens
                            in congregated spheres beyond or outside our own, was displayed, first to the intellectual,
                            and subsequently to the ocular vision, when one universal blaze of glory burst forth on an
                            astonished world, who beheld the Almighty traversing the in- numerable spheres with the same
                            flowing richness, beauty, and care, as is so conspicuous on this atom of a world upon which
                            we dwell." Thus, witnesses for the day, were Swedenborg and his followers, the
                            Spiritualists. For long ages, the human race had been religiously impressed, but their
                            rational faculties had been "held in durance vile." Man hungered after knowledge which
                            "State and Church" had withheld, by taking away the key of science, and substituting
                            therefor, the senseless dogmas of superstition. Light broke upon the religious world through
                            Swedenborg. Right began to be established in the religious world through Mother Ann. In due
                            time, these are now being conjoined together, and they are building up, or as Swedenborg
                            expressed it, are " forming the new Heaven "—the New Church— that will not lust after tin
                            adulterous union with the State—the New Earth—nor seek to put together what. God hath put
                            asunder.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Septimus" TEIform="persName"/>Septimus</byline></div2><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Biographical: teachings of Ann Lee" TEIform="index"/>BIOGRAPHICAL. Teachings of Ann Lee</head><p TEIform="p">(Continued.) 10. "Labor to feel the life of God in your souls; labor to make God's will your
                            will; lot it be your inheritance, 3?our treasure, your daily occupation. Labor for the good
                            of your souls, as though there were none on earth so needy of salvation as }*ourselves." 11.
                            "In dealing with humanity, endeavor to understand their temperaments, and dea' with them
                            according to their creation. Some will need the plainness and severity of the testimony to
                            bring them to a true sense of their condition; others will be saved by mercy and charity;
                            they cannot be saved in any other way. Who wins souls to Christ, must needs be wise; but
                            some never will find salvation except by feeling the judgments of God ! " 12. To one who
                            remarked that "he was ful of evil; " Mother Ann replied: " Not so; you are not full of evil,
                            for there is room in you to receive good; the conviction you feel for your sins, is good."
                            13. Some one sent Mother Ann a pair oi velvet shoes; she returned them with the remark: '¦ I
                            choose to have my feet shod with the preparation of the gospel of Christ." 14. " Eat and
                            drink with temperance. Le none abstain from food which they need; but let them not fail to
                            serve God by the strength of their food. The wicked eat and drink and consume it upon their
                            wicked desires. Ye must not do so; eat hearty and with thankfulless; then go and do the will
                            of God." 15. Some persons complaining that their bod did not satisfy their appetites, Mother
                            Ann replied: "Your bodies are not hungry; aut your souls are starving for the bread and
                            waters of life. Confess and forsake your sins; lunger after righteousness, and you shall be
                            filled to satisfaction." 1G. "Men and women can engage in the gratifications of their
                            lustful appetites in this world; but if they do not learn to crucify the flesh, it will
                            follow them into the world of spirits. Death does not destroy the passions, nor make them
                            less powerful; souls in hell feel the strength of their lusts a thousand fold stronger than
                            in this world; and finding no way to gratify them, their lust is their torment, and torments
                            them according to the proportion of its rage. "And further: they have to feel the wrath of
                            God against that filthy nature; and this torments them, even worse than their lusts. The
                            more people yield to gratify their sexual appetites, the stronger their passions grow, and
                            the more their lusts will rise in hell against them; torment will take the place of their
                            present pleasures. "I see now, in vision, souls suffering hell enough to take natural life,
                            for sins committed through generative lusts. They are bound in the prisons of suffering; and
                            their torment could be no greater, if they were in a cauldron of molten lead." 17. "Souls
                            who have had an offer of the gospel of Christ—to depart from sin and live a virgin life—but
                            who reject the offer, will go into the world of spirits and wander in deep distress looking
                            after God. I have seen some wandering, in despair of finding deliverance from the torments
                            of their sins; weeping and wailing until, to appearance they had worn gutters in their
                            cheeks! Flee, therefore, from the wrath to come, by sacrificing the causes of hell." 18.
                            "You must forsake the marriage of the flesh, or you cannot be married to the Lamb, nor have
                            any share in the resurrection of Christ." 19. "Some gifts of God are given to souls in
                            perverted nature's darkness; not because they have repented, but to lead them into a
                            repentance." Some asked: " What is repentance ? " " To leave off the commission of sin, is
                            the only repentance God accepts," said Mother Ann; "and this no one can do, only by an
                            honest and faithful confession of every sin that he has committed, to those who are already
                            saved from the sins he would repent of." 20. To some who kneeled before Mother Ann, asking
                            her blessing, she said: "Kneel not to me; kneel to God; I am only your fellow-servant. If I
                            reprove you, remember, I also love you, and desire to bring your soul nearer to my soul, and
                            nearer to the Spirit of God." *</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Shakers never accept any, nor reject any; they admit many, leaving it for the Holy Spirit to prove whether                                 they belong to their Society or not!" TEIform="index"/>The Shakers never accept any, nor reject any...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"The Shakers never accept any, nor reject any; they admit many, leaving it for the Holy
                            Spirit to prove whether they belong to their Society or not! "</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Emerson, R. W." TEIform="persName"/>R. W. Emerson</byline></div2><pb n="40" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To my youth, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>To My Youth—No. 2</head><p TEIform="p">Without watchfulness and self-examination, you cannot progress a single inch—without
                            self-examination you will stumble as you go every day; not only so, but you will be a
                            stumbling block in the way of other souls. A lack of the gift of self-examination is the
                            reason why young people need to be examined by others. They do things from an inward
                            pressure of evil. Against this pressure a cross has to be borne. And that is the reason why
                            Jesus taught hi3 disciples to bear a daily cross; and it is just the same with you to-day as
                            it was with the young disciples in Christ's day. And when he warned his disciples to watch
                            and pray, he, in the course of his labors, added another word—pray and faint not—do not give
                            up to the enemy. One of the reasons why youth do not examine themselves, is, because they do
                            not want to change. They want to remain the game kind of persons they have been—to follow
                            their own natural way, and not God's way. Now that will never do—Jesus .and his followers
                            changed—turned from their own ways— came not to do their wills. The youth who stands stiff
                            in his own will is not in a fruitful condition. Another reason why youth do not like to
                            examine themselves, is, they do not like to read the record of their own doings as written
                            on their memory—do not like to look at themselves, because they have been yielding here and
                            there, from the path of right, and so have been co-workers with Satan, and bo much under his
                            power, as to be afraid to say to him, "get thee behind me, Satan;" have not simplicity
                            enough to tell themselves and their parents the truth, and so shame the Devil. In examining
                            natural objects, men are not content with their ordinary vision ; they use helps—examine
                            things microscopically, and are much pleased to have the microscope open up something they
                            could not see with their naked eye. Now, how is it possible for any person to know himself,
                            if he will not examine himself with his own eyes. Those who do, will have the help of other
                            eyes, that see clearer and further than their own; in this way " God helps those who help
                            themselves." But those who have eyes and see not, shall wander—stumble and fall in the
                            dark—the darkness of their own will. It may be asked, how can the gift of selfexamination be
                            gained and maintained ? The answer is, by continually exercising it on all you do, by night
                            and by day. Persevere therein, till it becomes pleasant—becomes a delightful duty. Then you
                            will know for yourself, experimentally, and truly, that "Christ's yoke is easy, and his
                            burden light." I omit saying anything further on this interesting parable ; exercise your
                            own mind upon it, and gather information from others on the subject. And when you get
                            through with this parable—this beautiful casket, there are others equally beautiful. There
                            is the casket of the Fig Tree; of a grain of Mustard Seed; of a little learen; of the
                            Prodigal; of the unjust Steward; of the Beggar and the Rich Man; of the Man who thought too
                            highly of himself; of the unjust Judge; of the Man who went into a far country; of the Man
                            who planied a vineyard; of the Woman and the lost money; of the lost Sheep; of the Tares; of
                            the Shepherd and the sheepfold; of the net and the Fishes, and the Casket of the Pearl of
                            great Price. Every one of these caskets contains gems illustrative of the kingdom of heaven;
                            where lust has no place—even the uncleanness of marriage is not permitted. Blessed are those
                            who have a part in that kingdom, never to go out. I will now say a few words on the two-fold
                            life in man. Jesus said, "flesh and blood cannot inherit the kingdom of heaven." Now, all
                            the animal creation are flesh and blood; and are brought forth through the action of the
                            propensities; and we, in common with the lower animals, have the same kind of life, and the
                            same propensities; therefore, that life can have no part in heaven. Intellect, in connection
                            with our animal life, does not make it any better, nor change its nature. In addition to
                            that life, we have another life—a life, that the word of God can quicken; but no mere animal
                            can be so quickened. The Apostle said, "Ye hath he quickened, who were dead in trespasses
                            and in sins"—hath he quickened into a higher life, who were wont to live in the lusts of the
                            flesh and of the mind. And again, "if ye live after the flesh ye shall die; but if ye,
                            through the spirit, do mortify the deeds of the body, ye shall live." "And as many as are
                            led by the spirit of God, they are the sons of God," and no longer the sons of Adam. The
                            testimony of the gospel which you hear from time to time, is the testimony of life to the
                            inner man; and no soul can ever be quickened, except in obedience and subjection to it. You
                            ma)' gather from these few words an understanding which life is acceptable to God, and from
                            you to your Brethren and Sisters, and which life is not. Remembering at all times, that ye
                            cannot serve two masters. Which will ye serve? Carnal, fleshly nature, or will you strive
                            and pray that you may be quickened into a newness of life; and living the life of the
                            Angels—maintain your virgin characters—that never need to change to be eternal in character
                            ?</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Frazer, D." TEIform="persName"/>D. Frazer</byline></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">One little cherub from New Hampshire—seven years old—writes us some truths, which we are glad
                            to place before our little readers. Many long sermons have been preached, without containing
                            so much simple Shakensm. The kernel when reached, is: '•Confess and forsake sin; live
                            purely, and you are a Shaker without knowing it—regardless of your theology." Ed.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to make a shaker" TEIform="index"/>How to make a Shaker</head><p TEIform="p">To make a Shaker is to confess your sins honestly, live purely like the little spirits in
                            heaven; you must not hide your sins, because you do not like to confess them; you cannot
                            hold them forever; you will be found out before long, by the light of truth, which will urge
                            you to confess them. You cannot have your own way unless it be right; but will have to obey
                            what you are taught; you will not be allowed to be unclean, nor tell falsehoods among the
                            Shakers, without honestly confessing and repenting of them. If you do not do this, you
                            cannot make a Shaker, because the people will not bear it very long. This is true, for I
                            have been taught all this, and more. If I had room I would write you some more about it.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Gertrude" TEIform="persName"/>Gertrude, Canterbury</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To 'owe no man aught but love and good will'..." TEIform="index"/>To 'owe no man aught but love and good will'...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">To "owe no man aught but love and good will," is a fundamental principle of Shaker faith. Any
                            persons, therefore, trusting a Shaker, for longer or shorter periods, must do so at their
                            own risks, and without the sympathy of Society. None, within the precints of Shaker Society,
                            not excepting its officers, have any right to contract a debt. * Love is not lust; these two
                            are opposite. Oil and water cannot blend ; neither the generation of the earthly with the
                            resurrection of the heavenly. We cannot live fleshly lires, and at the same time be Children
                            of the Insurrection. *</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notices" TEIform="index"/>Notices</head><p TEIform="p">The address of Harvard Shakers, is " Ayer. Mass.'' The Postmaster General has established a
                            Post Office at " Shakers, Albany Co., N. Y., for which, Senator Fenton has our heartfelt
                            thanks. Inquirers are informed, that our Paper's beautiful appearance is the work of C. Van
                            Benthuysen &amp; Sons, Albany, N. Y. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="L., G. A." TEIform="persName"/>G. A. L. </byline></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker, monthly journal, devoted to the exposition of religion, acording to Shaker theology" TEIform="index"/>THE SHAKER. MONTHLY JOURNAL, DEVOTED TO THE EXPOSITION OF RELIGION, ACCORDING TO SHAKER
                            THEOLOGY.</head><p TEIform="p">Fifty Cents, Per Annum, in Advance. G. A. Lomas, Resident Editor, Shakers, Albany Co., N. Y.
                        </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Members of society" TEIform="index"/>MEMBERS OF SOCIETY</head><p TEIform="p">Appointed to ansiver Correspondents, among whom are the Board of Editors. Elder F. W. Evans.
                            Mt. Lebanon, Columbia Co., N. Y. " Issachar Bates, Shakers, N. Y. " Calvin G. Reed, Mt.
                            Morris, Livingston Co., N. Y. " Simon Mabeo, West Pittsfield, Mass. " Stoughton Kellogg,
                            Thompsonville, Conn., Shakers. " Albert Battles, Tyringham, Berkshire Co., Mass. " Wm.
                            Leonard, Ayer, Mass., Shakers. " John Whiteley, Shirley Village, Middlesex Co., Mass. "
                            Nehemiah Trull, Shaker Village, Merrimack Co., N. H. " Henry Cummings, Enfield, Grafton
                            Co., N. H. " John B. Vance. Alfred, Shakers, York Co., Me. " Alonzo Gilman, West Gloucester,
                            Cumberland Co., Me., Shakers. " O. C. Hampton, Union Village, WarronCo., O., Shakers. " Ezra
                            Sherman, Preston, Hamilton Co., Ohio, Shakers. " Stephen Ball, Dayton, Shakers, Ohio. "
                            George Runyon, Pleasant Hill, Mercer Co., Ky. " J. R. Eades, South Union, Logan Co., Ky. "
                            J. S. Prescott, Cleveland, Ohio, Shakers. </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Publications" TEIform="index"/>PUBLICATIONS.</head><p TEIform="p">Christ's First and Second Appealing Dunlavy's Manifesto ... Millennial Church . Compendium of
                            Shakerism - Three Discourses on United Interests Tracts free, where postage is paid. $1 25 1
                            25 1 00 0 50 0 50</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>