<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ss0412" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">Shaker and Shakeress</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Society</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Mount Lebanon, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">4</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">12</biblScope><date value="18741201" TEIform="date">December 1874</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">89-96</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="4" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="89" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="12" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!-- 
                        <p>Vol. IV. No. 12. F. W. EVANS, Edttor. PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETY Lebanon, Col. Co. TST. Y. December, Sixty Cents
                        per annum.</p>
                    --><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker theology" TEIform="index"/>SHAKER THEOLOGY</head><p TEIform="p">" Of the increase of his government and peace there shall be no end."—Is. ix. 57- Shaker
                            theology is the logical arrangement of all mundane and super-mundane facts, con- stituting a
                            system of ideas, subject to the law of evolution — change. To it new facts may be added, old
                            facts be revised or proved to be no facts at all. Shaker Creed is the present formula of
                            belief —the orthodoxy of to-day—generally accepted, for the time being, by the leading minds
                            of the order. The eye of faith looks into the interior of things, by the light of revelation
                            from spheres invisible to the earthly eye. The path of the right doer grows brighter and
                            brighter toward perfect daylight from the sun of righteousness. A declaration of faith in
                            certain doc- trines, by a Shaker elder or member, is an expression of his or her own
                            theology, or creed. Only as it commends itself to the understand- ing and conscience of any
                            member of the order, is it binding, except upon the one who utters it; and he or she may
                            increase with the increase of God. Oneness we all pray and labor for. Those points, upon
                            which we are agreed, are as the foundation stones of a building — not to be moved. So much
                            of the second temple is builded. The spirit of truth is, with us, stronger than the spirit
                            of theological controversy— stronger than the gates of hell, which, in Babylon, have
                            prevailed against all her sects and churches, not excepting the Churches of the Witnesses.
                            From the Constantine to the Quaker Church, from Dr. Beecher to Dr. Swing, theological
                            controversy has taken peace from the old Earth and from the old Heavens. All is turned to
                            blood, under Church and State gov- ernments — governments in Christendom. It commenced with
                            shedding the blood of Jesus. Then the blood of the martyrs flowed like a river, down through
                            the ages, until humanity, in its highest form of development, was drunk with blood — was
                            either killing, or being killed, in theological or secular wars — patri- ots, heroes and
                            soldiers, in battle array, with garments rolled in blood, destroyed the earth. Peace was
                            thus taken from the human family, until their most sacred, refined, religious emo- tions
                            were tinctured with horrid conceptions of the atoning blood of Jesus. Belief was life or
                            death, justification or damnation, temporal and eternal. By faith — Belief alone — souls
                            were saved, or lost. Error, in doctrine, was fatal to all hopes of salvation. Belief, in a
                            given propo- sition, was voluntary, not the effect of evi- dence — of demonstration.
                            Theology and science were implacable enemies. They, who killed the body to save the soul,
                            were doing God service — were loving their neighbors as themselves. They were inflicting
                            temporal suffering to rescue souls — obstinate heretics — from sufferings of eternal
                            duration. Thus did doctrinal error — doctrines of devils — produce its practical results —
                            ceaseless mur- ders. Shaker Theology is exempt from doctrinal controversy — the gate of and
                            into the Hells — holding that light and truth are sown for the righteous, who are compelled
                            to believe right, just so far and fast as they do right; because belief is the result of
                            evidence — demonstration — not subject to the will, being involuntary. Therefore, the Gates
                            of Hell have prevailed against the seven churches of the 1260 years of apostacy — the church
                            of Jesus, the Church of the Apostles, the Gentile Church of Peter, the Nicene Church of Con-
                            stantine, the Church of Luther and Calvin, and the conglomerate Infidel, Quaker, Catholic,
                            Protestant Church of America — but the Gates of Hell will never prevail against the Church
                            built upon the Rock of Revelation, past and present; and this is the foundation upon which
                            the Church of Christ's Second Appearing is being built. It possesses no final creed, but,
                            like the Bible, its " theology " is subject to per- petual, everlasting " revision," until
                            the Christ Spirit shall have led it into all truth, through Revelation — the Rock on which
                            the Church is founded. Then shall the Peace Makers have Peace, in leaving each soul free,
                            not only to speculate and reason out, but to work out its own theol- ogy, agreeable to the
                            Christ saying: " If any man or woman will do the works, he or she shall know and understand
                            the doctrine." Henceforth the faith, which works by love and purifies the heart — first
                            pure, then peace- able— shall take precedence of all Shaker Theology.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life thoughts" TEIform="index"/>LIFE THOUGHTS</head><p TEIform="p">Man being brought into the world under the influences and by the principles of the genera-
                            tive order, knows no life higher than, and com- prehends nothing else for justification, but
                            the natural order, until his senses are reached and his mind becomes enlightened by
                            ministrations from the resurrection heavens. Then convic- tion begins to find a seat in the
                            soul; and as it is treated, man rises or falls. Then com- mences the education that develops
                            manhood and capacitates him to an equality with angels. His understanding becomes enlarged
                            and progression is his life-thought. His soul is touched as with fire, his reason is called
                            to action, and from the light he accepts or rejects, justification or condemnation becomes
                            his reward, corresponding with volition. From the influx of light from the heavenly world,
                            he is, by induction, brought to a knowl- edge of the principles which introduce love and the
                            peaceful elements of Christ, the prince of love and peace — the principles which condemn
                            hate and ignore war and strife — which introduce regeneration — the resurrec- tion order —
                            and condemn the sensual carnal life — which introduce community of interest and condemn
                            selfishness, arrogance and that spirit which would give to one an advantage over another.
                            Heeding these ministrations from the Christ sphere, he becomes developed in the Christ life,
                            where the associations and relations are those of a common brotherhood and sisterhood, in
                            the whole economy of life — where " they buy and sell as though they possessed not" — where
                            "they use this world as not abusing it" — where " they that have wives be as though they had
                            none " — where "the fashion of this world passeth away." Here, finding an element they
                            become, in this life, children of the resurrection (Christ), and are " accounted worthy to
                            obtain that world and the resurrection from the dead " — they " neither marry nor are given
                            in marriage, neither can they die any more" — sin, the cause of death being taken away — for
                            they are equal unto the angels, and are the chil- dren of God, being children of the
                            resurrec- tion. In this relation, there is " one faith," that of Jesus ; " one Lord," the
                            God of the universe; " and one Baptism," that of the holy spirit. Query. Is that people to
                            be found ? Answer. Investigate Shakerism; learn the lives of its true members, and satisfy
                            yourselves. Relig- ion, that will not bear investigation, is not worth possessing ; and if
                            the lives of religious professors will not bear examination, they are not profited by
                            religion.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName"/>Elder Abm. Perkins, Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christ in us" TEIform="index"/>CHRIST IN US</head><p TEIform="p">In the passage, " Except Christ be in you, etc.", we learn two important lessons from
                            biblical scripture. First: The characteristics of the Christ; secondly, the condition of
                            repro- bates. Our ante and anti-christian educations have left much for us to unlearn in the
                            school of the New Creation. That which saved Jesus from being reprobate, was the entrance
                            into his soul, and its permanent residence there, of the Christ. This Christ is not an
                            individual- ity — not a personal being. We have erron- eously been taught, that whenever
                            Christ is mentioned, Jesus is intended; and that this beautiful appendage is only applicable
                            to <pb n="90" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 9O him. So, have we been taught, that heaven is a peculiar locality,
                            instead of being a condi- tion of the soul. The law of impenetrability, will not permit two
                            or more things to occupy one and the same place — where Christ is, else cannot be. The same
                            philosophy will not ad- mit, of one person or thing being in two or more places at one and
                            the same time. Christ may be in millions, at one and the same time ; and then, these are not
                            reprobates. What is Christ ? It is a power, emanating from God to humanity; and
                            transmissible from us, to other apostles of the same life. Upon whom this emanation rests,
                            to them is given power to rise superior to themselves, and to become sons and daughters of
                            God. Herein, by the power of Christ, are Christians saved from their temptations to commit
                            sin. It is, to them, " the power from God unto their salvation." With it, they will travail
                            — progress from the evil and good of the past, to an exceeding right- eousness. The gospel
                            has called us to come up higher, into new conditions of life. It has taken us "for better";
                            not "for worse"; and if we do not thus travail, the absence of Christ is ap- parent, and we
                            are reprobates. Let us learn and experience, that Christ is a saving power, not a person.
                            Let us manifest the salvation of this power to others, by impartation. As the disciples
                            became Christs, and did impart the power of salvation over every human weakness; so, in this
                            era of the new creation, let the same " Christ in us" be exercised. And let us progress from
                            the infantile class of the Christ School, having learned the a. b. c. of salvation from
                            gross sins and sensual predilections, " let us leave erroneous ideas of Jesus, and go on
                            unto perfection." We can never grow in truth, until we perceive that it is as really in our
                            power to become Christs, as it was the province of Jesus. And then, there will be no mixed
                            mists of uncer- tainty regarding this important principle. Then will Daniel Christ, Ann
                            Christ, and Christ attached to other Christian or Jewish names, declare the same power
                            intended by Jesus Christ.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/>Elder G. A. Lomas, Watervliet, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Geo. Francis Train—what he is not" TEIform="index"/>Geo. Francis Train—what he is not
                        </head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Geo. Francis Train, Esq. : I see by your article in the Shaker and Shakeress, that..." TEIform="index"/>Geo. Francis Train, Esq. : I see by your article in the Shaker and Shakeress, that...                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Thomsonville, Connecticut, September 30, 1874" TEIform="index"/></dateline><p TEIform="p">[From the Toledo Sun.] <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">GEO. FRANCIS TRAIN—WHAT HE IS NOT. Thomsonville, Ct., September 30,1874. Geo.
                                        Francis Train, Esq. : I see by your article in the Shaker and Shakeress, that
                                        you have seen some of the light and grandeur of the doctrines lived by the
                                        Shakers in America. You will be, I know, a mighty and valuable knight in the
                                        cause. You have every reason to believe a reformation in theology close at hand.
                                        All the signs of the times point to this work. God will bless you. No man has a
                                        right to be a reformer until he is reformed himself. You have chosen the true
                                        way. I want to tell you my experience in a few words : A few weeks since ] came
                                        to this Shaker village, and I was much impressed by their life. I finally
                                        received light such as you have got, and it seemed to open a new world to me of
                                        which I never thought it possible for mortals to know. Now I earnestly desire to
                                        be with you as soon as you commence to begin laying these mighty truths before
                                        the people. I have one lecture all ready now. I want to be enrolled as a private
                                        in this mighty battle. I will await orders from any direction, if the orders are
                                        only Forward I should like to go with you if you commence soon, as one of
                                        your^spiritual staff. You may remember we met on board the steamship Atlantic in
                                        1871, where you came to the rescue of Elde Evans and Mr. Peebles when the clergy
                                        gave them the cold shoulder, as among those who gave reci tations in the saloon.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Toledo sun" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit></p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dickson, James H." TEIform="persName"/>James H. Dickson</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="G. F. Train's reply" TEIform="index"/>G. F. Train's reply
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Miller's Bath Hotel, 41 West 26th Street 1, October 2, 1874 " TEIform="index"/></dateline><p TEIform="p">G. F. TRAIN'S REPLY <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Miller's Bath Hotel, 41 W. 26th St. 1 New York, October 2, 1874. j NOT A
                                        SHAKER. James H. Dickson, Esq. : Elder Evans and the Shakers invited me to be
                                        present at their Social Gathering (I believe the only outsider ever asked), and
                                        our affinities are strong on diet, exercise, hygiene, sexual conti- nence,
                                        abstention from poisonous stimulants, freedom from bigotry, fanaticism,
                                        superstition, and in bold advocacy of great truths. J am not yet a Shaker. NOT A
                                        MOBMAN. Brigham Young sent his son, Brigham, Junior, Congressman Canon, and
                                        another elder, as a delega- tion to my cell in the Tombs (where I was incar-
                                        cerated by the Beecher ecclesiastical tribunal for sublishing his impeachment in
                                        Bible quotations two years in advance of the New York journals), to assure me
                                        that the Mormons were with me to a nan, and a woman too, and I indorse his
                                        temper- ance, frugality, thrift, enterprise, independent thought, in
                                        establishing a colony free from asylums, jails, poor-houses, gambling hells, rum
                                        shops and aouses of prostitution. Yet I am not a Mormon. NOT A CHRISTIAN. I
                                        never drink, smoke, swear, lie, cheat, steal, fornicate; never back-bite, make
                                        pastoral visits, or wish I was dead; never introduced "nest-hiding " into the
                                        Christian fold, and have always observed all the noble precepts taught by all
                                        good men; have read the Bible from my youth upward, only to despise the morals
                                        of its prophets, David, Solo- man and Lot; I do not believe it possible by any
                                        act of mine that I could injure my fellow-man; am always happy; never
                                        discontented — living in the perpetual sunshine of an eternal present. Yet lam
                                        not a Christian. NOT AN INFIDEL. I rejoice in the brains and intellectuality of
                                        Vol- taire, Kousseau, Hume, Gibbon, Paine. Yet I am not an Infidel. NOT A PAGAN.
                                        I like Democritus, Lucretius, Euripides, Epicte- tes, Alcibiades, Aristotle,
                                        Plato and Pliny, but as I do not believe in immortality, I am not a Pagan. NOT A
                                        SCIENTIST. I like Newton, Davy, Bacon, Cuvier, Comte, Spinola, Herschell, Mill,
                                        Darwin, Huxley, Tyndall, Spencer. Yet 1 am not a Scientist. NOT A SPIRITUALIST.
                                        I admire the morals of Confucius, Buddha, Brahma, Moses, Christ, Zoroaster,
                                        Mahomet, Swe- denborg, and other ancient and modern Spiritual- ists. I can
                                        memorize the faces, forms and charac- ters of departed relatives and friends. I
                                        can respect Davis, Wilson, Peebles, Mansfield, Dake, Slade, Foster, Hume, the
                                        Eddies. I can imagine some grand, undeveloped power lying beneath all this
                                        slate-writing, mind-reading, table-turning, spirit-acting that agitates the
                                        public. I am not yet a Spiritualist. THE PSYCHOLOGIC LETTER IN THE SUN. All
                                        these show what I am not. What I am all the world will soon know. So I answer
                                        your kind note by handing you my letter in the Sun to-day, and enclosing yours
                                        to Elder Evans, the champion Shaker of Mt. Lebanon, and the lion of the fold of
                                        Judah, who so astonished the priests on board the Atlantic, and the press at St.
                                        George's Hall in London, who ought to invite you to deliver your first gun at
                                        the headquarters of the disciples of Ann Lee, in Massachusetts, or join him at
                                        the com- ing convention of the Shakers in Steinway Hall November 22.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Toledo sun" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit></p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Train, George Francis" TEIform="persName"/>George Francis Train</byline></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Is not friend Train a representative of one of the ten Horns..." TEIform="index"/>Is not friend Train a representative of one of the ten Horns...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Is not Friend Train a Representative of one of the ten Horns —Powers — that grow out of
                                the Beast They hated the Great Mother and her Brood oi Harlot Daughters —Church and
                                State Organiza tions — stripped her naked and burned her with fire—Truth — for God has
                                put it into their heart to do His Will. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/>Editor</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Philosophy of the oven" TEIform="index"/>PHILOSOPHY OF THE OVEN</head><p TEIform="p">The use of heat, to increase the digestibilit; and savor of food, is an art exclusively human
                            The highest order of animals below man ha not been entrusted with fire. Baking, or roast ing
                            must have preceded broiling. A shallow hole in the ground, paved with small stones is still
                            in use as an oven. Sarah, of Patriarchal times, when asked to mead three measures of meal,
                            and make cakes on the hearth, no doubt her oven was a flat, lot stone. Her cakes were a sort
                            of Graham wafer, a kind of wheaten hoe cake, and was he unleavened bread of the ancients. It
                            is )y far the most palatable of any form of un- eavened bread. Of all the new forms of
                            xread, none surpass it, not even the gems ; it s not hard, but it requires considerable
                            nias- ication. The first improvement on the hot stone oven, was a jar-shaped cavity in the
                            earth, lined with cement, in which fire was built, then came the Cottage oven. The elevation
                            of this hollow structure to a convenient height, may be re- garded as an important step in
                            the history of saking. The ovens of private families are all of this type, and the only
                            improvements made, lave been in the direction of saving fuel. This oven has one inherent
                            defect—from the moment the dough is put in, it begins to cool. The oven, with continuous
                            heat, we owe to a native of Woburn, Mass.—Benjamin Thomp- son. He was a wise and humane man.
                            His discovery of the nature of heat, and its appli- cation to useful purposes, rank him as
                            one of the most honorable of men. He is best known as Count Rumford. His oven was of iron,
                            and heated from without. The dough, at first, was subjected to heat to distend it and
                            partially cook it, at the proper moment he introduced air so hot as to brown the bread About
                            twen- ty-five years ago, the French applied this mode to a brick oven, maintaining a
                            regulated tem- perature. There is an oven known as the Vienna oven, to which two important
                            additions are made, one to admit steam, so as to maintain a moist atmosphere down to the
                            last few minutes of the baking, when an intense heat is thrown into the oven so as almost
                            instantly to redden a very thin crust. The bread of Vienna is probably the best of breads,
                            neatness and clean- liness are observed in preparing the yeast and dough. The oven is
                            surrounded with air heated to about a temperature of 380°—168 de- grees hotter than boiling
                            water. The ideas involved in this mode of baking are first, the steam saturates the air of
                            the oven with mois- ture and retards evaporation from the loaf, during the early part of the
                            baking." When the loaf has attained its fullest distension, and is penetrated by myriads of
                            minute pores, the steam is shut off, a side door is then opened, and an intense blaze is
                            flashed into the oven, giving to the loaf a delicate red crust, having a flavor most
                            grateful to the palate. This part of the operation is brief, and watched through a glass
                            door. Bread, fresh from the oven, should never be covered up ; on the contrary, it is
                            improved by exposure to a current of fresh air. In refer- ence to airing, thick loaves are
                            not so good as thin ones. The bread of continental Europe is excel- lent ; that of England,
                            less so; that of this country, is of the lowest quality. To improve the quality of the
                            staff" of life, among our peo- ple is the object of this paper. Some knowledge of chemistry
                            is necessary to raise breadstuff's from the soil. I venture to state, thatjthere is more
                            ignorance of chemical law manifested in the garden and on the farm than in the bake room. In
                            either, there are rich fields to be explored, and benefits to be gathered. Chemists have
                            thrown some light on the subject before us. They say that there are different kinds of
                            fermentation, one kind converts the starch (starch is not soluble), into dextrine and sugar,
                            these are soluble. Too much fermentation converts the sugar into an acid, and makes sour
                            bread ; the first develops an agreeable savor. The second spoils the bread, hence the
                            necessity to arrest fermenta- tion before acidity sets in. How acidity oper- ates will
                            hereafter be shown ; also, the proper temperature to be maintained in the treatment of
                            dough. In converting starch into dextrine —into sugar—carbonic acid gas is formed. This gas
                            swells up the loaf and fills it with little holes. If fermentation be suffered to pro- ceed
                            beyond the formation of this gas, and runs into acidity, it will break down the glu- ten,
                            and the loaf will be liable to collapse— become heavy and sodden. To make good bread, good
                            flour is neces- SHAKER <pb n="91" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKEEES8. 91 sary. The next thing is to have
                            good yeast. No sour yeast should ever be used. There is given a recipe for making yeast and
                            bread from the highest authority in this state (Massachu- setts). Boil, with the skins on,
                            enough of pota- toes to make a quart when mashed; peel the potatoes, and mash them to
                            fineness,-then mix, intimately with them, one pint of flour, and stir the whole to an
                            emulsion, with the water in which the potatoes were boiled ; cool the product to about 80°,
                            and add half a pint of the best baker's yeast, and a table-spoonful of brown sugar. Set the
                            mixture aside and main- tain a temperature of 80°, till it works well. Of this yeast, take
                            half a pint, to seven pounds of flour, mixed with three pints of water, at 80°. If the
                            weather be cool, warm the flour too. Knead well, and set aside to rise in a tempera- ture of
                            80°, till the full size is attained ; then put the loaves in the oven heated to not less
                            than 450°. Keep the loaves covered with stiff paper, till the dough is fully raised ; then
                            remove the paper and permit the browning to take place. The larger the loaves, the hotter
                            should be the oven. Bread has, sometimes, an agreeable nutty savor, acceptable to everybody.
                            Again, there is bread destitute of that aroma. To secure the former condition, first, have
                            good flour; second, use no more water than is necessary ; third, knead thoroughly—till
                            flakey ; fourth, bake well; fifth, cool it off in a current of fresh air; sixth, see that
                            the yeast is all right. The foregoing is affectionately dedicated to all the young sisters
                            in the gathering order, at Mount Lebanon and at Canaan, by their friend,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Fraser</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Village, Shirley, Massachusetts, October 23, 1874" TEIform="index"/>Shaker, Village,
                            Shirley, Mass., ) October 23, 1874</head><p TEIform="p">Beloved Elder Frederick and Brother Daniel : The foregoing is the fruit of some research, and
                            though condensed to a few pages, they but meagrely represent the labor bestowed on the
                            subject. I have thrown the matter into its present form trusting, thereby, that its
                            efficiency may be increased. Herewith accept my love. I bless all the Elders in your lot,
                            for their many labors of love, and pray that you all may be supported to bear against the
                            pressure, within and with- out, brought to bear upon your spirits, I sym- pathize with you.
                            Do us the favor to accept the love of this humble family. We are happy in the assurance that
                            when you are praying for the Household of Faith, we are included. Our love to all the burden
                            bearers and to all the beloved brethren and sisters, and in a special manner to Brother J.
                            Shaw and to the aged sisters.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="F., Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel F.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Little things" TEIform="index"/>LITTLE THINGS</head><p TEIform="p">Beloved Youth in Zion — Do not despise the important lessons that little things teach, and
                            think they are of no consequence — soci- ally considered. Life, and great things, are made
                            up of little things, and little things often lead to great results. No one can be guilty of
                            great offenses, who has not been accustomed to committing what he or she regards as " little
                            errors." Words are little things, but they sometimes strike hard. You wield them so easily,
                            that you are apt to forget their hidden power. Fitly spoken, they fall like the dew, the
                            sun- shine, and the fertilizing rain ; but, when un- fitly, like the frost, the hail, and
                            the desolating tempest*! Some youths speak as they feel, or think, without calculating the
                            force of what they say ; and then seem surprised if any one is offended. Springs are little
                            things, but they are the source of large streams. A helm is a little thing, but how evenly
                            it governs the course of the largest ship. Nails are little things, but they hold together
                            the largest buildings. A seed is a little thing, and may be buried a thousand years, and
                            hereafter spring into life, and become a great plant. The coral worms, tenants of the ocean,
                            are little things, but they create more important changes than the whales. As little drops
                            of water make up the rivers, and rivers form the sea, so, the " little habits " of
                            wrong-doing, make up the ocean of wrong in your whole lives. In a word, little things make,
                            or unmake you all; they are the true seeds of character, for they more than make up, by
                            their number, what they seem to lack in individual impor- tance ; and you might as well
                            plant the seeds of noxious weeds, and not expect them to grow, as to cherish " little vices
                            " and not calculate on their increase, or as reasonably hope to see the firm and noble oak,
                            where no acorns were ever planted, as hope for success in spiritual progress, where the
                            seedlings of a thousand little habits of virtue and purity, have not first been carefully
                            nourished.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt, Enfield, Conn.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Union" TEIform="index"/>UNION</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Editors — My emotions are deeply stirred by the unselfish interest and conse- crated
                            labor of soul and body, you put forth, to promote this most glorious cause. I hail our
                            little monthly as a messenger of light, to break the spell of monotony, furnish deeper
                            thought and elevate our aspirations. I appreciate the necessity of union in the great work
                            whereunto we are called. Herein is our strength. As Christ and the Father and Mother are
                            One, even so are Their Children — All their Children be one — No domestic un- kindliness.
                            Looking out, from my Shaker home, upon the broad expanse of earth and its inhabitants, what
                            do I see? Babylon—Mixture—Con- fusion. Viewing my dear Elders, Sisters and Breth- ren— their
                            aspirations all centering in a life of Virgin Purity — I exclaim, Blessed Dear Gospel
                            Relation ! Your Life shall be my Life ! your joys, my joys, and your sorrows, my sor- rows.
                            Twenty-four years ago, then a mere youth, I came, from the great metropolis, to this Holy
                            Mountain. Great was the change t— from the great city of turmoils and unmentionables, to the
                            peaceful, serene and innocent. O that all could comprehend and appreciate the beauty and
                            excellence of the higher life f Though young, I found the first principles more than child's
                            play. It was not to merely walk up to the Altar and receive the sprink- ling, nor to be
                            plunged into the water and come out the same old sinner. I was baptised in the Holy Fire of
                            Truth — Confessed my sins, one by one, as I committed them, and began the New Life — the
                            Resurrection. I began to feel that I could handle the things of God with clean hands, and
                            sing his praises with pure lips. The bands of death were broken. Transported to Elysian
                            fields, I could join the Ransomed of the Lord, chant their sacred songs, and go forth in "
                            the dances of them that make merry." God met me in mercy. I accepted the in- vitation— the
                            call. I rejoice in my deliver- ance from the thralldom of sin. My love for a life of purity
                            grows stronger and stronger. " Upward and Onward " is inscribed on my Banner. Dear Elder
                            Frederick — With the above, please accept largely of the Love, of Elders, Brethren and
                            Sisters, for yourself and all associated with you in spreading the joyful tidings of Truth —
                            Love that can be expanded and solidified— sweeter and sweeter, and better, the more it is
                            mixed and extended.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Barrett, Andrew" TEIform="persName"/>Andrew Barrett, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Philadelphia, October 20, 1874" TEIform="index"/>Philadelphia, Oct. 20th, 1874</head><p TEIform="p">Elder Frederick Evans : Dear Friend and Brother : — I have been thinking of writing to thee,
                            for some time past. When thee was here we had some con- versation about the peculiar views
                            and testi- monies of the Shaker fraternity. I have been for a long time satisfied that there
                            is great need of reform in regard to the sexual rela- tions among mankind. Personally, I
                            think the highest condition is that in which a man and woman can live together in all the
                            free- dom and purity of a true marriage, and be entirely above, not only sexual intercourse.
                            but all desire for it. I have been aiming for this, and am conscious of approaching such a
                            state. I fully accept the truth of the declara- tion of Jesus, " That he who looks upon a
                            woman, to lust after her, hath already com- mitted adultery in his heart." I am well aware
                            that there are persons whose presence produces more or less sexual excitement, and as a
                            sensitive person I have learned that it is better to avoid such persons. I was much
                            attracted to thee while thee was here, and am much interested in thy writings. Thy letter in
                            the Journal last week was gratifying to me. I wish there were more who could appre- ciate
                            the high standard of your people. My position as a physician with considerable practice, and
                            as a prominent spiritualist, occu- pies all my time, and yet I am glad to know of your
                            movements. My position is that sex- ual intercourse for the propagation of the species is
                            justifiable for those who are upon the proper plane to carry it out; but for mere
                            gratification, and especially after the time for that function to be carried on, I have no
                            doubt it is a very great injury to man and woman, and that the powers wasted in that
                            direction would, if preserved and turned in the right direction, give to the world many more
                            beau- tiful, intellectual and spiritual truths. Wishing thee and thy friends all success, I
                            am very truly thy friend and brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Child, Henry T." TEIform="persName"/>Henry T. Child, M. D., 634 Race Street</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, September 1, 1894" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, Sept. 1,1874</head><p TEIform="p">Charles and Amanda Deyo — Esteemed Friends : I hope my absence from your gath- ering will not
                            be noticed. My spirit is with you in the good cause of Peace. Of the Seven Seals, which the
                            Lamb opened, the first was a White Horse — Innocence and Peace. The rider had, for his
                            weapon, a Bow, and a Crown, as a sign of victory. Revelation was the Power. This was the
                            first Church, founded by the Apostles. For three hundred years, this Church denounced War.
                            When the Second Seal was opened, a Church was founded, of which Constantine was the head—a
                            Red Horse, signifying Blood. The rider took Peace from the Earth — that they should kill one
                            another. Constantine intro- duced war into the Christian system. It is there yet. The Moon —
                            Church and State governments — was turned to blood. Is it not so to-day ? Is there any hope
                            for peace, until all theology is purged from our Statutes — all Sunday laws and every form
                            of Priestcraft, and Woman is installed Human, as complete as Man — endowed with the same
                            inalienable right, to make Laws, and execute them. Lay not the flattering unction to your
                            Souls, that any Male Government will be a Peace government — Males will fight. Not until the
                            raw material is so far wrought up into Manhood, that the Man yields might to right, and
                            ceases to hold Woman as a Slave, can She become the medium of Heavenly Truth to him. When
                            Redeemed Woman rules the Souls of Men, as absolutely as heretofore the un- redeemed women
                            have ruled men's bodies, there will be peace. Dear Friends — Peace be with you. You will
                            meet a little company of our Brethren and Sisters. As a delicate and appropriate expression
                            of the welcome, we know you feel, you may, during their sojourn, practice a little more self
                            denial than is your wont. Dress plainly. Eat plain food. Be what you seem to be, and seem to
                            be what you are — that our countries may join. Please excuse the simple plainness of your
                            friend.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div2><pb n="92" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Buddha and Jesus" TEIform="index"/>[For the Shaker and Shakeress.] BUDDHA AND JESUS</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Peebles, J. M." TEIform="persName"/>J. M. PEEBLES</byline><p TEIform="p">The Buddhists of Asia consider Sakya Muni Gotama Buddha a much greater Saviour than Jesus of
                            Nazareth ; because, say they, the lat- ter, born in poverty, a carpenter's son, sought —
                            upon Jewish authority — to enthrone him- self as king; while Gotama Buddha, a king's son,
                            laid aside the prospective crown, hum- bled himself, walking the companion of beg- gars,
                            that he might break down caste; thus enabling him to more fully reach and en- lighten the
                            lower classes of humanity. Gotama Buddha died 543 B. C. Buddhists number in China, Ceylon,
                            Siam, Burmah and other oriental countries 170,000,000. And while the most numerous body of
                            religionists on the globe, they have never been known to persecute. Their teachers renounced
                            the world, and through fasting, prayer and pen- ance, sought to subjugate the lower animal
                            nature to the higher. In preaching, Buddha continually magnified the " wheel of the law" —
                            the four great principles. I. There is sorrow, want, pain. II. Examining 1he source of pain,
                            he found it to be selfish desire. III. Pain was destroyed by regulating the natural demands
                            of life, and destroying selfish desire by self-control. IV. The means of destroying it in
                            the sense of extirpation, were meditation, self-abnega- tion, and the practice of every
                            virtue. A Brahmin accusing Gotama Buddha of idling away his time, neither sowing nor reap-
                            ing, was met with this reply: " I do plough, and sow, reaping thence fruit that is
                            immortal." Where are your implements, Gotama ? ask- ed the Brahmin. " My plough is wisdom ;
                            my field is the law; the seed I sow is purity ; the weeds I clear away are the cleavings to
                            life ; my work, attention to the precepts of the spirit; and my harvest, Nirvana — eternal
                            peace 1" Among the beautiful teachings of Buddha and his disciples were these : "In a
                            corrupt world each ought to be a lotus without a spot." " So long as the desire of man
                            toward woman is not subdued, so long is his mind in bondage." " Sin will come back upon the
                            sinful, like fine dust thrown against the wind." " Master thyself, so mayest thou teach
                            others; and easily tame them after having tamed thyself." " Let us live happily, free from
                            greed among the greedy — happily, though we call nothing our own." " Better than ruling the
                            world is the reward of the first step in virtue." " Of all the lamps lighted in Buddha's
                            hon- or, one only, brought by a poor woman, lasted through the night." " Not even a rod, not
                            Maria, nor Brahma, could change into defeat the victory of man over himself." Brahmins and
                            Buddhists bearing much the relation to each other as Jews and Christians, agree in
                            considering Christian nations ex- ceedingly inconsistent and wicked — eating the flesh of
                            dead animals — drinking intoxi- cating liquors — sleeping several in the same bed — engaging
                            in the " unfruitful works of darkness " — in religious persecutions — in bloody wars; and
                            all, in the name of Jesus, the Prince of Peace ! The Brahmins of India and the Buddhists of
                            China seriously contemplate sending mis- sionaries through Australia, England, America and
                            other Christian nations to enlighten and imbue them with these divine principles taught by
                            Brahm, Confucius, Gotama, Buddha, Jesus Christ, and other great inspired souls. " Ex Oriente
                            Lux /" Will not the Shaker commu- nities of America heartily second the efforts of those
                            noble " heathen " ? It seems that this missionary movement has already been initia- ted in
                            Australia. The Weekly Queensland Advertiser has the following: <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">"At a numerous and influential meeting of the Chinese residents in Melbourne, it
                                    was re- solved, in view of the deplorable paganism which prevails, to establish a
                                    mission in Mel- bourne, Victoria, to bring its benighted inhabi- tants to a
                                    knowledge of Confucius and of the pure morality which he taught. Careful in- quiries
                                    and prolonged observations have con- vinced the promoters of this movement that the
                                    population of this Colony is sunk in the grossest idolatry, and that they worship
                                    med- als of gold and silver, stamped with the por- trait of the reigning monarch.
                                    Certain tem- ples, called banks, are erected as the shrines of these pocket deities;
                                    and so abject is the condition of thousands of idolators, that they not only adore
                                    gods of gold and silver, but they also worship those human beings who possess the
                                    largest collection of them. Desir- ous of reciprocating the zealous efforts of
                                    British missionaries in China, the Chinese residents in Melbourne purpose to send
                                    Eng- lish-speaking and highly educated Mandarins into the Metropolis and country
                                    towns of Aus- tralia with a view of weaning their inhabi- tants, if possible, from
                                    the degrading worship of that god who bears the name of Mammon. Our sacred books
                                    tell us, ' Contentment fur- nishes constant joy. Much covetousness constant grief.
                                    To the contented even pover- ty is joy. To the discontented even wealth is a
                                    vexation.' Now, we perceive that among the idolators and pagans calling themselves
                                    Christians there is much covetousness and no contentment. Therefore, we desire as
                                    fellow- beings created by the same Divine Power, to bring our Victorian and
                                    Australian brethren to a knowledge of the truth, as it is in Confu- cius, and
                                    convert them from the error of their ways."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Weekly Queensland advertiser" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit> The above document, with directions for depositing subscriptions, purports to come as
                            a sort of " first fruits " from Buddhist China- men in Australia, who when reflecting upon
                            the heathenish darkness that enshrouds Christ- endom, become fired with a genuine mission-
                            ary spirit. It certainly bespeaks the nobility of human nature in its best estate, as well
                            as reveals the half-hidden grandeur of the Orient. There are many Chinamen in Aus- tralia,
                            and mostly Buddhists. The Manda- rins of China admire the " Sage of the West," Jesus; but
                            despise that Christianity that forced opium into the Empire, and through an infuriated
                            soldiery, burned the Emperor's li- brary in Pekin. It is certain that India and China
                            purpose sending missionaries to Eng- land and America. Let those who have " put on Christ" —
                            those who " walk in the resur- rection " — forbid them not; but welcome them in the spirit
                            which breathes " peace on earth and good will to man."</p></div2><div2 type="history" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Torture of prisoners" TEIform="index"/>THE TORTURE OF PRISONERS</head><p TEIform="p">It is not more than a century ago that the torture of a prisoner charged with a criminal
                            offense was the common practice in nearly every country of Europe. England had become an
                            exception, by that time, to this rule, and so had Sweden. Prus- sia was reformed in this
                            regard by Frederick the Great early in his reign. Imperial Rome had for- bidden the torture
                            of the accused, unless he were a slave. The torture of a prisoner in the course of his trial
                            was justified on the ground that it was essen- tial to bring to light the real facts in the
                            case. At the same time a confession racked or wheeled from a prisoner was not deemed
                            satisfactory. With a stupidity which modern jurisprudence can hardly equal, the self-accuser
                            was compelled to reaffirm his statement under oath, as if evidence given in the agony of
                            torture would be strengthened by repetition, wrung from the victim through fear of further
                            torture. The outrageous practice was defended also on the ground that it was a sort of
                            extra-judicial purgation of infamy. Others again, went so far as to reason that the prisoner
                            might be guilty of some crime of which he had not been accused, and either he would be
                            brought to own up, or receive in the process, a punishment which would answer the demands of
                            justice. The iniquity of this practice was thoroughly shown up by the Marquis Beccario, an
                            eminent Italian philosopher, in a treatise on crimes and punishment, which swiftly passed to
                            several edi- tions ; and about the same time by Voltaire in his essay on the same subject.
                            The arguments used were so cogent and persuasive that a thorough revolution was the result.
                            Modern Christian juris- prudence owes an incalculable debt to those two humane men. One
                            would suppose that lawyers and judges, having most to do with such things, would have been
                            the first to move in this reform; on the contrary, it was brought about in spite of them.
                            The legal profession, bench and bar alike, do not search for principles. There are no pre-
                            cedents for taking advanced positions, until com- pelled to do so by public opinion.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Peace in the woods" TEIform="index"/>PEACE IN THE WOODS. </head><p TEIform="p">[From the Poughkeepsie News.] <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The Peace meeting which has been waited for with interest by large numbers of
                                    excellent people, was held yesterday morning and evening in Wi- ley's grove pursuant
                                    to the call. We are compelled to content ourselves for the day with the merest
                                    outline of its proceedings. The woods were well filled with the most intelli- gent
                                    and orderly assemblage it has ever known. About five hundred persons were present, a
                                    large proportion of whom were women, young and old, with conveyances by the hundred.
                                    The day was fine, the wind just swaying the tree tops, and making the softest
                                    accompaniment to one of the most peaceful scenes one ever meets. Upon a raised
                                    platform the venerable head of John A. Spear, of Philadelphia, was prominent,
                                    flanked by six of the sweetest of Shakeresses, with their plain caps and white
                                    handkerchiefs and drab gowns, two Shakermen and the Madames Deyo, Blake and Victor,
                                    with Messrs. Crummey, Gardner and others. The morning session was opened at
                                    half-past ten with singing by the Shaker friends, seven in all, two men and five
                                    women, with voices as gentle as the air above them. Order was then called by Mr.
                                    Charles Deyo, and singing again by the Poughkeepsie Temperance choir, the piece
                                    being " Glory to the Lord." The choir sang " Stand the Storm." Mrs. Blake made an
                                    address. Mrs. Amanda Deyo read lengthy and interesting letters from Alfred W. Love,
                                    of Philadelphia, L. C. Whipper, of Mystic, Conn., who was formerly imprisoned for
                                    not paying a tax, from J. W. On- derdonk, S. M. C. Perkins, President of the Amer-
                                    ican Peace Society, H. C. Denham and Gerritt Smith. The Shaker friends sang "
                                    Beautiful Shore," and everybody seemed to be wishing they were all there together.
                                    Daniel Offord, one of the members of the North Lebanon Shaker Society, gave an
                                    account of the origin and objects of the Society and of the hos- tile action of the
                                    government toward non-resist- ants. The Poughkeepsie choir then sang " Let us have
                                    Peace," which was not the composition of the late Gen. Grant. Mrs. Elizabeth
                                    Underhill then made an address, the Shakers sang " We are hastening On," while
                                    everybody wished they would stay, and the morning services were over. At two o'clock
                                    the meeting was opened again by singing from the Temperance choir, followed by the
                                    Shakers. Letters from F. W. Evans, the Sha- ker Elder, and Antoinette Doolittle,
                                    were read by Mrs. Amanda Deyo. Mrs. Blake then made a vig- orous speech, followed by
                                    L. V. Gardner of this city. The choir sang " Purity and Love," and the crowd was
                                    silent to a whisper. Mrs. Matilda Victor, of Michigan, made an im- passioned
                                    address. She was followed by one of the Shakeresses, Anna White, daughter of Robert
                                    White, of New York, who has belonged to the Lebanon Society for seventeen years, and
                                    was formerly a pupil of Mr. William Gibbons, who taught the seminary on Mansion
                                    Square, many years since. Better results or a better meeting could not have been
                                    reasonably desired.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Poughkeepsie news" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="93" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakeress: the government of children" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERESS: THE GOVERNMENT OF CHILDREN</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">The proper culture and government of chil- dren, is an intricate subject, not generally
                            understood. It is a science that demands deep study and attention ; for upon the proper
                            training of the young and rising generation, the future greatness and real character of the
                            nation — its morals — civil and religious pol- ity — depend. Great attention is given to
                            zoology, agri- culture, and horticulture. Continued efforts are made, not only to improve
                            the germs of each according to the family, or tribe to -which they belong, but also, to
                            understand their nature — their powers of endurance — the climate most congenial to health,
                            and the soil best adapted to their life and growth. Those possessing animal life, are
                            governed by instinct in regard to propagation — are under natural law — and observe times
                            and seasons. In this respect they are a law unto themselves. Times and seasons, are equally
                            necessary to be observed in the vegetable kingdom; but man is the judge and active agent in
                            reference to seed-time; and upon his knowledge, when and how to sow, plant and cultivate,
                            depends in a great degree the fruitage. But to return to our subject, the " Govern- ment of
                            Children." What do we find? In the first place, we find the major part of the children in
                            society in the same condition that David the psalmist found himself, when he said " Behold I
                            was shapen in iniquity, and in sin did my mother conceive me." In other words, my parents
                            did not regard times and seasons, and I was the product of inordinate desire and passion,
                            instead of the fruit of those who were perfect in the work of generating their kind. Under
                            these circumstances, we begin our work at a decided disadvantage. Children in our time are
                            precocious; and all the condition of society conduce to make them so. While great care is
                            taken to educate and develop the intellect, their food, dress and exciting amusements all
                            tend to stimulate the passion in children, who would, if in a normal, child- hood state, be
                            as innocent as the lambs tha' skip and play in green pastures; but are now subjects of
                            secret vice at an astonishingly early age; and through that source, the dispo- sition is
                            soured, the temper is easily excitec and a spirit of insubordination takes the place of
                            child-like obedience and submission. How the best way to meet these conditions, anc the
                            wisest means to be used to control them is the subject now under consideration. We read that
                            the God of the Hebrews at one time said, " The iniquity of the fathers shall be visited upon
                            the children to the third and fourth generations." At a later perioc the Lord God said by
                            one of the prophets " The son shall not bear the iniquity of his father, but both father and
                            son shall bear their own iniquity and die for their own sin. There is a qualified truth in
                            both of those averments. It is a self-evident fact, that physical dis- 93 of their being by
                            teaching them to think right; and as they mature, to unfold their reasoning x&gt;wers on
                            the intellectual, moral and spirit- ual plane! In our humble opinion this object can be
                            obtained the most effectually, by giving them the strongest evidence of our love, in kind
                            admonition, patient endurance with their faults, and by appealing to their better feel-
                            ings, showing them that obedience will in- sure happiness, and lead to enduring honor. Added
                            to this, children should be taught that physical health is essential to happiness; and in
                            order to secure it strict attention must be given to diet, dress and ventilation. It is a
                            duty, binding upon all who have the charge of children, to teach them to subsist upon plain,
                            wholesome food. Give them bread made of unbolted flour — vegetables — and healthy milk; and
                            let good refined sugar, with fruits of various kinds, take the place of poisonous candies,
                            and rich pastry, adulter- ated with deleterious substances. Then we may hope, if children
                            are reared properly, they will have no desire to depart from the path of rectitude in after
                            life.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Work" TEIform="index"/>WORK</head><p TEIform="p">Jesus said, "I must work the works of Him that sent me, while it is day. The night cometh,
                            when no man can work." We all know what it is to employ ourselves about something we call
                            work. It may be something of use, or it may be very frivolous and unnecessary ; still, if it
                            call out of us an earnestness of action, physical exercise for the body, and employment for
                            the mind, it is bet- ter than inaction For if we observe .nature faithfully we shall see
                            that every thing works, from man, whose pleasant work it was to till and dress the garden,
                            to the minutest insect, or tiniest leaf upon the tree. The laborious toil which depresses by
                            its long continuance and ill-paid servitude, is still better than idleness and inertia ; the
                            noisy blusterer better than the no worker. But how preferable the profound worker, who in
                            silence brings forth grand results. As the curse lifts itself from the so long groaning
                            earth, and woman, by self-denial and cultivation, rises above the plane of passional and
                            sensual life, will not man, too, feel that this life of toil is not without its
                            physiological use ? This beautiful earth needs multitudes of agriculturists to keep and
                            dress it, whose manliness would be better preserved than by crowding into the steaming
                            cities, and enter- ing upon pursuits calling' for but little outlay of muscle, or of mind.
                            The life-giving stimu- lus for work, derived from the fresh breezes of heaven and nature's
                            charms, is immeasur- able. The Apostle said, " Work out your own salvation," or deliverance
                            from any evil that oppresses or afflicts, particularly any sinful habit. Have we a temper
                            which would com- pel the tongue to utter words which our rea- son would condemn ? We have
                            work to do, that we say or do nothing we would not have another say or do to us. Have we
                            moodiness and moroseness in our natural temperament ? We have, if possible, harder work to
                            do, to be- come the genial, kind and loving beings the followers of Christ should be;
                            diffusers of that love which should control each thought and deed. Are we prone to be
                            trivial and giddy — thoughtless and indifferent in our spiritual nature — its sweet and
                            blessed resources yet unawakened ? Then let us heed the Apostle's word and commence on a
                            life of higher earn- estness. " The temple of God is holy which temple are ye." Let ns
                            realize, then, that the time for " the cleansing of the sanctuary " has come to us, and that
                            all that is not hallowed and of use, in purifying and refining the temple, should be driven
                            out. We find there is work in this ; and to have it thoroughly furnished, SHAKERE88. <pb n="94" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> fit for the Holy Spirit to inhabit, is work worthy of an angel's love
                            and zeal. As the poet has so fitly said — " Let us do our work all well, Both the unseen and
                            the seen, Make the house where God should dwell Beautiful and fair and clean." Cheerfully,
                            then let us " work with our might," feeling that by so doing we are put- ting ourselves in
                            harmony with the Creator and His works, and becoming resurrected into the angelic life of
                            pure and heavenly love and unselfish uses. Each and all of us, if we do truly follow Christ,
                            will find our " wilderness of temp- tation," our "garden of Gethsemene," as well as our "
                            mount of Transfiguration." And if we shrink not from them, nor deny the Christ, who is
                            seeking by every tender and loving appeal, to win and hold us to the service of love and
                            truth, great will be our reward. We may find the cross, sometimes, heavy and burdensome, and
                            the yoke galling; but the quiet rest of spirit we experience, after a temptation overcome,
                            or a decisive " Get thee behind me Satan," will more than compensate for all the pain. "
                            These are they who have come up out of great tribulation and have washed their robes (not
                            without labor) in the life of the Lamb "— by no vicarious atonement; for, as the Scrip-
                            tures say, " Obedience is better than sacrifice." " The blood is the life," and they have
                            lived his life, and " followed the Lamb whitherso- ever he goeth," or has led. Their
                            confession and repentance have " cleansed their robes " so that they have " no fearful
                            looking for- ward" to the future; but a quiet trust that the same loving heart which said —
                            " She hath done a good work " will receive them into his peaceful habitations in the spirit
                            land, or call them to still more earnest work in his spiritual vineyard. For every faithful
                            soul there awaits the solemn consciousness which prompted the words of Jesus, " I have
                            finished the work thou gavest me to do," and this will be the consolation whenever brought
                            before the bar of enlightened conscience, or in receiving the verdict of unchangeable truth
                            and right. That wise writer Ecclesiasticus said " Hate not laborious work, neither
                            husbandry, which the Most High hath ordained." So far from laborious work being degrading,
                            we believe it to be one of the means of man's regeneration. And that the measure of his
                            happiness and honor will ere long be — not how much wealth he has amassed, nor from whom
                            descended; but, how useful is he to his fellows ? How many anguished souls has he cheered
                            and comforted ? How many needy bodies fed and clothed? And he will be considered God's
                            truest nobleman who does most of such work, and sets an example of diligent hand-labour.
                            Mothers, whose active little ones surround you, teach them to work, and let them help you,
                            tho' their noisy, boisterous spirits tire instead of helping. And when play time comes,
                            snatch the moments for rest. Let them learn to work skillfully and well, when young, and
                            they will find something to occupy hand and brain as they grow older; and not, through very
                            disgust of life, find a suicide's grave. Teach them to work that they may be self-
                            sustaining and not obliged to wait for some opportunity to bring to them position and in-
                            fluence unearned. There will be work to do while there remain any poor souls grovelling in
                            the mire of sensu- ality, or unblest by the gospel of peace through self-denial. Some Christ
                            will still be needed " to preach to the spirits in the prisons" of darkness, discouragement
                            and death, a gospel of love and uplifting; and an aptitude gained in this life for
                            benevolent, self-denying labor, must surely add to the spirit's uses, and conse- quent
                            blessedness.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webster, E. H." TEIform="persName"/>E. H. Webster, Harvard, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Letter" TEIform="index"/>A LETTER</head><p TEIform="p">Editors Shaker and Shakeress— Will you allow a four months' member of South Union, to
                            congratulate you upon the excellent matter in the October number of your paper ? From first
                            to last, it is replete with good and wise sayings. Ideas of reform are inculcated, with
                            liberality of sentiment, worthy the generous patronage of its own people, and of the public.
                            Among Believers, the mingling of sexes is without the debasing influences, arising from the
                            present marriage system. Now, that the brave Shaker pioneers are passing away, after years
                            of physical toil incident to founding such a community home, those now gathering to it, can
                            begin to add the increase of mental endowments, that shall unite health to wealth, through
                            the practical wisdom that shall effect a perfect release from the mental thralldom, and
                            physical suffering, consequent upon ignor- ance. The Shakers are familiar with spiritual
                            intercourse, being, through Mother Ann's in- spiring prophetic genius, founded upon Divine
                            revelation. Were the outside Spiritualists familiar with the manifestations through her
                            followers, they would not feast so exclusively upon the " Rochester Rappings." It is only
                            another convincing proof, that " originality " is not safe to pin a modern discovered truth
                            upon. When the origin of human intelligence is ascertained, then Spirit communication can
                            specify the time when certain new thoughts were first revealed to mortals. The world is so
                            apt to forget principle, in the enthusiasm of building up systems, creeds and dogmas, it is
                            not wonderful that the contestants are defeated in reaching the Eternal, by a favored route
                            intended only for the elect. When I attended those immaculate places of worship — the Church
                            of God that offered the Holy Eucharist from the latest style of silver plate — I thought
                            truth was glorious, and Christianity its greatest exponent. But upon the proof of
                            immortality given me, by an Infidel Medium — resolving the atoning blood of the Lamb, into
                            good bread and wine, more efficacious to invigorate the body than to save the soul — I began
                            to question other things by the analysis of reason. The past, written records are simple —
                            rudimental — in comparison to the possibilities of the advanc- ing mind in its researches
                            after truth. Where- fore then, I asked, be bound to the past, when authority is not adapted
                            to requirements of the present 1 Being thus gradually released from the bonds of childhood
                            faith, I launched forth to seek my own spiritual salvation, by working in accordance with
                            individual responsibility. I have at last moored in the quiet orderly harbor of Shakerism. I
                            find the families genial (and so far as my own observations can judge), hospitable, generous
                            and self-sacri- ficing. They acknowledge faults — lean to virtue's side — and can never be
                            submerged by the corruptions of the world. If all the Communities are as well favored
                            with'pregressive Leaders as this one, no Brother nor Sister need despair of getting physical
                            and spiritual wants supplied. When a people are determined to make practical the righteous
                            theories of Christianity, how can they fail ? The world, concluding that mere preaching and
                            praying, have not, and cannot bring hap- piness — turn to question how the band of Believers
                            that grow by works instead of faith, manage to walk calmly, while the storm is raging so
                            fiercely without.— It is by firmness of purpose, in resisting the follies of social customs,
                            that enslave woman, by fashion's demoralizing hold, and aid her to an equal standard with
                            the opposite sex, in business, and mental culture. They battle against the debasing passions
                            — health destroying habits — that degenerate both soul and body. Shakers, repel the horrible
                            doctrine of total depravity and predestination to heaven or hell, as they do the physical
                            resurrection; which is against all scientific facts. They condemn War with its bloody sword
                            of devastation, and favor arbitration, and peaceful interposition, as a more enlightened way
                            to promote harmony and fraternal love. Can these principles ever die ? Nay; not if the
                            Shakers themselves were to ignore them. Well have they cher- ished these bright truths. The
                            excrescences incident to all organizations, will in the order of change be left in the past,
                            under the in creasing light of Divine Revelation. Salt in Bread cicatrizes the mucus
                            membrane of the larynx, inducing diphtheria.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dwyer, Annie T." TEIform="persName"/>Annie T. Dwyer, South Union, Ky.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Forgiveness" TEIform="index"/>FORGIVENESS</head><p TEIform="p">To love our enemies, and to forgive those who injure us, is a Christian duty that requires
                            self-sacrifice. The command, " Love your enemies, bless them that curse you, do good to them
                            that hate you, and pray for them that despitefully use and persecute you " is explicit. We
                            may find it difficult to obey this command ; but it is unchristian to do otherwise. It is
                            easier to endure privation and suffer- ing, severe bereavement and death, than to feel
                            kindly toward those who rejoice when we are afflicted, and delight to add to our sor- rows —
                            whose words are as arrows to pierce our hearts and blight our happiness. To pray for those
                            who have sought to wound our peace, and to rejoice where light shines upon their pathway,
                            after they have darkened ours, calls for an amount of self-denial and grace, which few
                            possess. If we are found wanting in this grace, how can we offer this petition, " Forgive us
                            our tres- passes as we forgive those who trespass against us ? " Yet, Jesus expressly
                            declared, " If you forgive not men their trespasses, neither will your Father in heaven
                            forgive your trespasses." If we cherish enmity in our hearts, we can- not feel the love of
                            God. He will hide his face from us, and we shall walk in darkness, not having the light of
                            life to guide us. When Christ taught his disciples to for- give, not only seven, but seventy
                            times seven, then they prayed " Lord, increase our faith ! " It is our duty, not only to
                            possess a spirit of forgiveness toward our enemies, but, also, to deal kindly with those
                            who, by misfortune, have been unjustly thrown upon the cold charities of the world. They who
                            are striv- ing to battle with the stern realities of life, with no friendly hand to aid them
                            in the strife, or voice of sympathy to whisper comfort and assuage their grief, need
                            compassion. Those who have passed through the troubled waters of affliction and destitution,
                            know better how to feel for the woes of others, than they who have never drank from the cup
                            of disappointment and sorrow. "Every such heart knoweth its own bitterness !" A soft word, a
                            kind act, may lift the threaten- ing cloud, banish the darkness of night, and give hope of
                            the dawn of a bright morning.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Breedlove, Virgie" TEIform="persName"/>Virgie Breedlove, South Union, Ky.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Liberty" TEIform="index"/>LIBERTY</head><p TEIform="p">Liberty consists in the power to act without restraint or control except from the immutable
                            laws of nature. In every phase of life, which forms the grand pyramid of material exist-
                            ence, and in the vast realm embracing mind, or spirit, in its unfolding growth, there is an
                            innate desire, an unconquerable love of Liberty, even from the smallest manifesta- tions of
                            sentient life through progressive degrees, to the center of Supreme Intelli- gence. Any
                            infringement of this native right in vegetable or animal growth, or in the de- velopment of
                            those faculties with which the human mind is endowed, is evinced by corre- sponding death, a
                            silent yet expressive lan- guage. Hence Liberty is life ! It is this love of life, this
                            quenchless fire in the heart of humanity, that has warmed to action and given momentum in
                            the strife against the foes of truth ; from early history to the present day, men have
                            struggled for religious liberty and political freedom. God has always had his witnesses;
                            while one class have battled for human rights with carnal weapons,— being advocates of war
                            on the low strata of physical force and retaliation, an eye for an eye their highest
                            conception of justice — another class have turned the combative elements of their nature,
                            energy and will into a higher channel, and relied on Almighty Power to aid them in wielding
                            the two edged sword of spiritual truth which subdues the enemies within the human heart, and
                            is a safe- guard against those without. In every Nation where Church and State have been
                            united, the increase of truth has been opposed by the Priesthood, operating through the
                            civil powers. Great has been SHAKER A.ND 94 <pb n="95" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKERESS. 95 the contest
                            between bondage and freedom. " Truth, is mighty and will prevail." Liberty is the herald and
                            guardian of progress, and floods of persecution cannot sweep away its power; the sword
                            cannot slay, nor the in- quisitor's flame consume it! Truth has ad- vanced and gained
                            strength in defiance of the rack and dungeon. Abcut a century ago, a company of heroic,
                            humanity loving men arose, and inspired by love of Liberty, they determined to break the
                            yoke of oppression which held them in politi- cal and religious servitude. The contest was
                            long and severe ; but they realized that the welfare of unborn millions was involved in the
                            success of the cause in which they had enlisted, and courageously they resolved to sacrifice
                            self-interest and life itself for the priceless boon — Liberty. It is evident that they
                            perceived that Religious freedom could not be gained and maintained, except through
                            Political liberty, based upon just laws. In a prophetic spirit, one of those patriots said,
                            " Here may the flame of Christian Liberty which has been kindled, burn brighter and
                            brighter, until states and empires shall be no more ;" evidently alluding to the Millennium,
                            for which they prepared a place. It is a remarkable fact, that cotemporary with those
                            workers for civil Liberty in America, a little band was raised up in Eng- land,— by the Holy
                            Spirit —whose hearts were warmed from celestial fires ; and with awak- ened consciences, and
                            deep soul-thirstings, they sought freedom from the tyrannical power of sin — to search out
                            its source — and if pos- sible to find an antidote. By divine revela- tion,— and a baptism
                            of the Christ Spirit — they were instructed, that only through the death of the carnal life,
                            could the spiritual life be gained, and the germs of immortality in the human soul find
                            expansion and growth. By spirit guidance, they were directed to find shelter beneath the
                            banner of political freedom which was about to be raised in America, where they might
                            commence to establish a Church in which they could enjoy liberty of conscience, to worship
                            God as they were moved in spirit to do, and be protected from harm. The ?eed of a New and
                            Living Church was committed to their charge, seed which was the product of suf- fering
                            witnesses of God — the saints and mar- tyrs of past ages — that had been gathered and
                            carefully stored by Angels appointed to the work, until the time was fulfilled. They laid
                            the foundations of the Church of Christ's Second Appearing — by the help of good Angels of
                            the Resurrection Order — deep and strong. Now, it becomes our duty to up- build the walls.
                            While those in the outward Order are striving to perfect the civil govern- ment — to make
                            the Land a birthright inheri- tance— placing capital and labor in just relations, thus
                            enhancing freedom and hap- piness, which will eventuate in the forma- tion of a New Earth,
                            let us learn to study more deeply the oracles of God pertaining to the spiritual angelic
                            life ; and be advancing in light and truth, and in obedience to all that belongs to the New
                            Heavens. Thus by united effort we may build a temple of Truth, over which shall wave in
                            triumph the ensign of sweet Liberty.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, Catharine" TEIform="persName"/>Catharine Allen, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tribute" TEIform="index"/>TRIBUTE</head><p TEIform="p">It is now a century, since there arrived in this country, one, whose very name, sends a
                            thrill of joy over the spirits of many who have been led by her. spirit (through the
                            instrumentality of others), to embrace her faith, and labor in the vineyard of Christ's
                            Second Appearing. And, when we consider how great were her trials, and how zealously and
                            perseveringly she labored to overcome them — nothing daunted by the cruel persecutions which
                            she was forced to endure from her vile opposers — we cannot be sufficiently thankful for our
                            privilege. Beautiful homes we have in various parts of the country, where all, from every
                            clime, and nation — who desire to live pure and godly lives — may find a haven of rest. Here
                            they can behold the fruits of the Gospel, and may also become living souls in the vineyard
                            of the Lord. Should not the sincere prayer of all Zion's Children be, that the day be not
                            far distant, when the sin-sick and weary shall flock to our courts pleading for admission 1
                            Not only for this increase should we pray but let us all earnestly labor for that spiritual
                            growth in ourselves, which is so necessary, if we would approximate those who laid the
                            foundations of this beautiful Gospel; and who endured hardships innumerable, in building
                            these homes whi^h we are privileged to enjoy, free from persecution. Shall we not then, dear
                            Brethren and Sisters, show our high appreciation of their labors and trials, by being good,
                            in the very highest acceptation of the term 1</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Barry, Ruth" TEIform="persName"/>Ruth Barry, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Plants" TEIform="index"/>(For the Juvenile Class.) PLANTS</head><p TEIform="p">Op all objects in nature, perhaps there are none more familiar to us than plants. They please
                            and interest us, and afford subjects for thought; many of them are emblematical of human
                            virtues. Indeed, I have thought whether a close observer might not be able to trace many of
                            the vicissitudes of life through these silent orators of nature. What wonders lie concealed
                            in them! If we look around us, what a variety of little sprouting spears we see beneath our
                            feet; no earthly hand could form and infuse life into one such. And the beautiful evergreen
                            trees, extending their branches in all directions, call forth our admiration. The maxim "A
                            place for everything, and everything in its place," is good and useful — forest trees are
                            out of their proper place when intermixed with choice fruit trees — wild plants are
                            unwelcome guests in a cultivated garden, and we seek to extirpate them. Notwithstanding, the
                            world would be robbed of much of its beauty were it denuded of the wild plants and weeds
                            Plants are made more beautiful, and useful, in propor- tion to the degree of cultivation
                            which they receive. The potato, once poisonous, has, by culture, become one of the staple
                            articles of food. Some plants are very remarkable in their formation. In southern Asia it is
                            said a plant is found called " Pitcher-plant," so called from its peculiar shape. The bowl
                            of this plant holds nearly a teacupfull of sap, and is formed with a lid on the top. It is
                            abundant in Ceylon, and is often called Monkey Gup, for the reason that Monkeys raise the
                            lid and drink the sap. In India, one kind of these plants grows on a climbing stem of nearly
                            a hundred feet in length, and is destitute of leaves till near the extremity ; it has no
                            cover, consequently in- sects are often drowned in the sap; and it is supposed that the
                            plant receives its nourish- ment from the decomposition of those insects. In South Carolina
                            there is also a plant called a Fly Trap. When the sun shines it opens — a fly lights upon
                            it, and immediately it closes and remains thus, until the victim ceases to struggle, then it
                            opens again to receive another. We are informed that this species of plants is found on the
                            borders of Cape Fear and Santee rivers only. The Cactus is another wonder, found in the
                            vegetable world. It has neither leaves nor stems and will live several months without water.
                            It is well adapted to its own climate. During the wet season of the year it absorbs a large
                            amount of water and stores it away for use through the dry season. We look upon the
                            variegated flowers and plants — their different shapes and hues — with admiration ; but we
                            cannot tell how one of them is formed. Nature is a silent, but a diligent and effectual
                            worker.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Offord, Miriam" TEIform="persName"/>Miriam Offord, Canaan, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Centennial" TEIform="index"/>CENTENNIAL</head><p TEIform="p">A century has passed, since the first gleam of a New Morn burst forth on America's soil — a
                            gleam of light that since that time, has pierced many dark places, and been welcomed by
                            thousands of weary souls, who had hoped and prayed for its dawn. Mother Ann, and the little
                            band that accom- panied her on the perilous voyage to this western land,—destined by
                            Providence to be a refuge for the oppressed of all nations — found the people struggling for
                            freedom from British rule and tyrannical exaction — to sepa- rate Church and State, and to
                            found a free government, based upon equal rights, where liberty of conscience could be
                            enjoyed. It was a momentous struggle ! The welfare of future generations depended upon its
                            success. Had those fetters, which bound the consciences of men and women remained unbroken,
                            the establishment of a Spiritual, " Shaker Order," would have been impossible. History tells
                            of the life-devotion, and power- ful action of noble hearts and wise heads, who made great
                            sacrifices to obtain full release from unjust taxation imposed on the colonies by the
                            English government. Its great oppres- sion, called forth strong efforts for freedom and
                            justice — which resulted in a long contin- ued war — by the people, under the leadership of
                            the bravest and truest men of the nation. After the dark night of peril had passed, they
                            lost no time in combining the wisdom and knowledge of Statesmen and Lawyers, in forming a
                            government that would subserve the best interests of humanity. Those great and
                            self-sacrificing men — justly called the fathers of our country — Americans, are, in duty
                            bound, to honor ; and for the religious freedom which they handed down, as a boon, to
                            posterity, we give thanks to-day. Can we over-estimate the privilege of sitting in peace and
                            tranquillity " under our own vine and fig- tree " ? The Declaration of Independence,
                            unlocked, and threw open the gate of truth for the Queen of Zion, robed in garments of
                            purity and salvation to enter, the Daughter, anointed with the Christ-spirit with an Olive
                            leaf — seeking rest in the hearts of a new people, in a new land. Starting from this point,
                            let us see what a century has effected. The revival which oc- curred near the close of the
                            eighteenth century, had prepared many for the reception of the testimony of Christ's second
                            appearing, through Mother Ann; and they were " a willing people in the day of God's power,"
                            — noble and generous souls — who, under the spiritual awakening of truth and religious
                            conviction, sacrificed worldly honor, and high position in the ranks of society, and gave
                            their soul energies, and physical strength, in laying the foundation of a glorious temple,
                            and in framing and establishing wise and just laws, which would safely guide and guard the
                            inmates of that temple through all storms that might arise ; and that would gather them into
                            community relation, and consolidate them one united body —true Believers in Christ. A
                            nucleus was then formed — a Central Power—that has been like a spiritual magnet to attract
                            other honest, sincere souls, who were seeking good; and who through faith and obedience have
                            found a relation to the first- born children of Gospel light. Of the varied and peculiar
                            ways by which individuals have been gathered — from the millions who trod the highway of
                            life — to stand in the ranks of the Zion Church on earth — we can only say, that He who
                            prepared the way, and sent messengers to rear a temple, constructed of " living stones,"
                            will protect his own from harm and blight; and not one stone will find a permanent resting
                            place there, that has not been tested by the rod of truth. Self-denial, Industry and
                            Economy, have formed a home with its " hundred fold of fathers — mothers — brothers and
                            sisters — houses and lands," and an accumulation of goodness, consequent upon a righteous
                            blend- ing of the New Earth, and New Heaven. If one century hath so well fulfilled the
                            promises of Jesus, what will Zion's attainments be when the years of the Millennium are
                            numbered by the thousands ?</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Collins, Elvah" TEIform="persName"/>Elvah Collins, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker meetings in Steinway Hall, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Meetings in Steinway
                            Hall, New York.</head><p TEIform="p">In response to invitations from New York and Brooklyn, Elder F. W. Evans, with a Delegation
                            of Speakers and Singers from other Communities, will hold three Meetings on Sabbath,
                            November 22d.</p></div2><pb n="96" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beautiful angel home" TEIform="index"/>BEAUTIFUL ANGEL HOME</head><p TEIform="p">1. O, my beautiful angel home! Fraught with blessing and peace, Where no sorrow of earth can
                            come, Where inharmonies cease; 2. Storm and tempest may wildly reign, Clouds as dark as the
                            night, Gather over the golden plain, Shutting thy glory from sight. Bas'd and built on the
                            rock of truth, Rear'd by an Almighty arm, Shall not hands of a holy pow'r, Chase and scatter
                            the mist, Heav'nly vigils protect thy youth, From all danger and harm. That the light of a
                            brighter hour, With thee may ever exist? O, my beautiful angel home! Fraught with blessing
                            and peace, Bright immortals around thee come, Crowning with joy thy increase. Thus the oare
                            of a father kind, And a mother's pure love, Bid thee prosper and union find To fair Zion
                            above ; Storm, and tempest and cloud defied, God thy life and support, Hosts of heaven upon
                            thy side, Light to the nations thou art. Chorus : O, my beautiful, etc. Bound to hearts that
                            are willing here, Toil and labor are mine, Till my spirit and life appear In thy glory to
                            shine; Till thy truth like a flood shall roll, O'er a sin-darkened earth, Drawing hither the
                            burdened soul, Weary of spiritual dearth. Chorus : O, my beautiful, etc.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Retrospective" TEIform="index"/>RETROSPECTIVE</head><p TEIform="p">Adown the highway of the past Fierce Passion's chariots clang and dash, To forward truths,
                            ordained to last When human weapons cease to clash. Through Jewish epochs we discern A
                            glimmering light — though faint and far, We watch it, till we see it burn— The pride of time
                            — the Morning Star. And then through Gentile ages search, To find a corresponding ray— A
                            gleam of the millennial church— A flush of the millennial day. What scenes of horror center
                            there ! Where savage factions strive for might; With arm of steel, not heart of pray'r,
                            Though God would guide them in the right. Far stretched the sacerdotal cloud ; Gross
                            darkness on the people lay; The Church and State with scepters proud, Forbade the dawning of
                            the day. Yet, Church and State, like marshes are That point their lances at the sky ; Their
                            festering odors breathe afar. Their reeds must bow when winds pass by. All strong through
                            carnage, England stood, And king and bishop bore the sway, When Cromwell rose in midnight
                            mood, To herald Freedom's distant day; He smote the altar, and the throne, And hurled them
                            from their lofty heights, Gave Freedom's Temple just one stone— The common people's vested
                            rights. The slaves that Moses sought to free, Were unprepared for freedom's boon ; And
                            Cromwell found that liberty Had come to England's sons too soon. Yet, was his mission timely
                            wrought, It made successive tyrants cower, Unfolded energy and thought, That gave Columbia's
                            land its power. O, England ! thou wert called to be. The greatest nation of the world I Thy
                            grand Republic, strong and free, Extending where thy flag unfurl'd. What priest or statesman
                            now could count The loss thy sordid children brought, For it was thine, to be the fount At
                            which redeeming gifts were wrought. The tide waves of a hundred years, Have flung their
                            wrecks on every land, Earth has writh'd on in blood and tears Since from thee went an angel
                            band, They were the messengers of God, Raised up to break the power of sin, To rend the
                            covering spread abroad, And let the light of judgment in. The Spirit of the Christ reveal'd,
                            Was in a lowly woman's heart: From thee her glory was conceal'd, She must from thee,
                            unknown, depart. Yet, the glad tidings of great joy, She published wide in Freedom's land,
                            Where king or priest cannot destroy The good which God designs to stand!</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Devyr, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/>Cecelia Devyr, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our sphere" TEIform="index"/>OUR SPHERE</head><p TEIform="p">Labor is the sphere assigned us, And our time we will employ, That a harvest we may gather.
                            Yielding peace and endless joy. In the light that's ever dawning, We will toil with fervent
                            will, With the loved and faithful number, Who the law of truth fulfill. While we're young
                            our souls will gather To our kindred pure and true, And with holiness of purpose, Seek the
                            inner realm to view. Upward to the sphere of angels Shall our aspirations tend, Where the
                            power of love can reach us, Where our hearts with good can blend. And along life's daily
                            pathway, We will cull celestial flowers, Bind them with the cords of virtue, Found within
                            fair Zion's bowers. 'Round our hearts we will entwine them. Till there is no room for wrong,
                            Till our souls can join the chorus Of the victors' happy song. While we rise on faith's
                            strong pinions, From earth's elements away, Where no blight nor sin can tarnish, Where no
                            treasure fades away. What though adverse clouds may lower, Beams of hope our course will
                            light, Till they guide us to the portals, Far beyond the shades of night.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Barnum, Mary C." TEIform="persName"/>Mary C. Barnum, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To subscribers" TEIform="index"/>TO SUBSCRIBERS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">To prepay postage, under the new law, sub- scribers to the Shaker and Shakeress, will please
                            remit sixty cents, for 1875.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lockwood, Nancy" TEIform="index"/>Nancy Lockwood
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Lockwood, Nancy" TEIform="persName">Nancy Lockwood</persName>, October 23, aged 84.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Crosman, Anna" TEIform="index"/>Anna Crosman
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Crosman, Anna" TEIform="persName">Anna Crosman</persName>, Oct. 24, aged 82, Mt. Lebanon, N.
                                Y.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sweet, Charles" TEIform="index"/>Charles Sweet
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Sweet, Charles" TEIform="persName">Charles Sweet</persName>, Oct. 1, aged 86, North Union,
                                O.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harwood, Jesse" TEIform="index"/>Jesse Harwood
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Harwood, Jesse" TEIform="persName">Jesse Harwood</persName>, Oct. 21, aged 74, Watervliet,
                                N. Y.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>HOME</head><p TEIform="p">Our Zion home is not adorned With pictured walls, or gold ; Nor in a glittering chain of
                            pearls, Is all her glory told. She bears the substance of sweet peace, The treasure of pure
                            love ; Her power, truth and holiness That rule the heavens above. Her walls are made of
                            living stones, With brightness they're aglow ; They form the temple of the Lord, Where souls
                            His truth may know. And all who come beneath this dome May work for virtue's fame, Gain the
                            true riches through that life Which claims a blessed name. O, happy home, what joys are
                            thine ! Who from thy courts would go, To be a slave to passions base, In wickedness to grow?
                            My heart will keep the sacred law That holds us in one band, And feast upon the heavenly
                            fruits, That grow in Canaan's land. With dear companions I'll unite In consecrated toil, And
                            growing in the glorious light, Will till the gospel soil. And when we leave this mortal
                            shore, To dwell with saints above, We'll breathe a pray'r that holiness May bless the nome
                            we love.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Burger, Sarah J." TEIform="persName"/>Sarah J. Burger, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Liberty of propagandism has almost always been greatly restricted in France" TEIform="index"/>Liberty of propagandism has almost always been greatly restricted in France
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"The liberty of propagandism has almost always been greatly restricted in France —narrowly
                            limi- ted by drilling and excessive regulations. In our unfortunate country it is not as in
                            free America; it is difficult to stir without authorized permission. Without Government
                            authority a lecture cannot be given, a place of worship opened, a meeting held, or tracts
                            distributed. Added to this, the Catholic priesthood is very powerful —more so, alas! at the
                            present time than ever, exercising particularly in small towns and country places,
                            considerable influence upon those in authority. It succeeds in fettering us in a thousand
                            ways. It does all it can to discredit us in the eyes of the nation, attacking us violently
                            from its pulpits, and not hesitating to employ against us the grossest calumnies. Most young
                            Frenchmen are brought up in a holy horror of Protestantism, and traces of this early
                            impression are even found clinging to the minds of men of independent thought —nay, of those
                            whose boast it is that they are free- thinkers."</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>